(wind whistling)
MAN: What's out there,
out in the great beyond?
And what's beyond that?
What's beyond beyond?
The answer is: I don't know.
And quite frankly,
I don't want to know,
because what I do know
is that they don't
hold a candle
to the greatest town
in the greatest country
on the greatest planet
in the whole universe.
Glenview, Ohio.
USA.
Earth.
Here in Glenview,
we value diversity.
I myself am friends
with an Indian man named Clyde.
And Mrs. Kim,
a wonderful widow from Korea.
Hey, Mrs. Kim.
Spray me.
Spray me, neighbor.
Whoo!
Sun shower.
Fun shower!
I don't have
any black friends yet,
but I am on the market.
My name's Evan Trautwig.
Oh. Ed Bosani.
Every day, I ask
not what Glenview
can do for me;
What can I do for Glenview?
Oh, geez, Jared, your glutes
are tighter than a snare drum.
That's why I founded
the running club,
the Spanish table
at the community center...
¿Donde esta
mi tanque de oxigeno?
...and created the position
of deputy secretary
at the city council.
All right,
next item on the agenda
stipulates curb height
for wheelchair access
be no more than six inches
in height.
Now, I know this is a hot topic,
so I will defer
to the commissioner.
Here, dreams
really do come true.
A simple man can start out
as a junior manager at Costco,
and 12 years later,
with hard work and gumption,
end up the senior manager
at that very same Costco.
I should know,
because that man's name
is me.
I don't mean to bust
your chops here, kid,
but this is total bullshit.
Those rats are as flat
as they ever have been.
I'm sorry. It really
should be working.
Excuse me, sir, if I might.
The activation button
is right there.
Holy shit.
This is incredible.
Yeah.
There's chipmunks all coming
out of the TV, Costco!
Look, the whole gang's here.
Yeah. Yeah,
it's a great set.
Full HD, 1080p,
240 hertz, TrueMotion.
Totally wireless...
Hey, hey, hey, buddy, please.
This is a miracle of technology.
This is incredible.
Where do I pay for this baby?
Justin will load you up.
Go to front-end checkout.
- You're a beauty.
- Okay.
Thank you, switch man.
All right.
Turning the switch on!
Ow.
Turning on a whole new
world for me.
Hey, Justin, if we stop by
some free food samples,
I'm not gonna be
pissed, either.
EVAN:
But you know what?
It's not all about work.
I've had a lot of fun
and formed friendships
that will last a lifetime.
(watch beeping)
Hey, there he is.
So?
There are 50 stars
on the American flag,
the Constitution
was written in 1787,
and...
I am now an American citizen.
(whooping laugh)
Really?
Yes.
Oh!
Antonio, that's great.
I knew it. I knew it.
You see, good things
happen to good people,
and you are a good man.
Oh. And look, boss.
I got a new tattoo to celebrate.
Oh.
Yeah.
Wow.
That's really fresh, isn't it?
Yeah.
"Proud to be an American."
Good. Maybe keep it
covered, though,
just 'cause it's not really
Costco policy, okay?
Yes, of course, boss.
I'm proud of you.
This is great.
All right, I got to get
out of here.
Okay.
Oh, hey, listen.
If a bag of Bugles
and a six-pack of Coke
go missing, it's on me.
You earned it.
Thanks, boss.
Buenas noches.
# Woke up quick at about noon #
# Just thought that I had to be
in Compton soon #
# I gotta get drunk
before the day begins #
# Before my mother
starts bitchin' #
# About my friends #
# A car pulls up,
who can it be? #
# A fresh El Camino
rolling Kilo G #
# He rolled down his window
and he started to say #
# It's all about making
that GTA #
# Yo, man #
Costco security, motherfucker!
# Yo, man, yo, man #
# Yo, man, get the fuck out #
# Cruisin' down the street
in my 6-4 #
# Jockin' the bitches,
slappin' the hoes #
# Went to the park
to get the scoop #
# Knuckleheads out there
cold shootin' some hoops #
# 'Cause the boys in the hood
are always hard #
# You come talkin' that trash,
we'll pull your card... #
Oh, yeah.
It's time to come out
of the pool, Denise.
# 'Cause I ain't
sayin' shit... #
Hey. What the hell, man?
(light switches clacking)
Shit.
(distant clank)
(grunts)
Hello?
Mr. Trautwig.
Is that you?
(panting, grunting)
(clattering)
Who's there?
(panting)
Okay.
(growling, clattering)
Oh.
What the fuck?
Listen!
They gave me a gun, okay?
And they didn't teach me
to use it properly.
So... you're in a lot of danger
if you don't just
back the fuck up, okay?
(heavy footstep)
(gasps) Oh, no!
No!
(whimpering)
Oh, no, no...!
(gasping)
(screams)
# #
WOMAN:
It's just a baby shower, hon.
EVAN: I don't know why you're
so excited about going there
when everything
is so great here.
We used to hate New York
together.
It was, like, one of our things.
It is great here, Evan.
I love it.
It's just a little boring.
Actually, it's super boring.
I just...
I want to get out
and see the world a little bit.
You know, get some culture,
eat some good food,
go to a few museums.
We have museums here.
All right, I think we're
still a couple days away,
but when I get back...
Yeah?
I'm going to walk
through that door,
and we are going to S-C-R-E-W.
Ooh, okay, okay.
(laughing):
Right on the kitchen floor.
Mmm, I love it
when you spell it.
Definitely.
Or we could do it
in the bedroom.
Thank you. Okay.
Or we could...
start in the kitchen,
then move up to the bedroom.
Bye.
Have fun.
Be safe.
I love you.
What is going on?
(siren whooping)
(indistinct radio communication,
helicopter hovering)
Whoa. Sorry, sir.
Can't let you in there.
No, no, no, it's okay.
I'm the, uh, manager.
This is my store.
Well, I'm afraid
your store is closed
- until further notice.
- What are you talking about?
I can't divulge that, sir.
Police policy.
Oh, wait a second.
You're the manager,
so do you happen to know
the name of the guy
who was working last night?
Yes... Antonio.
Antonio Guzman.
Antonio...
Why? Did something
happen to him?
Guz...man.
Yeah, he's dead.
What?
Are... are you sure?
Pretty sure.
Looks like your friend was
ripped apart by a wild animal.
Jesus.
We're dealing with one
sick son of a B.
Took the victim's skin.
Is... did...
did... are there...
are there any leads
or... fingerprints or...?
Slow down, guy.
I mean, we only got here,
like, two hours ago.
We strung up this yellow tape,
which took a while.
So, uh, you knew
the victim well?
Yeah. I...
He was a friend.
He was... just became
an American citizen.
And that made you angry.
No, it made me happy.
I was happy for him.
He was...
Then why'd you kill him?
I didn't kill him.
What... what are you
talking about?
Why are you staring
at me like that?
I'm just kidding.
Come on. Maybe you can
help I.D. the body.
Back here.
I had you going,
though... man!
("The Sound of Silence"
playing in Spanish)
FEMALE REPORTER:
The victim has been identified
as Antonio Guzman.
Here's what police told us
about the attack.
OFFICER:
We will do the best we can,
but I, for one,
would like to put
some of the responsibility
on the citizens of this town.
There's only like eight cops
in this town,
and there's thousands
of you guys, so,
not to point fingers
or anything, but...
Stay with us
for the latest details
on this developing story.
Back to you, Gail.
# #
(cheering)
(buzzer sounds)
ANNOUNCER: That's the half,
and as the players
march into the locking room,
we're going to be
joined on the field by, um...
Evan Trautwig.
(music fades)
Did anyone here cry themselves
to sleep last night?
(laughter)
EVAN:
It's okay. You can laugh.
Laughter is a common expression
of grief.
And yes, I did cry.
Because a man
was killed yesterday.
But tonight,
my tears have turned to fists!
(makes fart noise)
Because whoever did this
is still out there.
BOY: Who is this guy?
And we need to stop him
before he strikes again.
(makes fart noise)
Oh, struck again.
(laughing)
EVAN: No more murders!
Shh.
EVAN:
Because our society has rules.
And one of those rules is:
You can't kill someone
and take their skin!
That's not cool.
So, with that in mind,
I am forming
a neighborhood watch,
a task force
of concerned citizens
to solve the murder
of Antonio Guzman.
To keep an eye on any
and all suspicious activities,
and generally...
get to the bottom of things.
Thank you.
(cheering and applause)
(rattling)
(crunching)
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Solid turnout.
Thanks, everybody, for coming.
You're that guy
from Costco, right?
Yes, I am that guy.
Okay. Yeah.
Thanks.
All right, you want to, uh...
(doorbell rings)
Oh.
One more concerned citizen.
You mind if I look
around the place a little bit?
Looks like you got
a lot of knickknacks.
Oh, wow. Hi.
Neighborhood watch
meeting is...?
Yes. Really?
Yeah.
Great. Wow.
Okay.
I'm Evan.
I'm Jamarcus.
Great to meet you.
Good to meet you.
Great. That's great.
I was hoping another person
would come,
and you're the best type
of person it could be.
I mean, actually, I couldn't
have even hoped as much for...
Wow. This is...
Come on in.
I'm so pleased to have
this effect this early.
Terrific.
This is exciting.
Come on in.
Thank you. I'm excited, too.
Great.
Most people are disappointed
when they meet me, which...
British?
I am.
And you're American.
Yeah.
This looks like it's a, uh...
Thailand or something.
I don't know what it is.
I mean, it's b-beautiful.
Oh, my God!
There's another doll
in here! Hi!
Look at this,
there's a doll in here.
Hey, and look at this thing.
Oh, my God,
there's another one!
Look at this.
Did you know that?
Yeah, yeah, I did.
That's awesome.
It's a Russian nesting doll.
You want to have a seat
and we start the meeting?
That's incredible.
Look at that little doll.
Oh, my goodness, look at that.
Yeah, yeah, can you...
It keeps going.
It keeps going. There's more.
There's more dolls in here.
Yeah.
No, they call it
a nesting doll.
You want to sit down,
we can start the meeting?
No, but they keep going.
There's more dolls.
You have one doll,
you have another...
Uh, put this
on top of this doll.
I just got to see...
got to get to the bottom of it.
Yeah, there's a lot.
You're kidding me.
Okay, but why don't
we start the meeting.
You're not gonna tell me
that it goes again.
What's that?
Guys, there's another one.
Where can I pick
one of these up?
Yeah, I'm not sure.
Want to sit down?
We can, uh, get going?
Okay, I'm gonna jump in
here and do this.
Make a party out of
this thing, right?
Here's some handbooks.
Here you go.
Aha.
All right.
My name is Evan.
I want to thank
you all for coming.
And I thought we'd start out by
just getting to know each other.
Maybe we each stand up, say
who we are, why we joined up,
what it's all about
for us, okay?
You have any beers
while we get acquainted?
Beers? No.
No beers.
All right, well,
I'll start this off.
My name is Bob, with a "B."
(chuckles)
Okay. Welcome, Bob.
And, um, I love the town.
I love my wife,
I love my daughter,
and I love getting a chance
to hang with the guys.
So I'm really into
what you're doing here.
Once a week, away from
the wife and kids,
telling some dirty jokes,
having some beers,
if we're good.
I really look forward
to getting a chance
at tearing this shit up.
Really fucking it up.
Great. Thank you, Bob.
Really great to meet you, bud.
You, too, pal.
Uh...
Uh, that was a...
that was a great speech.
I'm Franklin.
(chuckles)
Welcome, Franklin.
Yeah.
Uh, few years ago, uh,
dropped out of high school.
Wasn't feeling the vibe.
Wanted to become a member of
the Glenview Police Department.
Mm-hmm.
I guess they didn't see
the magic that was me.
Apparently, I didn't pass
the written exam
or the physical exam
or the mental health exam.
Whatever that means.
So, here I am,
with this vigilante squad,
and I figure that's
the best way to work through
my emotional shit and
bust some heads in the process.
Okay, just to be clear,
we're not a vigilante squad.
Vigilante squad, militia...
whatever you're going for.
Doesn't matter.
No, not-not a militia
or a vigilante squad.
Every group needs a wild card,
and I think it's safe to say
we found ours.
I dig it.
Well, thank you, Franklin.
We got a good one here.
Yep.
What are you about?
Hello. Uh, yeah.
My name's Jamarcus.
Uh, recently
very happily divorced,
and just looking to get more
involved in the local community.
Well, that was simple.
Welcome, Jamarcus.
Ah, also,
um, I have this
one scenario in my mind
that I'm kind of hoping
plays out like this.
Young, sexy, Asian housewife
alone at night, frightened.
A noise out
by the trash cans.
Best call
the neighborhood watch.
I show up, look heroic,
and then... get this...
she sucks my balls.
(makes gunshot noise)
Hear me now!
I'm also interested
in that happening to me.
Okay.
Well, Jamarcus, Bob, Franklin,
I guess it doesn't matter
what brought us all here.
What matters is
that we're all united
in one cause.
And with that,
I'd like to welcome you all
to the first
official meeting of...
the neighborhood watch.
Okay, now,
I've taken the liberty
of dividing Glenview
into 12 sectors.
Though some might argue
there are 13,
if you abide by the Yorktown
Zoning Commission ruling.
I'm not buying it,
but then again
I'm not from Honeywell County.
Thank God. Regardless...
BOB:
I'm sorry to be
the squeaky wheel,
but it feels like you have
a lot of dense material
Yeah.
That you're starting
to go through here.
And to be honest with you,
you know,
my house is about
five blocks away,
and I just fixed her up.
Gentlemen, I got drinks,
I got La-Z-Boys,
I got flat-screens,
I got the whole nine.
I know you guys
are gonna love it.
So I just want
to throw it out there.
If I'm overstepping,
just say the word and you're not
gonna hear another squeak
from this little wheel.
Well, honestly...
That sounds a fuck-load
better than this.
No offense.
I don't even know why I'm still
sitting here.
I'm gonna go warm up the car.
You're gonna love this
place; it's awesome.
Gentlemen...
welcome to paradise.
Oh.
Oh! Yes!
I'm a construction manager,
and I built
this little slice of heaven
with my own two hands.
It's so nice. I love it.
Ah, thanks, everyone.
Yeah, I'll set up over there.
You have a pool table.
Yeah. Just got it re-felted.
Go ahead and take her
for a spin.
Here we go.
(chair vibrating)
Hey, you like that thing, huh?
It feels like this chair
is inside me, Robert.
That is the best 2,300 bucks
I ever spent.
I got it at a place
called Relax-the-Back.com.
It's like Toys "R" Us
for your ass and back.
Feels like a thousand
little baby wizards are
massaging my ass cheeks
with their little baby wands.
Powerful imagery, brother!
I'm digging
where he's coming from!
Handbooks. Boom.
Rack them up. I'm in.
What are you drinking?
What's your poison?
You down with scotch?
I... no poison.
Scotch and yes.
No, no, no. No poison.
Scotch and yes?
No.
Scotch and yes!
You know, we got a lot
of ground to cover,
and we're already an hour
behind, so why don't
we just dig in, and then we can
get to whatever afterwards.
Guitar.
Ah, come on, Evan.
We're just bonding
a little bit.
Tell me about yourself.
I know you got a wife.
Do you have any kids? How old?
Uh, zero years old.
No kids.
That's a shame.
I couldn't imagine my life
without my little Chelsea.
I mean, being a parent is...
well, it's unbelievable.
That's great.
CHELSEA: Dad, can I go
to a movie at 11:00?
Hell, no! It's a weeknight!
But Mandy and Judy are going.
BOB: Mandy?!
Thank you for proving my point!
Mandy's dead weight.
She's a succubus.
I told you that.
Dad, I'm trying to talk
to you like an adult,
and you just...
Don't want to listen!
That's right!
So skedaddle!
Get up there
and do your homework!
Are you serious?!
I fucking hate it here!
Well, I fucking love it here!
That's my little princess.
That's my little angel,
Chelsea, right there.
I'm sorry I didn't get a chance
to introduce you guys.
How about some drinks?
Fresh horses for my men!
Tonight we ride! Get in
here, Frankfurter!
Yes, thank you.
Yeah!
I don't...
Come on, Evaroo.
No, thanks.
You'll be bummed if you don't.
No, I don't...
Can I interest anyone
in some finger foods?
I got to order some pies
up in this thing, right?
You guys want some pies?
Okay, you know what?
You guys got your own thing
going on there.
I am going to
put up some flyers.
Come on, have one drink.
No.
Bye.
No?
All right, I'll see you guys.
Okay.
See you.
Hey, see you tomorrow night.
Okay.
Same Bob time, same Bob place.
Hey, fella!
What are you doing?
Ah.
There you are.
1162 Jerome Park Drive.
Excuse me?
I'm 1157 Jerome Park Drive.
Name's Paul.
Just moved in.
Oh! You're... oh.
Oh, sorry.
I'm, uh, I'm Evan.
Hi.
Evan.
Evan Trautwig, subscriber
to Men's Fitness.
Oh, yeah, that's... that is...
yeah, that's mine.
Thank you.
Not that you need it.
Excuse me?
You got the body of
a decathlete, Evan.
And you got great skin.
You live here alone
in this big old house?
No. No.
I live with my wife.
My female wife Abby.
I'm gonna go inside now.
Mm. All right,
Evan Trautwig.
Nice to meet you.
Stay fit.
Evan Trautwig!
Yeah.
ABBY:
It was really cute.
We all got our own puff paints
and made these little
customized onesies.
Oh, wow.
Okay.
So you started another club.
No.
It's not a club,
it's a task force
of concerned citizens.
I went to the Spartans game
and made a speech,
and the community
really responded.
Well, guess who peed on the
ovulation stick on the plane?
You?
Yep.
It's kind of faint, but I
think there's two pink lines.
Yeah, I can't tell.
Well, I think we
should do it anyway.
I would love to do it.
Just to be safe.
Mm-mm-mm.
But I got to go meet
the neighborhood watch guys
for a patrol.
Evan! You promised.
I know, but I also
promised Antonio's family
that I would catch his killer.
I made a vow.
Okay, okay, okay...
It's a great group of guys.
Really.
I'm very excited.
Here we go.
Bad-ass jackets for the watch.
I went to the mall
this morning,
and I had them made up.
Get them while they're hot.
- Blam.
- Let's do it.
Whoa.
What?
Thank you.
Got your names on them.
Got our names on them.
Yep.
All right, Bob.
This is great.
These are good.
Okay.
Hey, what-what happened
to my logo?
Oh, this is, this is
just like your initial logo,
only now it's awesome.
This has nothing to do
with my original logo.
My logo was an eye that was
watching over the neighborhood.
I don't know what this is.
What, a tiger with wings?
Exactly!
This is a tiger,
who's fierce and sleek.
But it's got wings, so it flies
above the neighborhood,
and if it sees a domestic
problem, it kills it!
The other thing is,
your original one's here.
So I think...
Got the eye right
there on the side.
It's always on the side.
Small on the side.
That's weird, 'cause it's like
an eye on the shoulder,
but there's a tiger
on your back.
Weird how?
What are we,
the flaming tigers?
'Cause that's what
it looks like.
We're the flaming,
flying tigers.
It makes no sense.
Are you out of your mind?!
This is inspiring
for the watch!
Whenever you have a
tiger, flames and wings,
all in the same logo,
it's like the Chinese symbol for
"Shut the fuck up and dance!"
This is inspiring
for the watch!
I don't know.
What are we, in a doo-wop group?
We're gonna, like,
stand over a garbage can
with fire and harmonize?
I would see this doo-wop group.
Hey, for your information,
doo-wop groups
were known to close ass.
Singing was their hobby,
closing ass was their job.
The baritone from
Boyz II Men had to
stop making music
'cause he got so much pussy.
- Thank you.
- They're like ass collectors.
This is not about fashion,
this is about brotherhood,
this is about solidarity.
You should get that
more than anybody.
He's actually right.
Pigs have uniforms,
I think we should
have uniforms, too.
We got to match those fuckers
on every level.
Understand?
Every level.
Can I just say, Bob,
that these are the shit.
Just the shit.
These are just shit.
Okay, you know what, fine.
I'll wear it.
But you have to
promise me that tonight
we're actually gonna
do something, okay?
Absolutely.
For sure.
Gentlemen, we're part of
more than a club,
we're part of a way of life.
We're making a
commitment to ourselves
and to the watch today.
Get your hands in here, Evan.
Get that pretty hand in there.
On three, let me
hear you sing it out
with pride in your hearts.
Neighborhood watch.
One, two, three.
ALL:
Neighborhood watch!
FRANKLIN:
Yeah, this is boring.
BOB:
Yeah, Franklin's right.
We're not gonna sit
here all night, are we?
Yeah, guys, we are.
Really?
If we need to.
It's a stakeout.
BOB:
I don't mean to
sound childish,
but I do have to pee.
You should've peed
earlier. I'm sorry.
As an adult, you're just
gonna have to hold it.
How you doing, Jamarcus?
Ready.
I still have to pee.
You know, the liquid comes in,
the liquid's
got to come out; I got to piss.
Here. Why don't you
just pee in this.
Oh, great.
That's a good idea.
No, no, don't pee in that.
I got to mount up.
What are you doing?
No, don't...
I'm mounting up to piss.
You're not gonna pee in a can.
Why not?
No, Bob.
I'm not gonna miss anything.
I'm a good shot,
I'm gonna get it perfect.
Open the door.
I've taken lots of road trips.
I've always done this shit.
No, piss out the door.
And blow our-our
stakeout position? No shot.
You're not gonna pee in a can.
I'd never hear the end of it
from you if I blew our stakeout
position; there's no shot.
So I got to mount up.
I'm mounting up.
Okay, and we're going.
Oh, my God, we're going.
You're in.
(urine sloshing)
This is almost like... I've had
to pee so bad for so long,
it's borderline sexual, Evaroo.
I'm not missing, either.
It's so controlled.
I mean, it's incredibly
controlled, Evan.
It's like he's threading
a needle.
I know I'm okay
'cause I can feel the steel
right around the tip.
I'm squishing it against it.
I got the mushroom pushed
right against the cold steel.
Bob, hit me with a beat.
Hit me with a stop and go.
Stop it. Make it happen.
(urine stopping and starting)
Stop it.
Make it happen.
- Stop it.
- Uh-huh.
Make it happen.
(sighs)
Killing it.
And we're done.
Good.
Well done. Well done.
Oh, thank you.
That was a good one.
Would you be a pal
and hold this for me?
Oh, come on! Come on!
Just so I can get repositioned.
That's enough!
Come on!
I'm busting your chain!
Hey, did I miss anything
while I was pissing?
Did we catch the killer?
(laughs)
Lighten up, big guy!
I'm glad you think
this is so funny, Bob.
I'm glad you think this
is a laugh riot, okay?
Let's all have a laugh while
Antonio Guzman's killer
continues to roam free.
You know what?
He's right.
That sicko's probably
out there right now,
staring at us from a distance,
beating the living shit
out of his dick,
reliving his sick fantasy.
(can pops)
What are you doing?
Popping a top.
No, no, you can't do that.
Why not?
It's against the law.
It's illegal. You can't have
open alcohol in the car.
The car's not moving.
There's not even a key
in the ignition.
Doesn't matter, it's still...
Franklin, you failed
the police test.
Is this illegal?
It's definitely illegal.
But I also failed the boring
test, you know what I'm saying?
I dig it.
Hook me up.
My guy.
# I'm gonna drink this
little, little cervezas. #
All right, Jamarky-Mark.
Cannonball coming at you!
Coming in hot.
Evaroo?
Want to hold off?
I don't blame you;
You're driving.
Cheers.
Hey, to great times.
And doing it right.
JAMARCUS:
To criminality.
FRANKLIN: # Evan,
taste these cervezas. #
Maybe a little...
Keep it low, guys.
Oh, shit.
Seriously, put it low,
put it low.
Put it between your knees.
Even lower.
I've been here many times,
trust me.
Act like there's nothing
going on, you're fine.
FRANKLIN (whispering):
Fucking guys.
I hate these motherfuckers.
Hello, Officers.
Evening, gentlemen.
Doing a little cruising?
EVAN:
No, Officers.
We're actually on, uh...
neighborhood watch business.
Hide your bong, Chucho.
Neighborhood watch is here.
Sergeant, you remember me?
SERGEANT:
No.
What, have I
arrested you before?
Not so good with faces.
(mutters):
Faces.
You're a cop.
What do you mean you're not...
You're not good
with faces? What?!
I don't see the connection.
What I have been seeing
are these babies.
How's it been going?
Good, actually.
Very good.
Great.
Yeah, we thought
we'd start here
at the Costco and stake
it out for a while.
'Cause, as you
know, most killers
return to the scene
of the crime, so...
Oh, of course they do.
The killer always returns
to the scene of the crime.
So, uh,
fancy seeing you here,
Trautwig.
At the scene of the crime.
I don't know what that means.
It means it's super-suspicious
that you're here right now.
And it makes me feel like
you have some secrets.
Well, I don't.
(clicks pen)
Any-who, when you fellas
finish playing Hardy Boys,
don't forget to pay this ticket
for those open
alcohol containers.
SERGEANT:
And...
this one is for putting up
200 flyers without a permit.
What?!
I'm sorry, guys.
You fellas have a safe night.
Hit it, Chucho.
(siren whoops)
Goddamn it!
I know he remembers me!
He's just messing with my head!
You can't drink
in your car anymore?
What the hell is
this country coming to?
(cell phone ringtone playing)
Evan Trautwig.
Yes, of course.
Noise complaint at
the football field.
This is it, guys.
It's our first call.
Hell, yeah. Let's roll!
Let's do it.
(engine starts)
(tires screeching)
You see anything?
Uh-uh.
Hello?
What the hell?
Turn off the lights!
(grunting)
What?!
I'm hit!
What the fuck is going on?!
Robert, we're getting
ambushed here!
They're kids!
Eggs!
Yeah, we're getting egged!
It's raining eggs!
We came to help!
Yolk's on you, ass wipes!
Yolk's on me?!
A fucking pun?!
I'm gonna kill this kid.
I'm gonna kill you!
Goddamn it!
They're getting away, Bob!
No, they're not.
Because one of us
is the founder
of the Glenview Running Club!
(yells)
(grunting)
Yeah, you fucked him up, man!
BOB:
Who's laughing now, kid?
I bet you didn't egg-pect
to get your ass kicked.
Huh? You throw eggs at people,
you think that's funny?
Look how much pain he's in.
Guess what you learned tonight.
You don't mess with
the neighborhood watch, baby!
Undefeated!
Come on.
Look at Evaroo
with the high hands!
(screams)
Whoa!
We got him!
(all shouting)
# La-da-da-da-da #
# It's the motherfucking
D-O-double-G #
# Snoop Dogg! #
# La-da-da-da-da #
# You know I'm mobbin'
with the D-R-E #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah #
# You know who's back up
in this motherfucker #
# What, what, what, what. #
Ha-ha!
That's right.
Neighborhood Watch.
Suck a fat dick, Chucho.
What's going on here, guys?
Egging, Sergeant.
Guy's an egger.
Eggs, huh?
Yeah, eggs:
The coward's weapon.
It's good you brought him in.
Then he tried to run away
on his little skitter-board.
Did you really?
Hmm?
Get back to the playground
and the monkey bars.
You think it's nice to
throw eggs at people?
Do you?
You gonna answer the question?
It's rude.
It hurts people's feelings
and it hurts their faces.
And now you deal with
the consequences.
Homegirl's trying
to make an omelet.
Yeah, look at me.
Look at his face.
Look at my face.
Look at his face
and listen to me.
Look at him and listen to me.
Look at him and understand me.
Look at both of us,
but understand no one.
Listen to my words
and hear his face.
EVAN:
Do you think it is funny
to throw an egg
in somebody's face?
FRANKLIN: You think it's funny?
You think it's a yolk?
I'll shove a full egg
inside your asshole
and watch it hatch.
Franklin. Inappropriate.
Sorry.
No, I understand, it's too far.
She's all yours.
Great work.
Here's your bag.
Well, that was super weird.
Am I under arrest?
Of course not.
Those guys are a joke.
Okay, can one of you guys give
me a ride home or something?
Fuck no.
I'm not a chauffer
and neither is
Chucho over here, right, buddy?
Get out of here.
Real nice.
(electricity crackling)
(chittering)
Hello?
(sparks popping)
Okay, yeah.
Really hilarious!
Hey, quit screwing around!
I'm gonna pelt somebody!
(metal thuds, creaks)
Screw you!
I'm out of here!
(eerie screech)
Come on, leave me alone!
(eerie growling)
Leave me alone!
(screeching)
(car alarm blaring)
(rock music playing)
FRANKLIN:
We are fucking gods!
BOB:
What do you say, Evan?
# You ain't seen nothing yet #
Come back again.
# B-B-B-Baby, you just
ain't seen nothing yet #
Tell me about it,
tell me about it.
(all mumbling words)
What-what-what?
# B-B-B-Baby, you just
ain't seen nothing yet #
Damn right! You been around!
(singing guitar solo)
All the way from
London, England,
put your hands together.
Make him feel welcome,
everybody.
BOB:
Jamarky-Mark!
(mumbling):
# Any love is good lovin' #
Here we go.
# So I took what I could get #
# Yes, I took
what I could get... #
(mumbling words loudly)
(loud thump)
(music stops, tires screeching)
Oh!
Oh, shit!
BOB: Is everyone all right?
You guys okay?
We hit someone.
We just... we have hit someone.
- What?
- Was it a kid?
Oh, no.
Evan, did you hit a kid?
No. What?
Why did you take your eyes
off the road to sing?
There's beer and piss
all over the car.
Hey, everyone just stay calm
for a second.
Let's focus. Just relax.
We can't calm down.
There's open alcohol,
we're inebriated,
I have weed in my pocket.
Evan could get
15 years to life for this.
What?!
Don't worry about that.
Oh, God!
This can't happen to me.
No, no, no, you don't get it.
So here's what we do,
we focus on the living.
Just drive us out of here.
Just drive away!
I'm not gonna drive away.
I'm gonna see what it is.
Evan. Shit.
What is it?
Looks like you just
hit some freakishly
big fly or something.
What the fuck is this thing?
Looks like an octopus tentacle
or something.
BOB:
All right, well, I think
it's very obvious what,
what happened here, guys.
It doesn't take, you know,
a brain surgeon
to figure this one out.
Evan accidentally...
obviously, right...
hit a crate that fell
off the back of a truck
that just so happened
to be carrying
some freshly caught octopus
to a nearby sushi
establishment.
It's octopus, and a fresh one.
Right, you got nothing but the
thing and the octopus and this,
and I think we pack it in
and we know what happened.
Okay, worst-case scenario:
Evan murdered a Japanese man
who was eating octopus
while crossing the street.
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa...
I didn't... come on,
I did not murder anybody.
Doesn't matter.
You know why?
'Cause no one's going to say
shit about this to anybody
'cause we don't dime
on our fellow neighborhood
watchers, okay?
Wait a second,
I've seen this stuff before.
Back at Costco, this was
the stuff by Antonio's body.
Had he just won a Nickelodeon's
Kids' Choice Award?
Franklin, he was dead.
So he wasn't eligible.
That's pretty amazing, then,
that he won 'cause usually
you have to do some sort
of kids type thing
to win that award.
Feels like cum.
Ew.
Well, I dare anyone
to touch it and tell me
it doesn't feel like cum.
May I?
Yeah, that's cum.
Well, it's green, it's not cum,
but I'm saying
it's a cum...
it feels like cum.
The texture, the flavor,
the color, the consistency...
It's very cum-like.
Hey, guys, check this out,
I found something.
What is it?
I don't know.
Looks like a big silver
basketball or something.
What is it?
BOB:
It looks like a toy.
Whoa.
What the fuck is that?
MAN:
What's going on
up here?
We got company.
What in the hell
are you people doing
in my yard?!
Hi, sorry, we're the
Neighborhood Watch.
We were just out on
a nightly patrol.
How you doing?
I'm Evan Trautwig.
I got your neighborhood watch
right here, sweet lips.
We-We're, we're
on your side, sir.
We're just wondering if
you heard anything strange
or just anything out of
the ordinary tonight.
You mean, like four nitwits
standing around
on my lawn in the middle
of the night?
That's kind of strange,
don't you think?
Okay.
Hey, you know what, pal?
If being overly aggressive
and a little bit snippy
was a crime, I'd be making
a citizen's arrest right now.
Why don't you just shut your
cocksucker there, dickweed?
You know, we're taking time
out of our busy schedules
to help the neighborhood,
so I think you could just...
you know, you don't have to...
("Sailing" ringtone playing)
Excuse me,
got a phone call here.
Hey, Bill.
Bill.
I got four members
of the Baby-sitters Club
up here...
It's the Neighborhood Watch.
...trying to solve some kind
of mystery
before beddy-bye time.
I'll call you back later.
All right, okay, we...
It's okay, sir,
we get it, we're...
Thank you for...
We'll just...
You guys,
I'm gonna count to ten.
Okay, you know what?
Let's start again.
I'm gonna count to ten!
He wants to count.
Okay.
One...
Steal that cool ball.
...two, three...
Nice to meet you.
Fuck you, Curly!
...four.
Get in your goddamn
soccer mom van and move on out.
(engine starts)
Neighborhood Watch.
What a fucking joke.
Look at this.
Every time I stick a finger in,
another light goes on.
That's weird.
Hey, why don't we try to stick
all our fingers in
at the same time,
see what happens?
All right, guys,
let's all finger
these holes together.
This is a bad idea.
Oh, don't be such a pussy,
Jamarcus, come on.
Come over here and finger-
bang this ball with us.
I don't like this.
Come on, Jamarcus.
Okay,
fine, but this is a bad idea.
Get your finger in there.
Okay.
(cow moos)
Whoa!
Jesus!
Shit! Holy shit!
Are you kidding me?
Did you see that shit?
That cow's fucking head
exploded all over the place.
That's terrible for the cow,
but this thing's
fucking awesome.
This is a major find.
This thing is the shit.
Okay, nobody touches this ball
till we figure out what it is.
We definitely should not
fuck around with this thing.
The last thing we want to
do is cause a disturbance.
("Straight Outta Compton"
by N.W.A playing)
# Straight outta Compton... #
(all exclaiming)
Good-bye, tractor!
Whoo!
So sick.
# Kick knowledge
and bodies are hauled off #
# You, too, boy,
if you get with me... #
Yeah, the ball!
# Off your back,
that's how I'm goin' out... #
(all exclaiming)
Whoo!
# Cook 'em in a pot
like gumbo... #
Whoo!
Hey!
Hay, yeah! Hay, now.
(overlapping chatter)
BOB:
Hey, wait, that's hilarious.
That was so fun.
I mean, we blew
that shit up.
That cow's fucking head
just poofed, just puffed.
Oh, man.
Guys, this is not
from this world.
I, I, I think it could be
the government, you know.
There are lots of these kind
of prototypes that you find.
It's always the government.
I don't disagree
that there could be
a government or an alien
or where governments
and aliens connect.
Get the fuck out of here, man,
this is not alien shit.
EVAN: I think you're paranoid.
I'm not paranoid.
Everything is on
the table; right now
we don't take anything off.
This was probably on the way
to the fucking Mac Store,
and it fell off the truck.
What the fuck is this?
This is like
a Magical 8 Ball bowling
ball that blows shit up.
I'm trying to find
a killer here.
Right, a killer alien.
It's a...
Somebody killed Antonio.
Okay, I don't know
if they're an alien,
I don't know
if it was an octopus.
I don't know what it was
or who it was,
but this has something
to do with it, right?
You. Well, you.
Yes, that's a yes.
Let's go to the things
we can agree on.
We don't know what it is.
That's correct as well.
It's the same goo that was
on Antonio's body.
This is
information you're sharing,
and I'll say yes to it.
The goo was on the car,
the orb was near the car.
Let's call her Lucy.
The second after
we find Lucy...
BOB: Lucy.
...who kicks us
off his property?
Crazy old guy with a shotgun.
Why'd he want us
off his property?
- Why did he not want us near the ball or the goo?
- Right?
This is the guy, we got
to kick his tires.
There's something we
got to figure out.
I think we dress
Franklin up as a girl
named Fran-Francesca, he goes
to the door as a salesman
because they'll suspect him any
other way. He's pretty enough.
I'm, I'm listening.
He's an attractive guy
and he has the features
where he can fool 'em.
- Feminine features.
- So we put Franklin in a costume,
send him for the old man.
He's lonely, he's lonely.
He'll let Franklin
in the house.
Boom, he's in.
We're inside the house.
Now it's intel,
he's under the radar.
It's an attractive lady
showing up.
His liver-spotted hands are
going to want to caress her.
Can I tell you something, Bob?
BOB:
Mm-hmm.
That could work.
Yes!
FRANKLIN: Here's the thing.
Finally!
I'm not going to go past
second with this old guy,
but if I have to, I will.
I think it's important we get,
we get really, really confirmed
on what you're prepared to
do so it's not a new thing.
Let's talk about it.
I will use both hands.
I won't use a mouth.
He may use his hands and
may not use his mouth.
Well, I think you got
to make it all go down
before you get found out.
FRANKLIN:
Here's the issue.
What's the best-
case on this one?
Okay, here's the
best-case scenario:
He's a lonely old man,
he wants to waltz,
he wants to listen to some
of the old songs
from his childhood.
Worst-case scenario: you're
getting fucked in the ass.
Either way we're gonna find
out who this old man is.
Either way we're gonna get
involved in this guy's life.
Here's the pressing question:
What do we do with this?
We don't give it to the cops.
JAMARCUS: Agreed.
This is ours;
No one hears about it.
EVAN:
I don't know, but we keep it
a Neighborhood Watch secret.
Cheers.
Well, we're in the game.
To the watch.
Boom.
(engine stops)
(sighs)
Ew.
(dog barks in distance)
(tapping keys)
"OMG, Mandy's party
is so awesome."
Good for Mandy.
Frickin' kidding me, right?
(partiers whooping on video)
Chelsea!
Dad, what the F?
Don't F me.
Who's this boy toy named Jason?
Boy toy?
What's his toy story?
Oh, wait, were you creeping
on my Facebook again?
Are you kidding me?
You're gonna let
some guy car-wash
the inside of your mouth
with his tongue
and then you're gonna post it
on the Internet?
Stop Internet stalking me, okay?
Just get out of my room.
You don't see me and your mom
posting our sessions
on the Internet, do you?
Ew, that's
disgusting, Dad.
Well, how do you
think that makes
me feel? It is disgusting.
You keep your tongue
in your mouth.
And what's going on
with this collage?
This is moving
in the direction of, like,
strippers on spring break.
Oh, my God.
That's a collage
of my friends, Dad.
This is uncomfortable.
The whole thing's
uncomfortable.
I'm not comfortable with
what's going on, Chelsea.
If you're uncomfortable,
then get out.
Sex is for love.
Here's what's happening
now... the video's off.
Okay, Dad, I'm gonna
get the video off.
Fine, right, okay.
Or we got a problem.
Please get out.
Houston, we have a problem.
Okay, Dad, that's good.
Really productive conversation.
Seriously, really.
We should do more of it.
Right on the edge.
You're right on the edge.
# #
(phone chirps)
# You and tequila
make me crazy... #
Hey.
Hey, buddy.
BOB: Come on, I saved
a seat for you.
Said you were desperate.
Yeah, here, take a load off.
Look, I know we're trying to
catch the Costco Killer, but,
well, it's good to have
an honest heart-to-heart
with just a couple
of guys, right?
There's my boy.
(clanking)
Bring it down here.
Get in here.
It's all about honesty, right?
Mm-hmm.
I've been being honest
with my daughter.
I don't think
she wants to hear it.
(chuckles)
My wife's been traveling
so much for work that a,
you know, a lot of the parenting
stuff has fallen on me lately.
How about you?
When are you going to take the
plunge and knock a few out?
Uh, it's not that simple.
Well, it's about as simple as
putting your dick in a vagina.
You know what I mean?
Make it happen.
Well, I don't really
have a choice, so...
It turns out that my
gun doesn't really
shoot too well.
Gun?
Yeah.
You mean your prick?
Why are you saying "gun"?
This is two guys
sitting on a bench.
You can say it,
say "prick," say "cock."
Just say "prick."
Anyway, did you take
a couple of those blue bombers?
No.
Got to get that wang
nice and stiff
and get you all monstered up.
N-No, no, no.
Oh, it will,
and then you'll be fucking
like a champ in no time.
No.
No, I can, I, that's...
I know a guy
that'll give you some
and I got some from Mexico...
That's not the problem.
I'll get you some
of those Mexican bombs.
I can do everything.
It's just that, uh...
I'm... about a year
and a half ago...
Okay.
Abby and I started trying
to have kids...
Mm-hmm.
...and nothing
was happening, so,
on my own, I went to see this
doctor, to get my sperm checked.
You know, I've always
wondered about that.
I've just had a curiosity
about it if you don't mind.
When you go to one
of those doctors,
do you jerk yourself off
or does the doctor,
like, jerk you off
or, like, an assistant?
Is it like a massage parlor or
do they have, like, a machine,
like, a medical machine
that does the milking for you?
Like, milks you like an animal?
I'm asking how you get
the cum out of you.
I...
They do it.
No, I jerked me off.
Okay.
Doesn't matter.
The point is, I went,
I got tested,
and... no go.
I'm shooting blanks.
I, I could shoot a bucketful,
it would make no difference.
Doctor's actual words...
"a bucketful."
It's because of me,
we can't have kids.
Just me.
I didn't realize that
that's such a big deal.
I mean, it's 2012.
Can't you just get,
like, a ball transplant?
Yeah, I don't think the
science is there yet.
What'd the old lady say
when you told her?
Evaroony, don't tell me
that you haven't talked
to her about it.
Well, what am I going to say?
Hey, honey, guess what?
The one thing you want
most in the world,
I can't give you.
Evan, you listen to me.
You talk to Abby.
She married you,
not your dead jizz.
Thanks.
("Shave and a Haircut" ringtone
playing)
Evan Trautwig.
(over phone):
Hey, this is Manfred Salisbury.
Are you on my roof?
What?
Well, there's somebody
on my roof
jumping around like a maniac.
Is that one of you idiots?
It most certainly is not.
Uh, please just hang
tight, Mr. Salisbury,
we'll be right there.
Yeah, I'll bet you will.
Got to get to Manfred's.
Call the Watch; come on.
Nobody's here.
Seriously?
You see anybody on the roof?
No.
Okay, we should fan out.
Franklin,
you and Bob get
in the car, check
the block, see if
you get any action.
Jamarcus and I will
go around back.
Okay.
Got it.
Good.
Hey, guys, let's stay focused.
We're in the field, right?
Okay.
N.W.
(owl hooting)
(distant howl echoing)
- Shh.
- # Sailing... #
Hear that?
# Takes me away to where
I've always heard #
# Sailing #
# Takes me away
to where I've al... #
(beeps)
This is Manfred's.
This is not good.
(rustling)
(whispering):
What is that?
I don't know.
(chittering)
Oh, my God.
Evan...
we should run for our lives.
(chittering)
We should go up to it.
Why would we go up to it?
We should go.
EVAN:
It looks scared.
Maybe he's injured.
Maybe that's what
we hit in the car.
Yeah, and maybe
he's really pissed off about it
and is going to eat us.
Only one way to find out.
Come on.
Evan.
(humming tones)
Evan, what the fuck
are you doing?
It obviously doesn't
understand our language.
I'm making friendly tones to
show it that we mean no harm.
# Hello... #
(chittering)
Wow.
Oh, no.
(chittering)
I see you.
I... see you.
Hungry?
Food?
Food...?
Gum?
It's okay.
You just chew it.
You want some?
("Close Encounters" tones):
# Gum, gum #
# Gum #
# For you. #
(chittering)
He likes it.
Jamarcus, he likes it.
Everyone likes gum.
Let's go.
He's digging something.
He's got something
he wants to show us.
Want to share your gift, huh?
Oh, mother of fuck!
(chittering)
(roars)
(screams)
(grunting)
(roars)
Jamarcus, what are you doing?
Run, man.
Run!
(snarling)
Fucker!
(alien screeches)
Oh, shit.
Jesus.
You okay?
Uh, that was really stressful.
I think I killed it.
BOB:
What's going on here?
EVAN:
Gentlemen,
we formed the Neighborhood Watch
with a very specific task:
To find the murderer of
my friend Antonio Guzman.
Well, tonight, I say to you...
Holy shit!
Jesus Christ!
What the fuck is that?!
It's an alien.
It killed Manfred, then
it tried to kill Jamarcus,
and I came up
and I nailed it
with a garden gnome
and it cracked its neck
and it's dead.
BOB:
This is fucking insane.
I know, I know.
We tried to find a killer,
but guess what...
we found a frickin' alien.
Ooh, it touches it
and it feels it... ugh!
This intelligent,
sentient being
traveled untold light-years
to come and visit our planet.
And you killed him.
Nice!
Evan, yeah!
Hah! He killed it.
Holy shit.
Man, screw
the police department.
I'm gonna get
into the CIA for this.
I think we should slow down,
we should keep this quiet.
Or a hundred miles an hour
and really loud,
because you're looking
at an alien.
I'm thinking
about T-shirts,
merchandising, movie deals...
my mind's going crazy
with this thing here.
All right, who wants
a snapper with the alien?
What am I thinking?
Right, let's go, bitches.
I don't want to put
pressure on you,
but it's the first
historical picture
of anyone with an alien,
so whatever that means to you.
Here we go, ready,
and we're bringing it.
Here, let me share in the
sunshine... somebody get in here.
# Does she walk, does she talk,
does she come complete? #
# The memory of my angel
could never cause me pain #
# My blood runs cold,
my memory has just been sold #
# My angel is the centerfold,
angel is the centerfold #
# Na, na, na-na, na, na, na-na,
na, na, na, na-na, na, na #
Get close to it.
# Na, na-na, na, na, na, na-na,
na, na-na... #
Yeah, put your dick
on its shoulder.
# #
Boom.
# Na, na, na-na, na, na,
na-na, na, na-na, na-na... #
# Make it last forever #
# Ever... #
# Don't let our love end... #
(laughter)
# Make it last forever #
# No, no, no, no, no #
# And ever. #
(alien growls, Bob screams)
(roars)
(both scream)
Evan, help!
(chittering)
Uh, uh...
Oh, my God.
Bob, the pool balls
aren't hurting him.
Franklin, you've got to hit him.
Fuck.
JAMARCUS: This is bad aim.
FRANKLIN:
Please don't kill me!
Hey, hey, al-alien.
What the fuck are
you doing, Jamarcus?
He's not a bumblebee!
Evan, help!
He's gonna kill me
and I don't know what to do.
(screaming)
Oh, shit!
Oh, shit! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
He's gonna eat my face!
(yelling)
He's getting goo in my mouth!
Pull him up.
FRANKLIN: Oh, my God!
(Bob grunts, alien screeches)
Franklin, Jamarcus.
(yelling)
I can taste the fucking goo!
Bring him down.
That's right.
Give up, go to sleep.
Shh, shh, relax,
you go to sleep.
(deep, growly):
We are already among you.
(all scream)
What the fuck was that?!
(groans)
You can forget about
the damn merchandising play.
Is everyone all right?
(spits)
Fucking alien came on my face.
(groans)
Ow.
FRANKLIN:
Did you hear that thing?
(groans)
"We are among you"?
What does that mean?
Means there's more
of those damn things out there.
Oh, my God.
That's why they take the skins.
To wear them.
They're among us.
Oh, fucking great.
And that damn thing's
been to my house.
He knows where I live.
I think if that thing
had wanted us dead,
we'd be dead, Bob.
So we don't know who is
and who isn't an alien.
Bressman's one of them,
I guarantee it.
1,000 percent.
Yeah, we should keep this quiet
until we find out
who we can trust.
And right now,
we can't trust anybody.
# People are strange #
# When you're a stranger #
# Faces look ugly #
(screams) # When you're alone #
What are you doing?!
# Women seem wicked #
Back off.
# When you're unwanted #
# Streets are uneven #
Aah!
# When you're down #
# When you're strange #
# Faces come out of the rain #
(siren whoops)
# No one remembers your name #
# When you're strange,
when you're strange #
# When you're strange #
# People are strange #
# When you're a stranger #
# Faces look ugly #
- # When you're alone #
- (School bell ringing)
# Women seem wicked
when you're unwanted #
# Streets are uneven
when you're down #
# When you're strange #
# Faces come out of the rain #
# When you're strange,
when you're strange #
# When you're strange. #
You guys been sleeping?
I haven't slept at all.
I'm not dealing with this well.
Any one of these people
could be an alien.
Check her out.
It's like she's studying
some new discovery
or something.
Some strange object,
some weird,
bizarre human... circle fruit.
Looks like she's thinking,
can I ingest this?
Should I put it
in my flavor snout?
Look at this piece of shit
over here.
BOB: That alien
hasn't learned
how to eat properly yet.
So primitive, so clumsy.
So dangerous.
There's that
motherfucking Jason kid.
That's the kid that's all
over Chelsea's Facebook page.
Magnums?! There's no way
your dick's that big!
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Bob.
It's a family store.
I'm just saying,
there's no way
his dick's that big
he needs to buy that shit.
Some people's are that big.
Otherwise, they wouldn't
sell condoms like that.
He's right,
they're a big seller.
I swear to God,
I'm gonna rip his dick off.
You're gonna need
two hands, Bobby.
Hello there, neighbor.
(screams)
Jesus.
(Paul laughs)
I'm so sorry.
Did I startle you?
Uh...
It's good for you,
you know, though.
Gets the heart racing.
And I know you like
to stay fit.
In any case, I just moseyed
on over here to invite you to
a little bit of a gathering
I'm having at my... home.
A lot of interesting characters
will be in attendance.
(voice fades):
And, um...
Um... well, I'll
think about it.
Oh, well, don't think
about it too long,
because before you know it...
(pops lips)
...life's over.
Isn't that the truth?
(whispers):
Holy shit.
He's one of them.
I can't believe I didn't
figure it out earlier.
He's so creepy,
he's been spying on me.
He said I had nice skin
the other night.
Get it?
Skin.
Yeah, you have incredible skin.
You don't have to
brag about it.
No, the aliens
rip off the skin.
Did you see all the batteries
that guy bought?
Nobody needs that
many batteries.
I mean, nobody from
Earth, that is.
He said, "Before we know it...
life ends."
Maybe he thinks
you're getting kind of close
and he wants to take you out.
This is what it's about,
tonight.
This is why we formed
the Neighborhood Watch.
Just got to grab my jacket.
ABBY (moans):
Oh, thank goodness.
It's the leader of the
Neighborhood Watch.
Abby, what the fuck?
I'm forming a little club, too,
and it's only got one opening,
do you have any water?
(gasps) Oh, my God!
No, no, no, no!
Go out, go out.
Whoa!
Get out, get out.
Is that Mrs. Evan?
- Just leave.
- That's your jacket.
That's your wife?
Stop.
It's nice to meet you,
Mrs. Trautwig.
- Well done, though.
- Get out!
I'm Franklin.
I work with...
I'm a dear friend of Evan's.
EVAN: She doesn't care.
Honey... what is... what?
You're starting a club,
you want me to fill your hole?
What-what's going on?
Are you making fun of me?
Honey, I'm not
making fun of you.
You look awesome.
It's just, the timing
kind of is weird and...
No, what's weird is that
I have to make an appointment
to have sex with my husband.
No, you don't.
And then he forgets and brings
a bunch of weird dudes over.
I mean, that little one
saw everything.
Evan, come on!
Oh, honey, I'm sorry.
I forgot. I'm sorry.
Yeah. You forgot.
BOB (in distance): Give her
some truth, pal. She needs it.
What? What is that?
Be that truth-teller, brother!
He's... I don't know.
I have no idea.
You know, I don't even care.
Just here.
Go play with your friends.
Take your stupid jacket and go.
Honey, please believe me.
There are forces greater
than what we're
talking about here
that I can't explain to you,
that I promise I will explain
to you at a certain point,
but it just can't be right now.
Go!
I'm sorry.
Honey, if I...
Come on.
(pops can open)
(slurps)
Hey.
It's beer.
(whispering):
You serious?
Do you want some?
Shh.
Here we go. Someone's coming.
(doorbell rings)
Do you see that?
We don't know what that is,
but that's a couple.
(door opens)
(door closes)
Guys, I definitely smell
alien all over this thing.
(cell phone ringtone playing)
(whispering): Bob! Vibrate!
Give me one second.
Hang on.
One second. Hello.
What?
EVAN: What are you doing?
Uh, are her parents
gonna be there?
Shh.
Absolutely not!
What the hell are you
talking about?
EVAN: Shh!
Chel... no!
EVAN: Shh. Hey.
Damn it, guys. I'm sorry,
we got to get out of here.
Come on, go.
What are you doing?
We got to move out quick.
Let's go.
What are you doing?
You're gonna give
away our position.
Okay, listen to me.
I got to fill you in quick.
Chelsea is on her way
to Mandy's house for a party.
Her parents are not there.
Now, what I can gather so far
from Mandy's Facebook page
is she's a total whore.
This is gonna be
a full-blown fuck festival.
There's gonna be
touching and pulling,
there's gonna be climaxing.
Chelsea's gonna
be there any minute.
I cannot allow that to happen.
I need you guys
to come with me.
We need to put a stop to this.
Let's go.
Bob, what are you
talking about?
We are literally on the possible
doorstep of an alien hive.
You're right.
You know what,
we got to split up
for a little bit.
Jamarky-Mark,
you stay with the Evanator.
That's right. And you,
Frankfurter, you come with me.
Me and my guy
work well together.
I'm so fucking far ahead of you
it's not even funny.
- No, no, no!
- Let's go!
Franklin, Franklin!
- Franklin, Franklin, Franklin.
- Let's go.
You're not going anywhere.
Bob, your daughter
is not official business.
Now, our mandate is
to pursue murderers
and thieves and aliens
and anyone who threatens
to tear the fabric
of this neighborhood apart.
Well, my mandate as a father
is to pursue little pricks
that try to tear the fabric
of my daughter's hymen apart!
Shh!
Don't you walk away.
Don't you dare.
Oh, I dare.
Caw-caw!
This sucks! This sucks!
Shut up!
I'm a bird!
They can't hear me, idiot!
We're good.
Let's go.
You...!
(man screaming inside)
(screaming continues)
Sounds like somebody's getting
ripped apart in there.
Smells funky and musty.
Do you see anything...
(Evan and Jamarcus scream)
You okay?
Aye.
Are you okay?
I'm okay.
Hi, Paul.
Hi, Evan.
Whew.
You all right?
Scared us.
(chuckles)
And who is this
mountain of a man?
My name's Jamarcus.
He's Jamarcus.
Shall we?
(dance music playing)
# Showtime like cable,
get up on that table #
# I love your sexy body
and I know you love this paper #
# Bottles coming
like they got legs on them #
# The way I kill 'em, man #
# This beat will make 'em
wanna call the feds on me #
# Good-good night,
good-good night-night-night #
good-good night #
Thanks for taking me here.
This is erotic as hell.
Big Bob, you got daughter
at midnight, 12:00.
Move to extraction?
BOB:
Stand down, Seal Six.
We go in there hot,
we'll humiliate her
for the rest of her
high school days.
Let's just lay low.
Just taking in intel.
Look, there's that kid from
Costco with the big fat dick.
Walking around with his massive
cock like he owns the joint.
That shit's just banging
against his kneecaps.
20 bucks that guy's dick
dips in the toilet
when he takes a shit.
Whoo!
(laughs)
Oh, hey, girl.
Uh-oh.
(laughs)
Oh, yeah.
Dig that shit!
Who's your daddy?!
I'm her daddy,
you piece of shit!
Come to Daddy's bedroom.
Yeah, it's the master bedroom.
Ooh!
Let's move ass!
Which way are we going here?
Down, down!
Right this way, gentlemen.
Please, after you.
Thank you, Jamarcus.
(lock clicks)
(clears throat)
It's a nice...
place you got here, Paul.
Like the paint.
Oh, thank you, Evan Trautwig.
And allow me to pay you
a compliment in kind.
I see you out there
jog, jog, jog, jogging,
and I often think to myself,
my God,
what a perfect specimen...
Excuse me.
Two perfect specimens.
Gentlemen...
say good-bye to the world
as you know it.
(moaning loudly)
More!
And say hello to paradise.
(women moaning, grunting)
Welcome to the sanctuary
of the human spirit, gents,
because tonight's
all about freedom.
And, uh, some about boning.
(chuckles)
Think we solved
the battery mystery.
(buzzing, vibrating)
Come on in, boys.
The water is just right.
MAN: Oh, yeah,
cinematography's unreal.
It's definitely
gonna win Best Picture.
Yeah. Switch?
Yeah.
EVAN:
This is disgusting.
It stinks in here.
Come on, I was wrong.
Let's go.
Hey.
Do you mind if I suck
on your balls?
I'm gonna see
how this plays out.
I'm going.
Oh, here we go.
I'll get your name
in due course.
# I'm fresh, I'm fly,
I'm so damn high #
Mr. McAllister.
Mandy, this is quite a
gathering you got cooking here.
I'm a little surprised.
It's a little late
for the chess club to be out!
Come on, what do we got here?
A little weed, little tequila.
Where's the
hard stuff, pussies?
Oh, my God, are you guys twins?
Yes.
Oh, my gosh, I can't even
tell you guys apart.
I'm kidding! I'm kidding!
Slow down!
You kids are out of your mind!
It's, like, I feel like
the three of us just met,
but I feel like
I'm the triplet in a weird way,
but in, like, like,
in a sexual way.
Like, where do we
take it from here?
I'm located about
45 minutes south of here.
I live with my mom.
Look, I'm not here
to break up the party.
I want you kids
to get hopped up.
Oh, wow. Wow.
But I'm looking for
a Chelsea McAllister.
Anyone here know
where she might be?
You guys know
who I'm talking about, right?
(music playing faintly
in distance)
(grunts softly)
Um, maybe we should
go back to the party.
No.
I want to keep doing this.
Um...
Okay, I just think we're
going a little fast.
We're not.
This is amazing.
We should keep moving
at this exact pace.
Maybe even a little bit faster.
Okay, seriously,
Jason, stop it.
Seriously, Chelsea,
I don't want to.
Chelsea?
Dad?
What are you doing here?
What the hell?!
Dude, get out of here!
Let's just go.
Are you okay?
Ruining this.
(sighs)
Catch you later, Chelse.
Oh, shit.
Hey!
Hey, jackass!
I'm talking to you, prick!
You think you're cute,
you little fuck?!
(grunts)
Oh, my God!
(crowd gasps, murmurs)
(coughing)
Ouch.
That looks like
a real gusher, Bob.
Come here, come here!
Dad!
(crowd gasps)
(groans)
Oh, my God.
Are you okay, Dad?
I'm okay.
It just stung a little bit.
You don't fuck with Bob.
You show Bob respect.
(chuckles):
Okay.
Bob's my special guy.
That's right.
That's right, that
just happened.
You don't tell your parents
about this.
You don't tell
your friends about this.
You write it in your
dream journal, you lock it up,
and you put it
under your pillow.
I will come back here
and I will kill
each and every one of you!
Except for those two hot girls
I was talking to.
They have my information,
please have them
get in contact with me;
They seem great.
No, I'm glad
you showed up tonight.
I'm sorry.
It's okay, honey.
Come on, let's go home.
Okay.
Daddy?
I'm okay, honey.
I think you got it all.
You can put it away.
You doing all right?
Mm-hmm.
Good.
Hey, Bob, can I talk
to you for a second?
Yeah, sure.
Okay, honey, I'll
be in in a second.
All right.
I love you so much.
I love you, too.
I appreciate you showing up.
I know it takes a big man
to apologize.
What happened
back there was not cool.
You abandoned your post.
If that had been an alien hive,
we would have been killed.
So, it wasn't a hive?
Where's Jamarcus?
Jamarcus decided
to stay at Paul's.
And no, it wasn't a hive.
It turned out
to be a local orgy.
What?
There's an orgy happening?
Locally?
So, wait, y-you're mad at
me for leaving an orgy?
Doesn't matter what it was.
The point is
you left us hanging.
It's the principle.
No, the principle
is I went to go
help my daughter
who was in trouble.
Evan, you can't be such
a control freak, man.
You're too uptight.
Yeah, Bob, I'm uptight.
I'm uptight about the aliens
that are killing people
in our neighborhood.
That's what I'm uptight about.
Neighborhood Watch
isn't for people
who can't handle
their daughter's personal shit.
Do you even hear
how you sound right now?
Why don't you look at
your own personal life,
Evan, 'cause you
don't even have one.
You don't talk to your wife.
You don't have any friends.
I have friends.
No, you don't, man.
I have tons of friends.
No, you don't.
You have clubs.
You start these clubs!
That's what you do!
And you become a dictator!
You just boss everyone
and tell them what to do
because you're running away
from what really matters.
You don't have the
guts to deal with
what's going on
in your own home.
Yeah, well...
I have the guts to do this.
You're out of the Watch.
You can't throw me
out of the Watch.
I just did.
Okay. You know what?
I don't care.
I'm gonna start my own watch.
You know what?
You can't, because
there already is a watch!
So you can't do that.
Oh, yes, I can start my watch,
'cause if I'm not
in your watch,
you can't give me
rules anymore.
I'm gonna keep
my own logo, too.
I never liked that logo anyway.
My logo is awesome!
My logo is "Chinee."
The "Chinee"
understand movement,
and I understand the Chinese.
I combined flight
with flames with a tiger.
What am I combining, Evan?
Serenity,
optimism, attack!
Franklin, let's get
some pudding inside you.
Franklin, you do not
go in that house!
Jesus, Evan, you don't own him.
You don't own all of us.
Franklin is his own man.
He can make his own decisions.
He can think for himself.
Now, Franklin, get your
fucking ass in the house!
Don't you speak with Franklin!
Franklin, you stay!
Franklin, stay!
Come! Franklin, come!
Come here!
Frank, come here, come here,
come here, Franklin.
Come here, Franklin.
Franklin, look at me.
Franklin.
Franklin, come on.
Um, Evan,
you're a special friend...
...but I live here.
How's it feel, Evan,
to be in a club of one?
(door closes)
# #
Maybe he's jacking off
too much.
No.
You know what I mean?
Like, the well is dry
by the time you get home.
Ew, stop.
Well, I don't know.
Have you noticed, like,
any abrasions or signs
of stress on his penis?
Abrasions? No.
Well, like,
he's pulling on it too hard.
(panting)
I'm sterile.
Bye-bye.
- Hey, Carla.
- Hey.
Honey, I can't have kids.
I went to a doctor
and got it checked out.
And I am barren.
It's me, it's not you.
It's not the both of us,
it's me.
And I've been trying to
tell you, but just every time
you wanted to have sex,
it was all I could think about.
And I didn't know
how to tell you, so I...
I mean, I mean, why?
Why wouldn't you tell me?
Isn't that the kind of thing
that couples figure
out together?
I just knew how much
you wanted this, and...
...I didn't want
to let you down.
Yeah, but I want this.
More than anything.
And... I don't know,
we can figure all
that other stuff out.
All I ever wanted was
for us to be a team.
That's all I ever wanted.
Honey, oh...
No more secrets, okay?
Actually...
there is one more secret.
(sighs):
Okay.
(doorbell rings)
(urgent knocking on door)
Hey, Evan.
Jamarcus, you know what,
now's not a good time.
Okay, well, I need
to tell you something.
I know. I just need to be
with my wife right now.
This is more important.
Whatever it is, it isn't.
Trust me.
We need to get the
Neighborhood Watch together now.
Do you want another one?
That gonna hold you over?
I'll eat more pudding
if you have more.
I don't know that I'm open
to an apology yet.
You serious?
Jamarcus, what's going on?
Oh...
The fuck?
Oh, my God.
Is that a...
like, a parlor trick?
It's okay. It's okay.
Touch my goo, Bob.
Feels like cum.
Holy fuck, it feels like cum!
What?
He's a fucking alien!
You stay the fuck back,
Jamarcus!
All right, what the
hell is going on?
Franklin, I'm not here
to hurt you.
Believe me, I've had
many chances to kill you.
You're one of them?
You're an alien?
Look, our ship came here
six months ago,
and we've been hiding
ever since.
We inhabited your human form
to infiltrate your society
and learn your weaknesses,
but instead...
Why is this thing still talking?
Let's kill him.
Because, in a few hours,
our transmitter
will become operational.
When it signals, our armada
will commence a global invasion
starting here in Glenview,
which is clearly
not ideal for you.
What?
Why?
We're aliens.
That's we do...
we come to planets,
we destroy them, we move on.
Wait a minute.
Did you kill Antonio?
No. God, of course not.
I know who did.
His name's Flertrok.
The man is a fucking cunt.
Where is this transmitter thing?
The only place big enough
with enough power and supplies.
Costco?
Yeah.
You've been planning
an alien invasion in my Costco?
You really do have everything
you need under one roof.
BOB: Why are you
telling us this
if we don't have
any time to stop it?
What kind of sick fucking
head game are you playing?
Well, because
there's good news.
If you leave now,
you will survive
the initial invasion,
and after that,
if you take to the desert
and live in caves and crevices,
you could, you know, live
with moderate dignity
for most of your lives.
I don't believe
a word he's saying.
He betrayed the Watch.
JAMARCUS: Yes, but since
then, I've come to know
humanity's compassion and...
and beauty and... and love.
I don't want to lie anymore.
And also, the ball sucking
was a real eye opener.
Look, I'm not going to ask
for your forgiveness,
because I don't deserve it.
I'm really sorry.
Just go.
Okay.
Please, save yourselves
while there's still time.
ABBY: What the hell
is happening?
FRANKLIN: Well, if we don't
leave here right now,
we're going to die.
Guys, are you actually talking
about giving up
and leaving Glenview?
EVAN: No, I think
we go and...
and alert the authorities,
get as many people out
as possible.
And then what?
And then... I don't know.
FRANKLIN:
Evan's right.
We need to hit the caves.
Guys, we're not going to let
Glenview become ground zero
for an alien invasion
and not do something about it.
We're the Neighborhood Watch.
This is what we do.
No, Bob, come on.
It's what we did...
or never really did,
because we didn't
really do anything.
Until now.
I say, tonight, we change that.
Evan, you started
the neighborhood watch
because you believed
in something.
You believed in this town.
You believed in these people.
You believed in us.
And damn it, I still do.
We're not going to let
a bunch of aliens
waltz in here and do
whatever the hell
they want to do.
I say, not on our watch.
I say they drew the short straw
when they picked Glenview.
Now, come on, guys,
and get your heads right.
This neighborhood's
going to need our best tonight.
Evan, some aliens
just set up tents in your store.
What do you want to do about it?
Costco is for members only.
Let's take out that transmitter.
Now we're talking.
All right, Watch.
This is it.
Now it gets real.
That's a cute
ten-milly Beretta, Bobby.
But I say we make
a little pit stop at my house.
# #
# I was a moving man #
# In my younger days... #
Welcome to the candy shop,
motherfuckers.
Jesus.
Nice.
Holy shit.
Ladies first.
Oh.
This one looks cute.
(chuckles)
Cute and deadly.
Just like me.
Ew.
FRANKLIN'S MOM:
Franklin, what are you doing?
Who are these people?
And what are you doing
with these guns?
Goddamn it, Mom,
stay the fuck out of my room!
I don't go through your shit!
I don't touch your butterflies!
Franklin.
Stay the fuck out. All right,
everyone out of my room.
Everyone out of my room.
Everyone leave. Everyone leave.
Everyone out.
- I got shit I have to do.
- Nice to meet you.
Politeness, yeah.
It was a pleasure.
(whispering):
I'm sorry, Mama.
I was trying to
impress my friends.
I was trying to be a big man.
I love you. Stay inside
the house tonight, okay?
What...
You're an angel.
(engine revving,
tires screeching)
BRESSMAN (over phone):
Glenview PD.
This is Sergeant Bressman.
EVAN: Bressman?
It's Evan Trautwig.
Listen to me very carefully.
There is an alien invasion
happening at the Costco.
I know it sounds crazy, but you
got to get down there right now.
BRESSMAN:
Oh, an alien invasion?
Really? At-at Costco?
Right now?
Oh, great, I'm on my way.
Oh, wait, no, I'm not.
I'm still here for some reason.
G-Give me the phone.
Give me the phone.
Bressman, you were right.
Trautwig is the Costco killer.
He's going to take us
to Costco right now
and kill us.
You got to help us. Aah!
He's coming.
Really?
Yeah.
He believed that?
# #
Look.
ABBY: Oh, my God.
That's an alien.
I-I-I...
I'm looking at an alien.
BOB: I know.
It can be a total mind-fuck.
What do we do, bust in
the front door, guns blazing?
I love the enthusiasm,
Frank 'n' Beans,
but I think we're going to need
a different kind
of strategy here.
There's only one way
underneath the store.
It's through the drainage grate
in frozen foods.
When we rebuilt
the tire section,
we put shelving
over the trash chute,
but we never sealed it off.
Stay behind me.
Let's go.
Pop this bitch open.
I'll cover you.
Come on, let's go, guys.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
I can't...
Shh.
Do you have nails?
# #
(walkie-talkie beeps,
feedback squeals)
BOB: He's guarding the grate.
Are you guys in position?
In position.
This is exciting.
Okay.
All right, we shoot
him on three.
I repeat... shoot on three.
One. Two.
Three!
(door banging open)
Freeze, Trautwig.
Game over.
Where'd it go?
Did you see it?
I don't know.
You're under arrest for the
murder of Manfred Salisbury,
Antonio Guzman
Shh! Shh!
And that little
punk skater kid.
(whispering): Shut up.
Drop the guns.
You don't understand
what's happening.
There's aliens in the store.
Oh, yeah?
Aliens? Where?
It was right over there
until you scared it.
Now, keep your mouth down.
Oh, aliens who are
scared by the sound
- of a door opening.
- Shh!
BRESSMAN:
Look out, Earth.
You've met your match.
Drop the guns!
EVAN: no, we're not
going to drop our guns,
because there are aliens here.
(grunts)
Chucho, what's up, buddy?
You got something to say?
(screams)
Oh, what the fuck
is that thing?
(screaming)
No.
(roars)
No!
BRESSMAN:
Fuck! Fuck!
Shit! Oh!
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck!
BRESSMAN:
Chucho.
(sobbing):
Oh, Chucho, Chucho.
Oh, stay with me, buddy.
Stay with me.
Oh, no, no, no, Chucho.
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on, stay with me.
Stay with me. Come on.
BOB: His, uh...
his heart is out
of his body, fella.
I-I don't think he's
going to make it.
What? No, no,
he's going to make it.
Come on! Come on!
Listen, cop!
You got a lot of shit you need
to brought up to speed on,
and I, for one,
don't have the goddamn time
to hold your hand
and walk you through it.
First, aliens exist.
Deal with it.
Second, your boy Chuch,
here, is dead as fuck.
And there ain't nothing
on God's green Earth
that's going to
bring him back to us.
Now, I have a bunch of aliens
underneath this Costco,
and we are moments away
from this Earth
being stomped a new asshole.
Now, I have one
important question,
and I need you
to answer it for me right now.
Are you with us?
Are you a cop?
No. You rejected me.
'Cause I was
too awesome for you.
Well, that was clearly
the biggest
goddamn mistake I've ever made.
I'll do whatever you say, kid.
Lock and load, bitches.
Anything from outer space,
kill it.
Come on. That alien was guarding
that grate for a reason.
(screaming)
Die! Die!
You... killed...
my... friend!
You stupid Flertrok!
I don't know
if we can confirm or deny
whether or not that's Flertrok,
but this thing's
a goner for sure.
Oh, it hurts.
(Bressman groaning)
I guess this is the part
where you leave me to die.
No, no.
Uh, you're not going to die.
Yeah, you're not going to die.
(whispering): He's going to...
he's going to die.
You better get some help.
(loud electronic whirr)
That doesn't sound good.
Come on, we got to find
that transmitter.
Hey.
Go kill me some aliens, baby.
All right.
Okay.
Hey. I need you to be
strong for me, okay?
Ew.
Okay...
Franklin.
What's the deal?
What are we doing?
All right, you ready?
Yeah, okay.
Okay, I'm just
going to lift your arm.
# #
Here we go.
(steam hissing)
(electronic whirring)
FRANKLIN: Holy shit.
JASON:
Gentlemen.
What the hell are you
doing down here?
JASON:
Nothing, really.
Just picking up
some paper towels in bulk.
Super-big tub of mayo.
And what else?
Oh, yeah.
Transmitting a signal
to my armada
to destroy your entire race.
FRANKLIN:
Holy shit!
He's an alien!
BOB:
You motherfucker!
You guys go destroy
the transmitter.
I'll deal with this jackass.
No. We're not going to
leave you alone with him.
Goddamn it, Evan, we don't
have time for this shit.
Just go, go, go, go, go!
I got him. I got him.
Bob's right. Look, they have
some shit they have to work out.
Let's just go. Come on.
Okay, you be careful.
Okay. Okay, Bob.
You can do this.
(grunting)
Come on, Bob.
This is too easy.
(grunting)
Whoo!
Yeah!
(grunting):
God.
Oh, my God.
What do we do?
I have an idea.
(bullet ricochets)
My idea didn't work.
(roars)
Evan, they're not dying!
I'm out of bullets.
So am I.
It's going to be an honor
getting skinned alive
next to you.
What is happening?
FRANKLIN:
Why are their dicks exploding?
Hi.
That's the only way to kill us.
Severe trauma to the dick.
That's where our brains are.
Like all guys.
Am I right?
JAMARCUS:
You know it.
EVAN:
Bob, come in.
If you can hear me...
(yells)
their weakness is their dick.
Their Achilles' heel
is in their dicks.
Die!
(screeches)
(screaming)
(grunts)
(Bob panting)
Magnum, my ass.
I only needed one hand
for that shit.
(whirring)
Jamarcus, how do you
shut this thing down?
Looks like the orb's
powering it,
so maybe removing the orb
would de-power it?
You're guessing?
You seriously don't know
how this thing works?
I'm not an engineer.
I didn't build it.
I mean, do you know
how your cell phone works?
Do I... Yes, I know
how my cell phone works.
You hit a bunch of numbers
and you hit send.
At least don't you know
the basic...?
What do you mean, the basic?
Look at it.
It's not fucking basic.
It looks complicated.
That light bit.
See, that light... that means
it's almost charged, right?
What's happening?
Whoa! What the fuck
is he doing here?
Bob, it's all right.
We were surrounded,
and he saved our asses.
EVAN: You okay?
FRANKLIN: He came in here
jacking dicks left and right.
(chittering)
Shit. What is that?
I'm going to go get
that orb thing.
You guys cover me, all right?
BOB: Yeah, Evaroo.
Just go quick. Hurry up.
This place sucks.
I've gone to
the other side, guys.
I'm fucking way in it.
If first thing in war is lost
is fucking innocence...
(spits) Yeah!
BOB:
Better watch it.
Hurry up, buddy.
Hurry up.
(trilling)
(whooshing)
FRANKLIN:
It's transmitting!
Get it off that thing.
(machine powering down)
(beeping)
It worked!
FRANKLIN: All right.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
What is it?
Franklin!
(roaring)
Holy shit. Evan, let's go!
(yells)
BOB: We got to get the orb
out of here.
Cover us. Let's go.
I got you, Frank 'n' Bean!
(roaring)
(gun fires)
(screeching)
BOB: Come on!
Let's go!
Get up there, Frank.
Come on, Evan.
Move, move, move.
This place is crawling.
(grunts)
(roars)
Jamarcus, give me your hand!
Just go.
Take the orb out and go.
No Watchman left behind!
Give me your hand!
Come on, pal!
Come on, brother.
Let's go.
Fridge! Franklin!
Get up here. Let's go.
(grunting)
Go! Go! Go! Go!
(roaring)
Come on, come on!
Let's go!
Franklin, the switch!
(alarm whooping)
Get back, Abby!
Abby!
Take cover!
BOB:
Come on, boys!
Let's plug
these motherfucking holes!
(whooshing)
Good-bye, sweet child of mine.
Evan!
# #
BRESSMAN:
Wait, what's happening?
Did we win?
I can't see.
Are those tears of joy?
They're not tears
of joy, are they?
Oh, no.
Your husband's dead, isn't he?
Your husband's dead.
I'm so sorry.
You're going to find somebody.
You're a great person.
Life goes on, though.
There's always something better
around the corner.
That's what my mom always said.
I'm single, too, actually.
# #
EVAN:
Hey.
(sighs)
Your Costco.
I'm sorry, baby.
Don't be.
She'll rise again.
Like a phoenix from the ashes.
And when she does,
we'll be there.
We did it, Ev.
Yeah, we did.
You came back for us.
We went to an orgy together.
We are, like,
friends forever now.
I'll explain that to you later.
Yeah.
Okay.
Hey.
Listen, I'm sorry
about that stuff I said before.
BOB:
Ah, forget it, man.
I'm really sorry about the stuff
I said, too, but...
I mean, that's what brothers do.
They fight.
But then they always
make up, right?
Are we cool?
Yeah.
All right.
Get in here, little big man.
That's my guy.
That was really
beautiful, you guys.
Now do me.
What?
Apologize to me.
For what?
If I have to tell you,
then the apology is meaningless.
All right, Frank 'n' Beans.
Get in here.
Thank you. Thank you.
Come on, Jamrock.
All right, guys.
Listen, baby, I know things
get tough, but I'm okay.
Yeah. No, look, I understand.
You got to stop that.
Really.
What are you doing? Really.
I'm in a weird place.
I'm sorry.
BOB: I don't want
to come off
as kind of a bottom-feeder,
but there could be
a couple of knickknacks
in that store
that no one's going to miss.
Don't even finish it.
What are you doing? No.
Pick up a couple knickknacks
or something for the...
That stuff's all covered
by insurance.
You can't...
What are you...?
EVAN:
I used to think I had it all,
but then I realized:
What was it all about
without friends?
All right, kids, let's get in
a little tighter here.
Let's keep the hands
above the hips.
Let's keep it 1950s
in this bitch, okay?
Is it true your dad ripped
your last boyfriend's dick off?
Yup.
Hey, you guys be home
by midnight.
I was thinking
actually 10:30, sir,
if that's okay with you.
Don't be such a suck-up. What, are you
going to blow me in the driveway?
Midnight's going to be fine.
EVAN:
Sometimes, someone you thought
was a total douche bag...
I mean, like,
a real piece of shit guy...
turns out to be your best
friend and your partner.
And for me,
even though my testicles
had completely betrayed me,
Abby hadn't.
She and I were a team.
Boo!
Whoa!
Mommy, Daddy.
And a family.
Oh! Where did you come from?
I now know
that we are not alone.
And I'm feeling pretty good
about that.
That's right.
EVAN:
So, if you hear something
go bump in the night,
never fear,
because the Neighborhood Watch,
as always, is watching...
the neighborhood...
for aliens.
# You ain't seen nothing yet #
# B-b-b-baby, you just ain't
seen n-n-nothing yet. #
# Woke up quick at about noon #
# Just thought that I had to be
in Compton soon #
# I gotta get drunk
before the day begins #
# Before my mother
starts bitchin' #
# About my friends #
# Then I let the Alpine play,
play #
(horn honking)
# Bumping new shit by N.W.A. #
# It was gangsta, gangsta
at the top of the list #
# Then I played my own shit,
it went somethin' like this #
# Cruisin' down the street
in my 6-4 #
# Jockin' the bitches,
slappin' the hoes #
# Went to the park
to get the scoop #
# Knuckleheads out there
cold shootin' some hoops #
# A car pulls up,
who can it be? #
# A fresh El Camino
rolling Kilo G #
# He rolled down his window
and he started to say #
# It's all about making
that GTA #
# 'Cause the boys in the hood
are always hard #
# You come talkin' that trash,
we'll pull your card #
# Knowin' nothin' in life
but to be legit #
# Don't quote me, boy,
'cause I ain't said shit #
# Yo, man, yo #
# Yo, man... #
# Yo, man #
# Get the fuck out, fuck out,
fuck out, fuck out... #
(music fades)
# #