(DISTANT RUMBLING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(MEN SPEAKING GERMAN)
While I'm very familiar
with you and your family,
I have no way of knowing if
you are familiar with who I am.
Are you aware
of my existence?
Yes.
This is good.
Now, are you aware of the job
I've been ordered to carry out in France?
Yes.
Please tell me
what you've heard.
I've heard
that the Führer has put you in charge
of rounding up the Jews left in France
who are either hiding
or passing for Gentile.
The Führer couldn't have
said it better himself.
But the meaning
of your visit,
pleasant though it is,
is mysterious to me.
The Germans looked through my house
nine months ago for hiding Jews
and found nothing.
I'm aware of that.
I've read the reports
of this area.
But like any enterprise,
when under new management,
there is always a slight
duplication of efforts,
most of it being a complete waste of time,
but needs to be done nevertheless.
I just have a few questions,
monsieur LaPadite.
If you can assist me
with answers,
my department can close
the file on your family.
Now,
before the occupation, there were
four Jewish families in this area,
all dairy farmers
like yourself.
Doleracs, Rollins,
the Loveitts
and the Dreyfuses.
Is that correct?
To my knowledge,
those were the Jewish families
among the dairy farmers.
Herr Colonel, would it disturb
you if I smoked my pipe?
(CHUCKLES) Please,
monsieur LaPadite,
this is your house,
make yourself comfortable.
Now, according
to these papers,
all the Jewish families in this
area have been accounted for
except the Dreyfuses.
Somewhere in the last year it
would appear they've vanished.
Which leads me to the conclusion that
they've either made good their escape
or someone is very
successfully hiding them.
What have you heard about the
Dreyfuses, monsieur LaPadite?
Only rumors.
I love rumors!
Facts could be
so misleading,
where rumors, true or
false, are often revealing.
So, monsieur LaPadite,
what rumors have you heard
regarding the Dreyfuses?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Again,
this is just a rumor,
but we heard the Dreyfuses
had made their way into Spain.
(MATCHSTICKS SCRAPING)
So, the rumors you've heard
have been of escape?
(AGREES IN FRENCH)
Yes.
Having never met the Dreyfuses,
would you confirm for me
the exact members of the
household and their names?
(CLEARS THROAT)
There were
five of them.
The father, Jacob.
Wife, Miram.
And her brother, Bob.
How old is Bob?
Thirty, 31.
Continue.
And the children,
Amos
and Shosanna.
Ages of the children?
(SIGHS)
Amos was nine or 10.
And Shosanna?
And Shosanna was
18 or 19.
I'm not really sure.
Well, I guess
that should do it.
(ZIPPER CLOSING)
However, before I go, could I have
another glass of your delicious milk?
But of course.
Monsieur LaPadite,
are you aware of the nickname the
people of France have given me?
(SIGHS)
I have no interest
in such things.
But you are aware
of what they call me.
I'm aware.
What are you aware of?
(THANKING
IN FRENCH)
That they call you
"The Jew Hunter."
Precisely.
I understand your
trepidation in repeating it.
Heydrich apparently
hates the moniker
the good people of Prague
have bestowed on him.
Actually, why he would hate the
name "the Hangman" is baffling to me.
It would appear he has done
everything in his power to earn it.
Now I, on the other hand,
love my unofficial title
precisely because
I've earned it.
The feature that makes me such an
effective hunter of the Jews is,
as opposed to most
German soldiers,
I can think like a Jew
where they can only
think like a German.
(CHUCKLING) More precisely,
a German soldier.
Now, if one were to determine what attribute
the German people share with a beast,
it would be the cunning and the
predatory instinct of a hawk.
But if one were to determine what
attributes the Jews share with a beast,
it would be
that of the rat.
The Führer and Goebbels' propaganda
have said pretty much the same thing.
But where our conclusions
differ,
is I don't consider
the comparison an insult.
Consider for a moment
the world a rat lives in.
It's a hostile world,
indeed.
If a rat were to scamper through
your front door, right now,
would you greet it
with hostility?
I suppose I would.
Has a rat ever done
anything to you
to create this animosity
you feel toward them?
Rats spread disease.
They bite people.
Rats were the cause of the bubonic
plague, but that's some time ago.
I propose to you any disease
a rat could spread,
a squirrel could
equally carry.
Would you agree?
(AGREES IN FRENCH)
Yet, I assume you don't share
the same animosity with squirrels
that you do with rats,
do you?
No.
Yet, they're both rodents,
are they not?
And except for the tail, they
even rather look alike, don't they?
It's an interesting thought,
Herr Colonel.
However interesting
as the thought may be,
it makes not one bit of
difference to how you feel.
If a rat were to walk in
here, right now, as I'm talking
would you greet it with a
saucer of your delicious milk?
Probably not.
I didn't think so.
You don't like them.
You don't really know
why you don't like them.
All you know is
you find them repulsive.
Consequently, a German
soldier conducts a search
of a house suspected
of hiding Jews.
Where does the hawk look?
He looks in the barn, he looks in
the attic, he looks in the cellar,
he looks everywhere
he would hide.
But there are so many places it
would never occur to a hawk to hide.
However, the reason the Führer has
brought me off my Alps in Austria
and placed me in French cow country
today is because it does occur to me.
Because I'm aware what tremendous
feats human beings are capable of
once they abandon dignity.
May I smoke my pipe
as well?
Please, Herr Colonel,
make yourself at home.
Now, my job dictates
that I must have my men
enter your home
and conduct
a thorough search
before I can officially cross
your family's name off my list.
And if there are any irregularities
to be found, rest assured they will be.
That is unless you have
something to tell me
that makes the conducting
of a search unnecessary.
I might add, also,
that any information
that makes the performance of my duty
easier will not be met with punishment.
Actually, quite the contrary.
It will be met with reward.
And that reward will be,
your family will cease
to be harassed in any way
by the German military during the
rest of our occupation of your country.
You're sheltering enemies
of the state, are you not?
Yes.
You're sheltering them underneath
your floorboards, aren't you?
Yes.
Point out to me the areas
where they're hiding.
Since I haven't heard
any disturbance,
I assume, while they're listening,
they don't speak English.
Yes.
I'm going to switch back to French now,
and I want you to follow my masquerade.
Is that clear?
(SNIFFLES)
Yes.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SHUSHING)
It's the girl.
(SOBBING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(PANTING)
Au revoir, Shosanna!
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
ALDO: Ten-hut!
My name is
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
And I'm putting together a special
team, and I need me eight soldiers.
Eight Jewish
American soldiers.
Now, you all might've heard rumors
about the armada happening soon.
Well, we'll be leaving
a little earlier.
We're going to be dropped into
France dressed as civilians.
Once we're
in enemy territory,
as a bushwhacking
guerrilla army,
we're going to be doing one
thing and one thing only.
Killing Nazis.
I don't know
about you all,
but I sure as hell didn't come down
from the goddamn Smoky Mountains,
cross 5, 000 miles of water,
fight my way through half of Sicily
and jump out of a fucking airplane to
teach the Nazis lessons in humanity.
Nazi ain't got no humanity.
They're the foot soldiers of a Jew-hating,
mass-murdering maniac
and they need
to be destroyed.
That's why any and every son of a
bitch we find wearing a Nazi uniform,
they're going to die.
Now, I'm the direct descendent
of the mountain man Jim Bridger.
That means I got
a little Indian in me.
And our battle plan will be
that of an Apache resistance.
We will be cruel
to the Germans.
And through our cruelty,
they will know who we are.
And they will find
the evidence of our cruelty
in the disemboweled,
dismembered
and disfigured bodies of their
brothers we leave behind us.
And the German won't be able
to help themselves
but imagine the cruelty their
brothers endured at our hands,
and our boot heels
and the edge of our knives.
And the German
will be sickened by us.
will talk about us.
And the German
will fear us.
And when the German
closes their eyes at night
and they're tortured by their
subconscious for the evil they have done,
it will be with thoughts of us
that they are tortured with.
Sound good?
ALL: Yes, sir!
That's what I like to hear.
But I got a word of warning
for all you would-be warriors.
When you join my command,
you take on debit.
A debit you owe me,
personally.
Each and every man under my
command owes me 100 Nazi scalps.
And I want my scalps.
And all y'all will get me 100 Nazi scalps
taken from the heads of 100 dead Nazis.
Or you will die trying!
(SHOUTING IN GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(INTERCOM BUZZING)
(KLIEST SPEAKING GERMAN
ON INTERCOM)
(KLIEST SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BUTZ SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
Hey, Hirschberg.
Send that Kraut
sarge over.
HIRSCHBERG: You. Go.
Sergeant
Werner Rachtman.
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
Pleased to meet you.
You know what
"sit down" means, Werner?
Yes.
Then sit down.
How is your English,
Werner?
Because if need be, we got a
couple of fellows who can translate.
Wicki here,
an Austrian-Jew, got the fuck out
of Munich while the getting was good.
Became American, got drafted,
come back to give y'all what for.
Another one up there
you might be familiar with.
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz.
Heard of him?
Everybody in the German Army
has heard of Hugo Stiglitz.
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
MALE NARRATOR: The reason
for Hugo Stiglitz's celebrity
among German soldiers
is simple.
As a German-enlisted man,
he killed 13 Gestapo officers.
Instead of putting him up
against a wall,
the High Command decided
to send him back to Berlin
to be made an example of.
Needless to say, once the
Basterds heard about him,
he never got there.
(GASPING)
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz?
Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
These are the Basterds.
Ever heard of us?
We just want to say we're
a big fan of your work.
When it comes
to killing Nazis...
(MAN GROANING)
...I think you show
great talent.
And I pride myself for having
an eye for that kind of talent.
But your status as a Nazi
killer is still amateur.
We all come here to see
if you want to go pro.
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
Can I assume
you know who we are?
You're Aldo the Apache.
(BASTERDS WHOOPING)
Werner,
if you heard of us,
you probably heard we ain't in
the prisoner-taking business.
We in the killing Nazi business,
and, cousin, business is a-booming.
HIRSCHBERG:
(LAUGHING) Oh, yeah.
Now, that leaves two ways
we can play this out.
Either kill you
or let you go.
Whether or not you're going
to leave this ditch alive
depends entirely on you.
Up the road a piece,
there's an orchard.
Besides you, we know there's another
Kraut patrol fucking around here somewhere.
If that patrol were
to have any crack shots,
that orchard would be
a goddamn sniper's delight.
So if you ever want to eat
a sauerkraut sandwich again,
you got to show me on
this here map where they are.
You got to tell me how many
they are, and you got to tell me
what kind of artillery
they're carrying with them.
(SCOFFING)
You can't expect me to divulge information
that would put German lives in danger.
Well, now, Werner, that's where you're wrong,
because that's exactly what I expect.
I need to know about
Germans hiding in trees.
And you need to tell me.
And you need to tell me right now.
Now, just take that
finger of yours
and point out on this here map
where this party is being held,
how many is coming and what
they brought to play with.
I respectfully refuse,
sir.
(BAT TAPPING)
Hear that?
Yes.
That's Sergeant
Donny Donowitz.
You might know him better
by his nickname.
The Bear Jew.
Now, if you heard of Aldo the Apache,
you got to have heard about The Bear Jew.
I heard of The Bear Jew.
What did you hear?
Beats German soldiers
with a club.
He bashes their brains in with
a baseball bat, what he does.
And, Werner, I'm going to
ask you one last goddamn time,
and if you still
respectfully refuse,
I'm calling
The Bear Jew over.
He's going to take
that big bat of his,
and he's going to beat
your ass to death with it.
Now, take your
Wiener-schnitzel-licking finger,
and point out on this map
what I want to know.
Fuck you.
And your Jew dogs.
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
(BASTERDS APPLAUDING)
Actually, Werner, we're all
tickled to hear you say that.
Quite frankly, watching
Donny beat Nazis to death
is the closest we ever get
to going to the movies. Donny!
DONNY: Yeah?
Got us a German here who
wants to die for country.
Oblige him.
(BAT TAPPING)
(CONTINUES TAPPING)
(BASTERDS CHEERING)
Did you get that
for killing Jews?
Bravery.
(BASTERDS EXCLAIMING)
Yeah!
BASTERD 1: Oh, no!
BASTERD 2: Oh, no!
Donny!
BASTERD: Yeah, Donny!
About now I'd be shitting
my pants if I was you.
(LAUGHING)
Teddy Fucking Williams
knocks it out of the park!
Fenway Park is on its feet
for Teddy Fucking Ballgame!
He went yard on that one,
on to fucking Lansdowne Street!
You!
Damn it,
Hirschberg!
Donny, bring that other one
over here. Alive!
Get the fuck up!
Batter up. You're on deck!
Two hits. I hit you,
you hit the ground.
English?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
ALDO: Wicki.
Ask him
if he wants to live.
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
Tell him to point out on
this map the German position.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BASTERDS LAUGHING)
Ask him how many Germans.
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
Around about 12.
What kind of artillery?
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Now, when you report
what happened here,
you can't tell them you told us
what you told us. They'll shoot you.
They're going to want to know why
you so special, we let you live.
So tell them, we let you live so you
could spread the word through the ranks
what's going to happen
to every Nazi we find.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
Now that you've survived the war, when
you get home, what you going to do?
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
WICKI: He's going
to hug his mother.
(SNIFFS)
Well, ain't that nice?
Ask if he's going
to take off his uniform.
(WICKI SPEAKING GERMAN)
(BUTZ SPEAKING GERMAN)
WICKI: He's going
to burn it.
Yeah, that's what we thought.
We don't like that.
See, we like our Nazis in uniforms.
That way you can spot them.
Just like that.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
But you take off that uniform, ain't
nobody going to know you's a Nazi.
And that don't sit
well with us.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
So I'm going to give you a little
something you can't take off.
You know, Lieutenant, you're
getting pretty good at that.
You know how you get to
Carnegie Hall, don't you?
Practice.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(EXCLAIMS)
(LAUGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CHUCKLES EXCITEDLY)
(EXHALES)
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(LAUGHS EXCITEDLY)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(BOTH SPEAKING GERMAN)
(OFFICER EXCLAIMS)
(OFFICERS CHATTERING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(EXHALES)
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS)
(SAYING GOODBYE IN FRENCH)
(DRIVER SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CAR APPROACHING)
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(GOEBBELS LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(FREDRICK LAUGHS)
(PANTING)
(BRAYING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(TRANSLATING IN FRENCH)
(TRANSLATOR
SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(COUGHS)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(TRANSLATOR
SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(TRANSLATES IN GERMAN)
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(TRANSLATING IN GERMAN)
(SCOFFS)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
(TRANSLATING IN FRENCH)
(FREDRICK SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
HANS: Au revoir, Shosanna!
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(FREDRICK SPEAKING GERMAN)
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING
GERMAN)
(HANS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(CHUCKLES)
(GASPING)
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHS)
(TRANSLATOR
SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SHOSANNA
(GOEBBELS SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SCOFFS)
MALE NARRATOR: At that time, 35 millimeter
nitrate film was so flammable
that you couldn't even
bring a reel onto a streetcar.
Hey, you can't bring those
here on a public vehicle.
They're films, ain't they?
- Yes.
Then they're flammable.
Go on, hop off.
MALE NARRATOR: Because nitrate film
burns three times faster than paper.
Shosanna has a collection
of over 350 nitrate
film prints.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
MAN: Right this way,
Lieutenant.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Lieutenant Archie Hicox
reporting, sir.
General Ed Fenech.
At ease, Hicox.
Drink?
If you offer me a scotch and plain water,
I could drink a scotch and plain water.
That-a-boy, Lieutenant.
Make it yourself like a good chap, will you?
The bar is in the globe.
Something for yourself,
sir?
Whiskey. Straight.
No junk in it.
It says here that
you speak German fluently.
Like a Katzenjammer Kid.
And your occupation
before the war?
I'm a film critic.
List your accomplishments.
Well, sir,
such as they are,
I write reviews and articles for a
publication called Films and Filmmakers,
and I've had
two books published.
Impressive. Don't be modest,
Lieutenant. What are their titles?
The first book
was called
Art of the Eyes, the Heart and the Mind:
A Study of German Cinema in the '20s.
And the second one was called
Twenty-Four Frame da Vinci.
It's a subtextual film criticism study
of the work of German director G.W. Pabst.
What should we
drink to, sir?
Well...
Down with Hitler.
All the way down, sir.
Yes.
Are you familiar with German
cinema under the Third Reich?
Yes. Obviously, I haven't seen any of
the films made in the last three years,
but I'm familiar with it.
Explain it to me.
Pardon, sir?
Well, this little escapade of ours requires
a knowledge of the German film industry
under the Third Reich.
Explain to me UFA under Goebbels.
Goebbels considers
the films he's making
to be the beginning of a
new era in German cinema.
An alternative
to what he considers
the Jewish-German intellectual
cinema of the '20s,
and the Jewish-controlled
dogma of Hollywood.
How's he doing?
Frightfully sorry, sir.
Once again?
You say he wants to take on
the Jews at their own game.
Well, compared to,
say, Louis B. Mayer,
how's he doing?
Quite well, actually.
Since Goebbels
has taken over,
film attendance has steadily risen
in Germany over the last eight years.
But Louis B. Mayer wouldn't be
Goebbels' proper opposite number.
I believe Goebbels sees himself
closer to David O. Selznick.
Brief him.
Lieutenant Hicox, at this point and time
I'd like to brief you on Operation Kino.
Three days from now
Joseph Goebbels is throwing a gala
premiere of one of his new movies in Paris.
What film, sir?
The motion picture is
called Nation's Pride.
In attendance at this
joyous Germatic occasion
will be Goebbels, Goring, Bormann,
and most of the German High Command
including all high ranking officers
of both the SS and the Gestapo,
as well as luminaries of the
Nazi propaganda film industry.
The master race at play?
Basically, we have all our
rotten eggs in one basket.
The objective
of Operation Kino,
blow up the basket.
And like the snows of yesteryear,
gone from this earth.
Jolly good, sir.
An American Secret Service outfit
that lives deep behind enemy lines
will be your assist.
The Germans call them
the Basterds.
The Basterds.
Never heard of them.
Whole point of the Secret Service,
old boy, you not hearing of them.
But the Jerries have heard of them, because
these Yanks have been them the devil.
You'll be dropped into France,
about 24 kilometers outside of Paris.
The Basterds
will be waiting for you.
First thing, you'll go to a
little village called Nadine.
In Nadine, there's a
tavern called La Louisiane.
There you'll rendezvous with our
double agent. She'll take it from there.
She's the one who is going
to get you into the premiere.
It'll be you, her, and two
German-born members of the Basterds.
She's also made all the other
arrangements you're going to need.
How will I know her?
I suspect that won't be
too much trouble for you.
Your contact
is Bridget von Hammersmark.
Bridget von Hammersmark?
(CHUCKLING) The German movie
star is working for England?
Yes, for the last
two years now.
One could even say that
Operation Kino was her brainchild.
Indeed.
Got the gist?
I think so, sir.
Paris when it sizzles.
You didn't say the goddamn
rendezvous is in a fucking basement.
I didn't know.
You said it was
in a tavern.
It is a tavern.
Yeah, in a basement.
You know, fighting in a basement
offers a lot of difficulties.
Number one being, you're
fighting in a basement.
What if we go in there
and she's not even there?
We wait.
Don't worry. She's a British
spy. She'll make the rendezvous.
Stiglitz, right?
That's right, sir.
I hear you're pretty good
with that.
You know, we're not looking
for trouble right now.
Simply making contact with
our agent. Should be uneventful.
However, the off chance I'm
wrong, things prove eventful,
I need to know
we can all remain calm.
I don't look calm to you?
(LAUGHS)
Well, now that you put it
like that, I guess you do.
This Jerry of yours, Stiglitz, not
exactly the loquacious type, is he?
Is that the kind of man
you need? Loquacious type?
Fair point, Lieutenant.
So you all get in trouble in
there, what are we supposed to do?
Make bets
on how it all comes out?
If we get into trouble,
we can handle it.
But if trouble does happen,
we need you to make damn sure
no Germans, or French, for that
matter, escape from that basement.
If Frau von Hammersmark's cover is
compromised, the mission is kaput.
Speaking of Frau von Hammersmark, whose
idea was it for the deathtrap rendezvous?
She chose the spot.
Isn't that just dandy?
Look, she's not a military strategist.
She's just an actress.
You don't got to be Stonewall Jackson to
know you don't want to fight in a basement.
She wasn't picking
a place to fight.
She was picking a place
isolated and without Germans.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(ORDERING IN GERMAN
AND FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(MAN LAUGHING)
(FEMALE SERGEANT
SPEAKING GERMAN)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING FRENCH
AND GERMAN)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN
SOFTLY)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(CORK POPPING)
Mmm.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(ALL TOASTING IN GERMAN)
(STAMMERING)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(LAUGHING)
(THANKING IN GERMAN)