It's me, Peter Parker.
Your friendly neighborhood... you know.
I've come a long way from being the boy who was bit by a spider.
Back then, nothing seemed to go right for me.
- Now...
- Wow, look, it's Spider-Man!
people really like me.
- Hey, stick around! It's gonna start again in a couple minutes.
- Yeah... - That's OK.
The city is safe and sound.
Guess I've had something to do with that.
My uncle Ben would be proud.
WHY NY <3'S SPIDEY
I still go to school,
top of my class.
Now, the Hamiltonian shows us
that the energy levels are perturbed by the electric field.
From the form of this matrix,
we can see...?
- Miss Stacey?
- That only the m=0 quantum states are affected.
Correct! Good work, Miss Stacey.
Parker.
You got something to add?
No, sir.
And I'm in love
with the girl of my dreams.
Hi. Um, Miss Watson left a ticket for me?
Peter Parker.
Excuse me. Sorry. Thank you.
It's my girlfriend!
Harry!
I need to talk to you.
Explain things.
Tell it to my father.
Raise him from the dead.
I'm your friend, Harry.
I cared about your father.
MJ.
Peter.
- Was I good?
- Good?
- You were great. You were...
- You say great?
I love my flowers. They're beautiful.
And those are from Harry.
Was he here tonight?
- Yeah, I ran into him outside.
What's with you guys anyway?
It's complicated.
Tell me again, was I really good?
I was so nervous.
My knees were shaking.
- Your knees were fine.
- The applause was not very loud.
Yes, it was.
It's the acoustics.
It's all about diffusion.
It keeps the sound waves from grouping.
- You see, when the sound waves, they propagate, then it's like an...
- You are such a nerd.
Did you see that one?
You know what?
I'd like to sing on stage for the rest of my life
with you in the first row.
I'll be there.
Tell me you love me.
I love you.
I love you so much.
I always have.
You can't hide here, Flint.
I'm just here to see my daughter.
You are an escaped convict.
The cops are looking for you.
You're not getting near her.
You're nothing but a common thief.
You maybe even killed a man.
It wasn't even like that.
Wasn't.
I had good reason for what I was doing.
And that's the truth.
You and the truth, sitting in prison, having three meals a day together.
I live in a prison. It's a great truth.
And that is the truth that you left behind.
Right there in that bedrooom.
I missed you.
I missed you too, Daddy.
I promise
I'll make you healthy again.
Whatever it takes.
- I'll get the money.
- You get out of here.
Now.
I'm not a bad person.
Just had bad luck.
Peter, what is it?
It's MJ...
I'm gonna ask her to marry me!
Oh, Peter! Oh!
The day that uncle Ben asked me to marry him,
he was so scared and excited.
And very young.
And I loved him so fiercely.
Then you said yes, right?
No. I wanted to say yes, but I said no.
I wasn't ready,
neither was he.
So we took our time.
Looked forward to it.
Didn't want to run into something with nothing to count on but love.
A man has to be understanding
and put his wife before himself.
Can you do that, Peter?
Yeah. I think I can.
Then you have my blessing.
I hope you've considered a proper proposal.
Your uncle had it all planned.
He took me to the beach one Sunday.
He was a knockout in his bathing suit.
And I, I didn't look too bad myself.
We were very good swimmers.
It was a beautiful day,
and he said: "Let's swim to the island."
And at the island,
we found a perfect spot by an old tree,
and we lay down and looked up at the sky.
And then he said, "Close your eyes, May."
And I did. And then he said, "Open them."
And I did.
And he was holding this ring.
Dazzling, in front of me.
I thought it was the sun.
We'd be married 50 years
come August... if...
So.
I hope you make it very special
for Mary Jane.
Do something she'll never forget.
Give her this.
Come on.
Take it.
- Harry.
- You knew this was coming, Pete.
Listen to me! I didn't kill your father!
He was trying to kill me. He killed himself.
Shut up!
I'm still here, Peter!
Hate those things.
Harry.
Harry!
Oh my God.
Come on!
God!
- 200.
- And clear!
- No response.
- Recharge. Let's go again.
Clear!
No response.
We charge it one more time. And clear!
Captain Stacey.
- What's this?
- Flint Marko, the guy we tied to the Ben Paker homicide.
- What about him?
- He just broke out of Rikers.
-And?
- He's on the run.
He's in the Marshlands. I think we got him.
There he is!
"DANGER PARTICLE PHYSICS
TEST FACILITY KEEP OUT"
Eton, take the west side. Tom,you take the east.
Where'd he go?
-That's it. It's charged.
- Right.
Donnie, we got a little fluctuation on 1.
There's a change in the silicon mass.
It's probably a bird. It'll fly away when we fire it up.
Initiating demoleculisation.
-How is he?
- He's gonna be OK.
But there's been some memory impairment.
Particularly his short-term memory.
Right now, he can't remember the accident
or anything that happened to him recently.
Is it permanent?
It could be.
Only time will tell.
He's awake if you want to see him.
Uh-- maybe I should wait.
Nah, it's fine. Just keep it brief. Allow him to rest.
- Hey, buddy.
- Hey.
Hit my head.
Yeah.
Doctor said I was in an accident. Hit and run.
I don't remember much of anything.
My father--
he died, right?
This is all so weird.
Hi. I got here as fast as I could.
I know that face.
How are you doing?
I don't know.
Last thing I remember, I was falling...
somewhere.
You're still fine.
We love you, Harry.
It feels like
somehow I've been gone for a really long time.
Now I'm back home.
It's good to have you back.
I'm sorry, I'm gonna have to ask you guys to scoot, OK?
- OK.
- All right, thank you.
Well, I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah, great.
I think he's gonna be fine.
Think so.
- And you guys seem great.
- Yeah.
You have lovely friends.
My best friends.
I'd give my life for them.
[knocks on door]
- Yeah?
- It's me. - Oh! Hey!
You know I can't open the door.
It's stuck again?
Come on and help me.
I'm coming.
- The review.
- Oh!
The hated it. They hated me.
Well, they can't hate you.
"The young Miss Watson is a pretty girl."
"Easy on the eyes, but not on the ears."
"Her small voice didn't carry past the first row."
That's ridiculous. I was right there.
You were in the first row.
Yeah, but that's...
Listen. You were great.
That's a critic.
This is something you're gonna have to get used to.
Believe me, I know.
- Spider-Man gets attacked all the time.
- This isn't about you.
It's about me.
- It's about my career.
- I know, and I'm just saying,
you can't let it bring you down.
You just gotta believe in yourself.
You pull yourself together,
- and you get right back on the horse.
- Don't give me the horse thing.
Try to understand how I feel.
It's just...
I look at these words,
and it's like my father wrote them.
All cars. All cars in the vicinity of 54th and 6th Ave,
please report. Crane out of control. Approach with caution.
Go get 'em, tiger.
Sorry.
Oh my God.
Seven *Atom* to Central. That crane's sheaves are off..
It's bigger than we thought.
We're gonna need a major mobilization right away.
Shutting down the accelerator! Now!
OK, Gwen.
I've got a secret. It's my call for ya.
What is that thing doing in my background?
Captain Stacey, the guys looks *kind short of it.
They can't shut down the crane.
Get Edison on the phone.
Have them kill the power of the whole block.
Are you all right?
It's coming back!
Oh my God. It's Gwen!
What?
What's she doing up there?
I don't know. I just saw her last night.
She said she had a modelling gig.
-Who are you?
- It's Brock, sir.
Eddie Brock, jr.
I work at the Daily Bugle.
And I'm dating your daughter.
-You OK?
- Yeah.
I'm fine.
Thank you.
Hey, Spidey, hold on. Bugle needs a photo.
-Thank God, you're OK.
- Daddy!
-Hey. I'm the new guy.
- New guy?
From now on, I'm gonna be taking shots of you for the Bugle.
So-- smile! Are you smiling?
Where's the other guy?
- Peter Parker?
Yeah, um, look, between you and me--
The guy's kind of an amateur.
Have you noticed, his stuff makes you look a little... bloated.
-Just a little chunky.
- OK...
Don't have to worry about that anymore, buddy.
Dazzeling.
Just a little something the boys in the ad department and I whipped up.
As you know, circulation of the Bugle has been pretty good.
Though not as good as the New York Times
or the Daily News
-or the Post or several other smaller...
- Get on with it, moron!
-What?
- Your blood pressure, Mr Jameson.
-Your wife told me to tell you to watch the anger.
- You tell my wife...
Thank you.
So, I propose this campaign:
"DAILY BUGLE" -- that's obvious.
"IT'S HIP, IT'S NOW" -- I came up with that one.
"IT'S WOW" -- that's actually Eric's.
"AND HOW!" -- that's me again.
Time to take your pill.
Not that one.
Drink plenty of water.
Thank you.
Continue.
He's busy.
Oh, no, I'm just here to talk to you, babe.
(- What's that smell?)
That's a little something called
"Nice 'n' Easy".
-What's on you?
- It's called "Go Away".
-That is the dumbest idea you've ever had. You have had some daunting...
- Blood pressure.
Hey, where are you going?
-Who are you?
- You hired him last week.
-Freelance.
- I did? What's that smell?
Brock, Sir. Edward Brock junior.
Wow, I really like that shirt.
Here. It's a crane accident. Check out the light source.
He likes my shirt.
-Hey, Betty.
- Hey, Pete. You better get in there.
A new guy. He's trying to sell some Spidey photos.
Uh. Thanks.
Parker! You're late! Maybe too late. Bruckner here beat ya to it.
-It's Brock, sir. Edward Brock junior.
- I got you this.
But he got me this.
-Wait. How'd you get that? I didn't see you.
- How'd you get that high?
Climbed. Nearly fell off a flagpole.
A flagpole?
-Which one do we use?
- I like Bernstein's.
-It's better.
- Cheaper, too.
Congratulations, son. We'll use your shot and pay you 50 bucks.
Uh-- all right, JJ. I'm your man.
I know more about what makes a good picture
than any photographer in this town.
See, photography, it's not just about
-- no offense -- flagpoles. Whatever.
It's about lighting. Composition. Drama.
I want a staff job, sir.
I have a girl that I intend to marry, and--
I have this stupid little dream of-- working with one of the greatest newspaper editors of our time.
J. Jonah Jameson.
Well, we do have an opening.
-Johnson quit, remember?
- You fired him.
- Whatever.
Wait a minute. I know what makes a good picture,
and I've been here for a long time. If there's a staff job,
Mr Jameson, I think I deserve it.
He's right, Jonah. Peter's been with us for years.
He's done a great job.
You want a staff job, and you want a staff job.
Anybody care about what I want?
I do.
- Shut up. Get out.
I want the public to see Spider-Man for the two-bit criminal he really is.
He's a fake. He's full of stickum.
Catch him in the act.
"Spider-Man with his hand in the cookie jar".
Whoever brings me that photo gets the job.
What are you waiting for, Chinese New Year? Go, go, go!
I'm on it, boss.
You'll never get that shot.
We'll see.
You know,
I guess one person can make a difference.
'Nuff said.
Welcome home, Harry.
Thank God you're all right.
Thanks, Bernard.
-Aperitif?
- Sure.
Got you a little homecoming present.
-Wha-- It's your old ball!
- Yeah.
Thanks, buddy.
We were pretty good in the backyard, weren't we?
We were terrible. And we tried out for the varsity team.
-Yeah, for the cheerleaders.
- Right.
Hey, do I have any girlfriends?
-I don't know.
- You don't?
-Hey Bernard, do I have any girlfriends?
- Not that I know of, sir.
That's a pretty cool pass, huh?
It's OK.
Looks like I'm not worrying for money.
No.
Well, I bet I can turn this little girlfriend thing around.
You know,
he always appreciated how you helped me through high school.
I just wish I could remember more about him.
He loved you.
That's the main thing.
Hey, let's watch the game in the kitchen.
- Get something to eat.
- OK.
Whoa, catch that!
Did you see that?
Still got the moves.
Yeah!
Why are you stopping?
What is she doing here?
Gary, you were supposed to call her agent.
Hi, honey.
We tried to reach you.
I'm sorry.
- One critic?
- No, all the papers, dear.
- Mary Jane, honey. Sit down. Let's explain it to you.
- If you like, we could say you became ill.
- That was so poorly handled.
- Yeah. Let's just rehearse.
All right, Spidey!
Excuse me, miss. Let me see that gorgeous smile.
Hi, Eddie.
You're so beautiful.
This is front page stuff.
I've got to practice. I'll see you later, OK?
- How about tonight?
- Not tonight.
Why not?
Think of that amazing-- night that we had.
We had a coffee, Eddie.
Hey, beautiful.
One more.
- Everything OK?
- Yeah. I'm fine.
You're not still mad at me, are you?
No, Peter. I'm proud of you.
Hey. I'm gonna be swingin' it from over there.
So you know where to look.
Give 'em a good show.
Don't worry about that review.
We're gonna be laughing about it tomorrow night.
- Promise.
- Yeah.
Isn't that that guy from that prison break?
He fits.
Hey you! Halt!
Cover the back!
Fire!
People of the city of New York, I am here today
because I fell 62 storeys
and someone caught me.
Someone who never asks for anything in return.
Someone who doesn't even want us to know who he is.
- Hey, MJ.
- Harry.
Where is Pete?
Um-- taking somebody's picture, I guess.
I'm so happy to see you. You look so good.
I've never felt better.
It's a weird feeling, not knowing New York.
Bump on the head, I'm just free as a bird.
- Will you bump me on the head?
- Bop.
Hey, Pete said you're in a play.
You came. You sent me flowers.
I did?
I'll come again tonight.
You can't.
I--I was let go.
What happened.
I wasn't very good.
You know, this is embarrassing, but...
I once wrote you a play in high school.
You wrote me a play?
- Yeah.
- Harry, that's the sweetest thing.
I ask you: When you're dropping without a parachute
or your store's being robbed
or your house is on fire,
who is it that brakes your fall, puts out the flames and saves your children?
Spider-Man!
They love me!
Then let's hear it! For your one and only friendly neighborhood...
Spider-Man!
[crowd shouting]
Kiss him! Kiss him!
Go ahead, lay it right on me.
- Really?
- Yeah, they'll love it.
Kiss him! Kiss him!
- No, Spider-Man, no!
Right...
Hope Pete's getting a shot of this.
- Hey, are you OK?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Jig's up, pal.
I don't want to hurt you.
- Leave now.
- I guess you haven't heard?
I'm the sheriff 'round these parts.
OK.
Where do all these guys come from?
Bonsoir. Le monsieur a-t-il un "reservation"?
- I'm sorry, I don't speak...
- But this is a French restaurant, non?
Oui.
- Name, please?
- Parker, Peter.
Ah. Here we are.
Table for two. Pekar.
- Parker.
- That is what I said.
Pekar.
Um, I have a request.
My girlfriend will be coming,
and I have this ring.
Ah. Allô.
Oh, so you want to pop the question tonight, hein?
Yes, and I want to do something very special.
I love it.
Romance.
I am French.
When I signal you, if you'd bring some champagne with the ring...
Inside bottom of her glass?
- Perfect.
- Magnifique.
Also I thought, at the same time
could the musicians
play this song?
Their favorite.
And take good care of the ring.