[Faint Whistling]
- [Gunfire]
- [Man #1 Over Radio]
We can't hold out much longer, sir.
General Hummel, you've got
to get us out of here now!
[Hummel]
I won't let you down.
I won't let you down, son.
Goddam it, sir!
How long do we have to wait?
I've lost 15 men already!
[Man #2]
Sir, they're lighting us up
like a firestorm!
This is Gen. Hummel.
You gotta get my men outta there!
[Man #3]
We don't have clearance
to go behind enemy lines, sir.
[Man #1]
They're not comin'for us,
are they, sir?
[Hummel]
Congressman Weaver
and esteemed members...
of the Special Armed
Services Committee,
I come before you
to protest a grave injustice.
[Marine]
Aim!
[Hummel]
It has to stop.
I miss you so much.
There's somethin'
I've gotta do, Barb.
Somethin' I couldn't do
while you were here.
I tried.
You know I tried everything,
and I still don't have their attention.
Let's hope this elevates
their thinking.
But whatever happens...
please don't
think less of me.
[Kissing Sound]
[Men Panting, Grunting]
Marine! Inform the garrison C.O.
that Gen. Hummel's coming on board...
- with a security inspection team.
- Yes, sir.
Sir, it's an honour
having you, sir.
Aah!
Huuh!
- Uuh!
- Oof!
Ya know, at least
we can get some...
[Continues, Indistinct]
- Yeah, I'll tell ya... Uuh!
- Ooh!
- [Bone Crunching]
- Aah! Aah!
Uuh!
I got the access card. We got
30 minutes till those darts wear off.
Move it!
The access card,
sir.
Let's do it.
[Beeping]
Twenty-four hundred
magazine check.
Man, it's wet out there.
Check me through,
will ya?
[Men Grunting, Groaning]
[Assailant]
Clear!
- I want 16, Major.
- [Major] Move it!
[Grunts]
Evac! Seal the door!
- [Man] No, no, no!
- [Evac Commander]
Come on, man, seal it! Seal it!
No-o-o!
Lemme outta here! Oh, God!
[Muted]
Lemme outta here! God!
Clear out.
Get outta here!
[Pained Gasping]
- [Gasping] Please!
- Sorry.
[Gurgling]
Let's move out.
[Technician]
Two more CCs of acetylene chloride.
That'll be five dollars,
Isherwood.
I suck.
[Phone Ringing]
- You guys have too much time
on your hands.
- Yes!
She's here. Bring it to me now.
Thank you, Phil!
- [Ripping Packaging]
- What's that?
Why'd you get it sent here?
Carla wouldn't approve. She thinks
it's dumb to spend $600 on an LP.
Carla's right. Why don't you just
spend $ 13.00 on a CD, man?
First of all,
it's because I'm a Beatlemaniac.
And second, these sound better.
- [Alarm Blaring]
- Could be serious.
Could be sarin gas.
Dog out at JFK caught a whiff
of something in this package...
postmarked to
a Bosnian refugee camp.
It could be detergent; :
it could be sarin gas.
Bosnian refugee camp?
Half a million Serbians
reside in the US, Marvin.
Serbians don't like Bosnians.
You guys wanna
get suited up?
- Bring the cockroaches?
- Got 'em.
We have air lock, Stanley.
You're all set to go.
October 1, 0900 hours.
Agent Stanley Goodspeed,
Agent Trainee Marvin Isherwood...
initiating exam
of wooden crate.
Suspicion of
sarin gas inside.
- Marvin, sarin is a...
- GB aerosol.
That is correct.
I see we have some dirty magazines.
Stone Age Cavegirls In the Raw.
Kinky.
And, uh... Not a good sign.
Helloo-oo-oo, little baby doll.
Lookit, Stan.
- Hi, there, Stanley!
- Marvin, don't!
- Hiya, Stan!
- [Hissing]
Shit! Move back!
Move back!
- Powering exhaust.
- [Technician] Hang on, guys.
We'll have that room cleared
in 50 seconds. You're going to be okay.
Jesus Christ!
Okay, I've got some bad news
and some really bad news.
The bad news is that the gas
is corrosive and it's eating our suits.
- It's all over my hand, man.
- The really bad news...
is there's enough C-4 explosive
and poison gas to blow the whole
chamber and kill everybody...
- in the building.
- [Technician] Detonation two minutes.
- Everybody, out of the room, now!
- Seal us inside.
Where are the sprinklers,
Lonner?
The acid's eating my su... It's eating
my fucking suit, all right? Shit.
Just wash us off.
Where are my sprinklers?
We're working on it.
It's coming. It's just a flow problem.
Well, it's a pretty big
friggin' problem, Lonner. Fix it now!
We're working on it! How much time
do you have on that detonator?
- A minute, ten.
- Hey, look at this!
[Technician]
We're gonna have the room clear.
- Tell 'em to take the atropine, now.
- The atropine, Isherwood.
- What?
- Where's my water, Lonner? One minute!
Marvin, the atropine! Now! Inject it
in your heart before your suit melts.
Shh-it!
- [Technician] Make him take it too!
- Where's that water?
- Get that away from me!
- Come on, Phil, fix it,
for Christ's sake!
- Take the atropine now,
Stan, for Christ's sake!
- We're fucked.
- [Stanley] Poison's mixing.
- What the fuck are you
waiting for, Stanley?
- You take the fucking needle now!
- Fucking shit, oh fucking shit...
- Forty seconds!
- If that suit melts...
If you die, we all die!
Inject your heart...
- and then diffuse the bomb!
- Come on, just do it, Stan!
Shit, what if I miss my heart?
I can't see shit!
- [Technician] Do it now!
- Look how big this is.
You want me to stick this into my heart?
Are you fucking nuts?
The sprinkler's coming.
It's coming.
Okay, here we go, man!
[Technician]
Sprinkler activated!
How much time left?
Twenty seconds.
We're not gonna make it.
- [Beeping]
- Fifteen.
[Whispering]
Oh, come on!
Clear!
[Panting]
Get me the fuck out
of this gas chamber.
I almost stabbed myself
in the heart with this thing!
- ? Please lock me away?
- ?? [Plucking Discordant Notes]
- Stan?
- Hey, darlin'.
- ? And don't allow the day here inside?
- Hi, baby.
? Where I hide
with my loneliness?
I had such
an interesting day today.
- ? I don't care what they say?
- Yeah, I had kind of
an interesting day myself.
- ? I won't stay in a world
without love? [Continues]
- Okay, you go first.
Oh, just some terrorists decide to send
a little care package... box o' goodies...
- which had to be neutralized
before blowing up the office.
- ?? [Plucks Discordant Note]
So, I took the rest of
the day off. Glass of wine,
a little guitar... just relaxin'.
- Wow.
- I mean it, honey.
The world is being
Fed-Ex'd to hell on a handcart.
I really believe that anyone
who's even thinking about having
a child in this world...
is coldly considering
an act of cruelty.
I know, I'm rambling, I'm complaining.
I'm sorry. What's your news, baby?
- I'm pregnant.
- I'm sorry?
I'm pregnant.
- [Chuckling]
- [Laughs]
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
- Is that all you're
gonna say is "wow"?
- You're pregnant?
- Three weeks.
How do you know?
I mean, h-how do you know?
[Sighs]
Blue.
Just turned blue,
so I went to the doctor.
- Well, you didn't mean
what you just said, did you?
- When?
Just right now, when you were talking
about bringing a child into the world...
- and having it be an act of... cruelty.
- I meant it at the time.
Stanley, at the time? You said it
seven and a half seconds ago.
Well... gosh, kind of
a lot's happened since then.
Look, we're not even married.
I know. It's funny
you should mention that.
- It's funny?
- Do you love me?
- Of course I love you.
- Good.
- Will you marry me?
- Whoa, whoa, hey...
Marriage Police, pull over.
Come on, Stanley.
I'm proposing to you right now.
[Man]
The Rock is the most famous and was
the most feared prison ever built.
Is it really true
that there's never been an escape?
Ah, that's true. From 1936 until '63
when the prison closed,
there were 14 attempts.
No one is believed to have made it
to shore... alive, at least.
[Conversation, Indistinct]
Uh, hey, hey, fellas. I'm sorry,
but tourists are not allowed back here.
- [Gun Cocking]
- I don't really give a shit.
You give a shit?
- No. Come here, fruity.
- Move!
- Hey, girls? Hi.
You all havin' a good time?
- [Girls Together] Yeah.
Will you do something for me?
It's really... It's really important.
I need you to tell your teacher
that you need to get back on
the boat and go home right now.
[Guide]
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Broadway!
This cell block housed...
the most awesome scum
in America.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I, Ranger Bob,
cordially invite you
to become inmates of Alcatraz...
temporarily, of course, heh!
On the line!
Pretty tight quarters,
aren't they, huh?
Like being a caged animal.
Spend a couple of years
in there...
- What's the matter, fellas?
Something wrong with the tour?
- Tour's over, Bob.
What kind of
fucked-up tour is this?
Gen. Hummel, Captains Frye
and Darrow reporting, sir.
Welcome to the Rock, gentlemen.
Land the choppers on the
back side and deploy as planned.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Aye, aye, sir. Move out!
I'm not allowed
to carry a gun!
Oh, you're not allowed to carry a gun?
I got a goddamned gun!
If I'd had known this was
gonna happen, I'd have brought
my motherfuckin' gun! Help!
All right, gentlemen, this'll
be our new home. Tom, I want
my command centre right here.
- I want coms up.
- Roger that, sir.
Put the satellite over there.
I want to be up at 1600. Let's move it.
- [Electronic Beeping]
- Systems up.
Possible penetration point in the shower
room. We're setting anti-intrusion.
I brought a personal touch, sir.
It's an antimotion trembler device.
It's custom-made. Nobody knows about it
and nobody expects it.
- What's it do?
- We head-fake 'em with the laser beam,
and then if they disturb
Mr Backup here...
[Chuckles] we own 'em.
- [Gunshot]
- [Tourists Screaming]
Ladies and gentlemen, you're
being detained against your
will. For that I apologize.
It is not our intention
in any way to harm you.
You will not be detained one
minute longer than is necessary
for us to complete our mission.
[Evac Commander]
Attention on deck!
[Sighs]
Stand easy, men.
Make no mistake about it, gentlemen.
We are now in harm's way.
For Major Baxter and I, this is the last
campaign in a career dating back...
to Tet '68.
Likewise for Captain Hendrix
and Gunnery Sergeant Crisp,
who cut their teeth
under my command in Desert Storm.
Capt. Frye, Capt. Darrow, this is my
first operational situation with you...
and your men, and I have to say thus far
your conduct reflects your reputations.
- Thank you, General.
- Thank you, sir.
We have achieved our position
through poise, precision and audacity.
To this we must
now add resolve.
We'll be branded as traitors;
the gravest capital crime.
Punishable by death.
Couple hundred years ago, a few guys
named Washington, Jefferson and Adams...
were branded as traitors
by the British.
And now they're called
patriots.
In time, so shall we.
God willing, in less than 48 hours we
will evacuate this island in gunships...
under cover of hostages
and VX gas warheads.
Your destination:
a nonextradition-treaty country.
You will each be paid a fee
of $ 1 million for services rendered.
But you can never again
set foot on your native soil.
- Can you live with that?
- [All] Yes, sir!
The men of Marine Force Recon
are selected...
to carry out illegal operations
throughout the world.
When they don't come home, their
families are told fairy tales
about what happened to them...
and denied compensation.
Well, I have choked
on these lies my entire career.
Well, here and now
the lies stop!
God be with all of you.
Man your positions, men.
[Phone Ringing, Receiver Clanking]
This is FBI Director Womack.
Director... be advised,
81... I say again,
81 civilians are under my control
as of this moment.
You are to take measures to assure this
remains a need-to-know classified fact.
- Who is this?
- Mr Director, you have
a very serious problem.
A battery of VX gas rockets
is presently deployed to deliver...
a highly lethal strike on the population
of the San Francisco Bay area.
I will call again at 0100 hours
to state my demands.
- I wanna know who I'm talking to.
- This is Brigadier General...
- Francis X. Hummel, United States
Marine Corps from Alcatraz... out.
- [Receiver Slams]
I'll cancel
your reservations.
Get the Pentagon and call
the San Francisco office.
It seems Alcatraz
was just reopened.
[Man]
Last night, Gen. Hummel using
brutal but nonlethal force...
under the guise of
a security exercise, walked off
with 15 VX poison-gas rockets.
He lost one of his own men
in the process.
That's Gen. Hummel in Vietnam.
I think he was a major at the time.
Three tours in Vietnam,
Panama, Grenada, Desert Storm; :
three Purple Hearts, two Silver Stars
and the Congressional Medal of...
Jesus. This man is a hero.
Well, I think "legend" might be
a better description, Mr Sinclair.
Well, now we can add kidnapping
and extortion to his list of accolades.
Mr Sinclair,
Gen. Hummel is a man of honour.
General, it's him.
- Frank, it's Al Kramer.
- Hi, Al. How ya doin'?
I don't know, Frank.
Why don't you tell me?
There are a lot of very,
very worried people here, Frank.
I'll come straight
to the point.
Eighty-three Force
Reconnaissance Marines have died
under my various commands.
Forty-seven in Northern Laos
and Southern China.
Southern China? We never admitted
we sent troops into China.
Who is this?
Identify yourself.
White House Chief of Staff
Hayden Sinclair, General.
How old are you,
Chief of Staff Sinclair?
- I'm 33.
- Well, Mr Sinclair,
you've probably got no fucking idea
what I'm talking about.
By your ninth birthday
I was runnin' black ops into China,
and my men were responsible
for over 200 enemy kills.
Now put some rigging tape
over Mr Sinclair's mouth.
- He's wasting my time.
- Ah, you want to continue, Frank?
Remember Operation
Desert Storm?
Those surgical hits made by our
smart bombs covered so well on CNN?
It was my men on the ground
that made those hits possible
by lasing the targets.
Twenty of them were left
to rot outside Baghdad
after the conflict ended.
No benefits were paid to their
families. No medals conferred.
These men died for their country
and they weren't even given
a goddam military burial.
The situation
is unacceptable.
You will transfer $ 100 million
from the Grand Cayman Red Sea
Trading Company account...
to an account I designate.
From these funds, reparations
of $ 1 million will be paid...
to each of
the 83 marines' families.
The rest of the funds
I will disperse at my discretion.
Do I make myself clear?
Except for the Red Sea
Trading Company. What is that?
- Identify yourself.
- This is FBI Director Womack, General.
It's a slush fund where the Pentagon
keeps proceeds from illegal arms sales.
Jesus, Frank!
This is classified information.
You alert the media,
I launch the gas.
You refuse payment,
You've got 40 hours...
till noon, day after tomorrow...
to arrange transfer of the money.
I am aware of your countermeasure.
You know and I know
it doesn't stand a chance.
- Hummel from Alcatraz, out.
- [Receiver Slams]
[Womack]
All right.
We have to identify the hostages
and contact each of their families.
Tell 'em somethin'. Make up a story,
and we've got to keep this undercover.
If this comes out, the city of
San Francisco will be in chaos.
I am talking anarchy.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
What is the potential casualty rate...
for a single rocket armed
with VX poison gas, Gen. Peterson?
Sixty or seventy.
Well, that's...
that's not so bad.
Thousand.
Seventy thousand dead.
- Oh.
- One teaspoon of this hits the floor,
it's lethal up to...
100 feet.
One teaspoon of this shit
detonated in the atmosphere...
will kill every living organism
in an eight-block radius.
Get the point?
What did Hummel mean by
your "countermeasure," General?
Standard poison is countered
by napalm. It burns it up,
consumes it upon detonation.
Now, the problem with VX poison gas
is that it's designed specifically...
to withstand napalm; that's
where thermite plasma comes in.
- Gen. Peterson?
- Thermite plasma incendiary systems...
can burn hot enough to consume VX,
but they're still in the test phase.
It's not operational.
Hummel knows this.
- We are dealing with
one smart son of a bitch.
- What's it going to take...
to equip a flight of F-18s
with thermite plasma
within the next 36 hours?
- An act of God.
- Excuse me?
All right. We can try.
But I strongly urge you to consider the
use of this as a secondary initiative.
Then we have to go to our
primary initiative. Uh, Admiral?
Sir, I'd like to bring in our SEAL
ground commander, Cmdr. Anderson.
Mr Womack, who is your best
chemical/biological man?
- [Creaking]
- [Stanley, Grunting]
That's interesting.
- Oh, yeah.
- That's very compelling.
[Both Moaning]
Ahh, you like my pigtails?
Oh, yeah.
Pigtails are naughty.
- Naughty, naughty...
- [Moans]
You're just an amaretto cream
with peach sorbet persuasion.
- [Phone Rings]
- This isn't happening.
- [Breathlessly]
No, Stan. Don't answer it.
- This isn't happening!
- No, just don't answer it. It's okay.
- I have to.
- It's the office, baby.
They know I'm home.
- Oh-h-h-h!
- How could they possibly know
that you're home?
- It's the FBI.
[Ringing Stops, Receiver Clicks]
- Stanley! Tsk!
- Goodspeed.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah, I'll be...
I'll be down...
- Yeah, downstairs in ten minutes.
- No, you won't.
[Phone Beeps Off]
- I have to go to San Francisco.
- No, you don't.
Stanley. No, you do not have
to go to San Francisco.
Are you kidding me? Right now, you need
stay here and talk to me about things.
- I've got to go, baby.
- [Disgusted Groan] I am Catholic.
Do you realize that?
I am pregnant and I am unmarried...
and this causes
a serious problem for me.
I cannot believe you.
[Sighs]
N-N-No.
- [Kissing Sounds]
- I love you.
I will marry you.
I just didn't plan on this, that's all.
- [Relieved Laugh]
- Come to San Francisco.
- Really?
- Yeah. I'm sure it's just
a training exercise.
Check into the hotel,
order up some champagne...
- And we'll finish what we started?
- Exactly.
- Baby, you gonna marry me?
- You know it.
[Laughing]
You're gonna marry me!
Oh, honey, come on.
- Just a really quick one.
- [Groaning] Oh! Oh! I gotta go!
A nighttime airdrop incursion
is out, due to the full moon.
Likewise a frontal
seaside attack.
If we're compromised and shots
are fired, Hummel might launch.
Our only alternative is an attack
from within the prison.
We penetrate the island through
the tunnels under the prison
buildings undetected...
and emerge in its centre; : that way,
we can jump the marines from behind.
And if we're lucky, take their
rocket positions without a shot fired.
- I don't understand. You-You've
studied the architectural plans?
- They're useless.
Alcatraz has been ripped up
and rebuilt for years.
Under there is a maze of shit.
There's no question, gentlemen.
We need firsthand intelligence
of the tunnel systems.
- So what about the former warden?
- Died in 1979.
All the guards
we contacted were useless.
Umm... there is someone who,
I think, can help us.
This is for the sake
of national security.
No, it's the sake of national
security that got us here
in the first place 33 years ago.
I knew... I knew someday this would
come back to bite us. Forget it.
- He does not exist.
- He does exist!
We just chose to forget him
for 30 years. We locked him
up and threw away the key.
Oh, and a lot of
goddam good it did us.
He broke out of two maximum security
prisons, and if he hits the streets...
He's not gonna "hit the streets," Jim!
[Chuckles]
Thirty years ago he was
a highly-trained SAS operative.
He is my age now, for Christ's
sake. I have to get up three
times a night to take a piss.
[Quietly]
We can't risk letting him out.
He's a professional escape artist.
[Lock Turning, Door Opening]
[Womack]
Oh, here is now.
- Ah. Neat, uh...
- Yeah.
- Neat, neat plane.
- Dr Goodspeed. James Womack.
- Pleasure meeting you, sir. Thank you.
- Welcome.
You come very highly recommended.
BA, Columbia;
MA, PhD,
Johns Hopkins.
Biochemistry/ toxicology?
Well, I'm one of those fortunate
people who like my job, sir.
Got my first chemistry set when
I was seven. Blew my eyebrows off.
We never saw the cat again.
Been into it ever since. [Chuckles]
- What do you know about VX gas?
- Liquid.
Failed pesticide discovered
by mistake in 1952.
Uh, actually it's kind of
like champagne that way.
The Franciscan monks thought...
they were making white wine, somehow
the bottle carbonated, voila, champagne,
- and then the whole thing...
- The gas, Dr Goodspeed.
It's very, very horrible, sir.
It's one of those things
we wish we could disinvent.
This isn't
a training exercise, is it?
No, Dr Goodspeed,
it's not a training exercise.
[Man Clears Throat]
[Siren Blurting]
- Ernest.
- Good morning, Director.
This is Ernest Paxton, agent
in charge of the West Coast
operation. Dr Goodspeed.
- Pleasure to meet you.
- How do you do, sir?
It's been a fairly interesting day
so far. The prisoner's here. Shall we?
Now, my boys, they haven't been
able to find a file on this guy.
Who is he, anyway, sir?
His name is John Mason,
a British national...
incarcerated
on Alcatraz in 1962;
escaped in '63.
- I was under the impression
that no one escaped Alcatraz, sir.
- Paxton, don't argue!
[Womack] This man
has no identity, not in the
United States or Great Britain.
He does not exist.
Understand?
I want one thing:
how he escaped the Rock...
specifically, the route he took
through the island's bowels.
[Man]
Papers are in order, sir.
[Womack]
We're prepared to offer him
a full pardon.
And Paxton, no strong-arming Mason.
I know him too well.
Well, if you know him
then why don't you question him?
No, he'll remember me. I don't want
his anger clouding the issue.
All right,
I'll take care of him.
[Latch Clinking]
Mr Mason, I'm special agent
in charge Ernest Baxter.
In charge of what? Fucking me over
for another three decades?
I don't know anything about your
previous matters. I'm here because...
a special situation exists that we feel
you might be able to help us with.
Now, what might that be? I've been
in jail longer than Nelson Mandela,
so maybe you want me
to run for president.
- Not exactly.
- Ah, pity.
I feel rather like
Alcamedes.
- Who?
- Alcamedes. He was imprisoned
by his king in ancient Greece.
Like Sir Walter Raleigh.
Same fate.
- James the First.
- Even someone as bright as you...
must be aware that, uh, there's
a certain pattern emerging here.
Alexander Solzhenitsyn?
Yeah, I heard of him. Didn't he
play hockey for the fuckin' Redwings?
- That's the chap.
- Get this straight, Pops.
I don't like you any more
than you like me.
But I'm here to make you
a legitimate offer.
You wanna hear
what I have to say or not?
By all means,
dear Paxton, by all means.
[Paxton]
We got a problem in a place
that I think you know.
- There's a hostage situation
on Alcatraz.
- Hostage?
Eighty-one tourists.
The Rock has become
a tourist attraction?
Why don't we cut the shit, huh?
You know the Rock. You broke out.
- Yes, successfully.
- Yeah.
So why don't you do yourself
a favour while you're helpin' us.
I mean, it'd be nice to get out
ofjail while you're still vertical.
Hmm? While you got a little lead
left in your pencil?
While I'm considering
your offer,
I want a suite
at the Fairmont Hotel.
You know, I'm here
to cut you a deal.
I am not here to bend over
and take it up the ass from you.
Here. Here's a quarter.
Do yourself a favour.
Call your lawyer.
You're goin' back to jail.
- You're sending him back to jail?
- I'm not sending him anywhere.
- I'm just givin' him
somethin' to think about.
- With all due respect, sir,
I don't think we have time for him
to just sit around and think about it.
- Oh, really?
- No, Goodspeed's right.
You, go talk to him.
- Me? Sir, I'm not qualified for that.
- Yes.
- You're an FBI agent.
- What is your specialty again?
- Chemical weapons.
- Don't mention that!
- You want me to lie?
- Yeah, lie.
We got less than 24 hours.
Give it a shot.
Okay.
Hiya!
I'm an agent with the, uh,
eh, Federal... FBI.
Uh... Eh, well, my...
I'm Stanley Goodspeed.
- But of course you are.
- At least he got his name right.
- Of course I am.
- And you have an emergency.
- That's right.
- [Chair Thumps]
- And you need my help.
- Exactly right.
- [Exhales]
- Coffee.
No, no, I'm fine,
thank you.
Offer me coffee.
Oh, yes. Well, that was, in fact,
going to be my next...
Could we get a cup of coffee
in here, please?
And offer...
to take these off.
Mr Mason, really.
- All kidding aside...
- As a gesture of your good faith.
- Prisoner requests
to have his handcuffs taken off.
- [Whispering] No, no, no!
Look, why don't you go ahead and have
his handcuffs taken off, please?
Well, I guess that's
one way to go.
This is a pardon and release contract
from the Attorney General's office.
Now, it makes you a free man...
provided you cooperate.
So, if you'll just,
ah, sign, uh, eh,
- uh, where it says...
- "Signature"?
- That's... Yes. "Signature."
- Well...
Timeo Danaos
et dona ferentes.
"I fear the Greeks
even when they bring gifts."
Oh, an educated man.
That rules out the possibility
of you being a field agent.
In point of fact,
I am a field agent, Mr Mason.
- Really.
- Yes.
- In which field?
- Antiterrorism.
Then you're trained in weaponry,
explosives and mortal combat.
Well trained.
- [Slaps Table]
- Then it's the Fairmont Hotel.
Okay.
I want a suite...
a shower, a shave...
and the feel of a suit.
May I also suggest a...
a haircut.
- Am I out of style?
- Unless you're a 20-year-old
guitarist from Seattle.
- [Inhales] It's a grunge thing.
- Grunge?
Yeah. Well, uh, uh...
Okay. Thank you very much.
All right. Call the Fairmont.
Close the floor if necessary,
but I want him sealed off
and he gets two hours max.
[Coin Clinking]
- Great job, Goodspeed.
- [Paxton] Why don't you
throw in a trip to Tahiti...
- while you're at it?
- I'll deliver this
to the Attorney General.
Ah, no, you'll give it to me.
Give it to me, Reynolds. And
take Attorney Reynolds outside.
There's a car waiting for you.
Thank you.
That's a signed federal document, sir.
Isn't that illegal?
You're not acquainted
with the full facts, Goodspeed.
With all due respect, sir, I'd like
clarification. I gave that man my word.
Damn it! You're on a need-to-know
basis, and you don't need to know!
It's uh, eh, kind of curious,
but, uh...
Sir Walter Raleigh, Alcamedes,
Solzhenitsyn, they, uh...
Well, they were all
wrongfully imprisoned.
[Screeching]
[Alarm Sounding]
Womack!
Now, why am I not surprised?
You piece of shit!
- Hey, peace! Peace!
- [Guard Shouting, Indistinct]
[Sirens Wailing]
[Punching Keypad]
[Ringing, Carla's Voice]
Hey, we're not home. Leave a message.
- [Answering Machine Beeps]
- Hi, darling, it's, uh,
[Clears Throat] it's me.
Uh, listen, don't come
to San Francisco. I repeat, do not...
- come to San Francisco.
- [Phone Beeps]
- Stanley, no! Like hell I'm not comin'!
- Carla! Carla!
- Wait! Carla...
- [Punches Keypad, Ringing]
Who's Carla? And why don't you
want her to come to San Francisco?
[Ringing Continues]
- You're on a need-to-know basis,
and you don't need to know.
- [Barks]
- [Agent]
Watch it, he'll bite you!
- [Agents Laughing]
Good. Mobile command
is fully operational.
We'll be there
in approximately two hours.
- I'm not armed, sir.
- Right.
- I am unarmed, sir.
- Well, where's your issue?
I left it in my... [Clears Throat]
uh, my sock drawer.
[Scoffs]
A gun?
For what?
You're a chemical freak.
[Chuckles]
I'm a chemical super-freak,
actually, but I still need a gun.
Give 'im a goddam gun.
Have you fired one of those things
since the academy?
- [Recording]
? wear some flowers?
- [Mason]? If you're going?
- ? In your hair?
- ? To San Francisco
Don't forget to wear flowers?
- ? In your hair?
- ? If you're going?
[Mason, Recording]
? If you're going to San Francisco?
- ? You're sure to meet some?
- ? You're gonna meet?
- ? Gentle people there?
- ? Some gentle?
- ? People there?
- ? And you come for...?
- ? If you're going to San Francisco?
- ? [Recording Continues]
- [Woman] Fairmont Hotel.
- Heh, uh, room service?
Uh, this...
this is the penthouse.
Do you do snacks,
drinks, huh?
[Man]
Hello-o-o.
- You the barber?
- No. Stylist.
Barber.
- [Buzzing]
- Just clippers, no scissors.
No scissors? You've got to be
kidding me, no scissors.
I mean, did they tell Picasso
"no brush"?
- With scissors,
this man could kill you.
- I can't cut...
anyone's balls off
with a trimmer, now can I?
Why don't we do this outside?
Get some sun.
Oh! Who did this to you? This is
just not right. In fact, it's nasty.
- Well, it's a... grunge thing.
- Well, it's some kind of thing.
Do you think we have time for a sea kelp
protein pack and maybe some colour?
- No.
- Okay. [Disgusted Sigh]
- Not very nice, is he?
- [Clippers Buzzing]
- No, he's not.
- ?? [Stylist Humming]
[Frank Sinatra]
? 'Cause I'm leavin'?
- ? On a jet plane?
- Hey, somebody ordered it.
Can't let it go to waste.
- ? Don't know when
I'll be back again?
- Don't you ever stop eatin'?
- Not when it's free.
- ?? [Continues]
- We're supposed to be on duty.
- Hey, don't worry. He's an old man.
The boss is watchin' 'im. Come on,
have... Try some of this lobster.
- Mm-hmm.
- My secretary here will settle the bill.
So, what do you have in store
for me, Womack, when this is over?
You'll get your life back,
Mason.
But you could've given me
my life back years ago.
Why should I trust you now?
You've got my word.
Will you shake on it?
- [Mason Grunts]
- [Womack Screaming]
- [Gasps]
- Freeze, mister!
[Womack]
Oh, man!
Help!
Drop the gun...
or I drop your boss.
- You will not!
- Aaah! Get!
- He's gettin' very heavy.
- Then pull 'im up!
Aah! Uuh!
Please don't.
- [Womack] Ohh!
- [Whimpering]
Help! Shit!
- ? Hold me like you'll never...?
- Come on, have a scallop.
Come on, catch.
[Womack]
Ohh!
[Whimpering]
Ooh-ooh!
- You hoist him in!
- Yaah! Oh!
Help! Help! Help!
Where's Mason? Where's Mason?
Hang on!
- Mason's gone!
- Gone?
- [Agent] Clear!
- [Stylist Gasps]
Living room's clear!
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- [Elevator Bell Dings]
All units, this is Caretaker.
We have a signal six. He's in the hotel!
Okay, I don't wanna know
nothin'. I never saw you throw
that gentleman off the balcony.
All I care about is,
are you happy with your haircut?
Aah! Easy! Aah!
- [Grunting]
- Watch it, you fuckhead!
You're gonna pull my arm out!
[Waiter]
Watch out! Aah!
[Shouting In Native Language]
- Uuh!
- Watch it!
- [Man] Hey, watch it!
- He's right over there!
Uuh! Ah!
Uuh!
Hey! Uuh! Ooh!
This is my Humvee. I don't want
any dings, dents or scratches,
or I'll have your ass. Hey!
Hey! Stop! Hey!
[Tyres Squealing,
Sirens Wailing]
- [Pedestrians Screaming]
- [Man] I was inside
the bedroom with Jack Powell!
- [Agent] Hey, call the guard!
- [Agent] Go!
FBI.
[Engine Revving,
Tyres Screeching]
Whoo!
- [Sirens Continue]
- Whoa! Whoa!
Suspect is in a black Humvee
heading west on California.
Speed approximately
70 miles per hour.
Get out of the way!
I want a net put on this
son of a bitch, you hear me?
[Screeching]
This guy's hittin' every fuckin'
thing in sight tryin' to block us!
Uuh!
Aah!
I hope you're insured!
- Oh, well, why not?
- [Engine Revving Higher]
You're goin' down!
[Phone Ringing]
- [Receiver Clicks, Phone Beeps]
- Hello?
[Humvee Owner]
Sie haben meine Hummer gestolen!
I'm only borrowing
your Humvee!
[Mason]
Information?
San Francisco.
Uh, Jade Angelou.
That's A-N-G...
[Bell Ringing]
Welcome aboard, y'all.
How y'all doin' today?
Hang on!
- [Riders Screaming]
- Holy shit!
[Horn Honking]
Whoa-oa!
- Oh, no!
- [People Screaming]
We're gonna crash!
Save yourselves!
Oh, my baby!
Oh, no!
Oh, no.
Oh! Oh, God.
Oh, God!
Hey, man.
You just fucked up your Ferrari.
- [Conductor] Oh, no!
Baby's goin'down in flames!
- It's not mine.
- [Chuckles, Grunts]
- Neither is this.
[Engine Revving,
Tyres Screeching]
Damn! This sucks!
Where's that son of a bitch at?
I'm gonna hunt him down!
That motherfucker ain't safe nowhere!
- [Ringing]
- Chem Weapons, Isherwood.
Marvin, look up
Wolfburg Federal Penitentiary.
The inmate is Mason, John.
- [Tapping At Keyboard]
- Hey, Stan, listen. I'm gettin'
out of this government shithole.
I'm goin' over to Orkin
to design Roach Motels. Cool, huh?
Look, I just stole
a kid's motorcycle.
I'm not really feeling too good
about it, okay? Wolfburg, got it?
Yeah, I got it. All right,
Magrane, Masconi, Masters. No Mason.
Go to February '76. Who was transferred
to Wolfburg from San Quentin?
- [Beeping]
- [Marvin] This is weird.
They got medical records,
they got place of birth... Glasgow...
Uh, but they don't
have a name.
Uh, wait a minute,
wait a minute!
They have next of kin, a Jade Angelou
of 32 Stenson Drive, San Francisco.
[Motorcycle Approaching]
Jade?
No, I'm Stacy,
Jade's friend.
Were you afraid
to come alone?
Yeah.
[Whispers]
It's okay.
I'll be over here
if you need me.
- Last photograph I had of you...
you were about ten.
- Yeah?
Well, I found a picture of you among
my mom's things... when she died.
Oh, yeah? Well, uh...
- Why don't we take a walk?
- I got 'im. Palace of Fine Arts.
Your mother, uh... [Sighs]
Ya know, well, she was very special.
Yeah, she was.
But I don't think we should romanticize
what happened between you and her.
Meeting in a bar
after a Led Zeppelin concert.
Head out,
and I was the result.
Well, I'd like to think
it would've led somewhere, if only...
If only what?
Six federal marshals hadn't kicked down
her door and dragged you back to prison?
I'm sorry.
[Mason]
It's all right.
- So they let you out?
- Yeah.
That's good.
[Sighs]
What did you do?
"I do"?
Jade, I don't have
a great deal of time here.
But I'll be coming back,
and, uh,
- maybe we can... -
- What? We can what?
You know...
you're almost the only evidence
that I exist.
But I don't know you.
That's what I want
to change, eh?
I've rehearsed this speech a thousand
times on the chance that we would meet.
Here we are...
and I'm lost.
[Chuckles]
Well, I don't know how I'm
supposed to be feeling either.
Jade, I'm not an evil man.
If you can believe that,
then it's a start.
Okay.
[Sirens Wailing
In Distance]
Is this about you?
You broke out of prison again,
didn't you?
- Why did you come to me?
- FBI, ma'am.
Your father's working with us.
He's helping us resolve
a dangerous situation.
- He is?
- Yes, ma'am.
[Sighs]
Well, gee whiz, John, I guess
we oughta get goin', huh?
Whatever you say, Stanley.
Thank you for that.
You could've handled it differently.
What do you say we cut
the chitchat, a-hole?
You almost got me killed twice,
and my jaw hurts like hell.
- Good.
- Cocksucker!
If I had my way, you would be shipped
back to Wolfburg in leg irons...
and caged like an animal for the
rest of your natural fuckin'life!
You wrecked half the city!
[Electronic Beepings, Phones Ringing,
Low Voices Chattering]
- [Man]
Give me a hand with the system.
- Now, tell me about the tunnels.
If you know the system it will
take you wherever you need to go.
All right, there's an intake pipe here,
below low tide. Is that our best access?
- Yes, that's exactly where I came out.
- Then beneath the cistern...
There's a connection to the abandoned
septic system. How many feet is that?
Ehh... 57 paces.
Where do we go from there?
[Muttering]
Where do you go from there?
That's a good question.
I have no idea.
- What?
- [Stifled Laugh]
I mean... I'll know
when we're all inside.
No. You're not goddam goin'.
Show us on the blueprints.
I can't! [Chuckles]
My blueprint was in my head.
I was underground
for three days in the dark,
just waiting for the tides
to be right.
But don't worry.
It'll all come back to me.
You're not going anywhere,
Mason.
Wait a second.
Now, this piece of work
might be the only chance
those people over there have.
If he's not going, then why the hell
did we get him out of jail?
- He's smart.
- I got him out to get you
people in, not go with you.
If it's the only way of getting
the intelligence I need,
- then he goes.
- He'll fuck with you.
You compromise my men's lives,
and I'll bury you out there.
Now, Womack... you're between
the Rock and a hard case.
Hmm.
How's your bowling arm?
Dr Goodspeed, the goal
is to take out the launchers...
then neutralize
the VX chemical rounds.
Well, we know the poison's being
kept in the prison morgue from
the satellite thermal imaging...
which is right here;
these colourized dots.
Have you ever actually seen
one of these devices?
No, sir,
but I've studied them.
I should really begin briefing your
guys on defusing and detoxification.
Got a really neat layout here
of the chem round as well as the
rocket, so let's get rolling.
That won't be necessary.
Oh, it's very necessary, sir.
The power of this chemical is way
beyond anything you can imagine.
An ecological disaster,
sir.
Plus, the devices themselves
are complicated.
That's why you're
coming with us.
I am?
You're the expert.
What's your problem?
You mean I'm going...
going out there... under the water?
Well, earlier today you wanted a gun.
Now you're getting a gun and a wet suit.
Have you ever been
in a combat situation?
- Define "combat," sir.
- Shep?
An incursion underwater to
retake an impregnable fortress
held by an elite team...
of US Marines in possession of
81 hostages and 15 guided rockets...
armed with VX poison gas.
Oh. In that case, no, sir.
Excuse me.
[Retching]
[Gagging, Coughing]
- Here.
- Ah, thank you.
[Gasping]
You don't look
too good.
In fact,
you look like shit.
My stomach's doing
hula hoops around my ass.
You all right? I mean, you gonna
make it through this thing?
I don't know.
I always expected something
like this was going to happen
but nothing prepares you for it.
Now I'm...
I'm responsible...
for a whole city.
[Faucet Creaks,
Water Splashing]
- [Turns Faucet Off]
- Look, I know this isn't easy for you.
Remember, you were trained
for this kind of situation...
and believe me,
it'll come back to you.
Besides, you got the best SEAL team
in the country backin' you up.
Okay.
You're right.
I'll be on the wire.
I'll help talk you through it.
There's something else.
It's terrible...
N-No, it's wonderful...
except it isn't.
My girlfriend's pregnant...
and she's...
just flown in to see me.
You keep your mind on what you're
going to be doing out there tonight,
and I'll send someone to pick up
your girlfriend and bring her
here to the command centre.
- Hummel!
- Hello, Frank. Lou Linstrom.
I'm at the White House
with General Kramer.
Uh, Frank, uh, we're havin' a few
problems with the account transfer.
Don't tell me problems,
tell me solutions.
We've spoken to the President,
and I know that you're aware
of his stance on terrorism,
- so what we'd like to do...
- This isn't about terrorism.
This is about justice.
It's about reminding you people
who found it politically
convenient to forget.
This is goin' nowhere,
Frank.
Well, let me tell you what is: 15 VX gas
rockets into the heart of San Francisco.
You've got 17 hours
to deliver the money.
Or be prepared to reap
the whirlwind, gentlemen.
What's the word
from Mojave?
General Peterson can give us no definite
assurance on the thermite plasma.
That is the word.
Green light
to SEAL incursion.
Fall in!
All right. Listen up.
Mr Mason will run point for us.
Lieutenant Shepard will be
attached to his hip.
You breathe,
he breathes with you.
You piss, he helps.
Understood?
Dr Goodspeed
is our specialist.
When he neutralizes the threat,
we launch green flares
and we wait for the cavalry.
Make no mistake, gentlemen,
we're in the fight of our lives,
against maybe the greatest
battalion commander...
in the Vietnam War,
I shit you not.
Any questions?
Let's load up!
After you, ace.
Pass out and activate
the Minicams.
Everything set here?
Minicams operational?
Roger that, sir.
We are on line.
Shep, what's the status on the special
operational gear for Mr Mason?
Let's see, we have, uh,
one quart of kerosene
and a squeeze bottle,
three washers
and waterproof matches.
Use the green flares to signal
when the threat has been neutralized.
Now, this is atropine.
If you come in contact with the gas,
you have 20 seconds
to inject it into your heart.
Don't fuck with me on this.
It may save your life.
I have three incoming bogeys
bearing 2-7-5. Range: 6,000 metres.
FBI Command Centre?
- Oh, I would just love for you
to tell me what is goin' on.
- Nope.
Listen, Stanley Goodspeed
is my boyfriend.
- Actually, he's my fiance. Where is he?
- Classified, lady.
Okay, well you just sit here
and act like a Bureau bonehead, then.
Hey, where are you...
Goddam it.
Decoy choppers commencing
run to Alcatraz.
I just lost one, sir.
I just lost one.
We only got two flying in.
Shit.
In my day, we did it all
with a snorkel and a pair of flippers.
- Your day?
- Yes, didn't you read my resume?
I don't... I don't know
anything about you.
- I know something about you, Godspell.
- Goodspeed.
Goodspeed,
Godspeed, Godspell,
you never went to
any anti-terrorist school.
So just make sure you don't
get us all fucking killed.
We're going dark.
Night vision!
Raider One has dropped
below radar coverage,
heading around Treasure Island.
Sir, we've got two bogeys
bearing due east and closing.
Decoys?
- Prepare to deploy!
- Good luck, Commander.
Sir, Raider One
is at the drop zone.
Stanley's not a very good swimmer.
I mean, he can't even snorkel.
- Everyone, good to go?
- Good to go!
- [Muffled Words] Good to go!
All right, so the SDUs
have been deployed,
and the Eagles are in the water.
Major, I want the perimeter patrolled
to the west end of the island.
- Yes, sir. Hendrix,
you lead the patrol.
- Aye, sir.
Let's move! Move out,
move out, move out!
The Eagles are on the rock.
They've entered the cistern room.
Thank you very fucking much, Mr Mason.
You've led us into a room with no exit.
Any ideas, Dillinger?
Figure it out soon.
We're sitting ducks.
- Real tight on time.
- You stand by the door. Until I open it.
I'd like to know how you plan
on accomplishing that.
Through here.
- You're shitting me.
- I memorized the timing.
I just hope
it hasn't been changed.
- You catch one of those
flame bursts, you're a corpse.
- Thank you.
- Commander, you said never
leave his side, but, uh...
- Stand fast, Lieutenant.
Have a nice day.
- Where'd you dig up this guy?
- That's classified.
Clear here, sir.
No motion sensors tripped.
Nothing.
Well, tell them
to stay out there.
Sweep forward!
Looks like he fucked us,
Commander.
I knew it.
That son of a bitch jumped ship.
Welcome to the Rock.
Mason.
That's a no-no.
That's the subway.
That'll drop you
into the tunnels.
Do it!
Sir, the Eagles
have breached the tunnel system.
You enjoying this?
Well, it's certainly
more enjoyable than my average day:
reading philosophy,
avoiding gang rape in the washroom.
Though it's less of a problem these
days. Maybe I'm losing my sex appeal.
We've got seismic activity
in one of the storm grates. North side.
Continue patrolling
the area.
Sweep forward.
Commander, halt.
We've got movement.
They're hearing
sounds above, sir.
Stand fast.
Down, down, down.
West storm drain's clear.
Ninety-seven paces
to the shower room.
The Eagles are now at the
access tunnel. They're right
under the shower room, sir.
Fibre optics.
Something's not right.
I've got a bad feeling
about this.
Quiet.
Motion sensors.
- Beam's cutting across manhole covers.
- Deal with it.
Commander, the beam is hitting
some sort of reflective device.
Possibly a prism.
I want to use a mirror
to cut the beam,
send the beam
back to its source...
and then I'm
going to move the prism.
[Electronic Beeping]
We've got motion on a trembler
in the shower room, sir.
We've got visitors.
Let's move.
Got it. Good to go.
[Indistinct Shouting]
Stand fast.
We'll secure the area.
They're entering
to the shower room, sir.
They're securing the area.
Just sit tight.
Drop your weapons!
Drop 'em!
- Stand back!
- Hold your fire.
Drop your weapons.
Hold your fire!
It's a fucking trap.
This is Gen. Hummel.
Drop your weapons.
Drop 'em!
Anderson here, Gen. Hummel.
Commander. Team leader.
Cmdr. Anderson, if you have any
concern for the lives of your men...
you will order them to safety their
weapons and place them on the deck.
This is not happening.
Sir, we know why you're out here.
God knows I agree with you.
But like you, I swore to defend
this country against all enemies...
foreign, sir, and domestic.
General, we've spilled
the same blood in the same mud.
You know goddam well
I can't give that order.
We're dead.
Your unit is covered from
an elevated position, Commander.
I'm not gonna ask again.
Don't do anything stupid.
No one has to die here.
You men following the general, you're
under oath as United States Marines!
Have you forgotten that?
We all have shipmates
we remember.
Some of them were shit on
and pissed on by the Pentagon.
But that doesn't give you
the right to mutiny!
You call it what you want!
You're down there; we're up here.
You walked into the wrong
goddam room, Commander!
- Stand fast!
- Commander, one last time.
You tell your men
to safety their weapons.
- I cannot give that order!
- I am not gonna repeat
that order!
- I will not give that order!
- What the hell is wrong
with you, man?
- Stand fast!
- Oh, my God!
- Let's waste these fuckers.
- One last time.
You order your men
to safety their weapons...
[Screaming]
Cease fire!
Don't go.
[Screaming]
Cease fire!
Shit. Goddam it.
Let go of me. Let go of me!
Don't, don't go.
[Yelling]
Fuck.
It's over.
[Gasping]
Oh, God!
- [Beeping]
- We got some movement.
- Who? Who is it?
- Two of'em. Eagles 11 and 12.
It's Goodspeed and Mason.
I knew it.
I've gotta get a team together.
We've gotta move with the second option.
What, and invite another
massacre? No way.
We've got a 60-year-old convict and
a lab rat. I'm telling you, it's over.
Not for Mason,
it isn't.
Goodspeed, I'm not
gonna kill you.
- Where are you going?
- Off this bloody island.
What? Wh... What for?
[Man On Radio]
Goodspeed, do you read me?
It's for you.
- Sir?
- What's the status?
The status is, they're dead.
They're dead!
It's just me and Mason.
Now he says he's leaving.
That is unacceptable,
do you hear me? Unacceptable!
Well, there's a problem, sir,
he's got a gun.
What do you have,
a fuckin' water pistol?
- No, sir.
- Go after him and stop him.
I didn't want this.
Jesus, I didn't want this.
- We knew this might happen.
- Maybe now they'll pay up.
- Maybe now they won't, Captain.
- Maybe we need to execute
a few hostages.
- Got a live one!
- Put a bullet in him.
You heard him, end it.
Holster that sidearm,
Captain!
Sir?
You made a terrible mistake. And more
of our brothers have died in vain.
Damn you for forcing me
into this position.
I need to talk to you.
Right now, alone.
Now you told me
I'm on a need-to-know basis,
and I'm tellin' you right now
I need to know who the fuck
John Mason is right now, sir.
All right, you wanna know?
1962,J. Edgar Hoover...
is head of the FBI,
some say the country.
It's no secret he kept microfilm files
on prominent Americans and Europeans:
de Gaulle, British
members of Parliament,
even the Prime Minister.
I mean, this guy had dirt
on everybody in the world.
Yeah. I know all
the cloak-and-dagger stories.
Where does Mason fit in?
Mason was the British operative
who stole the files.
But our Bureau agents caught him
at the Canadian border.
Of course, the British claimed
they'd never heard of him.
And we held him without trial
until he gave up the microfilm.
But he never did.
I'm surprised Hoover didn't
use his daughter as leverage.
Hoover was dead in '72.
She wasn't born yet.
Today, well, it's
a different bureau.
So you held this guy without trial
his whole life. No wonder he's pissed.
This man knows our most intimate
secrets from the last half-century:
the alien landing at Roswell,
the truth about the JFK assassination.
And Mason's angry, he's lethal.
He's a trained killer.
And he is the only hope
that we have got.
Mason! Mason!
There are 81 hostages
still up there.
Yeah. Like me.
You wanna play tough?
You wanna play tough with me?
Okay, FBI!
Freeze, sucker!
- I'll fire.
- No, you won't.
- Throw down.
- You're not the sort.
Let's find out.
I could; you, no.
Besides,
your safety's on.
Goodspeed, have you
resolved the situation?
[Gasps]
Not yet.
He's got
all the guns now, sir.
Shit!
You're right, I don't use guns
and I don't kick down doors.
This is what I do.
I haven't got my glasses.
What it says is,
"Chemical Weapons Specialist."
That's right.
I got a lunatic up there,
man, with 15 missiles...
armed with some
really funky stuff.
That lying Womack.
You could've told my daughter.
It was classified.
Look, I'm in
the same situation.
I've got my girlfriend in the city
with a baby on the way.
Look, I can
defuse the rockets.
I really can.
But I'm gonna need your help,
and I'm gonna need it right now.
Sir, this man's weapons
and tack radio are missing!
Shit, we got a rodent problem.
Flush the pipes.
There's probably a maze of
tunnels on this goddam island.
Check every access you can find.
Sir!
Even if you escape
from the island...
you can't escape
the rockets.
So, where are you
gonna go?
Go where?
What're you gonna do?
[Stanley]
Show me where
the morgue is, Mason.
[Mason]
I'm out of here.
[Stanley]
What about your daughter?
Mason?
Rodents located.
The way I see it, you don't
really have any choice, do you?
I don't think you do.
Move!
Ooooh!
They're on to us.
Burn 'em out.
This mother's gonna
blow big.
I don't understand. How could we lose
radio contact all of a sudden?
We've lost coms.
Still got 'em on locaters.
- So what's it gonna be?
- What?
- How do you like your choices?
- I don't.
- That's what I thought.
- Come on.
This is the oldest
part of Alcatraz.
Did you know it was originally
a Civil War fort?
Oh, really? Yeah, wow.
You know, I like history, too,
and maybe when this is over, you and I
can stop by the souvenir shop together,
but right now, I just... I just...
I wanna find some rockets.
Don't tempt me.
We are going
to the morgue.
- You sure you're ready for this?
- I'll do my best.
Your best?
Losers always whine
about their best.
Winners go home
and fuck the prom queen.
Carla was the prom queen.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Locaters have them
approaching the morgue, sir.
Come on, come on,
you can do it, Doc.
You must never hesitate.
I think you're shooting
too close to the rocket.
Him, but not the rocket.
Any other news,
professor?
The rocket!
Not the rocket!
Aaah!
Uhhh!
[Grunts]
[Groaning]
I got a little something
for ya.
Yaaaah!
Uh, yeah, okay, that's just about
the most awful thing I've ever seen.
Mason... the second
you don't respect this, it kills you.
Put it over there.
You've been around a lot of corpses.
Is that normal?
- What, the feet thing?
- Yeah, the feet thing.
- Yeah, that happens.
- Can you do something about it?
Like what?
Kill him again?
Listen, I'm
just a biochemist.
Most of the time, I work in a glass jar
and lead a very uneventful life.
I drive a Volvo,
a beige one.
But what I'm dealing with is one
of the most deadly substances
the earth has ever known.
So what do you say
you cut me some friggin' slack?
[Hissing]
A really elegant
string-of-pearls configuration.
Unfortunately,
incredibly unstable.
What exactly
does this stuff do?
If the rocket renders it aerosol, it
can take out the entire city of people.
Really? What happens
if you drop one?
Happily, it'll just
wipe out you and me.
- How?
- It's a cholinesterase inhibitor.
It stops the brain from
sending nerve messages down the
spinal cord within 30 seconds.
Any epidermal exposure or
inhalation, and you'll know.
A twinge at the small of your back as
the poison seizes your nervous system.
Do not move that!
Your muscles freeze,
you can't breathe...
you spasm so hard you break
your own back, spit your guts out.
But that's after
your skin melts off.
My God.
Well, I think we'd like God
on our side at the moment, don't you?
So what I'm doing now is removing
the guidance system chips...
so the rocket'll splash
down after 500 feet.
All right, let me have that.
You can let go of it.
All right, just back away.
Just back away!
Sir, morgue team
has not checked in.
Blackbird One,
this is Blackbird, over.
Blackbird One, this is Blackbird,
come in, goddam it!
Somebody's still here.
Let's move!
Rats alive! Close on the morgue!
Close on the morgue!
Go, go, go, go,
go, go, go, go!
Frye, Darrow, hustle up.
We got more company!
[Hummel]
Hold it! Converge
on the morgue! Move out!
Goodspeed, come on.
Come over here.
Yeah, I love pressure,
I eat it for breakfast.
Come on. Time's up.
There's three rockets somewhere else.
We have to find them!
Come on!
Clear!
I'm too old for this!
- Where's it go?
- I've no idea.
Sir, all the guidance
chips are gone.
Captain, I guess you didn't quite
take care of the rat problem.
No, sir.
Well, there are two dead men who
strongly suggest you go finish the job.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir!
[Indistinct Shouting]
- You really don't know
where this goes?
- No, I don't know where it goes.
Well, we're picking up speed.
Do you know how to slow it down?
No, I don't.
Aaaaaaah!
Uhhh!
[Grunting]
God!
[Groaning]
Mason! You all right?
Yes, perfectly okay,
you fucking idiot.
They're coming.
- Who?
- The Marines!
Where?
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
- What the fuck's goin' on?
- Let's cut him off.
[Screams]
[Screaming Continues]
[Screaming]
Mason!
[Grunting]
You motherfucker,
die, die, die!
I'm rather glad
you didn't hesitate too long.
How do you do it?
Oh, I was trained by the best.
British Intelligence.
Come on.
But in retrospect, I'd rather
have been a poet or a farmer.
Okay.
Okay, the President
arrives in three hours.
His directive is to string Hummel along
until the air strike is operational.
What's the word
from Mojave, General?
Same as last time, Lou.
They're going as fast as they can.
Do it over here.
On your knees!
[Hummel]
Navy SEALS, listen up.
You've got something
that belongs to me.
Twelve guidance chips
to be precise.
Let me remind you that there are lives
at stake, civilian lives.
Speak up.
[Panting]
- Speak up!
- Oh! I, uh...
- Uh...
- Tell them your name.
My name is Larry Henderson.
Oh, man.
And I'm a father
of three, and, uh,
they've got
a gun to my head.
You've got exactly three minutes
to return the guidance chips,
or Mr Henderson
won't have a head.
Oh, no.
Hey, what...?
Now, three to go.
You find them and defuse them.
- Okay? All right.
- All right.
I'll try and delay Hummel
and give you more time.
Hey, what about
Mr Henderson's head?
Okay. What do you mean?
Okay.
[Hostages Chattering]
General.
Who the hell are you?
I'm all that's left
of the enemy.
Bingo.
Stand easy.
Thought I'd been
in the service a long time.
Name and rank, sailor.
It's Army, actually.
Answer the question.
And address him as "General, sir."
Captain John Patrick Mason,
General, sir...
of Her Majesty's SAS.
Retired, of course.
You're a long way
from home, Captain.
How the hell are you
involved in this?
I have a unique knowledge
of this prison facility.
I was, uh...
formerly a guest here.
Hi, sweetie.
[Screaming]
Hey, come back here,
little boy.
Did they bother to tell you
who I am, why I'm doing this,
or are they just using you
like they do everybody else?
All I know is you were big in Vietnam.
I saw the highlights on television.
You wouldn't have any idea
what it means to lead the finest
men on God's earth into battle,
and then see their memory betrayed
by their own fuckin' government!
I don't quite see how you
cherish the memory of the dead
by killing another million.
And, uh...
this is not combat.
It's an act of lunacy,
General, sir.
Personally, I think
you're a fuckin' idiot.
"The tree of liberty
must be refreshed from time to time...
with the blood of patriots
and tyrants." Thomas Jefferson.
"Patriotism is the virtue of
the vicious," according to Oscar Wilde.
[Grunts, Groaning]
Thank you
for making my point.
Where are the guidance chips?
Where are the guidance chips!
I destroyed them.
That was a bad move, soldier.
Does that mean
you'll execute us both?
[Rapid Gunfire]
[Choking, Yelling]
[Screams, Grunts]
You're lucky that old man
Hummel wants you alive.
'Cause I'd take pleasure
in guttin' you, boy.
[Stanley]
I'd take pleasure
in guttin'you... boy.
I'll take pleasure
in guttin' you. Boy.
What is wrong with these
people, huh, Mason?
Don't you think there's a lot
of, uh, lot of anger flowin'
around this island?
Kind of a pubescent volatility?
Don't you think?
A lot of angst, lot of "I'm 16,
I'm angry at my father" syndrome?
I mean, grow up!
We're stuck on an island...
with a bunch of
violence-for-pleasure-seeking
psychopathic Marines.
Shame on them!
[Clears Throat]
Anyway, I only got one chem rod,
and there's two left.
Mason?
Yes, I'm here.
I was just thinking
how wonderful it was...
when the inmates weren't
allowed to talk in here.
Not allowed to talk.
How did you do it?
[Sighs]
Nurtured the hope
that there was hope...
that one day I'd breathe
free air.
Perhaps meet my daughter.
Modest hopes,
but they kept a man alive.
What did they put you
away for, John?
Oh, that's a long story.
Well, I'm not
going anywhere.
When was the last communication
from our men on Alcatraz?
Seven hours.
- [Phone Rings]
- Thermite plasma is operational.
Get me the President.
Be seated. Gentlemen,
consider yourselves on ground alert.
If we receive launch authority,
your mission is...
the complete thermal destruction
of Alcatraz Island.
The entire island is to be blanketed,
not one square inch missed.
Eighty-one American civilians
and a number of US Marines
will lose their lives.
Why didn't you just tell them
where the microfilm was
and create a solution?
[Chuckles]
The moment they had the
microfilm, they'd suicide me.
- Some solution.
- You ended up here.
Which brings me
to another question.
You broke out... let me see
if I can get this straight...
you went down the incinerator chute,
on the mine car,
through the tunnels
to the power plant,
under the steam engine...
that was really cool, by the way...
and into the cistern
through the intake pipe,
[Clears Throat]
but how, in the name
of Zeus's butthole,
did you get
out of your cell?
I only ask because
in our current situation,
well, it could prove to be
useful information, maybe!
Trade secrets, my son.
Wow.
General, two operational
rockets left.
One at the lower lighthouse
and one on the roof.
Both of the birds are ready to fly,
sir. General, can you hear me?
- I heard you, Captain.
- Just makin' sure.
Should we... prepare
for launch, General?
I'll handle
the strategy, Captain.
Yes, sir.
The hour is approaching, sir.
Just letting the General know
of the time, sir.
I'm very aware
of the time, Captain.
Aye, aye, sir.
Lettin'you know.
Me and my boys are cocked,
locked and ready to rock.
Mason, where are you going?
Thirty years ago I vowed
I wouldn't die in this toilet.
You're not leaving! There's a madman
in there with his hand on a button!
Shhh. Some sniper's
gonna get his ass.
Stop moving, Mason.
Mason, stop moving.
Hummel won't do it.
He's a soldier, not a murderer.
I read it in his eyes.
Read his eyes? Oh, well,
then everything's just fine!
- I can't afford to take that chance.
- Why don't you talk louder?
Three minutes to go, sir.
- They're not gonna call, Frank.
- Oh, they'll call.
They'll call if we fire
one of our rockets up their ass.
Sir.
[Phone Ringing]
- Hummel.
- Hi, Frank, it's Al Kramer here.
- How's it going out there?
- How do you think it's going?
- We're gonna need another hour, Frank.
- You've got three minutes.
- We have to get authorization
from the President.
- You've got three minutes.
Frank, please don't do
anything stupid.
They want another hour.
That's bullshit.
That's bullshit, General. They're lying.
They're calling our bluff, sir.
They're playing you for a fool.
Sir, order the launch,
General.
Come on, General,
let's be all we can be.
The mission's
not complete!
Well, mine is.
When this is over,
you'll go back home,
driving Carla and your baby
insane in your beige Volvo.
And I'll be dead, or back in prison
which is the same thing.
You're not leaving.
[Grunts, Groaning]
All right...
I'll do it myself.
I got three weeks'
weapons training.
I'll kick the... out of
a platoon full of Marines.
No problem.
Major, patch me
into roof battery.
Aye, sir.
Fire open control circuit
coordinates to the roof, sir.
Let's go!
Laser powered up.
Oh, no.
I said, on your knees!
My name's Stanley Goodspeed.
I'm a chemical weapons
specialist for the FBI.
- Uh, glass or plastic?
- What?
- Glass or plastic!
- Shut the fuck up!
Because if the winds change
and you launch those rockets,
we're all gonna die.
- Shut up!
- And you're gonna end up in
a glass jar or a plastic bag.
So do the math, hand over the gun
and let's go find some rockets!
I said shut the fuck...
[Neck Snaps]
[Panting]
You made the right choice.
I decided I didn't want your child
growing up without a father.
Hey, the last time I swam
this channel I was your age.
So I'm fucked either way.
So come on.
The weapon is hot. I am standing by
for the launch command.
Man, killing Navy SEALs is one thing...
Is this for real?
Hey, it's business.
Access code entered.
Weapon available for release.
Launch coordinates:
six, seven, five, four,
five, niner.
The weapon is hot.
I'm standing by
for launch command.
It's affirmative.
[Bell Chiming]
Standing by for command.
I'm waiting for
a launch command, General.
- Fire.
- Fire!
Missile loose!
Origin: Alcatraz, 67253725.
- What's the heading?
- Heading 185 degrees south southeast.
- Speed?
- 300 knots.
It's headed
right at Oakland.
The football game.
Oh, my God.
Missile radically
changing direction.
New direction:275 degrees west.
It's headed out to sea, sir.
Oh, Christ!
Missile losing altitude.
Falling.
Falling, 300 feet, 200, 100.
Bogey detonated under water.
What the fuck?
- It missed.
- Well, that's great.
Extremely great,
but there's still one left.
What happened to the rocket?
What the fuck happened
to the coordinates?
What the fuck is going on?
Sir! Major!
Captain, step outside.
- Talk to me, sir.
- Captain, step outside!
Get me the Pentagon.
What the hell
was that, Frank?
- I said, what the hell...
- I heard what you said!
- I'd appreciate a little more respect.
- Cut the crap, General.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I'm not ready to kill these people.
- Call the Pentagon. Ask for more time.
- No.
Do it, Frank!
We're coming loose.
You're coming loose.
The rest of us are in complete control.
- We're gonna ask them
for a new deadline.
- Put the phone down.
- The men are falling apart!
- The men are Marines!
- Are they?
I wanna talk
to General Kramer.
- You've been asked by an old friend.
- Put him on the phone right now.
- You've been ordered.
- This is Major Baxter!
Now you're being given your
last chance by a man with a gun.
Put the phone down.
I thought you weren't
ready to kill.
I'm warming up.
At ease.
They need a decision,
Mr President.
[Sighs]
These past few hours...
have been the longest,
darkest of my life.
How does one weigh
human life?
One million civilians
against 81 hostages.
And in the middle,
Frank Hummel.
[Sighs]
That we have ignored, abandoned...
or marginalized a great
soldier like Frank Hummel,
and American boys have paid
for that neglect...
in blood
is equally real...
and equally tragic.
We are at war with terror,
and fighting war
means casualties.
This is the worst call
I've ever had to make.
Air strike approved.
Red Thunder to Tower.
Request clearance.
The amount of firepower
they're gonna drop in there,
This is strike leader.
Prepared to go.
it'll be over in a few seconds.
[Pilot]
Flight time to drop point:
17 minutes.
Excuse me, General, sir,
with all due respect to you,
but what the fuck is going on?
- You changed the coordinates,
didn't you, General?
- That's affirmative, Captain.
So now they think we're gutless,
the Feds? They think we won't
actually do it.
They're gonna come at us with
everything they got. Air and sea.
They're gonna bomb our ass
back to the Stone Age.
They don't know
we missed on purpose.
Great. We're not gutless.
We're incompetent.
That right?
I don't think
I like your tone, Captain.
We planned for this contingency.
Load the VX into the choppers,
take four hostages and evacuate.
The consequences of our actions
I'll face alone.
Excuse me, General, but
what about the fucking money?
There is no fucking money.
Mission's over.
Bullshit, it's over.
You're talking to a general,
soldier! Maintain discipline!
I'm not a soldier, Major. The day we
took hostages we became mercenaries.
And mercenaries get paid.
I want my fucking money!
This mission was based
on the threat of force.
I'm not about to kill
80,000 innocent people.
Do you think I'm
out of my fucking mind?
We bluffed. They called it.
The mission's over.
Who ever said anything
about bluffing, General?
Stand down, Captain.
Stand down, Captain!
Major, I'm ordering you to take these
men to the choppers and evacuate.
That's a simple
order, Major!
It's not so simple, Frank.
Sergeant Crisp,
secure the general.
I'm relieving you
of your command, sir.
Sergeant!
- I'll have that sidearm, sir.
- You mean this sidearm?
Major Baxter, you're either
with us or against us.
It has been the greatest honour
of my life to serve with you, General.
But like he said...
it's over.
[Grunts]
Let's get him.
Mason!
[Groaning]
My God, what have I done?
Where's the last rocket?
Where's the last rocket!
- Where's the last rocket?
- Lower lighthouse.
- Lower lighthouse!
- Go.
[Shouting]
Darrow, go to the lighthouse!
I'll take care of this fucker!
One, two, three!
Eat that!
[Groaning]
Did it.
[Grunts]
[Groans]
Come here. Come here,
you little chickensh...
You shoot me, I drop this.
We're both dead.
Come on. Come on. Don't be scared.
I won't hurt you.
- Come on.
- You know how this shit works?
You know how
this shit works?
Come on.
I don't need the gun.
I'll put it down.
Come on. Let's play.
Come on. Come on.
Listen, I think we got started off on
the wrong foot. Stan Goodspeed, FBI.
Uh, let's talk music. Do you like
the Elton John song, "Rocket Man"?
- I don't like soft-ass shit.
- Oh, you... Oh, oh.
Well, I only bring it up because,
uh, it's you. You're the Rocket Man.
[Screaming]
How do you like
how that shit works?
Second rocket's away!
[Screaming Continues]
- [Squelching Noise]
- [Groaning]
It splashed into the bay, sir.
No detonation.
Shit.
Darrow!
Open up!
Come on.
[Grunts]
Hey, you mothe-e-e-er!
[Groaning]
[Grunting]
Oh, I'm gonna
get you now, baby.
Okay.
Got ya.
I got you, baby.
Come on.
[Groaning, Screaming]
Fucker!
[Grunting]
[Groans]
Red Thunder strike leader.
Time on target: seven minutes.
[Grunting]
English prick. [Grunts]
I tell you my old man was Irish?
Maintain air speed
4-5-0 knots.
[Grunting]
- [Thud]
- Aw, fuck!
[Gasping]
It's me and you, pal!
I want that fucking chip!
I love pressure.
I know you're in here,
and I know you can hear me.
Now pay the piper
and come out like a man.
[Yells, Grunts]
[Groaning]
[Grunting Continues]
Increase speed
to 5-0-0 knots.
You motherfucker!
[Yelling]
[Gasping, Groaning]
I'm gonna choke my million bucks
out of you! You're gonna die!
- Eat that, you fucker!
- [Grunts]
[Choking, Gasping]
[Grunts]
[Groaning]
All right, team inbound.
Time on target: 60 seconds.
On course heading
1-4-2 degrees.
[Anderson's Voice]
When he neutralizes the threat,
we launch green flares
and we wait for the cavalry.
Let's tighten up
that formation.
May God have mercy
on your souls.
Please don't let this happen. There has
to be something you can do. Please.
[Grunting, Groaning]
Let's drop to the deck,
100 feet below radar.
Target acquired.
Rolling in.
[Groans]
This is Red Thunder.
Master arm.
Master armed.
Time on target: 12 seconds.
- TOT: ten seconds.
- Please.
Stay tight, gentlemen.
I got green smoke.
I got green smoke!
This is CQ-1, CQ-1. Green smoke!
We have green smoke, over!
- Gimme that, gimme that,
gimme that! Abort.
- Abort!
- Flight leader, abort, abort!
- Jesus Christ!
- I already dropped 'em.
- [Screaming]
Oh, goddam it!
Oh, my God.
Get out of my way.
Let me through, please. Let me through.
The cells did not get hit.
The bombs hit on the back of the island.
- [Grunting, Gasping]
- I'm fed up saving your ass.
I'm amazed you ever
got past puberty.
I suppose all this will make a
great bedtime story to tell your kid.
You're insane, Mason.
The kid'll have nightmares.
I'll spend all my money
on shrinks.
Goodspeed, come in.
Goodspeed, Goodspeed,
do you read me? Come in.
Scanning all radio
frequencies.
Goodspeed, do you read me?
Come in.
[Walkie-Talkie Clicks]
Goodspeed, do you read me? Come in.
Goodspeed?
Do you read me? Come in.
This is Goodspeed.
Are the hostages alive?
Every one of'em.
[Cheering]
Goodspeed, it's Womack.
What about Mason?
He's dead, sir.
- How? When?
- Just come and get me.
Womack tore up
your pardon, John.
[Chuckles]
But of course. I knew he would.
The SDUs and the scuba gear should
still be where we came ashore.
If you can get
to the Pan Pacific Hotel,
there's clothes in my closet
and $200 in the Bible.
Room 26.
Well, it's been a long time
since I've said thank you to anybody.
But thank you.
Well, Stanley, uh, this is when
we go our separate ways, huh?
Uh... I'm sure you know the etymology
of your name, "Goodspeed."
Yeah, "Godspeed." To wish someone
a prosperous journey. Why?
Well, if you fancy
a journey,
I recommend
Fort Walton, Kansas.
I was thinking of Maui.
No.
Forget Maui.
"St. Michael's Church,
Fort Walton, Kansas.
Front pew, right leg.
Hollow."
Is this what I think it is?
Mason?
Congratulations, Dr Goodspeed.
You did it.
Thank you, sir.
You know, for a while there,
I didn't think you were gonna make it.
Well done, son.
So, where's Mason?
Vaporized.
Blown out to sea.
Blown out to sea, huh?
Yeah.
Poor bastard.
Goodspeed, where's Mason?
Where's his body?
I wanna see
that son of a bitch.
Vaporized, sir.
Excuse me, gentlemen.
What? Vaporized?
A body can vaporize?
Oh, yeah.
Absolutely, sir.
[Stanley]
St. Michael's Church.
Front pew, right leg.
[Man Shouting]
Vandals! Vandals!
Oh, yes, baby, come on!
- Stop! Vandals! Stop!
- I'm sorry.
- Come on, baby!
- I've got it. Okay, let's go!
- Stop! Stop!
- Sorry!
Stop! Hey, hey, you!
- Vandals! Vandals!
- [Panting]
Honey, uh, do you wanna know
who really killed JFK?