So here's what you missed
on Glee...
I needed you around,
and you weren't there.
Blaine cheated on Kurt
and they broke up,
and Rachel and Finn
broke up, too, and Finn
has no idea what he wants to
do with his life. We're done.
Jake has his eye on Marley,
which Kitty's
really not happy about,
and Emma's not sure she wants
to leave McKinley
to go to Washington with Will.
And that's what
you missed on Glee.
Why do I always feel
so at home in a tire shop?
That was a joke.
What do you want, Artie?
I got a lot of work to do.
I just wanted
to check in on you.
You've had
a rough couple of months,
and I thought maybe
you could use a friend.
It's not that bad.
I just embarrassed myself
out of the army,
lost Rachel completely,
and now I'm back in my hometown
working in a tire shop.
Figure maybe my luck
will change soon
and one of the lifts will break,
and I'll get crushed by a car.
I'm sorry, Artie.
I appreciate what you're
doing; You're a great friend.
I'm just kind of sitting
back and looking
at the next 60
years of my life.
It just sort of makes me
want to puke.
But it is what it is.
Do you remember what I said
when I dedicated that song
to you last year?
That you were
my friend, my hero.
I'm not gonna let you bury
yourself in self-pity, Finn.
You're better than that.
You know, I've heard that
a lot all my life, Artie.
That I'm better
than I think I am.
Well, look around.
Maybe I'm not.
You just lost
your confidence
because you forgot your place.
You're a creative person.
You need to find
an artistic outlet.
Come codirect the musical
with me.
Grease was your idea.
I don't know
how to direct a musical, Artie.
Directing is
about having an idea
and convincing everyone
around you to make it happen.
I don't think so.
Fine.
Then I'm not doing it, either,
which means there is no musical.
You can't do that, man,
hold the musical hostage.
That's like terrorism.
Basically, Olivia Newton-John
is strapped to my chest,
and unless you
codirect with me,
I'm gonna blow her up.
I'm serious, Finn.
Trust me, as your friend,
you need to do this.
Just so you can look
at the first month
of the next 60 years
of your life
and not want to puke.
Auditions are tomorrow.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(School bell ringing)
Sam: As president and vice
president, we can pretty much decree
which ever parts
we want, right?
I'm not sure I'm gonna do
the musical this year.
I'm not in the right headspace
to do a project like Grease.
Since Kurt and I broke up,
I haven't slept,
I lost my appetite.
I don't even gel on week.
This is pretty serious, then.
Sam, Kurt was my soul mate.
We talked about spending
the rest of our lives together.
About retiring in Provincetown
and buying a lighthouse
and starting an artists' colony.
And now he won't even
return my calls.
He won't text me.
And that gilmore girls box set
I sent him was returned
to me, unopened.
He's gone.
Maybe forever.
Dude, I get it, except
for the lighthouse part.
But look, everybody's
been there.
You'll get through it.
("Hopelessly devoted
to you" begins)
♪ Guess mine is not the first
♪ heart broken
♪ my eyes
are not the first to cry ♪
♪ I'm not the first to know
♪ there's just
no getting over you ♪
♪ I know I'm just a fool
♪ who's willing
♪ to sit around
♪ and wait for you
♪ but, baby, can't you see
♪ there's nothing else for me
♪ to do
♪ I'm hopelessly devoted
to you ♪
♪ but now
♪ there's nowhere
♪ to hide
♪ since you pushed
my love aside ♪
♪ I'm out of my head
♪ hopelessly devoted to you
♪ hopelessly devoted
♪ to you
♪ ooh-ooh-ooh ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ hopelessly devoted to you
♪ my head is saying, "fool",
♪ forget him"
♪ my heart is saying
♪ "don't let go"
♪ hold on to the end
♪ that's what
♪ I intend to do
♪ I'm hopelessly devoted
to you ♪
♪ but now there's nowhere
♪ to hide
♪ since you pushed
my love aside ♪
♪ I'm out of my head
♪ hopelessly devoted
♪ to you
♪ ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ hopelessly devoted
♪ to you
♪ ooh.
(Light applause)
Say something.
Like what?
I think I speak
for both of us when I say
that though you auditioned
with a Sandy song,
you are the Danny
Zuko of our dreams.
Right?
Yeah, yeah, totally.
You were awesome.
Amazing.
I can't.
I'm sorry, I just can't, Finn.
I didn't want to let you down,
but Grease is a romance,
and how can I play any of the
scenes if I have ruined mine?
The truth of Danny Zuko.
Thank you for letting me
audition, but I-I just can't.
But wait.
Is there any part you think
you could play?
I don't think so. Maybe...
Maybe teen angel.
It's only one scene,
but probably not.
Wow, I've never seen
Blaine so...
Masterpiece theater.
Look, sorry, man. I know
you're just trying to help,
but this is a bad idea.
(School bell ringing)
Finn, hold up.
What was a bad idea?
Me directing.
I'm not qualified
for any of this, Artie.
You have to trust
your instincts.
But also, part of
being a good director
is surrounding yourself
with the right people.
The right choreographer and
the right vocal Coach, right?
It is. Just trust me.
So I called in some favors,
and the cavalry
has just arrived.
(School bell ringing)
School arts programs are
going the way of the dinosaur.
Even the basics like choir
and band are disappearing.
No one is disputing that.
All I'm saying is
if I go with Will
to Washington...
Our relationship
will only grow.
This is not just a
once-in-a-lifetime experience
for me, but for both of us.
And I feel that Emma
is dismissing it.
And I feel
like Will just assumes
I'm gonna happily
drop everything,
play the part of the dutiful,
1950s housewife,
even though we're not even
married yet.
She's made this analogy
several times.
And that my job and my life
and my dreams
are somehow secondary
to that. I'm sorry,
but am I wrong
for feeling that way?
Pumpkins, bear Bryant once said,
"feelings aren't right
or wrong.
They just are."
My relationship with Cooter,
it was more sour
than Brian Urlacher's
compression shorts.
That doesn't mean true blue
sweeties like yourselves
aren't gonna have
a flag on the play.
Take a timeout. Call an audible.
It's all about knowing
when to pass and when to punt.
That's very insightful, but...
Shannon's right.
Time-out, time-out.
Emma, I made a mistake when I
first talked to you about this.
So let me just rewind
and start from scratch.
Oh, don't look like that, Emma.
Emma, Emma, I love you
with every fiber of my being.
And no matter where we go
or what we do,
I want us to always be together.
This time, it's Washington.
Next time, it can be
anywhere you want to go.
So, I'm asking
my partner, my equal partner...
To join me.
Would you consider it?
I'll go.
You-you sure?
(Sighs)
(School bell ringing)
We have plenty of girls
auditioning for Sandy,
but we're gonna have
a serious Danny Zuko problem
if Blaine can't do it.
What are the other options?
How about Sam?
He's got his heart set
on Kenickie.
Uh, "Greased Lightning"
is my cell phone ringtone,
and I've been knocked out
by a car door before,
so I was really looking forward
to re-creating
the reality
of that moment onstage.
Joe hart?
Won't cut his dreads.
I look like Erykah Badu.
Wait, what about puck's brother?
Can't he sing?
Not interested.
Why is it that we can't find
one dude to play the lead
in the school play?
Mercedes: Well, there aren't
a lot of dudes like you.
Even Mr. Shue had that problem
when he first started Glee Club.
That's why he went looking
for you.
(School bell ringing)
(Whistle blows)
Get them up!
Get your knees up. Let's go.
Hey, Coach.
Finn. There's no prize
for running the slowest!
Come on!
Good-looking bunch of
recruits this year.
Idiots on patrol.
But I'll knock them into shape.
Heck, I Coached you
to a state championship.
I'm kidding.
You're one of a kind.
I just wish
you still believed that.
Thanks, Coach.
It's just kind of hard to feel
that way about myself right now.
Give it time.
You're going through
the biggest change in your life.
Guys like you
always find their way.
You think you got any guys
like that out here today?
Searching for some
recruits of my own.
We need a male lead
for the musical.
What's his story?
Beiste:
Ryder Lynn, sophomore.
I think he flunked out
of his old school,
so they transferred him here.
Sweet enough kid,
but he's a loner and can't learn
to play for his life,
and if you ask me,
I say he's got a lazy streak.
Moves good, though.
You want to know the thing about
you that makes you special?
It's not the singing
or the dancing
or the way you threw the ball.
It's that you could move people.
Figure that Ryder kid's got
anything like that in him?
Bieste:
Maybe.
If he had the right guy
showing him the way.
Are you kidding me?
Huddle up!
Get over there!
(School bell ringing)
Hey, this is
the girls' bathroom.
I sit when I pee.
How psyched are you
for Grease auditions?
I want Sandy... so bad.
I'm not auditioning.
What?!
Why not?
You know you'd get a part.
I don't want a part;
I want the part: Rizzo.
No offense, Sandra Dee,
but Rizzo's the money
role of that show.
A hot bitch who thinks
she's pregnant,
and turns out to have
a heart of gold.
It's basically my life story.
But they won't
give me the role.
Everyone sees me
in drag as a joke or stunt
when we're performing.
But it would feel as weird
for me to play Danny Zuko
as it would for you.
Artie and those guys know that.
Just tell them you want
to audition for Rizzo,
and I'm sure they'll
give you a chance.
(Toilet flushing) You know,
the casual eavesdropper,
hearing the feminine
lilt of your voices,
would just assume you're
a couple of regular gals
yappin' away in the crapper.
But then the unmistakable
scent of talcum powder
and day-old panty hose
tells a different story.
Well, well, well, if it isn't
McKinley High's very own
Tina stomach-Turner,
and her trusty sidekick...
I'm trying to think of
a mean nickname for you
and I'm blanking.
But you, urethra Franklin,
you are a boy and you
are fooling no one.
You are smuggling more
kielbasa under those gowns
than a homesick Polish lady
trying to sneak through customs.
You can't say things like that.
Oh, I think you'll find
I can say anything I want,
absolutely stunning,
kind-faced, blue-eyed girl.
Now, I know full well
that gender confusion
is the liberal media's
new darling,
bored with drowning
the nation's airwaves
with tinny sitcoms so gay
that you have to stretch
a dental dam
over your television set
in order to watch them safely.
The Hollywood communists
are busy force-feeding us
drag queen reality shows
and soft profiles
of gender-confused
hormone-gobbling pre-teens,
who faint at the sight
of their own genitals.
There's no way in hell
you're gonna play Rizzo.
I will not allow you
to unleash a teenage maelstrom
of gender-bent sexual confusion
at this school,
so you can turn it around
and make it a launch party
for your very own line
of male girdles
and brand-new fragrance
call "nut whiff."
We don't care what you say.
We're both auditioning
for that musical.
(Pink's "blow me
(One last kiss)" Begins)
♪ White knuckles
♪ and sweaty palms from
♪ hanging on too tight
♪ clench of jaw
♪ I've got another
♪ headache again tonight
♪ eyes on fire, eyes on fire
♪ and the burn
from all the tears ♪
♪ I've been crying,
I've been crying ♪
♪ I've been dying over you
♪ tie a knot in the rope
♪ trying to hold,
trying to hold ♪
♪ but there's nothing to grab
♪ so I let go
♪ I think
I've finally had enough ♪
♪ I think I maybe
think too much ♪
♪ I think
this might be it for us ♪
♪ blow me one last kiss
♪ you think I'm
just too serious ♪
♪ I think you're full of it
♪ my head is spinning,
so blow me one last kiss ♪
♪ just when
it can't get worse ♪
♪ I've had a bad day
♪ you've had a bad day
♪ we've had a bad day
♪ I think that
life's too short for this ♪
♪ I'll pack
my ignorance and bliss ♪
♪ I think
I've had enough of this ♪
♪ blow me one last kiss
♪ da, da, da-da, da
♪ oh-oh, oh-oh...
♪ Blow me one last kiss
♪ I will do what I please
♪ anything that I want
♪ I will breathe,
I will breathe ♪
♪ I won't worry at all
♪ you will pay for your sins ♪
♪ you'll be sorry, my dear
♪ all the lies, all the lies
♪ will be crystal clear
♪ I think I've finally
had enough ♪
Unique: ♪ I think
I maybe think too much ♪
♪ I think this might
be it for us ♪
♪ blow me one last kiss
♪ you think
I'm just too serious ♪
♪ I think you're full of it
♪ my head is spinning so
♪ blow me one last kiss
♪ LA-LA, LA-LA, da-da, da-da
♪ LA-LA, LA-LA,
da-da, da-da ♪
♪ LA-LA, LA-LA, da-da, da-da
♪ blow me one last kiss
♪ just when it can't get worse
♪ I've had a bad day
♪ you've had a bad day
♪ we've had a bad day
♪ I think that life's
too short for this ♪
♪ I'll pack
my ignorance and bliss ♪
♪ I think I've had
enough of this ♪
♪ blow me one last kiss.
(Song ends)
(Whooping, applause)
Yeah! Bravo!
That had more energy
than the last three
auditions combined.
Ladies, do you have any preference
for the parts you want to play?
Sandy.
Definitely Sandy.
What about you, Wade?
I would like to play
the role of Rizzo.
(School bell ringing)
Finn:
Hey, Mr. Clippenger.
Uh, you got a phone call
in the teachers' lounge.
Why didn't they call my cell?
Hey, what are you doing?
Uh, studying.
In the study hall?
I think you're the first.
(Laughs) Uh...
I've got to work twice
as hard as everyone else
to do half as well.
I'm pulling a c-minus average
since I got here,
and if I don't get it
up to a B,
my parents are going to make me
quit football, so...
Whatever it takes, you know?
I'm-I'm sorry...
who are you again?
Uh, Finn is my name.
I graduated last year.
Played football, too.
Quarterback.
Oh. Awesome.
I also had a c-minus average
in my sophomore year,
but I graduated with
a b-plus.
Are you serious?
How did you do that?
Glee Club.
Learning the music and
the choreography,
it just... opened up
my brain somehow.
I'm not joining the Glee Club.
I mean, I hear it's fun, but...
I've got too much
on my plate already.
Start slow, then.
Come try out for the musical.
Who knows? Maybe it could be
like one of those gateway drugs.
I don't sing.
Prove it.
Auditions are at 4:00
in the auditorium.
See you then.
(School bell rings)
(Sighs) Another one?
I don't understand.
All I do is study.
I haven't even seen dark knight rises yet.
Oh, it was good.
Bane was a little hard
to understand, but so evil.
(School bell rings)
A director's job
is to make choices.
You have to pick one.
I-I don't know anything
about jukeboxes, Artie.
Well, that one is
a zodiac jukebox,
this is a wurlitzer bubbler...
a knockoff, I'd imagine,
because an original goes
for around 40 grand...
and that one is a seeburg...
you may recognize it
from the opening credits
of happy days.
Oh! Happy days is a show
from the '50s,
and so is Grease, so we should
use this one, right?
No, that's the exact
one we shouldn't use.
It's cliché.
I say we go with the zodiac.
But we're gonna have to change
the records in it.
It's filled with classic rock
from the '80s.
Ryder:
Hey.
Hey!
Auditions aren't
till 4:00, but...
I just want to make sure
I'm doing everything I can
to make my grades,
and if I'm dumb, then so be it,
but I want to be sure
I didn't miss anything.
Great.
So you want to audition, then.
As long as I don't have to sing.
(Laughs)
You know, I, uh...
I used to be just like you.
I didn't think that I
could do it, either...
But then...
I just did it.
No thinking.
I... I just started
singing and...
(Jukebox crackling, whirring) It
just started coming out of me and...
It felt awesome.
Like a really good poop.
Bet you're
a classic rock guy, right?
(Foreigner's "juke box hero"
begins playing)
Follow my lead.
♪ Standing in the rain
♪ with his head hung low
♪ couldn't get a ticket
♪ it was a sold-out show
♪ heard the roar of the crowd
♪ he could picture the scene
♪ put his ear to the wall
♪ then, like a distant scream
♪ he heard one guitar
♪ just blew him away
♪ he saw stars in his eyes
♪ and the very next day
♪ bought a beat-up six string
♪ in a second-hand store
♪ didn't know how to play it
♪ but he knew for sure
♪ that one guitar
♪ felt good in his hands
♪ it didn't take long
♪ to understand
♪ so he started rockin'
♪ ain't never gonna stop
♪ gotta keep on rockin'
♪ someday he's gonna
make it to the top ♪
♪ and be a jukebox hero
♪ got stars in his eyes
♪ he's a jukebox hero
♪ yeah, jukebox hero
♪ oh, oh-oh
♪ with that one guitar
♪ he'll come alive
♪ come alive tonight
(audience cheering)
(Guitar wailing)
♪ Yeah, he's gotta
keep a-rockin' ♪
♪ he just can't stop
♪ he just can't stop ♪
♪ gotta keep on rockin'
♪ that boy
has got to stay on top ♪
♪ he's gonna be
a jukebox hero ♪
♪ got stars in his eyes
♪ yeah, he's just
a jukebox hero ♪
♪ jukebox hero
♪ he's got stars in his eyes
♪ stars
♪ in his eyes...
(Song ends)
(Cheering fades)
Man, that was awesome.
So what do you think?
Should I audition?
Dude, you just did.
(Laughs)
(School bell ringing)
Hi. I'm Ryder Lynn.
I know.
I saw you in the football
game on Saturday.
You're end zone dances
are awesome.
Ah...
I'm Marley.
I know. I know.
Uh, your mom rules.
She always sneaks me extra
meatballs on spaghetti day.
Really?
Uh-huh.
(Both laugh)
Wow, she must really like you.
Uh, Finn Hudson told me
that you were probably
gonna play Sandy
in the school play.
I thought if we were gonna be
working together, I should say hi.
I think they want me
to play Danny.
What's that cologne you're
wearing, "jealousy by you"?
Uh, what am I jealous of?
Oh, just your girlfriend talking
to the hottest guy at McKinley
who also happens to be
a star football player
with yummy old-school
Justin Bieber hair.
She's not my girlfriend.
And who wants
Justin Bieber hair?
Half-black guys
who can't grow it.
Sorry, but you had that coming
since you broke up with me.
And nobody breaks up with me.
Which is why I've been
telling people I dumped you
because you have
a gross third nipple.
Now, if you'll excuse me...
Hey, Ryder.
Hey, Mona.
It's Marley.
Oh, right, "Marley,"
like the dead dog movie?
I heard you killed
your Grease audition.
And I know you're excited about
the prospect of playing Sandy
because everyone knows
poor people don't have
many opportunities to
actually enjoy anything.
Which is why it's gonna be
such a bummer when I
take the part from you.
You're auditioning?
I am.
By the way, Ryder, you should
know about this one's gene pool.
She's only got a month or two
before she starts ballooning
to her natural weight
of 5,000 pounds
and starts writing her memoir,
fifty shades of gravy.
Wow, you're kind of a bitch.
What'd she ever do to you?
Besides trying to steal away
my three-nippled
ex-boyfriend?
You cast yourself
as the poor little
simply adork-able
nice girl.
But I know, and you know,
and sweet baby Jesus
in the manger knows
what you really are: A
scheming little kiss-ass.
I'm single, by the way.
(School bell ringing)
Sign me up, too.
I thought you were too cool
for the school play.
Someone's got to keep you
from killing Marley.
And keep Marley from
fornicating Ryder.
I'm not as dumb as
you look, Puckerman.
I have the perfect
audition song for us.
Us?
(Neon trees'
"everybody talks" plays)
♪ Ah...
♪ ah...
(Clears throat)
♪ Hey, baby,
won't you look my way? ♪
♪ I could be
your new addiction ♪
♪ hey, baby,
what you gotta say? ♪
♪ all you're giving me
is fiction ♪
♪ I'm a sorry sucker,
and this happens all the time ♪
Both: ♪ I found out
that everybody talks ♪
♪ everybody talks,
everybody talks ♪
♪ it started with a whisper
♪ and that was when
I kissed her ♪
♪ and then she made
my lips hurt ♪
Both:
♪ I can hear the chitchat
♪ take me to your love shack
♪ mama's always
gotta backtrack ♪
♪ when everybody talks back
♪ hey, honey,
you could be my drug ♪
♪ you could be
my new prescription ♪
♪ too much can be an overdose
♪ all this trash talk
make me itchin' ♪
♪ oh, my, my, dear
♪ everybody talks,
everybody talks ♪
♪ everybody talks too much,
it started with a whisper ♪
♪ and that was when
I kissed her ♪
♪ and then she made
my lips hurt ♪
♪ I can hear the chitchat
♪ take me to your love shack
♪ mama's always
gotta backtrack ♪
♪ when everybody talks back
♪ everybody talks,
everybody talks ♪
♪ everybody talks, everybody
talks ♪
♪ everybody talks,
everybody talks back ♪
♪ it started with a whisper ♪
everybody talks, everybody talks ♪
♪ and that was when
I kissed her ♪
♪ everybody talks,
everybody talks ♪
♪ everybody talks, everybody
talks back... ♪
♪ uh! Mike: Oh!
(Cheering)
Oh!
Whoo!
Mercedes:
That was great, guys.
Okay, we need to do that thing
where we call people back.
What's that called?
Both:
Callbacks.
I don't know. I feel like Kitty
has the inside track on Sandy.
Sandy can't be brunette.
Oh, like Maria
couldn't be black?
That was a year ago,
Mercedes. Let it go.
Okay, so we call back all the Sandys
and the Dannys. What about the rest?
Brittany for cha-cha,
she's the best dancer.
You know, Tina would
make a great jan.
It's too bad she won't audition
because she refuses to be
in the same room with Mike.
Okay, what about Rizzo?
Now, I know it's way outside
of the box,
but I like Unique for it.
He wants it so badly.
He's the best singer, too.
So, we cast a brunette
as Sandy and a guy as Rizzo.
Who's directing this, Julie Taymor?
Think about how cool
it would be to do something
really different.
Though I don't agree
with your choices,
I appreciate your passion.
It's nice to have
the old Finn back.
Sue:
Finn Hudson?
In Principal Figgins'
office now.
Now, fatty!
(Bell ringing)
The twin idiots seated
before you are poised
to cast the she-male-fabulous
Unique Adams
as Rizzo in Grease;
The already overly sexualized
minstrel show
featuring teen pregnancy
and the ridiculously unnecessary
lubrication of lightning.
If they succeed,
they will set a legal precedent
that will clear the way
for Unique to become a Cheerio!
In the very year that I am set
to notch my 1,000th
tournament victory
and become the winningest coach
in cheerleading history.
Wait. When did Unique say
he wanted to be a Cheerio!?
Sue, I don't understand.
Unique Adams is nothing more
than an attractive,
buxom young woman
who's got it going on
in all the right places.
She's a brick house, Sue!
Uh, Principal Figgins,
Sue's right about that.
Unique is definitely a guy.
What? I don't see
what the big deal is.
If Unique identifies as a girl
and dresses
as a girl, she should be allowed
to play one onstage.
Cross-gendered casting
is as old as theater itself.
In Shakespeare's time, all the
female roles were played by men.
There's no way that's true.
In the last few years,
McKinley's become
the kind of place
where all kinds of outcasts
can feel free
to follow their dreams.
I don't think that should change
just because
Coach Sylvester's a bigot.
You know, I'd think twice
about calling someone a bigot
who's had gay Cheerios!, both
male and female on her squad,
and who resigned her post
as principal in protest
because this school
wasn't doing enough
to protect a gay student
from being bullied!
But you do have a point there,
mashed potato pants.
We've become somewhat of a
progressive bubble here at
McKinley High, and I think
that's due to the fact
that the Glee Club is being run
by a strange, weepy man-child
who has lotion
in his hair,
but no adult friends.
We live in Ohio.
And if you choose to cast Rizzo
with a naive,
gender-confused boy
in a dress,
I guarantee you someone...
Is going to raise
a very public stink about it,
and I don't think that's fair.
Don't put this kid in danger
because you want to make
some grand gesture
about how open-minded you are.
William, I spent the last year
stifling my natural hatred
for you and helping you win
a Glee Club
national championship.
Now is your moment
to pay me back by putting
a stop to this
so I don't have to.
It's not my call, Sue.
Finn and Artie are running
the musical this year,
and I trust them implicitly.
Enough! With all due respect,
this is none of your business.
I'm the director.
It's my decision.
William, maybe you need to
remind chubby-wan-Kenobi
of the daily nightmare that is
borne of being my enemy.
You can't threaten me, Sue.
I've already lost my girlfriend,
my future, my pride.
I've nothing more to lose.
I'm casting Unique,
and that's all there is to it.
And you know, I thought
that you would have known more
about being an underdog after
you helped us win nationals
and had a retarded baby,
but you...
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to say that.
That... that was the wrong word
to use. I apologize.
(School bell ringing)
You look more crooked
than Joe Theismann's leg.
It's just these places that the
realtor in Washington sent us.
They all have carpeting.
You know how many germs
and bugs and fluids
live in carpeting?
Call Stanley Steemer.
Cleaned carpets
that don't dry properly
can create kawasaki syndrome.
You know what the worst thing
you can do in a relationship is?
Besides hitting, of course?
Lie.
You don't want to go
with Will to Washington.
I saw it in your face
when you told him you would.
I have reservations; That is
much different from lying.
You know what they say
about reservations?
They won't seat you
till the whole party's there.
Dishonesty eats away
at a marriage.
You have to tell him
you don't want to go.
I can't. I can't get in the way
of his dreams.
That's what Terri did.
Pumpkin, Will loves you
like a farmer loves
his blue ribbon pig.
He'll understand.
I'm going. It's decided.
Then you'd better find
something to get excited about
doing down there besides him.
You know I love Will,
but I think you've spent
so much time working on being
his girl that you forgot
that the reason he's so into you
is because of all the things
you are besides that.
(School bell ringing) I've been
trying to see you since I got here,
but every time I get
near you, you disappear.
I was fine with our breakup.
Out of sight, out of mind.
But maybe you
could have called and asked
if I could handle you
choreographing
the school musical!
I'm sorry. Artie called me.
It seemed like a fun idea.
I didn't think you'd be upset.
Neither did I!
I know this is weird.
It's weird for me, too,
but if that's
what's stopping you
from auditioning for Grease,
then we have to
make this not weird.
There are still some
good parts left.
I'm sorry, I can't.
We could use you.
You're so talented.
I'm sorry. You're gonna have
to survive without my talent.
(Sighs)
(School bell ringing)
All right! You guys
killed your auditions,
but there can only be one Sandy
and there can only be one Danny.
The heart of Grease
is the Danny-Sandy romance.
This callback is all
about the chemistry.
We want to see how well you play
off each other. Is there heat?
Finn: We also want to see how
you sing and dance '50s-stye.
That's why we gave you the
audition song ahead of time.
I don't really read
music, so...
Mike:
It's okay.
Mercedes and I will get you started.
Kitty: Start away.
Everyone knows Kitty cat's
gonna finish it.
Oh, you have a lot
of attitude, little girl.
Let's see if you have the stuff
to back it up. Hit it.
(Sha na na's
"born to hand-jive" plays)
♪ Before I was born,
late one night ♪
♪ my papa said,
"everything's all right" ♪
♪ the doctor paid,
my mama laid down ♪
♪ well, they started bouncing
all around ♪
♪ 'cause the bebop stork
was about to arrive ♪
♪ mama gave birth
to a hand jive ♪
♪ I could barely walk
when I milked a cow ♪
♪ when I was three,
I pushed a plow ♪
Gentlemen?
♪ While chopping wood
♪ I moved my legs
♪ and they saw me dancing
when I gathered eggs ♪
♪ the townfolk clapped,
I was only five ♪
♪ he'll out-dance 'em all
♪ he was born to hand-jive
♪ oh yeah, yeah, yeah...
♪ Everybody... Artie: Break it up.
Break it up.
♪ Born to hand-jive, baby
♪ born to hand-jive,
baby ♪
♪ how low can you go?
♪ How low
can you go? ♪
♪ how low can you go?
♪ How low
can you go? ♪
♪ higher...
♪ Higher
♪ And higher, yeah
♪ now can you hand-jive, baby?
♪ Oh, can you
hand-jive, baby? ♪
♪ baby ♪ oh yeah
♪ can you hand-jive, baby?
♪ give me hand-jive
♪ oh, can you hand-jive, baby?
♪ Oh yeah ♪ oh yeah
♪ oh yeah ♪ oh yeah yeah
♪ oh yeah ♪ oh yeah
♪ born to hand-jive, oh yeah!
We did good.
(Whooping, laughing)
(School bell ringing)
Hey. I came to talk
to you about the play.
I get it.
I heard about
Coach Sylvester's meltdown.
I want to offer you the part.
but what about Coach Sue?
Well, Coach Sue isn't
directing the play.
I am.
So now all you got to worry
about is getting a curly way
***
and I'll take care of Coach Sue
or anybody else who
might try and st us.
Unique knows the song
and has the wig.
Good.
You okay?
I feel right
the men's locker room.
But I can't go into the girls'.
And I don't feel right
in men's clothing,
but I can't wear
dresses every day.
It's just nice, for once,
yeah, it is.
Well, uh...
(Sniffs)
Before I post the cast list,
I just need to Kat you're ready.
'Cause there's gonna be
a lot of heat on you,
and like I said, I can shield
you from some of it, but...
At the end of the day,
you're gonna be the one
out on that stage.
(School bell ringing)
All right, all right.
(Laughing)
Patty Simcox?
Who the hell is Patty Simcox?
I don't understand.
I pray really hard about this.
Maybe God didn't hear you
because he was busy
helping people with cancer.
Shut it, Avatar.
This is all your fault.
You screwed up "hand -jive."
No, I didn't.
We were both great.
It just didn't work out.
I've been hearing that
a lot lately from you.
Oh. One little thing,
honey boo boo.
I know a good, hot meal
is hard to resist,
especially when you're on
the free lunch program
but remember, the stage always
*** at least ten pounds.
In your case, it's close to 90.
So, when you and your mom,
strawberry hugryake,
are dumpster diving for your costume,
keep on picking till you
find something slimming.
Like a back hefty bag.
Kitty, my baby needs to be fed.
Emma, wow.
Did I forget it's one of
our anniversaries?
What? No.
(Sighs)
Your parents aren't
here, are they?
No no no. No, no.
I just thought I would, um,
challenge myself with
a few new recipes, that's all.
Okay. How many new recipes?
Uh, two or three.
Or seven. Sorry.
If you want, in just a couple
minutes, they'll be ready.
Just let them cool for a second.
Um...,
I just got home early
and I, uh, came across
these cookbooks
my mom got me when I got married
to Carl, and I thought you'd like it.
You know what? I've never
tried these. And I feel like
I do that sometimes, and it's
really not fair. Emma... ma.
Sometimes I need to try...
Emma.
Emma, stop.
Just... whatever it is,
just say it.
I don't want to go to
Washington with you.
Could you just sit down?
Just hear me out.
(Clears throat)
For the past three years,
all I've wanted
was to be your wife.
But then when I rely
stop to think about that,
I have no idea what
that means to me,
to be a wife.
You know? I, um...
I know what it meant to my mom.
It meant, you know,
having supper on the table
when my dad got home.
It meant lots of
"whatever you say, dear"s.
It was heroic doses of
clonopin and chardonnay, and...
That's not the life I want.
I know.
I love you.
I love you, but I love my job.
I love my kids.
I love helping my kids.
I love that you love your job,
and I... I am so
incredibly excited
for this job opportunity
for you, I really am.
But I am terrified
that if I go with you,
I'm gonna resent you.
And then I'm gonna pull away.
I would rather be here,
far from you
but feeling really close,
rather than close to you
but feeling really far away.
You upset?
No.
I me...
Do I like the idea of
not waking up next to you
every day for a few months?
Of course not.
But you're right.
I've spent so much
time talking about
getting married,
and no time talking about
what being a husband and
wife really means to us.
What does it mean to you?
Trust.
Having a partner I know I will
always be honest with me.
Who I know I will
always be honest with.
What about you?
Someone to accept me.
All of me.
Someone who I accept and adore.
Neither of us said someone
who is with me every minute,
or compromises their dreamsine.
No.
So... Then I guess
we're okay.
Um... we will
switch off weekends.
I'll come up or
you'll come down.
And then I will come home,
and then we will
finally get married.
(School bell ringing)
How you doing, buddy?
Yeah. Good. But...
How am I supposed to make
a car fly onstage
in the auditorium?
(Laughs)
You're really throwing yourself
into the musical, huh?
I guess they're wrong
when they say you
can't go home again.
Well, it's not about being
back in high school again.
I'm not interested in that.
I guess it's just...
Nice helping other people's
dreams come true.
It's called being a teacher.
I'm really gonna miss it.
Wait, what do you mean?
I'm leaving.
Not-not for good,
but for a few months.
I'm going to Washington
to fight to keep the as
alive in our schools.
I figure if I don't
take a stand now,
there won't be auditoriums
left to fly cars in.
But, Mr. Shue, you can't just
leave the Glee Club like that,
with no one in charge.
They need you.
(Sigh)
No, they need a leader.
Someone who understands
how to win,
but also understands that winning
is not more important than
doing the right thing,
or taking care of each other.
Someone who's really good at
making kids' dreams come true.
I spoke to Principal
Figgins about it,
and since Glee Club
is not an actual class,
we don't need a certified
teacher to run it.
We just need an adult.
Mr. Shue, I'm not an adult.
First of all,
I think maybe it's time
you start calling me Will.
And second how
you stood up to Sue.
How you went out and found Ryder.
You're ready.
And if you're willing, then
I can promise you that
there's no greater
joy in the world
than helping a young boy
like you turn into a man.
It's three months.
So what are you doing?
Will you take over the Glee Club?
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com