I got to meet a gang of people
at my mother's saloon.
You want to come? It's a
party for me, honest.
- I'd love to.
- Really? You mean it?
Why? Have you changed your mind?
No, no, I mean, I-I know
it isn't every day that a
glorified ziegfeld girl
like me asks you out.
Man: Thank you, Rachel,
that was lovely.
That's it?
All I needed to see.
It was a pleasure
reading with you.
And I loved you as Lancelot.
I saw the revival
of Camelot three times...
four, if you
include the bootleg
that my friend Kurt has, so...
(Clicks tongue)
Thanks.
Well, Paolo,
you're our Tony winner.
What did you think?
Aw, she's charming.
And she certainly looks
right for the part.
I just fear that
she's too young,
you know, too green?
That was my concern as well.
Lack of experience.
She'd be a discovery,
but it's such a risk.
Paolo: I mean, that
part, it's a mountain.
At her age, I never
could have pulled it off.
Now, where did we leave it
with Claire Danes' people?
(The Beatles'
"yesterday" begins)
♪ Yesterday
♪ all my troubles seemed
♪ so far away
♪ now it looks as though
♪ they're here to stay
♪ oh, I believe
♪ in yesterday
♪ suddenly
♪ I'm not half the girl
♪ I used to be
♪ there's a shadow
♪ hanging over me
♪ oh, yesterday
♪ came suddenly
♪ why he
♪ had to go
♪ I don't know
♪ he wouldn't say...
♪ I said
♪ something wrong
♪ now I long for yesterday
♪ hey, ye-ye-yesterday
♪ love was such an easy
♪ game to play
♪ now I need a place
to hide away ♪
♪ oh, I believe
♪ in yesterday
♪ why he had to go
♪ I don't know
♪ he wouldn't say
♪ I said something wrong
♪ now I long
♪ for yesterday
♪ hey, yeah
♪ oh, yesterday
♪ love was such
♪ an easy game to play
♪ now I need a place
to hide away ♪
♪ oh, I believe
♪ in yesterday
♪ ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ ooh-hoo.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(The Beatles' "Help!" playing)
(All whooping, cheering)
I don't think
we've ever spent two weeks
on an assignment, Mr. Shue.
Hey, the Beatles are so epic
that we need two weeks
to do them justice.
This week is all about the
early years of the Beatles,
when all they had was
a belief in each other
and a belief that together
they could do anything.
(Groans) The school year seems
like it's never ending,
and now we're wasting
two whole weeks
on a band from the 1940s?
Seriously, can anyone
still relate to the Beatles?
Pretty much the entire world.
Yeah, I can
definitely still relate.
Kitty:
Why?
Were the Beatles dyslexic
and cat-fished
by transsexuals?
And you wonder
why everybody hates you.
Marley:
When George Harrison was a kid,
he was made fun of 'cause
his dad was the bus driver.
Jake: John Lennon's dad
wasn't even around.
He walked out of John's
life when he was five.
I don't really know the Beatles;
I'm a little on the black side.
Artie: And Ringo starr was
a sickly little kid,
which probably means
he was sitting down a lot.
Will:
And they decided to form a band.
Which changed the world.
Now, you guys are
really gonna have
to challenge yourselves
this week.
Bring your a-plus games.
Perform these classic songs
in new and exciting ways.
If we can push ourselves
to a whole new level,
like the Beatles did constantly,
we can win back-to-back
national championships
and form
a new directions! Dynasty.
(All whooping, cheering)
(School bell ringing)
All right, see you
guys tomorrow.
Tina.
(Clears throat)
And speaking of...
Your chariot awaits.
Okay, we're moving
slower than Jonah hill
trying to get out
of the bathtub.
And everyone is staring.
Yeah, at our hotness.
You know, I never thanked you
for making me come
clean with my mom.
I'm going to the Brooklyn
film academy because of you.
And to thank you, I want
to take you to Breadstix.
Besides, we both know
that the raw, animal attraction
between us is undeniable.
Did you really just say that?
No wonder Tina
broke up with you.
And Brittany and sugar and
the girl in the wheelchair
with the disturbingly
massive boobs.
And ps, I hate Breadstix.
Okay, well, there's
a carnival in town.
That could be fun.
Yeah, if you want
to trust your life
to toothless carnies
who operate the rides.
Okay.
So is that a yes or a no?
(The Beatles'
"drive my car" begins)
♪ Asked a girl
what she wanted to be ♪
♪ she said
both:
♪ baby, can't you see?
♪ I want to be famous,
a star on the screen ♪
♪ but you can do something
in between ♪
♪ baby, you can drive my car
♪ yes, I'm gonna be a star
♪ and maybe I'll love you...
♪ I told the girl that my prospects
were good ♪ (All groaning)
♪ And she said, "baby..."
Both: ♪ it's understood are you kidding me?
Are you kidding me?
♪ Working for peanuts
is all very fine ♪
♪ but I can show you
a better time ♪
♪ baby, you can drive my car
♪ yes, I'm gonna be a star
♪ and maybe I'll love you
♪ beep-beep'm,
beep-beep, yeah... ♪
♪ I told that girl
I can start right away ♪
♪ and she said, listen, babe,
I got something to say ♪
♪ I got no car
and it's breaking my heart ♪
♪ but I found a driver
and that's a start ♪
♪ baby, you can drive my car
♪ yes, I'm gonna be a star
♪ and maybe I'll love you
♪ beep-beep'm, beep-beep, yeah
♪ beep-beep'm,
beep-beep, yeah ♪
♪ beep-beep'm, beep-beep, yeah
♪ beep-beep'm,
beep-beep, yeah ♪
♪ beep-beep'm, beep-beep
♪ yeah!
Tiger's my favorite, though.
I like the pink one.
Hey, Kitty-Kat.
Girl, you crashed
into me head-on.
I swear, you could have
paralyzed me.
My bad.
I'm Bree, spelled with two es.
Not like the funky cheese.
Artie.
You two were so cute,
all snuggly
and cuddled up
in that teeny, tiny car.
Are you two going out?
Nope. Just friends.
Well, you should.
You look really sweet together.
I hope you don't mind.
I took a couple of pictures
and instagrammed them.
Anyway, have fun.
She seems nice.
She's a stone-cold bitch
and she's out to destroy me.
(Phone buzzing)
Okay.
You and me...
We're more than "just friends."
What if we go out...
But we do it on the down-low?
You know, like secretly
gay conservatives do.
It'll make everything
all fun and forbidden.
So you like me...
But you don't want
to be seen with me.
I need status at this school
to survive.
Yeah, right.
(Car horns honking nearby)
(Siren blaring in distance)
(Whistle blows nearby)
This was a mistake.
Okay, no, Rachel, you
are not backing out.
I basically had to show
Gunther my left side boob
to get you this job.
Here, put this on.
Look, santana,
while I really appreciate
you freely prostituting
yourself for me,
that was before my
world came crashing down
and I totally blew my
funny girl chemistry read.
You're late, Lopez!
Yes, yes, I know,
sorry, Gunther.
Is that her?
Yes, this is her.
Rachel, that's Gunther.
Don't tell him if
you're Jewish or black.
Listen.
You said it yourself
a bazillion times.
You want to get to Broadway,
you have to pay your dues.
(Shrieks)
Well, I mean,
I guess that's true.
Patti Lupone was a waitress,
Pre-Evita.
And, you know, this is
the spotlight diner,
and it's on Broadway, and
waiters get to sing and dance.
Plus my dads would pay
my rent till I died,
and I don't want that anymore
because I want to be
grown up and living
and making it on my own.
We're basically
working actresses.
Blaine: So, you excited
to go back to school?
Kurt:
Yeah, fashion week is coming up.
But this farewell picnic's
been perfect, though.
What's the story
with this New York guy?
There's no story.
He was nice and people liked
the idea of us as a couple,
but never got serious.
All right,
let me break it down for you.
the last time we tried dating,
and I was in New York
and you were here,
you cheated on me.
All right, unacceptable.
We've been through this.
I thought you were done with me.
I thought it was over.
I thought I was completely
out of the picture in your life.
Look at me in the eyes
when I say this.
I'm being beyond serious.
I will never, ever...
Ever cheat on you again.
I'm gonna need you to sign one
of those non-cheating contracts.
You know, you can get one
on Oprah's web site.
I will sign whatever you want.
Just please say that you and I
can be boyfriends again.
What?
I don't know
if relationships actually work.
I mean, weren't Bethenny and
Jason supposed to be forever?
For every Bethenny and Jason,
there is a Will and a Jada,
and a-a Kurt and a Goldie.
Come on, can we at least
just give it a try?
But I'm Goldie, of course.
Of course you are.
I-I can't believe
we're gonna do this again.
I was hoping you would say yes.
Actually I was kind
of planning on it,
which I why I sort of, um,
put something together
to try to convince you
to stay a little longer.
Uh, no, no, no,
that's not gonna happen, okay?
I-I'm not sitting down
and listening to you
sing to me anymore.
Okay.
Which is why
I prepared something.
(Blows whistle)
(The Beatles' "got to get you
into my life" begins)
♪ I was alone, I took a ride ♪
♪ I didn't know what
I would find there ♪
♪ another road where maybe I
♪ could see another
kind of mind there ♪
♪ ooh
♪ then I suddenly see you
♪ did I tell you I need you
♪ every single day
♪ of my life?
♪ Got to get you into my life
♪ what can I do?
What can I be? ♪
♪ When I'm with you,
I want to stay there ♪
♪ if I'm true, I never leave
♪ and if I do, I
know the way there ♪
Both:
♪ ooh, then I suddenly see you
♪ ooh
♪ did I tell you I need you
♪ every single day
♪ of my life?
♪ Got to get you into my life
(musical interlude)
♪ I was alone, I took a ride
♪ I didn't know
what I would find there ♪
♪ another road where maybe I
♪ could see another kind
of mind there ♪
♪ and I suddenly see you
♪ did I tell you I need you
both:
♪ oh
♪ I got to get you
into my life. ♪
America, your prayers
have been answered.
Sue Sylvester is back
at McKinley.
Sure, I enjoyed my time away,
but once Becky Jackson
fessed up and started serving
her month-long suspension,
the school begged me to return,
but I knew if I was gonna
come back,
I had to come back big-time,
in a next level way.
Welcome back, Coach Sylvester.
It's Principal Sylvester.
I broke into Figgins' office
and planted
incriminating evidence
of every conceivable variety.
Man:
We've had some complaints.
Oh, Mr. Roberts.
What's going on?
I think you have a few
things in your desk
you may want to share with us.
Sue:
Gambling receipts,
porno mags...
We're gonna be
here for a while.
...gay porno mags,
gay foot fetish porno mags...
It's not mine!
That's puppy porn.
I'm telling you, it's not mine!
I go to church every Sunday,
for God's sake.
...a polygamous
marriage certificate,
a bill of sale granting
campus drilling rights
to a fracking company,
an autographed copy
of Mein Kampf.
I'm telling you, I am innocent!
Roberts:
Our hands are tied, Mr. Figgins.
Where am I supposed to go?
What am I supposed to do?
Well, superintendent
Harris, I have to say,
I'm truly humbled.
We're in a pinch here, coach,
and you're a proven champion.
You've led the school before
as interim principal,
and if all goes well
after a few months,
I see no reason
why this position
shouldn't become permanent.
Sue: Do I feel guilty
about what I did?
Not at all.
Jesus said it best:
"The end justifies the means."
Last time
I was acting principal,
I squandered an opportunity
for greatness.
This time
I'm going to get it right.
You're a monster, Sue Sylvester!
(The Beatles' "you've got
to hide your love away" begins)
♪ Here I stand, head in hand
♪ turn my face to the wall
♪ if she's gone
♪ I can't go on
♪ feeling two foot small...
♪ Everywhere people stare
♪ each and every day
♪ I can see them laugh at me
♪ and I hear them say...
Both:
♪ hey
♪ you've got to hide
♪ your love away
♪ hey
♪ you've got to hide
your love away ♪
♪ how could she say to me
♪ love will find a way?
♪ Gather 'round
♪ all you clowns
♪ let me hear you say...
♪ Hey
♪ you've got to hide
your love away ♪
♪ hey, you've got to hide
♪ your love away
♪ oh
♪ hey
♪ you've got to hide
♪ your love away
♪ oh, hey
♪ you've got to hide
your love away. ♪
(School bell ringing)
Okay, listen up, everybody.
Come on.
Blaine has a very special
announcement to make.
That's right.
(Clears throat)
So, as most of you know already,
um, Kurt and I are
officially back together.
(Cheering)
I know,
but what most of you don't know,
and this is top secret,
is that I'm going
to ask Kurt to marry me.
Yeah, guys, come on!
Get up! Come on, guys!
He's my best friend.
Gay marriage... good.
It's good, it's good things.
They're all happening so fast.
- Let's go!
- Sam, not now.
Anyway, I want this proposal
to be just incredible,
so I'm asking for
all of your help,
but I'm also asking for some
of our competitors' help.
Like the warblers
and vocal adrenaline
and the Haverbrook
school for the deaf.
(Scoffs)
Vocal adrenaline? No, ma'am.
The warblers are
evil incarnate little craps.
Are you crazy? Are you insane?
Good God,
have you lost your mind?
Tina, everybody,
hear him out.
Look, I want this to be more
than just an ordinary proposal.
I want this
to be a cultural statement.
Sure you do.
Hey, our generation
is at a turning point.
People everywhere...
except, like, Russia...
are beginning to see
that it doesn't matter
who you are
or where you're from
or even what God you believe in.
They're beginning to see
that people
really aren't
all that different.
And honestly, if we can get a
bunch of cutthroat show choirs
to stand side-by-side
and unite in something,
then anything is possible.
Okay, okay,
but Blaine is just using
the world of rival glee clubs
as a metaphor
for this incredible time
we're in right now.
(Quietly): But I still
think you're too young.
♪ Help! I need somebody
♪ help! Not just anybody
♪ help!
♪ You know I need someone
♪ When I was younger,
so much younger than today ♪
♪ I never needed
♪ anybody's help in any way
♪ but now these days are gone
♪ I'm not so self-assured
♪ now I find
I've changed my mind ♪
♪ and opened up the doors
♪ help me if you can
♪ I'm feeling down ♪ down ♪
♪ and I do appreciate
♪ you being 'round ♪ 'round ♪
♪ help me get my feet
♪ back on the ground
♪ won't you please
♪ please help me?
♪ And now my life has changed
♪ in, oh, so many ways
♪ my independence seems
to vanish in the haze ♪
♪ but every now and then
♪ I feel so insecure
♪ I know that I
♪ just need you like
♪ I've never done before
♪ help me if you can
♪ I'm feeling down ♪ down ♪
♪ and I do appreciate you
being 'round ♪
♪ 'round ♪
♪ help me get my feet
♪ back on the ground
♪ won't you please,
please help me? ♪
♪ When I was younger
♪ so much younger than today
♪ I never needed anybody's help
in any way ♪
♪ but now these days are gone
♪ I'm not so self-assured
♪ and now I find
I've changed my mind ♪
♪ I've opened up the doors
♪ help me if you can,
I'm feeling down ♪
♪ down ♪
♪ and I do appreciate you
being 'round ♪
♪ 'round ♪
♪ help me get my feet back
on the ground ♪
♪ won't you please,
please help me? ♪
♪ Help me, help me, ooh.
We need an official vote,
but in the spirit of brotherhood
and cleaning up
our tarnished reputation,
I think we'd all be happy
to help.
Uh, Trent, we said
I'd do the talking.
All in favor of helping Blaine?
All:
Aye!
(All whooping)
Artie, we've been
friends for a long time,
so I'm just gonna ask,
are you and Kitty an item?
What? No.
I mean, yes.
I mean, maybe.
I'm unclear. It's sort of this
secret affair
we're not really supposed
to talk about.
Yes! I knew it!
Why? Why can't you?
Lower your voice, Tina.
Because Kitty's uncomfortable
with people knowing
she's dating...
Someone who wears glasses
who's in a wheelchair
who's in glee club?
Where's your self-respect?
Tina, I know you're trying
to help.
Like, at least I think you are.
So I'm gonna say thank you.
(School bell ringing)
All right, got your burger
and your salad. Enjoy.
Oh, my God, you're not gonna
believe this text
I just got from Blaine.
You're not gonna believe
who's sitting in my section.
Mmm, I'll take this.
Okay, so we have one Roxie
and one Velma,
a side of Billy Flynns.
Yes, it's me,
and, yes, it's awkward,
but I don't care,
because I am a professional.
Even when people are calling me
"too young" or-or "green,"
which, for your information,
I'm not.
I am a...
Am a star.
Yes, I am a star.
Rachel, look,
it's not personal.
Everyone thinks they're a star,
even when they're not.
Look around.
They all want
to be on Broadway.
Look, I'm not saying
you're not a star, Rachel.
Just saying
I'm not sure just yet.
I understand.
I guess I'll just have
to prove it to you, then.
(The Beatles' "a hard day's
night" begins)
♪ It's been a hard day's night
♪ and I've been working
like a dog ♪
♪ it's been a hard day's night
♪ I should be sleeping
like a log ♪
♪ so why on earth
should I moan? ♪
♪ 'Cause when I get you alone,
you know I feel okay ♪
♪ when I'm home
♪ everything seems to be right
♪ feeling you holding me tight
♪ tight, yeah
♪ it's been a hard day's night
♪ and I've been working
like a dog ♪
♪ it's been a hard day's night
♪ I should be sleeping
like a log ♪
♪ but when I get home to you
♪ I find the things
that you do ♪
♪ will make me feel all right
♪ ow!
♪ So why on earth
should I moan? ♪
♪ 'Cause when I get you alone
♪ you know I feel okay
♪ when I'm home
♪ everything seems to be right
♪ feeling you holding me tight
♪ tight, yeah
♪ it's been a hard day's night
♪ and I've been working
like a dog ♪
♪ it's been a hard day's night
♪ I should be sleeping
like a log ♪
♪ but when I get home to you
♪ I find the things
that you do ♪
♪ will make me feel all right
♪ you know I feel all right
♪ you know
I feel all right. ♪
(Song ends, patrons cheering)
Let's get out of here.
Wait... after all that?
We have to go home.
There's something special
we need to do.
(Cheering continues)
I don't know what
you're so nervous about.
She's not going after
the cheerios!
It's the glee club she hates.
Bitch, please.
Sue Sylvester's had it out
for me since day one.
I took her job, remember?
I just know she's dug up
all kind of dirt on me.
What kind of dirt?
Number one, this bronze
damn olympic medal
in individual synchronized
swimming I won
at them Chinese Olympics
may have been
the result of some performance-
enhancing drugs and weed.
Number two, I may have
perpetrated a buttload
of credit card fraud.
An old lady in Florida
may have paid for my condo,
and I might have just
flat-out stole my lexus
off a used car lot.
Well, then, yeah,
we're both screwed.
Sue's gonna take out
the glee club
and the cheerios!
In one fell swoop.
Oh, now why on earth would I do
something like that, Buttchin?
Because you're vindictive
and petty.
Oh, well, you're forgetting
one thing, William.
I have been given the post of
interim principal at this school.
A post that will be made
permanent
at the end of the year
if all goes according to plan,
allowing me to demolish
this office down to the studs,
ridding it once and for all
of the deep, ethnic musk
that is Figgins' hallmark.
Now, in order to achieve that,
I need the programs
at this school to be successful.
I need the teams
at McKinley high to be winners.
Wait, wait,
y-you're not firing us?
Not if you win a national
championship, I'm not.
However, if you fail to win at
Nationals, I will fire you.
You'll be forced to build
creepy relationships
with teenagers on your own time.
And you, you'll have to go back
to being a full-time spokesmodel
for Billy Dee Williams'
yellow hair helmets
for women who couldn't possibly
be less blonde.
Congratulations.
You're on my watch now,
which means...
You're winners.
Okay, guys, week one of
our Beatles fest has been epic.
I think we've really unpacked
what made the fab four
such a instant sensation,
but now I want to turn to their
oft-ignored middle period.
Mr. Shue, would you say
that the early Beatles looked
out for each other
even when they didn't want
to be looked out for?
Oh, God, no.
If I understand your question,
Tina,
yes, the early Beatles
always had each other's backs.
In that case, I'm sorry, Artie,
but this
is for your own good.
Everyone, Kitty and Artie
are dating,
but Kitty's making Artie hide it
because she's embarrassed
by him,
and I think
that's emotional abuse.
Artie is a great guy, and
he deserves to be loved openly
and proudly
and without conditions.
For once we agree.
It's true.
Arthur and I are dating.
We are? Officially?
And for the record... and not
that it's anyone's business,
especially not yours,
Tina Cohen-agitator...
I did want to keep it hush-hush.
Because you were ashamed.
Yes, memoirs of a lame geisha,
because I occupy
a certain place
in the McKinley hierarchy,
and you all occupy a different,
lesser place in that hierarchy,
and before exploding
said hierarchy
by jumping up and down
on Oprah's couch,
declaring my undying love for
someone who is, let's face it,
not my usual body type...
I wanted to be sure.
Of what?
That I really, really liked him.
And that I would be willing
to risk
not just my social standing
but also getting hurt
by letting him wheel
into my heart.
And even though I know
he's getting ready to graduate,
and we're probably just
as doomed as every other sad,
broken, backwards relationship
that's ever started
in this Jesus-and love-forsaken
choir room...
Kurt and I will have
a happy ending.
But I do like you, Artie.
You make me laugh,
and not just with those stupid
YouTube fail videos
you're always showing me.
Look, asking you to keep
our stuff private wasn't cool,
and I'm sorry.
It's okay, Kitty.
But, um, as far as, like,
updating my Facebook status...
Yes, we are officially,
publicly, shockingly
a thing.
(All cheer)
You guys...
(School bell ringing)
Do any of you know
why I call you in here?
Uh, is it to get prepared
in case
the North Koreans invade
through Mexico?
I just saw red dawn, okay?
It could happen.
One of our own has turned
into a mean, bitter,
and angry person.
Tina. Tina. That'd be Tina.
She didn't used to be like this.
She was a sweet girl who dated
Artie until he dumped her
because he found out
she was faking her stutter.
And then she dated Mike Chang
until he dumped her
because she wasn't Asian enough
or something.
Wait... is that really why
he dumped her? Yeah.
Look, the point is, is that
it's time for us to step in.
She's falling apart.
I walked by
the too young to be bitter club
meeting this morning, and
she was the only one in there.
Those cakes are truly awesome.
Dude, those things were moist
and chocolaty at the same time.
Totally, totally.
Guys, this isn't
about the cakes.
I know how good they are.
I've had them, too.
This is about us trying
to help Tina.
Oh, of course, Blaine.
You know, even though this is
all clearly your fault,
you know, whatever you think
we should do, we're in.
Ah, settling in nicely,
then, are we?
You know, I think you
found your calling.
Janitor Figgins, I think,
has a quiet dignity to it.
You're not gonna get away
with this, Sue.
Well, I believe I already have.
And considering all
the scandalous behavior
that I recently uncovered,
I would say you are lucky
to have a job at all.
You had better be nice to Donna.
That woman is a Saint.
And she's my rock.
I'm afraid Donna isn't long
for this world.
As soon as she returns
from her suspension,
I plan on installing Becky
as my secretary.
And I will refer
to her as my "beckretary."
(Chuckles)
What is that?
That? Well, that's just
a five-gallon bucket
of expired grade D meat slurry
the poor kids at this school
were forced to eat
every taco Tuesday under
the jackboot of that corrupt,
decadent regime from which
they were recently liberated
by one Sue Rodham Sylvester.
That's not your middle name.
Oh, yes, it is.
I had it legally changed
this morning.
(Chuckles) Now, what would you
like me to do with this canister
of rancid horse offal?
No, Sue, please! No!
(Distorted):
No!
Sue Sylvester!
You are a monster!
Tina:
What is happening
and why did you
make me wear this?
I had to break out
one of the grease costumes.
(British accent):
Tina, I'm Paul.
That's George, that's Ringo,
and black John Lennon.
Half black.
(Cockney accent): We love
you, and this is for you.
One, two, three, four!
(Playing the Beatles'
"I saw her standing there")
(Girls screaming)
♪ Well, she was just 17
♪ and you know what I mean
(screaming)
♪ and the way she looked
♪ was way beyond compare
(girls whooping)
♪ So how could I dance
with another ♪
♪ ooh
♪ when I saw her
♪ standing there?
♪ Well, my heart went boom
♪ when I crossed that room
♪ and I held
her hand in mine... ♪
(Screaming)
♪ Whoa, we danced
through the night ♪
♪ and we held each other tight
♪ and before too long
♪ I fell in love with her
(Screaming)
♪ Now I'll never dance
with another ♪
♪ ooh
♪ since I saw her
standing there ♪
♪ ow...!
(Girls screaming)
Come on, dance!
Hey!
(Screaming, whooping)
♪ Whoa, we danced
through the night ♪
♪ and we held each other tight
♪ and before too long
♪ I fell in love with her...
(Screams)
♪ Now I'll never dance
with another ♪
♪ ooh
♪ since I saw her
♪ standing there...
(Screaming)
(Sobbing) ♪ oh, since I saw her
♪ standing there
♪ yeah, well, since I saw her
♪ standing there.
(Cheering)
That was awesome.
But I don't understand
what it was for.
Well, we saw how lonely
you've been lately.
And since we're the only
single guys left in glee club...
And by single,
we mean single prom dates...
We just wanted
to offer our services
as dance partner
or corsage buyer
or just general arm candy
for the big dance.
Yeah, so you can pick one.
And it's your choice.
Obviously I'm excluded.
Well, it's hard to pick.
Ryder has arms
and Blaine is my boo,
but I think I'll go with Sam,
because he's the least gay
and least Asian of all of you
and I'm looking
to change my patterns.
Seriously, though...
Thank you, guys.
I really needed this.
Bring it in, Tina.
Oh, I love you.
I love you.
Thank you, boo.
(Indistinct conversation)
Look, I, uh, know
we usually take
the highway to the airport,
but somebody told me
about this shortcut
through the back roads.
Dad, you can stop it.
I know you're driving me
to my surprise proposal.
I should have known you knew.
You're the kid who planned
his own surprise party
for his tenth birthday.
That Justin Timberlake piñata
was a perfect likeness.
Well, I wouldn't know.
You okay?
You look like I'm driving you
to your execution.
I can't tell.
I mean, I really
love Blaine, and...
He makes me feel so connected
and safe and loved,
and I don't think I'm ever
gonna find someone else
who's gonna make me
feel like that.
But we're both so young.
Um...
Your mom and I met
when we were 22,
and I asked her to marry
me six months in.
We were just kids.
Yeah...
It was really hard at first.
You know, you go in
with all these fantasies
about what your life together
is gonna be like:
Nothing but laughing
and dancing around
in your underwear,
cooking pasta,
and sex.
A lot of sex.
(Kurt sighs)
It's hard being married, though.
It's hard enough
being in your 20s.
Do you wish you'd waited?
Not one second more.
I wish I'd met her
ten years earlier.
I didn't know then that
I was only going to get
so much time
with her, you know?
That she was gonna
leave us so soon.
I'd take 50 more years
of late-night fights
about, you know,
me working late
or the gas bill
or her letting the milk
go bad for just...
Ten more minutes
with her next to me.
We only get a few days
when you come down to it, Kurt.
You know that
better than anyone.
Look, totally
being honest here...
Blaine asked me
what I thought about this,
and I gave him my opinion.
Which was?
My opinion doesn't matter here.
You're your own man now.
But giving you a choice
means you gotta make one.
So relax.
Hear what the guy has to say.
I mean, all you gotta do
is say yes, no, or maybe.
Is there another option?
(Laughs)
(The Beatles'
"all you need is love" begins)
♪ Love, love, love
♪ love, love, love ♪
♪ love, love, love
♪ there's nothing you can do
that can't be done ♪
♪ nothing you can sing
that can't be sung ♪
♪ nothing you can say
♪ but you can learn
how to play the game ♪
♪ it's easy
♪ nothing you can make
that can't be made ♪
♪ no one you can save
that can't be saved ♪
♪ nothing you can do
♪ but you can learn
how to be you in time ♪
♪ it's easy
♪ all you need is love
♪ all you need is love, love
♪ love is all you need
♪ nothing you can know
that isn't known ♪
♪ nothing you can see that isn't
shown ♪
♪ there's nowhere you can be
♪ that isn't where
you're meant to be ♪
♪ it's easy
♪ all you need is love
♪ all you need is love, love
♪ love is all you need
♪ love is all you need ♪
♪ all you need is love
♪ love ♪
♪ all you need is love, love
♪ love is all you need
♪ love is all you need ♪
♪ he loves you,
yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ love is all you need ♪
♪ he
loves you, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ love is all you need ♪
♪ he loves you, yeah
♪ yeah, yeah.
(Cheering)
We met right here.
I took this man's hand,
and we ran down that hallway...
And for those of you
that know me,
know I'm not in the habit
of taking people's hands
I've never met before, but...
I think that
my soul knew something
that my body and my mind
didn't know yet.
It knew that our hands
were meant to hold each other,
fearlessly
and forever.
Which is why
it's never really felt like
I've been getting to know you;
it's always felt like I was
remembering you from something.
As if in every lifetime
that you and I have ever lived,
we have chosen to come back
and find each other
and fall in love all over again,
over and over for all eternity.
And I just feel so lucky
that I found you
so soon in this lifetime,
because all I want to do,
all-all I've ever
wanted to do...
Is spend my life loving you.
So...
Kurt Hummel...
My amazing friend,
my one true love...
...will you marry me?
Yeah. Yeah.
(Cheering)
♪
Beautiful.
(Laughs)
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com