__
WOMAN:
Show circle, everybody.
Welcome to Nationals.
(cheering)
I want you guys
to remember something.
Glee Club is not
about competition.
It's about something deeper.
Glee is about
opening yourself up to joy.
ALL:
Whoa...!
It's time.
(sighs)
Can't remember the last time
I was this nervous.
Oh, well, you don't
look nervous at all.
You look great.
Are you ready?
Yeah.
ANNOUNCER: 20, count 'em,
20 of this nation's
best high school show choirs
have poured out their talent
all over this stage.
And now we're down
to the best of the best.
From Greenville, South
Carolina, the Harmony Busters.
(audience cheers, applauds)
From Lima, Ohio,
the New Directions!
(audience cheers, applauds)
And from Portland, Oregon,
the Soprano-gasms.
(audience cheers, applauds)
Only one of these amazing teams
can claim the title
of the best high school
show choir in America.
In third place,
it's the Harmony Busters.
(audience cheers, applauds)
And now, the first place winner
of the 2015 high school show
choir nationals championship is
the New Directions!
♪ ♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(school bell ringing)
Uh, uh, I-I'm sorry.
Would you mind
saying that again?
I-I'm not sure
I understood you correctly.
The District Board of
Education has decided
to make McKinley an arts school.
In a very short time from now,
you and I will be standing
in the choir room
of the William McKinley
High School
for the Performing Arts.
Wh-Wh-What happened?
To be completely honest, Will,
you happened.
Over the last decade,
school districts across the
country have been facing
multi-million dollar
budget shortfalls.
Yeah.
And our quick fix was
eliminating arts
programs altogether.
Prioritizing what we
would hope would be
more essential subjects
like math, reading, science.
You know what?
We were wrong.
Scores did not go up.
In fact, in some places,
they got worse.
But you... you refused
to let that stop you.
And I decided it was time
for me to stick my neck out
and make a pitch to the board.
And to my great surprise,
they agreed with me.
Superintendent Harris, I mean...
this is incredible news.
Please, please,
if-if there's anything
I can do to help,
just-just let me know.
What are you talking about?
I'm gonna have you
run the school.
Uh, I beg your pardon?
I'm making you principal, Will.
Congratulations.
WILL:
Okay.
Wait, now, remember.
What? That cookie
is for dessert.
Oh, come on.
Okay?
That is not an appetizer,
all right?
Now that you're the principal,
you have to set
a good nutritional example
for the other teachers...
I don't know if I can
live up to that standard.
You're just gonna have
to come have lunch with me
every single day.
Oh, my goodness, Will.
Will...!
(laughing)
We have to do everything
possible to be appropriate
and professional now
that you are management.
(sighs deeply)
I am never gonna have to worry
about getting funding
for another Glee Club costume
or paint brushes or tap shoes
for a kid who can't afford them.
Our son will be in the day care
that we set up in the gym.
And my beautiful wife
will be right down the hall,
working tirelessly to help kids
get into the best arts
colleges in the world.
Oh, my goodness.
I'm so proud of you, Will.
It has been quite a journey
to get to this place.
And you've made it the whole way
without losing your integrity.
Except for those days
when you were rapping.
(laughs)
Can I be honest with
you about something?
I am scared to death.
Do I have the talent
to actually do the job?
Will, you're the most
talented man in the world.
Or at least in Ohio.
That's more like it.
(chuckling):
Right.
I'm serious... you don't have
anything to be scared about.
I'm not saying that
it's gonna be easy,
but I am saying now is
the time for you and I
to relax and have fun...
Yeah.
...and be in
love, right?
Because if we don't like
something now, we can...
you know, we can fix it.
So no more bad guys.
It is just you and me
and the power of
our imaginations.
I love you so much.
I love you.
Now go get
your son, Mr. Shue,
and I will see you at school.
(sighs) All right.
You see that, Danny?
Dreams really do come true.
Yeah.
(chuckles)
Here he is!
(cheering, whooping)
Wow, um...
I have to say this is
the most exciting first day
of Glee Club
that we have ever had.
No offense to the alumni
who have been here
since the very first-ever
Glee Club meeting.
(sighs)
All right, please,
everyone, have a seat.
(clears throat)
So, Mr. Shue when are you
gonna start auditions?
KURT: Yeah, I think you're
gonna have trouble sticking
to your whole "whoever wants in,
gets in" rule.
Not true, Mr. Hummel.
The New Directions!
will be only one
of the glee clubs
at this school.
I'm bringing back
the Troubletones
and starting an all-boys version
called the Duly Noted.
And we're also gonna have
a junior varsity squad
for those who feel like they
need a little seasoning
before they're ready
for the big time.
So, wait, how are you gonna
teach all those glee clubs
and run a school?
I'm not.
I'm actually not coaching
any of them.
Not even the New Directions?
Well, uh, I've interviewed a...
a candidate for that particular
job that I really like.
But until then,
I wanted to say farewell
to you all
with a song that I prepared
for this occasion.
My life changed...
because of all the magic
that we created in this room.
And if I've learned one thing,
it's the message in the lyrics
of this song.
This is for you guys.
(plays Crosby, Stills, Nash &
Young's "Teach Your Children")
♪ You ♪
♪ Who are on the road ♪
♪ Must have a code ♪
♪ That you can live by ♪
♪ And so ♪
♪ Become yourself ♪
♪ Because the past ♪
♪ Is just a good-bye ♪
♪ Teach ♪
♪ Your children well ♪
♪ Their father's hell ♪
♪ Will slowly go by ♪
♪ And feed ♪
♪ Them on your dreams ♪
♪ The one they picks ♪
♪ The one you'll know by ♪
♪ Don't you ever ask them why ♪
♪ If they told you,
you would cry ♪
♪ So just look at them
and sigh... ♪
♪ And know they love you ♪
♪ You ♪
♪ Of tender years ♪
♪ Can't know the fears ♪
♪ That your elders grew by ♪
♪ And so please help ♪
♪ Them with your youth ♪
♪ They seek the truth ♪
♪ Before they can die ♪
♪ Teach ♪
♪ Your parents well ♪
♪ Their children's hell ♪
♪ Will slowly go by ♪
♪ And feed ♪
♪ Them on your dreams ♪
♪ The one they picks ♪
♪ The one you'll know by ♪
♪ Don't you ever ask them why ♪
♪ If they told you,
you would cry ♪
♪ So just look at them
and sigh... ♪
♪ And know they love you. ♪
(applause, whooping)
(no voice)
(grunting):
Come on... a little...
Hey, what are you doing?
Oh, uh, just a little inventory.
We got to do it
before we sell all this stuff.
I mean, all these balls are
under one PSI, so...
they're basically, uh, useless
unless we fill them up
to 12.5.
So listen, um,
considering that you're
going to be unemployed
somewhat soon, I was wondering
you'd given
any thought to maybe,
I don't know,
moving back to New York.
We have this spare room
for you... it-it's perfect.
It's really small; it's more of,
like, a closet, really, but...
Uh, yeah.
No, we talked about this before.
I told you that
New York's not my speed.
It's too fast; it's too loud;
there's too many sports teams,
so I get confused on who I'm
supposed to root for.
We just root
for whichever one's winning.
Okay, that's something
Kurt would say.
That's what happens
when you get married.
Kurt and I are
really happy, all right?
That's good. W-We're having
a very good life together.
We see everybody...
We see Rachel,
we see Artie, Brittany,
Santana, Kitty...
It's a lot of fun,
but I miss my best friend.
Dude, I miss you,
too, man, you know?
But this is home, okay?
I need to be out in
the wide-open spaces.
I need to be able to just
go out on the weekends
and just shoot
stuff if I want to.
Look, I'm happy.
I am genuinely happy here, okay?
This is where I'm meant to be.
I just don't want you
to waste all of your talent.
I'm not... I'm using all of
my talent in my new job.
All right.
Congratulations to all of you.
You have been selected
as the best of the best.
You are this year's
New Directions!
Now I would like to introduce
you all to your new teacher,
Mr. Sam Evans.
Wait, hold on, no.
Y-You're taking over
the glee club?
Jealous?
Yeah.
I could not be more proud
to pass the baton off to you.
Go get 'em, buddy.
All right, all right, all right.
So look,
I've been thinking a lot
about the first week's lesson.
This week, your assignment is...
...country!
Uh-oh.
Let's see
where he goes with this.
Country and blues come
from the same roots.
The hardship of a rural life.
Country uses little
personal stories
about breakups or
broken-down pickups
to express the deeper pains
of poverty and anxiety
that was in still, uh, such a
normal part of life
in the American South.
Now, if we want to be great,
we need to be able
to sing about hurt and loss.
And even if we can't
relate to the specifics,
make them our own.
So who wants to start us off
with a country song?
Let's do "She Thinks
My Tractor's Sexy."
(others enthusiastically agree)
MAN:
Yeah.
WOMAN:
Okay.
Well, looks like we're all
right where we belong.
I wouldn't have it
any other way.
MERCEDES:
Okay, wait.
Stop right there.
I just want you guys
to come in and listen,
because I have to get
through this without crying.
Okay, I have officially
been picked up
to be the opening act
for Beyoncé's new world tour.
(gasping, all talking excitedly)
MERCEDES:
Effective immediately.
- Yay!
- MERCEDES: I know.
You know,
ever since I've been back,
I've just been
walking these halls,
trying to remember
how invisible I used to feel.
And the funny thing is...
It's getting really hard
to remember that Mercedes.
Even when I got
the call earlier,
I didn't think, "Oh, this must
be some kind of mistake,"
or, you know,
"They must not mean me."
That's because of you guys.
Having friends like you
really did change me.
You made me know
that good things are possible.
It's not really... it's not
really that common to come by...
and I'll remember you guys
for it.
No, no, no, no,
do not come up here,
because that is not
even the hard part,
and if you come up here now,
I am gonna lose it,
and I am determined to walk out
of here with some class.
So, between
the tour and rehearsals and
me cutting an album right after,
I won't be seeing you guys
for a while.
Maybe even a-a long while.
You know, we'll keep in touch,
but it's not gonna be the same,
and I think that we've all had
enough group hugs
that can last us a lifetime.
So, I wanted to say good-bye
my way... with a song.
And then, I want to walk
out of here...
like I'm gonna be seeing
everybody in Glee Club tomorrow,
and like it's not
really good-bye.
(Diana Ross & The Supremes'
"Someday We'll Be Together" begins)
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ We'll be together ♪
♪ We'll be together,
yeah-ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ You're far away ♪
♪ From me, my love ♪
♪ Ooh, baby ♪
♪ But just as sure,
my, my baby ♪
♪ As there are stars above ♪
♪ I wanna say,
I wanna say, I wanna say ♪
♪ Someday we'll be together ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ We're gonna be together,
be together, baby ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ We'll be together ♪
♪ We'll be together,
oh-oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ A long time ago,
my, my sweet thing ♪
♪ I made a big mistake, honey ♪
♪ I-I-I... say,
I-I-I-I said good-bye ♪
♪ Oh, oh, baby, ever ♪
♪ Ever ♪
♪ Ever and ever
and ever and ever ♪
♪ Ever since
that day now, now, now ♪
♪ All I ♪
♪ All I wanna do ♪
♪ Oh, is cry, cry, cry ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ I long for you ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh, baby ♪
♪ Every, every night ♪
♪ Ooh, just to kiss
your sweet, sweet lips, baby ♪
♪ Just to kiss your sweet lips ♪
♪ Hold you ever, ever so tight ♪
♪ I wanna say, ooh... ♪
♪ I wanna say ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Oh! ♪
♪ We'll be together ♪
♪ Yeah-ah-ah,
ah-ah-ah-ah, ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ Ooh, someday ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ We'll be together ♪
♪ Yeah, we'll be together,
yes, we will ♪
♪ Ooh, someday ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ We'll be together ♪
♪ I, I-I-I-I-I, I know ♪
♪ Ooh, someday ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ We'll be together! ♪
(song ends)
Mercedes Jones has left
the building.
(Blaine clears his throat)
Oh, hello, Porcelain.
Mrs. Porcelain.
What are you doing, Sue?
Well, I just came in to, uh,
drink in the old office
one last time,
and to drop a hot one
in the middle of Will's desk.
But that seemed childish, so,
I, uh, just peed everywhere.
Can you have a seat
for-for a second?
We wanted to talk to you.
As you probably already know,
Blaine and I are leaving
for New York in a few days,
but before we leave,
we wanted to thank you for
getting us back together.
If it hadn't been for you,
we would still be apart,
and we would still be miserable.
BLAINE:
So...
thank you.
We really meant it:
Porcelain...
(sighs)
The first moment
I laid eyes on you,
I truly didn't understand
what I was looking at.
With your hippo broaches
and your knee-length sweaters,
standing there all sassy
with your arms crossed
and your hips
all... cocked out,
and your eyes rolled back
as if to say, "Oh, how droll."
But then, I got to know you.
And even though
you still constantly annoyed me,
I got to watch you go through
what you went through.
The whole
coming-out thing
with your dad, the death threats
from the bully
whom Blaine later dated.
I never knew
I had thoughts and feelings
about those things
until I watched you
go through them.
But you expanded my mind.
You taught me things
about myself
that I would have never
discovered on my own.
And for that, I thank you.
Thank you.
Blaine...
I still don't really get you.
Um, I guess I just am not
a fan of your thing.
But, hey,
you're doing you...
and that's swell.
Thank you, Sue.
I feel the same way about you.
And now, if you'll excuse me,
there's somebody I need to see.
I was coming to see you!
I was coming to see you, too!
Oh!
Coach, I'm sorry that I said
those horrible things
to a horrible adult.
Oh, honey, I'm the
one who's sorry.
I've been treating you
like an unpaid intern,
when I should have been
treating you like a paid intern.
But honey, there's still one
last person I have to see.
- All right.
- All right, babe.
(piano plays intro to ABBA's
"The Winner Takes It All")
Hey, Sue.
You wanted to see me?
Uh, what's...
what's going on?
♪ I don't wanna talk ♪
♪ About things
we've gone through ♪
♪ Nothing more to say ♪
♪ No more ace to play ♪
♪ The winner takes it all ♪
♪ The loser's standing small ♪
♪ Beside the victory ♪
♪ That's her destiny ♪
♪ But tell me, does she kiss ♪
♪ Like I used to kiss you? ♪
♪ Does it feel the same ♪
♪ When she calls your name? ♪
(quietly):
Butt Chin...
(in harmony):
♪ The game is on again ♪
♪ A lover or a friend ♪
♪ A big thing or a small ♪
♪ The winner takes it all ♪
♪ I don't wanna talk ♪
♪ If it makes you feel sad ♪
♪ And I understand ♪
♪ You've come to shake my hand ♪
♪ The winner takes it all... ♪
(holding note)
♪ The winner takes it all ♪
♪ The winner
takes it all ♪
♪ The winner takes it all ♪
♪ The loser has to fall ♪
♪ The winner takes ♪
♪ It all! ♪
(song ends)
Look, I know why you want...
Brad!
__
Snipers stand down.
Pocahontas has landed.
GERALDO RIVERA:
Welcome back, everybody.
President Jeb Bush will win
the crucial battleground state
of Ohio, and reelection
to a second term
as President
of the United States.
With me now, before she heads
down to Times Square
to meet the president and
the crowd of tens of thousands,
the vice president,
Sue Sylvester.
Madam Vice President, thank you
so much for being here.
Well, thank you, Geraldo.
And I just spoke
to the president,
and he was curious
about where I was,
and I told him
that victory rally could wait
until I had a chat
with my old buddy Geraldo.
Now, Madam Vice President,
I have to ask you,
will you be running
for president in 2024?
You bet your sweet ass, Geraldo.
Well, folks, you heard it here
first... the vice president.
Thank you very much.
Congratulations to you.
We'll be back with more election
night coverage right after this.
I wanted to make a time capsule
of my time at McKinley.
I know it's stupid, but it'd give me a
reason to come back every once in a while.
Oh, it's really, really sweet.
I have programs
from our show choir
competitions,
and... and oh, my Rocky
Horror Picture Show wig,
and oh, my Gaga
heels, and, uh...
and, oh, my favorite photo of
Finn, and oh, prom queen crown...
and, oh, our picture from prom, and
the ring you got me that Christmas.
(laughs)
Wh...
Wh-Why are you crying and
laughing at the same time?
(laughs): Because you're
the only person I know
that would do
something like this.
(chuckles)
You're the only one.
And-and that is why
I love you so much.
I love you, too.
♪ ♪
MAN: Kids, we have
two very special guests here
at the Harvey Milk School
for Career Day
and Celebrity Tuesday Singalong.
Kurt Hummel and Blaine Anderson
are coming,
because I think
they're just inspirational.
Recently, they performed
the first LGBTQ version
of Who's Afraid of Virginia
Woolf at Lincoln Center.
So please give a warm,
Harvey Milk
Elementary School welcome
to Kurt and Blaine!
Hello.
We are so excited to be here.
It is so cool to be
in a place where it's safe
and okay to be who you are.
It kind of reminds us of our school.
Mm-hmm.
Or at least one
room in our school.
And that was called
the choir room.
Now that's because we had
an amazing teacher who
accepted us. Well, all of us.
BLAINE: Yeah. So we want to
encourage all of you guys to be
proud of who you are
and to find friends that accept
you and to not only dream,
but to dream big
and surround yourself
with people
who can help
those dreams come true.
(The Monkees'
"Daydream Believer" begins)
♪ Oh, I could hide
'neath the wings ♪
♪ Of the bluebird as she sings ♪
♪ The six o'clock alarm ♪
♪ Would never ring ♪
♪ But it rings and I rise ♪
♪ Wipe the sleep
out of my eyes ♪
♪ My shaving razor's cold ♪
♪ And it stings ♪
♪ Cheer up, Sleepy Jean ♪
♪ Oh, what can it mean ♪
♪ To a daydream believer ♪
♪ And a homecoming queen ♪
♪ You once thought of me ♪
♪ As a white knight
on his steed ♪
♪ Now you know how happy ♪
♪ I can be ♪
♪ Oh, and our good times
start and end ♪
♪ Without dollar one to spend ♪
♪ But how much, baby ♪
♪ Do we really need ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh! ♪
♪ Cheer up, Sleepy Jean ♪
♪ Oh, what can it mean ♪
♪ To a daydream believer ♪
♪ And a ♪
♪ Homecoming queen ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
♪ Cheer up, Sleepy Jean ♪
♪ Oh, what can it mean ♪
♪ To a daydream believer ♪
♪ And a homecoming queen ♪
♪ Yeah! ♪
(whoops)
Hands in, everybody.
Hands in, hands in, hands in.
ALL:
Amazing!
("This Time" begins)
♪ These walls ♪
♪ And all these picture frames ♪
♪ Every name ♪
♪ They show ♪
♪ These halls ♪
♪ I've walked a thousand times ♪
♪ Heartbreaks and valentines ♪
♪ Friends of mine all know ♪
♪ I look at everything I was ♪
♪ And everything I ever loved ♪
♪ And I can see
how much I've grown ♪
♪ I'm not afraid ♪
♪ Of moving on and letting go ♪
♪ It's just so hard
to say good-bye ♪
♪ To what I know ♪
♪ This time no one's
gonna say good-bye
♪ I keep you
in this heart of mine ♪
♪ This time that we had ♪
♪ I will hold ♪
♪ Forever... ♪
♪ This old ♪
♪ Familiar place is ♪
♪ Where every face is ♪
♪ Another part of me ♪
♪ I played
a different game then ♪
♪ They called me
a different name then ♪
♪ I think of all
the things I did ♪
♪ And how I wish I knew
what I know now ♪
♪ I see how far I've come ♪
♪ And what I got right ♪
♪ When I was looking
for that spotlight ♪
♪ I was looking for myself ♪
♪ Got over what
I was afraid of ♪
♪ I showed 'em all
that I was made of ♪
♪ More than trophies
on a shelf ♪
♪ For all the battles
that we lost ♪
♪ Or might have won ♪
♪ I never stopped believing ♪
♪ In the words we sung ♪
♪ We sung ♪
♪ This time no one's
gonna say good-bye ♪
♪ I keep you
in this heart of mine ♪
♪ This time that we had ♪
♪ I will hold ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ I'm looking out ♪
♪ From the crossroads ♪
♪ I don't know ♪
♪ How far away I will roll ♪
♪ I take a breath ♪
♪ I close my eyes ♪
♪ And your voice will carry me ♪
♪ Home... ♪
♪ I keep you
in this heart of mine ♪
♪ This time I know ♪
♪ It's never over ♪
♪ No matter who or what I am ♪
♪ I'll carry
where we all began ♪
♪ This time that we had ♪
♪ I will hold ♪
♪ I will hold... ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ Forever. ♪
(siren wailing,
car horns honking)
Mercedes!
We have amazing news.
Remember that movie that Artie
wrote for you but you were
too busy on your own world tour
so we gave it to me?
Well, it got into
Sundance Film Festival.
No, Tina, I told you
it got into Slamdance.
Also, big favor, Mercedes.
We want to use your songs
for the soundtrack.
Oh, my agent usually
handles that.
I am kidding. You can have
whatever song you like.
- Guys, come on. We're gonna be late.
- Oh, yeah.
BLAINE: Oh, did you
hear about Sam?
He already has a new girlfriend.
Can you believe that?
Come on, I don't want
to miss a moment.
MERCEDES: Well, then, why does
he keep texting me?
Knock, knock.
Come in!
Is it time already?
It's time!
We're all here!
- ARTIE: Hi! We're here!
- TINA: Hey, Rachel!
Oh, no, don't strain yourself.
Please. I've been sweating
my boobs off
at Tracy Anderson's
for the past nine months.
This baby can have my body now,
but then, after that,
Mama wants it back.
Well, we got you
some, uh, organic juice
from this special
place in Tribeca.
Thank you. It's supposed to
help the baby's brain grow.
Okay, hold on. So, I've heard
this story from Kurt and Blaine,
but now, I want
to hear your side.
What in the heck made you say
"yes" to being their surrogate?
Obviously, there's a full-circle
story based on how I was raised,
but these guys have just
been so amazing.
And I figured, they've given up
so much of their lives
to make me happy.
The least I could do was
give them nine months of mine.
Hi.
Oh, I love you guys so much.
You're gonna be
the most amazing dads.
I can't wait for that.
Oh, here's my husband!
Because I'm ready to get started
on a little co-production
of our own.
(laughs) So romantic.
Come on, we're gonna be late.
Okay.
Wish us luck, you guys.
Bye, your guys.
Break a leg.
Bye.
You guys, we'll be praying...
Bye. Have fun.
Fingers crossed.
(gasps)
JESSIE:
So, as a former Tony winner,
I feel like I need to
give you some pointers
of what you're gonna say
when you get up there.
I'm not gonna win. Yes, you are.
You are gonna win.
Really? Okay.
So, when you get up there,
you stand up straight,
you fake humility,
you cry only once when
you talk about your dads,
and you give all the credit
to your incredibly
talented director.
Well, he is pretty amazing
and handsome,
and has the best taste in women.
(laughs)
Here we are.
- You okay?
- Whew. Yeah.
ANNOUNCER:
Ladies and gentlemen,
presenting the award for
Best Actress in a Musical...
(boys shouting)
...please welcome Broadway's
very own Andrew Rannells.
Bad dog!
(shouts playfully)
(laughing):
Hey.
- Oh.
- Oh, my gosh.
RANNELS (on TV):
The nominees for...
- Oh. Here we go... - Best
Actress in a Musical are:
Maggie Smith in Miss Jean
Brodie's Second Prime.
(applause)
Willow Smith in Cabaret.
(applause on TV)
Anne Hathaway
in her one-woman show,
Anne! exclamation point.
(applause on TV)
And Rachel Berry
in Jane Austen Sings.
(applause and cheering)
And the Tony goes to...
Rachel Berry
in Jane Austen Sings.
(applause and cheering)
(all gasping)
Oh, my God.
(laughs) (whooping)
(indistinct chatter,
screaming and whooping)
♪ ♪
(whooping)
(applause and cheering)
(audience cheering, whooping)
(whistling)
Thank you.
Oh, my gosh, I, um... I-I want
to thank my amazing husband
and director, Jessie.
And I want to thank my
two dads for all of those
singing and dancing lessons.
Okay, I want to thank...
Carmen Tibideaux at NYADA
for giving me a second chance
at my degree,
and to all of my friends
at McKinley High.
Um, but I want
to dedicate this award
to the person who's responsible
for getting me
on this stage tonight,
and that is Mr. Will Schuester.
Um, Mr. Shue always taught
to my strengths
and not my weaknesses,
and he cheered the loudest
when I soared.
And he picked me up when I was
in a million pieces.
He taught me the one great thing
that all teachers do,
and there are
so many of them out there.
And that is, being a part
of something special
does not make you special.
Something is special
because you are a part of it.
Mr. Shue, I love you so much.
And to all of the boys
and girls out there,
I just want to say quickly
before I walk off the stage,
that dreams really do come true,
so, thank you.
(applause and cheering)
__
Ladies and gentlemen, the Vice
President of the United States.
(school bell ringing)
(applause)
Fantastic.
Becky? Becky?!
It's okay, honey.
He's clean.
You know, a great big fat person
once stood on this stage
and told a group of a dozen
or so nerds
in hideous disco outfits
that "glee,"
by its very definition,
is about opening yourself up
to joy.
Now, it's no secret
that for a long time,
I thought
that was a load of hooey.
As far as I can see,
the glee club is nothing more
than a place where a bunch
of cowardly losers
go to sing their troubles away,
and delude themselves
that they live in a world
that cares one iota
about their hopes and dreams,
totally divorced
from the harsh reality
that out in the the real world,
there's not much more
to hope for than disappointment,
heartbreak and failure.
You know what?
I was exactly right.
But I was wrong
about the cowardly part.
What I finally realize,
now that I'm well
into my late thirties...
It takes
a lot of bravery to look
around you, and see the world,
not as it is,
but as it should be.
A world where the quarterback
becomes best friends
with the gay kid,
and the girl with the big nose
ends up on Broadway.
Glee is about imagining
a world like that,
and finding the courage
to open up your heart
and sing about it.
That's what Glee Club is.
And for the longest time,
I thought that was silly.
And now, I think it's just about
the bravest thing
that anyone could do.
I'm honored to be here
to rededicate this theater
the Finn Hudson Auditorium.
William,
it is with your hard work,
in his memory, that you managed
to accomplish something
unimaginable.
McKinley High School
for the Performing Arts
has become
an overwhelming success,
a model for public schools
that showcase the arts,
now being replicated
all across the country.
(sighs)
Congratulations, Will Schuester.
You and your little Glee Club
have accomplished something
quite remarkable.
And now, without further ado,
it is my pleasure to introduce
the New Directions!
(OneRepublic's "I Lived" begins)
♪ Bah, bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ Hope you take that jump ♪
♪ Bah, bah... ♪
♪ You don't fear the fall ♪
♪ Bah, bah ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ Hope when the water rises ♪
♪ Bah, bah... ♪
♪ You built a wall ♪
♪ Bah, bah ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ Hope when crowd screams out ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah... ♪
♪ They're screaming your name ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ Bah, bah ♪
♪ Hope if everybody runs ♪
♪ You choose to stay ♪
♪ Bah, bah, bah, bah ♪
♪ I hope that you fall in love ♪
♪ Bah-bah, bah-bah ♪
♪ And it hurts so bad ♪
♪ Bah, bah ♪
♪ Yeah-ah-ah ♪
♪ Bah ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Bah, bah ♪
♪ The only way you can know,
you give it all you have ♪
♪ Hey, yeah ♪
♪ Bah-bah, bah-bah ♪
♪ And I hope that you don't
suffer ♪
♪ Bah-bah, bah-bah ♪
♪ But take the pain ♪
♪ Bah-bah, bah-bah, bah-bah ♪
♪ Bah-bah, bah-bah, bah ♪
♪ Hope when the moment comes ♪
♪ You'll say ♪
♪ I, I, I ♪
♪ I did it all ♪
♪ I owned every second
that this world could give ♪
♪ I saw so many places,
the things that I did ♪
♪ With every broken bone ♪
♪ I swear I lived ♪
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ Yeah... ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh,
oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh,
oh-oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh,
oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Hey-ey-ey ♪
♪ With every broken bone ♪
♪ I lived... ♪
♪ I, I, I ♪
♪ I did it all ♪
♪ I did it all, yeah ♪
♪ I owned every second
that this world could give ♪
♪ This world could give ♪
♪ I saw so many places,
the things that I did ♪
♪ Yeah, with every broken bone ♪
♪ I swear I lived ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh,
oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, yeah-ah-ah-ah-ah ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh,
oh-oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ I swear I lived ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh,
oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Mm, mm-mm ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh,
oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Mm, mm-mm ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh! ♪
♪ Mm, mm-mm-mm-mm. ♪
(song ends)
(laughter, whooping)
Amazing!
(applause and cheering)
__
(chatter, whooping, applause)
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com