Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.Addic7ed.com/
Previously on Smash...
I'm Marilyn.
I think
she'd be a great musical.
Marilyn, the musical?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
We are in the middle
of an adoption.
I was working on
my audition tonight.
Darling, I need to see
everything you've got.
All assets go into escrow
immediately.
I'll see you in court.
Ivy Lynn is coming in.
Derek wills is available.
He is a terrible
human being!
I got called back
for Marilyn.
I got a callback.
♪ color me
your color, baby ♪
♪ color me your car ♪
♪ color me a color,
darling ♪
♪ I know who you are ♪
♪ come up off your
color chart ♪
♪ I know where
you're coming from ♪
- ♪ call me ♪
♪ on the line ♪
♪ call me, call me any ♪
♪ any time ♪
- ♪ call me ♪
♪ call my love ♪
♪ call me, call me any ♪
♪ day or night, call me ♪
♪ cover me with kisses,
baby ♪
♪ cover me with love ♪
♪ emotions come,
I don't know why ♪
♪ cover up those alibis ♪
- ♪ call me ♪
♪ on the line, call me ♪
♪ call me any, any time ♪
- ♪ call me ♪
♪ oh, my love ♪
♪ when you're ready
we can share the wine ♪
♪ call me ♪
Karen.
What are you doing?
You've got a three-top,
and the guy at your front table
wants more coffee.
What?
I'm sorry... what?
Relax.
I took care of it.
But you are so not here.
Still haven't heard?
- No.
- How long has it been?
- Four days.
- That's not so good.
I know.
I'm so stressed,
I just wish
they would call me.
- Karen.
- Ugh.
Here ya go, hon.
You're gonna get it.
Thanks.
It's Ivy's part.
She has Marilyn's soul.
She has her body.
She looks like Marilyn.
This girl feels like
Marilyn.
How do you know
what she feels like?
Okay, don't go there.
Straight men
are gonna go there.
- This girl is hot.
- They're both beautiful girls.
But only one of them
has the experience to do this.
Well, that's the thing, tom.
Experience is precisely
what we're not looking for.
That innocence, that freshness...
It's very Marilyn.
She has to have chops.
- That girl has chops.
- I agree.
- What a great voice, huh?
- Give me a break.
Ivy has one of the best...
Yes, Ivy also has
an amazing voice.
No one here is saying
she doesn't.
And she can act.
And she can dance.
And she has ten years
of Broadway experience.
Okay, look, we can't just keep
going over and over and over
- the same question!
- No...
He's right.
I'm sorry... huh?
What did you say?
You are right, tom.
You are absolutely right.
I'm fighting this hard I can
'cause' kidding myself.
I can't handle this over
to a completely neophyte
not withtout more information.
- Can I help you?
- I'm tom's assistant.
I know who you are.
Get me Joe Machota at CAA.
You have to do
another callback?
It's Marilyn Monroe.
It's the part of a lifetime.
If I have to jump through
a few hoops, so be it.
- Are they seeing more people?
- Just me and one other person.
Somebody new.
Karen something.
They didn't see her do
a dance audition,
so they're calling her back
for that.
We're both getting
called back for scene work,
- but I don't have to dance.
- It's classic.
You put in ten years
in the chorus,
stop, please.
I'm a wreck.
I'm just pretending
to be brave.
- I'm scared to death.
- So it's another callback.
- You'll nail this one too.
- I'd better!
'Cause I really don't wanna
put on those feathers anymore.
I'm so sick of
going out on that stage
looking like
a demented duck.
Tell me about it.
[Laughter]
Everyone, uh,
gather round.
The budget is almost ready.
We'll have all the schedules
printed and distributed
both in hard copy
and electronically
by this afternoon, at which
point the budget director
- will be available for questions.
- You got nothing else?
Something we maybe
could sell papers with?
I apologize for our current
lack of scandal.
I know this makes your life
boring and difficult.
I'm sure someone
will do something stupid
or illegal soon.
If I were you,
I'd count on it.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have a lunch date
with a young lady who's
significantly more attractive
than you clowns.
- You okay?
- My agent called.
They want another callback.
I have to dance.
Oh, well,
you're a terrific da...
The choreographer's
gonna love you.
- It's the director.
- The director?
He's the choreographer.
Sometimes they do both,
you know?
Oh. This is the guy who had
you come over to his apartment
at 10:00 at night
for a coaching session.
Mm. You never said much
about what happened that night.
Well, because nothing
happened.
Come on.
Birth certificates
notarized and authenticated.
Marriage certificate.
18 years?
That's impressive.
Unheard of
in show business.
Once the agency
signs off on your application,
it gets bundled
with other applications,
then we send it to Beijing,
and it gets translated
into mandarin.
That should all take
about three or four months,
and then the waiting begins.
Begins?
We've been at this
for ten months.
Chinese bureaucracy
is very thorough.
Well, how much longer
are we talking about?
Well... two years?
I know.
The waiting is the hardest part.
Hi. Sorry.
There was police action
on the subway.
Right.
Sorry. There was a police
action on the subway.
Yeah.
So we've heard.
- Hi.
This is our music composer
tom levitt
singing on the recording,
who, by the way,
makes a lovely Marilyn.
[Upbeat Latin music]
♪ in this factory
where dreams can come true ♪
♪ are you ready
to make someone new ♪
♪ you're the team that must
teach me to do ♪
♪ the 20th century
fox mambo ♪
- [music stops]
- Okay. [Snaps]
First move brings Norma Jeane
into the cabal of groomers
as they affect
the transformation.
It's a fast, tight spin.
- Here.
- [Whispers] Sorry.
Good.
Let's make ourselves
a Marilyn.
[Orchestra tuning up]
♪ ♪
[baton tapping]
- You did what?
- Josh called me,
said they needed a couple people
to help out with the dance call,
- so I said yes.
- You spied!
Yes, I did.
She showed up late
and had to be shown the first
combination three times.
I talked to her on the break.
She's from Iowa,
and her name
is Karen Cartwright.
Marilyn's name
was Norma Jeane Mortenson.
Which would be
why she changed it.
[Cell phone chimes]
It's half-hour.
My sweet.
If we put
let me be your star here
right after
the DiMaggio duet,
then the breakup number
goes...
Here?
[Groans]
You know, it takes longer
to adopt a baby
than it took to write
West Side story?
Wow. No.
I did not know that.
You know how many criminal
checks they put you thorough
before they'll let you
write a musical?
I'm guessing none,
since we didn't have one?
None is right!
And let me tell you,
there are a lot of people
that should be
stopped
from writing musicals.
[Laughing]
I'm aware.
You know what we should do?
We should write a song
for DiMaggio,
Arthur Miller, and JFK to sing
about what they look for
in a wanan.
Julia, we have to start
thinking about structure.
You can't build a musical
by just writing songs.
Maybe it's not so linear.
We start with
let me be your star.
- You start with it.
- Seriously.
- I can see it I my head.
- You don't think
- it's the act break?
- No.
No. It's like this.
The stage is black.
She stands alone
in a pool of light.
She's just Norma Jeane.
Behind her...
Figures in shadow emerge.
Young women,
exactly like her.
You're nothing.
Your father left
because he didn't want you.
Your mother is crazy.
Certifiably nuts.
- Nobody wants you.
- Nobody wants you...
- You're nothing.
[Light music]
♪ ♪
♪ fade in on a girl ♪
♪ with a hunger for fame ♪
♪ and a face and a name ♪
♪ to remember ♪
♪ the past fades away ♪
♪ because as of this day ♪
♪ Norma Jeane's gone ♪
♪ she's moving on ♪
♪ her smile
and your fantasies ♪
♪ play a duet ♪
♪ that will make you forget ♪
♪ where you are ♪
♪ the music starts playing ♪
♪ it's the beat
of her heart saying ♪
♪ let me be your star ♪
but which girl
plays Marilyn?
Well we don't
know that yet, do we?
You know, Ellis,
your help is fantastic, but...
I kind of need to be
more alone in this space
with tom around the structure.
Oh, of course.
I just...
I get so excited watching
my idea just come to life.
[Chuckles]
Eh... yeah, you know,
a lot of people think
that something
that is said in passing
is the same thing
as an idea,
which isn't strictly true.
I-I don't think anything,
I...
Totally understandable.
But we're the ones that
have to do all the work.
And you are tom's assistant,
which is what tom
needs you to be...
Right, tom?
Absolutely.
So maybe you can
just give us a little room.
I'll go pick up
the dry cleaning.
Terrific.
He's a really good
assistant.
For the first time
in my life,
- my closets are organized.
- Organizing closets.
Hey, you know what?
That would be
a great idea
for a musical too!
Has anyone heard from Derek
about how the work sessions
are going?
I haven't talked to him.
Five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Oh, again!
Five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,
- five, six, and seven, eight.
- Oh, again!
Five, six, seven
and one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Concentrate, please!
It's just
it's pretty intense.
Yeah, it's supposed to be.
Look, the gesture goes
all the way to the end
of the fingertips,
and then the chin comes up.
Josh, show her the combination
again, please.
Hey.
Sorry. We've been
running a little late.
That's all right.
Oh, how is that?
Oh, this one a actually
really good
about the Arthur Miller-
Elia Kazan stuff.
Not so good on the movies,
but there's so much of that
in some of the other ones,
I don't really miss it.
How many have you read?
A lot.
- And the movies?
- [Laughs]
All of them.
Come on,
clash by night?
Even monkey business.
[Both laugh]
Listen, um...
I really appreciate you
doing this.
I understand
it's a lot to ask.
You know, after the demo
and the dance sequence,
not to mention
the two auditions.
It's Marilyn.
I didn't expect it
to be simple.
One, two, three,
four, five, and...
Come on in.
And one, two, three,
four, five,
six, seven,
and one, two, three, four, five,
and seven, eight.
One, two, three, four, five...
Okay, everyone,
we're done.
Let's call it a day.
Karen. Come here.
I'm sure you two
would like to meet.
Ivy Lynn,
this is Karen Cartwright.
- Oh, hi.
- Oh, yeah, hi!
So great to meet you.
I love your scarf.
Thanks. My mom gave it to me
for my birthday.
Oh... it's so cute.
Okay. Well,
I'll see you Wednesday.
- Absolutely.
- Bye.
Um...
- I hate him.
- I thought you said
- it was going well.
- He's a psychopath.
- Why? What's he doing?
- He's messing with my head.
He brought in the girl,
the other girl up for the part,
and he was like, [Accent]
"Oh, hello, I'm sure you two
- would like to meet each other."
- He's a Brit?
Of course he's a brit.
I told you that.
No, no,
you didn't, actually.
Well, it's not important.
What's important
is he's a creep.
Well, get used to it.
What is that supposed
to mean?
Well, it means there are
a lot of guys out there
with a lot of power,
and they're hard to deal with,
so you should
get used to it.
I don't wanna get used to it.
Then you create
your own suffering.
I am not creating
my own suffering.
He is creating my suffering.
Your British accent's
terrible, by the way.
- Marilyn's not British.
- Yeah, well, good thing too.
Hey, listen, we've been invited
to dinner this Wednesday.
- Who with?
- One of the deputy mayors.
- Ooh!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
They're thinking about
promoting me, actually.
Awesome!
- Then you'll be powerful too.
- Yeah.
- And very hard to deal with.
- Mm...
[As Marilyn]
Thank you ever so.
Okay.
That's a little spooky.
She does this thing
with her lips...
The top lip doesn't move
with the bottom one.
[Breathy gasp]
Thank you ever so.
Okay,
you're freaking me out.
How are you doing that?
[Breathy laugh]
[Continues giggling]
Stop it!
[Both laughing]
Hmm.
Great. Yeah.
Thank you, Rene.
I'll... I'll get right on this.
Bye.
What was that?
Umum...
Meetings for our group
start Friday.
We need...
To write a short letter
to the birth mother
of our child.
Obviously,
she'll never get it,
because the babies
are abandoned
and our daughter,
let's face it,
isn't even born yet,
but...
Something they ask you to do
to get people...
Engaged in the process.
Okay?
What?
I just... I just think
we need to be
more realistic about this.
Meaning what?
[Sighs]
Their most conservative
estimate... two years.
I'll be 47
when that baby comes.
Well, I mean...
Which would make me 65
when she graduated High School.
So what, you don't want
to do this anymore?
I'm sorry.
- Well, that's just great.
- Okay, first of all,
you should not be
eavesdropping.
It's the only way I find
anything out around here.
- That is completely unfair.
- Oh, yeah,
you're just ready to tank
the whole thing,
- and I'm the one who sucks.
- Let me.
So I don't get a vote.
- It's just over.
- No one is saying that.
He said it.
Dad said it.
Your father has been anxious
about this for a long time, Leo.
People say things
when they're anxious.
- Yeah, like, "I quit."
- That's not what we're saying.
Mom, we've been talking
about this forever.
Ever since I was a little kid,
you told me I'd be getting
a brother or sister.
- We did say that.
- You just told me
I had to wait,
and then you said...
You said my sister
is in China.
She's waiting for us
in China.
And I believed you.
Why wouldn't I believe you?
You told me.
She's waiting for us
to come and get her.
What is gonna happen to her
if we don't go get her?
- Good show.
- Bye. Thank you.
- Hmm.
- Good night.
I hope Derek's
not too hideous.
He's very professional.
If he steps out of line,
let me know?
Ohh.
My own Johnny Hyde.
- Who's Johnny Hyde?
- Marilyn's first agent.
He adored her.
He was very protective,
and then he died tragically,
and her career
totally tanked.
You don't know
who Johnny Hyde is?
I do. I just like listening
to you talk about Marilyn.
[Laughs]
I would have just
given it to you.
I know.
[Dinner music]
Eileen.
Hello, Jerry.
Wow. You're Eileen rand.
Wow. You are such
a great producer.
- Hi. I'm Lindsey Mullens.
- We've met.
- I don't think so.
- I do.
- You all right?
- Absolutely.
How's it going?
Well, Ivy's terrific.
She's a perfectionist.
If I'm gonna sink $200,000,
in this workshop,
I need to know
the girl can carry it.
Too perfect
I can live with.
Yeah, she's trying
too hard.
What about the new girl?
excellent.
Green doesn't even
beginning to it.
Well, Marilyn was green
at the beginning.
You don't say.
I don't know.
Maybe neither of them's
right for it.
Maybe...
Scarlett Johansson's movie'll
fall through.
Get it out of your head.
We're not chasing stars
on this one.
We're casting Marilyn
on Friday.
Eileen, Derek.
- Hi, Jordan.
- Hey, Jordan.
Can I borrow him
a second?
- Sure.
- I'll be right back.
- Not too long.
- I know.
Have I given you
any indication
that I have any interest
in speaking with you
ever again?
Can I have a Manhattan?
She'll have one too.
So...
Derek wills, huh?
You managed to hang on to him
after my fair lady fell through.
Ryan
has a vampire musical.
Would you
get out of my booth?
I'm not giving you Bond 45
in the divorce, Jerry.
What's this Marilyn thing I?
- It's none of your business.
- Where you getting the money?
Why don't you
go back to Mindy?
Lindsey.
I dot t care
what her name is.
Would you
get out of my booth?
Let me give you
a little advice, Eileen.
We were good partners
because I knew the business,
which allowed you
to be the romantic.
All this nonsense,
theatre is art...
You deluded yourself,
and then you fell in love
with the delusion.
Marilyn, the musical?
No one is gonna buy it.
You're making a fool
of yourself.
Hey!
Oh, dear.
We're gonna have to find
ourselves another restaurant.
Okay.
Okay, we're talking
20 the most
experienced dancers
and singers.
And what are we gonna do
for the other principals?
They haven't even finished
the end of the book yet.
- We'll call you back, Bernie!
- We'll call you back.
I'm just gonna touch base
with Julia
and find out what's happening
with the new pages.
Hang on, Eileen,
can we just take a minute
to talk about the bigger
picture of this?
Nothing is bigger
than Broadway.
I'm aware.
But what's the plan
after the workshop?
We... we give people a taste,
and then what?
We'll work on it
for two or three years, and...
No. Mostly what I see
on Broadway's overworked.
You know,
I love the songs.
I love the scenes they have.
I love Marilyn.
Why don't we just do it?
- Okay. So...
- So...
We do a workshop,
we try it out of town,
we bring it to Broadway.
Well, it's pretty fast.
I love fast.
Go get me a Marilyn.
[Under breath]
♪ in this factory ♪
♪ where dreams
can come true
♪ are you ready
to make someone new ♪
see? I was right.
You're a terrific dancer.
The rhythms
are really complicated.
- I can't remember this.
- You have the address
- of the restaurant, right?
- Yeah. It's in my cell.
I can't pick you up,
you know.
No, no, no,
we rehearse till 7:00,
so I'll just change
at the rehearsal hall
and come straight over.
Don't worry.
I know it's important.
I'll be there.
Go. You're making me nervous.
Get out.
What are you working on?
Oh.
You know, just stuff.
[Light laugh]
Listen...
I wanna go back to work.
- Oh...
- I know. I know.
It's been a while.
But there's always a market
for good science teachers...
And I miss it.
You miss
the periodic table?
I do, actually.
Ha.
And...
I miss the kids.
And what about
the adoption?
- Julia.
- Hmm?
I can't wait anymore.
You have your writing.
All I ha I is the waiting.
Leo's gone all day.
I need something.
And... I'm a teacher.
I'm a good teacher.
Even though I never could get
you to understand p orbitals.
Well, that was because
every time you'd start
describing them,
it was just so sexy,
I'd get distracted.
I'll see everyone
at the callbacks on Friday.
Thanks for your work.
I appreciate it.
Thank you.
- There a problem?
- Oh, no, no, no.
- She's on her way.
- I finally get to meet
- the famous Karen.
- I didn't know she was famous.
Andrew says
she's very attractive.
That's why he wanted you
to bring her.
Klein has an eye
for the ladies.
[Chuckles] Look, I'm not
gonna say that he doesn't,
but fact is, Dev and I are
the ones on the line tonight.
Oh, hang on,
miss Cartwright.
I haven't finished
with you yet.
- Oh.
- We would have done it earlier,
but the dance took a little
bit longer than it should have.
You ready for me?
Oh, yeah, come on in.
Dave's gonna read with you.
I'm sorry, is there a problem?
- It's not gonna take very long.
- No, no.
Good.
So you're the deputy
press secretary.
- Yes. Yes, sir.
- He's doing an amazing job.
He is much better with those
animals in the press corps
- than I ever was.
- They can be quite a handful.
You've just got to
feed them properly...
No red meat.
Andrew says
you're very dedicated.
She coming?
Oh, yeah, no.
I'm sure she's on her way.
'Cause stability
is important in this job.
Even though none of you
are ever home.
[Andrew laughing]
I think we should
go ahead and order.
Yeah.
[Ahem]
I don't like the way
they look at you.
I can't help the way
they look at me, Joe.
You love it.
You love every bit of it.
The way you walk,
the way you sing,
- the way you dress.
- It's my job to look like this.
Your job is to take care
of me and our home.
I gave up baseball.
Why can't you give up movies?
I want to, Joe.
Do you need me to be doing
more Marilyn?
Sorry.
It's hard to say
what it needs,
'cause right now
you're not doing anything.
Dave, move.
Look, Karen...
You have a lot of what
makes Marilyn Marilyn
essentially in you, okay?
So just play the action.
You wanna please him.
You wanna make him happy.
It terrifies you
that he's this unhappy.
So don't do her.
Just be her, okay?
Okay.
Okay, let's try again.
[Phone vibrating]
Where were you?
Rehearsal went late.
I've been texting you
for hours.
I know, I...
It was mortifying.
I'm sorry.
I just don't understand
why you couldn't call or text.
The last I heard from you was,
"I'm on my way."
I was worried about you
the whole dinner.
- I couldn't focus.
- I couldn't get out.
You couldn't even say,
sorry, I need a minute?
I have to text my boyfriend
who I'm standing up!
This brilliant,
powerful director
is that powerful that you
couldn't even ask the question?
I got confused.
There wasn't the right moment.
I'm sorry.
Dev!
I'm really sorry.
I'm not crazy.
People wanna think that.
They say I'm crazy...
[Exhales]
I'm sorry.
No, no.
It's difficult.
Well, the DiMaggio scene
is less internal.
Quite a bit.
It's just that word,
crazy, it...
Just feels so volatile.
She was so afraid
her whole life
that she'd end up being crazy
like her mother.
Yeah. That's definitely
in there.
[Exhales]
I'm not crazy.
People want to think that.
They say I'm crazy
because I want things,
but the things I want...
I want love.
I don't want...
Well...
A sex object is a thing.
Who would want
to be a thing?
Okay, hang on.
May I?
- Hey, Dennis.
- Hi.
- Hey, Ivy.
- Oh...
- You look fantastic.
Ha. I'm fine.
I'm good.
You're gonna be great.
Ivy.
[Gasps]
Hi, hi, hi!
Mmm!
[Giggles]
You look stunning.
Doesn't she?
Look at that top.
Perfect choice, of course.
Sit, sit, sit.
Thank you so much
for doing this.
Oh. I'm thrilled
you've given me the chance.
Well, hopefully,
we won't be torturing you
for too much longer.
It is nerve-wracking.
Everything feels so important
the first time.
Doesn't it feel that way
every time?
Yes. It does feel
that way every time.
You're just a a little more
used to it driving you crazy.
[Footsteps]
Yeah, just be you.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
- Come on, tom.
- Okay!
Have to go.
So we'll start with
the dance call
and then move on
to the scene work.
Good for me.
He hey.
Just relax.
You're great in this.
Thanks.
Oh, and guys,
the song was so good,
we just went ahead
and staged the whole thing.
Karen, let's take a look.
Josh.
- [Jazzy music]
- Norma Jeane Mortenson,
screen test
for 20th century fox.
Are you ready to fox-trot,
miss Mortenson?
♪ ♪
♪ at Paramount,
it's ooh-LA-LA
♪ ♪
♪ the Warner brothers
cha-cha-cha ♪
♪ ♪
♪ and l.B. Mayer
loves his schmaltz ♪
♪ so MGM made
the great waltz ♪
♪ ♪
♪ but the 20th century
fox-trot ♪
♪ it's precious
but precious ♪
♪ it's not hot ♪
♪
♪ to make the big boys ♪
♪ hire me ♪
♪ please make that rhythm ♪
♪ fiery ♪
♪ ♪
♪ come on, boys and girls ♪
♪ make me over ♪
[Latin rhythm]
♪ ♪
♪ in this factory
where dreams can come true ♪
♪ are you ready
to make someone new ♪
♪ you're the team
that must teach me to do ♪
♪ the 20th century
fox mambo ♪
♪ done the homework,
and I'll pass the test ♪
♪ I'll do whatever
my teacher suggests ♪
♪ I can do it clothed
or undressed ♪
♪ the 20th century
fox mambo ♪
♪ make it up,
shake it up ♪
♪ let the fantasies begin ♪
♪ here's the dope ♪
♪ to get cast,
change the past ♪
♪ make the light
just right for sin ♪
♪ emascope ♪
♪ take a gamble ♪
♪ 'cause it's safe
to bet ♪
♪ Mr. Zanuck
ain't seen nothing yet ♪
♪ when we're finished,
he'll never forget ♪
♪ the 20th century fox ♪
♪ ♪
♪ for fame ♪
♪ play the game ♪
♪ change your name ♪
♪ to the 20th century fox ♪
♪ make it up,
shake it up ♪
♪ make me feel like
the main attraction ♪
♪ change the clothes,
fix the nose ♪
♪ and then five, six,
seven, eight ♪
- ♪ action ♪
♪ now I'm blonde,
but I ain't so dumb ♪
- ♪ no ♪
- ♪ Hollywood ♪
- ♪ will be under my thumb ♪
- ♪ yes ♪
♪ I'll change partners ♪
♪ until I've become ♪
♪ the 20th century fox ♪
♪ mambo ♪
well, no one can say we don't
have enough h information.
Nope.
Information we have.
I thought Karen's dancing
was good.
She might be green,
but she's certainly trained.
- She's a star.
- Well, you can't say that
until it happens,
but it could happen, yes.
Ivy was incredible.
- She was.
- I thought she was
completely spontususus
and sexy.
Yes, she is that and more.
She's intelligent,
she's passionate.
She's beautiful.
I thought her reading
of the new pages
was pitch-perfect.
Was it too perfect?
Yeah, I dunno.
There's a lonelys there,
a wound that...
Was heart-breaking, really.
[Sighs]
And Karen is more of
an innocent,
which is also good
for Marilyn.
So?
They getting anywhere?
Not yet.
Any word yet?
I'm about to crawl
out of my skin.
Oh...
- Nothing yet?
- Not a word.
- This is awful.
- I know.
Night, you guys.
Night.
- You okay?
- I don't want to talk about it.
I can't believe
it's going on like this.
I don't want
to talk about it.
Ivy.
Hi.
I wanted to come
and tell you in person.
I didn't get it.
God, I didn't get it.
It's okay.
It's okay, tom.
I just have to get outta here.
Ivy, stop!
You got it.
I got it?
You're Marilyn.
Oh, my God, I got it!
[Laughter, chatter]
Are you all right?
I don't know what to do.
I don't know what to do!
[Laughter]
So you feel good
about our choice?
If I didn't, I wouldn't
have gone along with it.
She's a very talented
young lady.
- And lucky.
- We're all lucky.
And the Cartwright girl,
maybe not so much.
That's true.
But I'd keep my eye
on that one.
Eileen, I need to talk
to you about something.
Yes?
I, uh...
I don't want it getting
back to you in a bad way.
Jerry's picked up the option
on my fair lady.
He did?
Yeah. He wants me
back on board.
You know, I spent three years
of my life on that production.
- That's a lot of work
- mm.
So I, uh...
Basically went ahead
and told him to, uh,
shove it.
You did?
Yeah.
Call me crazy,
but I kinda like Marilyn.
She is not the American
Eliza Doolittle at all.
She's much more
interesting than that.
I certainly think so.
It also helps you reasier
on the eye than Jerry.
See you tomorrow.
[Sniffles]
Whew.
Hey, I just heard
that it's a special night
for one of our friends.
Ivy Lynn just landed
a big gig playing Marilyn Monroe
in a new musical
headed for Broadway.
Come on, Ivy,
how 'bout a song?
Oh, no.
[Chanting]
Ivy, Ivy,
Ivy, Ivy, Ivy!
Okay. Would anyone else
like to share their letter?
I-I guess I can.
"To the birth mother
of my daughter.
"Our lives are so far distant
from each other,
"it is as if
neither of us exists.
"I will never know you,
"even though you may
give birth to her,
"my daughter may never
know you as well.
"But I want you to know
I will guard her like a lion.
"I will raise her with love,
"I will protect her from
the wounds of loneliness.
"She will be a child
of two lands,
"and she will wear
that knowledge with pride.
"And at night, we will call
to you on the wind
"and perhaps
you will hear us and know
she is safe."
Sorry.
Uh...
I thought
I couldn't make it.
But, uh...
Then I decided
I couldn't miss it.
Well, we were just
reading the letters
that people have written.
And she wrote
the best one.
I wish I had
written that one.
- [Whispering]
- ♪ hello, you long shots ♪
♪ you dark horse runners ♪
♪ hairbrush singers ♪
♪ dashboard drummers ♪
♪ hello,
you wild magnolias ♪
♪ just waiting to bloom ♪
♪ ♪
♪ there's a little bit of a♪
♪ inside me and you ♪
♪ thank God even crazy
dreams come true ♪
♪ ♪
♪ I've stood at the bottom
of some walls ♪
♪ I thought
I couldn't climb ♪
♪ ♪
♪ I felt like Cinderella
at the ball ♪
♪ just a-running
out of time ♪
♪ so I know how it feels ♪
♪ to be afraid ♪
♪ you think that
it's all gonna slip away ♪
♪ hold on ♪
♪ here's to you free souls ♪
♪ you firefly chasers ♪
♪ tree climbers,
porch swingers ♪
♪ air guitar players ♪
♪ here's to you
fearless dancers ♪
♪ shakin' walls
in your bedrooms ♪
♪ there's a lot of wonder ♪
♪ left inside of me and you ♪
♪ thank God
even crazy dreams come true ♪
♪ ♪
♪ never let a bad day
be enough ♪
♪ to go and talk you
into giving up ♪
♪ 'cause sometimes everybody
feels like you ♪
♪ oh, feels like you ♪
♪ just like you ♪
♪ thank God
even crazy dreams ♪
♪ come ♪
♪ ♪
♪ true ♪
[mouthing words]
I love you.
♪ ♪
[mouthing words]
Thank you.
Sync & corrections by Rafael UPD
www.Addic7ed.com/