TRUNDLE:
'Twas the night before Christmas
When all through the house
Not a creature was stirring
Not even a mouse
The stockings were hung
By the chimney with care
In the hopes that Saint Nicholas
Would soon be there
The children were nestled
All snug in their beds
While visions of sugarplums
Danced in their heads
And Mama in her kerchief
And I in my cap
Had just settled our brains
For a long winter's nap
Ugh. If only I could sleep. If only I knew.
[CLOCK TICKING]
FATHER MOUSE:
'Twas the night before Christmas
And all through the house
Not a creature was stirring
Not even a mouse
Well, I'm stirring.
If only I could sleep. If only I knew.
We got trouble, the boss and me.
Big trouble.
How would you feel if it was
three minutes to Christmas...
...and you didn't know whether?
As we say when approaching
a tall piece of cheddar...
...better start from the top.
The trouble began two months ago
when the mailman came.
Hey, wait a minute, this isn't for us.
It's for Santa.
- So is this.
- And this.
- I spilled that ink.
- These are the letters we wrote to Santa.
- The letters we wrote to Santa, returned?
"Not accepted by addressee."
- What does that mean, Father?
- Santa doesn't want our letters.
- But why?
- I don't know, Sarah. I don't know.
FATHER MOUSE: The same thing
was happening all over town...
...as boys and girls got their letters
back from Santa.
No one knew what it meant.
But we grownups knew one thing for sure:
We were gonna do everything we could
to find out.
[ALL CHATTERING]
FATHER MOUSE:
While people stormed the village hall...
...and the mayor was wishing
he was somewhere else...
...I decided to give Mouse Bell a whirl
and get the word from up north.
North Pole substation.
This is Father Mouse in Junctionville.
Am I coming through?
The equipment is in working order.
Oh, well, listen, we want to know
what's the matter with Santa.
- You'll have to be more specific, sir.
- I'll be specific.
How about these letters that all came back
not even opened?
- You did say Junctionville, sir?
- Yes, Junctionville.
Ooh, that explains it, sir.
Santa didn't like that letter in the
Junctionville Register, sir. Not one bit.
Letter? What letter? Who wrote it?
I wish I knew. It was signed, "all of us."
Hello.
Back issues, Junctionville Register,
in the cellar.
[ALL CHATTERING]
MAN: A citizen to see you, Mr. Mayor.
- Citizen?
They're not allowed in here.
This is public property.
This one says he has an answer
to our problem.
Then show him in. Show him in!
Mr. Joshua Trundle, a clockmaker.
TRUNDLE:
Mr. Mayor and honorable councilmen...
...I think we all know what the problem is.
We have concluded that,
for reasons unknown...
...Mr. Claus, Santa, that is...
...has taken an unconscionable attitude
of hostile retaliation toward...
Oh, heck, he's mad at us.
That's just what I think too,
and I want to make him happy again...
...with this.
Very handsome, Mr. Trundle.
But how will a clock make him happy?
It's not an ordinary clock.
At exactly midnight on Christmas Eve,
when Santa is flying overhead...
...he'll hear this.
CHILDREN [SINGING]:
Christmas chimes are calling
Santa, Santa
Every heart recalling
Come on ol' Kris Kringle
Down the Milky Way
Of course, this is only a small model.
With the children singing,
I must make a big one...
...big enough for Santa
to see and hear.
- I move to authorize construction at once.
- Second.
All those in favor? And don't you
dare say no, McDavitt.
MEN: Aye.
- Carried.
You may build your clock, Mr. Trundle.
And may the enchanting tones
of its melody...
...soar to the pinnacle
of the celestial heights where...
Oh, heck, get started.
MOTHER MOUSE:
I found it, I found it.
"Dear Editor, Santa Claus
is a fraudulent myth...
...rooted in unconscious fantasies
and emerging as a deceitful lie."
"P.S. The reindeer are phony too."
MOTHER MOUSE: "Signed, all of us."
- No wonder Santa's angry.
- Who would send him a letter like that?
- Big words. It sounds like the mayor.
Long words.
- Long words.
- Oh, no. It couldn't be.
- Albert?
- Yes, Father.
There'ssomethingwe've
got to talk about.
I said, yes, Father.
- "Yes, Father," what?
- I wrote the letter...
...my friends and I, that is. All of us.
You didn't, Albert.
"Dear Editor, Santa Claus
is a fraudulent myth rooted in..."
Enough. Enough.
Write another one right
away, apologizing.
But I can't.
- Why not?
- That letter was true.
You don't know as much as you think,
because you only think with your head.
So you have a lot of trouble believing
in things you can't see or touch.
Like, for instance, what things?
[SINGING]
How about fairies and leprechauns
On St. Patrick's Day
How about
Just about everything
That makes a holiday gay
There's more to the world
Than meets the eye
When doubt's in your mind
Give your heart a try
Let up a little on the wonder why
And give your heart a try
If you can't believe
What you can't see
Well, here's what to do
To become like me
Let up a little on the wonder why
And give your heart a try
CHORUS: What is spring
Without the Easter Bunny?
Like a rainbow
That doesn't end in money
And a Valentine
Would certainly look stupid
Without a cupid
So let his arrow in your heart
FATHER MOUSE:
That would be a start.
CHORUS & FATHER MOUSE:
There's more to the world
Than meets the eye
When doubt's in your mind
Give your heart a try
Let up a little on the wonder why
And give your heart a try
FATHER MOUSE:
Here's our first example...
...of how you ruined
everyone's Christmas with your opinions.
This children's hospital once knew
laughter, best medicine there is...
...but not anymore.
[CHILDREN CRYING]
There's Davey Thomas,
best artist in school.
He made that picture of Santa
when he thought that Santa cared.
These are just kids.
Grownups never believe in Santa.
Don't quite know everything, do you?
Shh.
Everyone's asleep.
Mr. Trundle's been hard at work
making a special clock.
There's the model.
When the clock strikes 12
on Christmas Eve...
...it'll play a song welcoming Santa.
Does that sound like a man
who doesn't believe?
[WHISPERING] A song? When the hands
come together like this?
[SONG STARTS TO PLAY]
What's the matter with you?
Do you wanna wake everyone up?
Neat. Does it work
on the gear-and-pinion principle...
...or an AC synchronous motor?
Well, it's more of a...
A gear what? Synchronous who?
Ever since Copernicus, Dad,
it was known that...
Never mind. Never...
You may know algebra, son...
...but this time, the whole town's
counting on this clock.
[MARCHING BAND PLAYING]
Fellow citizens...
...we are gathered
on this auspicious occasion...
...to honor a distinguished gentleman...
...whose inspired
and consummate excellence...
...in the craft of chronometric
creation has, uh, ahem...
Oh, heck, he made one whale
of a clock. Mr. Joshua Trundle.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
And now, Mr. Trundle, if you will start
your magnificent clock and its song...
...that will make Santa Claus
our friend again.
With pleasure.
[SONG STARTS TO PLAY]
FATHER MOUSE:
After the clock went kerplooey...
...life changed for Mr. Trundle.
No one trusted him anymore.
Please, come back.
I'm still a good clockmaker.
Really, I am.
- What do you want?
- I'm Joshua Trundle.
I've come to fix the clock.
Ain't you fixedthings
enougharound here?
But I made that clock
for the town, for Santa.
It's got to work by Christmas Eve,
and I can make it work. I...
- What seems to be the trouble?
- This joker wants to get in.
- He came to fix the clock.
- Is that what he says?
Well, let me tell you something, Trundle.
Of all the incompetent, insolent purveyors
of chicanery that I have ever...
Oh, heck, go home.
FATHER MOUSE: Winter came, and things
got tough for the Trundles.
And if you think they had it bad...
We'd have swapped our whiskers
for a peanut shell or a ripe apple seed...
...but meals don't fall from empty tables.
Then, finally, it was Christmas Eve.
- No sense in hanging stockings, Dad.
- There's no one to fill them this year...
...unless you believe in miracles.
Now, don't go saying that.
The night's not over yet. There's...
There's always hope.
Miracles happen most every day.
[SINGING]
To people like you and me
But don't expect a miracle
Unless you help make it to be
So you hope
And I'll hurry
You pray and I'll plan
We'll do what's necessary
'Cause
Even a miracle needs a hand
You love
And I'll labor
You sit
And I'll stand
Get help from our next-door neighbor
'Cause
Even a miracle needs a hand
We'll help our maker
To make our dreams come true
But I can't do it alone
So
Here's what we're gonna do
- You hope and I'll hurry
- We'll hope
- You pray while I plan
- We'll pray
We'll do what's necessary
'Cause
Even a miracle needs a hand
BOTH:
We'll help our maker
To make our dreams come true
But we can't do it alone
So
What are we're gonna do
- You wish while I whittle
- We'll wish
You drip while I dry
Let's all try to help a little
'Cause
Even a miracle
- Needs a hand
- Even a miracle needs a hand
MOTHER MOUSE:
Come, children, it's time for bed.
[SINGING SOFTLY]
Even a miracle
Needs a hand
[ALBERT SOBS]
- What is it?
- It's my fault. All my fault.
- I've ruined everyone's Christmas.
- I know you wrote the letter, Albert.
You told us so, and that was honest of you.
But as you said, it was your opinion.
ALBERT:
No, that isn't it. Something else.
FATHER MOUSE: What else?
- Mr. Trundle's clock...
...in the village hall.
I wanted to see how it worked...
...so I climbed up into it and...
- Kerplunk.
- Kerplooey.
- You broke the clock?
- I didn't mean it, Father.
I'm sorry. So sorry.
It's not enough. When you've done
something wrong...
...you have to correct the thing you did.
That's it. I'll fix it, Father.
I'll fix the clock by midnight.
- Then maybe Santa will...
- You believe in Santa?
I don't know. I don't know. But I've
learned that I still got a lot to learn.
But, son, you don't know
how to fix a clock.
That's all right, Father. Copernicus knew.
[SINGING] You hope
And I'll hurry
You pray
And I'll plan
We'll do what's necessary
'Cause
Even a miracle
Needs a hand
Good luck.
[TICKING]
Psst.
- Father Mouse?
- Merry Christmas, Mr. Trundle.
- Not very merry, I'm afraid.
- You're right, of course.
And it's my fault, my family's.
- How so?
- My older boy, Albert.
First, he insulted Santa, and then...
- I can hardly say it.
- Go on.
I'm afraid he got into your clock
to see how it worked, and then...
- Kerplunk.
- Kerplooey.
So that was it.
The boy has repented.
He's trying to make amends right now.
Diameter of coil in inverse ratio
to mainspring.
FATHER MOUSE: Which brings us to where
we were three minutes...
Three seconds to Christmas.
No chimes.
No song.
No Santa.
CAROLERS [SINGING]:
All is calm
All is bright
Round yon
Virgin Mother and Child
[CHIMES SOUNDING]
CHORUS:
Christmas snow is falling
Carols fill the air
But it won't be Christmas
Till Santa Claus is here
[BELLS RINGING]
Christmas chimes are calling
Santa! Santa!
Every heartbeat calling
Come on ol' Kris Kringle
Down the Milky Way
Christmas chimes are calling
Santa
We need you today!
If you don't believe in
Santa! Santa!
Think that he's deceiving
Think about a Christmas
With no Christmas cheer
Christmas chimes are calling Santa
And his eight reindeer
We love his laughter
His jingle-ling-a-ling
Forever after
The bells will ring
Christmas chimes are calling
Santa! Santa!
Every heart beat calling
Come on ol' Kris Kringle
Down the Milky Way
Christmas chimes are calling Santa
We need you today!
TRUNDLE: When out on the lawn
There arose such a clatter
I sprang from the bed
To see what was the matter
Away to the window
I flew like a flash
Tore open the shutters
And threw up the sash
The moon on the breast
Of the new-fallen snow
Gave the luster of midday
To objects below
When what to my wondering eyes
Should appear
But a miniature sleigh
And eight tiny reindeer
With a little old driver
So lively and quick
I knew in a moment
It must be Saint Nick
More rapid than eagles
His coursers they came
And he whistled and shouted
And called them by name
SANTA: Now, Dasher! Now, Dancer!
Now, Prancer and Vixen!
On, Comet! On, Cupid!
On, Donner and Blitzen!
To the top of the porch
To the top of the wall
Now dash away, dash away
Dash away, all
Ho-ho-ho!
TRUNDLE: As dry leaves that before
The wild hurricane fly
When they meet with an obstacle
Mount to the sky
So up to the housetop
The coursers they flew
With a sleigh full of toys
And Saint Nicholas too
And then, in a twinkling
I heard on the roof
The prancing and pawing
Of each little hoof
As I drew in my head
And was turning around
Down the chimney
Saint Nicholas came with a bound
He was dressed all in fur
From his head to his foot
And his clothes were all tarnished
With ashes and soot
A bundle of toys
He had flung on his back
And he looked like a peddler
Just opening his pack
His eyes, how they twinkled
His dimples, how merry
His cheeks were like roses
His nose like a cherry
His droll little mouth
Was drawn up like a bow
And the beard of his chin
Was as white as the snow
The stump of a pipe
He held tight in his teeth
And the smoke, it encircled his head
Like a wreath
He had a broad face
And a round little belly
That shook when he laughed
Like a bowlful of jelly
He was chubby and plump
A right jolly old elf
And I laughed when I saw him
In spite of myself
A wink of his eye
And a twist of his head
Soon gave me to know
I had nothing to dread
He spoke not a word
But went straight to his work
And filled all the stockings
Then turned with a jerk
And laying his finger
Aside of his nose
And giving a nod
Up the chimney he rose
He sprang to his sleigh
To his team gave a whistle
And away they all flew
Like the down of a thistle
But I heard him exclaim
Ere he drove out of sight
Happy Christmas to all,
and to all a good night!
---The end---