'You're sweatin'.'
'I'm excited,
I can see it all happening.'
(# Piano: "These Are A Few
Of My Favourite Things")
A little turn. Now side to side.
- # Raindrops and roses...
- Other people can sing.
(All) # ..on kittens
# White copper kettles
and warm woollen mittens
# Brown paper packages
tied up with string
# These are a few
of my favourite things... #
- Can we talk?
- But she's fantastic.
- I think she sings funny.
- God!
- Her dancing's not great either.
- It's the first time she did it.
Bum bum-bum, bum bum-bum,
bum bum-bum...
But I had the kettle by then,
she didn't take the kettle.
Do you want me to...
No, I just want Kathy
to put it here. This is...
You say these words, put
your hands out and they're there.
(All) # These are a few
of my favourite things... #
Please, don't drop the props, Kathy.
# Cream-coloured ponies
and apple strudels
# Doorbells and sleigh bells
and schnitzel with noodles... #
(Samuel) Why are you putting it
on her head? I'm a little confused.
I don't know... Because she's not
going to pick it up.
It looks like you're trying to put
a hat on her head.
You're fantastic. You just have
to listen to your heart, Cvalda.
I don't want you to call me Cvalda.
You're Cvalda to me.
Let's do some sound effects.
- Uh! # When the dog bites
- (All) Woof!
- # When the bee stings
- Ouch!
# When I'm feeling sad...
- (Selma) # When the dog bites
- Woof!
# When the... #
- I'm not barking.
- # ..I'm feeling sad
# And then I don't feel so bad #
(Applause)
Wait!
I told you no tapping
in "The Sound of Music"!
It needs rhythm,
like drums or something.
(Samuel) Everybody's doing
a great job.
Really.
- Hello, Selma. Come in. Ready?
- Yeah.
- OK, you know where to stand.
Let's try this one.
F-E-Z-D
Maybe the last one.
D-E-F-P-O
I think you can work
that machine safely.
I'll write a note to the plant.
OK, thank you.
Bye.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Bye.
(Roar of machines)
# So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, adieu... #
# I'd like to stay
and taste my French champagne
# Ah-ha!
# So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, adieu #
We lost five hours cos some
idiot broke the machine.
- Bill's here.
- So?
Well, he's here with Gene.
That sounds like bad news.
What are you going to do?
I guess I gotta tell her, don't I?
# So long... #
You can't bring the script
to work, Selma.
Keep your eyes on the machine, OK?
Yeah.
Sure, sure.
Bill's here.
Bill?
He's here with Gene.
Damn.
Not again.
You gotta come right back, OK?
Don't be too worried.
We'll work this out. Here she comes.
(Sighs)
Why are you not in school?
When I say so you go to school.
Do you think I joke?
You have to study!
Come on, Selma, stop.
We talked about this, didn't we?
Hanging out with those
automobile thieves.
- So what?
- He's learning.
Selma, he's learning.
Gene, this is the most
important thing.
You have to go to school.
I-I-I can drive him back to school.
Since when was that your business?
If you need a ride home...
I-I don't even punch out
till another two hours.
- Sometimes you punch out around now.
- I never punch out early!
Don't need a dump!
Don't need a ride!
..in your little head.
Let's get you to school, Mr G.
(Train whistle)
Thank you, but...I'll just,
I'll just ride my bike.
Bye, Jeff.
She likes you.
I'm sure of it.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure of it.
This is my punishment,
that you help me with this.
And you've got...
You've got to make your bed as well.
And you forgot to wrap up
the bread...two times.
There's no more of that.
You keep reading.
"So long, farewell,
auf...wiedersehen,
"adieu, adieu, adieu
to yieu and yieu and yieu."
To "yieu" and "yieu"...
What does that mean...
"yieu"?
- It's your dumb musical.
- And yieu?
It's German.
Do you think?
- Y-you want some more ketchup?
- No.
Are you tired?
Wh-Why should you...always
ask me so, so stupid questions?
Shall I show you my step?
(Metronome clicks)
# So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, adieu
# So long... #
- Oh, hi.
- Hi, Gene. Hi.
How's the dancin'?
- Oh, good, yeah.
- Yeah?
You want to come to me and Bill's
place and listen to some music?
That...that would be lovely.
But we couldn't.
- Come on. Come on.
- Yeah, I'll...
Let's go. Come on.
You should ask Bill about his money.
Linda likes it
when we talk about that.
(Classical Spanish guitar)
You're doing a nice job of these.
How about that?
You have to be very careful
not to bend the card.
Otherwise I don't get paid for it.
No?!
That's fair, because the people
in the shops
would never buy it if it's bent.
- You wouldn't buy it if it was bent.
- That's true. No.
In Czechoslovakia...I saw a film
and they were eating candy
from a tin just like this.
- No (!)
- I thought to myself...
how wonderful it must be
in the United States.
(Linda) Yeah? You think
my house looks like a movie?
- Our house looks like a movie!
- (Bill) You look like a movie star.
Bill gives me a lot of money,
you know.
Of course, it's all that money
you inherited, Bill.
(Bill and Linda) That's right.
Hey, Selma...
(Take the rest with you.)
- Are you sure?
- (Go on.)
(Sweets rattle in tin)
(Whistle)
- (Bill) Hello.
- (Selma) Good morning.
Got the rent.
Oh, you always pay right on time.
Don't worry about Gene,
I'll get him to school.
Thank you. Thanks very much.
Remember your bag.
- (Linda) Bye.
- (Selma) Bye.
You're always so serious, Kathy.
Ah, again we start.
(Laughs) I don't think
inside you're serious at all.
I don't know.
- Not always.
- Cvalda.
- Why do you call me that?
- It's like...someone who's...
- What?
- Dunno, big and happy.
Hey! I'm not that big.
Happy, I don't know.
You just need someone
to pull it out.
# You're getting to be
a habit with me... #
- (Kathy) Beautiful eyes.
- (Selma) Yeah. But he's not happy.
How's she doing?
It's when she cannot keep up
and she is going to faint.
(Kathy) She fainted.
- (Man) Please, be quiet.
- She doesn't see that well.
- I paid good money to see this.
- So did she.
I love it when they dance.
It's a musical,
of course they're dancing!
- We know.
- You're so smart!
- Yes.
- Oh.
I think you made friends, Kathy.
Shh!
(Stop.)
(Linda) So?
So what did she say?
- What?
- What did she say?
She didn't say anything.
Are you trying to tell me something?
It's about the bike.
- (Selma) The bike?
- (Bill) Mmm. The bike.
Oh...I-I cannot give...
give Gene a bike.
- Is this his idea?
- (Bill) It is not.
- Gene?
- Yeah?
Did you ask them to come over?
No.
(Kathy) No, he doesn't
know anything, Selma. Frankly.
- Why? Have I done something?
- No.
I haven't got the money.
I'm almost the only kid in class
who doesn't have a bike.
I even know a boy
who's got a scooter.
You all know I haven't got any money.
All the extra money I've got...
The times I save up -
I send it to Grandpa.
Come and have a look.
Your mother is only teasing.
Look what she's brought for you!
It's a bike!
- (Selma) We can't accept that.
- (Kathy) It's not new.
I can't give him any expensive things
- not even for his birthday.
He's just gotta accept
I'm not that sort of mum.
I-I-I'm just not
that kind of mother, G-Gene...
Can't you be that kind of a mother?
It's not exactly a scooter.
We'll see.
- (Kathy) Careful! Careful!
- (Linda) Don't ride so fast!
(Bill) Gene, bring it over here.
- He looks very happy.
- (Bill) He does look happy.
(Kathy) Here he comes again.
Attention!
(Bill) Bring it over here.
- Mom?
- OK.
(Kathy) Did you hear that?
- (Gene) Did you say OK?
- (Kathy laughs) Yeah.
- (Bill) She said OK?
- (Linda) Yeah.
- But promise to go to school.
- Yes, yes.
Every day...on time.
I didn't know
you were such a good biker.
(Jeff) Rust and women are the same.
Rust and women are the same?
Yeah, I'm just saying...
- Your father said that.
- Yeah.
I didn't know what it meant.
(All laugh)
He is so kind. Look at me...
He did all the work.
He's really kind.
Thank you, Jeff.
(Jeff) You're welcome.
Come in.
Something up, Bill?
No. I just couldn't sleep,
that's all.
I have no money.
All the money that I inherited is...
It's gone.
And Linda...
Ah, Linda.
She just spends and spends.
And my salary is nowhere near enough.
I can't say no to her.
The bank is going to repossess
the house...
because I'm so far behind
on the payments.
And I'm going to lose Linda.
I know it.
I know I am.
She loves you, Bill.
(Bill sobs)
Ah, don't cry.
I shouldn't have told you.
- Don't worry. It's OK.
- I shouldn't have.
No, I think you've got...
enough stuff...
Would it make you feel better
if I told you a secret?
What could you tell me?
I'm going blind.
Not yet, but...soon.
Maybe sometime this year.
Blind?
It's not as bad as it sounds.
It's a...
It's a family thing.
- But blind?
- I've always known it.
From...from...
I was a little girl, I knew.
(Sniffs)
And you're OK?
Well, I came to America,
because in America they can give
Gene an operation, you know?
Gene?
But, he doesn't know about it.
You mustn't tell him
because then it could get worse.
I just have to save up money,
you know. Enough money to...
Oh, I almost got it.
To, um... For the operation.
They can operate on Gene
when he turns 13.
You made up that story
about your father?
I never had a father.
I made up his name too.
That's why you put in all these
hours and do everything you do.
For him? For his operation?
Well, it is my fault...I guess.
How is it your fault?
Because I knew he would...
he would have bad eyes like me.
But I had him all the same.
You're very strong.
I'm not strong.
I've got little games I play
when it goes really hard.
When I'm working in the factory...
and the machines,
they make these...rhythms.
And I just start dreaming
and it all becomes music.
- You like movies, don't you?
- I love them.
- Yeah?
- I just love the musicals.
- When they're all tap-dancing?
- All of them tap-dancing.
All of them in those huge long lines.
I... Wouldn't you like
to be in that line?
- Yeah.
- Just kicking your feet.
Yeah.
When they're like spiralling up
the huge enormous wedding cakes.
- Yeah, yeah.
- To the top?
Isn't it annoying when they
do the last song?
Why?
You know when it goes really big
and the camera goes, like,
out of the roof
and you just know it's going to end.
I hate that. I really hate that.
I used to cheat when I was
a little girl in Czechoslovakia.
I would leave the cinema just
after the next to last song.
And the film
would just go on forever.
- It's lovely, isn't it?
- It is lovely.
- Selma?
- Yeah?
Thank you for telling me your secret.
Thanks for telling me yours.
Mum's the word, right?
Mum?
- We don't tell anybody.
- Oh, yes.
(Selma) I won't tell anyone.
Good night.
Thank you.
So, can I get you another?
Yeah, sure.
- How about a big one?
- How many is there in a big one?
Ten thousand.
I'll have a big one.
(Man) What's this guy's name again?
(Kathy and Selma) Who?
The old man - the guy we're
carding these pins for?
Her father? I know. Oldrich, right?
Yeah.
Oldrich Novy.
He used to dance in Prague.
You commies make a big deal
out of sharing everything.
Yeah, it's a good thing.
What are you doing here,
if Czechoslovakia is so much
better than the US of A?
No, Selma, no!
There are two plates.
It's all right.
You know what happens when you put
two plates in, don't you?
Well, she didn't. It didn't..
You destroy the tool!
Takes a whole day to mend.
Never two plates, Selma!
You cheated the doctor.
You shouldn't be working here.
How dare you! How much can you see?
We could do it with our eyes closed.
No.
It's just because I was daydreaming.
Daydreaming? Dreaming about what?
- I just hear music.
- Come on, Selma. Music?
You could cut off your hand.
You have to watch out.
Promise me you'll stay awake.
I promise I will stop daydreaming.
No, you're not really,
you repeat but...
I don't know why I bother that much.
(Car engine)
(Jeff) Hi, Selma.
If you're not going with Kathy
can I give you a lift?
I don't want a boyfriend.
I-I told you.
You're a really nice guy,
Jeff, but...
I just don't have time
for a boyfriend.
Not right now.
I know.
If I wanted a boyfriend,
it would be you, Jeff.
I just don't want one right now.
No problem, you know - on the
back - to have the bike there.
Yeah.
Bye, Jeff.
I don't think it's very safe,
riding the bike wearing glasses
and all.
- Selma?
- Bye, Jeff.
(Jeff) Are you OK?
Yeah, I'm fine.
- Hi, Selma.
- Hi, Bill.
- Heading home?
- Oh, yes.
Wanna throw that in the back?
That would be lovely. Yes, please.
- Hi, Jeff.
- Hey, did you see the truck?
No.
Like, driving like crazy.
- He what?
- He was driving like crazy.
Getting dirty.
Thank you.
- (Selma) Bye, Jeff.
- Bye. Thank you, Bill.
- OK?
- (Bill) OK.
If I could make the next payment,
I'd have a bit more time.
Yeah.
All I need is a loan.
Just be a month.
This money's Gene's.
- I'm sorry, Bill.
- I shouldn't have asked.
Don't worry,
there's no harm in asking.
No, I shouldn't have asked.
Linda wants new couches.
Huh.
I could always shoot myself.
You mustn't say things like that.
It'd just...make things easier.
- You know that, Bill?
- No, Selma...
- You mustn't say those things.
- I'm kidding.
Hi, Selma. Come on in. Hi, Gene.
- Good morning.
- Hi.
- (Linda) How are you?
- (Selma) Fine, thank you.
- (Gene) Can I see the gun?
- (Linda) Yeah, go on.
- He's got a gun?
- Sure, he's a police officer.
Just didn't know he'd keep
it here, in the house.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Keeps it in his desk.
Maybe I should pay more rent.
It's been the same
since I've been here.
No, Selma. I won't hear it.
You keep your money,
you need it more than we do.
Two boxes?
You are going to do two boxes
at the same time now?
- Yeah.
- Selma, ten o'clock, then?
Yeah, ten o'clock.
What happens at ten o'clock?
I'm gonna do the night shift.
The night shift? You can hardly
see enough to do your own shift.
It suits me fine.
It's just after drama class.
You are going to do that too?
I've had my fill of you.
Do what you want.
Go ahead! Break your neck.
You do your night shift.
But don't think
I'm going to come rescue you.
(Jeff) Selma.
Kathy split already.
I'm not looking for Kathy.
I was looking for you.
Just have to go to a drama rehearsal.
What do you say?
You always ride your bike.
You have it over there.
I...I left it at home. I thought
it would be quicker if I walk.
How do you reckon that?
I'd just walk along
the railroad tracks.
It's, a...short cut.
I don't understand, in musicals...
why do they start to sing
and dance all of a sudden?
I mean, I don't suddenly start
to sing and dance.
No.
You're right, Jeff. You don't.
The last thing on the list
is the bake sale.
Two Sundays away.
- Hi, Selma. Come on in.
- Hi.
I'm gonna introduce you
to your understudy.
- My...my understudy?
- Yeah.
This girl, Suzan, whom Boris knows.
She's a good singer and dancer.
She'll learn your part too.
Because, say you get a cold
and...you can't do it...
then the show
doesn't have to stop. OK?
Suzan - Selma. Selma - Suzan.
Ah... Could you take off
your glasses?
I think we'll do the part
without glasses.
Next Sunday you will see both Marias.
I mean Selma will do the role, but
I'll have you read too. All right?
It's your first night shift, right?
While this is being pressed,
you'll be cutting here.
That means you'll be in charge
of two machines.
You have to feed Sarah
over there, right?
This palette must never be empty.
- Is it always so dark in here?
- What?
It's exactly the same as the daytime.
But you have to work a little faster.
- That's what we're paid for. OK?
- Thank you.
Excuse me. You have to work,
you know, a little faster.
OK.
What are you doing here?
What do you think?
I didn't put you down
for the night shift, Kathy.
Run along, Norman.
I'm on my own time now.
How I spend it is my own business.
- Night, ladies!
- Good night.
Faster. A little faster.
I like it better when you dance.
You should dance more, Cvalda.
I will when there is music.
(Machines begin working in rhythm)
# Clatter, crash, clack
# Racket, bang, thump
# Rattle, clang, crack
# Thud, whack, bam...
# Clatter, crash, clack
# Racket, bang, slam
# Rattle, clang, crack,
thud, whack, bam
- (Selma) # It's music
- (All) Dance, dance
- (Selma) # Now dance
# Listen, Cvalda
# You're the dancer
# You've got the sparkle
# In your eyes
# Look
# At
# Me
# And transcend...
(Harp crescendos)
# Clatter, crash, clack
# Racket, bang, thump
# Rattle, clang, crash,
splash, whack, bam...
# The clatter machines
# They greet you and say...
# We tap out a rhythm
# And sweep you away
# A clatter machine
# What a magical sound
# A room full of noises
# That spins you around
(Rhythmical clattering,
banging and whirring)
# Darling, Selma, look who's dancing
# Faster than a shooting star
# Cvalda's here
(All) # Dance...dance
(All) # Dance, dance, dance,
dance, dance, dance, dance
(All) # Clatter, crash, clack,
racket, bang, thump
# Racket, clang, crack,
thud, whack, bam
# Clatter, crash, clack,
racket, bang, thump
# Rattle, clang, crack,
thud, whack, bam...
# The clatter machines
# They greet you and say
# Tap out a rhythm
# And sweep you away
# A clatter machine
# What a magical sound
# A room full of noises
# That spins us around
# That spins us... #
(Kathy) Selma!
Stop it you've cut yourself!
Get away from the machine. Henry!
Oh, Jeff is here.
- Hello, Jeff.
- Hi, Kathy.
Do you live here?
She might say yes to a ride
when it's this late.
Maybe Kathy...wants a ride.
No, it's all right.
What's that on your hand?
- She cut her...
- Cut my finger.
- It's going to be all right.
- The plates are sharp.
- Good night.
- Careful.
(Birds twittering)
I think I found a solution
to my problem.
That makes me really happy.
It's nothing special.
But I've made up my mind
I'm gonna tell Linda.
I mean, after all,
she loves me, and...
We'll just work it out together.
That sounds like
a really good idea, Bill.
Sorry. I'll let you get to bed.
I guess I'm kinda tired.
Thanks, Bill.
- Good night, Selma.
- Good night, Bill.
Bill?
What's happening now?
(Samuel) Here we go.
Selma, are you ready?
# So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, goodbye
# I hate to go
and leave this pretty sight... #
(Samuel) And...
You're on.
(Samuel) Cut, cut.
Stop, stop, please.
(Samuel) This is
Selma's entrance, OK? Yeah?
OK, Paul, please.
(All) # ..an absurd little bird... #
How far do you think it is?
I don't know.
(All) # So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, goodbye... #
(Samuel) And...
Kathy, what are you doing?
This is Maria's entrance.
Yes, I'm sorry. It's my mistake.
Please, I don't have all night.
- Six steps.
- OK.
(Samuel) Good.
OK, I'm thinking maybe, Selma,
you could take a little circle
around Boris on this next part.
Unless you have something else
you want to suggest.
I'm open.
OK?
- Samuel?
- Yes?
I need to talk to you.
If it's about the drummer,
I have been looking everywhere...
- I promised you...
- It's not about the drummer.
- Just a quick word.
- Do you wanna go outside?
- Yeah.
- OK.
(All) # And up in the nursery
an absurd little bird
# Is popping out to say cuckoo
I'm...I'm not gonna play Maria.
What?
My heart just isn't in this,
like, I shouldn't be wasting
my time on something...
that isn't that important, really.
I've been watching Suzan
and she's...she's great.
She's...she's a much better
dancer than I am.
Suzan's terrific,
I'm not denying that.
But, you... I thought
you lived for musicals.
So you've been pretending
the whole time?
Yes, I've just been pretending.
I don't know what else...
Everything's cast now.
Yeah.
The only part that's left
is the old nun.
I don't think you'd want
that part. There's no dancing.
She's quite serious, then?
She's serious, yeah.
It's important for the part.
And not dancing, really. No.
I could put a little dancing
in there.
You think so?
I didn't have it in mind.
You can have your tapping.
She could be just a little
humorous once in a while.
Even though she's a nun.
You'll always be my perfect Maria.
Where are all the hairpins today?
I left them at home.
And she won't be playing Maria.
What will I do
if I can't bawl you out
for learning your lines
on company time?
One...two...three!
What kind of a joke is that?
- I need a word with you.
- We're talking now.
All right. Come on.
Please, sit down.
We were off for the whole day.
Everything stops when the
machine breaks, you know that.
I-I can do my job just fine
if I stick to the day shift.
This won't happen again.
I-I daydream too much.
I-I decided to quit.
I guess, then, I forgot.
I've been ordered
to let you go, Selma.
You don't have to pay for the machine
you broke. I got them to agree.
Thanks, Norman.
This is your, ah...salary.
And you know, ah...
maybe we can find you something
away from the machines...
where your eyesight
wouldn't matter so much.
- Not right away.
- That's very kind.
But, um, I'll be OK.
I-I really will.
- Thanks, Norman.
- Thank you, Selma.
Thank you.
What is she going to do now?!
Did you ever think about that?!
Don't worry, Kathy, really.
I'm going to be fine.
Has anybody seen Jeff today?
He's usually here early, Selma.
But not this early.
That's a shame.
Selma!
Selma.
I could give you a lift if you want.
I-I will need a lift...later.
I need to do something important
at, ah...three.
You need to get your truck,
then, don't you?
Yeah.
(Whistle)
Train's coming.
Get off the track, Jeff.
You have to be careful.
Stick to the side.
You can't see, can you?
What is there to see?
(Whistle)
(Rhythmical clacking
of train on tracks)
# I've seen it all
# I have seen the trees
# I have seen the willow leaves
# Dancing in the breeze
# I've see a man killed
by his best friend
# And lives that were over
before they were spent
# I've seen what I was
# And I know what I'll be
# I've seen it all -
there is no more to see
# You haven't seen elephants,
kings or Peru
# I'm happy to say
I have better to do
# What about China?
# Have you seen the Great Wall?
# All walls are great
if their roof doesn't fall
# And the man you will marry
# The home you will share?
# To be honest, I really don't care
# You've never been to Niagara Falls
# I have seen water
# It's water, that's all
# The Eiffel Tower, the Empire State
# My pulse was as high
on my very first date
# Your grandson's hand
as he plays with your hair
# To be honest, I really don't care
# I've seen it all
# I have seen the dark
# I have seen the brightness
in one little spark
# I have seen what I choose
and seen what I need
# And that is enough,
to want more would be greed
# I've seen what I was
# And I know what I'll be
# I've seen it all -
there is no more to see
(Workmen) # You've seen it all
and all you have seen
# You can always review
on your own little screen
# The light and the dark,
the big and the small
# Just keep in mind
you need no more at all
# You've seen what you were
and know what you'll be
# You've seen it all,
there is no more to see #
(Music stops, train keeps beat)
(Jeff) You can't see, can you?
See you at three.
I can see.
Gene hasn't come back yet.
I need to talk to Bill.
He decided to take the day off
to go to the bank for his box.
Is he...is he upstairs?
I know everything, Selma.
Bill told me.
I want you to move out.
I don't understand. What do you know?
That you came on to him.
That you asked him into the trailer,
but he turned you down.
You've got nothing
to say for yourself?!
No. I want to talk to Bill.
(Record has finished playing)
Hi, Bill.
Linda saw me go up to the, um...
up to the trailer.
I told her it was you
who wanted to...
That you'd... That you'd fallen
in love with me.
I know. She told me.
And what did you tell her?
Nothing.
You didn't tell her I was lying?
Mum's the word, right?
Linda told me you went to the bank.
I went to the bank
to ask for more time.
But I couldn't do it
and I brought the box home instead.
Linda always gets so proud when she
sees me sitting in here with it.
But you've put my money in it,
haven't you?
To make it look like it's yours.
But it's my money, Bill.
I'm gonna have to take it.
You can have it back.
Y-You can...
you can have it back in a month.
But I can't do that, Bill.
Selma...
I-I've decided to...
to pay the doctor this afternoon.
I can't save up more money.
That's over now.
Gene doesn't even turn thirteen
until after Christmas.
There was $2,026
and ten cents in the tin.
I can't count it now,
but I trust you.
And it's thirty dollars
I got today...
which makes it...
2,056...ten cents.
It's not enough...
but it'll have to do.
- Selma.
- Bye, Bill.
Selma.
Selma, stop.
I'm pointing my gun at you, Selma.
I don't believe you.
You're just trying to scare me.
I can't see a gun.
Just feel this.
Feel this. Feel it. Feel it!
(Selma sobs)
Do you believe I have the gun?
I believe you. But it's my money.
No, it's my money.
It's the money I had in MY box
and you're trying
to steal it from me.
Selma! Selma!
SELMA! STOP! SELMA, STOP!
LINDA! LINDA! LINDA!
What's the matter, Bill?
She was trying to steal our money.
She knew I had the gun
in my drawer and she...
Is that why you wanted him?
For the money?
Run to the car and get my handcuffs.
Go get the handcuffs.
Give me the money.
(Give me the money.)
(Gimme the money
and I'll let you go.)
Where should I go?
(Just gimme the money.)
(Selma, just gimme the money.)
Gimme the money. Give me...
No! No! No!
(Gunshot)
(Selma cries)
You shot me.
I'm gonna...
No, no, Selma,
you did the right thing.
I should have done it myself.
Kill me.
Just kill me.
Be my friend and show some
mercy, please, and just kill me.
You handcuffs aren't in the car.
Show some mercy, Selma, and just...
Linda, run. Run up to Miller's farm.
Call the station
and tell them to hurry.
RUN! GET UP THERE!
Go to Miller's farm!
If you want the money...
(Breathes heavily)
You're going to have to kill me.
Don't do this to me.
(Selma cries)
I'm not letting go.
No.
Just shoot me. Just shoot me.
Shoot me! Shoot me! Shoot me!
(Gunshot)
(Bill shouts and gasps)
Can't you just stand up
and pull the goddamn trigger!
(Sobbing) I want to take my money.
(Music starts)
# Black night is falling
# The sun is gone to bed
# The innocent are dreaming
# As you should, sleepyhead
# Sleepyhead, sleepyhead
# Does it hurt?
# I hurt you much more
# So don't you worry
# I don't know what to do
# Everything just feels so wrong
# Everything is fine
# Just stay strong
# Silly Selma
# You're the one to blame
# (Gene) You just did
what you had to do
# You just did what you had to do
# The time it takes a tear to fall
# A snake to shed its skin
# Is all the time that's needed
# To forgive. Forgive me
# You are forgiven
(Siren)
# Come on, hurry
(Metallic tapping)
# I killed your man
# You have to hurry up
# I've called the police
# They're just down the road
# They've come for me
# Why should I run?
# They'll take your money
# Run for your boy
# Silly Selma
# You're the one to blame
# (Gene) You just did
what you had to do
# You just did what you had to do
# The time it takes a tear to fall
# A heart to miss a beat
# A snake to shed its skin
# A rose to grow a thorn
# Is all the time that's needed
# To forgive me
# I am so sorry
# I just did what I had to do
# I just did what I had to do #
Selma?
Jeff.
What are you doing here?
Is it already three?
Well, not really.
But, hell, I'm always early.
You cut yourself again.
There's some blood on your blouse.
Strange.
I couldn't feel it at all.
(Sirens)
Selma?
We're here now.
By the bus stop?
Yeah, the bus stop.
It's over there.
And the lake is here.
Promise me that you won't
follow me. Promise.
Yeah, I promise.
(Speaks Czech)
I would like to pay for
the operation now.
2,056 dollars and ten cents.
I know it's not quite
what you told me, but...
But it's all I could get together.
What last name
shall I put on the receipt?
Oh, I don't need a receipt,
I really don't.
I have to know the name of your son
for when he comes in
for his operation.
Novy.
He will come and he will say
that his name is Novy.
And then you will know...
that he's been paid for.
Novy?
Like Oldrich Novy,
the tap dancer?
It is strange, isn't it?
He never really made it
over here, did he?
I saw his films when I was a kid.
He was in the first musical
I ever saw.
Same here.
(Jeff) Selma?
(Car door slams)
It's Tuesday night.
What about your rehearsal?
Yeah, I guess...
You wanna go?
Yeah.
And maybe put your arm around her
and a little bit of...
Hi, Selma.
Hi, Samuel.
We weren't sure you'd show up,
actually.
Sure I show up.
Nice to see you. Be right back.
OK.
(Murmuring)
(She's here.)
(Yeah. OK. OK. OK.)
Uh...
OK, I think you could try it
one more time for me.
But I should... I should be going
now. Gene might wonder where I am.
Jeff, he hasn't seen me all day.
I think we could do your scene.
Let's do the tapping scene. OK?
We haven't done it in weeks.
While you're here, we might as well
take advantage of the time. Please?
Let's do the tapping scene.
Let me have the nuns up there.
Imagi... You do Selma's part
for her for now, all right?
(Piano)
- Like it?
- Yes.
We haven't done it for a while.
(Selma hums along)
Remember that part we did where you,
uh, you come to the convent gate?
To say goodbye to Maria.
I should leave, Jeff.
- What?
- Gene is probably worried now.
I haven't seen him all day.
I'm sorry, Samuel, but...
Betty, come here a second.
The drummer you wanted, remember?
I found somebody. She's fantastic.
She's here for the first time.
Please meet her. This is Selma.
- Hi, Betty. You play the drums?
- Yeah.
Tell her how long
you've been studying.
Two years.
She's wonderful. You've gotta
stay and enjoy this. You've...
I have an idea. Let's do the finale.
(Samuel) I just remembered,
you hate finales.
No finale. I've a better idea.
"Climb Every Mountain", part one.
(All) # Climb every mountain
# Ford every stream
(Samuel) Like Indians!
# Follow every rainbow
# Till you find your dream #
# Why do I love it so much?
# What kind of magic is this?
# How come I can't help adore it?
# It's just another musical
# No one minds at all
# If I'm having a ball
# Cos this is a musical
# And there's always someone
to catch me
# There's always someone to catch me
# When you fall #
(Siren)
The State will show...
that the defendant has not only
perpetrated the most callous
and well-planned homicide
in recent memory,
but is also a fundamentally
selfish individual
who cynically hides
behind a handicap,
devoid of sympathy for anybody
but herself.
This woman found trust
and friendship
when she sought refuge
in our country.
And the evidence will show that
she has repaid such kindness
with betrayal, robbery and murder,
inflicted upon the VERY people
who opened their homes
and hearts to her.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
the evidence will prove
that she herself
did not show that mercy
she will ask of us.
Is this the bag here, Detective?
Uh...
Yes, the very same.
Houston's blood was all over it.
Shortly before the homicide
I had a check-up on her vision
and I found that she was myopic.
That's near-sighted.
Near-sighted, but she COULD see.
Yes.
She said communism
was better for human beings.
She had nothing but contempt
for our great country and...
Apart from its musicals. She said
the American ones were better.
So...
The defendant preferred
Hollywood to Vladivostok.
I suppose that's
an acknowledgement of sorts.
She just asked many times
about the money.
(DA) She wanted to know where it was.
That's right.
- She asked about the gun?
- Yes, she did.
She wanted to know where it was kept?
That's right.
Bill was lying on the floor...
and he was wounded and...
Um...
(DA) He was pleading for his life.
Yes.
"I beg you. I beg you. I beg you."
You showed him no mercy, Selma.
You should have no mercy either.
(DA) Would you state your name
for the record, please.
Selma Jezkova.
And Bill and Linda Houston...
were your friends. Is that right?
Yeah.
In fact you lived in a trailer
on their property.
Yeah.
And didn't they also take care of
your young son when you were at work?
Yeah.
They bought him
a birthday present recently.
Is that right?
Yeah, they got him a bike.
Right.
Your sight was poor, you claim -
contrary to the expert testimony
we received.
But you saw well enough
to inflict 34 wounds on Bill Houston.
So why did you kill him, actually?
If I may be so bold to ask.
He asked me to.
He did?
How intriguing.
A man with a fine career,
some wealth and a happy marriage?
Why would this Bill Houston
ask you to kill him?
I promised not to say.
Oh! That clears things up
immensely (!)
You promised you wouldn't say.
In that case we'll just have
to take your word for it
that the money you stole was yours
despite the fact that Bill
Houston's savings
also disappeared so mysteriously
that same day.
Just, ah....
Just where did you get your money?
Well...
I'd been saving up.
I suppose you could call it that.
What were these savings
to be used for?
You never bought your son so much as
a birthday present, as we've heard.
Um...
Yes?
My...my father...
in Czechoslovakia.
Your father.
And what, pray tell, is his name?
My...my father is...
Oldrich Novy.
So...
We're meant to believe
that you killed Bill Houston
by inflicting 34 wounds on him
because he asked you to?
Just as we're meant to believe
that you were blind when you did it.
As we're meant to believe that it
was your savings you stole from him.
Just as we're meant to believe
you sent all you had
to your father back home.
A man by the name of Oldrich Novy.
Is that right?
Yes.
Thank you, Miss Jezkova.
Ladies and gentlemen, you've now
heard from the defendant's lips.
You must believe her.
Just as you must believe her
when she claims her father's name
is Oldrich Novy.
Your Honour,
at this time the State
calls to the witness stand...
Oldrich Novy.
(DA) Please state your full name.
My name is Oldrich Novy.
And you used to live
in Czechoslovakia.
That is right. I live now
in California, as you know.
Right. That's where we found you.
What exactly is your relationship
to the defendant?
I do not know her.
You don't know her?
So...you have
not received money from her?
Money, that...that she says
was so dearly earned?
No, I have not.
Perhaps you're not her father, then.
- No, I am not.
- No.
Well, if this relationship
was made up by the defendant
then can you think of any way
she might know your name?
(Novy) I was once well-known
in Czechoslovakia
because of my profession.
Yes, and Mr Novy,
what is your profession?
Maybe that can give us a clue
to why -
why this somewhat romantic,
certainly communistic woman
who worships Fred Astaire,
but not his country -
why she might have lied
and misused your name -
to make everybody think all
her money was spent on a poor father
and not her own vanity?
- What do you do?
- I was an actor. I made films.
They were musicals.
(Pencils tap in rhythm)
(Music starts)
# Why do I love you so much?
# What kind of magic is there?
# How come I can't help adore you?
# You were in a musical
# I didn't mind it at all
# That you were having a ball
# At my musical
# And I was always there to catch you
# You were always there to catch me
# When I'd fall
(All) # Say it again
(Novy) # I don't mind it at all
# If you're having a ball
# This is your musical
# I'll always be there to catch you
# You will always be there
to catch me
# I'll always be there to catch you
# You will always be there
to catch me
(All) # We'll always be there
to catch you
# We'll always be there to catch you
# When I fall #
(Officer) Will the court please rise?
The honourable
Judge AD Mantle presiding.
Have you reached a verdict?
Yes, Your Honour.
(Officer) Will the defendant
please rise?
We, the jury, find the defendant,
Selma Jezkova,
guilty of murder in the first degree
and hereby sentence her to death.
(Judge) Is this the verdict
of this jury?
You fully understand
that it must be unanimous?
(Foreman) We do, Your Honour.
(Judge) Selma Jezkova...
you are hereby sentenced
to be taken from this place
and confined
in the state penitentiary
until such time
as you shall be executed
by being hanged by the neck,
until you are dead.
This court is adjourned.
(Officer) All rise.
I just heard about the...
the Supreme Court decision.
Yeah, I...I just want to talk
practical stuff.
On Gene's birthday...
he will receive a letter.
And it's so important, Kathy,
that he reads it very carefully.
I need you to take care of that
for me.
Because I'm not going to be there
when he gets it.
He should not be afraid, because
there's nothing to be afraid of.
Listen, Gene wants
to see you so badly.
Won't you let him? Please.
There's nothing for him to see.
He's got you now, Kathy.
And there's one more thing.
He has to call himself Novy.
That's very important.
- All right. Time's up, Selma.
- I know it sounds foolish.
Sorry I didn't tell you before
about this, I didn't dare to
because they would ruin everything.
But why does he have to call
himself Novy?
Stop asking those questions, Cvalda.
Please, let me tell Gene hello,
from you to him.
No.
I know you love your son very much.
I love him very much.
Got a boy of my own back home.
You never told me that.
- Good night, Brenda.
- Good night.
Say hi to your son from me.
Thank you, Selma.
Can I help you?
Did you once have a patient called...
Jezkova?
Selma Jezkova?
Well, if it wasn't too long ago,
I can check my records.
Jez...Jez...Jez...
Sorry, there's no one here
by that name.
What about Novy?
- I have good news for you.
- What's that?
We found a new lawyer and he is
going to get your case reopened.
He says your lawyer was incompetent.
W-what do you mean?
Well, the case is going
to be reopened.
You won't get the death sentence.
- Is that true?
- Yes. New information has turned up.
What information?
We know the whole story, Selma.
Why didn't you tell us anything?
You know, about...about the money
for Gene's operation.
How did you find out?
Well, Jeff talked to the doctor.
Does...does Gene know?
Have you told Gene?
No. No, I didn't. But you've got
a much better case now.
That's very important, Kathy.
His eyes might get worse
from worrying.
And then the operation won't work.
Yes, Selma, but don't you see,
it would help you if they knew
that you were trying to save
your son from going blind.
The lawyer will come
in two weeks' time.
Kathy, by then... You know
they're hanging me in one week.
We know, but he says
you can apply for a stay.
Most cases get one the first time.
Well, you can smile.
- Selma?
- Yeah... It's just too much for me.
I thought I was strong.
I just can't take it, Kathy.
Apply for a stay.
What if they don't phone?
Ah, well, you'll be transferred
to the other...
cell block at some point tomorrow.
That's the cell block
where they hang people?
Yeah, that's where they...
spend the last day.
And then they do their 107 steps
that's from that room...
to the gallows, isn't it?
That's what they say, Selma, but...
Look, it...
You're gonna get your stay.
Why don't you try to think
of somethin' nice, all right?
It's just so quiet here.
What's that got to do with it, Selma?
You know, when I used to work
in the factory,
I used to dream
that I was in a musical.
Because in a musical
nothing dreadful ever happens.
But it's so quiet here.
Don't the prisoners march
or something?
March? No. No, they don't...
they don't... There's not...
There's not much noise
around here, Selma, I know.
But later they turn on the radio.
No, no, no. There's no...
They don't allow radio
in the isolation block, Selma.
But I've been listening
to the ventilation shaft.
I hear sometimes people
singing there, like...
hymns, or...
It's not against the rules
to listen, is it?
No.
I wonder if...
if maybe you're hearing the singing
coming from the chapel.
Yeah?
- Maybe you'll even get a sermon.
- Yeah?
(Choir singing)
# Raindrops...and roses
# And whiskers on kittens... #
(Sniffs)
(Crying) # Raindrops and roses
and whiskers on kittens... #
(Sniffs)
(Clears throat)
# Bright copper kettles
and warm woollen mittens
# Brown paper packages
tied up with string... #
(Ghostly humming
continues in background)
# These are the few
of my favourite things... #
(Sighs deeply)
# Cream-coloured ponies
# And crisp apple strudels
# Doorbells and sleigh bells and...
# Schnitzel with noodles
# Wild geese that fly
with the moon on their...wings
# These are the few
of my favourite things
# When the bee stings
# When the dog bites
# When I'm feeling bad
# I simply remember
my favourite things
# And then I don't feel so sad #
Selma.
You got your stay.
You got the stay.
I'm so happy for you.
I'm your new legal counsel.
My name is Luke, OK?
Hi, Luke.
I'm quite sure I can get
your sentence commuted.
All I need is a signature
stating you want the case reopened.
Then I can get the paperwork
ready by tomorrow.
There are things your other lawyer
didn't do that I'm going to do.
A lot of ground wasn't covered
that I'm going to cover.
The fact you were fighting for your
boy is something we can really milk.
And I have some experience
in cases like this, so...
That's what the attorney before said.
Oh, yeah.
You see, he was appointed
by the court.
And you don't get the best
legal counsel that way.
You were not appointed by the court.
I'm not, no.
You're gonna have to pay me.
- But...not to worry.
- Yeah.
That's been taken care of.
I made a deal with your lady friend.
- Deal?
- Yeah, in regard to my fee.
I'm going to accept the amount
that she said she could raise.
How much... How much was it?
I can tell you precisely
because I received an envelope.
- It was, ah...$2,000...
- $2,056 and 10 cents?
That's it, precisely.
Now...ah...
There's something here...
Uh...I'd like to...
just sort of go over our tactics.
I have a couple of questions
to ask you.
If he doesn't have the operation
next month it'll be too late!
He'll never be able to see!
This is what it's all about.
So he can see his grandchildren...
- Let me tell you...
- It's the only thing that matters!
You don't understand, Kathy.
It's plain stupidity
to waste that kind of money
on a blind woman in jail.
But he needs his mother!
No matter where!
You don't understand!
He needs his eyes.
- He needs his mother.
- NO!
- Yes, alive...
Listen to reason for once, Selma.
- Selma...
- I listen to my heart.
I will go to the police, I will tell
them you stole the money from Bill.
I will say that.
I will tell them that.
That you stole it from Bill.
Then you'll never see it again.
They will be gone for good.
No parachute. No mother. Nothing!
You can have your money back.
I just want to make sure
you fully comprehend
what this means - this decision.
- Yeah.
- You realise what will happen?
Yeah. I've already
asked for no more stays.
Once this starts there's no
stopping it, do you understand?
Yeah.
I'm prepared.
(Walkie talkie)
Gene says thank you.
Thanks for what?
Oh, some comic book on his birthday.
You can't buy him presents
and say it's from me.
You're to stop doing that, Jeff.
Maybe you can just...
phone him.
Just say, you know...
something to him.
No, that's... That's not a good idea.
He wants to be the one...
who's allowed to be there
when it happens.
But I... And then they told him
he's too young.
Who put that crazy idea
in his head anyway?
I don't want him to be there.
I'd be there if you would...
And Kathy?
You know Kathy, she's...
She's still angry.
If you think you can take it...
I would love you to be there.
Don't cry, Jeff.
Jeff, don't worry.
It's gonna be fine.
Jeff?
Why did you have him?
You knew he would have
the same disease as you.
I just wanted
to hold a little baby...
in my arms.
I love you.
It's time, Selma.
OK?
OK.
Your meal, Jezkova.
(Rattling of keys)
(Footsteps)
(Key in lock)
(Door opens)
(Sobs softly)
Selma Jezkova.
It's time.
Please stand.
She can walk on her own.
Selma.
I'm afraid my legs
aren't working very well.
- You can do it, Selma.
- Yeah.
- I have a plan, OK?
- You're gonna stand up with me.
- Yeah.
OK, I will make some noise.
It will give you
something to listen to.
- Yeah.
- Listen.
(Selma sobs)
(Stamping continues)
It's 107 steps.
- Listen to the march.
- I couldn't even do one.
- You can do it.
- (Sobbing) I can't do it.
Now, listen Selma,
I want you to do one.
There - one.
Come on.
Listen.
Two.
(Soft music)
(Brenda) ..five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten, eleven, twelve,
thirteen, fourteen,
fifteen, sixteen...
(Brenda continues counting
in time to march)
..twenty-one, twenty-two,
twenty-three...
(Rattles against bars)
..twenty-five, twenty-six,
twenty-seven,
twenty-eight, twenty-nine, thirty...
# Thirty-one
# Thirty-five, thirty-eight
# Forty-two... #
(Brenda continues to count)
# Forty-eight
# Fifty-one, fifty-four
# Fifty-eight
# Sixty-four
# Sixty-eight, sixty-nine
# Seventy-five
# Seventy-nine
# Eighty-two, eighty-six
# Eighty-nine, ninety-three
# One hundred and seven
# Steps #
(Brenda) One hundred and seven.
Selma Jezkova,
do you have any last words?
Very well. Proceed.
Selma. Selma. Selma, are you OK?
It's OK.
Come on, now.
- Use the board.
- No, wait. Give her a chair.
(Brenda) She can stand up,
she can stand.
(Man) Get her feet.
(It's OK. It's OK.
It's OK. It's OK...)
(Man) Straps on her hands...
- I'm scared. I'm so scared.
- I know.
(Guard) On the mark.
No. I can't do the hood.
It's OK, Selma.
I have to breathe.
Nobody told me about the hood.
- It's just so you can't see...
- I can't breathe!
- Look, look...
(Screams) I can't breathe!
She can't breathe!
- (Screams)
- She can't breathe!
She can't...
I'm taking it. I'm taking it.
- Look...
- This is irregular.
I don't care. She can't see...
- We have regulations...
- I don't care!
The girl is blind for Christ's sake.
- I'm gonna make a call.
- Make the call.
(Screams)
Gene!
We have a situation here.
I'll hold for him.
Gene.
The woman is blind.
Gene!
Gene.
We're waiting for a call.
(Screams)
Gene!
(Piercing scream)
He's just outside.
He gave me these for you.
So he had the operation?
He will see his grandchildren.
He's just outside.
You were right, Selma.
Listen to your heart!
(Sobs quietly)
(Heart beating)
(Hums)
# Dear Gene, of course you are near
# And now there's nothing to fear
# I should have known
# I was never alone
# This isn't the last song
# There's no violin
# The choir is so quiet
and no one takes a spin
# This is the next to last song
# And that's all
# All
# Remember what I have said
# Remember, wrap up the bread
# Do this, do that, make your bed
# This isn't the last song,
there's no violin
# The choir is quiet
and no one takes a spin
# It's the next to last song
# And that's a... #
# Train whistle, sweet clementine
# Blueberries, dancers in line
# Cobwebs, a bakery sign
# Ooh-ooh-ooh
# A sweet clementine
# Dancers in line
# Ooh-ooh-ooh
# If living is seeing
# I'm holding my breath
# In wonder
# I wonder what happens next
# A new world a new day to see
# See
# I'm softly walking on air
# Halfway to heaven from here
# Sunlight unfolds in my hair
# Ooh-ooh-ooh
# I'm walking on air
# To heaven from here
# Ooh-ooh-ooh
# If living is seeing
# I'm holding my breath
# In wonder, I wonder what comes next
# A new world, a new day to see
# See
# To see
# See #