sub2srt by ¿­³ë(Yeolno)
http://nfou.net/
[Woman] Once upon a time, in
a magical kingdom known as Andalasia,
there lived an evil queen.
Selfish and cruel,
she lived in fear that one day
her stepson would marry,
and she would
lose her throne forever.
And so, she did all in her power
to prevent the prince from ever meeting
the one special maiden with whom
he would share true love's kiss.
[Birds] Giselle, Giselle,
how about this for your statue?
- Oh, this will be perfect. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Come on! OK, you mookses, move it!
We have got a face to put together here
while it's still ingrained
in her subcranium.
Oh, Pip, it was
such a lovely dream.
We were holding hands
and dancing, and...
- Oh!
- And these for the eyes.
Blue? Oh, how did you know?
And they sparkle just like his. Mm!
OK. There we go.
[Gasps]
- Yes! That's it!
- [Laughing] OK. Yeah, yeah.
- Floor's yours, honey.
- Presenting my one true love.
My prince. My dream come true.
- [All gasping]
- [Gasps] Oh, my goodness!
- Whoa, whoa. What? What's the problem?
- I didn't give him any lips.
- [Pip] Ooh!
- Does he have to have lips?
Of course.
When you meet the someone
who is meant for you
¢Ü Before two can become one
There's something you must do
- Do you pull each other's tails?
- Do you feed each other seeds?
No.
¢Ü There is something sweeter
¢Ü Everybody needs
¢Ü I've been dreaming
of a true love's kiss
¢Ü And a prince
I'm hoping comes with this
¢Ü That's what brings
¢Ü Ever-afterings so happy
¢Ü And that's the reason
we need lips so much
¢Ü For lips are the
only things that touch
¢Ü So to spend
- ¢Ü A life of endless bliss
- [laughing]
¢Ü Just find who you love
¢Ü Through true love's kiss ¢Ü
[sighs]
If we're going to find
a perfect pair of lips,
we're going to need
a lot more help.
[Vocalizing]
[Animals vocalizing]
[All] ¢Ü She's been dreaming
of a true love's kiss
¢Ü And a prince she's hoping
comes with this
¢Ü That's what brings
ever-afterings
- ¢Ü So happy
¢Ü That's the reason
we need lips so much
¢Ü For lips are the
only things that touch
Humph!
¢Ü So to spend a life
¢Ü Of endless bliss
¢Ü Just find who you love
¢Ü Through true love's kiss ¢Ü
[grunts] Look out below!
[Grunts] Look out below!
- [Laughing]
- Amazing, sire.
Your tenth troll this month.
[Straining]
Oh, I love hunting trolls.
Big trolls, little trolls.
Trolls, trolls, trolls...
- Sorry.
- Oh, that's OK.
Ah, trolls are fine
to pass the time, Nathaniel,
but... but my heart longs
to be joined in song.
¢Ü I've been dreaming
of a true love's kiss
- ¢Ü And a...
- [Giselle] ¢Ü ... prince I'm hoping
- ¢Ü Comes with this
- Do you hear that, Nathaniel?
Me? No.
No, I hear nothing.
- Nothing. [laughs]
- [Singing continues]
- [Vocalizes] Oh!
- I must find the maiden
- that belongs to that sweet voice.
- Oh, no! Come back, sire.
- No, you're hallucinating!
- Ride, Destiny!
Oh!
Oh, pooh. Oh, no.
No. This isn't good.
All these years of troll chasing, trying
to keep him from ever meeting a girl.
Oh, the queen.
No, she's not going to like this.
¢Ü True love's kiss ¢Ü
[chuckles]
[Vocalizing]
¢Ü True love's kiss ¢Ü
[rumbling]
[Troll] ¢Ü True love's kiss ¢Ü
Oh, you shall not prevail, foul troll.
That maiden is mine!
[Whinnies]
Honey, do you really think
your dream boy exists?
Oh, Pip. I know he's
out there somewhere.
[All] Eye! Eye! Eye-Eye.
- I... I what?
- [Troll] I eat you now.
- [Yelps]
- Everybody, scatter!
- Gotcha. Huh?
- [Yelps]
Hey! That's cheating!
I supposed to eat you.
Oh, no you don't,
you big lug.
Oh? Oh!
- Ah!
- [Troll groaning]
Wow, I got to lay off the nuts.
Girl yummy.
Fear not, fair maiden.
I am here.
- [Giggles] Whoa!
- [Pip shrieks] Gotcha!
- Whoa!
- [Screams]
Uh-oh. Whoo!
- Oh! Pip!
- [Pip stammering]
Just hang on, honey.
I'm going to...
[screaming]
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Oh, my gosh.
- It's you.
- [Laughs] Yes, it's me.
- And you are?
- Giselle.
Oh! Giselle! We shall be
married in the morning.
¢Ü You're the fairest maid
I've ever met
- ¢Ü You were made...
- ¢Ü To finish your duet
[both] ¢Ü And in years
to come we'll reminisce
- [whistles]
- [Prince] ¢Ü How we came to love
[Giselle] ¢Ü And grew and grew love
[both] ¢Ü Since first we knew love
¢Ü Through true love's kiss ¢Ü
Oh, so this is the little forest rat
who thinks she
can steal my throne.
Never!
[Clears throat]
Oh! Excuse me.
I am so sorry.
- Oh! Am I late?
- No, miss.
- I do hope I'm not late.
- Just in time.
- Oh, thank goodness.
- Hey, honey, wait up!
- We ain't done with you yet.
- No! Ah!
Oy!
- Oh! Thank you.
- You're welcome, Giselle.
- [All chattering]
- You're getting married!
Oh, and what do we look like, garbage?
- Close the door on me!
- [Nathaniel] If you'll allow me...
[Giselle] To think that in a few moments
that Edward and I...
- Yes, yes.
- That he and me... That we...
[laughs, gasps] Oh, my.
Oh, what a lovely bride.
That's very kind of you,
- but I really...
- No, no!
- Granny has a wedding gift for you.
- Thank you.
But I really should be going.
You see, I'm going...
- 'Tis a wishing well, dear.
- Oh!
But all my wishes
are about to come true.
If I ever see that fat mook's
face again, I'm gonna...
[Giselle] I really do have to go.
[Granny] But a wish on your wedding day.
That's the most magical of all.
Just close your eyes,
my darling, and make your wish.
That's right. That's right.
Lean in close.
- Are you wishing for something?
- Yes, I am.
And they both lived happily
ever aft... [gasps]
[Screaming]
[Gasping] Help! Edward!
Prince Edward, we need help!
Speciosus, formosus, praeclarus!
Where, my most adored queen,
where did you send her?
To a place where there
are no "happily ever afters."
[Screaming]
Oh! Oh.
Oh!
[Yelps] What is this?
Oh! [yelling]
[Screaming]
[Panting]
[Siren wailing]
[Indistinct chatter]
- [Fabric tearing]
- Oh!
- [Tearing]
[Truck horn blowing]
Oh!
[Horn blowing,
tires screeching]
- Oh!
- [Glass shatters]
[Gasps] Oh!
- [Man] Get out of the street!
- Oh!
- Whoa!
Lady! Are you crazy? Now you
have to pay for all of this.
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
I was wondering if one of you
kind people might
direct me to the castle?
Oh!
Hey, watch it, will you?
- Grumpy!
- Jeez, lady. Are you for real?
I think so. Oh, wait! Wait!
Where are you going? Please, if you
could just point me to the castle?
I'm supposed to be at the ball
to wed my true love,
Prince Ed... Oh! Edward!
Edward?
Oh! Edward!
- Edward?
- [Sirens wailing]
Oh, no.
Oh! Hello, old man! Oh!
Hello.
- May I sit with you?
- [Grunts]
Oh!
I'm very tired, and I'm scared.
I've never been this far away
from home before,
and I'm not sure at all where I am.
If somebody could show me
just a bit of kindness,
a friendly "hello" or even a smile,
I'm sure that would
lift my spirits so much.
[Chuckles]
Oh. You have a lovely smile.
- Oh! Where are you going?
- [Laughing]
That's mine!
Bring that back here!
You! Come back here!
I need that!
Oh! Please?
You...
...are not a very nice old man!
[Thunder crashes]
[Woman] No way you're getting him,
Ethan.
- [Man] You want him because I want him.
- I'm not letting you have him!
- Forget it. Hank is coming with me.
- Wait a minute, guys.
- I'm getting confused. Who is Hank?
- Hank Aaron.
Milwaukee Braves?
His 1954 rookie card.
A baseball card?
That's what this gets down to
is a baseball card?
You never loved Hank like me.
- You never loved me like Hank!
- How did I make you so angry?
- Robert?
- Yes?
- It's time.
- Ask what you didn't do.
- It's a longer list!
- What would you do if you...?
I have to pick up my daughter.
Can we do this around 9:00?
- 9:00 sounds good.
- Great. I'll see you then.
Phoebe, I'll see you in the morning, OK?
You're just afraid
I don't need you!
- [Man] I need a vacation!
- Thank you.
After a whole day of that,
you still want to get engaged?
Those people got married
on a crazy romantic whim.
It's not like that with Nancy and I.
Right. None of that crazy romantic
stuff for you, huh?
Oh, come on.
- I mean, we're rational.
- [Laughs]
We understand each other's
strengths and weaknesses.
Sounds like building a bridge.
Have you told your daughter?
No, I haven't. Not yet.
I'm going to tonight.
I got a present to ease her into it.
With news like this, I hope you
got her a Shetland pony.
No. Something much better than that.
- A book?
- Oh, come on. Don't give me that look.
I know it's not that fairy tale book
you wanted, but this is better.
Look at this. See?
Rosa Parks.
Madame Curie.
She was a remarkable woman who
dedicated her life to research...
...until she died from...
...radiation poisoning.
- She... died?
- [Cell phone rings]
- I wonder who that is.
Yeah, hi.
Tomorrow morning
would be great. 7:30?
- [woman] With her now?
- Yes, let me call you later.
All right. Bye-bye.
It was Nancy.
- Mm-hmm?
- Mm-hmm.
She's a lot like
the women in your book.
Sweetie...
...I'm going to ask her
to marry me.
- What?
- Yeah, you like her, don't you?
We all get along.
- Where's she going to live?
- She's going to live with us.
Do I have to give up my bedroom?
No, you don't have
to give up your bedroom. No.
Come on, it's going to be great.
I promise.
It's not like she's gonna
try and be your mother.
- Stepmother.
- She's gonna be a nice stepmother.
She's gonna take you
to school tomorrow, just you and her,
for some grown-up girl-bonding time.
I'm only six.
You won't always be.
[Thundering]
Hello!
It's me, Giselle, from Andalasia.
- Is there anybody home?
- [Knocks]
Hello, please open the door.
[Giselle] It's very cold out here.
Daddy, why is there a princess
on the castle billboard?
It's an advertisement.
It's a mannequin.
- She's really there!
- No, she's not. What are you doing?
Get back in here! Stop!
- Morgan! Stop!
- Hey!
- Princess!
- Morgan!
- Don't you ever do that again!
- Look! Look!
Is anybody there?
Do you know Edward?
- Stay here.
- Oh, please be home!
- Hey, lady!
- Oh, hello.
I was wondering if maybe you...
Whoa!
- Hang on!
- [Yelping]
- Oh!
- Don't let go! Wait!
- Just hang on!
- Oh, no!
Catch her, Daddy!
- Oh!
- Ow!
- You OK?
- I'm fine.
- Are you OK?
- What were you doing up there?
- I was looking for some help.
You see, I've been wandering
very far and long tonight,
and I'm afraid nobody's
been nice to me.
Yeah, well, welcome to New York.
Thank you.
Right. OK,
you sure you're all right?
- Oh, yes.
- You need me to call somebody for you?
Well, I don't think
they'd hear you from here.
- What?
- [Thunder crashes]
- [Elevator dings]
- Morgan, show her the way, please.
And then
the old hag told me to...
Oh! ...look into the well
and wish for my heart's desire.
But I must have looked very far
because I fell,
down, down, down.
And then I climbed out
of this big, round hole
and I got very lost,
until I fell off of the castle.
- And now here I am with you!
- Is this a big habit of yours?
Falling off stuff?
Well, usually someone catches me.
But, not to worry, I'm certain that
Edward is already searching for me.
No doubt by morning he'll come
and rescue me from this strange land.
Take me home, and the two of us
can share in true love's kiss.
True love's kiss?
It's the most powerful thing
in the world.
Right.
Now if I could only find a place
to rest my head for the night.
- What kind of place?
- Oh, I don't know.
Maybe a nearby meadow
or a hollow tree.
A hollow tree?
Or a house full of dwarves.
I hear they're very hospitable.
All I can do is let you in for a minute.
Dry off, use the phone if you want to.
We have our own bedtime
to stick to. Let's go.
That's very kind of you.
- What is it with this dress of yours?
- Oh. Do you like it?
- No, it's just...
- I gathered the silk
from my silkworms and I spun it
into thread on my spinning wheel.
- You made it all by yourself?
- Well, the mice and rabbits
did help with the sewing.
- They're good!
- Oh!
- [Tearing]
- Whoa!
[Giggles]
Why don't we see about
getting you a car.
[Thundering]
- Couldn't she sleep here, Daddy?
- No. That's a big no.
[Sighs]
- Are you really a princess?
- Not yet.
But... [yawns]
...I will be soon.
Wow, Dad.
She's really sleepy.
Oh, no.
That's not acceptable. No.
You're not really gonna
make her go, are you, Daddy?
I want you to go to bed.
But I think she might be
a real princess.
Morgan, just because she has on a funny
dress, doesn't mean she's a princess.
She is a seriously confused woman
who's fallen into our laps.
- So we're not going to let her stay?
- No.
Put on your nightgown
and go to sleep.
Good night, OK?
Hi. I need a car
at 116th and Riverside, please.
- [man] Hold, please.
- Thank you.
[Thunder rumbling]
Hello, sir.
Destination, please.
Sir?
[Sighs]
- Morgan.
- What?
I want you to sleep
in my room tonight.
- Why?
- Just come on.
All right.
Fear not, Giselle!
I will rescue you!
Yeah, but who's
gonna rescue me?
- All right, let's close it up.
- Whoa!
- Hey, buddy! You ain't...
- Silence!
- [Yelling]
- Guys, I got it.
- Your name, peasant! Quickly!
- Arty.
Are you in league with
the wicked old hag who sent
my poor Giselle
to this foul place, Arty?
[Yelling]
Is this man party
to this evil plot, chipmunk?
[Squeaking]
[Coughing, squeaking]
- Uh-oh.
- Aw, poor chipmunk.
- Speechless in my presence.
- [Squeaks]
What say you, sir?
Don't try my patience.
- What are you talking about?
- I seek a beautiful girl.
My other half,
my one coquette,
the answer
to my love's duet.
I'd like to
find one of them too.
Then keep a wary eye out, Arty.
- Come along, Pip.
- Are you OK?
- [Squeaking]
- Hey!
- [Man] Hey! Get off the car, you nut!
- [Honking]
Did you see that chipmunk?
[Yawning]
Oh, my. [clicking tongue]
This just won't do.
[Vocalizing]
[Buzzing]
Whoa!
- [Squeaking]
- [Shouting]
[Gasps] Oh, my goodness.
Are you all right?
- [Warbles]
- Oh. [giggles]
- [Squeaking, warbling]
- Hello.
Oh...
Well, it's always nice
to make new friends.
All right, everyone,
let's tidy things up.
¢Ü Come, my little friends as we all sing
a happy little working song
¢Ü Merry little voices
Clear and strong
¢Ü Come and roll your
sleeves up so to speak
¢Ü And pitch in cleaning
crud up in the kitchen
¢Ü As we sing along
¢Ü Trill a cheery tune in the tub
as you scrub a stubborn mildew stain
¢Ü Pluck a hairball
from the shower drain
¢Ü To that gay refrain
of a happy working song
¢Ü We'll keep singing
without fail
¢Ü Otherwise we'd spoil it
¢Ü Hosing down the garbage pail
and scrubbing up the toilet
¢Ü How we all enjoy letting loose with
a little "la da dum dum dum"
¢Ü While we're emptying the vacu-um
¢Ü It's such fun
- ¢Ü To hum a happy working song
- ¢Ü Ooh
¢Ü A happy working song
¢Ü Oh, how strange
a place to be
¢Ü Till Edward comes for me
¢Ü My heart is sighing
¢Ü Still, as long as I am here
¢Ü I guess a new experience
¢Ü Could be worth trying
¢Ü Hey, keep drying
¢Ü You can do a lot
when you've got such
¢Ü A happy working tune to hum
¢Ü While you're sponging up
the soapy scum
¢Ü We adore each filthy chore
that we determine
¢Ü So, friends even though
you're vermin
¢Ü We're a happy working throng
¢Ü Singing as we fetch
the detergent box
¢Ü For the smelly shirts
and the stinky socks
¢Ü Sing along
¢Ü If you cannot sing
Then hum along
¢Ü As we're finishing
our happy working song ¢Ü
Ah.
Wasn't this fun?
[Chittering]
- Wake up, wake up!
- What?
- Wake up!
- What is it?
- Come, you have to come see!
I can't tell you.
You have to come see!
What's wrong? Are you OK?
- Yes. What is it, Morgan?
- Look!
Oh, my gosh. Get out! Out!
- What do I do with them?
- Get them outside.
- Get rid of them.
- Put them back?
Put them outside!
Don't put them back.
Open the door!
Good! Watch out!
- [Giselle humming]
- [Water running]
- Stay there.
- But, Dad.
Shh. Stay there.
- Hello.
- Come in!
- Yeah, can I...
- Oh. Good morning, Robert.
Oh! That's too thoughtful of you.
Thank you! Oh, I hope
you had nice dreams.
- I think I'm still in one.
- This is a magical room.
Where does the water come from?
Uh, well, the water comes
from the pipes.
- And where do the pipes get it?
- Uh, I don't know. From...
...wherever the pipes get it.
- Oh.
It is magical.
[Knocking]
- Hey, girlfriend.
- Hi, Nancy.
What do you say,
you ready to kick it?
Kick what?
Why do you still have your PJ's on?
It's been pretty busy around here.
Wow.
It's really neat in here.
- Did you guys get a maid?
- No. Not exactly.
[Giselle] Don't worry.
My friends will do that.
- [Vocalizing] Oh!
- [Grunting]
[Laughing]
- Nancy?
- Oh, hello!
- Who is this?
- This is nothing.
- I'm Giselle!
- This is nobody.
I was on my way to the castle
to get married...
- She's married?
- No, she's not.
- Not yet!
- What does that mean, "yet"?
- She was lost. I was trying to help.
- With finding the shower?
The shower.
The shower is wonderful, Nancy.
- I'm sure it is.
- That's enough. Thank you.
- Calm down. Please, let's talk.
- Talk about what, Robert?
How I never stay the night?
Because we both agreed,
Morgan's here, and you have
to maintain boundaries
and I thought,
"I'm so lucky. He's sensitive!"
I didn't realize you were
worried about crowd control.
- We'll talk.
- Don't bet on it.
What about taking Morgan?
Some grown-up girl-bonding time.
What, so you can have some
grown-up girl-bonding time?
- I don't think so.
- But... just...
Goodbye!
Oh, she is lovely.
Get dressed, please.
For school.
Just... Please.
- Nancy!
- Thirty-eight and Seventh.
Nancy, wait!
[Groans]
- [Giselle] Hello?
- You got to go.
I don't know what your deal is,
if you're waiting for Prince Charming...
- Prince Edward!
- Whatever.
I'll get you to a bus,
a train, a plane, wherever,
and then that's it!
I can't get involved after that.
What is this?
- Where did you get that?
- I made it.
Do you like it?
You're unhappy.
You made a dress out of my curtains?
Oh, you are unhappy.
I am so sorry.
- I'm not unhappy, I'm angry.
- Angry?
It's an unpleasant emotion.
Ever heard of it?
- I have heard of it, but I...
- You have created a completely
unnecessary problem with Nancy
that I now have to resolve.
See, the fact is,
I was just getting ready
to take a very serious step forward.
- A proposal, actually.
- Oh!
Well, now she's got it
in her mind that you and I...
- Kissed?
- Yeah, something like that.
Oh, no.
- You should sing to her!
- Sing to her?
And maybe that would reassure
her of your affections!
You need to rush to her side
and hold her in your arms
and then pour your heart out
in a beautiful ballad.
And then she'll know for sure.
- Why are you staring at me?
- I don't know.
It's like you escaped from
a Hallmark card or something.
Is that a bad thing?
[Sighs] School! We're late!
We've got to run!
Oh!
[Door slams]
Oh, wouldn't she just love to come
crawling back here and steal my crown!
Cast me aside like
so much royal rubbish! What?
Perhaps Prince Edward won't find her.
- Perhaps he will!
- Oh! Oh, dear.
[Grunting]
Oh...
Oh! I do wish there was someone
who cared enough for me
- to go after him.
- [Chuckles]
Oh, a man like that,
strong and brave,
- I'd do anything for him.
- [Chuckling]
Never fear, my queen.
I will stop him!
- [Echoing yelling]
- [Clanging]
- What now?
- Another one?
Whoa! Get him out of there.
Let's go. Get in there.
Where are these people coming from?
- Come on!
- Upsy-daisy.
- [Straining]
- Get him up.
- Hey, pal.
- Yow!
Let me guess. You're, uh,
looking for a beautiful girl too.
No.
I'm looking for a prince, actually.
- Right.
- [Edward laughs]
You've met your match,
you foul bellowing beast!
[All shouting]
- Everybody, stay on the bus.
- Giselle? My love?
- [Laughter]
- Drat!
The steel beast is dead, peasants.
I set you all free.
- [Man] Move that bus!
- [Man 2] Come on, already!
- [Man 3] Get that bus out of there!
- Are you crazy?
Nobody stabs my bus!
I'll tear you apart!
Do you hear me?
- You get down here!
- If you'll allow me...
- Nathaniel, old friend!
- Sire, may I suggest that you...
You? A friend of his?
Crazy tight-wearing...
Come here and mess up my route?
I'll tear you both apart!
- Don't you roll your eyes at me!
- [Squeaks]
A rat!
Get it away from me!
Well, strictly speaking,
he's a chipmunk.
- [Screaming]
- Sire, may I suggest we seek elsewhere
for your bride?
- What are you looking at?
- She's beautiful.
It's just a statue!
- [Elevator dings]
- Come quickly. Quickly.
Sam? Sam, please don't tell me
Mrs. Banks is already here.
- Mrs. Banks is here.
- Great.
With Mr. Banks and his lawyer.
- Perfect, how long?
- Do you want to know?
No, I don't. I need you to
handle something for me, OK?
- See this girl?
- Who is she?
No idea. I'm pretty sure
she's from out of town.
- What do I do?
- Find out where she's from,
and get her there.
And make sure it's cheap.
If Nancy calls me,
I need to talk to her.
Giselle? Don't drink that, OK?
I have a meeting.
Sam is gonna get you home.
Sam? This is Giselle.
Giselle, this is Sam.
- Yes? Hi.
- Stay out of trouble.
[Laughing]
Oh... Oh.
- It's nice to meet you.
- It's nice to meet you too.
[Growling]
Your Majesty.
- [Queen] Nathaniel!
- Your Majesty?
Nathaniel, here!
- Nathaniel!
- [Clanks]
Finally. Finally.
I'm boiling in here. [sighs]
- Have you found her yet?
- I'm afraid I haven't, My Lady.
[Sighs] Time is of the essence.
We can't risk my stepson
bringing the girl back.
He shan't, Your Majesty!
I swear it!
No, he shan't. I intend to make
absolutely certain of that.
But, Your Majesty,
how exactly did you...?
...ever end up tasting so...
Mmm... delicious?
Poisoned apples, My Lady.
- You want me to...?
- Don't you see, my darling?
If there's ever going to be
a happily ever after for us...
- Hmm?
- Happily...
...ever after?
Oh, My Lady.
Mmm, yes.
It won't be difficult.
It's just one bite.
That's all it takes.
One small bite to drag her down
into a deep and troubled sleep.
And when the hands
of the clock strike 12,
that precious little pretender
to my throne
will be gone!
It shall be done, My Lady.
- I swear it.
- [Laughing] Yes.
You'll find the girl
at Columbus Circle...
Your Majesty?
[Squeaks] Hello.
You little...
[man] Whoa! Hey!
- Pip!
- Sire! Sire, please. I beg of you.
Don't listen to that
insane little vermin.
He's probably eaten some bad nuts.
We should put him down
for his own good.
Nathaniel, please.
Let him speak.
But, sire! No. He's delirious.
He came to tell all sorts of...
[choking]
- [Coughing]
- Go ahead, Pip.
- What is it you want to say?
- [Clears throat]
You watch me. OK?
- [Squeaks]
- Nathaniel?
Uh-huh. Nathaniel...
- Nathaniel's glad to have me near.
- No, no, no.
Hmm... Oh!
[Imitating Nathaniel]
[Imitating Giselle, singing]
Oh, oh, oh!
I know this.
- Uh...
- Apple?
No, thank you.
It's good.
Oh, OK.
[Choking]
Ta-da!
- You feel you'd die without me here.
- [Groans]
Yes. Here we go. Good.
Well, I have to say,
I really think that went well.
There's no reason not
to be reasonable.
Great. We might be in the
neighborhood of a settlement.
Excuse me. I'm gonna
check on your cars for a second.
- Sorry. [laughs]
- What? What?
She has no driver's license.
No passport.
Can't find this place she comes from.
- What place?
- Andalusia.
- Andalasia.
- Whatever.
I've called every travel agent.
I don't know if it's
a country or a city.
- It can't be a state.
- More like a state of mind.
She told me it's just
beyond the Meadows of Joy
and the Valley of Contentment.
What is that all about?
Oh, my goodness.
Your hair is lovely.
- You're beautiful.
- Well, thank you.
The man who holds your heart
is a lucky fellow indeed.
- You try telling him that.
- I'm certain he already knows.
- Excuse me?
- [Gasps] Are you him?
You are very lucky. Just look
at the way her eyes sparkle.
- It's no wonder you're in love.
- I got it!
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
Giselle? Please?
It's not like that, all right?
They're not together anymore.
- I don't understand.
- They're getting a divorce.
- Separating from each other.
- Separating?
- Yeah.
- For how long?
- Forever.
- Forever and ever?
Shh. Yes.
- Oh, no.
- What are you doing?
- Don't cry.
- Are you crying?
- She's not.
- I'm sorry. I can't help it.
- Is she actually crying?
- It's just so sad.
What kind of an operation
are you running here?
This is so unprofessional.
Good morning, Phoebe.
How are you? It's good to...
If you guys
are trying to manipulate us,
you can throw this whole deal out.
What is going on here?
Who's she?
Uh, a friend. No, she's
an acquaintance, actually.
You begged me to put you on the case,
and this is what I get for it?
I walk in here
and find everybody upset?
And some girl is crying
like we're on Oprah.
I'll take care of it.
Carl, it's gonna be fine.
- What is wrong with you?
- Me?
Yes, you. This whole Kumbaya,
Up With People routine.
- Those people are in real pain.
- Of course they're in pain.
They're separated forever.
Married one day
and the next they're not.
- What sort of awful place is this?
- It's reality.
Well, I think I'd prefer to be
in Andalasia.
- I think I'd prefer that too.
- Get in, please.
[Squeaking]
I wonder if we might cover
more ground separately, sire.
Uh, you by yourself,
and me with it.
An inspired plan, Nathaniel.
Where do you suppose I should look?
[Squeaking]
Look, sire! Over there!
[Edward] Ah! Giselle!
Run to her, sire! Hurry!
Not a moment to lose! [laughs]
- [Edward] Giselle!
- [Robert] I try to do the right thing.
Oh, you've been very nice to me.
Severely punished for it.
OK, look, Giselle?
- I can't help you anymore. OK?
- What?
Here's some money. I want you
to take it. Call your prince.
Have him pick you up,
bring his horse.
Because I honestly,
I just can't handle it.
- Robert?
- Just go.
I'm so sorry.
You have been a very kind friend
to me when I had none.
And I would never want to make you
unhappy or cause you any trouble, so...
...I'll go.
I wish you every happiness.
[Giselle] You have lovely friends.
[Woman] Would you like to feed
the birds? Just a dollar a bag.
Certainly.
By chance,
have you seen my prince?
He was here.
- Do you really think so?
- Oh, yes.
- Oh!
- Giselle? What are you doing?
- Robert! This is Clara.
- Mm-hmm.
- She saw Edward.
- Oh.
He was on the bus this morning.
- He tried to kill me!
- Great. Wonderful. Thank you.
- Oh!
- What are you thinking?
- You can't just give people money.
- You gave me money.
- That's not the point.
- And she was very helpful.
So, what's the deal,
this prince of yours?
- How long you two been together?
- Oh, about a day.
You mean it feels like a day
because you're so in love?
- No. It's been a day.
- You're kidding me. A day?
- One day?
- Yes.
- And tomorrow will be two days.
- You're joking.
- No. I'm not.
- Yeah, you are.
But I'm not.
You're gonna marry somebody after a day
because you fell in love with him?
Yes.
Yes!
Oh! Ooh! [laughs]
I don't get it. How can you talk
about loving some guy
- you don't even know?
- Well, I know what's in his heart.
Oh, OK. Great.
This was so yummy.
I didn't know that food
could taste like this.
- You all done? OK.
- Mmm!
- Let me put that out for you.
- What about you?
- How long have you known your Nancy?
- Uh, it's five years.
- And you haven't proposed?
- Well, no. I...
Well, no wonder she's angry.
[Nathaniel using accent]
Hello, nice lady.
You want juicy,
sweet caramel apple, maybe?
Mm.
No charge for the beautiful
young woman.
- Oh, really. It's free?
- Of course!
Today is free caramel apple day.
Tomorrow is free beef... jerky.
Thank you very much, kind sir.
- You're welcome, miss.
- [Squeaking]
You...
- [muffled squeaking]
- Shut up.
Most normal people get to know
each other before they get married.
They date.
- Date?
- Yeah. You know, date.
You go someplace special.
You know, like a restaurant,
or a movie, a museum. Or you
just hang out and you talk.
- What do you talk about?
- About each other.
About yourself.
About your interests.
Your likes, your dislikes.
You talk!
You have such strange
ideas about love.
Maybe we should do what you would do.
You meet, have lunch, and get married.
Oh! You forgot
about happily ever after.
Forget "happily ever after."
It doesn't exist.
Well, of course it does.
[Gasps] Oh!
- [Sizzling]
- Oh!
[Robert] I hate to disagree,
but marriages are a success
if they manage not to end.
- Forget about happiness.
- What about you and Nancy?
You know that you will
live happily ever after.
I don't know if I'll make it
through today, let alone a lifetime.
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
It's complicated.
But it doesn't have to be.
- Not if she knows.
- Knows what?
- How much you really love her.
- Of course she does.
We just don't talk about it every minute
of the day, but she knows.
- How?
- What do you mean, "how?"
¢Ü How does she know
- ¢Ü You love her?
- [Laughs] No. Don't.
- ¢Ü How does she know
- People looking.
- ¢Ü She's yours?
- Don't sing. It's OK.
Let's just walk.
Can we walk? OK?
- Well, does she?
- Yeah.
¢Ü How does she know
that you love her?
- Oh.
- He knows the song too?
¢Ü How do you
show her you love her?
[Playing calypso music]
¢Ü How does she know
that you really
- ¢Ü Really, truly love her?
- I've never heard this song.
¢Ü How does she know
that you love her?
- ¢Ü How do you show her you love her?
- Really nice work.
- ¢Ü How does she know that you really
- That's it. OK.
- ¢Ü Truly love her?
- Let's go.
¢Ü It's not enough to take
the one you love for granted
¢Ü You must remind her
or she'll be inclined to say
¢Ü How do I know
¢Ü He loves me?
¢Ü He's mine?
¢Ü Well, does he leave
a little note to tell you
¢Ü You are on his mind?
¢Ü Send you yellow flowers
when the sky is gray?
¢Ü Hey, he'll find
a new way to show you
¢Ü A little bit every day
¢Ü That's how you know
he's your love
- See?
- I've seen quite enough. Let's go.
- A ball?
- Yeah.
- That would be fun!
- That would not be fun.
¢Ü You got to show her
you need her
¢Ü Don't treat her
like a mind reader
¢Ü Each day do something
to lead her
¢Ü To believe you love her
¢Ü Everybody wants to live
happily ever after
¢Ü Everybody wants to know
their true love is true
¢Ü How do you
know he loves you?
¢Ü How do you know he's yours?
¢Ü Well, does he take you out dancing
just so he can hold you close?
I don't dance.
¢Ü Dedicate a song with words
meant just for you? Ooh
- And I really don't sing.
- ¢Ü He'll find his own way to tell you
¢Ü With the little things he'll do
¢Ü That's how you know
he's your love
¢Ü He's your love
Giselle!
- ¢Ü I've been dreaming...
- [grunting]
[Giselle vocalizing]
Take these flowers to Nancy, please?
Are you crazy? They're birds.
They don't know where she lives.
[Cooing]
¢Ü That's how you know
¢Ü He loves you
¢Ü It's true
¢Ü Because he'll wear
your favorite color
¢Ü Just so he can match your eyes
¢Ü Plan a private picnic
¢Ü By the fire's glow, oh
¢Ü His heart'll be yours forever
¢Ü Something every day
will show
¢Ü That's how you know
¢Ü He's your love
¢Ü That's how she knows
that you love her
¢Ü That's how you show her
you love her
- ¢Ü That's how you know
- ¢Ü You've got to show her you need her
¢Ü That's how you know
¢Ü He's your love ¢Ü
[cheering]
Thank you.