We're on our way to Nashville,
Been traveling quite a spell.
The road's been mighty bumpy!
Yeah, and I don't
feel too well!
We've got to get to Nashville!
Yes, it's really quite a spot!
You're going to
like old Nashville.
I still don't feel so hot!
It's Jamboree time!
Jamboree time!
I can hardly wait to
meet up with the crowd!
It's Jamboree time!
Jamboree time!
Come on, let me hear
it, clear and loud!
We're on our way!
We're on our way to a
swinging Jamboree!
Yeah! We're on our way.
We're on our way!
We're on our way to
Nashville, Tennessee, 000eeee!
Drop it!
It's okay. Sorry you got
caught in the middle!
What's goin' on?
- Spies!
That's right! Over in
Acme City, and these hills.
- They're all over the place!
- Let's get out of here!
Jeepers, you have to relax!
You're headed for a
nervous breakdown
If you don't
unwind a little bit!
Well, don't worry ma'am,
they won't bother you,
Uh, unless you're carrying
some secrets in this guitar!
- You entertainers?
- Yes, sir.
We're on our way to Nashville.
We're doin' a Jamboree there!
- Well, good luck!
- Thank you.
The road's clear.
You can pass on.
Thank you.
Woody, we have to do
something about Jeepers!
Yeah, I know!
He's been working
night and day,
And I think his
nerves are on edge!
- Jeeps.
- What?
Now Jeepers,
You know we appreciate
what you've done for us.
We sure do, Jeep!
And, I realize you've
worked awfully hard
To try to get
the show lined up
So we could appear
back in Nashville.
That's right!
And, the show isn't
- until tomorrow night.
- That's right.
And, Woody and I are
going to find a nice,
Quiet, restful place for you.
We'll see that you relax.
Yeah, relax. That's what
Jeepers needs, relax.
Howdy!
Hi! Thought this
place was closed!
Well, it should be!
- Nobody ever comes this way!
- Where are we?
- Sleepy Junction.
Oh!
Hey Woody! We're in
Sleepy Junction!
Sir, we're looking for a nice,
quiet place to spend the night.
- Uh, a motel.
- No.
- A hotel.
A boarding house?
Ma'am, there just ain't
nothin' around here!
What happened to this place?
Everybody moved out!
Moved over to Acme City!
They got a big
missile plant there,
And the people go
where the work is.
Jeeps, I'm sorry buddy.
But, we'll find a place for
you, so you can rest and relax.
Aw, that's okay.
I feel good now.
I'm not nervous or anything.
- Thunder?
- Thunder!
Yeah, it looks like a
storm's coming up!
It don't look too
good, does it?
Hey! I just
thought of something!
There's the old
Beauregard mansion!
Oh, it's quiet alright!
At least you'd get in out of the
rain, and have a place to stay!
- Well, where is it?
- Just follow this road.
Thank you.
Hey! Wait!
I forgot to tell
'em it's haunted!
Hurry up! That rain's going
to be coming down any minute!
Wait! Listen! Listen!
Jeepers! Come on!
- You're not afraid, are you?
- Oh no!
Well, come on!
What are you two waiting for?
I'm waiting for my
courage to come back!
Come on, let's go!
I think my courage
just left again!
Oh Jeepers! It's just
a shutter that fell!
Listen, I don't like
this place one little bit!
Heehaha! Heeha!
I said, put that
monkey back in the cage!
- Alright, alright!
- I want him to stay
in the cage!
If he comes out once more,
once more, I'll kill him!
Oh Anatole, you get in
there, be a good boy.
Be a good boy. Ahnananana!
- Be quiet!
- (GORILLA) Ohohoh! Ohohoh!
You shouldn't talk to Anatole
like that! He's sensitive!
(GORILLA) Euch!
Euch! Euch! Euch!
Stay away from that monkey!
Well, it's not
exactly a Hilton hotel!
Oh!
Jeeps, go get the
television set!
- Let's start a fire!
- Okay!
Hey, I'd put the top up on the
car, but I know it don't work!
Hey! This is kind of fun, you
know? Sorta like camping out!
I'd like to explore this
place once we get settled down!
Woody?
There's something out there!
- What?
- Calm down, boy.
Listen, I saw uh, uh,
a thing out there!
Jeepers, you're a nervous wreck!
Now you're seeing things!
- I am?
- Boy, you in bad shape!
What you need is to relax!
Now, I want you to know
Jeeps, no matter what happens,
That you've been
one of the best
Little business
managers anybody could have.
But, you need to unwind!
Come over here and sit down
in this comfortable chair,
And just relax man!
That's what I'll
do. I gotta relax!
Sing him a song Woody,
that always relaxes him!
Alright!
Jeeps, this is one I was telling
you about I wrote the other day.
Called uh,
What was the name of that?
Oh, uh, 'Livin' in a Trance'.
- Yeah.
- Oh yeah!
Yeah, let me begin here.
You cast a spell on me,
The first time we met.
Bewitched and enchanted
at first glance.
I didn't know then,
The spell that I was in.
Now I'm living in a trance.
Living in a trance.
In a world of lost romance,
I never had a chance.
Living in a trance.
Duhhh, duh-deh-duh...
Shhh! He's sleeping
like a baby!
Is he asleep, or
is he hypnotized?
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
Who's there? Wait a
minute, I'll see who it is!
Who's there? Come on,
speak up, who is it?
- Nobody!
- Well, come on in then!
You a ghost?
Not yet, but, you durn near
scared the life out of us!
Me too!
What are you doin' here?
We were just passing by,
And we thought we heard guitar
music coming from this place!
Oh! That was me!
You live around here?
Just over the hill.
We figured, if it was a ghost,
It must be friendly if
it plays the guitar!
What makes you
think it was a ghost?
'Cause, this place is haunted!
Nobody comes near here!
Well, we've been here
for quite a while,
And nothing has happened!
Huh! You're one of
the lucky ones.
Oh, I don't think
nothin' will happen!
Come on in and warm
yourselves by the fire.
Okay?
Yup. There's all
kinds of strange lights
And strange sounds always
comin' on around this place.
Somebody comes in to
see if they're real,
(Snaps finger)
leaving just like that!
Well, let's leave,
just like that!
Oh Jeepers! Don't be a baby!
We haven't heard a thing!
Say! Aren't you
Woody Weatherby?
I'm guilty.
I knew it! He's a big star!
Thank you very much. I'm
proud you heard of me!
This is Boots Malone.
- Hi!
- And, my manager, Jeeps.
Heard of you folks, too.
We play and sing a little.
How about singin' one for us?
We'd like to!
I feel like we're
auditioning an act!
Well, you never know where
you'll find good singers!
There is one song that we
sing about this mansion,
And 'Old Tom Cat',
one of the ghosts here.
Years ago, this song was
made famous in these parts.
Now, old Uncle John had
troubles of his own,
He had an old yellow cat
that wouldn't leave home.
He tried everything he
knew to keep the cat away.
He even gave it to a preacher
and told him to stay,
But the cat came back...
The cat came back.
I thought he was a goner,
but the cat came back.
'Cause he wouldn't stay away!
Now, he gave the old cat
to a man in a balloon.
He told the man to leave him
with the man in the moon.
The balloon, it busted,
and everybody said,
Ten miles away they
picked a man up dead,
But the cat came back.
The cat came back.
I thought he was a goner,
but the cat came back,
'Cause he wouldn't stay away.
Bum-de-dum, bum-bum-bum-de-doo
Now the cat was a terror,
and they thought it was best,
To give him to a feller
that was headed out West.
The train went around a corner,
and it hit a broken rail,
Not a soul aboard the
train lived to tell the tale,
But the cat came back.
The cat came back.
I thought it was a goner,
but the cat came back.
'Cause it wouldn't stay away.
Bum, bum, bum-by-um, bum.
Now the farmer on the corner's
gonna kill the cat at sight,
He loaded up his gun
with nails and dynamite.
Well, he waited in the garden
'till the cat came around,
And seven little pieces of
the man was all they found!
But, the cat came back!
The cat came back!
I thought it was a goner,
but the cat came back.
'Cause he wouldn't stay away!
Bum, bum, bum, bu-de-bum.
Bum, bum, bum, bah-bum.
Rrrrrrrarr! Bum!
- Oh wonderful!
- That's fine!
Really, that's good.
Can you sing any love songs?
- Sometimes.
- Would you sing one tonight?
The minute you're gone, I cry.
The minute you're gone, I die.
Before you walk out of sight,
I'm like a child
all alone at night.
I stare into emptiness,
I'm filled with
such loneliness.
The world goes
from right to wrong,
The minute you're gone.
The minute you're gone I see,
How lonely a man I'll be.
My life would be oh so-blue,
If I couldn't be with you.
The minute you're gone,
I pray.
I say,
Please don't stay
away too long.
The minute you're gone.
Doo-doo-doo-doo.
The minute you're gone I see,
Oh how lonely a man I'll be.
My life would be oh-so-blue,
If I couldn't be with you.
The minute you're
gone, I pray.
The minute you're gone,
I say,
Please don't stay
away too long.
The minute you're
Gone, gone, gone.
Gone. Gone.
Oh! That was just wonderful!
(CRACKLING NOISE OF
BONES AND EERIE MUSIC)
Ah!
Why! There's nothing there!
You suppose, maybe
it's mass hopitism?
- That's hypnotism!
- That's what I said!
Maybe we've all been
working too hard!
Well, I for one, do
not believe in ghosts!
And, I think we
ought to investigate!
Isn't anyone coming with me?
(CREAK OF STAIRS
AND EERIE MUSIC)
- Arrrrhhh!
- Ahhhh!
Ahhhh!
What was it?
- Didn't you see it?
- See what?
That horrible looking thing!
Are you sure you saw it?
I think so! Oh, I don't know!
I heard a sound, and
I was so frightened!
Look, maybe we better get
out of here while we can!
It could've been
my imagination!
Well, between the three of us,
There's sure a lot of
imaginating going on!
(EERIE MUSIC)
One thing for sure,
There's something
funny about this house!
Well, I don't
think it's so funny!
And, I'm not laughing at all!
(SOUND OF BONES
KNOCKING TOGETHER)
Oh! Maybe it's an owl!
An owl! Doin' what?
Draggin' a chain to his nest?
Look, I do not
believe in ghosts!
And, there must be some
explanation for all of this!
Where are you going?
To continue the search!
Look Boots, this is
an old empty house.
I know there may be a
few ghosts in here,
But I think we've
searched long enough!
I think we ought to
get out of here myself!
I'm with you!
(EERIE MUSIC)
- Wooodddyy!
- What's wrong now?
- I saw a, uh, uh...
- What? What?
- I don't know what it was!
- Well, I'll go check the car.
Come on!
Poor Jeepers! This isn't a very
relaxing place for you, is it?
No!
My dear Dr. Himmel,
We have more important
things to settle
Than your concern
with that monkey.
- It infuriates me!
- Of course it does!
But, we've little
choice in the matter!
I knew from the beginning,
that it was a mistake!
That was not your
decision to make!
Maximillian is my man!
Yes, of which you so
consistently remind us!
From the moment we
began this project.
You forget that I am the contact
with Dr. Fu! Without me...
Without you, we
might be much safer!
Indeed we might!
You've been warned again and
again to use the secret entrance
Yet tonight, you walked
right into the house
As if you were some
neighbor on a social jaunt!
I saw a strange car,
And I decided to
make an investigation.
Such foolish investigation
endangers the whole project!
No matter what your authority,
You've no right to
take such risks,
Especially since we're so
close to achieving our goal!
You know perfectly well
that we often have visitors
Who are curious to discover if
this is really a haunted house.
The simple fact is, that if
you had contacted us by radio,
We could have notified
you of our visitors.
What is done, is done!
So, we are no longer safe.
You have always known this was
not a safe business to be in.
But, tonight is
our last night!
It's foolish to endanger
the entire project!
Don't worry! Everything
is going to be alright!
Bad news.
- Why? What happened?
- The car won't start!
- Oh no!
- Yippee!
Well, I guess we'll just
spend the night here.
Jeeps, you can help me
build the fire up some.
We'll bake it so it
will last until morning.
And, I think we ought to
stick real close together.
- Good thinking!
- Boots, I want you to...
Boots?
- Boots? Boots?
- Oh boys!
Here I am.
Come and see what I've found!
Where are you?
What do you mean runnin' off?
Well, I was just
down this hall!
Well, we've got to
stick together!
- Yeah! We got to tick together!
- I'm sorry!
We don't know what's
goin' on in this house!
- Anything could happen!
- Okay!
Come on and see what I found!
When I open this door, you
won't believe what's inside!
By now, I'd believe anything!
You're right! I
don't believe it!
Isn't it beautiful?
Oh, I could spend forever
right in this one little room!
It's so elegant!
Maybe this is the room of
the great lady of the house,
That's been kept
exactly as she left it!
Way back in the Civil War days,
when she was a southern belle!
Gowns! Gowns! Beautiful gowns,
Satin, and lace
from across the sea.
Gowns! Gowns! Beautiful gowns,
Bring back a precious memory.
Of summer nights,
Twinkling stars above,
A night so right
For people in love.
As we dance, dance,
I realize,
The gown I was wearing,
Hypnotized.
So I gaily
Danced through the night
In my lovely gown of white.
Loo, loo,
Loo-loo-loo.
Loo-loo-loo-loo,
Loo-loo, loo-loo.
Loo, loo,
Loo-loo-loo.
Loo-loo-loo-loo,
Loo-loo, loo-loo.
A summer night
Twinkling stars above,
A night so right,
For people in love.
As we dance, dance,
I realize,
The gown I was wearing
Hypnotized.
So, I gaily
Danced through the night,
In my lovely gown of white.
Ooh, ooh-loo-loo-loo-loo.
Loo, loo-loo-loo-loo.
Dream girl, we got
to get out of here!
Oh, but it's so beautiful!
I could stay here forever!
Well, let's go.
(FOOTSTEPS HEARD IN HALLWAY)
Let me in! Is someone there?
Yes Madam Wong!
There are three of them.
What beautiful trespassers!
Ah, who are you?
I'm Woody Weatherby,
Boots Malone, and Jeepers.
Delighted! Now, tell me what
are you doing in my house?
Oh! We didn't know
it was your house!
I bought the
Beauregard Mansion,
So that I could restore it
to its original beauty.
We didn't mean to trespass!
Well, never mind. Just tell me,
what are you doing here!
Well, it looked like a
storm was comin' up,
And we needed a place to stay.
Come! Let us leave this room.
Of course, you
cannot stay here!
Haven't my ghosts
bothered you?
Well...
- Are they real ghosts?
- Of course they are!
I told you we should
have gotten out of here!
Ma'am, if you'll just
let us spend the night.
You see, we're entertainers,
And we're on our way to
Nashville, Tennessee,
To do a Jamboree there.
And, I'm afraid our
car won't start.
And uh, well, we're gonna
have to wait until morning.
Tell me, what kind of
entertaining do you do?
I'm a singer.
And, I pick a guitar.
How charming.
And, what do you do my dear?
I sing, and dance.
Ah, that's nice, nice.
Are you an entertainer?
Uh, no. Not exactly.
What are you exactly?
I are exactly his
business manager.
What's goin' on?
I don't know, but,
it looks phony.
They seem real nice to me!
I have decided that, uh, you
may stay, at least for tonight.
- Well, fine!
- Let me warn you.
Stay in that room.
You'll be much safer.
We'll stay right
by the fireplace.
Good!
We sure do, hey, they've gone!
- Where'd they go?
- They didn't go out that door!
You think, maybe
she was a ghost too?
Sure seemed real to me!
Well anyway, she was nice
Letting us stay
here and all tonight.
Well, let's settle down
and try to get some rest.
All right.
(THUNDER)
(EERIE MUSIC)
Woody? Hey Woody!
- Hmmmm.
- You asleep?
Eyeah!
Boots? Boots?
Hmmm? What's wrong?
I can't sleep!
Oh, for heaven's sake!
Well, let us sleep anyway!
- For crying out loud, Jeeps!
- Watch T.V. or something!
Yes Sir, Ladies and Gentlemen,
for a terrific used car buy,
Hurry on down right
now to Acme City Sales!
And now, for a full hour of
country and western music,
Here's Merle Haggard!
I played a brand new
record on the juke box.
And, I scarcely could
believe the song I heard.
It told of how you
left me for another.
It was almost like I'd
written every word.
Someone told my
story in a song.
The lyrics told that
happiness had gone.
They told of how
you done me wrong.
Someone told my
story in a song.
The writer must have
seen the way you left me,
For he told it all and
never missed a line.
He told of swinging
doors and a juke box.
He even knew I
almost lost my mind.
Someone told my
story in a song.
The lyrics told of
happiness that's gone.
Then it told of how
you'd done me wrong.
Someone told my
story in a song.
Now, we give you Jim Kent.
Hi there shoes,
Are you the ones
she wore last night?
Was she with him?
Did he hug and hold her tight?
Or, was she just out walking
Like she said,
Down by the sea.
Tell me shoes,
Was she stepping out on me?
Oh say there telephone,
Did he call here
and talk to her?
Did he say, he'd meet her
- at their rendezvous.
- Woody?
Woody! Boots?
Did you hear her say,
She couldn't wait
To be with him.
Is that why she wasn't here
To answer you?
Hi there pretty dress.
Are you the one that
she would choose?
While I called here,
Were you out with
one or with two?
Did he put his
arms around you,
As he held her tenderly.
Tell me dress, was she
stepping out on me?
Woody?
Woody wake up!
Boots!
- Boots!
- What's going on?
For crying out loud, Jeeps!
Look at the T.V.!
Look at the television!
That's very nice, Jeepers.
Yeah, he picks a mean guitar.
Now, let's go back to sleep!
No! I saw these two weird
faces on the television.
Ah hell, you're watchin'
the late, late, show!
What late, late show?
Listen, I saw that
Chinese lady and her friend!
- Well, so did I!
- I mean on the television!
Jeepers, you're in bad shape!
You need a long, long, rest!
If you don't stop
seeing things,
You're going to end up
in the 'funny farm'!
Well, I saw something!
And, it looked like 'em!
(RATTLING AND WIND)
Now, I'm hearing things!
They are entertainers.
- Oh really!
- Of course they are!
You take their word
unconditionally?
They were carrying guitars,
weren't they Matt?
Yeah! Two or three of them!
Anyone can play a guitar!
That doesn't make entertainers!
In fact, it could well
be a cover disguise!
I believe, they're from
the master organization
To halt enemy resistance!
- He's right!
- Oh come now!
They are not 'Mother' agents.
I'll take care of them!
The torture wheel!
The rack! Hehehehe!
And, the iron maiden!
Effective, but primitive!
We have other methods.
Quicker and surer!
No! We must not waste
time eliminating three,
Who are obviously nothing
more than what they appear!
Then you still think
that they're entertainers?
You don't want us
even to question them?
I thought we had
resolved that problem!
Well, I suppose we must bow to
her judgment in this matter.
As long as I am in
charge, you must!
I wish I could be as
sure of them as you are.
Dr. Himmel will
continue to observe them,
While I attempt to
contact headquarters.
- Yes?
- Who are you?
Agent Ming Toy.
Thirty-eight,
twenty-four,
thirty-six.
Oh!
Let me speak to the Chief.
One moment, please.
Good evening, Dr. Fu.
Kreagar, have you the
rest of the formula?
No, but Maximillian is leaving
Almost immediately
with Madame Wong.
Let him make contact tonight
With the agent at the
Acme City Missile Plant,
At which time they'll receive
the balance of the formula.
Excellent.
When we receive the
balance of the formula,
We'll report back
to you at once.
I will be expecting your call.
Meantime, may I suggest
That you have everything
in readiness for the test.
Of course.
Well, now it's up to you.
I suggest that you keep in
close radio contact with us.
We will. Come Max.
Anatole, I've got it!
He, he, he.
- Max!
- Huh?
Don't you realize we
have important business?
- Yeah.
- Gentlemen! Gentlemen!
Gentlemen! This is no
time for disagreement.
Max, here's your laboratory
smock, your identification card,
- and your badge.
Good luck.
- Yeah.
Woo! Woo!
Hi there! Working kind
of late, aren't you?
Yeah.
You scientists
really work hard.
Yeah, that's right.
Hey, you're new
here, aren't you?
Yeah, sure.
I thought so. I didn't recognize
your face. What project you on?
It's top secret. No comment.
Ooooh, that's alright,
I know all about them.
I been workin'
here for five years.
The things I know, and
the things I've heard,
You wouldn't believe!
I tell you one thing, if
anybody wanted to be a spy,
The thing to do is
become a janitor.
Janitor knows
everything that goes on.
I ain't got time
for conversation,
- now, let me by will ya?
- Sure. Sure.
I see you're
cleared for top secret.
- Yeah, that's right.
- Hey, that's pretty good.
Of course, I'm cleared
for top secret too.
Janitors have to be.
Well, I told you I ain't
got time for conversation!
Now, let me by, will ya?
Locked out, huh?
It looks like it.
That's okay. Don't
worry, I've got the key.
As long as you're
cleared with security.
- Huh, huh, thanks a lot.
- Glad to help.
Hey, uh, ain't you
forgettin' something?
Oh, that. Thank ya.
- Are you George?
- Yes.
- Do you have the formula?
Give it to me!
If you'd betray your
country, you'd betray us.
Augh!
Oooooh! Owuoh!
Oooh!
No, no, don't try
to say anything.
I'll, I'll get help for you.
Yeah, Chief? This is Jim.
My partner's just been shot.
Yeah. You'd better get an
ambulance over here right away.
No, he hasn't
said anything yet.
I'll follow through. You'd
better hurry! Okay, will do.
- Now don't try to say anything.
- Ooh!
- Take it easy.
The old Beauregard mansion.
Ooh!
The mission is completed.
- Do you have the formula?
- Yes.
That's what we've
been waiting for.
I'll be glad to get out of
this cold, damp cellar!
We both need a
vacation, Kreagar.
- Um-hum, Florida.
- The Caribbean.
- Wait a minute.
Um, Mexico.
- Puerto Vallarta.
Ah, marvelous! Come on.
Let's call the Chief!
Just to let him know our
mission was successful,
And we'll be calling
with the formula soon.
I don't believe in ghosts.
I forgot about that door.
It looks as though he's
waiting for someone.
Or, he may be initiating
an investigation,
Whatever Madame may think.
Madame is not always right.
We may be making
a grave mistake.
I don't think
they're entertainers.
- They're not in costume.
- True. Quite true.
Yes?
It looks like we
are being followed.
- Can you lose them?
- Of course we can.
- Are you alright?
- We lost them.
Imagination, that's
probably what it was.
I wonder, perhaps we should
question one of our visitors.
Hmmm?
(ANATOLE MAKES NOISES)
What'd you say?
- You awake?
- Awake!
How do expect me to sleep,
With you rollin'
around half the night?
Sorry about that chief.
It's a bad sign, Jeeps.
What were you talkin' about?
I don't know. That's the
first time I heard it.
Well, when you figure it
out, tell me all about it,
When I'm wide awake.
I'm telling you,
There's something
goin' on in this house.
Sure, it's your uh...
Well, I can't be
imaginating all of this!
I don't know. You've been
doin' pretty good at it.
- Now, go back to sleep.
- I can't go to sleep!
(MUFFLED CRIES FROM BOOTS)
You hear that?
That all depends on
what it sounds like.
It sounds like somebody's
moaning or somethin'.
- Yeah, the wind.
- Oh.
- What's that?
- I don't know. Let me see.
- Shutters?
- I don't think so.
Maybe nothin', huh.
It may be the branches
Hittin' up against
the side of the house.
Yeah.
Help! Help me!
Naw, that sounds
like somethin'.
- Imagination.
- No, that sounded like...
Boots?
- She's gone!
Well, don't panic!
- I'm not! I'm not!
Don't panic! We would have heard
the door by the way it squeaks.
Let's try the hall!
Boots?
Where are you, Boots?
Check the closet.
Anything in there?
Just a wierdwolf. A wierdwolf!
- Wait a minute.
- Well, what?
- We can't forget Boots.
- Oh, yeah.
What am I running for?
I didn't see anything!
Come on.
That stupid gorilla!
- (GORILLA MAKES NOISES)
- Oh shut up!
Don't pick on poor old
Anatole all the time!
He's not so bad.
Don't you remember,
I said just now that
We ought to question
one of our visitors?
Yes.
Well, he must have heard us
talking and he wants to help us.
The only smart
thing he's ever done.
Huh, ha, ha, ha.
Jeeps, we've got to separate.
I'll go upstairs. You go
outside and look around.
Okay.
- Say, Woody?
- Yeah.
You know, after
really thinking about it
For three or four seconds,
Don't you think we
ought to stick together?
You're not afraid, are you?
Well, I never won
any bravery contest.
Why don't you take that hat
off. It might be bad luck.
Oh, okay.
And, I thought
the front was bad!
Man, it's spooky out here!
Boots? Ooh! Boots!
Hey, honey.
Boots, where are you?
Well, she's not out here.
- Let's go back in.
- Hold it.
I don't see anything.
Me neither, let's go back!
- They're getting too close!
- Then do something!
Did you hear something?
- Must be wind.
- Yeah, I guess so.
Move the ghost a
little closer.
Alright.
Jeeps, I think
something's behind us.
- You sure?
- I think so.
- You think we ought to look?
- I'm almost afraid to.
I'll count to three, then
we'll both turn and look.
One, two,
Two and-a-half.
Three. Heahhh!
Come on Jeeps, hurry!
Jeeps!
- Jeeps, where'd you go?
- Woody! Help!
What're you doin' down there?
Well, I ain't lookin'
for new talent!
They seem
thoroughly frightened.
You should get rid of
them once and for all.
If it doesn't work, we'll
have to take drastic measures.
Should we question
the girl now?
Let's wait, at least
until Madame returns.
Are you afraid of her?
We're all dependent on each
other in this operation.
Hmmm, we could
still question her.
George, my dear friend,
without Madame Wong,
We get no payment
for our services.
I think it's imperative that
we wait until she returns.
We could start questioning.
I have no intention
Of jeopardizing our
position with Madame.
I suspect she'll be angry enough
when she sees the young lady.
- It's not our fault!
- Yeah, I know, the gorilla.
Hey Woody. Man, I'm
putting this hat back on!
I wonder where she went to.
Stand right where you are.
I suggest you
raise your hands.
Very high. Higher!
(FOOTSTEPS ON STAIRS)
(ANATOLE MAKES NOISES)
- You idiot!
- The gorilla did it!
I told you to
leave them alone.
Never-the-less, I decided that
we should question one of them.
Perhaps you are right. Hmmm.
Do not scream, dear.
Maximillian has a
nervous finger.
Perhaps you'd better
answer a few questions!
We don't have time
to answer questions.
Our girl singer is missing.
How long have you
been contact agents?
The only agents we
know get ten percent.
What does that mean?
That means,
we're entertainers.
Now look, I've got to
find my girl singer.
Hold it! What proof do you have
that you're an entertainer?
My guitar?
Play!
Look, that girl
may be in trouble!
If you're an entertainer, you
can play any time, now go on!
Well, perhaps you
are entertainers.
Now, would you mind
telling' me what's happening?
Have you ever heard
of M.O.T.H.E.R.?
M.O.T.H.E.R.,
that spells mother!
I know 'Mother McCree', and
some other songs about mother.
M.O.T.H.E.R. is,
Master Organization To
Halt Enemy Resistance.
'Mother', hey
that's clever, huh?
My name's Jim Meadows.
'Mother' agent number thirty.
We're after an organization
whose sole purpose
Is espionage and
counter-espionage.
They will contact
and sell to anyone.
I thought that you
were contact agents.
We wouldn't know a
contact agent if we saw one!
Tell me one thing.
How did you get here?
Well, it's a long story.
Yesterday, we were
driving down the highway
On our way to Nashville.
Alright, let's begin.
What's your name?
- Boots Malone.
Her name is Boots Malone.
Is that all the information
you got from her?
- That's all we asked.
- I'll kill her.
Oh Max, shut up!
It's my opinion that
Boots Malone is a code name.
Quite possible.
- Boots. Boots.
- What could that mean?
I don't know. Ahhh, Malone!
- Ma-lone.
- Ma, ma, that's it!
Ma is a colloquialism
for 'Mother'!
She's a 'Mother' agent,
just as we thought!
Now, lone,
Lone, I, o, n, e.
Got it! L-1.
She is 'Mother' agent L-1!
What are you talking about?
My mother's in Las Vegas!
You leave the
interrogation to us.
You go make contact
with headquarters.
And, Max give
them the formula.
We have been waiting.
We have the
balance of the formula.
Dr. Himmel will
read it to you.
C-three, H-five,
radical, 0-number-three.
- Is that all?
- No. There's more.
It would be much
simpler if you'd talk.
Talk! Talk about what?
Four,
immedasoli-bi-tholomaine.
Beta-ameno-thexalaine.
Could you repeat that please?
We have ways of
making people talk.
H-five-radical,
0-number-three.
- Four...
- Come on.
Immedasoli-bi-tholomaine.
Beta-amenothexalaine.
Heh, heh, he, huh-huh. We have
waited so long for someone.
- Heh, heh, hee.
- Help me! Somebody!
I don't know any
of this. Aaaaahh!
Aaaaahhhhh!
Aaaahhhh!
Aaaaahhhh!
Aaahhh!
Now, I think perhaps you had
better answer a few questions!
- Alright!
- Did 'Mother' send you?
I told you, my
mother's in Las Vegas!
This is the bedroom of
the lady that lives here.
Nobody lives here! This place
has been for sale for years!
Well, there is
somebody living here.
Maybe it's a ghost.
I'll have to see that
before I believe it.
That's where we saw that
wierdwolf, over there.
- In that closet there.
- I want to take a look.
Here's your werewolf.
Come take a look.
Here he is!
Well, that's sure going to a lot
of trouble just to scare a guy.
This whole house is rigged!
We've got to get out of here.
Let's go find that girl.
Put her in there.
That'll make her talk!
Oh! Oh! No! Oh! Ahgh!
Help! Help! Help!
Help!
Help! Help!
We may have some
trouble relocating all this
Equipment on our
new assignment.
Well, let's start
dismantling it.
No, we'd better wait until
we get a report from Dr. Fu.
We should have
heard from him by now.
There's no need to be anxious.
It'll take some time to
put the formula through.
There are some
elaborate tests to be made.
And, there are two
parts to the formula.
Could you determine what
the ingredients were?
No. Of course, I didn't have
time to examine, it carefully.
There's some strange
and unusual components.
Maybe something entirely
new in atomic research.
Hmmm, let's see.
No. There's nothing
here I recognize.
Do you think that
maybe we should split up?
Well, alright.
Why don't you take upstairs.
I'll take the outside.
- What about me?
- Why don't you go with him?
Oh by the way, what
does she look like?
Blonde, blue eyes,
very beautiful.
You have been tricked!
This formula is a fake!
You gave me the formula for
Nitroglycerin and
an antihistamine!
- How can that be?
- Are you certain?
We are certain!
Our contact must have
been a 'Mother' agent!
It is too dangerous
to stay there.
Move quickly to
your next assignment!
Well, what about the girl?
Poor Max! How you would
love to dispose of the girl!
- The girl can identify us.
- We can leave her here.
No one will ever find her.
No one will even hear her!
Help! Help!
Our next assignment
is in Allamagoridore.
Oh! I'm looking
forward to that!
The dry climate will be
wonderful for my sinuses!
- But, I'll miss this house.
- It has been fun, hasn't it?
Perhaps, we could create
another haunted house.
No!
Could we try the
ghost just once more?
- No!
- Oh! Just once more!
We'll find something else that
will be just as fulfilling.
Max, go check the car.
Kreagar and Dr. Himmel will take
care of the others upstairs.
Come, we'll take
the passageway.
Now, wouldn't you say
that was some trick?
Boy, I'd say that
was some trick.
Boy, isn't it! You
sure it's a trick?
Why sure it's a trick!
What else could it be?
- Well, it could be a ghost!
- Naw.
It sure does look
real! Don't it?
Yeah. Go away!
You don't scare us!
Leave my house!
You are intruders!
Don't move!
- Now, they look real, enough.
- So do the guns!
After them!
Help! Let me out!
- Are you alright?
- I think so.
Boy, am I glad to
see a friendly face!
- Who are you?
- I'll explain later.
- Where'd they go?
- I don't know.
That gorilla must be
playing games again!
- We'll stop him.
- This time I'll kill him!
Give yourself up!
Leave my house! You are
intruders in my house!
But, you're not one of ours!
A ghost! A ghost, a real one!
You fool! There are no ghosts!
- But, I saw him!
- Oh!
Get the gun, Woody!
Quit playin' around
and get the gun!
Come on! Woody!
Get over there! Face
the wall! Both of you!
Yes Ma'am.
It's that nice,
friendly, Chinese lady.
Not very friendly
right now! Go on.
(ANATOLE GROWLS AND
SOUNDS OF SCUFFLE)
You! Augh! Augh!
Augh!
Oh, you know,
I really enjoyed that!
I didn't like him at all!
You have intruded.
You have taken my
name and my house.
You have disturbed the dead!
Is that a promise? You will
look me up in Nashville.
When I make a promise,
Especially to a
beautiful girl like you,
- I don't break it.
- Thank you.
'Mother' is very grateful.
- Thank you. Glad we could help.
- You'll get a medal for this.
Glad to help. Just mail
the medal to Nashville!
We're on our way.
We're on our way to a
swinging Jamboree.
Yeah! We're on our way.
We're on our way.
We're on our way to
Nashville, Tennessee.
Oueee. Oueee. Oueee.
We're livin' it up tonight!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
we travel,
That is most of the entertainers
in the Country Music field,
I'd say, better than a hundred
thousand miles a year.
A lot of shows we work,
We're not lucky enough
to have women on them.
Tonight, we're real fortunate.
Here's another beautiful blonde,
dressed in a beautiful blue.
Marcella Wright!
Now we're strangers,
Completely strangers.
When we meet, you turn
and look the other way.
How can we be strangers,
completely strangers,
When we were so in
love just yesterday.
On the night that we met,
It was true love
at first sight.
You held me in your arms,
And your arms
felt oh so right.
Our love seemed to blossom,
As the days grew windy, dear.
And, you went away and
filled my heart with fear.
And now, we're strangers,
Completely strangers.
I just can't believe you'd
take your love from me.
Now, we're strangers,
Completely strangers,
And, I'm alone
with just a memory.
Now we're strangers,
Completely strangers.
When we meet, you turn
and look the other way.
How can we be strangers,
Completely strangers,
When we were so in
love just yesterday.
Ladies and Gentlemen, one
of my favorite singers,
One of my favorite people,
Mr. Merle Haggard! Merle
This old smoke-filled bar is
something I'm not used to.
But, I gave up my home
to keep you satisfied.
I just called to let you
know where I'll be living.
It's not much, but, I
feel welcome here inside.
I've got swinging doors,
And a juke box,
and a barstool.
My new home has a
flashing neon sign.
Stop by and see me
anytime you want to.
'Cause I'm always here at
home 'till closing time.
I've got everything I need,
To drive me crazy.
I've got everything it
takes to lose my mind.
And in here, the atmosphere's
just right for heartaches.
Thanks to you I'm always
here 'till closing time.
Now I've got swinging doors,
A jukebox, and a barstool.
My new home has a
flashing neon sign.
Stop by and see me
anytime you want to.
'Cause I'm always here at
home 'till closing time.
I'm always here at
Thank you, very much.
Now, I'd like to
introduce somebody to ya,
That I've known for a few
years. As a matter of fact,
We worked together when she
was about eleven years old,
Out in California.
She was real cute then, now,
she's even more beautiful.
Let's make her welcome,
Miss Molly Bee.
Heartbreak U.S.A.
The harbor's empty.
My love has gone.
With aching heart I face
The cold and lonely dawn.
Until the trade winds
Bring him home to stay,
I'll live in heartbreak U.S.A.
Don't let those geisha girls
Get your heart in a whirl.
And, if you meet
some sweet frauline,
Remember, you're mine.
Don't forget your sweetheart
While you're away.
Back home in heartbreak U.S.A.
U.S.A.
Sometimes I'm lonely,
And time stands still.
And, I wonder if you feel,
The way I always will.
So darling write me,
Letters every day.
In care of, heartbreak U.S.A.
Don't forget your sweetheart
While you're away,
Back home in heartbreak U.S.A.
In heartbreak U.S.A.
Back stage while ago,
Cricket Stone and
myself were talkin' about
Singers and all that,
and we tried our best
To get this next
fellow to sing a song.
We finally talked him into it.
Make him welcome,
the good Jeepers!
And they got into the
wrong house again last night.
I bought myself a
house a few months back.
And, it's a darlin'
little house, that's a fact.
How-some-ever, there's a certain
seven others there that's exact.
And, would you believe, I got in
the wrong one again, last night!
My neighbor's got a dog
about two feet high.
Cutest little dog,
wouldn't hurt a fly.
One day, I stumbled in
their house by mistake,
This mornin' about five.
And, that cute little,
stupid dog nearly ate me alive!
I came in last night, and
felt like I had two heads.
And, I was
sneakin' in the house,
When this sweet voice
yelled out and said,
Oooh Bill darlin',
Put out the kitty
cat, and come to bed.
And I said, Oooh,
surprise, my name's Fred.
I went to the next house,
and knocked on the bell.
And, this guy about eleven feet
tall answered the door and said,
What the... And, I said, well
I was just sorta in the area,
And I thought maybe you'd
like to chit-chat for a spell.
But, he threw me out the back
door, and called me some names.
So I went to sleep
in the next house,
And I saw it
looked about the same.
I woke up this morning with
my arms around a great dane.
Some silly kid lookin' in the
door, yellin' Gravy Train.
And, I got into to the
wrong house again, last night.
Sure am glad I'm me!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
Here's somebody that
needs no introduction,
But, I'm going to
introduce her anyhow.
My part time lover,
Boots Malone!
- Kill them baby.
- Thank you.
Well now, on Monday
I'm your darlin',
On Tuesday I'm your baby,
But on Wednesday you
don't get around to me.
I don't want a
part time lover.
Can't take a part time lover.
Won't have a part
time lover, no siree!
I need your huggin',
I need your kissin'.
It's your huggin' and your
kissin' I've been missin'.
Now, if I'm not
your one and only,
I'd rather go on
feelin' lonely,
'Till the day the
right one comes my way.
I must refuse a
part time lover.
Can't use a part time lover.
Got to have a full
time lover every day.
- I need your huggin'.
- Need your huggin'.
- I need your kissin'.
- Need your kissin'.
It's your huggin' and your
kissin' I've been missin'.
Now, if I'm not
your one and only,
I'd rather go on
feelin' lonely,
'Till the day the
right comes my way.
I must refuse a
part time lover.
Can't use a part time lover.
Got to have a full time lover
- everyday.
- Everyday.
Got to have a full time lover
- everyday.
- Everyday.
Got to have a full time lover
Everyday!
Well, huh, huh,
Fellows, are you ready to cross
one of these bridges with me?
Okay Red, take it off.
That's the one bridge
I have never crossed.
Everyone I ever
loved, I always lost.
For a true love, I'd
gladly pay the cost.
But, that's the one
bridge I have never crossed.
All my life I have
traveled over the country.
I've even flown and
sailed across the sea.
Name a famous bridge, I'll
bet you that I've crossed it.
And, all the women that I've
loved have all crossed me.
That's the one bridge
I have never crossed.
Everyone I ever
loved I always lost.
For a true love, I'd
gladly pay the cost.
But, that's the one bridge
I have never crossed.
I've made a lot of
money in my lifetime.
I've got a million friends,
and I know some enemies.
But, nobody knows how
bad I need affection.
And, how I long to find a
love that won't cross me.
That's the one bridge
I have never crossed.
Everyone I ever
loved, I always lost.
For a true love, I'd
gladly pay the cost.
But, that's the one
bridge I have never crossed.
That's the one bridge
I have never crossed.
Everyone I ever
loved, I always lost.
For a true love, I'd
gladly pay the cost.
But, that's the one
bridge I have never crossed.
Yes, that's the one
Everyone I ever loved,
I always lost.
For a true love, I'd
gladly pay the cost.
But, that's the one
bridge I have never crossed.
That's the one bridge
I have never crossed.
It's Jamboree time in
Nashville, Tennessee.