(SINGING) I could go on singing
Till the cows come home
And the rooster starts to
Crow, crow, crow
When I see your eyes
I go all out
I must vocalize
Till you shout
"Enough already"
I could go on singing
Till the moon turns pink
Anything from Faust
To ink-a-dink-a-dink
Love does funny things
When it hits you this way
I must keep on singing
Like a lark
Going strong
With my hear': on the wings of a song
Singing day
(RINGING DOORBELL)
- Dr. Donne?
- Please come in, Miss Bowman.
- Mr. Donne's expecting you.
- (SOFTLY) Thank you.
This way, please.
David?
Hello, Jenny.
Is this awfully inconvenient?
I don't think so.
Come on up.
I'll take your coat.
DAVID: That's for social calls.
Well, you did say this was business,
didn't you?
Yes, Doctor. Business.
Well, the business department is in here.
Why do they call you "mister"
if you're a doctor?
- Surgeons are called "mister."
- I see.
You mean, like a marquis
being called a "lord."
That always mixes me up, too.
Secrets of the trade.
Would you sit down?
- Yes, thank you.
- Now then, what is it?
Ear, nose or throat?
Do you take care
of all three of those things?
Yes.
Which is it?
Were you surprised to hear from me?
A little.
You sang this afternoon.
Charity concert, wasn't it?
Yes. How did you know?
It was in all the papers.
How did it go?
Oh, it was ghastly.
- That means it was good.
- No, it was terrible. It was awful.
My throat was very raw and I couldn't...
I... I just sort of croaked out
the performance.
Tell me, am I keeping
this secretary person of yours?
No, no. She works here.
I know, but it's terribly late
and it's Sunday, and I thought...
She's used to it.
Will you go on?
Well, I just...
I just got scared
I was going to lose my voice.
Mmm-hmm. Since when?
Since when, what?
Since when were you soared
that you were losing your voice?
Oh, um...
Well, since I got to England.
And don't tell me it's the climate
because Tebaldi and Callas sing here
and they do very well.
Should we take a look?
All right.
Would you come over here, please?
Yes.
DAVID: Sit down.
How are your sinuses?
- Oh, I don't know. They're kind of...
- DAVID: Any cold recently?
- No.
- You used to have a lot of colds.
Yes, but then they invented
paper handkerchiefs
and sort of took the fun out of it.
Would you, um, open your mouth, please?
Wide.
Thank you.
- Say, "Aah".
- Aah.
Thank you.
Now I'm going to have a look
at your larynx.
- I'm going to take this piece of gauze...
- Gauze...
And you're going to hold my tongue with it,
and you want me to relax
and breathe slowly in and out
and completely...
- Would you just do it?
- Yes, I will.
Thank you. Would you put out your tongue?
Yes, thank you.
You know, I've been thinking...
Would you just sit there, please,
for a moment?
Would you come back?
All right.
Excuse me.
I've been thinking about Atlantic City.
Do you ever think about
Atlantic City, David?
Yes, I have done.
Does this hurt?
Mmm-mmm.
Would you swallow?
Thank you.
(DRAWER OPENS)
Well, am I going to lose my voice or what?
What do you think?
You mean, there's nothing wrong with me?
Your throat's a bit rough, it's red.
You've been singing
and you've been smoking too much.
When do you open in London?
Five days.
Do you mind if I get out of...
No, I'm very sorry, no, of course, do.
I'll give you something to ease
the roughness, not that you'll take it.
But if you have got five days,
I strongly urge you to take
three of them off.
What would you advise?
A, um, brisk walk through Hyde Park?
Sleep, rest, relaxation.
Where can I buy those?
- And to gargle night and morning.
- Mmm-hmm.
All right.
Well, uh, why don't you
get me off on the right foot
by offering me a drink.
You're going to get me in there
if it kills me, aren't you?
(CHUCKLES)
All right.
- It's still Scotch?
- Still Scotch.
- No ice, I'm afraid.
- That's all right.
Thank you.
You know, uh, you've changed.
Oh, I'd be scared to hell if I hadn't.
(CHUCKLES)
No, you've become so...
Careful.
Have I? Well...
It comes, you know.
Care comes.
With gray hair and spectacles.
I heard about your wife's death.
Janet was her name, right?
Yes, Janet.
- I read about your marriage.
- Which one?
Well, it doesn't make any difference
because neither one
was worth writing home about.
I should have married you, David.
I really should have.
And it would have worked.
- Yes, it would.
- No, you're wrong, Jenny.
- You so sure?
- Mmm-hmm. It's better as it is.
Tell me something, do you still play
that awful harmonica thing?
- No.
- Oh?
- No, I gave that up.
- I'm glad. You were terrible.
(DAVID CHUCKLES)
- Do you still knit?
- Oh, no.
Nothing I knitted ever fitted. (CHUCKLES)
(DAVID CHUCKLES)
Oh, we must have had fun, David.
At least that the way I remember it.
Is that the way you remember it?
Yes.
Twist my arm and yes.
Salud!
Why did you come?
I don't know. l...
Tell you the truth, I don't know.
Maybe it's just that I...
Didn't want to be alone on the first night
in a strange town.
You have a mess of friends in town,
you couldn't be alone.
Alone.
That's the most awful word.
And I know what it means.
Because I've been alone since you, David.
You've been married twice.
Well, I was alone then, too.
Tell me, is this when you were knighted?
The CBE or the...
- OBE.
Mmm-hmm. That good, isn't it?
Not quite, I'm afraid.
It's something.
Yes, it's something.
- Why did you hide him from me?
- I didn't hide him.
I saw you.
All right, I hid him.
Excuse me, Mr. Donne.
Do you require me for anything else?
Ah, no, thank you, Miss Plimpton.
I'll see Miss Bowman out.
Good night, Miss Bowman.
Good night.
Is he here?
No, he's at school. He boards.
- I'd love to see him.
- I know.
Oh, David, please!
I didn't come here to ask that.
I swear, I...
I came here to see you. I...
I admit that.
It's just that now that I am here, I...
I must ask you. Please.
I'm sorry, Jenny, you can't see him.
Well, why not?
What's the matter with me?
Have I some dread disease
or some kind of...
What are you so afraid of?
- What is it, David? I wanna see him.
- It's impossible.
Well, "impossible" isn't a word that
very many people use with me.
It must come as rather
a surprise to you now, then.
I want to see him.
You cannot see him, Jenny.
We made an agreement a long time ago.
An agreement that you wanted.
Never to see him ever again,
do you remember?
Yes, I remember.
It was a long time ago.
It was the only good thing
lever made in my life.
Now I can't...
Oh, forget it!
Tell me, does he like school?
I mean, any more than anyone does?
Yes, he...
He likes it very much.
Is he clever?
He's average.
Better at Mozart than maths.
And musical?
A little odd if not.
Yes.
And the rest?
Well, he is...
He's really pretty good.
I think you'd be proud of him.
- Let me see him.
- No.
- Just once.
- And then what?
Nothing. I go.
Look, Jenny, to see him now
would make it much harder for you,
for me, for all of us.
And that's final?
Final.
Well, I think I've taken up
enough of your time, David.
And I'd like to get out of here.
- Where's my coat?
- It's outside. I'll call you a cab.
- No, thank you, I'd rather walk.
- It won't take a moment.
No, thank you, I'd rather walk.
Don't bother to see me out.
I'll take care of myself.
Jenny...
What?
You forgot your prescription.
What does it say?
Three times a day before meals?
And shake the bottle.
(CHUCKLES)
It's good for what ails me?
Good night, David.
You've been very kind, and thank you.
DAVID: Jenny.
It really would mean so much
to you, wouldn't it?
To see him again?
Yes.
If I let you...
And mark these words, if I let you...
You promise to look once
and never look again?
I promise.
All right.
(CROWD CHEERING)
DAVID: Are you sure
you want to go on?
JENNY: I can't stop now or I'll sink.
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
- (MAN SHOUTING)
Tell me, do all the mothers do this?
Yes, but they usually wear
"good woman" shoes.
(CHUCKLES)
Where is Matt'? Is he...
No, he's with that lot over there.
The under-fourteens.
BOY: Come on, Roger,
don't be slow, get to the ball!
Ooh, David, wait a minute! Oh!
JENNY: (LAUGHING) Here.
Are you holding?
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
- Yes, I'm holding.
(MAN SHOUTING)
- You really should've worn more sensible...
- Oh! (LAUGHING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
(MUTTERING INDISTINCTLY)
Come on, on to the under-fourteen.
(ALL CHEERING)
Where is he, David? Where?
There.
Where?
There. That thing with the ball.
(GRUNTS)
- They'll kill him!
- Only once.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
REFEREE: Break up. Half-time.
- Well, what's that?
- That's half-time.
Oh.
You must come around,
especially the wing forward.
- Can I go and see my father, sir?
- Yes, all right, hop it.
Hello, Father. Nine to six against us.
We're getting ticked off.
Still, it's a good game.
DAVID: They made you fly half again?
What happened to Gregson?
- Broke his leg playing Eastbourne.
- Ah, silly arse.
- I'm faster anyway.
- Don't be such a show-off.
Hello.
Hello, you're Miss Bowman, aren't you?
Father said you were coming.
Oh, Miss Bowman's an American, Matt.
They do things differently.
- How do you do? (LAUGHS)
- Oh, how do you do?
You're going to be on in London,
aren't you?
Yes, I'm going to be on.
- At the Palladium.
- Mmm-hmm.
We have all your records at the house.
At home?
MATT: Oh, no, no, the house,
here at the school.
- Father goes in more for Beethoven.
- DAVID: Oh, for Pete's sake,
who introduced you to Ella, to Basie,
and to Benny Goodman?
Yes, I know, and who introduced you
to Chubby Checker?
(MATT AND DAVID LAUGHING)
I have an extra pair of boots in my locker.
You could always pretend
you'd been playing in fire.
(LAUGHING)
- I think they'd suspect.
- Sorry.
No, Matt, I have these.
I'm saving them for a dry day.
He looks like you.
MATT: Oh, I shouldn't, I'm adopted.
DAVID: Well, you could. You could.
Adopted children do grow
like their parents.
Like dogs.
Like dogs?
Yes, it's an old saying
that dogs are like their masters.
- Or masters grow like their dogs!
- (LAUGHING)
Look, I think you better get back
to that game, don't you?
I'll take Miss Bowman back to the hotel
and get her cleaned up, all right?
I'll show you around the school,
Miss Bowman.
DAVID: Oh, Matt, do we have to?
I'd like that, Matt.
I'd love it.
(BELL TOLLING)
These ruins are Norman, you know,
1066 and all that stuff.
The school buildings are
all around the cathedral.
And they're just as old.
The dining hall goes back to King Henry V.
And the food goes back
to William the Conqueror.
Morning, sir.
Major D, modern languages.
We call him Major Disaster.
(LAUGHING)
Is the biology wing finished yet?
- It's been finished for ages!
- Oh.
Most parents get down twice a term.
But I'm lucky if my father
gets clown once a year.
- Now that is not true.
- (LAUGHS)
And what happens when I do come down?
Oh, we stare at each other
like couple of deaf-mutes.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Unless you need some cash.
But today's different.
You get a jolly good view
from around this corner.
(CHOIR SINGING)
We have all our services in the cathedral.
That's the school choir you can hear
practicing in there now.
Would you like to go up the tower?
We can see for 20 miles.
No, Matt, not again!
Oh, you can do it, Father.
Exercise is good for you.
I wasn't thinking about myself,
as it happens,
I was thinking about Miss Bowman.
Well, I took Auntie Beth up last week
and she loved it.
Who's Auntie Beth?
Well, she's father's aunt, and she's 60.
Well, if Auntie Beth can do it, so can I.
Oh, come on, Father! Come on!
(SINGING CONTINUES)
(CHOIR DIRECTOR
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(WHISPERING) We go through there.
We'll have to get permission
from the verger.
I won't be a moment.
I like him.
So do I.
I feel so happy!
It's like having a family of my own.
- Lovely feeling.
- Good.
Would you have dinner
with me tonight, David?
I don't think so.
I'm going to be in London 10 more days,
and I'd love to see more of you.
You really are persistent, aren't you?
(CHUCKLES)
A little over-anxious, maybe.
Look, I tell you what we're going to do.
We're going to come down
from that tower,
if we ever reach the top.
We'll take Matt out to tea.
We'll stuff him full of food.
And then I'll drive you back to London.
And drop me at my hotel.
That's right.
It'll be better that way, don't you think?
No, I don't
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
We can go up now.
You will be down by 4:30, won't you?
Yes, thank you, we'll hurry.
I'll lead.
Every 20 steps, stop and count five,
that way you won't be out of breath.
DAVID: Oh, go on, Matt, go on.
Everyone all right?
Fine. Fine!
There are 237 steps. I've counted them.
DAVID: What did he say?
He says he's counted the steps.
What does he want to count them for?
It's hard enough to climb them.
Oh, by the way, I ordered extra tickets.
J EN NY: what tickets?
For the Gilbert and Sullivan tonight.
It's the end-of-term play.
We're doing the first act of H.
M. S. Pinafore.
Eighteen, nineteen, twenty...
What was that?
He says he's got tickets
for the play tonight.
(PANTING)
(CHUCKLES) Is this the top?
No, but we're almost halfway.
(GROANS) on, my!
This is fun, isn't it?
Mind the cobwebs.
Not many people get up here.
Matt, I'm terribly sorry,
we can't stay for the show tonight.
Miss Bowman has to get back to town.
But you must stay. I'm playing Cousin Hebe.
He says you must stay
because he's playing Cousin Hebe.
Ah.
Oh, blast. (SPUTTERS)
JENNY: I think we've lost your father.
MATT: Not much further.
I can see daylight.
(PANTING)
How old was that... (PANTING)
How old was that aunt you were
talking about?
She's so. (PANTING)
But she's very athletic.
I can believe that.
She must be a champion
long distance runner.
Oh, my gosh, look out!
Be careful.
It's all right.
You have to get to the
edge to get the view.
Look, you can see Ashford from here,
where the Vikings fought.
Mmm-hmm.
Please say you'll stay for the show,
Miss Bowman.
Because if you do,
then Father will have to stay, too.
(WHISPERS) I'll talk to him.
Somebody didn't stop to count five.
(LAUGHING)
Be generous, David.
He wants you to stay so much.
MATT: You can see the sea
on a clear day.
But we don't get many clear days.
(TAPPING)
Oh, good, we are in luck.
- What's wrong?
- Wait for it.
JENNY: What's happening?
You'll see.
- (BELL TOLLING)
- (SCREAMS)
That's the loudest bell
in the south of England.
My God!
- (BELL TOLLING)
- (SCREAMS)
(SINGING) A British tar is a soaring soul
As free as a mountain bird
His energetic fist
should be ready to resist
A dictatorial word
His eyes should flash
with an inborn fire
His brow with scorn be wrung
He never should bow down
to a domineering frown
Or the tang of a tyrant tongue
His nose should pant
and his lip should curl
His cheeks should flame
and his brow should furl
His bosom should heave
and his heart should glow
And his fist be ever ready
for a knock-down blow
His foot should stamp
and his throat should growl
His hair should twirl
and his face should scowl
His eyes should flash
and his breast protrude
And this should be
his customary attitude
His eyes should flash
His breast protrude
His eyes...
Yes, his eyes should flash
His foot should stamp
and his throat should start to growl
His hair should curl
and his face should scowl
His eyes should flash
and his breast protrude
And this should be
his customary attitude
(APPLAUSE AND CHEERING)
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(SINGING) God save our gracious Queen
Long live our noble Queen
God save our Queen
Send her victorious
Happy and glorious
Long to reign over us
God save our Queen
Who's that?
That's the headmaster. We can go now.
(ALL CLAMORING)
We used to do Gilbert and Sullivan
in our school.
- Only the girls played the boys' part.
- (LAUGHS)
I can't get over Matt. He's so pretty!
Well, don't tell him
that, for heaven's sake!
JEN NY; All right!
DAVID: I'm never sure with you.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- Did you enjoy it, Mr. Donne?
- Yes, thank you very much.
Oh, you directed the play, didn't you?
Oh, we loved it.
This Mr. Reynolds, Miss Bowman.
- How do you do'?
- I'm afraid we're not exactly in your class.
Oh, I'd say much more professional
and more spirited, too.
That's very kind of you. The boys do try.
- There he is! Could I?
- REYNOLDS: Yes, of course.
Excuse me.
Say, you were terrific!
- Was it all right?
- It really was.
- Did you really?
- Yes, really.
What did you think of Buttercup?
He was ace, wasn't he?
I think everybody was ace.
- Would you like to meet some of them?
- I'd love to.
Oh, this is Miss Bowman.
This is Bobby Evans.
Hello. Well, Josephine!
You're stunning. You were marvelous.
(LAUGHING)
And this is Ray Fagshaw,
the finest topman in all the fleet.
- Hello.
- Nice to meet you. How are you?
- Lovely.
- Thank you very much.
The Right Honorable Sir Joseph Porter,
KCB, First Lord of the Admiralty.
Ah, the monarch of the sea!
And these are all his sisters,
and his cousins, and his aunts.
Well, I think you were all
absolutely marvelous.
(ALL CLAMORING)
JENNY: Let's all sing together.
Okay?
ALL: Sing! Sing!
(PIANO PLAYING)
Shall we have a go?
- ALL: Yes!
- (LAUGHS)
(SINGING) / am the monarch of the sea
The ruler of the Queen's Navee
- Aren't you a bit young?
- (LAUGHING)
Whose praise Great Britain
loudly chants
And we are his sisters,
and his cousins, and his aunts
His sisters, and his cousins,
and his aunts
They are his sisters, and his cousins,
- (PRONOUNCING DIFFERENTLY) Aunt.
- No, aunt.
(LAUGHING)
- When at anchor here I ride
JENNY". Yes.
My bosom swells with pride
You do look a bit strange.
And I snap my fingers
at a foeman's taunts
You'll never beat him that way, kid.
And so do his sisters,
and his cousins, and his aunts
His sisters,
(VOCALIZING)
They're his sisters, and cousins, and aunts
They're his sisters,
and his cousins, and his aunts
(LAUGHING) You and I are the only
ones doing any work around here.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Come on, we must all pull together.
Let's go!
Go.
But when the breezes blow
Where do you go?
I generally go below
Why?
To seek the seclusion
that a cabin grants
- You chicken! Chicken!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
And so do his sisters,
and his cousins, and his aunts
All those people in one cabin?
It must have been very crowded.
And so do his sisters,
and his cousins, and his aunts
(SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
(ALL CHEERING)
Hey, Matt, I've got a marvelous idea.
You had me to your opening night,
now I want you to come to mine.
- At the Palladium?
- Yes.
Would you like that?
Oh, gosh, yes, if my father won't mind.
Oh, we can bring him, too.
What do you say?
- Shall we bring him along?
- Yes, if you're sure it will be all right.
Oh, I do.
I think he should definitely come, too.
- Come on, let's ask.
- I'll ask him, yes.
Hello, sir.
Father, can I go to Miss Bowman's show?
You remember you promised me
three clays in London'?
Oh, say yes.
- Will you excuse me?
- Yes, of course.
Matt, what are you talking about?
MATT: Miss Bowman's invited me
to the first night of her show.
The both of us.
Oh, well, why not, David?
The best seats in the house
for you and Matt.
You're supposed to spend
the first week of your holiday
in Canterbury with Aunt Beth,
and you know that.
Well, she won't mind.
I know she won't mind.
Oh, please, Father.
You can buy me that tape recorder
you promised me.
I'd love to come and see you,
Miss Bowman.
- Make him say yes.
- (CHUCKLES)
I don't seem to have any choice, do I?
I don't think so.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) I've got a lovely
bunch of coconuts
There they are, all standing in a row
Big ones, small ones,
some as big as your head
Give them a twist, a flick of the wrist
That's what the showman said
I've got a lovely bunch of coconuts
Every ball you throw will make me rich
There stands my wife,
the idol of me life
Singing roll up bowl or ball
a penny a pitch
(WHISTLING)
- She's here.
- Yeah? How is she?
Fine.
So smile.
- Hi, darling!
- George, telegram from David Donne.
Urgent case. Terribly sorry and all that.
Best of British luck and everything, but...
- In plain American, he ain't coming.
- So?
So...
- What do we do'? Deliver it?
- You want to blow the show?
Yeah.
- I'll tell her it came after she went on.
- Mmm.
- How you feeling, honey?
- Fine.
Hey, did you see them out front?
Cops on horseback,
you can't rate any higher.
- London's my lucky charm.
- Any town's your lucky charm.
I could live in London, George.
I really could.
I could settle here.
(VOCALIZING)
- George, you sent the tickets?
- Yeah, they're at the box office.
- David's picking them up?
- That's right, darling.
Oh, good. I feel marvelous. Come on, Ida.
(VOCALIZING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- How do I look?
- Fabulous.
- I mean, really.
- Really fabulous.
Darling, shall I start the overture?
Oh...
- What time is it?
- Twenty past.
It's funny, they said they were gonna
come backstage before the show.
Oh, they probably thought
you meant after the show.
They didn't want to disturb...
George, will you call the box office
for me, please?
Honey, I just called.
There's a lot of confusion.
See, they're all jammed up.
He may have got caught in the traffic.
Well, that's the price
of popularity, darling.
What's going on?
What do you mean?
Just what I said. What's going on?
Honey, you know everything that I know.
Now, don't get upset.
I'm not upset, George,
but I'm liable to get very upset
if I don't find out what's going on.
Give it to her.
He said he was going to come.
Jenny, I know this is
a big disappointment to you, but...
You expected 2500 people,
but you got 2498.
That's an awful lot of people.
What do you say?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in.
A Mr. Donne to see you, Miss Bowman.
Show him in, please.
All right, you can go in now.
- Hello, Matt!
- MATT: Hello.
Well, how nice you look.
Come in, come in, please.
Gosh, it's a bit different from school,
isn't it?
(CHUCKUNG)
- How do you do, sir?
- Hi.
- Good evening.
- How do you do?
Matt, did your father bring you...
Didn't you get the telegram?
He got a call from Italy.
An emergency case.
Well, it's standing roorn only outside.
(CHUCKUNG)
George, will you start
the overture, please?
GEORGE: Right.
Would you excuse me?
I'll be right back.
JENNY: Okay, Ida.
IDA: Yup.
Fine, turn around.
- The seams all right?
- Splendid.
IDA: There you go.
I hope it was all right. My coming.
Oh, it's more than all right.
As a matter of fact, it's a great big
compliment to me that you came.
I'd have been awfully disappointed
if you hadn't.
Come on, let's go!
(ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Well, actually you see,
I came up to town on my own.
- They don't know I'm here.
- You mean your father doesn't know?
No, he thinks I'm in Canterbury.
But I wouldn't miss your opening night
for anything.
Listen, Matt, you're going to see my show
and then we're gonna have supper together
and then I think I'll bed you down
at the Savoy.
And after that we'll get your tape recorder
tomorrow that he promised you
and a couple of other things, maybe.
That sounds marvelous,
but I think Aunt Beth would worry...
Oh, no, don't worry about that.
You'll take care of Aunt Beth,
won't you, Ida?
Yes, I'll call Aunt Beth.
- Joe.
- Yes, ma'am?
Will you show this young man
to his seat, please?
Yes, certainly.
- Good luck, Miss Bowman.
- Thank you.
You know, we may have
such a good time tonight,
your father will be sorry he missed it.
'Bye-bye.
GEORGE: Did you check the pinboard?
Well, something looks like it's out.
Check it. And fix it fast.
(INAUDIBLE)
(ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Honey, it's a gas!
Come here! Come here!
- Go!
- Yeah.
(APPLAUSE)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(PIANO PLAYING)
(SINGING) Hear that bluebird,
up in the tree
Hear him, what a song
Joy he's bringing, singing to me
Singing, all day long
Goodbye to skies of gray
For I'm back home
Today
All day long I jump and run about
You can always hear me shoutin' out
"Hello, bluebird"
Got no time for blues or anything
I'm so happy, I just wanna sing
"Hello, bluebird"
Blue skies, sunshine
Friends that are real
Old folks, sweetheart
Oh, how I feel
I'll not go roaming like I did again
I'll stay home and be a kid again
"Hello, bluebird, hello"
All day
Long I keep Singing
"Hello, I'm glad I found you, bluebird"
Make yourself at home
No
More
Blues
Just because I'm happy
When I'm around you, bluebird
No more need to roam
Up above the sun is shining
The world is ideal
I just can't describe
The marvelous way that I feel
With nothing but the bluest skies ahead
What a rosy future lies ahead
Thank you, bluebird
Happy, happy, bluebird
Mister Bluebird
Hello
(APPLAUSE)
This was a good idea, coming on the river.
There's St. Paul's.
Christopher Wren designed it.
- Are you cold?
- No, not a bit.
We take cold baths every morning at school.
EW. (SHUDDERING)
But we can get some shelter
further up there.
Everyone's watching you.
Does it bother you?
Oh, no. It doesn't bother me.
Tell me, do you like living at school
the way you do all the time?
Oh, I don't mind. I've been away
from home since I was eight.
Don't you get lonesome for your family?
Oh, I haven't really got a family.
Father's away quite a bit.
He's rather busy, you know.
- Yes, I know.
- Well, it's the same for you, too, isn't it?
I mean, you don't get home
very often either.
No.
Well, that puts us in the same boat then.
(CHUCKLING) Yes.
(HORN BLOWING)
I have to get off at the next landing stage
if I don't want to miss my train.
Oh?
- I don't want to rush you.
- No, it's no rush.
Can I have your autograph, please,
Miss Bowman?
- There you are.
- Thank you.
Thank you. Matt.
Why do we have to get off here?
Why don't we have the whole day together?
- Oh, I couldn't.
- Yes, you could.
Stay with me. Spend the day with me.
Do me a favor, come on.
Well, there's a 6:56,
but I'd have to let them know.
- Well, I fixed it last night, didn't I?
- You did.
Well, I'll fix it again tonight.
- Corne on!
- All right.
(VOCALIZING)
(LAUGHING)
- Oops, we're locked out.
- (DOORBELL BUZZING)
Ah, that was a nice day.
Don't panic, Ida, we're here.
- We've been all the way up the river...
- Down.
- And all the way down the Strand.
- Up.
I haven't had so much fun in years.
Well, you got messages.
Press conference tomorrow at noon.
Oh, rehearsal's at 3:00.
Phone calls, your agents,
New York, George several times,
and they left the hats.
Oh, good, you can help me pick one out.
I made that call to Canterbury,
but I don't see how he's
going to make the 6:56.
Oh, I've got news for you, Ida.
Matt's gonna be my guest for
one more night and one more morning.
We're going to the ionic propulsion
exhibition at the science museum.
So, it looks like you're gonna
have to make another call.
Look, why don't you go powder
your nose or something, hmm?
Okay.
Canterbury wasn't any too happy
when I called this afternoon.
In fact, Canterbury is getting
just a little irritated with us.
Well, I'm sure you took
care of everything, Ida.
You think this is my style?
How long is this going on?
- What do you mean?
- You know what I mean.
Look, I took him out for the day.
What's so wrong with that?
Jenny, this is me, see,
Ida, 18 years, remember?
- I just want to get to know him a little bit.
- And then what?
Let him go home, Jenny.
Tomorrow.
Why don't you quit while you're ahead?
You wanted to see him, fine, you saw him,
now, say goodbye.
GEORGE: Well, we blew the recording room.
Oh, George, hi.
When did you get back?
- Are you all right? We were worried.
- I'm fine.
Well, look, if you ever get hung up again,
let us know.
We'd work it out for you,
that's what we're here for, darling.
You still here?
Good evening, sir.
Yeah.
Well, I'll set it up again.
Are we on our way?
Are you ready, honey?
Jenny, I... I don't think
I ought to stay. I'm...
I'm keeping you from important things.
Nothing's that important, Matt.
I haven't missed a thing.
George, I have a new escort tonight.
And a very attractive one, too.
See you later. Come on.
(APPLAUSE)
(SINGING) I've been running through rains
And the wind that follows after
For one certain face
And an unforgotten laughter
I've been following signs
I've been searching through the lands
For a certain pair of arms
And a certain pair of hands
Yes, I tried a kiss here
And I tried a kiss there
For when you're out in company
The boys and girls
Will pair
But it never was you
It never was anywhere you
An occasional sunset reminded me
Or a flower hanging high on a julep tree
Or one red star hung low in the west
Or a heartbreak call
From a meadowlark's nest
Made me think for a moment
Maybe it's true
I found him in the star
In the call
In the blue
But it never was you
It never was anywhere
You
Anywhere
Anyone for ionic propulsion?
She's out.
That's French for not up yet.
Well, I wouldn't want to disturb her.
Oh, go right ahead, she
won't even hear you.
(KNOCKING)
(WHISPERING) Jenny?
Jenny, it's quarter to 12:00.
Jenny?
(LOUD THUD)
What?
Oh!
Good morning, Jenny.
- I'm sorry, I...
- Good morning, darling.
Is it awfully late?
No, not really.
Weren't we supposed to be someplace
this morning?
The science museum.
But it doesn't matter.
Oh, I'm sorry, Matt.
Please, come sit down.
We could queue.
We could what?
Stand in line.
We don't wanna do that.
I've got a much, much better idea.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
- She's not back?
- No, just a call to call Canterbury.
- Oh, well, she's out of her so-called mind.
- More than you know.
- They're in the middle of a six-country tour...
- Seven.
Seven, huh.
- Oh, they're gonna murder me.
- Cigar.
Cigar.
Good afternoon, girls.
Girls, listen, uh, Jenny has
asked me to stand in for her.
- (DISAPPOINTED EXCLAIMING)
- Aw, now wait a minute now.
Come on, let's be fair, you know, she
loves talking to the ladies of the press.
She's very disappointed
that she can't be here.
But eat, drink, be merry,
have any questions,
think of me as though I were Jenny, okay?
- When did you start smoking cigars?
- Where is she?
Uh, give me that, will ya?
- Well, she had a business date.
- (ALL EXCLAIMING)
Well, it went on way beyond time.
(ALL GRUMBLING)
Way, way beyond.
(MOOING)
What did you say
the name of this place was?
Stoke Poges.
Stoke Poges?
It's where Gray wrote his elegy.
Do you know about that?
No, I know more about Gray's Anatomy.
- Stoke Poges?
- That's right.
- (CHUCKLES)
- "The path of glory leads but to the grave."
Oh, dear.
- Do you ever look at gravestones?
- No.
- They're great fun.
- Fun?
Yes, they're not a bit depressing, really.
Listen to this.
"Here lies my wife, here let her lie.
"Now, she's at rest, and so am l."
- (LAUGHING)
- That's terrible!
You're a terrible boy.
- (When I die, I think I'll be cremated.
{CHUCKUNG)
- Would you like to be cremated?
- I don't know. I suppose so.
It's very sanitary and sort of chic.
I guess so.
Well, my mother was cremated.
- Your mother?
- Janet.
But she's not my real mother.
- She must have loved you very much.
- She liked me.
Come on, let's sit down for a second,
shall we?
Don't you ever wonder about your mother?
Your real mother?
Not really.
I mean, who she was and...
No.
I'll miss you, Jenny.
Will you?
Yes.
Matt, I'm going to go
to Paris in a few days,
and I wish you could come with me,
just... Just for a little while.
I'll... I'll talk to your father about it
and I'll make all the arrangements.
All you have to do is say yes.
Jenny, I don't understand
why you're being so kind to me.
Well, maybe it's because
I've never had a son of my own
and I like to pretend.
And you fit the bill.
Will you help me?
Yes, Jenny.
Good man, good.
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT OVER PA)
- I thought you'd got lost.
- No.
Miss Bowman's here.
Oh, is she?
She said she wanted to talk to you
urgently as soon as you were back.
Then she decided to come here
and meet you.
- Where is she?
- She's in her car, over there.
I didn't know what you wanted to do,
so I brought your car as arranged.
- Is she still at the Savoy?
- Yes.
Well, look, take my car back to town,
will you?
Take it to the hotel, leave the keys
with the porter and take those along.
Yes, of course.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
- How was your trip?
- Fine.
- You were in... In Rome, weren't you?
- That's right, yes.
Must've been an opera singer.
They're very delicate creatures,
opera singers.
- David, I have a confession to make.
- Really?
Yes, I'm afraid I've done something
that I shouldn't have.
Yes, I know that.
- You know'?
- News travels, Jenny. Even to Rome.
Are you terribly angry?
I'm so sick with anger
that I can hardly speak to you.
I don't know what to say, I...
I haven't got any excuses
except that it was wonderful being...
There's only one thing
I want to know from you.
How far have you broken your promise?
I haven't said anything, I swear.
I know you're angry,
but I haven't done any harm.
That remains to be seen, doesn't it?
Well, if I'm such a shady character, why
did you let me see him in the first place?
Have you forgotten how you begged,
how you implored, how you pleaded...
I don't beg. I don't beg.
You don't beg.
You just damn well assume.
Everything you want, you get.
- David...
- You haven't changed.
You never will.
You're nothing but a self-centered,
grasping, egocentric little bitch.
And you're a cheat.
Before you go in there and start to act
like the heavy father...
It wasn't his fault.
I brought this about myself.
Will you remember that?
Ida, would you get Matt for me, please?
Hello, Father.
I wanted to come down to the airport
with Jenny,
but she said better not.
She said that she'd explain
about everything.
- About Paris and all that.
- Matt...
We didn't win.
Oh.
Jenny explained everything perfectly, Matt.
All I want you to do now is to pack up
and come along. Are you ready?
No. No, I'm not quite packed.
Nothing much. That won't take long...
Well, you hurry up then, the car's outside.
- Yes, sir.
- All right.
So, now it's Paris, is it?
And then the rest of the tour.
Rome, Athens...
Oh, for God's sake, don't sulk.
You saw his face,
you saw how sorry he was.
And you know how sorry I am.
What do you want us both to do, just die?
I don't want you to do anything.
I just want to get out of here
as soon as possible.
Well, what was so terrible about it anyway?
He came to see the show, we took a trip
up the river and we had a good time.
What's so terrible about that?
We had a wonderful time.
And you're standing there as if
I'm some kind of criminal or something,
like I'm Lizzie Borden.
- Oh, for God's sake, Jenny...
- Oh, for God's sake, Jenny!
I stayed out of the way as long
as your wife was around.
And she was good for him.
Well, fine.
But what now?
You with your grave demeanor,
or your Auntie Beth in Canterbury
who's 40 years too late!
What kind of life are you offering him?
What you fail you to realize, Jenny,
is that we have a very good relationship,
Matt and I.
We were doing very well
before you came along,
and we'll do a damn sight better
after you've gone.
Boy, you know where to hit, don't you?
Well, I want to tell you something.
He needs me.
And I want him!
He's not yours to have.
You gave him back to me a long time ago.
I need him, I love him,
and I'm going to keep him.
You need him and I want him
and you want him and I...
He's not a bone, my God, he's a child!
He's my son.
And I'm going to keep him.
There's just one thing
we seem to both have forgotten.
He's my son, too.
I made him.
Now, where do we go from there?
I packed.
There's some other things
in the bedroom, but...
We'll send for those later, Matt.
Yes.
Can I have the tape recorder?
It was a present.
Is it true?
Yes.
MATT: Why didn't you tell me?
I... I meant to, uh...
I kept putting it off, I'm afraid.
But...
Why didn't you tell me?
I made a promise to your father.
Matt, I think we better be
moving along now.
No.
No, I don't want to go just yet, Father.
Not yet.
I'd like to stay here for a bit with you
and get it clearer.
If you have no objections.
No, I have no objections.
Please stay.
Matt, I've never ordered you to do
anything in your whole life, have I?
But I am asking you now
to come home with me.
Will you?
All right.
Jenny, please.
Yes, Matt.
I'm going because
my father has asked me to.
Not because I want to.
Do you understand?
Yes.
It's what you must do.
Thank you.
Could I call you then, and... And talk?
Oh, yes, of course.
Call me tomorrow.
All right?
Yes.
You won't drop it, will you?
No.
Don't let him wait alone.
Please go with him.
Anything I can get for you, Jenny?
(SINGING) I'll go my way by myself
This is the end of romance
I'll go my way by myself
Love is only a dance
I'll try to apply myself
And teach my heart how to sing
I'll go my way by myself
Like a bird on the wind
I'll face the unknown
I'll build a world of my own
No one knows better
Than I, myself
I'm by myself
AH alone
I'll go my way by myself
Here's how the comedy ends
I'll have to deny myself
Love and laughter and friends
The great clouds in the sky above
Have put a blotch on my fun
I'll try to fly high above
For my place in the sun
I'll face the unknown
I'll build a world of my own
No one knows better than I, myself
No, no one knows better than I, myself
How I wanted love, and fell
Now I say, "What the hell?"
All of those black days are gone
'Cause it's solo
AH alone
By myself
From now on
(APPLAUSE)
- Did you call New York?
- Called New York.
- And?
- Well, it's a little complicated, honey.
- Well, tell me.
- Can't it wait till after the show?
No, it can't, George. Tell me.
- All right, you've got a case.
- I knew it.
I told you.
Ida, I've got a case.
Jenny, what you've got is a technicality.
Now, I'm gonna lay it out for you just
the way the lawyers laid it out for me.
The records were searched
and the adoption was legitimate.
JENNY: What'd you say?
I said, the adoption was legitimate.
As far as it went.
But there's such a thing as second papers.
Now, don't ask me what they are.
They're second papers
and you never signed them.
JENNY: Well, thank heaven for me.
Well, that means
if you wanna fight it, you can.
Now, no guarantees.
A whole long megillah in court.
Frankly, darling, it's a long shot.
JENNY: Well, did you tell them to go ahead?
No, I didn't tell them anything just yet.
JENNY; Well, tell them so!
George, will you please call the lawyers?
Jenny.
Jenny, right now, at this moment,
you're on top of a career
you've been building for over 20 years.
And half that time I've been with you.
So, I know a little bit about the subject.
Jenny, I can't stand by
and watch you destroy it and yourself.
If you fight this case, you might win.
It's possible, I don't know.
But do you realize what it would mean?
You couldn't be in Rome one week,
Miami the next.
No, you'd have to stay here, in England,
and fight it out in the courts.
Jenny, the boy's got a home,
he's got a father,
a school, a way of life.
You can't jump into the middle of that
and start making all kinds of waves.
Oh, George, please.
All right.
All right. Suppose, you got him.
What would you do with him?
Trail around the world
with a tutor from day to day?
Hotel suites, rented oars,
other people's houses.
And they're pretty strict
in England about schools.
You might have to send him to a school
and come and visit him now and then
at vacation time.
Jenny.
Jenny, you'd be strangers, don't you see?
- (STAMMERS)
- All right. All right.
And what would happen to you?
How would you be able to work
with this pull all the time?
I mean, do you know
how to handle a small boy?
It's a full-time job.
Forgive me, dear,
but I don't think you know how to do it.
This. All this. This is your job.
You do it better,
better than anybody else in the whole world
because you know it.
Don't force this, Jenny.
Let it rest.
George, I know you're trying
to help me, but...
You... You see, I love him.
And oddly enough, I think he loves me.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
MAN: You have three minutes,
Miss Bowman.
(INHALES SHARPLY) I'm ready.
(APPLAUSE)
(OPERA MUSIC PLAYING)
Matt.
I've got to interrupt, I'm afraid.
It's all right.
Did you mind me taking this?
No, not a bit.
Have you just got back?
I've been finishing some notes.
No, don't put it away.
It's rather fine.
I've spent most of today
wondering how to explain things to you.
You've had some pretty rough things
flung at you,
and now you'd better have the truth.
It's up to me to give it to you.
- Shall we sit down?
- Yes.
I don't know how much you heard today,
but I presume enough to know
that I'm your real father.
And Jenny's your mother.
Were you and Jenny married once?
No, Matt, we were never married.
We fell in love
while I was in New York, studying.
I did ask her to marry me.
To come home, to England.
But I hadn't reckoned with one thing.
That was her career, which meant more
to her than anything else.
I couldn't make her change her mind,
and I had to come back here to work.
So, I came alone.
- That's pretty clear, isn't it?
- Yes.
And then I met Janet again.
We'd known each other
since we were almost your age.
It was always rather expected
that we'd get married, so we did.
And then I heard
that you were about to be born.
Jenny did her best to look after you,
but touring the world with a small child
isn't always convenient.
So, Janet and I talked things over
and it was decided that you would
come and live with us as our son.
Our adopted son,
because that was kinder to Janet.
I don't understand
why you didn't tell me when Janet died.
I didn't expect you to understand entirely.
That'll take time. Perhaps a long time.
But the important thing now is your future.
(SIGHS)
Will you... Will you help me?
All right.
Well, you've promised to telephone Jenny.
- And I expect you'll be thinking about that.
- Yes.
And what shall you say to her?
What do you think I should say to her?
That's a decision
you have to make yourself, Matt.
But I can tell you what she'll say to you.
She'll ask you to meet her in Paris.
And when you get there,
it'll be another place.
- And then another...
- How do you know?
Because she wants you.
But she just said for a few days.
It doesn't stop there, Matt.
Just because you're angry with Jenny,
why should I be?
Look, I'm not angry with Jenny.
I'm not angry with her.
I know her,
and I know what I'm talking about.
She wants you, not for a weekend.
But you.
She wants you to leave your friends,
your home and your school.
To start a new way of life.
Matt, I... I know
what fun she's been to be with,
I know how kind she is,
and good and wise, too, sometimes.
And it would be exciting.
You'll see places you've never seen before,
you'll fly, you'd catch boats.
And you'd laugh a lot.
I know her, Matt.
I loved her.
I still do love her.
But mark this,
Jenny gives more love than anyone.
But she takes more love
than anyone can possibly give.
Can you understand that?
But what if I do go with her?
Well, if it was something
you really wanted to do
and was going to make you happy,
I'd get used to it.
So, you don't really care.
Oh, Matt, of course I care, you idiot.
Of course I care!
If it was up to me, I'd say,
"Go and telephone Jenny and say goodbye."
Tell her you've got a good life here
and you're not gonna muck it up.
Matt, you're my son.
I love you.
And I want you to go on being my son.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Hello.
Oh, Matt.
How are you'? Are you... Are you all right?
Wake me'? No. I... I've just been
sitting here, waiting for you to call.
Where are you?
Oh, good.
Matt, would you come over
right away, please?
I've got so much to explain.
Everything was so hideous yesterday.
Especially for you.
Please, come over right away, darling.
Oh, well, what about this afternoon?
My day is free.
Why?
(CHUCKLES)
What's happening?
Oh.
Well, why don't you
bring your friends along?
And... And you and I can have
a private talk for a little while.
And then we can all join forces
and... And have a lovely day.
Yes, it sounds a bit complicated.
What about tomorrow, Matt?
My, you are a busy fellow. (CHUCKLES)
Matt, you know that trip to Paris
we were planning?
The one we talked about.
Oh, good, I've been thinking about it, too,
and I just don't see how I'm going
to be able to work things out.
Yes, that's right.
I'll be busy from morning till night,
and I have...
Well, we couldn't be together at all.
You might wind up very lonely.
I'm glad you understand.
Well, of course
you're going to be seeing me.
I'll be back in London in no time.
We'll have lots of laughs and lots of fun.
Okay?
All right.
Well, now, you take care of yourself,
you hear?
And thank you for being
such a fine young man.
Bye-bye.
Matt?
God bless.
(CRIES SOFTLY)
Ida.
Get me my black dress, I'm going out.
(ALARM RINGING)
Wait for me, will you?
(INAUDIBLE)
I hope you don't mind us
getting onto you, Mr. Donne.
But she was asking for you
and wouldn't see anyone else.
Where is she?
Of course, you realize we are trying to
keep this matter completely confidential.
Yes. Yes, of course. I know.
Unfortunately, we're full up at the moment,
so we had to put her in there.
Thank you very much.
- If there's anything you need...
- Yes, I'll let you know immediately.
- Right.
- Thank you.
Don't ever go to an exhibition
of abstract art for the millions.
No, I won't.
Thank you, nurse.
And if you do go, don't drink the martinis.
No.
Because they're half gasoline.
And you've had enough.
I've had enough to throw up Fire Island.
Does it show?
Someone told me.
That was pretty sneaky.
Oh, there's a young lord
I must warn you about.
- Oh?
- Hmm.
A young Lord George...
Hell, whatever his name was.
He asked me if he could take me home.
And I said thank you.
And we got into a cab.
The next thing I knew, it was "all
fall down" and I wound up with this.
He knew where he lived, all right.
But I was out. I was out cold. I was out.
And nobody asked me where I lived.
Well, how did you get here?
Cab driver named Gerald.
Gerald brought me here.
And they fixed my foot
and they gave me coffee.
And somebody asked for an autograph
for their cousin Marilyn.
Oh! I feel awful, David.
- Have some of this, come on.
- Oh, no more coffee. No.
I couldn't take any more coffee. If you...
You'd have to feed me through the vein.
I'm full. I'm full to the brim
with the whole goddamn world.
Yes, but now, come on.
Be good, drink this. Come on.
Have you come to take me home?
No, I've come to take you to the theater.
Oh, no, you haven't.
- I'm not going back there.
- Drink some of this.
- I'm not going back there ever, ever again.
- Listen, they are waiting.
I don't care if they're fasting.
You just give 'em their money back
and tell them to come back next fall.
- Jenny, it's a sellout.
- I'm always a sellout.
You promised. They're waiting.
- There's George and Ida and 200,000...
- George and Ida and 200,000, I know that.
I know. Just let them wait.
To hell with them.
I'm... Can't be spread so thin.
I'm just one person.
I don't wanna be rolled out like a pastry
so everybody'd get a nice, big bite of me.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm just me. I belong to myself.
I can do whatever I damn well please
with myself,
and nobody can ask any questions.
Now, you know that is not true, don't you?
Well, I'm not gonna do it anymore.
And that's final.
I... It's just not worth all the deaths
that I have to die.
You have... You have a show to do tonight.
You are going to do it.
And I am going to see that you do.
You think you can make me sing?
Do you think you can...
Do you think George can make me sing?
Or Ida?
You can get me there, sure,
but can you make me sing?
- No, we...
- I sing for myself. I sing when I want to.
Whenever I want to. Just for me.
- I sing for my own pleasure.
- Yes.
- Whenever I want.
- Do you understand that?
- Yes, I do understand that.
Just hang onto that, will you?
Hang onto that.
Well, I've hung onto every bit of rubbish
there is to hang onto in life.
And I've thrown all the good bits away.
- Now, can you tell me why I do that?
- No.
No, no. I can't tell you why you do that.
But I can tell you this,
you are going to be late.
I don't care.
Darling,
I don't give a damn who you letdown.
But you're not gonna let you down.
You haven't called me that for years.
I haven't been able
to call you that for years.
Now, come here, look.
Just look at me. Please, look at me.
- Are you listening to me?
- Hmm.
There's something I haven't been able
to say to you in years, too.
- L...
- David, don't.
Don't say it.
Because if you said it now
and if you didn't mean it,
(SOBBING) I think I'd... I think I'd die.
- I'll mean it.
- Mmm-mmm.
I love you.
(CRYING) Oh! Oh, dear! Oh, dear!
- (CRYING)
- Darling, help me. Help me.
- I'll help you with...
- Help us. Help us.
(CRYING) David.
He didn't want to go with me.
He didn't want to.
He made all kinds of excuses.
He didn't want to stay with me.
Darling, I know, I know.
Help me, please.
(STUTTERING) I want to help you,
but I don't know how.
Now, look...
Come with me now.
Come now, Jenny, please.
David...
You wouldn't cheat me, would you?
- You wouldn't pretend to me.
- Oh, darling, I wouldn't cheat you.
You wouldn't say you love me, would you?
- No, I wouldn't say I love you if I didn't.
- Then tell me again.
JENNY: Please tell me, again.
Please, once.
I'll tell you as often as you want me to.
I've always loved you.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
That's where it ends, isn't it?
That's where it ends.
We were the right people
that met at the wrong moment.
With all the right ideals.
We were just too strong-headed
to give up everything for each other.
We just didn't fit.
We fitted.
The rest didn't.
That doesn't make much sense.
The loving does.
Yes.
The loving always does.
- Are you all right now?
- Mmm-hmm. I'm all right.
I think you're gonna have to help me
with my foot...
(WINCES)
- Can you manage?
- Mmm-hmm.
(SNIFFLES) Oops.
You know, there's an old saying.
"When you go onstage,"
pardon me,
"you don't feel any pain at all.
"When the light hits you,
"you don't feel anything."
(CHUCKLES) It's a stinking lie.
- Will you stay with me?
- Yes, I'll stay.
How long?
Until you can stand on your feet again.
(CROWD SHOUTING IN THE DISTANCE)
David, I don't think...
(CHUCKLES)
No, no. I've had it.
It's an hour past curtain.
You'll be 45 minutes getting dressed.
You think they're gonna wait for you?
There are 2500 people out there
who paid money to see Jenny Bowman.
But you're gonna let them down.
Now, that may not mean anything
to you anymore,
but I still have a certain reverence
for audiences.
They mean a great deal to me.
And if they still do mean something to you,
then I'm gonna find it very difficult
to forgive you.
And if they don't mean anything
to you anymore, then...
Then I am genuinely
and profoundly sorry for you, Jenny.
(AUDIENCE CLAPPING)
MAN: There she is!
(CROWD CHEERING)
MAN 2: Where you been, Jenny?
- What?
- MAN 2: Where you been?
Oh, I've been having a hell of a time.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Thank you very much.
MAN 3: What happened to the ankle?
I've been skiing or sheeing or both.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Like my furs?
AUDIENCE; Yes!
Where'd you get 'em?
I just shot 'em.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(APPLAUSE)
I'd like to sing for you,
if we can get these things...
Can you pull them up or... Pull them up.
I think everyone's gone
to sleep back there.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- Thank you.
I Could Go On Singing.
(SINGING) When a dove is in love
with a doll of a dove
He is out all night, coo, cooing
When an owl's on the prowl
for a feminine fowl
He goes out all night, woo, wooing
Every bird and bee has his lunacy
In the way he works his dream off
But when I feel high
Here's the way
That I like to get my kind of steam off
Owls hoo, hoo
Others sigh
Doves coo, coo
Ah, but I
I could go on singing
Till the cows come home
And the rooster
Starts to crow, crow, crow
When I see your eyes
I go all out
I must vocalize till you shout
"Enough already"
I could go on singing
Till the moon turns pink
Anything from Faust
To ink-a-dink-a-dink
Love does funny things
When it hits you this way
I must keep on singing
Like a lark
Going strong
With my hear': on the wings of a song
Singing day
I could go on singing
Till the cows come home
And the rooster
Starts to crow, crow, crow
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
When I see your eyes
I go all out
I must vocalize
Till you shout, "Enough already"
I could go on
I could go on singing
Till the moon turns pink
Anything from Faust
To ink-a-dink-a-dink
Love does funny things
When it hits you this way
I must keep on singing
Like a lark
Going strong
With my heart on the wings
Of a song
Singing day
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)