[Wagon Rattling]
[Man Singing]
Isn't it time to stop this travelin',
for it dark and the child shiverin'?
We will not. And us not two hours,
or maybe three, from Chicago itself?
"Ha, ha," says I.
[Chuckles]
Get along with ya, ya lazy devils.
I'll be layin' me whip on your backs.
Chicago will not be movin'...
and us living there for the rest
of our days, God willin'.
I'll not be held back
by your tongue.
A fine city waiting there
just over the rim of the land.
"I'll rest there tonight,"
I said to myself.
And so I will.
'Tis a mighty city will be built here.
The hub. Yes, the hub
of the country...
fillin' all
this prairie land...
and you boys
living to see it.
- [Train Whistle Blowing]
- Huh, indeed.
Come on.
Get along with ya.
Look, Pa.
It's a train.
Come on, Pa.
Let's race her.
By the twinklin' stars
of heaven, I will.
- Come on, boys.
- You'll do no such.
Go on, Pa!
You can lick it!
We're licking it!
- [Train Whistle Tooting]
- [Horses Whinnying]
Whoa! Whoa there!
Hold on, boys!
Whoa, boy. Whoa there.
Whoa!
Whoa, boy.
[Grunts]
Holy Mary, Mother of God.
- Pat. Pat!
- Pa.
[Boy Cries]
[Boy Crying]
Pat. Jack,
fix the water, quick.
[Crying Continues]
Dion, my petticoat,
tear it.
- Ma. [Crying]
- Shh!
Dion, take off your coat
and put it under his head.
[Train Whistle Blowing]
- Is he hurt bad?
- How should I be knowin'?
- Pour a little water over his head.
- [Crying Continues]
That's enough.
Dion, get the whiskey.
Never mind me.
Are the rest unharmed?
- Not a scratch.
- Heaven be praised for that.
'Twas me own fault
and no other.
[Crying Continues]
[Chuckles]
Ain't it the devil's
own doin', though...
to be draggin' me down and then
bumping the life out of me?
Just when the smell
of Chicago's in me nose.
Jack.
Dion.
Bob.
Come closer here,
the three of ya...
and mind what
I have to say.
'Tis a grand new place,
this Chicago.
And them that grow with it
will be rich and strong...
like I was always
minded to be.
'Tis a boom,
and you'll boom with it.
Someday you'll be
fine, big men...
a credit to me name...
and everybody speakin'
with respect of the O'Learys...
and how they grew up with the city
and put their mark on it.
You're wastin' yourself, Patrick.
You with your fine talk.
It's me last breath I'm usin',
and I'll have me say.
- Help me put him in the wagon.
We've got to find a doctor.
- No.
No, it's no use.
Just bury me here...
and let Chicago
come to me...
that couldn't come to it.
Molly...
[Grunts]
- [Wind Whistling]
- Patrick.
- Ma!
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
help my Pat rest in peace...
him that was so restless on Earth,
for he was a good man...
for all his fine
ambitions.
And if there ever was to be food
to be got or shelter...
or you wanted someone to laugh with
or have a bit of a good time...
you didn't have to look
any further than Patrick O'Leary.
But I need not
be tellin' you all this...
who know it better
than I do.
Amen.
Get the horses ready,
boys.
Good-bye, Pat.
Someday, I'll be
sendin' the priest...
to speak
the proper words.
Ma, I'll
take care of ya.
I'll do what he said.
You know, about Chicago and...
Sure, Ma, we'll
take care of ya.
I'm gonna make a lot of money
and get ya things and...
Hush it,
the both of you.
Get in the wagon.
[Clicks Teeth]
Giddap.
- [Player Piano]
- [Dog Barking]
[Cattle Driver Yelling]
- Ho!
- [Lowing]
- [Dog Barking]
- [People Chattering]
Ma, we've gotta find
someplace to stay.
- We can't keep on living in a wagon.
- Time enough for that.
- It's a job I'm looking for first.
- Look!
There's a theater.
Maybe I could get
to be an actor.
You an actor, and your father
not cold in his grave.
- But we've gotta do something.
- It's school you'll be going to,
the three of ya.
School, at my age.
[Molly]
Whoa.
Look. Right under
my very eyes.
Wait here.
I won't be a minute away.
And keep your eyes
off this picture...
- and her in tights or worse.
- All right, Ma.
Gee! Look at them horses.
Ain't they beauts?
[Women Squealing]
[Laughing]
- Look. They're stuck.
- Yeah, in the mud.
Young man.
I mean you.
Could I bother you to assist
us ladies to the sidewalk?
I'm sorry, ma'am, but I got on
my new store-bought pants.
[Clicking Tongue]
Whoa, boy! Whoa, whoa!
Ladies, if me and my brother
here can make a saddle,
maybe we could get you out.
- Saddle?
- Yes'm, like this.
All you gotta do
is hold on.
Why, that's marvelous.
Ada, you try it.
That's gonna be grand.
Now mind your dress.
[Giggling]
- [Molly] Dion.! Jack.!
- [Screams]
- Up to The Hub.
- We just slipped.
- You little brats!
- [Man Laughing]
- I'll... I'll...
- And who will you be hittin'?
- Look at me!
- A bit of mud, and it behind.
A pair of tender hands and plenty of soap,
it'll be as good as new.
You don't know what
you're talking about!
There's not a washerwoman
in this town that could save this dress.
Is that so now? And what
would you say if I told you...
that I could do it myself,
if it was worth me time?
All right. You're so smart.
You save this dress, and I'll give you...
I'll be namin' the price, and you
providin' the soap and the tub.
[Man Singing]
[Ends]
Hey, Ma.! Ma, I'm back.!
I got three from Gil Warren
and two from Mrs. Palmer.
- She says a pair of her
whatchamacallems are missing.
- Oh, she did?
You can tell the fine lady she'll get 'em
back when she pays for the soap she owes.
- Yes'm.
- And put up the horse.
Give her some oats. And be sure
the barn door's fastened.
And then get your hands and face
washed before it's supper.
Yes'm.
Gretchen.
- Ja?
- [Snorting]
- Look out!
- [Shrieks] The milk!
- It's gone!
- Oh, it's all right.
No use crying over it now.
It's spilt.
- [Crying]
- She might've kicked you.
I told you never to milk her without
putting that bar between her legs.
That's what it's for.
Daisy, you hussy!
Mrs. O'Leary!
What will she say?
- Oh, that's all right. I'll fix it with Ma.
- Ja?
Ja.
Aw, gee.
Ja. Gut.
- Thank you, Daisy.
- Ma.! Ma.!
- Out here, Jack.
- I thought you were coming down
to court to hear me.
With all Chicago waitin' to be washed?
Get along with ya.
- Where'd I get the time?
- I sure made 'em sit up and take notice.
- Did you now?
- I told 'em just what I thought about 'em.
"My client is right,"
I said, " and you know it.
But what do you care about people,
as long as you can fill your pockets?"
No wonder they say this is
the worst city, with politicians
like Gil Warren running things.
- And how did the fine gentleman like that?
- Oh, he was sweatin' plenty.
- " Sure," I said. " What do you
care about Chicago being bad...
- Take the handle.
"as long as business is good
and you've got all the beef
and pork in the world?
"But I'll tell you this. It takes more than
those things to make this a great city.
"It takes people with
some sense of decency...
to make this not only the biggest city
in the world, but the best."
It's a fine silver
tongue you ha'...
and your father would be
that proud of you.
- And I told him...
- [Bell Ringing]
- [Dogs Barking]
- Here you are!
Well, good-bye, boys.
Don't let 'em keep you too long.
If you see my old lady, tell her I'm sitting
up with a friend that was took sick.
Have a cigar, Jim. Thanks for the ride.
I'll do the same for you.
Thanks, lad. Anytime you're
coming our way, let us know.
- We'll be glad to have you with us.
- I'll remember that.
Watch the mud on your shoes,
Pickle. You know Ma.
Hey, Ma! It's me!
- [Laughing] Hello, Ma!
- Howdy, Mrs. O'Leary.
- Hi, Jack.
- Hello, Pickle.
- Sorry you lost your case, Jack.
- Lost?
Sure. I, uh... I forgot to tell you.
The judge dismissed it.
Heaven help me. And all the time
I thought he'd won it.
Don't worry. Warren won't
hold it against you, as long as you lost.
I heard about it. A fella said Jack
had the courtroom hypnotized.
Yeah, everybody
but the judge.
Had him too, only Gil Warren
put him on the bench.
Keep your hand
away from that.
But, Ma, it's just
the right size.
- Ma, for the last time, will you
quit this laundry business?
- Why should I be quittin'?
'Cause I don't want my best girl
bending over a washtub all her life.
- Go along with you now.
- I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll get you a new place, out of the Patch,
set you up like the finest hussy in town.
Huh? Look. Look, Ma.
- Where did you get that money?
- A fellow paid me.
You're lyin'. You've been gambling
at that racetrack again.
There wasn't
any gambling to it, Ma.
There are only eight horses in the race...
mine and seven others.
- All we had to do was shoot the other seven.
- Hmph!
Huh, indeed. Come on, Ma.
How about it, hmm?
- I'll not be livin' on money
that isn't honestly got.
- Give us a kiss then, huh?
- Now, Dion, get along with ya.
I've got my work. Dion!
- Aw, come on. [Laughing]
[Speaking German]
Won't wash out.
Look at it.
I told that Gil Warren...
I wouldn't wash any more tablecloths
they'd been drawing pictures on.
- Send it back.
- Wait a minute. This looks like a map.
Maybe Warren's gonna hunt
for a buried treasure.
Hunt for it? He's already found it
in the city treasury.
Something about
Randolph Street...
and...and Madison.
This looks like the tracks
for the horse car line.
I know what it is.
This means they're gonna run
the car line along Randolph Street.
You're crazy. They've already surveyed
Madison for the tracks.
Sure, they have. That's exactly
what makes me think they're
gonna run along Randolph.
- By golly, maybe you're right.
- Of course I'm right!
That's the way they cheat the people...
get them to invest on Madison Street...
and then switch the line
by their own property.
- What an idea.
- You're right. This information
is worth a fortune.
- Ha! Listen to him.
- And I'm gonna get part of it.
You with your fine talk
and your grand plans...
not a penny ever honestly
earned to your name.
Maybe so. But if I had
this corner here...
where all the traffic meets,
I'd put up the biggest saloon in town.
- Saloon?
- And free beers to you, Mrs. O'Leary.
I wouldn't be stepping
my foot inside.
Then I guess we'll have to keep on
rushing the growler for you.
Oh, but look.
There's a name already scribbled
in right on my corner.
B-F-A-W-C-E-double "T."
- B. Fawcett.
- Ever heard of him?
No. It's a new one on me.
- Stop it! Stop it! Are you out of your mind?
- I've gotta have this name.
We'll go down to Gil Warren's
and see what we can find out
about this Fawcett fellow.
- You've ruined it!
- There was already a hole in it, Mrs. O'Leary.
The scamp.
[Hoofbeats]
[Women Singing]
- [Continues]
- Hello, Rondo.
- Where's Mr. Warren?
- The other end of the bar.
[Continues]
- Hello, Mr. Warren.
- Oh, hello, son.
- Howdy, Mr. Warren.
- What can I do for you?
- I'd like to talk to you for a moment.
- Sure. Go ahead.
- It's kind of private, and I thought that, uh...
- [Singing Ends]
- Not now. Not now. Little later, perhaps.
- [Traditional American]
Stick around.
Glad to have seen you.
[Singing]
[Continues]
- Whew!
- [Chorus Humming]
- What a woman.
- Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
- Is she new?
- Yeah, she's new, new as far
as Chicago's concerned.
She was the biggest hit Niblo's Garden
in New York ever had.
A sensation.
And I'm paying her a bigger price...
than any entertainer
in this town ever got.
- That's Belle Fawcett.
- Oh, Belle Fawcett.
B. Fawcett?
[Humming Continues]
[Singing Together]
[Continues]
- [Banjo]
- [Continues]
[Continues]
[Ends]
[Applause]
[Audience Cheering]
Ladies and gentlemen,
as an added treat tonight...
the proceeds to go
to the widow and orphans...
or our late bartender,
Aloysius O'Malley...
who was shot in front
of this very door...
my little girls are going to give a special
performance of our famous classic...
Living Statues...
an artistic divertissement straight
from New York and Paris, France.
[Cheering]
And remember, gentlemen...
it's all for sweet charity,
and no tights.
[Cheering]
What am I bid?
- One dollar.
- One dollar? Do I hear two?
- Four dollars.
- Four, the gentleman says.
- Who'll make it five?
- [Man] I'll pay five.
Five. Now we're getting somewhere.
Who'll make it six?
Speak right up, handsome.
What is it? Six?
I'll pay $100 to charity
if Belle Fawcett plays Venus.
[Audience Gasping,
Murmuring, Laughing]
We have a comedian
in the house.
- Go ahead. Take his offer.
- Sold to handsome for $100.
Come on. Let's see the color
of your money.
Fifty, 70, 90, 100.
Whiskey!
Right through that door. I'll be
with you in a moment. Thank you.
[Applause Continues]
[Gasping]
Hey, what's this? Wait a minute!
[Piano]
Yes, Miss Fawcett.
Your carriage is here.
Will you tell Mr. Warren I'll meet him
for lunch tomorrow at the Palmer House?
- Yes, Miss Fawcett.
- Thank you.
- Good night.
- Oh!
- Get in.!
- Let me go! [Shouting]
- [Stammering]
- Shut up!
- I won't! Let me out of here!
- Shut up.
- Let me out of here, or I'll jump!
Go ahead. Jump.
Oh, it's you.
Driver! Driver!
- No use yelling at him. I fixed him.
- Oh, you're crazy!
Maybe. But I was sane
enough until tonight.
Then I heard you sing,
and something happened to me.
Something swept over me I've never
felt before or ever expect to feel again.
- What are you talking about?
- I'm in love with you, Belle.
- Get out, or I'll call the police!
- They can't stop me from loving you.
Maybe not, but they can sure
cool you off, brother.
I know it sounds crazy...
and I apologize... but it's true.
[Sighs]
Right now, my heart's pounding so.
- Listen to it. Ow!
- Oh, you fool.
I'm trembling all over.
And I wanna be calm and cool
so I can make you understand.
Say, are you
on the level?
Absolutely.
- But I don't even know who you are.
- Does that matter?
It does to me.
And I'll tell you another thing.
- I didn't like that cheap
trick you pulled on me.
- I had to talk to you alone.
What gave you the idea you could
make love to me like this?
Just give me a chance.
I'll tell you the whole story.
All right. You can stop here
and buy me a drink.
No, not here.
It's too crowded.
Since you've
taken me by storm...
the least you might do is to take me
to your place so we can really talk.
Very well, but your story
had better be good.
All right, George. You can drive
to Miss Fawcett's home.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
- So this is where you live?
- Yes.
Way up there
on the second floor.
I think I can make it.
Back to The Hub quick!
Hey! Hey, wait a minute!
Whew! What a woman.
- Let's tell Ma.
- Ja. You want to?
Do you reckon
she suspects?
I was never that surprised
in all me life.
All this hand-holdin' and goo-goo eyein'
and sighin' and gigglin'.
I'm all wore out tryin'
to look the other way.
- Aw, Ma.
- Now, I suppose you'll be tellin' me...
you want
to get married.
- Why, sure.
- You scamp. Takin' the best ironer I ever had.
Well, if it's love
you're after...
I guess a few shirts and tablecloths
can't stand in the way...
but I won't have you sittin' around
and waitin' and not eatin'.
You'll be gettin' married right away
and I want no back talk about it.
Now, give me that pail.
And I'd be ashamed,
with a fine spring moon outside...
and you in a barn puttin' ideas
in the head of a temperamental cow.
- [Mooing]
- [Both Laugh]
[Whistling]
- So, you're in love at last.
- Sure, Mike... with you.
And are you now? And I suppose it's
for me that you're slickin' your hair...
anticipatin' yourself in front of a mirror
until it's half wore out.
[Laughs]
Well, you want me
to look nice, don't you?
And I suppose you'll be holdin'
her hands, maybe stealin' a kiss...
and her tellin' ya how grand ya are
and callin' ya pretty names.
- Here, let Ma do it. And you believin' her.
- [Chuckles]
[Yells]
That shirt! I thought so. Take it off.
Oh, but, Ma, it's a beaut.
Look. "D.V.S."...Who's that?
His name is Swift and he sells pigs.
Now take it off.
- It needs to go back in the morning.
- Oh, come on, Ma!
Take it off.
Oh! Who's the best darn washer woman
in the whole bloomin' city of Chicago?
- [Screams, Laughs]
- [Laughs]
Ma! Say, Ma!
I won my first case!
- I knew you would!
- Congratulations.
The jury wasn't out
more than 15 minutes...
and the judge said it was the finest
speech he's heard all session.
So did the lawyer from
the other side. And... yippee!
Congratulations. I always
knew you had it in your tongue.
A fellow from the Tribune
said he's gonna write it up.
- You're gonna get your name in the paper?
- Yes!
- How much did you get?
- Huh?
- You did get paid for it, didn't you?
The fellow only makes $10 a week,
and he's got a wife and a family.
Ten dollars a week?
That's just $10 more than you make.
- I couldn't take his money, could I?
- I give up.
I've got one son that steals
my laundry and spends his money
heaven knows where...
another a lawyer and wins cases
and don't get paid for them.
I should have brought the two
of you up as Irish bricklayers,
and every Saturday payday.
Don't mind her, as long as
she can keep her job.
- Night, Ma. Don't sit up for me.
I may be late.
- Hmm.
Huh, indeed.
Where's he going
all dressed up?
Where is any of us going?
And where is it all going to end?
For one thing, we can
be going in to supper.
I wish you could have heard
what that judge said.
[Humming]
[Singing]
[Door Opens]
- That you, Miss Belle?
- Yes.
- Any messages for me?
- No.
Nothing except a heap more
flowers and some champagne
from that same gentleman.
[Laughs]
Lord, honey, you sure got
him snortin' in his sleep.
I hope you threw them out.
I throwed out the roses, but you knows
what a mess broken bottles make.
Did you tell him not to come
around here anymore?
I done told him that
till I'm black in the face.
[Groans]
These corsets are so tight,
I can hardly breathe.
As long as the men folks likes a small waist,
us gals has got to suffer.
[Sighs]
- You want anything else, Miss Belle?
- No, thank you, Hattie.
- Good night.
- You can call me early tomorrow afternoon.
- Yes'm.
Get out of here.
- Get out.!
- But listen...
- I'll tell you, I wanna...
- Get out of here!
- Belle, I wanna talk to...
- Get out.!
- Listen, Belle. Don't act like that.
- What do you mean
by breaking into my place?
- Don't be like that.
- Don't act like that. I want to speak to you.
- Get out of here!
- Get out of here! Hey! Help! Help!
- I want to speak to you.
Hattie! Hattie!
- You calling me, Miss Belle?
- Hattie.!
- Help! Let me...
- [Screams]
[Screams]
Police! Murder! Help!
Police! Police!
[Shouting]
Hattie! Let me go!
[Grunts]
[Groans]
Oh, you!
[Grunts]
- Now, won't you tell me
what this is all about?
- I love you, Belle.
I mean, really.
- Well...
- I want the truth.
- You have a piece of property
on Randolph Street.
- Of all the...
I thought if you and I were
to put up a place like Warren's...
only better, more class...
we could make a lot of money.
But I really meant that
about being crazy about you.
[Chuckles]
Why didn't you say so
in the first place?
I'm a businesswoman.
I'd have listened to any proposition...
without all
this foolishness.
- You would've?
- Of course I would.
What a woman.
Right through this way,
Mr. Police.!
Sorry, boss...
but it looks like
the fire's out.
Now, look, Senator.
Gil Warren controls...
the Patch with
all its votes.
You need votes. Now,
as long as Warren goes along...
with no opposition, he has you and
your interests just where he wants them.
Who knows, but the day
may come when Warren...
gets other ideas
that'd be embarrassing.
- We have an offer to make you.
- Now, I have the greatest...
attraction that ever came to Chicago...
Miss Fawcett.
Now with your backing
and your money to get us started...
we'll open the greatest saloon
Chicago's ever known...
on the busiest
corner in town...
and I'll control the Patch...
I'll tell 'em how to vote.
And what's more, Senator,
you see this floor?
You see those real silver dollars
that Potter Palmer put in there?
Well, every month
after we get started, Senator...
they'll be 1,000
of those for you.
What do you say?
Are you in?
[Smacking Lips]
I'm always in the market
for marketable goods.
Go ahead.
Full protection for me,
security for you and your family...
and a hundred dollars in cash
every Monday from now on.
[Spits]
Young man,
are you trying to bribe me?
Why, Commissioner,
how can you say such a word?
[Band Playing]
[Bell Ringing]
[Band Continues Playing]
Mrs. Kelly, good evening. Welcome to
The Senate, and I hope you enjoy yourself.
Good evening, sir. Good evening,
Mr. O'Shaughnessy.
Welcome to The Senate.
Hey, you mugs, where do you think you are?
Take off your hats.
Keep on your coats
and shake hands with the boss.
- Where do you think you're going?
- Now listen, shorty.
You're taking
the wrong "altitude"...
'cause this is the only saloon
in town I ain't been thrown out of.
I'll give you
just five minutes.
I can do it in three.
That's tellin' him.
[Audience Applauding]
[Singing]
[Continues]
[Singing Together]
[Tapping]
[Ends]
- Captain Jamison.
- Captain Jamison, welcome.
- And this is my daughter Ann.
- Miss Colby.
- How do you do?
I've been begging Father
to bring me here for the opening.
- I'm glad he did.
- It's marvelous.
- I've never seen anything like it.
- Thank you.
- May I show you to your table?
- Please do.
Gentlemen, you give me The Senate,
I give you Chicago.
Father says you're the smartest
young man in Chicago.
That's because he knows
I'll deliver the Patch on Election Day.
He says you have a great future, as big
as Gil Warren's if you do as he says.
He's the boss, and one
of America's finest.
- And now... I must change my costume.
- Allow me.
I want to talk to you, my boy.
I have some great plans in store.
Surely not tonight, Senator,
when you have so beautiful
a daughter to entertain us.
Father won't talk business
if I ask him not to. Will you, darling?
I can't imagine the senator doing
anything that you asked him not to.
That's right. She wraps me around
her finger all the time.
Uh, excuse me, please.
- I'll be right back.
- We'll expect you.
He's nice-looking, isn't he?
I mean, for someone from the Patch.
- Hello, Warren.
- Why, hello, son.
- Mr. O'Leary.
- Jim-dandy place you've got here.
- Thanks.
- Nothing like it in Chicago. I'm proud of you.
- You mean, you're not sore?
- Why, no. I've come over to bury the hatchet.
Live and let live...
that's my motto.
- Come on. Have a drink.
- Matter of fact, I wanted
a word in private with you.
- Oh, sure. Come on in my office.
- See you in a minute, Rondo.
Rondo, step up to the bar.
Anything you want, on the house.
Thank you, Mr. O'Leary.
- How old are you, son?
- Old enough to vote. Why?
I was just thinking,
you've come along mighty fast.
When I was your age,
do you know what I was doing?
I was rounding up runaway slaves
and practically starving to death.
- Sit down, Gil.
- Take it from me, times have changed.
- Everything's youth today.
- Well, you seem to have done pretty well, Gil.
I've managed, but you've got a great future
ahead of you. Mark my words.
Well, I hope you're right.
I don't blame you for taking Belle.
She's a great woman.
I'd have married her if I'd had the chance,
but she never cared for me.
- It was just a business deal,
and you outbid me.
- What's on your mind?
What would you say, son, if I told you
I was gonna close The Hub, quit?
I'd say you were up to something.
What is it?
I'm thinking of
running for mayor.
Mayor?
I've been electing them
long enough.
Now I'm going to elect myself,
if you'll ride along with me.
- How do I come in?
- You're a smart young fella.
If you watch your step, you're going
to be a big power in this town.
I could build a bigger place and give you
trouble, but I've had all I want of this.
- You say the word, and I'm through.
- You close The Hub?
Exactly, and give you
an open field.
Now, we either work together
politically or fight it out.
It's up to you.
It's a nice place you have here,
but, like a tinder box...
touch a match to it, and it'll go off
like a Roman candle.
But what the devil? Chicago is big enough
for both of us and more.
Together we could run
this town and run it right.
You, Belle and me pulling together,
it'd be a lead pipe cinch.
Yeah. Sounds all right.
But naturally there's a little expense
involved, and right now with the...
I took the liberty of bringing
my check for $10,000.
There'll be more between now
and election time.
I think we'll manage
very well, Your Honor.
[Chuckles]
Now I could use that drink
you were talking about.
Come on.
Now, Belle, you've got to come
to my table right now...
and have a bottle
of wine with me.
I'd love to, but you'll have to
excuse me for one minute.
Belle!
Hello. I thought I
saw you come in here.
I was just telling Dion
what a great place you've got.
I never saw you
looking so beautiful.
- I always did say she was the
best looker Chicago ever saw.
- Thanks.
Better watch yourself, son.
I'll get her back if I can.
- But it looks like it won't be to The Hub.
- Gil's closing The Hub for good.
- Really? Why?
- [Band Playing Intro]
There's the music for your song.
Better hurry.
Dion'll tell you
all about it later.
Whew! What a woman.
Yes, that's exactly what
I said the first time I saw her. Remember?
[Singing]
[Continues]
[Men Singing]
- [Continues]
- [No Audible Dialogue]
[Belle Singing]
[Singing Together]
[Ends]
Oh, I'm... Miss Colby,
Miss Fawcett.
- How do you do?
- How do you do? So sorry.
You'll have to excuse Mr. O'Leary
another few minutes. I'll send him back.
- That'll be very sweet of you.
- Thank you.
- Is that the woman?
- Why, yes, I believe so.
She's pretty... in a way.
- Women like her have all
the advantage, don't they?
- All except one.
I wasn't thinking
of marriage.
- So you're taking his money?
- What's the matter with his money?
- The check's good, isn't it?
- You know how he feels about us,
the threats he's made...
I wouldn't worry about
that if I were you.
Ever since I left his place,
he's schemed to get even.
Now he's trying to do it
with your own help.
- He knows that if he's mayor...
- What makes you think he's gonna be mayor?
- But you took his money.
- Sure.
Sure, and I'll vote for him
myself, if necessary...
but I didn't say
how the Patch'll vote.
- Why, that's...
- Politics.
He'd knife me if he could,
and I simply mean to beat him to it.
Why, you dirty dog.
- You love me?
- Certainly not.
Go on. Say it before
I break your back.
Who was that little doll-faced blonde
you were smiling all over yourself about?
Senator's daughter.
I have to be nice to him, don't I?
Why weren't you breathing
down his neck?
Stop it.
You and The Senate
and Warren on the run.
In other words, Mr. O'Leary
is rising in the world.
- Mr. O'Leary and present company.
- [Knocking]
- [Door Opens]
- [Pickle] Chief, Mitch is here.
Come on in
and shut the door.
Is it true that you were caught
registering under a false name?
Gee, chief, how was I to know
that guy was already registered?
I told you this bozo
don't use his head.
Oh, have a brain, you. Getting caught
with an election coming up...
and that reform crowd
already yelling its head off.
It would serve you right
if I let them send you to jail for life...
but, no, I've got to sit through a trial
and figure a way to get you out.
I oughta...
Oh, get out.
Yeah! Come on out!
Now, where were we?
Oh, yes.
- Good morning.
- Everything fixed?
- The district attorney said if you're worried...
he'll let us have witnesses to prove
Mitch hasn't been in Chicago in two years.
That's the kind
of prosecutor I like.
- What'd you give him?
- The usual.
Chief! It ain't fair!
It ain't fair!
- It ain't fair!
- What's the matter?
The district attorney...
and after we had him all fixed.
- What are you talking about?
- Well, he fell down...
and broke his ankle
and he ain't here!
- The fool doesn't know how to walk?
- And the judge appointed...
somebody to take his place
and I don't know who.
- What's this mean?
- It means it ain't fixed.
Oh, come on.
In view of the unavoidable
detention of the district attorney...
the court has appointed
a special counsel...
a representative
of the Election Reform Committee...
in the case of The City
of Chicago v. Edward Mitchell.
Mr. O'Leary, are you
prepared to proceed?
- We're ready, Your Honor.
- Oh, yes.
- Is the defense ready?
- Uh, Your Honor...
Your Honor, certain matters
have come up.
New evidence have been uncovered
that compels me to...
Go ahead with the trial.
- Go ahead?
- Proceed.
The defense is ready,
Your Honor.
You may proceed,
Mr. O'Leary.
Your Honor, it is no secret
that multiple voting...
for years has been
a common practice...
in that section of Chicago
known as the "Patch."
So common, it has come to be regarded
as one of the minor evils...
in that district.
Men who occupy the highest
offices in this city...
openly and brazenly
bid against each other...
for that very vote.
Any mention of it is dismissed
with an indulgent smile...
as something that
should not be talked about.
There are men in this very courtroom,
Your Honor...
who control every election
in this city...
with such illegal votes.
Men who sit in their
fine saloons...
surrounded by every luxury
that money can buy...
or that they can steal...
while public officials bow and smile
before them and fight for their favor.
Until today, nobody has ever obtained
sufficient evidence to convict them.
Now, however, we have
an eyewitness...
who was actually present
when the defendant, Edward Mitchell...
was caught attempting to register
under four different names...
The last time,
as the beloved
Bishop Cornwall himself.
- [Laughter]
- You know, he's really good.
- Some day he'll be a great lawyer.
- I think he's all right now.
Mr. Clerk, call Carrie Donohue
to the stand.
Carrie Donohue
take the stand.
- She can't do this to me.
- Shh! Quiet!
Stand up. Raise your
right hand.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth and nothing but the truth...
- so help you God? What's your name?
- I do.
- Carrie Donohue.
- Sit down.
- Miss Donohue, you know this defendant?
- Do I know him?
- Hmph! That big squirt.
- None of that now.
- I'll haul off...
- Quiet!
- [Laughter]
- [Clerk] Order in the court.
- Refrain from personal remarks.
Tell the court what you know
about this man's registration.
- Well, my gentleman friend's...
- Face the judge.
hired to watch the registration
and I'm keeping him company...
when this big squirt
walks in.
- [Laughter]
- Well, he don't see me
and I don't say anything...
but when he keeps comin' back,
I get suspicious...
and I'm just about to tell my friend
that something funny's going on...
when, sure enough,
back he comes again...
and, this time,
he says he's a bishop.
- Well, that's too much even for me.
- [Laughter]
- [Banging Gavel]
- [Clerk] Order in the court.
- That's what you get for marrying 'em.
- You married to this woman?
- What?
- Can you imagine it?
- Ever divorce her?
- No!
- Your Honor!
May it please the court,
we ask that this woman's testimony...
be stricken
from the records...
and this case dismissed
on the grounds that the law says...
a wife cannot testify
against her husband!
- That woman is my client's
lawful-wedded spouse.!
- Madam, is this true?
- [Crowd Murmuring]
- Well, I married him once,
if that's what you mean...
- but I can tell you...
- That will do.
- Well, I mean that he...
Well. Hmph.
Mr. O'Leary,
you distinctly told me...
that you had had time to familiarize
yourself with all the facts in the case...
and, yet, you take up this court's time
allowing your only witness...
to testify, although
she's clearly unqualified.
Your Honor, I assure you, this is
as much a surprise to me as it is to you.
I ask the court's pardon.
Case dismissed.
- Tough break, kid.
- Yeah.
- Congratulations.
- Aw, you can never
tell about these women.
They'll put it over on you every time,
if they can...
but you were great yourself,
I was proud of you.
Wait'll I go after the big fish,
the higher-ups...
- then you'll really hear something.
- That's the way to talk.
- How about meeting Belle?
- It's about time.
Belle, this is brother Jack.
Jack, Miss Fawcett.
- How do you do?
- I've been looking forward
to this for a long time.
- You have?
- Yes.
Dion isn't the only admirer
of beauty in the family.
- [Laughs]
- Thank you.
- That was a very nice thing to say.
- I couldn't help...
but look at you
all through the trial.
- Maybe that's why you lost your case.
- [Laughs]
- Uh, can we drop you someplace?
- Oh, no. No thanks.
I've, uh... I've got some things
to do here in the building.
You know, it seemed kind of funny,
you and Dion on one side...
and me on the other,
fighting each other.
[Laughs]
When we were kids,
we were always fighting.
I bet if any other Irishers tried
to horn in...
it was the O'Learys
against the world.
- Oh, you said it.
- You two must've had fun
when you were little.
- We still do.
- Even though we don't
always see eye-to-eye.
Well, I've got
to leave you here...
but I'll tell ya what you do,
Miss Fawcett...
- or shall I call you "Belle"?
- Please do.
Let Dion bring you up the house
some time for dinner, meet Ma.
Well, I'd be
delighted.
I wanna show you
some pictures of Dion...
in his First Communion
suit at the age of nine.
And some of you without any suit
at all at the age of six months.
[Laughing]
I wish you'd keep
an eye on this fellow for us.
He's getting up in the world so fast,
it might go to his head.
I'd kind of hate
to have to knock it off.
I'll try.
Good-bye.
See you soon.
Good-bye, Jack.
- You know, I like him.
- They don't make 'em any better.
That was nice of him,
wanting me to meet your mother.
Well, yes. I've been thinking
about that myself.
Oh, don't. I understand how
she feels about me.
Oh, Ma's all right...
A little old-fashioned, perhaps.
Oh, please.
I had no idea he was so...
so human.
Oh, sure.
Takes after me.
You know, there's something
almost normal about him.
He just looks so real, you know
he believes everything he says.
Honestly, it just makes me sick
to think of a man like Gil Warren...
trying to run Chicago when there
are men here like your brother.
Can you imagine the mayor
he'd make if he had the chance?
Well, if he hadn't gotten mixed up
with that reform crowd...
Wait a minute.
- I've got an idea.
- What?
I just thought what do with that check
Gil Warren gave me.
Back to The Senate.
In brief, we've come here
to ask you to run for mayor.
- What?
- We have canvassed the field,
and you're the man we want.
Well, this is all
very flattering, gentlemen.
May I... May I ask
whom you represent?
The respectable
people of Chicago...
citizens who want a new deal
in our city administration.
We're organizing
a reform party.
- I'm not sure I'm the man.
- We're willing to take that chance.
- It's a great opportunity.
- Decent people are waiting
for an honest program.
You'll carry every district, except,
perhaps, Gil Warren's Patch.
I'm not so sure
he won't get that too.
Your brother's influential there.
Surely he'll support you.
I'm afraid you can't
count on my brother.
You see, we O'Learys
are a strange tribe.
- Then we'll win without the Patch.
- Chicago needs you.
- Yes, Mr. O'Leary.
- Will you do it, sir?
Thank you, gentlemen.
I'll run.
[All Voicing Approval]
[Laughing]
What did he say when you suggested
that I would support him?
- He said he's afraid he couldn't figure on you.
- [All Laughing]
Well, at least he's agreed to run.
That's the first step.
What worries me is,
can you control him once he's in?
He's a pretty stubborn
young fellow.
You leave that to me.
We O'Learys are a strange tribe.
- How's that?
- Not bad.
Of course, it doesn't
look much like you.
"Jack O'Leary, candidate for mayor.
Reform ticket."
That's a great thing for Chicago.
I'd like to help.
- You help me?
- Sure. Why not?
If other people say you're good enough
to be mayor, I'm not going to say no.
Of course, I couldn't
support you openly.
You know how I feel
about the Patch.
Oh, of course.
No strings attached.
- The fact you're my brother
wouldn't mean a thing.
- Stop arguing, will you?
If you stood in the way of something
I felt oughta be done...
I'd go after you as fast as I would
after anybody else, maybe faster.
Because I'm in dead earnest. I see Chicago
as a great city people can be proud of.
I'd wipe out
all this mushroom growth...
start all over on a sound basis,
with steel and stone.
You don't have to make
speeches to me, Jack.
I just wanted you
to know where I stand.
- Well, how much do I owe you?
- I'm two games up on you.
Ah. Twenty cents.
What a gambler.
- It's in the blood.
- [Laughing]
Say, why don't you get Belle
and come to the house tonight
and take her and Ma for a drive?
- Ha! You know Ma.
- We'll get a couple of beers under her belt.
Well, heaven help us
if it doesn't work out.
[All Singing]
[Continues]
[Ends]
[All Laughing]
- To His Honor, the future mayor.
- To Chicago!
And to herself,
the first lady of the city!
Oh, to the lot of you!
- The compliments
of the season to you, ma'am.
- Oh, go on. More presents.
You should see the grand house
we're gettin' for you. Inside plumbing.
- And a butler in short pants.
- Heaven help me.
It's himself.
- Pa.!
- It looks just like him.
- Sure got my nose.
- [Laughs]
I can remember the day we took it
like it was yesterday...
and the trouble we had
puttin' the collar on him.
- Well, Ma, where are we gonna hang him?
- Hang him?
You'll do no such. He's gonna
spend the rest
of his days on this organ.
- [All Laughing]
- If he only could have seen it himself.
Isn't he beautiful?
I want the baby to see it.
[Coos]
Look, that's
your grandpa.
Aw, Pat,
would you believe it?
And Bob
just a baby himself.
If you turn out half as good as the blood
that's in you, I'll not complain.
You know, Ma,
it looks like Pa had...
sort of a roving eye
for the ladies.
I'll thank you to keep
a civil tongue in your head.
Roving eye, ha!
I'd like to catch him.
- [Blubbering]
- Look.
You're so good to me, the lot of you.
You'll have me in tears.
- Oh, Ma. Beer always did make you cry.
- Listen to him.
We'll play him a tune,
his favorite one.
- Come on, Ma, and play it.
- Come on, the four of you.
We'll show him a thing or two.
The O'Learys against the world.
- [Together]
The O'Learys against the world!
- We will. Come on, Ma.
[Laughing]
[Irish Jig]
You should've seen your father dance,
as light as a canary...
and stealing a kiss
before you could shut your eyes.
And the fair Molly Callahan
loving it, I'm thinking.
And why shouldn't I
be loving it?
Himself as fine a man as ever stood up
with a girl in front of an altar.
And that's what
you should be doin'.
- That's what I was telling him today.
- Is it herself, you mean?
I met Miss Fawcett. She's a fine woman.
You oughta know her.
Hmm. I will not. And her workin'
in a saloon like any hussy.
- Oh, that's not fair, Ma.
We're living in modern times.
- That's right.
Don't forget, things have changed
since you were a girl. This is 1870.
Times may have changed,
but I haven't changed.
And I don't want any daughter-in-law
that's the talk of the town...
and kickin' her heels
in the air for anyone to see.
When you were a little one, no bigger
than that, and me over a tub...
I used to dream of the day when you'd
bring me home a sweet one...
and her all blushes,
and present me with fine grandsons...
as would be like sons
of my own, only sweeter.
It's my own life, Ma.
Who'll have some more beer?
- Me.
- I wouldn't mind another drop.
[Knocking]
Here, Ma.
Put a head on it.
Good evening, Mr. Jack.
Will you tell Mr. Dion his buggy's here?
- Oh, thanks.
- He'll be right out.
Now, Ma, drink your beer and forget
about it, and let's go for a ride, huh?
Oh, sure.
How about it, Ma?
- That I will.
- Oh, fine. I'll get your coat and hat.
Aw, Ma.
There you are.
[Laughs]
Drink it all, Ma.
Come on, Ma.
Now, First Lady, I've got
a real surprise for you...
two of the fastest fillies
you ever sat behind.
Now, close your eyes and get inside.
Close 'em. Up one step. There you go.
Inside. Ma, this is Miss Fawcett.
This is Belle.
- Hmm! So it's a trick.
- No, wait a minute!
You're going to meet Belle, so you
might as well get used to the idea.
- The devil I will. Let me out.
- Ma, you always were so stubborn.
If you don't stop it,
I'll give you the licking of your life.
- Well, you don't think
I'm gonna ride with her!
- Oh, come back here!
- [Shouting]
- Sit down! Driver, drive on! Drive on!
[Molly]
Let me out! Let me out, I say!
- Sit still!
- Let me out! Stop it, I tell you!
I won't be treated
this way!
You Irish lunkhead!
What do you think you're doing?
My son an Irish lunkhead?
How'd you like to be treated?
You with your grand manners.
Just as any woman who's going
to be his wife has a right to be treated.
He'll never marry you. And now,
if you'll stop, I'll be takin' my leave.
- Stop here.
- Whoa!
- Wait. I'll get out.
- You'll do no such.
It's you who'll be saving
the wear and tear of walking.
- Ma.
- Hmm!
How could you?
I'm sorry. I didn't think
Ma would act like that.
Take me home, please.
My friends...
this campaign
has resolved itself...
into one
clear-cut issue.
Shall the Patch
run Chicago...
or shall Chicago
run the Patch?
I promise you
that if I am elected...
the Patch will
either be cleaned up...
or it will be wiped out
like that.
- [Man] Hooray for Gil Warren.!
- [Laughter]
- Who said that?
- Shh, shh.
- Oh, it's a shame.
- The trouble with him is
he looks too honest.
People never trust
an honest man in office.
Well, I wish
he hadn't tried it.
He'll never beat Warren.
Never say never
about politics.
What are you up to now?
Well, I was just wondering
what would happen...
if all Gil Warren's ward heelers
and poll watchers and repeaters...
failed to show up
on Election Day.
- What do you mean?
- He wouldn't stand much chance
of being elected, would he?
George, drive
to Commissioner Beavers'.
Gil Warren's my friend.
I won't do it. I can't.
I won't do it! I can't!
I'll be ruined forever.
For doing your duty? Oh, come, come,
Commissioner. Be a man.
He'll kill me.
Besides, what you're asking is against
the law, against all my principles.
You've been getting $100 a week
for doing what I tell you.
Every cent I got
was in cash.
Sure, I paid you in cash, but I always
sent it by a different man.
What? What do you mean?
Those 15 or 20 people would make fine
witnesses if you ever got any ideas.
Blackmail, eh?
All right. I'll fight.
Go ahead. Fight.
And you'll be back pounding
the pavement so quick,
it'll make your head swim.
Come on.
He'll be there.
[Band]
[Crowd Cheering]
[Quiet Chattering]
Hey, you!
Where's your ticket?
- I'm with him.
- You know this guy?
- I never saw him before in my life.
- One of us is in error.
Outside, before I cloud up
and rain all over you.
- That severs our relationship.
- One of them Reform guys.
They got no manners.
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Band Playing Waltz]
Belle, when you were working
for me at The Hub...
I bet you didn't think you'd be having the
first dance with the future mayor, did you?
Are you counting your chickens
before they're hatched?
- [Laughing] It's a lead pipe cinch.
- Oh.
[Horse Neighing]
You looking for me,
Commissioner?
Hey, look what you done
to my suit!
[Both Yelling]
- Hey, what's the idea?
- Stop it!
Stop them, somebody.!
Stop them, somebody.! Stop them.!
[Yelling Continues]
[Blowing Whistle]
Ladies and gentlemen!
The house is pinched!
Stay back!
Get back!
You can't get out this way.
Can you beat that? And just when
we were beginning to have a little fun.
You let me catch you with that Colby
woman again, and you won't call it fun.
Come on, come on.
Inside. Inside.
[Yelling Continues]
All right,
take it away.
[Bell Ringing]
[Shouting]
- What about it, chief?
- Yes, what about it?
It's all right, boys. It's all right.
You haven't got a thing to worry about.
I'll have you out of here
in no time at all.
- What about the bail?
- If it's bail they want, I've got it!
Better hurry, chief.
The polls are open already.
Don't worry. You'll be at your posts
in 30 minutes. All right. What's the bail?
Sorry, Mr. Warren. Orders are to hold them
24 hours without bail...
- On suspicion.
- What kind of suspicion?
- Suspicion of what?
- Just plain suspicion.
You can't do that. This is Election Day.
They're my workers.
By the Eternal,
you've got to let them go!
- It ain't up to me.
- I'll get the commissioner!
I'll get Senator Colby!
I'll get my lawyer!
I'll tear this town wide open!
[Shouting]
- Where's Commissioner Beavers?
- Gone to the sanitarium.
- What sanitarium?
- I'm not allowed to give out his address.
Doctor's orders.
- Where's Judge Bender?
- Oh, the jud-jud-judge...
- I've got to see Judge Bender!
- Judge Bender left...
on a h-hunting trip
this m-morning.
All the jud-judges
in town went with him.
They're o-organizing
a h-hunting club.
- Then I've got to see Senator Colby.
- I'm afraid that's imposs...
You can't do it.
See, S-Senator Colby...
It's 12:00! The polls have been opened
six hours, and I'm tied hand and foot!
Every man in that jail controls at least
10 votes, enough to swing the election.
- What are we gonna do?
- We're gonna stop squawking.
- What's that?
- You're through. I've sold you out.
Don't try anything, Warren.
And now, if you'll excuse me,
I'll go and vote for my brother.
We O'Learys
are a strange tribe.
["When Johnny Comes
Marching Home Again"]
Look at him. You know,
he really looks like a mayor.
Gee, I bet Ma feels great.
[Song Ends]
[Irish Jig]
[Singing]
- [Continues]
- Dion, look at this!
Huh.
Huh, indeed.
Belle, we're friends,
aren't we?
I hope so.
I've got a proposition
to put up to you.
It may startle you at first,
but I think you'll see my point.
I'm gonna clean out the Patch. I want
to be sure Dion doesn't oppose me.
- And you want me to help you?
- Exactly.
But after all,
what has it to do with me?
You know how things
are down there.
Everything that's rotten in
Chicago comes out of the Patch.
The whole thing is an atmosphere
of vice and crime.
It's getting out of control,
and I'm gonna wipe it out.
How?
The law gives us the right
to condemn property.
The courts will have it
appraised and set a fair price.
It's what they call the right of eminent
domain. It's perfectly legal and fair.
But all of Dion's money
is tied up in The Senate. Mine too.
That's what's worrying me.
If he won't see it our way,
there'll be trouble.
I don't know what to say.
Dion's a great person.
He can go anywhere, do anything...
if he only gets
on the right track.
Belle, I want
to see him marry you...
have a home and children,
get something real out of life.
Don't you think that's
what I've been hoping for?
That's what he wants too,
if he can only see it.
What do you want me to do?
He couldn't stand
a public investigation.
You know how he operates
in the Patch.
I couldn't do
a thing like that.
Believe me, Belle...
if I can't bring him
to his senses any other way...
I'll start an investigation
that'll crack this town wide open.
I'll use you
as chief witness against Dion...
let you tell the whole rotten story
of how he operates in the Patch.
How do you feel
about that, Belle?
I just wanted Belle
to understand my position...
same as I want you
to understand it.
- Dion, listen to Jack.
- I heard him. I know now where he stands.
You knew exactly where
I stood before the election.
I told you and I told
the people of this city.
- I elected you, not the people.
- You?
Sure. It was my idea. I sent
that committee to see you.
I paid for it, ran it, framed it,
threw Warren's men into jail.
I even voted for you.
I don't believe you.
Is that true?
- Yes.
- I just wanted it to look hunky-dory.
[Sighs]
Why did you want me
to be mayor?
Oh, a lot of reasons.
I wanted to see if I could do it.
Or maybe it was because I wanted
to see the smile on Ma's face...
when she rode with you
in the carriage election night.
All right. You elected me,
but I'm mayor.
Yes, you're mayor,
but I'm Chicago.
I'd hate to
have to kick you out.
Don't try it. A lot of people
like what I'm doing.
- What are you going to get out of this?
- Nothing.
But I happen to have sense
enough to see what Jack's
after, even if you haven't.
- Now, wait a minute. Don't you two start...
- You keep out of this!
Well, of course,
since you've gone for Reform...
I guess we won't be seeing
very much of each other.
You're not gonna walk out
on Belle like that.
It seems that she's the one
that's done the walking out.
Dion. Dion!
Oh!
A grand jury investigation.!
Terrible.! Terrible.!
How did you ever get involved
in such a mess?
I wouldn't be a bit surprised
if you weren't...
in for a bit of sweatin'
yourself, Senator.
You've been milkin' the Patch
for a long time.
Me? Why I'll give you to understand, sir,
that my life is an open book.
Open or shut, brother, your shirttail's
out with the rest of us.
It's my daughter
I'm thinking of.
I'll have to take her to Europe,
get her away from here.
- The trip would do her good.
- I'll have to ask you...
not to see my daughter
again ever.
- To think I should be so
deceived in the character...
- I've always wanted to see...
what a senator looks like...
when he gets a good,
swift kick in the pants.
- Oh, Hattie, hurry, will you?
- I'm hurrying, honey.
Miss Belle,
you want this old plush?
Yes. No. Throw it away.
I don't care what you do with it.
Oh, this just fits
in my trunk.
Now, Miss Belle, ain't a bit of use
in you carryin' on like this.
- Ain't no man worth it!
- Oh, Hattie, hurry, will you?
I'm hurryin', honey.
- Get out of here!
- I'm gettin' out, honey.
- Belle, don't act like that.
- [Hattie Screaming]
- Belle, I want to talk to you.
- Hattie, get out of the way!
- [Hattie Screaming]
- Get him away from me!
- Get out of here, white man!
[All Screaming]
- Hattie, help me! Help me!
- Murder! Police! Help!
- Get out!
- Belle, please.
I'm sorry,
but I had to come.
Just let me say one thing,
then you can put me out. I won't care.
- Oh, please go.
- I don't ask you to forgive me.
I've said and done things
no woman could ever forgive.
But you've got to believe
I love you, Belle.
I always have
and I always will.
Oh, why talk about it?
But you said you loved me.
That's over.
You can't change in a moment
any more than I can.
We can't do
without each other.
I can.
I'll make myself.
Oh, we've fought, and maybe we'll
go on fighting, but we'll do it together.
We were meant
for each other.
Belle, marry me.
Now. Tonight.
I've got the license
and the ring.
We'll go to Jack,
have him marry us.
Will you, Belle?
Oh, my darling!
Come on, Mr. Policeman.
Right in here. She...
She's done
backslid again.
Do you realize that 75%
of the buildings in the Patch...
are made of pine?
There are no sewers,
no hydrants.
Nothing but filth, cesspools.
But worst of all,
it is a veritable firetrap.
Now, that sort of thing
may have been excusable when
Chicago was just beginning...
but that time has passed.
Today it's a menace
to a great city...
a cancer
that must be cut out.
Now, I propose to condemn
the whole district...
wipe it out
and start all over again.
- Yes, what is it?
- [Whispering]
Tell him
I'll be right out.
Will, uh, you gentlemen
go ahead with the discussion...
and excuse me
for a little while, please?
Yes, Mr. Mayor.
Well, Jack, you've won.
- I've won what?
- I've been a fool.
I wouldn't take a million
for this moment.
Now it's really the O'Learys
against the world.
Well, here's the little
lady who's responsible.
As if I didn't know it.
As the mayor of this great and noble city,
can you marry people?
Marry?
Why, sure!
Wait a minute.
I'm not so sure.
- But I'll find out.
- [Rings Bell]
What a mayor.
Is there anything in the charter
about whether the mayor
can perform a marriage?
- I don't know, sir, but I'll find out.
- Hurry up and find out!
"Having taken these pledges
of your affection and vows of fidelity...
"I do, therefore, by right of
the authority in me vested...
"by the laws
of the state of Illinois...
"pronounce you,
Dion Patrick O'Leary...
"and you,
Belle Catherine Fawcett...
lawfully married,
husband and wife."
That makes us
kissing kin, doesn't it?
- I don't have to tell you how lucky you are.
- That's right.
- I just want to say congratulations.
- Thank you.
I wish you every happiness
and... good night.
Congratulations.
Good night.
You'll never know
how much all this means to me.
Remember that day
I told you he wasn't so bad?
The O'Learys
are a strange tribe.
Right.
[Laughing]
Now, let's go home
and tell Ma, huh?
Sure, but first there's just one
little matter I'd like to clear up.
And now, Mrs. O'Leary, suppose
you go ahead and testify against me?
[Laughing]
Listen to him.
You didn't think I was gonna
let you two get away with it, did you?
- Why, Dion!
- Go ahead with your grand jury investigation.
She's my wife,
and you know the law...
A wife cannot testify
against her husband. [Snickering]
Oh!
Belle, where
are you going?
[Laughing]
What do you think of that?
Why, you dirty...
I haven't licked you
since we were kids.
[Grunting]
[Sighs]
Of all the low, disgusting tricks
you ever pulled, this is the worst.
Well, you won't
get away with it.
I'm gonna wipe out the Patch
and you along with it!
- Johnson!
- Yes, sir. I've sent for the police.
I don't want the police!
Get the city attorney!
Tell him to start
the condemnation proceedings.
And you get out of here! I never
want to see your face again!
Get the police commissioner.
Tell him to swear in 500 special deputies.
Get the newspapers. Tell them that when
I get through with the Patch...
- there won't be a stick
or stone left standing.
- Yes, sir.
Hey, one at a time.
Quit that nudging.
You'd think you
never been fed before.
You're so full already, you oughta be
sleepin' it off on the parlor sofa.
Mutter, Mutter,
komm schnell!
Stop that heathen
jabbering and talk sense!
Dion, Jack, they fight!
Bitte, Mutter, komm.!
The devil you say!
You can take one more nip
while I'm knockin' their heads together.
- Dion married Belle Fawcett.
- What?
Yeah, Jim Fellows
just came by to tell us.
Dion and Jack have had
a knock-down, drag-out fight
about the Patch.
- And them grown-up and brothers.
- I'm gonna find 'em.
Wait. I'll go with you. And wait till I get
my hands on that Dion...
fightin' and marryin'
that creature behind my back.
Mrs. O'Leary!
Oh, Mrs. O'Leary!
Your barn! Look! Look!
I didn't put the bar
between Daisy's legs.
Fire! Fire!
Get Daisy and the calf
and the horse!
Get that baby
back into the house!
Fire! Turn the alarm!
[Shouting Continues]
[Bell Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
- Fire!
- [Men Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
- [Shouting Continues]
- Come on, boys!
Never mind the barn!
Let it go!
Save the house!
The house!
Mrs. O'Leary, I'm gettin' out
everything that I can.
Mrs. Donovan, your
own house is a-goin'!
Me own house? Mrs. O'Leary,
me own house is a-burnin'!
[Woman Screaming]
[Bell Ringing]
[Shouting Continues]
[Woman Screaming]
- Get that cow!
- Come on, Daisy! Come on!
[Shouting Continues]
[Man]
Get a hose over here.!
Come on.!
[Shouting Continues]
Giddyap.
- Chief!
- Dion!
Here I am, Pickle!
Dion, oh, Dion!
- What's the matter?
- There's a big fire in the Patch!
- Yeah? Where?
- DeKoven Street. The whole street's goin'!
You suppose that's
some of the mayor's doings?
Sure. The mayor's
burning us out.
- He said he'd get us.
- Said he wouldn't leave
a stick or a stone standing.
- Looks bad, boy.
- Yeah, burning us out, huh?
- Couldn't even wait
for condemnation proceedings.
- I'll go with you.
No, you stay here.
I've gotta find out how Ma is.
Give the boys a drink.
I'll be back in half an hour.
He's asked for a fight.
Well, I'll give it to him.
Well, what'll
you fellas have?
- I'll take some of this.
- Mighty funny business.
- What?
- Well, I'm not saying anything...
but I haven't got much faith in these fights
between brothers...
not when they're O'Learys.
They've pulled some pretty
smart tricks in the past...
and I wouldn't put it
past 'em to do it again.
You heard what Dion said!
No one's gonna burn him out,
brother or no brother.
Well, I hope not. When I was running things,
nothing like this happened.
- Hmm! Come on, fellas.
- All right, boys. You heard what he said.
Spread the word. We'll have
something to say about bein'
run out of the Patch.
Wait a minute.
Get the boys together.
- Tell them that I said
we'll meet at the armory.
- We'll get this Jack O'Leary!
[Bells Continue Ringing]
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
Back up! Back up!
I've gotta get through! Back up!
Here, I think I can make
better time on foot.
[Shouting Continues]
[Steam Whistles Blowing]
All right, boys!
Put her on the other roof!
- Mommy!
Mommy!
Mary!
[Steam Whistles Continue]
All right, boys, pump!
[Woman Screaming]
It's moving might fast in this wind,
leaping ahead blocks at a time.
The Patch is like tinder.
There hasn't been a drop of rain
for nearly three months.
We've got to keep it away from the gas works.
We gotta keep it south of the river.
Have you any suggestions,
General Sheridan?
Yes. Make a firebreak
at the edge of the Patch.
Blow up that entire section
along Randolph Street.
- Fight this fire with dynamite!
- I authorize you to do everything
possible to stop this fire.
Commissioner,
mobilize your whole force.
Swear in as many deputies as you need.
Clear that whole area.
- Requisition all the foodstuffs you need.
- Yes, sir.
Donovan, you and Johnson
get in touch with Milwaukee,
all the surrounding cities.
Ask them to send us
all the fire apparatus they can.
Wire Washington. Tell them
we're gonna need relief...
money, medicine, troops.
- Keep me advised.
I'll be with Gen. Sheridan.
- Yes, sir.
[Steam Whistles Continue]
Miss Belle,
pull yourself together!
Come on, honey. Let's get outta here.
Come on, baby.
Pull yourself together. Let's get out
of here before judgment day gets us.
- Come on, honey. Come on.
- [Steam Whistle Blowing]
Bob! Bob!
Where's Ma?
She's gone to the North Side with Gretchen
and the baby in the wagon.
They had to go. Our house
was the first to burn.
- Our house? Why, that dirty...
Where did they start it?
- In our barn.
Ma heard about you fighting,
she left the lantern in there
and Daisy kicked it over.
I thought Jack did it
to burn out the Patch.
That mob thinks so too.
We gotta get to him.
- Well, where is he?
- I don't know, but we've gotta stop that mob.
[Shouting Continues]
- Back up, I tell you!
- How can I back up?
Why can't you look
where you're going?
Get that flea-bitten
thing out of here!
[Shouting Continues]
[Horses Neighing]
Come, darling, get out.
We have to walk.
Wait! I'll just
be gettin' it.
[Speaking German]
I'll not be leavin' his picture.
It's all I've got left.
That fool cow!
- [Explosion]
- Look out! The wall! It's falling!
Mutter.!
- Gretchen! Gretchen!
- Mutter.!
Gretchen!
Don't waste any time.
Get those people behind the line.
- Captain!
- Yes, sir?
Take all of your men you can spare.
Use some of mine if necessary.
Search every building. See that no one
is left behind. No one! Quickly!
Yes, sir.
Sergeant, move all police lines back
one full block and let no one through!
Hey, where are you going?
- I've got to get through to The Senate.
- Nobody's going through.
Mayor's orders. The streets cleared.
They're gonna dynamite.
- Dynamite?
- Yeah, to make a firebreak.
Come on, open up! Get back!
Back to the next corner!
- Come on. Back to the next block.
- What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Jack! Jack!
Get back! Come on!
- I've gotta get through.!
- Jack! Jack, I...
Turn him loose.
I'll take care of him.
Get away from here,
you dirty, contemptible liar.
I've stood for all
I'm gonna stand from you.
I've got work to do,
and nobody is gonna stop me.!
You've got to listen to me! Gil Warren
and his mob are out to get you!
Everybody down here thinks
you set fire to the Patch.
They're organizing against you.
It's my fault.
I thought so too.
- You lowdown, good-for-nothing...
- Jack!
Until I got home and found the house
burned to the ground...
- Ma, Gretchen and the baby gone.
- Where are they?
I put 'em in a wagon and started them
for the North Side.
They oughta be
across the river by now.
I'm sorry. I should have known better.
Jack, you've got to believe me.
There's Gil Warren
and his gang now.
What the devil do I care
about Warren and his gang now?
The only thing that matters is that
we're together and thinking alike. Come on!
There they are, men!
Just like I told you.
The O'Learys.
The three of'em together.
You men, hold that line!
Don't let anybody through.
Keep those people back. I don't care
how you do it, but keep them back!
[Man]
Right.
Men! Listen!
Listen, men!
The fire was an accident. My brother
didn't have anything to do with it.
That's what you say,
but we know different.
We've got to dynamite.
It's our only chance to save Chicago!
- Let it burn.!
- [Man Agreeing]
Men! Men! Think!
That's just what we're doing. Thinking.
Thinking it's another O'Leary trick.
[Men Agreeing]
- Mayor O'Leary.!
- Yes, General?
Have your men move this crowd
back to the end of that street.
- The dynamite is set. We're ready to light.
- All right, move that crowd!
Push them back!
Get 'em back!
Oh, no, you don't! We're not moving!
No one's running us out.
We got rights too,
and we know where we stand.
You're not gonna blow us up.
You don't dare.
We're not gonna let 'em destroy
our homes to save their own.
We're staying right here.
We'll show 'em who they're dealing with.
They don't own Chicago.
They're... What?
Hey.! Look.! Look.!
Stop him, somebody.!
[Shouting Continues]
Dion! Dion!
Don't move an inch, men.
We've got our rights.
- Dion!
- Jack, light 'em. Light 'em!
- You're hurt.
- It's just a scratch.
Get back, you fools!
All of you! And keep back!
Light 'em.
[Shouting Continues]
Dion! Dion!
[Officer]
Get back, and keep back.!
Get him, Rondo.!
Rondo, get him.!
- Get him, Rondo.!
- [Gunshot]
[Shouting Continues]
Get those fuses out.!
Pull 'em down.! Pull 'em down.!
[Shouting Continues]
[Man]
Get 'em down.!
We're too late! We're too late!
Run for your lives, men!
- We can't put 'em out.!
- Run for your lives!
Where's Jack?
Jack!
[Cattle Lowing]
[Lowing Continues]
Open up!
Help! Help! Help!
- [Crowd Screaming]
- On to the lake, folks!
[Steam Whistles Continue]
[Whistle Blowing]
Cast off! Let go of that forward line
and get this boat away from here!
There's 10,000 barrels
of kerosene in that warehouse.
If this boat catches fire,
the warehouse is sure to go...
and we'll take
the whole North Side with us!
[Whistle Continues]
[Indistinct Shouting]
Try to get through
to the North Side!
On to the lake.!
[Gretchen]
Bob.! Bob.! Bob.!
That's Gretchen!
- Bob!
- Gretchen.!
Bob!
Gretchen!
- Bob.!
- Gretchen!
Bob! Bob!
Gretchen!
Take your foot
off that picture! Oh!
Mrs. O'Leary! I thought I saw you.
Lean on me.
- Go on. Save yourself.
- Please, Mrs. O'Leary.
- Oh, it's you.
- Give me your arm.
- I will not.
- You'll be killed!
I'll not be owing
my life to you!
Hattie! Hattie!
Hattie!
Come on.
Get up, please.
Please. Come on.
Come on.
- Go on and save yourself.
- I won't leave you. Hattie! Hattie!
- You married him.
- Hattie!
I married him,
but it's all over now.
He only married me
to save the Patch.
You're lyin'. He loves you, and you turned
him against his own people.
- He doesn't love me.
- But you love him.
- Hattie!
- [Explosion]
Yes. Yes, I love him.
- Try, Mrs. O'Leary.
- I can't do it.
- Please.
- No, it's no use. I'm done for.
Please help me.
Please help me,
won't you?
Won't you, please?
[Shouting Continues]
[Steam Whistles Continue]
[Baby Crying]
Dion, any
word of them?
No. No, I've been
all over the North Shore.
There's not
a trace of them.
You stay with Gretchen.
I'll look.
No. I'm gonna try
the South Shore.
[Explosions Continue]
Mommy!
Mommy.!
Mommy.! Mommy.!
[Steam Whistles Continue]
Ma. Ma!
Ma! Ma!
Heaven be praised!
It's Dion! Oh, Dion!
- Oh, Ma!
- Dion!
- Oh, Dion, Dion!
- Ma!
- Are you hurt?
Come on. Come on up
out of the wet.
- Oh, my child.
- Ma.
Where are the others?
Bob and Gretchen
and the baby are all right.
And Jack?
Oh, Ma.
He's dead?
- Did you make it up with him?
- Yes.
Then I'll not be weepin'.
It's the livin'
that need lookin' after.
Belle...
- Belle?
- What kind of a woman are you...
with that kind of a heart
and him your husband?
It's gone, and
my boy's gone with it.
But what he stood for
will never die.
It was a city of wood,
and now it's ashes.
But out of the fire
will be coming steel.
You didn't live
to see it, my lad...
no more than your
father did before you.
God rest the two of you.
But there's Dion left,
and his children to come after.
He'll have his dream, Ma.
Nothing can lick Chicago,
any more than it could lick him.
Aye. That's the truth.
We O'Learys
are a strange tribe.
There's strength in us.
And what we set out to do,
we finish.