♪♪ Turtles ♪♪
♪♪ berries ♪♪
♪♪ gumbo ♪♪
♪♪ turtles ♪♪
♪♪ sweet old turtles ♪♪
♪♪ I've got turtles ♪♪
♪♪ for you ladies ♪♪
♪♪ I've got berries
nice and fine ♪♪
♪♪ I just took 'em
from the vine ♪♪
♪♪ took me about
1,000 trips ♪♪
♪♪ but none are sweet ♪♪
♪♪ as your lips ♪♪
♪♪ I've got gumbo
steaming hot ♪♪
♪♪ and it comes
straight from the pot ♪♪
♪♪ I cooked and stirred it
all the day ♪♪
♪♪ for you pretty girls ♪♪
♪♪ to take away ♪♪
♪♪ turtles ♪♪
♪♪ berries ♪♪
♪♪ gumbo ♪♪
♪♪ crawfish ♪♪
♪♪ fresh and ready, too ♪♪
♪♪ well, I went to the bayou ♪♪
♪♪ just last night ♪♪
♪♪ there was no moon ♪♪
♪♪ but the stars were bright ♪♪
♪♪ put a big, long hook ♪♪
♪♪ on a big, long pole ♪♪
♪♪ and I pulled Mr. crawfish
out of his hole ♪♪
♪♪ crawfish ♪♪
♪♪ see, I got 'em ♪♪
♪♪ see the size ♪♪
♪♪ stripped and cleaned ♪♪
♪♪ before your eyes ♪♪
♪♪ sweet meat, look ♪♪
♪
♪♪ fresh and ready to cook ♪
♪♪ crawfish ♪♪
Woman: ♪♪ crawfish ♪♪
♪♪ now take Mr. crawfish
in your hand ♪♪
♪♪ he's gonna look good
in your frying pan ♪♪
♪♪ if you fry him crisp ♪♪
♪♪ or you boil him right ♪♪
♪♪ he'll be sweeter than sugar
with every bite ♪♪
♪♪ crawfish ♪♪
♪♪ see, I got 'em ♪♪
♪♪ see the size ♪♪
♪♪ stripped and cleaned
before your eyes ♪♪
♪♪ sweet meat, look ♪♪
♪♪ fresh and ready
to cook ♪♪
♪♪ crawfish ♪♪
♪♪ see, I got 'em ♪♪
♪♪ see the size ♪♪
Sailor: Next week, baby.
Hey!
Songbird, you come
here tonight,
and I'll dance
with you free.
Oh, no, you don't.
You gotta pay me.
Danny, come on.
Your breakfast.
Come on.
Don't let pop catch you
talking to that.
Why not?
I'm just being neighborly,
and he picked
the neighborhood.
Oh, why don't you
lay off?
He went broke.
The neighborhood
picked him.
Sit down and eat
your breakfast.
Boy, it sure don't feel
like the last day of school.
Everything's so quiet
just like any other day.
What were you expecting,
a 21-gun salute?
Why not?
I mean, at 3:00,
it's all over.
Don't that make it
kind of special?
Tomorrow they call my name
and give me a piece of paper.
It's for sure,
isn't it, Danny?
I mean, this time, huh?
Sure, kid. I'm a cinch.
You said that
last year.
Pop went out and
bought all this junk
for a graduation
party,
and then there was
no graduation.
That old Mrs. Pearson,
she's the one that flunked me,
and she'd have done it
again this year,
but I showed her.
I showed the old man, too.
He's been waiting a whole
year to have this party.
Now he can stop
bugging me about it.
He doesn't mean
to bug you, Danny.
He wants to be
proud of you.
Sure.
I've been thinking a lot
about the old house, Mimi,
and about mom.
I wish she could be here
tomorrow for the graduation.
I really miss her.
I miss her, too.
He misses her the most.
It's a terrible thing to
lean on someone so hard,
you don't know
you're leaning.
Never finding out
until the day she
isn't there anymore.
It's been like stumbling
around in the dark
for him ever since.
When he sits there and
watches you graduate,
he'll have eyes again
for the first time
in 3 years.
Well, then I'd better hurry.
Got a whole day's work
ahead of me
between now
and miss Pearson.
How do you think that's
been eating at him, huh?
You working in a joint
like the blue shade?
One man in the family's
gotta have a job.
What's the difference
where you sweep up?
It all looks the same
on a garbage truck.
Danny, you got pa
all wrong.
Yeah, me and the world.
Now, look, sis, what
are we fighting for?
It's the last day
of school, okay?
Yeah.
Bye.
Morning, Chico.
Hi, Danny.
Who's that?
Oh, some of
Maxie's friends.
They've been here
all night.
I couldn't
get rid of 'em.
Try to work around
'em, will you?
See you later.
Okay. See you tonight.
Man: Don't be like that.
Come on, Ronnie,
Maxie said to be nice.
Now be nice, huh?
I am being
nice to you.
I haven't spit in
your eye yet.
That's very funny.
You better do
what Maxie says.
You know, he's
the boss around here.
Hey, kid.
What happened
to the music?
Well, the band
went home.
How about you?
Can you play the piano?
Nah.
Leave him alone.
He's just a busboy.
This joint's got a cabaret
license, ain't it?
I paid my money, and
I want to be entertained.
Come on,
let's dance, honey.
That's enough
entertainment
till the real thing
comes along.
The band
went home.
That's all right.
Busboy here will
sing us a song.
Hey, come on, kid.
Sing us a song,
and I'll buy you
a drink, huh?
Aw, look, mister,
I got work to do.
I've gotta stack the chairs
and sweep up.
I appreciate your offer,
but I'll be late for school.
School?
The kid goes to school.
Ain't that nice?
I went to school once.
Bartender's school.
Hey, Ronnie,
you ever go to school?
Huh? I said, you ever
go to school?
Wake up, stupid,
I'm talking to you.
No, they never had
to give you lessons.
Why, you--
Look out! Let go
of me, will you?
Forget it.
Okay, okay, take it easy.
I'll sing.
Did you hear that, Ralph?
The kid is gonna sing.
Don't ever try
that again, huh?
All right, what are
you gonna sing?
Sing your school song.
You gotta have
a school song.
An Alma mater.
You know,
the one with the words
about loyal and true.
Well, you heard
the lady.
Go ahead.
♪♪ Farewell ♪♪
♪♪ royal high school ♪♪
♪♪ we'll remember you ♪♪
♪♪ dear Alma mater ♪♪
♪♪ we're steadfast,
loyal, and true ♪♪
Come on, kid.
Jazz it up, huh?
♪♪ Farewell,
royal high school ♪♪
♪♪ we'll remember you ♪♪
♪♪ dear Alma mater ♪♪
♪♪ we're steadfast,
loyal, and true ♪♪
That a boy, kid.
That's real nice,
kid, real nice.
Here.
What do you do
for an encore?
Aw, never mind.
Come on, honey,
let's finish the dance.
We don't need no music.
Stop it!
What do you
think I am?
I know who you are
and what you are.
Come here and be quiet.
You know who
and what, huh?
It's a lifetime
study
to find out
who you are.
To thine own
self be true,
and it follows
as the day...
To thine own
self be true...
If you can
afford it.
If you'll excuse me,
my mother is waiting up
for me with a hot toddy.
Get out of here.
You never
had a mother.
What's with you,
kid?
You looking for
trouble, too?
No. I'm like the lady,
just looking
to get out of here.
Let me go with you.
Okay, get out of here and mind
your own business, huh?
Ronnie: Aah!
Get up!
You're not a baby.
Leave her alone.
Come on.
Get out of here.
Oh, boy.
You're a pretty fancy
performer, ain't you, kid?
Now you know what I do
for an encore.
Go on, get out of here.
Ronnie: Taxi!
Come on, baby,
have a drink, huh?
I guess I'll lose
the job for this.
No, you won't.
They won't tell Maxie.
Maxie doesn't like to have
his merchandise manhandled.
He'll loan me out
for an evening
to be mauled
a little bit,
but when it comes
to a sock in the eye,
that pleasure is for
Maxie Fields alone.
Nice fella.
Maxie?
Yeah.
He wouldn't
like you.
You know why?
Because I like you.
Maxie hates
everything I like.
Maxie's
my benefactor.
He's the circus master,
the cheese,
the big cheese.
Big and green
and moldy.
You've had
too much to drink.
You know it's 8:00
in the morning?
I was supposed to be
home by midnight--
I forget whose--
Or my convertible
turns into a pumpkin.
Maxie turns everything
into a pumpkin.
Danny...
Why don't you
kiss me?
All the wrong
people try to.
Look, we're almost
to the school.
Will you tell me
where you live?
I want to go
to school with you.
I used to love
to go to school.
I was going to be
everything.
A nurse
and a bus driver.
You know what I am?
You're in the circus.
That's right.
I'm in the circus.
I'm going in
and explain everything.
You're going home,
wherever that is.
Danny, Mrs. Pearson
marked you absent.
Well, we'll show Mrs. Pearson
a thing or two.
Hey, where'd you
pick that up?
Aw, go on.
You ever seen anybody
with a few too many?
Go on.
Will you tell the man
where to take you?
I'll be a good girl.
If you'll give me
a good morning kiss,
I'll tell the man
where I live.
[People laughing
and ribbing]
[Whistling and laughing]
Boy: How about
that chick, huh?
Go on.
Hey, Danny,
you're blushing.
[Bell rings]
Man: Just
a second, Danny.
Go ahead,
Mrs. Pearson.
Arriving late
the last day of school,
your mouth all smeared
with lipstick.
How do you explain that,
Mr. Fisher?
Well, I don't know as I can
explain it, Mrs. Pearson.
You see, sir,
this morning I--i went in--
I usually go in
to sweep up, see?
But, uh, uh--
Well--well,
look, honey, I mean--
Mr. Fisher.
I have been instructing
here for some 20 years,
and no one ever
called me honey.
Oh, I believe you.
Mrs. Pearson,
let me talk to the boy.
If you'll
forgive me, sir,
I have talked to
the boy many times,
and to what avail?
On his last day
of school,
in an unprovoked
display of violence,
he attacked
two of his classmates.
The boy has
no conception
of respect
and discipline.
Under
the circumstances,
regretfully, perhaps,
I have no choice.
Mr. Fisher will not
be graduating tomorrow.
Danny, wait a minute.
I'd like to talk to you.
You know I'll have to go
along with her, don't you?
I just want you
to know that I'm sorry.
Well, thanks.
Well, I'll be seeing
you next year.
No, you won't
see me next year.
Now, wait a minute.
Sit down, Danny.
Sit down, I said.
Now, you've just
been told
that you're not
graduating tomorrow.
Doesn't that mean
anything to you?
You said I'm not graduating.
Okay, that's it.
Now what do you want?
I once had a son, Danny.
He lived 13 years.
Some hoodlums jumped him
one night, and he died.
I'm sorry, but what's
that got to do with me?
Because you have all the
earmarks of being a hoodlum.
A hoodlum or a hustler.
Whatever you
want to call it.
This isn't
principal talk.
Well, the more difficult
the student,
the more I try
to lean over backwards.
Listen, Mr. Evans,
we moved into this
neighborhood 3 years ago.
In the 3 years that I've
been going to school here,
I've shined shoes and dusted
people off in a barbershop.
I've done towel duty
in four different men's rooms.
I've stacked chairs and bottles
and swept the floor up
of every joint
on bourbon street.
It's gotten so I look longer
at a dame with clothes on
than one without.
I'm not a hoodlum,
but I am a hustler.
I've had to be for
a very simple reason--
My old man.
You see, sir, my mother
was killed in an accident
about three years ago.
Well, after that,
it might as well have
gotten the old man, too,
because he took himself
right out of the lineup.
He quit cold.
He lost
the drugstore he owned,
he lost the house,
and then finally what few
little jobs he's had since.
You know, maybe I could have
liked school, Mr. Evans,
but every time
I wanted to play ball,
I had to go to work.
Somebody had to.
Anyway, now I'm through.
I'm through.
I wasn't aware that you
worked after school, Danny.
It's not the working
after school, Mr. Evans.
It's the working before.
It's been nice
talking to you.
I'm sorry I said
what I did, Danny.
That's all right.
My life's a long way
from over yet,
and you never know.
You may be right.
That's him.
Excuse me.
You Danny Fisher?
What about it?
Let's take a walk.
Okay, what's the beef?
They call me shark.
This is sal,
and that's dummy.
I--
All right.
Now, you beat up my brother
in school today,
and I believe
in an eye for an eye.
Okay, okay!
You go for the knife,
I'll bash his brains in.
Well, you go
real fast.
All right.
You--you're right
about my brother.
He should learn
a little manners.
So would you like to
hang out with us, huh?
No.
Why not?
Wait a minute.
Wait.
We get money.
Sometimes
we get a lot.
Listen, we got something
cooking for us tomorrow.
If you change your mind,
we'll be right here.
I said no.
[Kicks knife]
Thanks.
Good boy.
Fights real dirty.
Hi.
Well?
What's the matter?
Old lady Pearson
flunked me, Mimi.
I'm not graduating
tomorrow.
Oh, Danny, no.
Oh, Danny, yes.
For the second year
in a row, yes.
If this keeps up much longer,
I'll be a freshman again.
But you could go
back another year.
Yeah? You don't make
money in school, Mimi.
Pop's been fired four times
in the last year,
and he hasn't
got a job now.
You're working,
I'm working,
and from now on,
full-time, kid.
Well, guess
where I've been.
Got a quart
of ice cream here
and this to go with it.
A little special dessert
for the celebration.
Papa, I want
to talk to you.
Good, good, son.
I want to talk to you, too.
Mimi, you're gonna have to do
your listening from the kitchen.
Go on now.
Well, let's see now, son.
Where do I begin?
There's something
I have to tell you, pop,
but you gotta
understand--
Now, now, I don't
gotta nothing, huh?
You gotta, 'cause
I'm older than you.
I go first.
Now, Danny, I made
some notes last year
when you were
supposed to graduate,
and I think I still
have them here.
Yeah, here they are.
That's kind of silly,
isn't it?
A father making notes
on things
that he wants to say
to his own son.
Aw, pop--
Oh, I can--i can really
say it all in one breath.
I'm proud of you, son.
I'm proud of you because
you went back to school.
Pa, there's something
you don't understand.
Don't say it.
Don't even say it.
I know all about it.
Now, Mr. Evans called me
this morning.
I spent all afternoon
with him.
We had a nice
long chat together.
I'm sorry, pop.
Well, I'm sorry,
too, son,
but things are gonna
be different, definitely.
That's why
we're celebrating.
We also had a talk
with that Mrs. Pearson woman.
Now, she said that you could
graduate before next year
if you'd go to night school
and make up your marks
and learned
a little discipline.
No--
So from now on, Danny,
that's the way it's gonna be.
No more working for you.
You'll do
the going to school.
I'll do the going to work.
How many times have we
been through this?
Danny, you've got
to graduate.
You've got to graduate
if you ever want
to take up a profession.
Pa, we've been
all through this.
And I want you
to have a profession.
I don't want you working
on bourbon street
with hoodlums and bums
the rest of your life.
No. A profession
sets a man apart
from the rest
of the world.
Like you?
A registered pharmacist,
and you can't get a job.
You're wrong
about that, Danny.
There was an opening came up
at the regal pharmacy,
and the employment office
is sending me over
to see the manager.
Well, that doesn't mean
you've got the job.
Oh, they'll hire me.
Sure, they will.
They'll hire me,
and I'll keep the job.
Things are gonna be
different.
I'm not going
back to school.
Look, son,
you didn't fail because
your marks were bad.
Mr. Evans said you failed
because of your attitude.
He said anybody
that disagreed with you
got a punch in the mouth.
Is that what I brought
you up to do, to fight?
No, pa, that's not what
you brought me up to do,
but I stopped
listening to you.
I ran out
of other cheeks.
You know, I remember
once, pop,
when I was no more
than three feet high,
you took me
to the circus.
You accidentally
bumped into some guy,
and he turned around
and punched you.
He punched you
right in the mouth,
and you know
what you did?
Nothing.
When they swing
at you, pop,
it's not enough
to duck.
You gotta
swing back.
Maybe you can't
anymore,
but I'm not
taking after you.
You go to school.
I'm going out
and make a buck.
Sal: Yeah, but we can't
count on him.
What good is he, huh?
Collecting money
or something.
That's about all
he can do.
Hi.
Well, well,
now we're somewhere.
I was hoping
you'd show.
You said something
about money.
Funny you should
bring that up.
That's just what
we were talking about.
Do you know that five-and-dime
on Charles street?
Well, we were gonna pull
a phony fight there,
but my brother,
he gave me a better idea.
He told me that you sing
like a bird.
In fact, he says that's
what you're famous for
in that school of yours--
Singing and flunking.
What's singing
got to do with it?
What a cube.
Look, I'm gonna
tell you something.
I ain't never
stole nothing before.
That's all right.
You're not gonna
steal anything now.
All you're
gonna do is sing.
Now here's the plan.
It's that five-and-dime
on Charles street. Now...
[Music playing]
♪♪ Lover doll ♪♪
♪♪ oh, lover doll ♪♪
♪♪ lover doll ♪♪
♪♪ you're the cutest
lover doll ♪♪
♪♪ that I ever did
ever see ♪♪
♪♪ let me tell you,
lover doll ♪♪
♪♪ you were meant,
just meant for me ♪♪
♪♪ from the first time
that I saw you ♪♪
♪♪ how I fell for your
cuddly charms ♪♪
♪♪ lover doll,
I'm crazy for you ♪♪
♪♪ let me rock you
in my arms ♪♪
♪♪ I'm so glad
I found you ♪♪
♪♪ never thought dollies
came full-grown ♪♪
♪♪ I want to tie
a ribbon around you ♪♪
♪♪ wrap you up
and take you home ♪♪
♪♪ I would never
treat you badly ♪♪
♪♪ like a castaway
broken toy ♪♪
♪♪ lover doll,
I love you madly ♪♪
♪♪ let me be
your lover boy ♪♪
♪
♪♪ I'm so glad I found you ♪
♪♪ never thought dollies
came full-grown ♪♪
♪♪ I'm gonna tie
a ribbon around you ♪♪
♪♪ wrap you up
and take you home ♪♪
He sings beautiful,
don't he?
He sure does.
♪♪ Like a castaway
broken toy ♪♪
♪♪ lover doll,
I love you madly ♪♪
♪♪ let me be
your lover boy ♪♪
♪♪ lover doll, lover doll ♪♪
♪♪ let me be
your lover boy ♪♪
♪♪ lover doll, lover doll ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ let me be your lover boy
[applause]
You sing nice.
Thanks.
You were in on it,
weren't you?
In on what?
Could I trouble you
for a glass of water?
Certainly.
Thank you.
What'll you have?
Oh, I'll--I'll--I'll--
Root beer?
Yeah.
My, it's hot
in here, isn't it?
Isn't it?
Don't you think so?
Yeah.
It's always hot
this time of the year.
Oh, my,
that does taste good.
Thank you again.
What's your name?
Nellie.
What time
you get through work?
Why?
Well, I thought
I might meet you.
What do you think I am?
I'd like to find out.
Woman: Mr. mcintyre,
Mr. mcintyre, hurry!
Look at the counter.
Oh, Mr. mcintyre.
You gonna meet me
after work?
I'm through
at 10:00,
so if you're here, I
can't help but see you.
Thanks a lot, kid.
Woman: I don't know
how it happened.
It wasn't my fault.
Look. The watches are gone.
Man: Mr. furst, I'm always
very careful about the accounts,
very particular
about them.
The books
show it clearly.
I'm sure there can't
be any mistake.
Excuse me.
There's a customer.
Anything I can do
for you, sir?
Yes, sir, yes, sir.
I came about the job.
My name is Fisher.
I'm sorry.
That job has been filled.
But the employment
office told me that--
I hired a man yesterday.
But I've got to
have the job.
The agency sent me.
I--i have
my diploma.
See, I'm
a registered pharmacist
with 25 years behind me.
What's the trouble?
Oh, no trouble
at all, Mr. furst.
Just a mistake
about a job.
What's the mistake?
I want a younger man.
He looks
younger than me.
We've had four younger men
in the last three months.
Have you read
this man's credentials?
Is he a good man
or an incompetent man?
How do you tell that,
by looking at his suit?
I'll wait over here.
Give the man
an application.
I don't have
any applications.
Then give him the job.
You start work
tomorrow morning.
Oh, thank you.
[Band playing]
[Whistling and applause]
[Music stops]
[Band starts playing]
Chico, you better start
looking for somebody else.
I don't think I'm gonna
make it at night anymore.
Up to you, Danny-o.
No complaints from this end.
You do your work good.
Yeah, well, the old man
came home with a job today,
and we made kind of a deal.
He goes to work,
and I go to school.
You know how it is.
Not really.
I got an old man,
just give him a jug
of wine, he's happy.
Hey, Danny.
What's the matter--
Trouble?
No. We're gonna divvy up
in the alley later.
That fence give us
over 90 bucks.
What'd I tell you, huh?
Well, hello,
Mr. Fields.
Hiya, kid.
Hello there.
Could I get by,
please?
Don't you, uh...
Hey, you.
That's Maxie Fields.
That's your boss.
Are you crazy?
Hey, Mr. Fields.
How about that, huh?
Who's this guy,
Ronnie?
The king of yugoslavia.
How should I know?
Take your hand off
my arm, Mr. Fields.
How come you're so friendly
with the lady, boy?
We met in Paris
last year.
The king of France
introduced us.
You're a pretty
fresh boy, aren't you?
Uh, Mr. Fields,
how about that job?
When you gonna put me
on that payroll?
I'll let you know,
shark.
Thanks a lot, Mr. Fields.
Thank you.
Hiya, Maxie.
Hiya, kid.
How you feelin'?
Same as usual?
What's the matter
with you,
you lookin'
for an early grave?
He's your boss.
Him you don't fool with.
Why not? I'm the king
of yugoslavia.
No. He is. He's
the king of everything.
And he even owns the air
you're breathin'.
Only in here.
Out there, too,
Danny.
He can shut it off
real quick.
Why does a busboy
look at you like that?
A busboy!
Where did you meet him?
Maxie,
you're hurting me.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You know the kid.
Don't lie to me.
I'll break every finger
you got.
Maxie, stop it, please.
I heard him sing a song,
that's all.
Oh. You do know him?
He sang here once for
your big-shot friends.
I told him he had
a nice voice.
That was all, huh?
That's all.
Hey, you, kid.
Maxie: Come here.
Yeah, you, busboy.
Come on over here.
Maxie...
The lady tells me that
you sing. That right?
Well, I--
It better be right,
'cause if it ain't,
then the lady is lying.
Okay, I sing. So what?
Nothing.
Just wanted to make sure
she was telling the truth,
that's all.
Hey, jimmie.
Just a minute.
Sure, boss.
I want to make sure you're
telling the truth, too.
I'd like to hear you.
Go on up there
and sing a song for me.
Now?
Yeah, now.
Right now.
And you better
be a singer.
[Drumroll, cymbal crashes]
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have a little
surprise for you.
There's a great new singer
here tonight--the busboy.
[Laughter]
Nah, nah, nah.
On the level,
a very good friend
of Mr. Fields
says this guy
can really go.
So let's all get together
and give a real good listen
to--what's your name, kid?
Caruso!
[Laughter]
Caruso the busboy! Come on,
let's make it right.
[Whistling]
[Band starts playing]
♪♪ If you're lookin'
for trouble ♪♪
♪♪ you came
to the right place ♪♪
♪♪ if you're lookin'
for trouble ♪♪
♪♪ just look right in my face ♪♪
♪♪ I was born standing up ♪♪
♪♪ and talking back ♪♪
♪♪ my daddy was a green-eyed
mountain Jack ♪♪
♪♪ because I'm evil ♪♪
[Whistling]
♪♪
♪♪ my middle name is misery
♪♪ yeah, yeah ♪♪
♪♪ well, I'm evil ♪♪
♪♪ so don't you mess around
with me ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ I never look for trouble
♪♪ but I never ran ♪♪
♪♪ I don't take no orders ♪♪
♪♪ from no kind of man ♪♪
♪♪ I'm only made out ♪♪
♪♪ of flesh, blood, and bone ♪♪
♪♪ but if you're gonna
start a rumble ♪♪
♪♪ don't you try it all alone ♪♪
♪♪ because I'm evil ♪♪
[Whistling, cheering]
♪♪
♪♪ my middle name is misery
♪♪ well, I'm evil ♪♪
♪♪ so don't you
mess around with me ♪♪
♪♪ well, I'm evil, evil,
evil as can be ♪♪
♪♪ I'm evil, evil,
♪♪ so don't mess around,
don't mess around ♪♪
♪♪ don't mess around with me ♪♪
♪♪ I'm evil ♪♪
♪♪ evil ♪♪
♪♪ so don't mess around,
don't mess around with me ♪♪
♪♪ I'm evil ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ I tell you, how I'm evil
♪♪ so don't mess around with me
yeah.
Sing it again.
Let's hear it again.
Come on.
More, more.
You're a singer, kid.
I just got a dirty mind,
that's all.
Sorry, kid.
Yeah.
Crazy, Danny! Crazy!
Thanks, Chico.
Congratulations.
That was
a great song.
Thank you.
Give me my coat,
kid.
I sure will.
That was swell.
My name's Legrand.
You wanna stop
being a busboy?
I just stopped.
I'd like to talk to you.
I own the king creole
down the street.
Well, good for you.
Yeah, it's a dying swan,
but I figure maybe
we can put you over
and bring the swan back
to life. You interested?
Hello, Charlie.
Well, hello, rat.
What's the matter, kid?
Can't you stand the whiskey
down at your joint?
I always like to see
what the competition
is doing.
I was gonna offer the kid
here a little job myself.
Well,
I beat you to it.
Yeah, you always do,
Charlie,
but I wind up with 'em
sooner or later.
He handled Ronnie
when she was a singer.
Now I do.
What do you say,
kid?
I got a date.
How about one on me,
Charlie boy?
Aw, I never touch it.
Hi, Danny.
You're late.
We started without you.
How much did you get?
We got $95, and that's
only the beginning.
Pretty good.
Here.
Uhh!
Oh, now, come on,
dummy, come on.
Cheer up now.
You ought to be glad
you got that.
How much did you
give him?
You got 30. What are
you worried about?
I asked you a question.
How much did you give him?
I gave him five bucks.
He's a dummy.
What does he
need money for?
Five bucks.
Here you go, kid.
Come on, give me.
If he lays a hand on you
or tries to take it back,
you tell me, okay?
You understand?
Now go on,
beat it, kid.
Look, Danny, I don't
think I want you
hanging around
with us anymore.
You're trouble.
I got news for you, buddy.
I'm not gonna
be around anymore.
I--i...
I wanna pay you.
Uhh...
That's all right, pal.
Good night, girls.
Girls: Good night.
Hi.
Oh. Hello.
Aw, don't give me that.
I saw you looking.
You're pretty sure
of yourself, aren't you?
Well, not always.
To tell you the truth,
I was scared to death
this afternoon.
I thought you were gonna
blow the whistle on me.
It was nice of you
not to.
I like you, that's why.
W-w-well, where
would you like to go?
Why, I don't care.
I mean, I really
don't know why I'm here.
I have to be home early.
My mother's old-fashioned.
Well, what about you?
What do you mean?
Say, I know what.
Some friends of mine
are having a party.
How would you
like to go?
I'm not exactly dressed.
Aw, what's
the difference?
We'll just stop by
for a half hour or so
and have some drinks
and some laughs,
and I'll take you
home, okay?
Just for a half hour?
Then you'll take me home?
Okay.
What can I do
for you, sir?
Oh, what room's
the party in?
I beg your pardon--
What party?
You know, the party
the fellas are having.
Oh. Oh! It's up in 205.
Well, it looks like
my friends are late.
Or maybe
we're early, huh?
What kind of a game
are you playing?
It's no game.
Honest.
I like you.
What's your name?
Nellie. I told you
in the store.
Oh, yeah. Nellie.
I--i like you, Nellie.
I like you a lot.
What's your name?
George.
How much did
this room cost you?
My name's Danny.
Danny Fisher.
You comin' in?
I don't know.
I've never been to a place
like this before.
But I want
to see you again.
Is this the way?
I've been looking
at the door
of that lousy
five-and-ten for a year.
And today when you
walked in, I thought...
Oh!
Well, what are you
bawling about?
Stop bawling.
I like you.
That's the reason
I'm crying.
I--i like you more than
I like anybody I know.
And I don't even know you.
That's why--
That's why I'm crying.
[Closes door]
The party's over.
Let's go.
Well,
I guess this is it.
Good night, Danny.
I guess I'd better
go upstairs now.
Good night.
I didn't mean nothing
by it, honest.
But you played up to me
this afternoon.
I--i thought
you knew the score.
I'm sorry.
I liked you right away,
that's all.
I better go now.
Will--will I see you
again, Danny?
Well, I--i don't know.
You see...
I'm pretty busy.
I don't know.
If you ever had the time,
I'd--I'd like to see you again.
Good night.
Hey, schoolboy.
I thought this was gonna be
turned into a pumpkin.
You really showed Maxie.
You can sing.
So do you, I hear.
I used to.
Yeah, I met a guy named,
uh...Legrand.
Charlie?
Yeah.
He's a nice fellow.
Smart, too.
He sounded broke to me.
He is.
Now, how smart
do you call that?
He owns the king creole.
It's the only place
on bourbon street
without Maxie Fields'
fingerprints
on the cash register.
I'd say that's smart.
Uh, that's, uh...That's
a pretty piece of material.
You ought to have a dress
made out of it.
Don't you like it?
I love it.
Hey, what do you say we
get together sometime
and sing all the old songs
or--or anything else
you want to do?
I'd like to.
I--i can't.
I'd really like to,
but I can't.
I get it.
Maybe we'll meet
someplace by accident.
Well, you tell me
where you think
the accident
will take place,
and I'll make sure
I'm there.
It'll take place.
Just don't rush it.
I'll be waiting.
You'd better go now.
What's the big rush?
Maxie'll be here any
minute. You'd better go.
You remember in the cab
when you wouldn't leave
until I kissed you?
Well, I'm standing right
here until you kiss me.
I'll see you sometime.
Boy, that's gonna be
some accident.
Woman: ♪♪ crawfish ♪♪
♪♪ crawfish ♪♪
♪♪ see, I got 'em ♪♪
♪♪ see the size ♪♪
♪♪ stripped and cleaned ♪♪
Hey, Mimi,
is pop awake yet?
He left long ago.
♪♪ Sweet meat, look ♪♪
♪
♪♪ fresh and ready to cook ♪
Mr. primont, off and on
for over 25 years,
I've been doing
the same kind of work,
and I've filled a lot
of prescriptions
just like this one.
Now--now,
in my opinion--
I don't care how long
you've been filling
out prescriptions.
What I'm telling you is
that I'm running the store.
Why, of course, sir.
But see, all I'm saying
is that in my opinion,
the mixture
that you're using--
Finnell, will you shut
your old mouth up?
Just shut your old mouth up
and do things the way
I say or get out.
Why, yes, of course.
Now take that jar
and put it back
on the counter
where it belongs.
Yes, Mr. primont.
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Danny.
Hey, pop.
Danny, what--what
a pleasant surprise.
You been here long?
No. I--i just walked in.
I wanted to wish you
luck on your first day.
Well, thank you.
Would you like to sit down
for a few minutes?
No. There was something
I wanted to talk
to you about, pop,
but, you know,
you were up and gone
before I even turned
over this morning.
Uh-huh. This job I keep.
Well, we'll talk
about it tonight, pop.
Anything wrong here?
Uh--
Uh, yes. There's
plenty wrong here.
I had a prescription
filled here last week,
and I got
the wrong medicine.
It almost poisoned me.
Oh, that pharmacist
is no longer with us.
So I was just told.
Lucky for you
this gentleman knows what
he's talking about.
Thanks to you, sir,
I'll be coming back in.
Good day, sir.
Uh, good day, sir.
Call again.
I will.
Well, hello.
Hi.
I figured you'd decided
to stay with Maxie.
No, but...
Well, I don't know what
to do, Mr. Legrand.
You see, my old man's
against all of this.
He wants me to
go back to school.
Oh? Sit down.
What does he
want you to be?
Well, he used to talk about
me becoming president,
but, uh, I think he
gave up on that idea.
How much does
a singing job pay?
Here you start at scale--
85 a week.
If they like you,
you get more.
How does it sound?
Well, it sounds good,
but, uh...
Well, I--i never sang
professionally before.
I don't even know
if I can do it.
Well,
you did it last night.
Yeah, but last night,
I was mad.
Oh, so stay mad.
You've sold me.
Now if I could just
sell my old man.
Well, if you do as he
says and go to school,
what about after school?
No deal.
He says I do the studying,
he does the work.
Only, I saw him
do the work.
You hate to see someone
crawl, Mr. Legrand,
especially if it's
your own father.
Now, I pushed him
into that job,
but $85 a week
could get him out.
Let me talk to him.
It won't do you no good.
I've known him
since I was born.
Invite me to dinner.
You're wasting
your time.
Why? It's a free meal.
You afraid of him?
No.
Then invite me.
Okay, you're invited.
29 royal street,
all the way up.
29 royal.
Ronnie says
you're smart.
Does she?
She ought to know.
She could have
had a career.
Not that she
hasn't got one.
Maxie Fields--
There's a name for you.
Everything he touches
turns to drink.
You know him all right.
Know him?
Maxie and I
go a long way back.
We were kids together.
I remember the first words
that came out of his mouth--
"stick 'em up."
See you at dinner.
Okay.
No, you don't understand
how I feel, Mr. Legrand,
and you won't watch out for him
like he's your own son,
because he's not your son.
He's my son.
Just a minute,
Mr. Fisher.
You keep speaking of Danny
having a profession.
Singing is a profession.
All right, so he's
starting in a sewer.
Sewers can't be ignored.
They run under
the best cities,
and some of them lead to the
fanciest plumbing at the ritz.
But Danny
isn't a plumber.
What I meant--
I know what you meant.
The answer is no.
I'm sorry, Mr. Legrand.
No, you're not sorry.
Why don't you ask him
what he wants to do?
The boy was born
with an unusual talent.
He has the right
to think for himself.
You don't have a right
to ask me these questions.
Mimi, will you please
get Mr. Legrand's hat?
All right, pop.
Thanks for dinner, Mimi.
You're some cook.
Thanks.
I may be leaving
empty-handed,
but everywhere else
I'm full.
I'm going out
for a while, pa.
I'll be back.
I'd like to speak
to you again about this.
Maybe we can have a drink
and talk it over quietly.
I don't drink.
No, I didn't
think you did.
Good-bye, Danny.
Why'd you bring
a man like that here?
Pa, you didn't have
to talk to him like that.
He thinks I can
do a job for him.
But you don't care what
he thinks or what I think
or what I want,
for that matter.
What do you want, son?
A pink convertible.
Then register at school.
Look, pa, I got
a very average brain.
I'm not
a brilliant student.
I'm average.
Do you understand?
I don't want to crawl.
Oh, I crawl, is that it?
Is that what I do?
Yeah, you crawl.
You have no choice.
They got you
on the run early.
That's not so!
That's not the truth!
I've fought--
You fought!
Sure, you fought!
You back-pedaled
all the way.
I saw what happened today
between you and your boss, pa,
and it's not going
to happen to me.
Charlie Legrand's
got 85 bucks a week
that says
I can be a performer.
If he's willing to take
a chance, then so am i.
What about school?
I went to school.
And you failed.
I'm through failing.
You know, if you
weren't so young,
I'd ask you to have
that drink with me.
I think I'm old enough
to have a drink, Mr. Legrand.
Swell. Let's go.
No, not tonight.
I think it would
look kind of funny.
Tomorrow night?
I'll pick you up
at 9:00.
All right,
it's a date.
You know,
I was wondering.
Is there anything
in particular
a man of 40 says
to a girl of 20?
Mm-hmm.
Say you're 38.
Yeah.
[Chuckles]
Danny.
I'm sorry,
Mr. Legrand.
I knew it was
gonna happen.
That's all right.
You don't mind
if I have a drink with
your sister, do you?
Well, you know
I don't care,
but you'd better check
with the old man.
Mr. Legrand isn't going to make
a singer out of me, so why--
No, but he's going
to make one out of me.
Do we sign papers or
shake hands or what?
We shake hands.
After you open
and you're a smash,
then we sign papers.
I'll be at the club
tomorrow morning.
Good.
Doorman: Rock and roll
at the king creole.
It's the hottest show
in town, folks.
See fabulous forty Nina
doing the dance that
started the gold rush!
And opening tonight,
the new sensation
of bourbon street--
Danny "boom boom" Fisher!
♪♪ Banana ♪♪
♪♪ anybody want banana ♪♪
♪♪ ripe and ready,
this banana ♪♪
♪♪ come and pick it
off the tree ♪♪
♪♪ oui ♪♪
♪♪ hey, honey ♪♪
♪♪ if your heart
does not go reeling ♪♪
♪♪ when you see
banana peeling ♪♪
♪♪ then, monsieur,
you arefinis ♪♪
♪♪ mais oui ♪♪
♪♪ banana ♪♪
♪♪ how she loves the sun
to warm her ♪♪
♪♪ any mother's son
can warm her ♪♪
♪♪ hey, baby,
maybe it's you ♪♪
♪♪ voulez-vous ♪♪
[Whistling]
Yeah!
[Laughter]
The old man
wouldn't come, huh?
Mm-mmm.
Some father.
Oh, he's a good father.
Oh, he's a good father,
but a lousy audience.
♪♪ No bones, all meat ♪♪
♪♪toujoursso sweet ♪♪
♪♪ don't wait ♪♪
♪♪ what for ♪♪
♪♪mon cheri,
I'll guarantee ♪♪
♪♪ you'll find it
easy to adore ♪♪
♪♪ banana ♪♪
♪♪ how she loves the sun
to warm her ♪♪
♪♪ any mother's son
can warm her ♪♪
♪♪ hey, baby,
maybe it's you ♪♪
[Tink tink]
[Applause]
Here we go. You'll
be great tonight.
I heard you
rehearsing before.
What kind of songs are
you singing, folk songs?
Yeah, I guess so.
That's what I thought.
What planet?
Just laughing it up,
kid.
No offense. Ha ha!
Ha ha.
Nervous?
A little.
I just wanted you to know
the place isn't full.
But half a house can hate
you as hard as a full house.
Right.
When you walk
out there tonight,
as far as you're concerned,
the place is jammed.
They're expecting the best,
and that's what you've
got to give them.
You know something?
I'm glad you told me this.
I'm not nervous anymore.
Good.
I'm scared to death.
What for?
All you have to do
is sing like you're mad,
and you'll be a smash.
[Drumroll]
Here we go.
The 2 biggest words
in show business...
"You're on."
Now, ladies
and gentlemen...
The moment
you've all been waiting for.
The king creole takes
great pride in presenting
a young man
with a big future.
The new sensation
of bourbon street...
The boy with the beat...
Danny Fisher!
[Mimi clapping]
[Audience clapping]
♪♪ Went down to New Orleans
at the golden goose ♪♪
♪♪ I grabbed a green-eyed Dolly
that was on the loose ♪♪
♪♪ well, I dig that music ♪♪
♪♪ she said, me, too ♪♪
♪♪ I said, pretty baby,
come on, let's do ♪♪
♪♪ the dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ well, the dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ let your hair down, sugar ♪♪
♪♪ shake it free ♪♪
♪♪ and do the dixieland rock
with me ♪♪
♪♪ with the blue light
shining on her swinging hips ♪♪
♪♪ she got the drummer
so nervous ♪♪
♪
♪♪ that he lost his sticks ♪
♪♪ the cornet player
hit a note that's flat ♪♪
♪♪ the tromboner hit him
where the poor cat sat ♪♪
♪♪ do the dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ well,
the dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ let your hair down,
sugar ♪♪
♪♪ shake it free ♪♪
♪♪ and do the dixieland rock
with me ♪♪
♪♪ hah hah hah ♪♪
♪♪ I was all pooped out ♪♪
♪♪ when the clock
struck 4:00 ♪♪
♪♪ but she said, no, daddy,
can't leave the floor ♪♪
♪♪ she wore
a clinging dress ♪♪
♪♪ that fit so tight ♪♪
♪♪ she couldn't sit down ♪♪
♪♪ so we danced all night ♪♪
♪♪ to the dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ well,
the dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ dixieland rock ♪♪
♪♪ let your hair down, sugar ♪♪
♪♪ shake it free ♪♪
♪♪ and do the dixieland rock
with me ♪♪
♪♪ let your hair down, sugar ♪♪
♪♪ shake it free ♪♪
♪♪ and do the dixieland rock
with me ♪♪
♪♪ dixieland,
dixieland ♪♪
♪♪ dixieland rock
with me ♪♪
Eddie!
Put his name up
in lights.
Right.
Hey, Danny.
Hi.
You busy?
No.
Okay. We got a date?
Where are we going?
I'll show you.
[Riverboat whistle blows]
We're almost there.
It's just around this bend.
Wait till you see it.
You don't know how
I was hoping you'd come by.
I don't even understand it.
I mean, lots of fellas
have come into the store
asking for a date.
Just like you.
Making cracks.
You were even worse.
You came in to rob the store.
But I was looking
for you when I came out.
Then you took me
to that hotel...
And I went with you.
I don't understand it.
I thought
I was a nice girl.
You are a nice girl,
Nellie.
I've been thinking about
that night, and I'm sorry.
Yeah, me, too.
I told you before--
No, Danny, that's not
what I'm sorry about.
It's like everything
just started with you.
I guess both of us
did something that day
we'd never done
before, Nellie.
I never robbed a store.
I guess there's a last time
for everything, too.
Danny, I--i
didn't mean it.
Wait. We're
coming to it now.
You see that house
over there?
Way over there?
See it?
That used
to be our house.
Pa bought it when
I was about 8 years old.
It was kind of
my birthday present.
We sure had a lot of
happy times there.
I'm gonna buy that
house back someday
or one just like it.
And I guarantee you,
nobody's gonna take
it away from me.
Nobody.
I told my mother
about you.
I told her I met
a million-dollar boyfriend
in a five-and-ten-cent store.
Danny...
Aren't you ever going
to kiss me tonight?
Nellie, don't fall
in love with me.
Love means getting
married, having kids.
I don't even know
who I am yet.
Who do you have to be?
I don't want to be
like my old man.
Love, marriage,
having kids.
I want to be
somebody first.
Do you know
a better way?
You could still kiss me.
Just...Just leave it
at that, Nellie.
For now, anyway.
I mean,
just so it was you
that I wanted
to be with tonight
to show
my house to.
♪♪ Young dreams of love,
young dreams of love ♪♪
♪♪ young dreams ♪♪
♪♪ young dreams,
young dreams ♪♪
♪♪ my heart is filled
with young dreams ♪♪
♪♪ dreams ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ and I'm longing to-oo-oo
♪
♪♪ share them all with you ♪
♪♪ in my eyes ♪♪
♪♪ eyes ♪♪
♪♪ oh, can't you
see in my eyes ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ his eyes
♪♪ that you're
the only one who ♪♪
♪♪ who ♪♪
♪♪ can make my young dreams
come true ♪♪
♪♪ I have young arms ♪♪
♪♪ arms ♪♪
♪♪ that want to hold you ♪♪
♪♪ hold you ♪♪
♪♪ hold you,
oh, so tight ♪♪
♪♪ I have young lips ♪♪
♪♪ lips ♪♪
♪♪ that want to kiss you ♪♪
♪♪ kiss you ♪♪
♪♪ kiss you morning,
noon, and night ♪♪
♪♪ take my hand ♪♪
♪♪ my hand,
my hand ♪♪
♪♪ oh, darling,
take my hand ♪♪
♪♪ take hand ♪♪
♪♪ and let me make you a part ♪♪
♪♪ of all of
my young dreams of love ♪♪
♪♪ I have young arms ♪♪
♪♪ dreams ♪♪
♪♪ that want to hold you ♪♪
♪
♪♪ hold you good and tight ♪
♪♪ I have young lips ♪♪
♪♪ that want to kiss you ♪♪
♪♪ kiss you morning,
noon, and night ♪♪
♪♪ take my hand ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ my hand, my hand
♪♪ oh, darling,
take my hand ♪♪
♪♪ oh-oh-oh-oh ♪♪
♪♪ let me make you a part ♪♪
♪♪ let me
make you a part ♪♪
♪♪ of all my young dreams
of love ♪♪
♪♪ a part ♪♪
♪♪ of all of
my young dreams of love ♪♪
♪♪ young dreams of love,
young dreams of love ♪♪
♪♪ yeah ♪♪
Hurry up! Your breakfast
is getting cold.
Okay, I'm coming.
Well, big shot.
Sing a couple of songs
and right away sleep
all morning, huh?
Ahh, you're a little behind
schedule yourself, kid.
Lookit there.
Mr. Legrand kept me
up half the night
talking about you.
What happened
the other half?
Why, you!
[Chuckles]
Charlie's
a very fine man.
I could like him a lot.
You seen pop
this morning?
For a minute.
Did he ask how
it went last night?
I told him they all applauded.
Everyone loved you.
What did he say?
Oh, you know pop.
He said wash your hands
before you bring him his lunch.
Sounds like pop.
Here, Danny.
I don't care how long
you've been filling out
prescriptions.
Maybe been filling them out
too long for all I know.
Will you ever understand
that I'm running the store?
I understand,
Mr. primont.
You understand, Mr. primont.
That's what you're
getting paid for.
You can't teach
an old dog new tricks.
That's what I told furst
when he made me hire you.
I'm not an old dog.
And don't answer me back
when I talk to you!
Here, maybe at least you
can mop up this floor.
Well, go ahead
and take it.
Now mop over there.
Hey, Danny.
Wowie. You know you got
this whole street buzzin'?
Yeah?
Yeah.
Already they're saying
you're the next somebody.
And I knew you when you were
just singing for watches.
Well, it's a little
early to reminisce.
I'll see you around,
shark.
Maxie Fields wants
to see you, Danny.
Well, I don't want
to see Maxie Fields.
He told me to bring you.
Well, you tell him--
Maxie is no guy
to give the brush to.
He can get rough
if he wants to.
You know what I mean.
If he wants to see me,
let him make a reservation.
There's three shows a night
at the creole.
That drugstore
you just come out...
That's where your old man
works now, ain't it?
So?
Nothin'. I just go in there
and get a pack of cigarettes
once in a while.
I been thinkin'.
If my old man was getting
knocked around like that,
I'd sure try to
help him if I could.
I been working on it.
I'll make you a deal.
You come see
Maxie Fields,
I'll try to work up
an angle.
You never can tell.
You do me a favor,
and I'll try to do you
and your old man a favor.
Where's Fields?
I'll take you to him.
You know I'm on
his payroll now?
I am. I'm one
of his boys.
And that drugstore
situation...
Is liable to clear up
just like that.
Well, this is it.
Come on. Walk right in.
Hiya, pal.
Shark treating you okay?
[Grunts]
Go right up them stairs.
Maxie's expecting you.
Aren't you
coming up with me?
I'll wait here.
Oh. This is where
you live, huh?
This is
where I visit.
Maxie: What's all the chatter?
Send the kid in.
Hi, Danny.
I hear you're a smash
over at that joint.
Good news travels fast.
Sit down. Sit down.
Care for a drink?
No, thanks.
Was there anything
special, Mr. Fields?
No, no, nothing special.
Just a friendly little
get-together, that's all.
I'm interested in any new
attraction on the street.
It's good for all of us.
One tie, all tie.
And then again,
you never know.
What's friendly one day
is business the next.
[Chuckles]
You've got good taste,
Danny.
But you know, you got
to be able to afford it.
Ronnie wants money
even to serve a drink.
Maxie,
please.
Serve the kid
a drink for nothin'.
Nah, I don't
want a drink.
You know, Ronnie
won a contest once.
Best legs
in the state of...
Where's that
you're from, honey?
Maine.
That's it. Maine.
Show the kid
your legs.
Maxie, please.
Well, you won a contest
with them legs.
Must have been 2,000 people
watching them in the finals.
Don't be embarrassed.
Show the kid what won.
All right,
Maxie.
Pretty good, huh?
And there's nothing wrong
with the rest of it.
I gotta get going.
All right, kid.
I just wanted to have
this little chat with you,
get to know you
a little better.
I like to see
people get ahead.
And like I said,
who knows?
Maybe someday we'll be
doing business together.
You may be working
for me again.
I don't think so,
Mr. Fields.
You never can tell.
Wheel comes around.
After all,
I saw you first.
I gotta admit, I was a little
put out when you quit.
Especially to go
with a crumb like Legrand.
Charlie's no crumb.
He's a pretty
decent fella.
Oh, yeah, I forgot.
I forgot about him
and your sister.
Eh, this has been quite
a week for Charlie.
First, he finds
himself a singer,
then he finds himself
a girl.
You're some
talented family.
What are you
trying to say?
I got only one thing
to say, kid...
I don't like losing things.
I don't mind taking,
but I don't like to lose.
Not even a busboy.
When I lose something,
I want it back,
and sooner or later,
I get it.
That's all.
You got a long way
to go, boy.
Lots and lots
of good luck.
Show him to the door,
will you, honey?
[Softly] Don't come
back here anymore, Danny.
Stay far, far away.
Thanks. I could give
you the same advice.
As Maine goes,
so goes Maxie Fields.
Maxie buzzed me.
I was downstairs,
and he buzzed me.
Yeah.
Maxie: Shark!
Yes, Mr. Fields?
Excuse me.
[Door closes]
Come over here, shark.
I want to talk to you.
Get some ice,
will you, Ronnie?
Yes, sir. Mr. Fields.
What can I do for you?
Come on. Move it.
What have you got
on this Fisher kid?
Well, nothing much.
He helped us
do a little job
on the five-and-ten once.
That's all.
Not big enough.
I want to be able
to twist real hard.
You work on it, huh?
That's a funny thing,
Mr. Fields.
I--i just got an idea.
It's about his old man.
You see, he works
in a drugstore...
Hello, ladies.
Just in time
for the show, ladies.
Hope you made
your reservations.
[Jazz playing]
[Applause]
[Whistling]
♪♪ You'll never know ♪♪
♪♪ you'll never know ♪♪
♪♪ what heaven means ♪♪
♪♪ until you've been down
to New Orleans ♪♪
♪♪ New Orleans ♪♪
♪♪ you ain't been livin' ♪♪
♪
♪♪ till you cuddle and coo ♪
♪♪ with a black-eyed baby ♪♪
♪♪ by the old bayou ♪♪
♪♪ you've never seen ♪♪
♪♪ kewpie doll queens ♪♪
♪♪ you've never seen
those kewpie doll queens ♪♪
♪♪ like they got 'em ♪♪
♪♪ where ♪♪
♪♪ in New Orleans ♪♪
♪♪ New Orleans ♪♪
♪♪ and, ooh,
they love you like-a ♪♪
♪♪ no one can ♪♪
♪♪ ow ♪♪
♪♪ it makes you awful glad
that you were born a man ♪♪
♪
♪♪ if you ain't been there ♪
♪♪ been there ♪♪
♪♪ man,
you ain't been nowhere ♪♪
♪♪ nowhere ♪♪
♪♪ the livin's lazy,
and the lovin's fine ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ it's so fine
♪♪ if you feel lowdown ♪♪
♪♪ lowdown ♪♪
♪♪ so help me, Hannah ♪♪
♪♪ Hannah ♪♪
♪♪ you're sure
to lose the blues ♪♪
♪♪ in Lou-si-oo-
si-oo-si-Ana ♪♪
♪♪ so get the lead ♪♪
♪♪ get the lead ♪♪
♪♪ out of your jeans ♪♪
♪♪ get the lead
out of your jeans ♪♪
♪♪ and hotfoot it,
hotfoot it down to where ♪♪
♪♪ where ♪♪
♪♪ New Orleans ♪♪
♪
♪♪ New Orleans ♪
♪♪ Lou-si-Ana, baby ♪♪
♪♪ tells you
stay a while ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ yeah ♪♪
♪♪ yeah
♪♪ live it up ♪♪
♪♪ love it up ♪♪
♪♪ Southern style ♪♪
♪♪ way down in new ♪♪
♪♪ down in new ♪♪
♪♪ New Orleans ♪♪
Wasn't Danny
wonderful tonight?
Yes, wonderful.
That man gets better
all the time.
Hi, Danny.
Hi.
Hey, Nina?
Yes?
You know
my girl Nellie?
If she comes by tonight,
tell her I can't see her.
I got something
to take care of, okay?
You're the boy
who can do it.
Mmm, boy, what a mob!
That kid is sure
bringing in the business.
He's ruining
my performance.
Ever since he started,
there's nothing
but women out there.
They don't want to see me,
and tonight I heard one
of them yell, "leave it on!"
Maybe I should
do the strip.
Why don't you?
Hey, Eddie?
Yeah?
I'll probably be a little
late for the next show.
Will you stall 'em off
as long as you can, huh?
[Thunder]
Shark: There's
old man primont
getting ready to take
the dough to the bank.
I hope he doesn't leave
before Danny gets here.
It's almost 11:00.
Just don't leave, mister,
till Danny gets here.
You sure
he's gonna be here?
He'll be here. He really
bought the idea.
I gotta hand it
to you, shark.
You sure are
a good salesman.
Here comes the pigeon.
[Thunder]
I tried to get you
on the phone.
What for?
Call it off, shark.
You don't owe me nothin'.
You were pretty hot
for this before.
I've been thinking--
You're crazy.
It works out both ways.
We get the money,
you get that drugstore
situation cleared up.
You get even
for your old man.
It's no good, shark.
The old man wouldn't--
He would
if he could.
Hey, look. Primont's
getting ready to leave.
Well,
you go on home.
On your way--you know
where the bank is--
Just drop this off in
the night deposit box.
I'll finish up
the inventory.
I hope it
stops raining.
Okay, okay, take
my hat and coat.
I didn't mean it
that way.
No, no, go ahead
and take it.
Well,
thank you, sir.
All right, Danny boy,
you have it your way,
but don't you say you
never had the chance.
All right, there he is.
There's primont.
Now, are you
with us or not?
It's for your old man,
you know.
Okay!
Come on.
That's not primont.
That's Danny's father.
We take him anyway.
This may turn out even better.
But, sharky,
it's his old man!
Shut up. I mean,
how do we know?
We just play dumb.
[Thunder]
Uh, mister, do you know
where front street is?
No.
No, young man,
I--i don't.
I don't know where
front street is.
[Groans]
Come on.
Can't figure this kid.
He's been shut up in there
for half an hour.
He looked sick
when he came back.
I've got to see
Danny.
So does that audience
out there.
He's in there,
Nellie.
Danny?
What's wrong?
It's your father,
Danny.
Mimi phoned
from the hospital.
Some thugs
beat him up.
She didn't want me to
tell you on the phone.
She wants me
to bring you there.
Oh, no...
He was taking some
money to the bank,
and they jumped him.
He's in bad shape,
Danny.
Mimi and Charlie are
at the hospital now.
Is he all right,
doc?
He's alive. Just.
There's been damage
to the brain.
We've relieved
the pressure temporarily,
but he's going to need another
operation immediately.
A delicate one.
Cabot.
Dr. Martin cabot has performed
this kind of operation.
Is he good?
He's the best,
but expensive.
How expensive?
Oh, a couple of thousand,
maybe more.
I'm still deep in hock,
but maybe
I can scrape up 500.
We'll get it someway.
Dr. Patrick.
Where's this man?
Where's this Fisher?
Dr. cabot!
You know,
it took me a whole year
to wangle this dinner
invitation. Lucy pitman.
Well, anything
for Maxie Fields.
Thank you.
You the boy?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Fields must be
very fond of you.
Said you used
to work for him.
When he heard about this,
he wanted to help out.
Well, let's go.
When you work
for Maxie Fields,
it's better
than blue cross.
What's the case?
They've been in there
for hours.
Must be some kind
of world's record.
[Elevator doors open]
He made it.
Oh, thank god.
Well, I think
I'm going to go home.
No sense in going
to that dinner party.
Lucy gives me
a pain anyway.
Thank you,
doctor.
He's going
to be all right.
May take
a little while, though.
But he's a strong man.
A real fighter.
But, doc, about
Maxie Fields. How--
Strange man, isn't he?
Very coarse, vulgar,
very powerful.
Send him my best.
I'll send him my bill.
Thank you, doctor.
Thank you.
[Crying] I'll
pay him back, sis.
I'll pay every cent.
I got a lot of
payin' back to do.
A lot of payin' back.
Doorman: Soon as
the show breaks, folks,
there'll be plenty
of tables for everyone.
Just stand in line
and don't go away.
It's a fabulous show.
This kid is absolutely
sensational!
Just be patient, folks.
It won't be very long now.
[Danny singing]
Good evening, folks.
Hi.
Good evening, miss Fisher.
How's your father?
Oh, much better,
thanks.
Let her through, folks.
Let her through.
Her brother pays the bills.
Danny: ♪♪ a hardheaded woman bee
a Thorn in the side of man ♪♪
♪♪ uh huh huh ♪♪
Sorry I'm late.
They wanted to run
the final check on pop.
Everything okay?
Mm-hmm.
He'll be coming home first
thing tomorrow morning.
It's been a long 4 weeks.
♪♪ King ♪♪
♪♪ creole, go ♪♪
♪♪ there's a man in New Orleans
who plays-a rock and roll ♪♪
♪♪ he's a guitar man
with a great big soul ♪♪
♪♪ he lays down a beat
like a ton of coal ♪♪
♪♪ he goes by the name
of king creole ♪♪
♪♪ you know he's gone,
gone, gone ♪♪
♪♪ jumping like
a catfish on a pole, yeah ♪♪
♪♪ you know
he's gone, gone, gone ♪♪
♪♪ and a hip-shakin'
king creole ♪♪
♪♪ king creole,
♪♪ when the king starts to do it
, it's as good as done ♪♪
♪♪ he holds his guitar
like a Tommy gun ♪♪
♪
♪♪ he starts to growl
way down in his throat ♪
♪♪ he bends a string,
and that's all she wrote ♪♪
♪♪ you know
he's gone, gone, gone ♪♪
♪♪ a-jumpin' like
a catfish on a pole, whoa ♪♪
♪♪ you know
he's gone, gone, gone ♪♪
♪♪ and a hip-shakin'
king creole ♪♪
♪♪ king creole,
♪♪ he sings a song
about a crawdad hole ♪♪
about a jelly roll ♪♪
♪♪ he sings a song
about pork and Greens ♪♪
♪♪ he sings some blues
about New Orleans ♪♪
♪♪ you know
he's gone, gone, gone ♪♪
♪♪ a-jumpin' like
a catfish on a pole, yeah ♪♪
♪♪ you know
he's gone, gone, gone ♪♪
♪♪ and a hip-shakin'
king creole ♪♪
♪
♪♪ king creole ♪
♪♪ go ♪♪
[Cheering and shouting]
♪♪ He plays something evil,
then he plays something sweet ♪♪
♪♪ no matter how he plays,
you gotta get up on your feet ♪♪
♪♪ and when he gets the rockin'
fever, baby, heaven sakes ♪♪
♪♪ he don't stop playin'
till his guitar breaks ♪♪
♪♪ you know
he's gone, gone, gone ♪♪
♪♪ a-jumpin' like
a catfish on a pole, yeah ♪♪
♪♪ you know he's gone,
gone, gone ♪♪
♪♪ and a hip-shakin'
king creole ♪♪
♪♪ king creole, yeah, go ♪♪
♪♪ you know he's gone,
gone, gone ♪♪
♪
♪♪ hip-shakin' king creole ♪
Hiya.
What do you want?
Mr. Fields would
like to see you.
What about?
Just wants
to see you.
Well, I don't
want to see him.
Wait a minute.
You don't understand
the job I got.
You see, when Maxie
tells me to bring somebody,
I got to bring them.
So I'll make it
short and sweet.
He wants to see you.
This here's the key
to his apartment.
You just take this,
go up the stairs,
and turn the lock.
You understand?
You know,
for a little guy,
you make an
awful lot of noise.
Now, for a little guy,
I'm remembering a rainy night
and a man carrying
a bag of money.
Now, your old man,
he's been in that hospital
about a month now,
ain't that right?
And I hear
he gets out tomorrow,
and I'm real glad
about that.
[Jingling]
Why don't you
just take this here key?
You know where it is.
I should have finished
you off a long time ago.
Come on.
Uhh.
You're working for
Maxie Fields, too, huh?
That's right. We're all
working for Maxie now.
That figures.
Go right on up.
Thanks, pal.
Hi.
Come on in.
I've been waiting
for you.
It's a nice night
for an accident.
Yeah.
Where's Fields?
I'm supposed
to see him.
You wanna see him?
Come with me.
There he is.
Out and gone.
Isn't he sweet?
Every time I see him
lying down,
I keep looking
at his chest
and hoping.
But the pig keeps
right on breathing.
I guess he can't
see me tonight.
Danny, wait.
He didn't want
to see you tonight.
He wanted me to see you.
What about?
We wants you to quit
Charlie Legrand
and go to work for him.
And what are you
supposed to do about it?
Whatever
I can do about it.
Your heart
wouldn't be in it.
You wouldn't miss it.
Would you like a drink?
Would you like
a cigarette?
Shall we talk?
Can I do anything
for you?
Anything at all?
The general idea is...
I'm supposed
to befriend you.
You know, for a--a...
For a bum? A tramp?
For what?
Oh, I was just gonna say
you got a pretty good
way of talking.
Hmm.
You'd be surprised
how many tramps graduate
school with honors.
As a matter of fact, me.
Well, I flunked
without honors.
I'm sorry,
but I don't think
I'm going to be able
to handle this setup.
This is a setup,
isn't it?
It was all fixed
in advance.
Mmm.
You tell Maxie Fields
that I wasn't in the mood.
I'll be square with him
in a few months.
I won't owe him
anything,
and that's the way
I wanna keep it.
Danny...
I wish
you wouldn't go.
This isn't the accident,
honey.
The accident happened
that first morning
in the blue shade.
From then on,
everything's been fixed
just like
a crooked fight.
And you're wrong
about the heart.
I do miss it.
I miss it so much
there's a girl I may marry
just because she has one
to give me.
I'm not asking you
to marry me.
Well, you're asking me
something.
You're a little tight,
aren't you?
I'm not tight.
I'm drunk.
But I'll tell you
what you are.
You're being rude.
You're condemning me
and ignoring
my god-given charms.
God didn't give you
the charms
for what you're using
them for, honey.
That's funny.
And I read the instructions
so carefully.
Danny...
Please don't go.
Come here.
I want to show you
something.
Look.
What's he doing
down there?
He has orders
from the pig
to clock your entrance
and exit.
You see, you're supposed
to spend a few hours here,
and in those few hours,
acquire the habit
of coming back.
In due time,
Mr. Fields will
approach you
with a bill
for my graciousness.
Double-cross
Charlie Legrand.
Exactly.
What if I leave now?
Then the pig will punish me
for having failed.
If you were kind,
you'd stay
for a few hours
and just pretend
like you like me.
We could--we could
smoke some cigarettes.
We could play some music.
Just make it seem
as though I have charm.
I--i could sing
some songs for you.
I used to be a singer,
you know?
Yes, I did.
[Softly]
♪♪ let the stars ♪♪
♪♪ fade and fall ♪♪
♪♪ and I won't ♪♪
♪♪ care at all ♪♪
♪♪ as long ♪♪
♪♪ as I ♪♪
♪♪ have you ♪♪
You remember that one?
Yeah.
That's a real oldie.
Used to be
my theme song.
I ask you to stay
because I hate to be
punished by Mr. Fields.
He's not a very
sensitive man.
All right.
I-I'll stay.
And i...
I think you
arecharming.
I don't use that word,
but you are.
Thank you.
Oh.
Ohh.
Ah, Ronnie.
I'm sorry.
Don't--don't cry.
You'll wake up
the circus master.
Oh, Danny, hold me.
Hold me, please.
Ronnie, what are you
doing here with this man?
How'd you get
into this?
How do you get out?
Go home, Danny.
Go home.
Ronnie, please.
No, no. Not here.
Not in this house.
I wouldn't know if it
was because I wanted you
or because
Maxie wanted you.
Maxie's got nothing
to do with it.
Maxie:
I wouldn't be too sure.
Sorry to intrude. Uh...
I don't mind you two
wrestling around
a little bit together,
but as everyone knows,
wrestling is all a fake.
Let's not forget
who's supposed to win--
Me.
I told you once before.
I'm not gonna work for you.
Well, it's too bad.
I was hoping
it could be arranged
on some kind
of a friendly basis.
But...
It can be done
the other way, too.
Now, you listen to me,
punk.
You're gonna work
at my club.
I can do a lot for you,
and I can do a lot
against you.
Your old man's coming out
of the hospital tomorrow.
Might not be so good
for his health
if he found out it was you
who help put him there.
It was an accident.
Was it?
Somebody was gonna
get hit.
Too bad it was him.
But you were in
on it.
It was all done
because of you.
You don't think
he'd mind?
Okay, you tell him.
Or shall I?
You do it,
and I'll kill you.
I got an easier way.
All you gotta do
is sign this little
piece of paper.
There's nothing on it,
but don't worry.
I'll fill it in later.
No, Danny. No!
Shut up.
Or maybe you'd like me
to fill Charlie's place
with stink bombs
every night.
Or if that's
an unpleasant thought,
how about real bombs?
You think I wouldn't?
Everything goes boom.
Easiest thing in the world.
Make it all look
like an accident.
Anything can be made
to look like an accident.
What do you say, kid?
Well, that's
more like it.
Now, don't let me
interrupt you any longer.
You were just saying
to her, um...
"Maxie has nothing
to do with it."
So now you know.
That's how
you get into it.
Now Maxie's got you
like he's got me.
It's too late.
You do something wrong...
And that makes you
do something worse.
And the first thing
you know,
you don't know
the difference anymore.
Oh, Danny, I'm so sorry.
[Glass shatters]
[Sobbing]
[Strumming guitar]
[Band begins playing]
♪♪ I'll go on ♪♪
♪♪ loving you ♪♪
♪♪ don't ask me why ♪♪
♪♪ don't know ♪♪
♪♪ what else ♪♪
♪♪ to do ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ooh ♪♪
♪♪ don't ask me why ♪♪
♪♪ doo do do doot ♪♪
♪♪ how sad ♪♪
♪♪ my heart ♪♪
♪♪ would be ♪♪
♪♪ heart would be ♪♪
♪♪ if you should go ♪♪
♪♪ though you're ♪♪
♪♪ not good ♪♪
♪♪ for me ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ooh ♪♪
♪♪ I want you so ♪♪
♪♪ it's not ♪♪
♪♪ the kind ♪♪
♪♪ of love ♪♪
♪♪ I dreamed ♪♪
♪♪ about ♪♪
♪♪ but it's the kind ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ that I can't live ♪♪
♪♪ without ♪♪
♪♪ doo do do doot ♪♪
♪♪ you're all ♪♪
♪♪ I'm longing for ♪♪
♪♪ longing for ♪♪
♪♪ don't ♪♪
♪♪ say good-bye ♪♪
♪♪ don't say good-bye ♪♪
♪♪ I need you ♪♪
♪♪ more ♪♪
♪♪ and more ♪♪
♪♪ don't ask me why ♪♪
♪♪ doo do do doot ♪♪
♪♪ I need you ♪♪
♪♪ more ♪♪
♪♪ and more ♪♪
♪♪ doo do do doot ♪♪
♪♪ don't ♪♪
♪♪ ask me ♪♪
♪♪ why ♪♪
♪♪ don't ♪♪
♪♪ ask ♪♪
♪♪ me ♪♪
♪♪ why ♪♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
I would just like to say
thanks for everything.
You people have been
wonderful to me here,
and I'll never forget you.
I just want you to know
that I'll always
be grateful.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me.
What's the matter?
[Dixieland music playing]
Hey, kid, that
was a great show.
Thanks, Charlie.
What was the curtain
speech all about?
Charlie,
we never got around
to signing those papers
you talked about.
So what's the hurry?
There's no hurry.
I just don't know how
to tear up a handshake.
What do you mean?
I'm quitting you,
Charlie.
I got a better offer
from Maxie Fields.
You're no good,
Danny.
You belong
on the street
with all the bums
and the hoodlums.
I thought
you changed,
but you belong
with them.
You threw it
all away--
You, me,
everything.
Yep.
[Sobs]
Danny...
Is anything wrong?
Are you all right?
Sure.
You sounded so funny
when you called.
I got here as soon
as I could.
I told Mr. mcintyre
it was an emergency,
I'd be right back.
Nellie,
there's something i...
What's the matter,
Danny?
Nothing.
Did you speak
to father Franklin yet?
I stopped by
this morning.
He's a wonderful man.
He's known me ever since
I was a little girl.
He was so happy
I finally found someone
I was serious about.
He can't wait
to meet you.
He's there now if you--
I can't, Nellie.
I wouldn't know
what to say to him.
That's why
I had to see you.
I think maybe too much
has happened too fast.
I mean,
you're a swell girl,
and I--i don't want
to hurt you,
but something's
happened.
A lot's happened.
I walked out on
Charlie Legrand last night--
And now you're making it
a parlay.
I guess so...
For now, anyway.
That girl Ronnie,
does she have anything
to do with it?
I don't know.
Maybe.
It's--it's...
It's all kinda
mixed up.
See, the other night...
I can't walk in
that church till I'm sure.
I have to be getting
back to the store.
I can't afford
to be fired
from two places
in the same day.
[Grunting]
You sure?
[Grunts]
I'm sorry,
but there's no use
talking about it
any longer.
A deal is a deal.
Mr. Fields, I beg you.
I'm not here to speak
for my son.
It's my daughter.
You see, Mr. Legrand
has asked her to marry him.
I just found this out
myself.
He's counting on Danny
remaining at his club.
This could ruin
their future,
their--their plans,
her chance
for happiness.
Your boy's gotta think
about himself, too.
I can do a lot more for him
than Charlie Legrand.
No, you--you don't
understand. This--
I'm afraid it's you
who don't understand.
Mr. Fields, the collector
made the delivery.
Good.
It's all taken
care of, chief.
Good deal.
Is there anything else
I can do for you?
That--that's
the face of...
That's the one
who almost killed me.
You're mistaken,
Mr. Fisher.
This man
works for me.
Mistaken? I'm not.
I'm--I'm not mistaken.
I could never forget
that face.
What's he talking about?
Okay, go ahead,
beat it. Go on.
How about that?
I never saw him
before in my life.
Wait. You can't
let him go.
I don't care what you do to me.
I'll go to the police.
Oh, no, I don't think
you'll do that.
I don't think you'll go
to the police.
All right. All right,
you say a deal is a deal.
I'll make you a deal.
You let Danny
out of his agreement,
and I'll forget
that I ever saw this man.
Otherwise,
I go to the police.
You're okay, Mr. Fisher.
I gotta hand it to you.
But you better
listen to me first.
There's something
you don't know
maybe make you
change your mind.
Pa, what are you
doing here?
It was an accident, pa.
I'm sorry. Honest.
I tried to stop 'em.
I did it for you.
[Door slams shut]
[Breathing heavily]
You double-crossed me,
didn't you, Maxie?
Who sent for you?
You told him.
Sure, I told him.
He was running
to the police.
I told you I'd kill you
if you ever told him.
Knock it off, kid.
I don't like guys
coming at me like that.
I'm warning you!
Oh!
No!
No, leave him alone!
Leave him alone!
Why, you tramp!
I own you!
No, you don't own me!
You bought me!
You don't own me!
I meant to tell you
that!
Youdisgustme!
I hate you!
Every time you put
your hands on me,
you make my flesh crawl!
Go ahead, hit me!
That's the only thing
you're man enough to do!
Get out of here, Ronnie!
Don't come back!
[Footsteps]
He's in the alley.
Go around the block.
Come in the other way.
Okay.
Danny...
We know you're in here.
You come on out now,
and you got a chance.
You can't get away.
Maxie's got
the whole town covered.
This is it, buddy.
This is
the big get-even day.
We got a lot to settle up,
you and me.
Danny, I knew it was
your old man that night.
I knew it,
and I slugged him anyway,
so you come on out
and get me.
You come on out and get me,
or we're coming in.
Shark: I'm gonna let you in
on a little secret, kid.
We've been
laughing at you.
Me and Maxie,
ever since it happened,
we've been splitting a gut.
You told me once
we'd tangle again.
Well, now's your chance.
Come on, Danny boy.
You got him?
[Muffled voice]
Yeah.
Hold him. I wanna
put my mark on him.
Shark: Where is he?
Aah.
[Knock knock]
[Rattles door]
Who's there?
It's me, pa. Danny.
Let me in, will you?
Pop: Go away.
I can't.
Please, let me in, pa.
Please?
Please let me...
[Tires squealing]
Danny. Danny!
I found out from dummy
what happened.
You've got to get out
of here.
They're all after you.
You've got to hide.
Hurry, Danny.
Hurry.
Hello, Danny.
Hello.
How ya feel?
I don't know yet.
You know, it's Sunday.
You've been out of your
head for two days.
Maybe even longer.
Where are we?
Oh, just some place
to run to.
I've had this for years.
What about Maxie?
Does he--
No. No, here
there's no Maxie.
Here I don't have
to think about Maxie
or yesterday
or today
or the day after.
It was nice having
someone to take care of.
Thanks.
Thanks for everything,
Ronnie.
Sure.
What are you staring at?
You look like a kid.
[Laughs]
I am.
104-year-old kid.
I guess it all started
that first morning
when you rescued me.
You had courage,
and I admired that.
I have so little myself.
You'd be surprised
at all the happy endings
I had figured out.
You see, Danny,
girls like me,
if we stick around
for the finish,
generally finish up
pretty much the same way.
Sooner or later,
the party's over,
and we go to
our hometowns
and play it
very straight
and marry the first
respectable guy who asks us.
You'd be amazed how many do.
Only I never
wanted it that way.
That's why
I kidded myself
into thinking maybe
you were the one.
I used to dream
that maybe someday Maxie
and I would be through,
and I'd meet you
someplace,
and we'd run away
together.
We did.
It's never the way
you imagine it, is it?
Danny, I'm not proud.
I haven't got
much pride left.
I know what can be
and what can't be.
But do you think that...
Maybe for a little while
we could make it the way
I dreamed it?
That you could love me,
and my dream
could come true?
It wouldn't be hard
to love you.
Then love me, Danny.
Take a day out
of your life
and love me.
Wait here.
[Grunting]
[Gunshot]
[Grunts]
Ronnie.
[Groans]
It was a lovely day...
For a little while.
Ronnie.
Ro--
Oh, no.
I'm sorry.
[Dixieland music playing]
[Knock on door]
Danny.
Danny, I'm so glad
you're back.
I hope now we--
Not yet, Nellie.
In a little while, maybe,
when the time is right,
but not now.
I'll wait.
I have lots of time.
Oh, it'll be all right.
[Band begins new song]
[Applause]
Good luck, Danny.
Thank you.
[Slow ballad playing]
♪♪ Let the stars ♪♪
♪♪ fade and fall ♪♪
♪♪ and I won't care
at all ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ as long as I ♪♪
♪♪ have you ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ every kiss ♪♪
♪♪ brings a thrill ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ and I know
that it will ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ as long as I ♪♪
♪♪ have you ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ooh ooh ♪♪
♪♪ let's think ♪♪
♪♪ of the future ♪♪
♪♪ ahh ♪♪
♪♪ forget the past ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ you're not
my first love ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ but you're my last ♪♪
♪♪ take the love
that I bring ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ and I'll have
everything ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ as long as I ♪♪
♪♪ have you ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ooh ooh ♪♪
♪♪ let's think
of the future ♪♪
♪♪ forget the past ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ you're not
my first love ♪♪
♪♪ but you're my last ♪♪
♪♪ ah ahh ♪♪
♪♪ take the love
that I bring ♪♪
♪♪ ooh ♪♪
♪♪ then I'll have
everything ♪♪
♪♪ as long as I ♪♪
♪♪ have you ♪♪
♪♪ as long ♪♪
♪♪ as long as I ♪♪
♪♪ have ♪♪
♪♪ you ♪♪
♪♪ as long as I ♪♪
♪♪ have you ♪♪