(WAVES SPLASHING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
MALE SINGER:
♪ A long, long time ago
♪ There was a volcano
♪ Living all alone
in the middle of the sea
♪ He sat high
above his bay
♪ Watching all
the couples play
♪ And wishing that
♪ He had someone too
(DOLPHINS SQUEAKING)
♪ And from his lava came
♪ This song of
hope that he sang
♪ Out loud everyday
♪ For years and years
(LOW RUMBLING)
♪ I have a dream
♪ I hope will come true
♪ That you're here with me
♪ And I'm here with you
♪ I wish that the earth...
♪ sea and
the sky up above-a
♪ Will send me
someone to lava
(WIND WHOOSHING)
♪ Years of
singing all alone
♪ Turned his
lava into stone
♪ Until he was on...
♪ the brink of extinction
♪ But little did he know
♪ That living
in the sea below
♪ Another volcano...
♪ was listening to his song
♪ Every day
she heard his tune
♪ Her lava grew and grew
♪ Because she believed...
♪ his song
was meant for her
♪ Now she was so ready
♪ To meet him
above the sea
♪ As he sang
his song of hope...
♪ for the last time
♪ I have a dream
♪ I hope will come true
♪ That you're here with me
♪ And I'm here with you
♪ I wish that the earth...
♪ sea and
the sky up above-a
♪ Will send me
someone to lava
(SONG ENDS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Rising from
the sea below
♪ Stood a lovely volcano
♪ Looking all around...
♪ but she
could not see him
♪ He tried to
sing to let her know
♪ That she was
not there alone
♪ But with no lava...
♪ his song was all gone
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
♪ He filled
the sea with his tears
♪ And watched
his dreams disappear
♪ As she remembered...
♪ what his
song meant to her
♪ I have a dream
♪ I hope will come true
♪ That you're here with me
♪ And I'm here with you
♪ I wish that the earth...
♪ sea and
the sky up above-a
♪ Will send me...
♪ someone to lava
(EXPLOSION)
MALE SINGER:
♪ Oh, they were so happy
♪ To finally
meet above the sea
♪ All together now...
♪ their lava grew and grew
♪ No longer
are they all alone
♪ With aloha
as their new home
♪ And when you visit them
♪ This is what they sing
BOTH:
♪ I have a dream
♪ I hope will come true
♪ That you'll
grow old with me
♪ And I'll
grow old with you
♪ We thank the earth,
sea and the sky
♪ We thank too
♪ I lava you
♪ I lava...
♪ You ♪
(SONG ENDS)
(WAVES SPLASHING)