Ten long years
Living a mere façade of life
Wasting my time on smoke and noise
In my mind
I hear melodies pure and unearthly
but I find
I can't give them a voice without you!
My Christine
Lost and gone
The day starts
The day ends
Time crawls by
Night steals in, pacing the floor
The moments creep
yet I can't bear to sleep
till I hear you sing
And weeks pass, and months pass
Seasons fly
Still you don't walk through my door
And in a haze
I count the silent days
till I hear you sing
once more
And sometimes in darkness
I dream that you are there
but wake holding nothing
but the cold night air
And years come, and years go
Time runs dry
Still I ache
deep in my core
My broken soul
can't be alive or whole
till I hear you sing
once more
And music, your music
It teases at my ear
I turn, and it fades away
And you're not here
Let hopes pass
Let dreams pass
Let them die!
Without you
what are they for?
I'll always feel
no more than halfway real
till I hear you sing
once more!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Coney Isle
Glistening and glimmering!
Rising bright
Drenched with light
See it smile
Beckoning and shimmering!
All a-gleam
like a dream
Every fantasy set free!
Sodom rising by the sea!
Wonders and astonishments
for your delectation!
Phantoms and automatons
for your fascination!
Marvels undreamt
since the dawn of creation!
Coney Isle!
Miracle on miracle!
Speed and sound
Whirling round
Mile by mile
Loud and lewd and lyrical
Thrill on thrill
Never still
Welcome one and welcome all!
Welcome to the monster's ball
Welcome to the, welcome to the
Welcome to the, welcome to the...
(SCREAMING)
Coney Isle!
Miracle on miracle!
Speed and sound
Whirling round
Mile by mile
Loud and lewd and lyrical
Thrill on thrill
Never still
Welcome one and welcome all!
Welcome to the monster's ball
Welcome to the, welcome to the
Welcome to the, welcome to the...
Mr. Y welcomes you
to Phantasma!
Featuring Dr. Gangle,
master of ceremonies!
Miss Fleck, aerialist extraordinaire.
The amazing Squelch,
the world's strongest man.
And direct from Paris, France...
It's Coney Island's
Ooh-La-La Girl...
Miss Meg Giry!
Meg Giry!
Welcome
each and every one
to our festival of fun!
Something notable and new!
We bring glamour from afar
plus a touch of the bizarre!
And it's only for you!
See the wonders of our age
all assembled on our stage!
Too fantastic to be true!
What sensation-seekers seek!
Every kind of living freak!
And it's only for you!
If it's marvel and illusion
that your soul and body crave
you'll be leaving
here content without a doubt!
Are you ready?
Are you willing?
Are you braver than the brave?
There's an oh-so-simple
way of finding out!
Is your life a little humdrum?
Is your wife a little glum?
We've the remedy for all who wear a frown!
We won't bite you, we'll delight you!
We invite you to succumb
to this singular attraction
which is offered at a fraction
of the price of any other show in town!
We've got jugglers from the east!
We've got bird and we've got beast!
It's a pretty heady brew!
We've a fiddler from the west
who is said to be possessed
And it's only for you!
We bring magic, we bring mirth!
We've been halfway round the Earth
from Teheran to Timbuktu
to present to you today
this delectable display
which is only for you!
Such a show you've never seen!
Such a show there's never been!
And today's our grand debut!
Prince and pauper, come on in!
Let the spectacle begin
'cause it's only for you!
Let the banners be unfurled!
Raise the curtain on our world!
Without any more ado!
Mr. Y has all you need
Satisfaction guaranteed!
And it's only for you!
Welcome each and every one
to our festival of fun!
For you!
(CHEERING)
Ladies and gentlemen, Miss Meg
Giry, the Ooh-La-La Girl!
Five shows daily.
Only here at Phantasma.
And not forgetting,
the fabulous Miss Fleck...
Hurry up, people! You have
four more shows to do.
No time to dawdle.
Mother, did you see?
Was it all all right?
Mother, was he watching?
Was he keeping out of sight?
I was frightened half to death
and I had to catch my breath
as the lights began to dim!
I was suddenly aware
of a presence in the air
and I knew it was him!
Yes, I know there were some snags
There are moments where it lags
Mother? Mother,
what's wrong?
A surprise announcement
from Mr. Oscar Hammerstein.
Christine Daaé left Paris this morning
to sing at the opening of his
new Manhattan Opera House.
Christine, Christine...
Christine
Ten long years
Not a sign, not a word
Ten long years, now she comes to our shores
We must pray she keeps away
from us and from him and
his dreams and his scores
What do you mean?
In Paree
when the mob surrounded him who was there?
We were there!
Where was she
when the lawmen hounded him?
Gone, long gone
We stayed on
Who concealed him safe away?
Smuggled him up to Calais?
Found a freighter out of France?
I don't see the problem
This is ancient history
And who helped him buy his first sideshow?
Mother, don't.
And who plied the politicians?
That's all over now.
Charmed investors and the press?
No, not her!
And who stayed with him
helped him and advised him?
We stayed with him
loved and idolized him!
She betrayed him
shunned him and despised him!
She chose Raoul, chose to make a new start
Chose beauty and youth over genius and art
Fixed her aim on wealth and fame
Fled from the master
yet fled with his heart...
It seems a hundred years ago
when you and I were both on show
dancing side by side
shy and starry-eyed
The waves now bring you back to me
and any day we soon will be
side by side again
just the same as then
Ah, Christine! Long ago
how I watched, as you rose like a star!
Ah, Christine!
We have all traveled long
traveled far! Ah, Christine
You seem a thousand miles away
and yet your ship sets out today
Sails across the sea
bringing you to me
And I will show you all the sights
Manhattan's noise and Coney's lights!
Friends at last again
just the same as then!
Just like
way back when
(CHUCKLES)
(SHIP HORN BLARING)
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Hey, have the passengers disembarked yet?
Yeah, they're going through customs now.
Here they come!
Hey, it's Mrs. Astor.
Hey, Mrs. Astor! Over here!
Over there, Lucille!
Is that the latest Paris style?
Look, it's Colonel Vanderbilt!
Thanks, Colonel!
Hey, Colonel, is Christine
Daaé still on board?
I believe so, young man.
What's she doing?
Waiting for the conductor?
Hey, Christine, where are you?
(YODELING)
Look, there she is!
Christine Daaé!
Miss Daaé, over here!
WOMAN: Christine!
MAN: Christine!
Her name...
Her name is Madame de Chagny!
Stand aside.
Stand aside!
Gustave, come here.
No pictures, do you hear?
No pictures of the boy!
Hey, Christine, sing something!
Your first performance in years!
Why ain't ya singin' at the Met?
The vicomtesse has been engaged
by the well-known impresario,
Mr. Oscar Hammerstein,
to open his new Manhattan Opera House.
How'd he lure the great Christine
Daaé over here anyway?
It's the money, right?
All that American moolah!
My wife is an artist.
Oh, yeah, and her art is payin'
off your gambling debts,
is what they're sayin' in France.
Is it true you left your entire fortune
on a roulette table in Monte Carlo?
You insolent jackals!
How dare you!
Hey, kid, how does it feel
to have a famous mother?
Your first time to America?
It's two weeks till the Opera House opens.
What are you gonna do?
You gonna go see the Statue of Liberty?
Gonna ride the new subway?
You gonna go to the baseball?
I want to go to Coney Island.
And learn how to swim.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Mother, look!
Right over there!
Across the square!
That carriage!
Look at that! No horses!
That's the darnedest thing I've ever seen.
How does it work?
Honored friends
welcome to America!
Take a seat! Rest your feet!
Honored friends
Mr. Hammerstein's expecting you
Climb aboard, fledgling lord
Gustave!
Where is Hammerstein?
We were assured he'd be
here to greet us in person!
Here my dreams can wander free
Tell me what we're going to see!
This way, prima donna!
We three will escort you!
Please, Monsieur
Mr. Hammerstein
sent us to transport you
I give up.
Take us to Hammerstein!
Mysteries and melodies
play inside my mind
Fairytales and fantasies
silently unwind
Ask no questions, have no fear
Anything can happen here
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
I am your Angel of Music
Come to me, Angel of Music
What a dreadful town!
What a vulgar place!
What an awful mistake to have come here!
To be on display in that shameless way
for the crude, common
lower-class scum here
How could he dare to treat us so?
Father, dear, come play with me
Come and see this toy I've got
What a snub, at most
from our so-called host
Did he think sending freaks would be funny?
Could the fool have thought
that our pride was bought
by his filthy American money?
What a farce! What an
outright slap in the face
It's an utter disgrace
I've got a mind to pack and go
Never you mind the debts we owe
Who would believe we've sunk this low?
Father, please, come play with me
Gustave, enough!
The answer's no!
(PLAYING SOFT TUNE)
Must you play now?
I think it's beautiful.
RAOUL: What is it, anyway?
I don't know, it was
just here on the piano.
Well, it hurts my head.
Please, let's not fight, dear
I'm sure Mr. Hammerstein
never intended a slight, dear
How dare he patronize us?
We should never have accepted
We need the money, that's all
That's why things haven't been right, dear
Why doesn't it surprise me
that I get the blame here?
Let's leave tonight, dear
if that would serve to
ease your troubled mind
Leave the hurt behind
Father, dear, come over here
and look at what they gave to me
Wind it up and, Father, see
Look, it plays a melody
Raoul.
(KNOCKING)
What's this?
What is it?
It's from Hammerstein.
He wants to meet me in
the hotel bar. Alone.
Alone?
Well, he may lack courtesy,
but he does show a certain savoir faire
in choosing a business rendezvous.
Raoul, please.
Please what?
Nothing.
Father never plays with me
Doesn't he love me?
Oh, darling.
Love's a curious thing
It often comes disguised
Look at love the wrong way
it goes unrecognized
So look with your heart
and not with your eyes
The heart understands
The heart never lies
Believe what it feels
and trust what it shows
Look with your heart
The heart always knows
Love is not always beautiful
not at the start
So open your arms
and close your eyes tight
Look with your heart
and when it finds love
your heart will be right
Learn from someone who knows
Make sure you don't forget
Love you misunderstand
is love that you'll regret
Look with your heart
and not with your eyes
The heart can't be fooled
The heart is too wise
Forget what you think
Ignore what you hear
Look with your heart, it always sees clear
Love is not always beautiful (LAUGHING)
not at the start
But open your arms
and close your eyes tight
Look with your heart
and when it finds love
your heart will be right
Time for bed now, Gustave.
I'll be in in a minute.
(GASPING)
So it was all an empty lie?
One final lie to fool us all?
To make your death our story's end?
To put your life beyond recall?
How dare you come and claim me now
invade my life, ensnare my voice?
If you could know the pain I've known
then you would know I had no choice
My Christine
Your Christine
I was yours one brief night long ago
Long ago
with a man that I no longer know
Ah, Christine!
You came and found where I hid
Don't you deny that you did
that long ago night!
Once, there was a night
beneath a moonless sky
too dark to see a thing
too dark to even try
I stole to your side
tormented by my choice
I couldn't see your face
yet trembled at your voice
and I touched you
And I felt you
And I heard those ravishing refrains!
The music of your pulse
The singing in your veins!
And I held you
And I touched you
And embraced you
And I felt you
And with every breath and every sigh!
I felt no longer scared
I felt no longer shy
BOTH: At last,
our feelings bared
beneath the moonless sky
And blind in the dark
as soul gazed into soul
I looked into your heart
and saw you pure and whole
Cloaked under the night
with nothing to suppress
a woman and a man
no more and yet no less
And I kissed you
And caressed you
And the world around us fell away
We said things in the dark
we never dared to say
And I caught you
And I kissed you
And I took you And I begged you
With a need too urgent to deny
And nothing mattered then
except for you and I
Again and then again
beneath the moonless sky
And when it was done
before the sun could rise
ashamed of what I was
afraid to see your eyes
I stood while you slept
and whispered a goodbye
And slipped into the dark
beneath the moonless sky
And I loved you!
Yes, I loved you!
I'd have followed anywhere you led
I woke to swear my love
and found you gone instead
And I loved you!
I loved you!
And I left you!
How I loved you!
And I had to, both of us knew why
We both knew why
And yet I won't regret
from now until I die
the night I can't forget
beneath a moonless sky
And now?
How can you talk of now?
For us...
There is no now.
Once upon another time
our story had only begun
You chose to turn the page
and I made choices, too
Once upon that other time
we did what we thought must be done
And now, we have no choice
We do what we must do
We love, we live
we give what we can give
and take
what little we deserve
Once upon another time
I knew how our story would end
and maybe I was wrong
but now the moment's gone
Were it still that other time
I'd make time itself somehow bend!
But now I'm not that strong
and time keeps moving on
We love, we live
we give what we can give
and take
what little we deserve
We love, we live
we give what we can give
and take
what little we deserve
Once upon
another
time
(PANTING)
Ten long years of yearning
years of dreaming of this moment
when that miracle
that peerless instrument
plays for me just fleetingly
lays the ghost which tortures me
Tortures me
Ah, Christine
I know what Hammerstein is paying you.
I will double the amount
for just one night's work.
Here, in my concert hall.
No.
Just one night, Christine.
One song.
That is all I ask.
Why should I?
For 10 years, you've let
me believe you were dead,
and now you lure us here and
expect me to do your bidding,
submit to you again.
I won't do it.
I owe you nothing.
Mother, please, I'm scared!
What a dream, an awful dream!
Someone strange and mad
Seizing me and drowning me
Gustave, it's all right, darling.
Come and meet a friend of mine
Welcome to my world, young friend
Your world?
Where are we?
We're in Phantasma, little vicomte.
On Coney Island.
A world of fantasy
where illusion is emperor.
Tell me where you'd like to go
Tell me what you want to see
Madam, please, I insist
Could you show me, if you please
all Phantasma's mysteries?
All that's strange and wild and dark
in the shadows of the park?
You shall see it all tomorrow.
In fact, I myself will show you.
I promise.
CHRISTINE: Back to sleep
now, Gustave.
Why does he wear a mask,
Mother? Is he a magician?
Yes, darling.
In his way.
What a child.
Full of life.
Full of you, my Christine.
Help me through this sadness
Do this kindness for your mentor
or your progeny
that perfect specimen, may disappear
on Coney Island
Vanish here
Ah, Christine
What are you saying?
How could you?
After all that we've been.
Who are you?
I am your Angel of Music!
I am dying, Christine!
Suffocating here in the dark!
Give me breath! Give me life! Sing for me!
Or I will take from you
everything you have ever loved.
No, no, you can't!
Oh, but I can.
A man as hideous as this, believe
me, is capable of anything.
And what am I to sing?
One song composed by me
And then we're free to leave?
And will, of course, receive a princely fee
Is it on with the show?
Does he stay, does he go?
(SOBBING)
(HUMMING)
He's nowhere to be seen.
Insolence!
Who?
Hammerstein.
What the devil is going on in this place?
Darling.
Christine?
Things have changed, Raoul.
Bathing beauty on the beach
see her practically glow!
Takin' the sun in,
till all the boys are runnin'!
Rollin' in clover,
and gettin' tan all over!
Wearing a smile and giving Coney Island
a bathing beaut
of a show!
Bathing beauty, say hello
Gentlemen, gentlemen, you must take care.
Go spend some time working with Meg.
Ladies, come, let's go
over the port de bras.
Gentlemen, remember to
plié before the lift.
Then some control, gentlemen, please.
(GUSTAVE LAUGHING)
Slow down, Gustave. There are
people working here, be careful.
But I want to find Mr. Y,
and go see the island.
I'm sure he'll send
for you when he's ready.
Who is this Mr. Y?
What does he do?
Apart from spend ludicrous amounts of money
on light entertainment?
Father, look over there!
Gustave, slow down!
Heaven help me, could it be?
No, it couldn't possibly
Sorry, do I...
Yes, I think you do!
Have we...
Go on, take a guess!
Wait, it can't be! Is it...
Yes!
Oh, my God, I can't believe it's you!
Look at you, Christine! Regal
as a queen and beautiful!
Meg, and you as well!
I could hardly tell it's you!
My dear old friend!
Can't believe you're here, old friend!
After all this time!
Christine, you came!
You look sublime!
You look the same!
My sweet old friend
never thought we'd meet, old friend!
What of your career?
Everything's great
And isn't fate a splendid thing!
It brought me here...
To see the sights?
And sing!
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
Oh, my goodness!
You!
My God, it's you!
It can't be true Is this a dream?
It's been 10 years
What brings you here?
Who do you think?
Christine
She's here to sing
I read the news.
For Hammerstein?
No, plans have changed.
He's been outbid
Outbid by whom?
The contract's here.
It's rather strange
Sorry, did I hear you right?
Here to sing?
Tomorrow night
That seems odd, there must be some
mistake That's the leading lady's slot
I've been booked No, surely not
This was meant to be my lucky break
Look, I hardly sing
Just one little thing, an aria
Christine, it's a thrill just
to share the bill with you
My dear old friend
it's becoming clear, old friend
someone's overlooked his leading act
Well, double booked to be exact
Now, my old friend
Can you clarify, old friend
this Mr. Y
with whom we've signed
who hides behind the pseudonym?
You haven't guessed?
I've no idea
It's him!
Him?
That's what I said
You work for him!
Now you do, too
And my poor wife, we thought him dead!
She'll be appalled!
Unless she knew
Darling, please, are you all right?
Tell me now, this music!
Who was its creator?
Darling, please, don't squeeze so tight
Something's going on here
I'll deal with you later
What's this about?
I wish I knew
The truth will out before we're through
My dear old friend
Can't believe you're here, old friend
My dear Christine
My dear vicomte
What does this mean?
What does he want?
My grand old friend
I don't understand, old friend
Maybe it's a joke!
Some silly game!
And what his aim is in the end
I couldn't claim to comprehend
Old friend!
It isn't fair!
We need to think
I need some air
I need a drink
My poor old friend
Isn't this a bore, old friend?
I'm still amazed
I'm still confused
I'm feeling dazed
I'm feeling used
And yet, old friends let's
not get upset, old friends
We can sort this out
I'm sure we will
Without a doubt
Because we're still
such grand old friends
such devoted, grand old friends
Back again at last with everyone
Isn't it great?
Won't this be so much fun?
With two old friends trustable
and true, old friends!
Let us raise a glass
To times gone by
To Mr. Y
To happy ends
To such sincere
and very dear
old friends
Old friends
No offense, but I need
something stronger. Raoul!
Madame, I shall see you
tomorrow night at the concert,
where I am sure you will
both surpass yourselves.
Good day.
Raoul! Please.
I can explain!
I'm sorry.
Meg, I wonder would
you mind... Gustave?
What's wrong? My son. He was with...
Gustave! Gustave!
MEG: Christine, wait!
Come along and follow us
Come and follow faster
Come and meet the master
Hurry up and follow us
Hurry if you care to
Soon the dark will swallow us
Follow if you dare to
What is this place?
This is my realm, illusion's domain
where music and beauty and artifice reign
One moment, little vicomte,
while I prepare our adventure.
May I?
Does the young vicomte play?
(PIANO PLAYING)
What's this?
Just a song in my head
Go on.
I think it's beautiful
Hear how each note seems to float?
Hear how they all die and fall?
Just like the night
It's beautiful
This boy...
So very beautiful!
This music...
Music that comes uncontrolled
He plays like me...
Haunting and lovely and bold
He's just 10 years old
Ten years
old!
My God!
Come with me.
I need to show you something.
Follow me. I want to
know what you think!
Have you ever yearned to go past
the world you think you know?
Been enthralled to the call
of the beauty underneath?
Have you let it draw you in past
the place where dreams begin?
Felt the full breathless pull
of the beauty underneath?
When the dark unfolds its wings
do you sense the strangest things?
Things no one would ever guess?
Things mere words cannot express?
Yes!
Do you find yourself beguiled
by the dangerous and wild?
Do you feed on the need
for the beauty underneath?
Have you felt your senses surge
and surrendered to the urge?
And been hooked as you looked
at the beauty underneath?
When you stare behind the night
can you glimpse its primal might?
Might you hunger to possess
hunger that you can't repress?
Yes!
It seems so beautiful!
So strange yet beautiful!
Everything's just as you say!
And he's so beautiful
Perhaps too beautiful
What I suspect cannot be
And yet somehow we both see
the very same way!
Is there music in your head?
Have you followed where it led
and been graced with a taste
of the beauty underneath?
Does it fill your every sense?
Is it terribly intense?
Tell me you need it, too
need the beauty underneath!
When it lifts its voice and sings
don't you feel amazing things?
Things you know you can't confess?
Things you thirst for nonetheless?
It's all so beautiful!
PHANTOM: Can it be?
Almost too beautiful!
Do you see what I see?
Heavenly!
To him, it's beautiful!
My world is beautiful!
How can this be what it seems?
All of my most secret dreams
somehow set free!
You can feel it?
Yes!
Come closer
You've no fear of the beauty underneath?
You can face it?
Yes!
You can take it?
You see through to the beauty underneath?
To the splendor?
And the splendor!
And the glory?
Glory!
To the truth of the beauty underneath?
The beauty underneath!
You'll accept it!
GUSTAVE: Yes!
PHANTOM:
You'll embrace it!
GUSTAVE: Yes!
Let me show you the beauty underneath!
To the splendor!
Splendor!
And the glory!
To the truth of the beauty underneath!
The beauty underneath!
You'll accept it!
Yes!
You'll embrace it!
Let me show you the beauty under...
(GUSTAVE SCREAMS)
MEG: Gustave!
CHRISTINE: Gustave! Gustave!
Gustave. It's all right!
It's me!
It's horrible, horrible!
Shh. Don't be frightened.
PHANTOM: How could you
think I wouldn't guess?
How could you think I wouldn't know?
Do you have something to confess?
I want the truth, right now, if so!
Listen, darling, I want
you to go with Miss Giry
back to the hotel.
All right?
I have to talk
to Mr. Y alone.
Meg, do you mind?
Please? Please.
Once upon another time
you loved me
yet left me alone
But that's not all you did
You left me with a son
Ever since that other time
I've wished you could somehow have known
I kept the secret hid
the secret my marriage forbid
What else could I have done?
Just love
A son!
Just live
My son!
Just give what I could give
and take
what little I deserve
Forgive me.
He sees me and shuns me
as you did once
Take him now, take him and go!
Go now, be free!
But swear one thing to me
He will never, ever know!
I swear it
Believe me
You know you have my word
And I swear this music
won't remain unheard
This music
your music will live again!
One last time
just as I swore!
BOTH: And soul to soul
we will once more be whole
when I hear you sing
once more
From out of ugliness, such light!
From out of darkness, such a flame!
In him my wrongness is made right
and yet he loathes me, just the same!
So let him shun me in disgust!
Let him flee this cursed face!
If I must hide from him, I must
yet he shall be
my saving grace!
For Christine, my Christine
if it's true, he's my reason to live!
Ah, Christine
then our son shall have all I can give!
Ah, Christine!
All I create on this Earth
all that I'll never be worth
all shall be his!
All shall be his?
Ten long years, and he casts us aside!
Ten whole years, this is how we're repaid!
Ten dark years of toil and tears
and now what we've worked for
will go to that child!
All our hopes
were at last in our grasp!
All the dreams and the plans that we laid!
Everything is vanishing
and we get discarded, rejected, reviled!
All of the bonds in between us, now torn!
All of the love that we gave him foresworn!
All would be ours
if that bastard had never been born!
One more.
Ah, buddy, don't you think you had enough?
It's practically morning already.
One more, I said!
All right.
My shift is over anyway, so
let's settle the bill, okay?
Jeez, you're in a bad way, ain't ya?
Worse than most that wind up here.
Here's the morning shift. Maybe
he'll know what to do with you.
(SCOFFS)
Yes.
Yes, what to do with me.
That's the question, isn't it?
That's always been the question,
ever since the beginning.
She looks for sympathy
I give her sorrow
She asks for honesty
I've none to borrow
She needs my tender kiss
She begs it of me
I give her ugliness
Why does she love me?
She yearns for higher things
Things I can't give her
The rush that music brings
I can't deliver
And even when she sings
And soars above me
I try to clip her wings
Why does she love me?
One more drink, sir
That's what I need, don't you think, sir?
Leave the hurt behind...
Did you hear me?
Another drink!
She wants the man I was
Husband and father
At least, she thinks she does
She needn't bother
Beneath this mask I wear
There's nothing of me
Just horror, shame, despair
Why does she love me?
How 'bout you, sir?
Tell me, what am I to do, sir?
Leave the hurt behind
Morning, Bernie Coffee, please
Hurry up before I freeze
I'll just take it black
Vicomte.
Fancy meeting you here.
Miss Giry.
Drowning your sorrows, are you?
On the contrary, I'm celebrating
a reunion with old friends.
Friends I had long thought dead and buried.
And you?
Me?
I've been for a swim.
This town is coarse and cold and mean
It's hard to keep your conscience clean
Faceless in the crowd
Anything's allowed
And so I come at dawn each day
Come to wash it all away
Sink into the sea
Blue and cool and kind
Let it set me free
Let the past unwind
Leave the hurt behind
Miss Giry?
What do you think will happen, Vicomte?
At the concert.
Have you thought?
When he hears her sing
again? When she sings...
Miss Giry, I wish I knew.
But I'm afraid her music has always
been somewhat of a mystery to me.
But there's more to this
than the music, monsieur.
Believe me. I saw it.
There's something...
I don't know.
Just take her away. Now.
For all our sakes.
Sail across the sea
Put us out of mind
Close your eyes and flee
Let yourself stay blind
What do you mean?
What are you talking about?
Trust me, monsieur.
Don't let her sing.
Once he gets into her soul, there's
nothing she won't do for him.
Leave this place behind
Miss Giry! Miss Giry!
He's not Mephistopheles, you know?
When it comes down to it, he's
just another circus freak.
I'm not afraid of him.
No. It can't be!
Not afraid of me, you say?
Stay back! Or I'll kill you, I promise you.
Insolent boy.
You think you own more
of her soul than I do?
She is my wife!
Your music may speak to her,
but her heart will always follow me.
You think so?
You really think so?
Follow you?
With all your charms?
Look at you, deep in debt
Stinking drunk, pitiful
Shall we two make a bet?
Devil take the hindmost?
Look at you, foul as sin
Hideous, horrible
Call the stakes, deal me in
Devil take the hindmost
Our Christine shall choose
tonight Let her choose
Is she yours or mine?
Draw the line
If she sings, you lose tonight I won't lose
You leave from here?
Fine
Disappear?
And if she won't?
If I win?
All your debts wiped away
Very well, let's begin
BOTH: Devil take the hindmost
Our old game You think you have the odds
It's been changed
You think you're in control
Every throw... You think
you've fixed the dice
...riskier
Well, I will gladly roll
All the rules...
I'll bet against the house
...rearranged
I'll even double down
Fate has redesigned most
Fortune's on my side
Cut the deck I won her long ago
Let us play I won her from you then
You and I I wager even now
Once again I'll win her back again
In the end And when the game is done
Either way
BOTH: Devil take the hindmost
Now Christine shall choose at last
Is she yours or mine?
We've a son Our bond's secure
Are you sure?
What?
Are you so sure?
What do you mean?
Such a child Strange to see
Talented, musical
Is he more you or me?
Which one do you find most?
You lie!
Yet you doubt No woman could
Doubt your wife Or ever would
Doubt your son Love such a man
Everything You're insane
Now we play...
So now I play...
...for your life
... for my life
BOTH: Devil take the hindmost
Deal the cards I call your bluff
Let them fall The game is on
Choose your hand And we will see...
Try your best
... who wins out
He who wins...
Once and for all...
BOTH: Wins it all
Devil take the hindmost
(GROANS)
She walks, you leave together
Pockets full, debts paid
She sings...
You leave alone
Devil take the hindmost
Dear God, what have I done?
I could lose her forever.
My Christine!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Ladies, gents
You, good sir
And you, my friend
ALL: Everyone
Time for fun
Starting soon upon our stage
The performance of the age
Wonders and astonishments
for your delectation
Phantoms and automatons
for your fascination
Plus a finale to sweep you away
BOTH: Brought from Paree
to perform just one day
The beautiful, breathtaking Christine Daaé
But first, for those of you whose taste
is a little
more earth-bound...
It's Phantasma's
famous Ooh-La-La Girl!
The incomparable...
ALL: Meg Giry!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
I took a little trip to Coney Island
To get away from all the city sprawl
I couldn't bear to choose
Which bathing suit to use
So goodness me, I guess I brought 'em all
But when at last I got to Coney Island
And found myself a spot upon the sand
I noticed something strange
Ooh!
There was no place to change
And so I asked my friends to lend a hand
Girls?
(VOCALIZING)
GIRLS: Bathing beauty
Take a look at you
Bathing beauty on the beach
Bathing beauty, say hello
What a cutie!
What a peach!
Bathing beauty, watch her go
Posing under her parasol
She is what ya call a real spectacle
Prim and proper with class and poise
But she's got the boys apoplectical
Bathing beauty on the beach
See her practically glow
Wearing a smile and giving Coney Island
A bathing beaut of a show
Bathing beauty on the beach
Checks.
MEN: What a cutie!
What a peach!
Stripes.
ALL: Bathing beauty
Bathing beauty
Dots?
GIRLS: Dots?
Dots? Dots?
MEN: Dots?
Dots?
ALL: Dots!
Bathing beauty on the beach
See her practically glow
Taking the sun in
Till all the boys go running
ALL: Rolling in clover
And getting tan all over
ALL: Wearing a smile
And giving Coney Island
ALL: A bathing beaut
Of a show
Bathing beauty, say...
Hello!
Whoo!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Ladies and gentlemen, Miss Meg
Giry, the Ooh-La-La Girl!
In just a few moments, Christine Daaé,
the world's most celebrated songbird,
will be making her American debut.
Mother, did you watch?
Everything is solved
Mother, can you tell? The
new routine it went so well
I was worried just a touch
That it might've been too much
Just a bit Well, rather free
But just listen to that crowd
Why, they've never been so
loud Screaming only for me
Meg...
And the master must have heard
Every note and every word
Mother, tell me, did he see?
Meg, stop it.
Even he will now concede
I'm the only one he'll need
Meg, sweet fool You did all that you could
Charming, bright And yet still not enough
What do you mean?
How you danced!
They're all entranced
Yes, all but the one whose
entrancement we sought
He wasn't even there?
Where, poor girl, do you think that he was?
Yes, that's right, in with her all along
With Christine?
Dreaming of their son, their love
Too smitten to spare you
one moment of thought
Their son?
All that you gave him has all been a waste
No, you're wrong!
All that you've done It has all been erased
Don't say that!
Now he has them
As for us We have both been replaced
No! No!
Gustave, could you hand me those earrings?
The sapphires on the left.
There!
How do I look?
You look so beautiful
So very beautiful
Like a queen in a book
You, too, are beautiful
So very beautiful
Once this performance is through
We'll spend some time, just us two
Won't that be fun?
Father! Doesn't Mother look lovely tonight?
Indeed she does.
As lovely as she looked the very first time
I came to her
dressing-room door.
And look at you, Raoul.
You look just like that
handsome boy in the opera-box,
the one who would always
toss me a single red rose.
Please, Gustave If you don't mind
Would you wait outside a while?
But when's Mother going to sing?
We don't want to miss it.
Go and wait backstage, my dear
Soon Papa will fetch you there
You can both watch from the wings.
Since our wedding day
Things have gone astray
Raoul...
I'm not proud of the way that I've acted
We've both been...
The demands I've made All our hopes mislaid
I'm aware of the price they've exacted
Though I've no right to ask you to
There's one thing more I'd have you do
If you love me as I love you
Anything, darling.
Don't sing the song, dear
What? But...
You have to know something's
terribly wrong, dear
But I have to do this
It's what we agreed to
That hell-spawned demon
He's had us playing
his game all along, dear
Let me just get through this
Listen, please I need to
You need so much, it's true
And I've denied you
You need the man you knew
Back here beside you
You'll have him back, I vow
Just ask it of me
But we must leave here now
If you still love me
But, darling, I'm due
on stage in 10 minutes.
How can I possibly...
I beg you please. Please.
I have a passage for three to
Cherbourg on the Atlantic Queen.
It leaves tonight. Let's be
on it, for both our sakes.
And for Gustave.
Leave this place behind
Go and find Gustave.
Tell the stage manager not to disturb me.
I need some time.
You know his love is not enough
You know it isn't what you need
You know you're made of finer stuff
I think on that we're all agreed
It's time to leave him in the dust
It's time to be who you should be
It's time to do now as you must
And set the music in you free
In moments
Mere moments
Drums will roll
There you'll stand Just like before
The crowd will hush
And then in one sweet rush
I will hear you sing once more
And music, our music
Will swell and then unwind
Like two strands of melody
At last entwined
Fulfill us
Complete us
Make us whole
Seal our bond forevermore
Tonight, for me
Embrace your destiny
Let me hear you sing
Once more
STAGE MANAGER:
Five minutes, Miss Daaé.
Twisted every way What answer can I give?
I know I can't refuse
And yet I wish I could
Oh, God
RAOUL: Christine!
Christine!
Don't think that I don't care
PHANTOM: But every hope
and every prayer
Rests on you now
(VOCALIZING)
Ready on the rail?
STAGE HAND 1:
Ready on the rail.
(CONTINUES VOCALIZING)
Will she sing?
Will she flee?
What is she thinking now?
Is it him?
Is it me?
Devil take the hindmost
STAGE MANAGER:
Ready on the floor?
STAGE HAND 2:
Ready on the floor!
RAOUL: Will she stay?
PHANTOM: Obey your heart
Will she go?
And sing for me
Does she know even now? You
want it so, stay and be mine
Please, Christine, stop the show Eternally
BOTH: Devil take the hindmost
Now it's time So make your choice
Do it for our son
PHANTOM: Use your head
RAOUL: No time to wait
Hesitate We're all undone!
STAGE MANAGER:
Ready in the pit?
STAGE HAND 3:
Ready in the pit!
Perhaps she won't go on
Perhaps she'll lose her nerve
Perhaps her voice won't serve
And she will fail him now
And then my child and I
We'll get what we deserve
ALL: Devil take the hindmost
Perhaps she won't go on
Perhaps she'll lose her nerve
Perhaps her voice won't serve
And she will fail him now
And then my child and I
We'll get what we deserve
ALL: Devil take the hindmost
Now it's time No turning back
All is on the line
Here it is The final dance
One last chance To get what's mine
I hope Christine is worthy of you.
I hope her singing makes
up for what your blindness
has done to Meg and me.
Devil take the hindmost
STAGE MANAGER: And curtain.
Who knows when love begins?
Who knows what makes it start?
One day it's simply there
Alive inside in your heart
It slips into your thoughts
It infiltrates your soul
It takes you by surprise
Then seizes full control
Try to deny it And try to protest
But love won't let you go
Once you've been possessed
Love never dies
Love never falters
Once it has spoken
Love is yours
Love never fades
Love never alters
Hearts may get broken
Love endures
And soon as you submit
Surrender flesh and bone
That love takes on a life
Far greater than your own
It uses you at whim
And drives you to despair
And forces you to feel
More joy than you can bear
Love gives you pleasure
And love brings you pain
And yet, when both are gone
Love will still remain
Once it has spoken
Love is yours
Love never dies
Love never alters
Hearts may get broken
Love endures
Love never dies
Love will continue
Love keeps on beating
When you're gone
Love never dies
Once it is in you
Life may be fleeting
Love lives on
(GASPS)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Ah, Christine My Christine
What a triumph you gave me tonight
My Christine
All the dark, silent years now put right
Ah, Christine
The song was beautiful
It sounded beautiful
Every note Every word
And it felt beautiful
And I felt beautiful
BOTH: Lost in
the music once more
Feeling it rise up and soar
Alive once again
(GASPING)
"My dearest wife."
Little Lotte, I beg you, forgive me
Raoul, no!
RAOUL: Little Lotte Ah,
what fools we once were
BOTH: Long ago, in our youth
"In Paris, at the opera"
Romantic idiots.
"Those two people
are gone."
BOTH: Now I must go
Our choices are made
The opera is done The last
notes have been played
May your angel of music Watch over you now
And give you what I wish I gave you somehow
Yours, in regret...
"Raoul."
Gustave.
What is it?
What's wrong?
I told him to wait for Raoul.
Before he asked me to...
Surely he wouldn't...
That perfidious Raoul I
will kill that drunken fool
That he'd dare take this
child A child that isn't his
SQUELCH: Sir.
The Vicomte de Chagny left here alone, sir
Saw with my own eyes, sir
There was no one with him
Was there anyone else here backstage?
Madame Giry, she was here
With that vicious little sneer
And that comment she made The
ungrateful, back-biting snake
Go now, quickly Bring her round
Bring the boy back safe and sound
Then I'll make that vixen pay
What is the meaning of this?
How dare your circus ghouls
manhandle me in this fashion?
The boy, woman!
What have you done with him?
The boy? You think I took the boy?
Why would I do such a thing?
Do you think I don't know who he is?
FLECK: Sir?
I just passed Meg's dressing
room It was silent as a tomb
But her mirror was smashed
All in pieces on the floor
God, I left her so distraught
God knows what she must have thought
Foolish child, she must be caught
My poor Gustave!
But she won't hurt him!
Meg would never hurt him
I know where she's going.
But we must hurry!
(OMINOUS CARNIVAL
MUSIC PLAYING)
(ROARING)
Please, Miss Giry I want to go back
Gustave!
GUSTAVE: Miss Giry,
I can't swim.
I want my mother
The sea is calm The sea is gray
It washes everything away
Please. You're hurting me. I can't swim.
Don't worry.
It's almost over.
Sink into the deep
Blue and cool and kind
Then drift off to sleep
Let the past unwind
Leave the hurt behind
CHRISTINE: Gustave!
Mother?
PHANTOM:
Let go of the boy, now!
Not another step
Let go of him, girl.
Not another word
Always wondered how to make you watch
Well, watch me now
I took a little trip to Coney Island
I took a little trip because of you
I did as Mother said And
followed where you led
And tried to do what little I could do
But here's the way it works on Coney Island
They make you pay for every little crumb
I gave what they would take
I gave it for your sake
Now look at me
And see what I've become
Bathing beauty on the beach
Bathing beauty in her dressing room
Bathing beauty in the dark
On their laps In their arms
In their beds
Meg. My little Meg!
And who kept singing
Desperate for your favor?
Who kept dancing
Hoping you would save her?
Who kept dying?
And this is all you gave her
CHRISTINE: Gustave! PHANTOM: No,
don't do that, girl. Please.
(PHANTOM WEEPS)
Now that I've got your attention at last
(SOBBING) Here's the big
finish And then you can go
No, Meg, don't!
Give me the gun, Meg
Give me the hurt and the
pain And the gun, Meg
Give me the blame for not seeing
the things That you've done, Meg
Give me the gun, Meg
Give me the chance to see you clear at last
See me clear at last
You feel ugly You feel used
You feel broken You feel bruised
Ah, but me I can see
all the beauty underneath
Yes.
You've been robbed of love and pride
Been ignored and cast aside
Even so, I still know
There is beauty underneath
Yes.
Diamonds never sparkle bright
If they aren't set just right
Beauty sometimes goes unseen
We can't all be like Christine
Christine? Christine!
Always Christine!
(GUN FIRES)
(SHRIEKING)
(GASPING)
No! No! Madame Giry, get help.
Quickly!
Meg!
No!
Father!
Where's Father?
Gustave!
Your father...
Christine, no!
I know. I promised.
But you are all he has now.
He has to know the truth.
Christine, please.
Gustave.
Your father, your real father
is here.
No. No.
Look with your heart
And not with your eyes
The heart understands
The heart never lies
No!
Gustave!
Once upon another time
Our story had only begun
I had a taste of joy
The most I ever knew
Now there isn't any time
And somehow our story is done
And what about the boy?
What am I to do?
Just love
Just live
Just give what you can give
And take the love that you deserve
BOTH: Just love
Just live
And give...
I'll give all that I have
And take what little I deserve
Come closer I beg you
Closer still
Remember
Love never dies
Kiss me one last time
No!
(SOBBING)
Love never dies
Love never falters
Once it has spoken
Love is yours
Love never dies
Love will continue
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(AUDIENCE WHOOPING)
(AUDIENCE CLAPPING
RHYTHMICALLY)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING LOUDLY)