A
MightyMike77020
Christmas Sub.
♪ It's great to be back,
back, back, back, back, ♪
♪ Great to be back, on Broadway. ♪
♪ Great to be back
with the pack ♪
♪ On top of the
stack on Broadway ♪
♪ Telling the press ♪
♪ Heat up a mess ♪
♪ Of those bob bob
bob bob bobbles. ♪
♪ Flock of soc-soc-socko's ♪
♪ You'll need them for sure ♪
♪ House lights hit
that overture ♪
♪ Opening night, night,
flash, flash, flash ♪
♪ I'll be a smash on Broadway ♪
[whistles]
♪ It was a fight
fight bash bash ♪
♪ But I had to crash on Broadway. ♪
[Crash]
.
♪ I'm gonna shine.
Will you turn me on ♪
♪ Like the neon
that you see on ♪
♪ Broadway?! ♪
[Screech]
♪ Broadway! ♪
♪ Great to be back back
back back on Broadway. ♪
Hee hee, Now, where
is that theater?
"Stage door entrance."
Eh, I knew it every time.
[Crash]
I am t-the star.
[Pots, pans crashing]
I don't want to.
Ahh! Unhand me you roughnecks!
Call the police.
U-Unhand me I say.
Aah, aah Oof.
Magoo, where have you been?
Oh my god Sir, I'm afraid I'll have
to complain about your stagehands.
A-A bunch of roughnecks Sir.
See here Magoo,
Do you realize we been holding
the curtain for half an hour.
In that case my good fellow,
I suggest you stop wasting
time and bring it up.
Eee-Eee Ooo.
Places everybody.
[whistles]
Magoo! Your costume.
You're not in costume!
Relax my good man,
I've never missed
an entrance yet.
♪ I'm gonna shine.
Will you turn me on ♪
♪ Like the neon that you see on. ♪
♪ Broadway?! ♪
♪ Broadway! ♪
♪ Great to be back back
back back on Broadway. ♪
[women screaming]
Ahhh! Ohhh!
Ahhh!
Ha ha. Yes Sir!
♪ Broadway! ♪
He's made it.
Magoo is on stage.
Everything is going to be…
fine.
♫ Joy to the world,
the Lord is come! ♫
♫ Let earth receive her King. ♫
Merry Christmas.
Eh, eh. Thirty-five hundred.
Excellent, excellent.
Only thing to be
said for the season,
people feel obligated
to pay their debts.
Heh, heh, heh.
Oh, wouldn't old Jacob
Marley have been proud.
Heh, heh, yes.
Thirty-five hundred and twelve.
Money piling up, I love it!
Ha, ha, hay...
[door opens, bell rings, closes]
Scrooge and Marley's I believe.
Have I the pleasure of addressing
Mr. Scrooge or Mr. Marley?
Mr. Marley has been
dead these seven years.
We have no doubt his
liberality is well
represented by his
surviving partner.
At this festive season of
the year, Mr. Scrooge,
'tis more than usually desirable we
should make some slight provisions
for the poor and destitute.
Hundreds of thousands are in
want of common comforts, Sir.
Are there no prisons?
Plenty of prisons.
And the workhouses, uh, are
they, uh, still in operation?
They are. Still I wish I
could say, they were not.
What shall we put you down for?
Eh, nothing.
You wish to remain anonymous.
I wish to be left alone!
I support the establishments
I have mentioned,
they cost enough, and those who
are badly off, eh, must go there.
Many can't go there, and
many would rather die.
If they would rather die,
they had better do it
and decrease the
surplus population.
Now I'm very busy, gentlemen.
I BID YOU, GOOD AFTERNOON!
BE GONE! OUT!
[door closes]
[shivering]
[squeak]
Dratted busy-bodies.
A man can't get any work done.
Now, well, let's
see, where was I?
Huh, yes, come on... yes.
[clattering coins]
Oh... hee, hee.
Four thousand and six.
♪
Four thousand and twelve... huh.
♪ Ringle, ringle, coins
when they mingle ♪
♪ Make such a lovely sound. ♪
♪ Oo guineas and tuppence ♪
♪ And thruppence and bobs. ♪
♪ Make my ears tingle ♪
♪ And keep my heart throbbing. ♪
♪ Crowns and coppers, ♪
♪ Little eye-poppers ♪
♪ Can make my pulses pound. ♪
♪ Coin in a column ♪
♪ Can make the establishal ♪
♪ Denominational ♪
♪ Or alphabatical ♪
Alphabatical, ringle.
Ringle.
When they tingle
♪ Makes such a-ha lovely ♪
♪ Sound! ♪
Cratchit!
[Crash]
You've had you coal for today.
There will be no more.
Begging-begging you pardon, Sir.
I simply thought, Sir,
since it is Christmas Eve.
Since it is Christmas Eve.
This would be a disastrous time for
you, Cratchit, to find yourself
without a position.
Uh-oh, no Sir, yes, Sir
you're absolutely right, Sir.
Forgive me, Sir.
If you spend more time
tending to your job
you wouldn't have time
to feel the cold.
Bah! Blasted help situation.
He'll be wanting a feather bed and
tea service next thing, you know.
You never can... heeee.
Four thousand and thirty,
four thousand and thirty-six,
Ha, [wheezeing] hee, hee.
- ♪ Ringle, ringle, coins when they mingle ♪
- ♪ It's cold. ♪
- ♪ Make such a lovely sound. ♪
- ♪ It's cold. It's frightfully cold. ♪
- ♪ Ah, guineas and tuppence. ♪
- ♪ Please, ♪
- ♪ And thruppence and bob. ♪
- ♪ Please, Mister Scrooge. ♪
- ♪ Make my ears tingle. ♪
- ♪ Please, ♪
- ♪ And keep my heart throbbing. ♪
- ♪ One piece of coal. ♪
- ♪ Mister Scrooge, ♪
- ♪ And keep my heart throbbing. ♪
- ♪ Crowns and coppers, ♪
- ♪ Mister Scrooge, ♪
- ♪ It's cold. ♪
- ♪ Crowns and coppers, ♪
- ♪ Little eye-poppers ♪
- ♪ It's cold. ♪
- ♪ Can make my pulses pound. ♪
- ♪ So cold, so frightfully cold ♪
.
♪ Humbug, it's humbug its
giving to charity. ♪
♪ Orphans are pesky and
Christmas a parody. ♪
- ♪ Ringle, ringle, coins when they mingle ♪
- ♪ Please Mister, Please Mister. ♪
- ♪ Please Mister Scrooge. ♪
- ♪ Ringle, ringle, coins when they mingle ♪
- ♪ Make such a lovely sound. ♪
- ♪ It's cold, it's cold, it's cold. ♪
[lock clicks]
Cratchit!
Oh! You called, Sir?
In the future, Cratchit, I advise
you to take less time in answering.
Yes, Sir.
Eh, eh, secure this in the safe.
- And, mind you, you be careful.
- Yes Sir.
♫ Hark, the herald angels sing.
Glory to the new born King. ♫
- ♫ Peace on earth and mercy mild... ♫
- BE GONE!
Be gone you miserable little beggars,
before I give you something to sing about!
[ Cup clanks ]
Ah, don't you understand
the King's English?
[slam]
Nothing to eat and they
sing of Christmas.
Ah-ha bah humbug.
I might as well close
shop for the night.
We'll finish tomorrow.
Oh, but, Sir, tomorrow
is Christmas Day.
I have a holiday tomorrow.
You'll want all day, I suppose?
Oh, yes, Sir. Please,
Sir, you see I...
Never mind! It's Christmas.
Oh Lord, help us.
Hea, hea, hea. The whole
population is mad!
Will you stop! I'm,
I'm quite capable.
Hea, yegh. Fool.
A..very..Merry
Christmas to you, Sir.
Christmas! Ha! Bah! Humbug!
[slam]
Heh, heh, Merry Christmas.
Out upon Merry Christmas.
If I could work my will
every fool who goes about with
"Merry Christmas" on his lips
should be boiled
with his own pudding
and buried with a stake of
holly through his heart.
Bah!... Humbug!
[wind howling]
Mean weather. It's the
worst I can remember.
[lock clicks]
Oh! Humm. What have we here?
Soon take care of this.
Very strange. Very strange.
Eh, uh, could I need spectacles?
[thump]
Ooh!
By heavens. I-I'm seeing things.
Err, Perhaps I do
need spectacles.
No, no, no. This
miserable gruel.
That's no doubt the cause.
Sour, sour, that's what it is.
It's been a tiring day.
Sleep. Sleep, th-that's
what I need.
[wind howls]
Burr. Oh, ho, uh, wee.
Beastly wind.
Must have forgotten to
lock the cellar door.
[thump-clank, thump-clank,
thump-clank...]
Rats?
[thump-clank, thump-clank
thump-clank...]
Hear, h-hear, what
nonsense is this?
Ebeneezer,
Ebeneezer Scrooge.
Oh! Don't you b-believe
in knocking?
Would you have unbolted the door
to let me enter, Ebeneezer?
That door was bolted. Wh-who.
Who are you?
In life I was your
partner, Jacob Marley.
Humbug!
You don't believe in me.
I do not!
Still, you must admit
that you see me.
You might be nothing more than
that, sour gruel I ate at supper.
Eh, humbug.
Ohhhhhhhhhhhhh!
Ohh-aa-haa! Mercy,
dreadful apparition.
Why do you trouble me?
Do you believe in me or not?
Yes, yes, yes, I-I believe in you.
I do.
But, why do you walk the earth?
And, and why are you here?
Ohhhhhhhhhhhhhhh!
[rattle, rattle, rattle]
You are bound with chains.
Tell me why?
I wear the chain I
forged in life.
[thump-clank]
Do you know the weight
and the length of the
strong coil you bear yourself?
It is a ponderous chain.
More captive bound
and double-lined.
Not to know that
no space of regret
can make amends for one
slight opportunity misused.
Yet, such was I.
Look, this is the
fate that awaits you.
[wind gusts]
Ha-haaaa!
I am simply here to warn you
that you still have a
chance of escaping my fate.
You must expect the visits
of three more ghosts.
I think I'd rather not.
Expect the first tonight
when the bell tolls one.
Well, couldn't I take 'em all at
once and have it over, Jacob?
Ahhhhhhhhhhhhh!
[wind blowing]
Humbug!
[thump!]
I'm gonna get to bed, eh.
Huh, mmmm.
Of course, must have dozed
off for a few hours.
Huh, had a nightmare,
yea..tee-dum.
Humbug?
[ticking, strikes one]
Wha, wha, ooh, huh. Where am I?
Who, who did that?
Oh, can't a man sleep?
What, what.
I am the ghost of
Christmas present.
Look upon me. You have never
seen the like of me before.
Well, I'm not sure I see
the like of you now.
Oh, but I hear you, I hear you.
[Laughing]
So I've heard
You're the one who's
too tight with a penny
to buy himself a
pair of spectacles!
Come. Come and know
me better, man.
Are you the Spirit, Sir, who's
coming was foretold to me?
Touch my robe.
[thunder clap]
Have you visited this
dwelling, before?
No, no, no, no. I'm
certain that I haven't.
I thought as much.
[laughter]
Why are we here?
These people mean nothing to me.
Know you not the family of the
man who has slaved for you
from dawn to dark
these many years?
Bob Cratchit?
Uh, why, it's, it's impossible.
But they appear to be so happy.
I pay Cratchit a wage
of but 15 bob a week!
Their happiness lies in something
apparently quite foreign to you.
And, uh, what is that?
Love.
What is keeping your father
and your brother, Tiny Tim?
[child laughs]
Why bless you heart, my
dear, how late you are.
And how did Tiny Tim behave?
As good as gold and better.
He told me coming home that
he hoped the people saw him
in church because
he was a cripple.
And it might be pleasant to let
them remember upon Christmas Day
who made lame beggars
walk and blind men see.
Hurry children. Our
dinner is ready.
♫ Will we have a dinner and
some razzleberry dressing? ♫
♪ Oh, razzleberry
dressing would be nice. ♪
♫ Will we have a pudding made of
liver while we're guessing? ♫
♪ Or maybe razzleberry
dressing twice. ♪
♫ We haven't had a hen, since
I can't tell you when. ♫
♫ We'd love a hen again. ♫
♪ With razzleberry dressing. ♪
♫ We've been so awful good, ♫
♪ From me down to the baby. ♪
♫ And we're not made of wood. ♫
♪ Or razzleberry gravy ♪
♪ We'll have the Lord's
bright blessing ♪
♪ and knowing we're together, ♪
♪ Knowing we're together
heart and hand. ♪
♪ We'll make the
whitest Christmas. ♪
♪ The very brightest Christmas. ♪
♪ A Christmas far more
glorious than grand. ♪
♪ We can't afford to have a hen.
We will someday I vow, ♪
♪ so I suggest you
dream of then ♪
♪ and prize what we have now. ♪
♫ Could we have a Christmas tree
and on each branch a pudding. ♫
♫ Some woofle jelly cake
would be so nice. ♫
♫ Could we have a stocking full
of presents on it, could we? ♫
♫ Some woofle jelly
cake perhaps a slice. ♫
♫ And on the tree a star. Of
shining Christmas gold. ♫
♫ A candle in a jar ♫
♪ of razzleberry dressing. ♪
♪ We can't afford a
Christmas tree. ♪
♪ We will someday I vow. ♪
♪ Start smiling and
enjoy with me ♪
♪ the miracle of now. ♪
♪ We'll have the ♪
♫ Lord's bright blessing. And
knowing we're together. ♫
♫ Knowing we're together
heart and hand. ♫
♫ We'll have the whitest Christmas.
The very brightest Christmas. ♫
♫ A Christmas far more
glorious than grand. ♫
A very Merry Christmas
to us all, my dears.
God bless us.
God bless us every one.
What's wrong with that boy?
The tiny one?
I see vacant seat in the chimney corner
and a crutch, tenderly preserved.
If these shadows remain unaltered by
the future,... the child will die.
What then? If he'd like
to die, he'd better do it
and decrease the
surplus population.
[ Applause ]
[snoring]
[dong]
One o'clock.
Oh, One o'clock!
Oh, it isn't possible.
It was past two
when I went to bed.
An icicle must have
gotten into the works.
Uh, yes, that's what...
[ tympani ♪- ♪ ]
Who and what are you?
I am the ghost of
Christmas past.
Eh, long past?
No, your past.
Uh, what brought you here?
Your welfare.
Well, I'm much obliged. A
good night of unbroken rest.
I-is what I need. I-If
you're so concerned.
Rise and walk with me.
Oh, ho, humbug, forcing a-a
fellow to leave his bed.
In the middle of
the night and...
Come.
It's freezing cold!
Not a decent stitch of clothing
to warm these old bones.
But I am a mortal
and liable to fall.
Touch my hand and you
shall be upheld.
Why, why are we stopping here?
Do you know this place?
Good heavens. Why, I was
a, I was a boy here.
Do you remember the way?
Remember it? I could
walk it blindfolded.
- Merry Christmas!
- Hello, there!
Merry Christmas, Peter.
Merry Christmas, Jill.
A Merry Christmas, Mayfield.
A Merry Christmas,
Mrs. Doolittle.
Come. These are but shadows
of things that have been.
They are not conscious of us.
Do you know this child?
Eh, t-t-the child is,
is young Ebeneezer Scrooge!
You see he is left
here, all alone.
Nobody wants him. Poor lad.
♪ Oh, poor lonely child.
Poor lonely child. ♪
♪ When you're alone,
alone in the world. ♪
♪ When you're alone
in the world. ♪
♪ Blown away leaves get
blown in the world. ♪
♪ Swirled away leaves
get swirled. ♪
♪ Listening to your
heels when you walk. ♪
♪ Making a lonely clack. ♪
♪ You don't know how it
feels when you talk, ♪
♪ And nobody's voice talks back. ♪
♪ A hand for each hand was
planned for the world. ♪
♪ Why don't my fingers reach? ♪
♪ Millions of grains of
sand in the world. ♪
♪ Why such a lonely beach? ♪
♪ Where is a voice to
answer mine back? ♪
♪ Where are two shoes
that click to my clack? ♪
♪ I'm all alone in the world. ♪
♪ A hand for each hand was ♪
♪ planned for the world. ♪
♪ Why don't my fingers reach? ♪
♪ Millions of grains of sand in the world. ♪
♪ Why such a lonely beach? ♪
♪ Where is a voice to
answer mine back? ♪
♪ Where are two shoes
that click to my clack? ♪
♪ I'm all alone in the world. ♪
Come.
Let us see another Christmas.
Do you know this place?
I..yes... yes, I-I do!
I was apprentice here.
Come.
Why it's old Fezziwig, bless his heart.
It's old Fezziwig. And he's alive again.
Heh, heh, heh, heh. Yo-ho, there.
Ebeneezer, Dick!
- Yes, Sir.
- Coming, Sir.
Oh, Dick Wilkins, to be sure.
Bless me, yes.
He was very much attached
to me, was Dick.
Yo-ho, my boys. No
more work tonight.
Christmas Eve, Dick.
Christmas, Ebeneezer.
Heh, heh. Clear away my lads, and
let's have lots of room here.
Heh, heh.
[Swish, swish]
♪
Excellent.
Excellent!
♪♪
[happy voices]
Ho, he does love to dance.
Look at him dance.
[lady laughing]
Belle!
[Belle giggles]
[giggles again]
Huh, b-b-but she won't
dance with them.
Hum, hum, hee, hee.
♪
Did you see? She chose me.
Beautiful little Belle.
Hee-hee, She chose me.
Spirit!... They're gone!
Spirit!... They're vanished.
Not quite all.
- Was there ever such a party?
- Was there ever such a Christmas?
- Was there ever such an employer?
- Never, never, never.
A small matter to make these
silly folk so full of gratitude.
Small? It is impossible
to count it up in money.
The happiness he gave us is-is quite as
great as if (hee-hee) it cost a fortune.
My time grows short. Come.
It matters little.
To you, very little.
Another idol has displaced me.
What idol has displaced you?
A golden one.
This is the way of the world.
There's nothing on which it
is so hard as-as poverty.
Nothing which it condemns so
much as the pursuit of wealth.
Oh, I have watched
the change in you.
I have seen your noble
ideals fall off one by one
until... nothing matters
to you but gold.
True! I-I have grown
so much wiser.
I am going to release
you, Ebeneezer.
Have I ever sought release?
In words, no.
In-In what then?
In the very things you worship.
Tell me truthfully. If
you were free,... now,
would you choose a girl whose
father left so little money?
Yes, Belle, yes.
♪
Was it so long ago?
That sleigh ride,
the warm glow of happiness
when you asked me?
It was snowing. But
we didn't notice.
♪ Winter was warm ♪
♪ Summer soft that year ♪
♪ The winter was warm ♪
♪ Without a sign of frost ♪
♪ Like winter lost ♪
♪ Its way that year ♪
♪ It seems as I recall ♪
♪ No blossoms fell that fall ♪
♪ May didn't leave at all ♪
♪ Or did love paint an illusion? ♪
♪ Now trees with a sigh ♪
♪ Stand and shiver ♪
♪ while their dreams
fall and die ♪
♪ And all my dreams are there ♪
♪ Wrapped up somewhere
in summer leaves ♪
♪ Oh, what I'd give to be ♪
♪ To be in love again ♪
♪ This year the winter is cold ♪
♪ Will it ever be warm ♪
♪ As it was then? ♪
Goodbye, Ebeneezer.
Belle, Belle, d-don't leave!
[sobbing]
Belle, Belle.
Don't, don't leave.
Spirit, Spirit, show me no more.
One shadow more.
No no more, no, no, Spirit.
I don't wish to see it.
Spirit, I cannot
bear it any longer.
Uh, harm me no more.
Ha, ha, ha, ha...
Don't leave me. Don't...
[Sobbing]
O-o-oh my!
Oh!
Spirit.
Am, am I in the presence of the
ghost of Christmas yet to come?
[ominous tympani beat]
You are about to show me shadows
of things that will happen
in the time before us?
Is that so, Spirit?
[ominous tympani beat]
Ghost of the future. I fear you
more than any specter I have seen.
Will you not speak to me?
Lead on, Spirit, lead on.
[thunder clap]
[laughter]
Well, James. A-Good morning, Brady.
Morning Billings.
No, I don't know much
about it either way.
I only know he's dead.
When did he die?
Last night, I believe.
What was the matter with him?
- I thought he'd never die.
- Heaven only knows.
What's he done with his money?
He hasn't left it to me.
That's all I know.
Well, it's likely to
be a cheap funeral.
Upon my word, I don't know
anybody who'll go to it.
I don't mind going if a lunch is provided,
but I must be fed if I do. [Sniff]
[laughter]
[sniff, sneeze]
Spirit, what connection do these
people have with my future?
Of whom are they talking?
Jacob Marley's death was
in the past, and...
Where am I?
I-I'm always here at
this hour of the day.
Always.
[squeaks]
[Laughing]
Well! The char woman, the
laundress and the undertaker.
What poor stiff have
you robbed, now?
Not so poor that I shouldn't
get a handsome price.
Have a look.
Bed curtains, huh? You
don't mean to say you took
'em down rings and all
with him lyin' there?
[Laughing]
Why not? Who should care
for the likes of him?
I got his boots
and cuff buttons.
All I got was his sheets.
[hearty laughter]
[♪ lively march tune ♪]
♫ We're despicable. ♫
♫ We make ourselves. ♫
♫ Plain sickable. ♫
♪ Berate ourselves, hate
ourselves, viciously. ♪
♪ Still none of us wishes he...
would change. ♪
♪ We're slick as shifty birds. ♪
♫ With fingers quick...
as 50 birds. ♫
♪ While stealing your purse
or your ticky-tock. ♪
♪ Just for a kick we
knock you flat. ♪
♫ La, La, La la la la la. ♫
♫ We're just
blankety-blank-blank no good. ♫
♪ We're not tea party blokes. ♪
♪ No chitty-chat and artichokes. ♪
♪ We're twice as blood-thirsty
as canibules. ♪
♪ And wilder than animules...
are we. ♪
♫ We're reprehensible. ♫
♪ We'll steal your
pen and pencible. ♪
♪ Then sneer at you, leer
at you, naughtily. ♪
♫ And really we ought
to be in jail. ♫
♫ La, La, La la la la la. ♫
♪ La la la la la. ♪
.
♫ La, La, La la la la la. ♫
♪ La la la la la. ♪
.
♫ La, La, La la la la la. ♫
♪ La la la la la. ♪
♫ We're just
blankety-blank-blank all bad. ♫
[cackling laughter]
I-I see, I see. The case of that
poor, unhappy man might be my own.
My life tends that way now.
[cackling laughter]
Oh, please, kind Spirit,
let me see some tenderness
connected with the death.
Ah, sewing away my dear?
So late, Robert?
[Door closes]
I... I had something to
see to on my way home.
You went... there again?
Yes.
I-It does my heart good to
see how green a place it is.
But you'll see it often.
I-I had promised you that
we would walk there on Sundays.
[woeful crying]
Hush, my dear, hush.
Tears cannot bring
Tiny Tim back to us.
Tiny Tim! Ho-ho, no.
Oh, no, not Tiny Tim!
Sleep peacefully,...
my little love.
Spirit, could I not have done something,
so that Tiny Tim might still live?
Have I truly been so heartless?
Oh, Spirit, Spirit,
show me my future self.
[ominous tympani beat]
Oh, what, what is this?
B-Be, before I look,
tell me please.
Are these the shadows of
the things that will be,
or are they shadows of the
things that might be?
[ominous tympani beat]
[thunder crash and rumble]
No! No!
No. No, Spirit. No. I will
honor Christmas in my heart
a-and try to keep
it all the year!
And-and I will not
shut out the lessons
that have been taught to me.
I promise.
[sobbing]
Oh, tell me that I may sponge
away the writing on the stone.
Please, Spirit, please.
I beg of you.
Give me, give me some sign
that I may be saved from this.
Please, dear Spirit... oh, ho...
Spirit, Spirit, don't leave me here alone.
Oh, I'm afraid.
♪ You don't know how it
feels when you talk, ♪
♪ And nobody's voice talks back. ♪
[sobs]
♪ A hand for each hand was
planned for the world. ♪
♪ Why don't my fingers reach? ♪
♪ Millions of grains of
sand in the world. ♪
♪ Why such a lonely beach? ♪
♪ Where is a voice to
answer mine back? ♪
♪ Where are two shoes
that click to my clack. ♪
♪ I'm all alone in the world. ♪
[applause]
Oh, no, no. Please, Spirit, please.
Don't leave me here alone.
I'm afraid. Oh!
Oh, oh, who oh no um, my bed?
Oh, they are not torn
down, rings and all.
They are here.
And I am here.
The shadows of things that would
have been may be dispelled.
Oh, I know they will.
Oh, Jacob Marley, Heaven-in-the-
Christmas-Time be praised for this.
I say it on my knees, old Jacob.
Yessssss. I mean. Oh! Oh!
Oh, I don't know what to do.
Yeah, I'm as light as a feather.
I'm as happy as an angel, and I
am as merry as a school boy.
I'm as giddy as a drunken man.
Ha, ha, a Merry
Christmas to everybody.
Eh, ha, a happy New
Year to all the world.
I don't know how long I have
been among the spirits.
Yea, I don't know anything.
I am quite a baby. Hello there!
Hoop!
Hello! Hello, there!
[horse whinnies]
Ah, the same to you.
Oh, yes indeed. A
pleasant fellow.
Hello, there! Hee, hee,
hee, what's today?
Eh?
Ha, what's today,
my fine fellow?
Today?
Why, it's Christmas Day.
Whoop! Oh, it's Christmas
Day, and I haven't missed it.
The spirits have done
it all in one night.
Oh, do you hear? The spirits
have done it all in one night.
[laughs heartily]
Eh, tell me, do you
know the poultry
shop in the next
street, at the corner?
Do you, my boy?
Well, I should hope I did?
An intelligent boy.
A remarkable boy.
Do you know whether they've sold that
prize turkey that was hanging up there?
- The big one.
- What, the one as big as me?
Ho-ho, what a delightful boy.
It's a pleasure to talk to him.
Yes, yes, my buck.
Well, it's hanging there now.
It is? Well, go and buy it.
Whah-kur.
No, no. No, no, stay.
I am in earnest. You
go and buy it, and
tell 'em to bring it here.
Come back with them in less
than five minutes, my boy,
and I'll give you half a crown.
Hee, hee, hee.
A half a crown!
[Zoom]
Ho, ho, ho. A fine boy.
A clever boy.
Hee, hee. I'll send it to Bob Cratchit.
He shan't know who sent it.
It's twice the size
of Tiny Tim, Ha ha.
God heavens, they'll
need to be paid.
[clattering]
Money, money.
♪ Ringle, ringle coins
when they mingle ♪
♪ make such a... ♪
Hee, look at me.
Going outside like this
on Christmas morning.
Lock me up for a looney, they
will, I said, yes, ha, ha, ha.
Yes.
Oh, there now! Oh, that's
better, yes, ha, ha.
[ Opens door ]
Ahh, there you are.
[laughs heartily]
Hello, how are you?
Yes, Merry, Merry Christmas.
Well, [giggleing] yes,
Oh, oh, oh that is a turkey.
Why, it's impossible to
carry that to Camden Town.
My boy, you must have a cab.
Now, for the turkey, for the
cab, and for you, my boy,
an extra bonus for
a brilliant lad.
Ah-ha, Now, off with you.
Take it to Bob Cratchit,
at 21 Crovny Lane,
and, mind you, don't
say who sent it.
No, no, indeed.
It's a wonderful knocker. I shall
love it as long as I live.
[Door latches closed]
♪ Ah-nahh-dee-heigh-ho... ho.
Ah-ha, hello there.
Merry Christmas.
A Merry Christmas to you. Hello, there.
[thump!]
Oh, so sorry, old man.
Clumsy of me.
Oh, not at all. It's
my fault entirely.
- Mr. Scrooge?
- Do I know you?
Eh, ahem, we were in
your office last evening.
Oh, of course. How do you do?
A Merry Christmas to you, Sir.
Eh... you are, Mr. Scrooge?
Yes, I am. Allow me
to ask your pardon.
Here.
Bless me. My dear, Mr. Scrooge.
Are you serious?
Oh, if you please, and
not a farthing less.
I, I don't know what to say.
Say nothing, then. No. Thank you.
Much obliged.
A Merry Christmas, to you.
A Merry Christmas.
I'll give you Mr. Scrooge.
The founder of the feast.
The founder of the feast, indeed!
I wish I had him here!
I'd give him a piece of
my mind to feast upon!
Oh, my dear, Christmas Day.
Well, I'll drink his health for your
sake and the day's. Not for his.
Long life to him. A Merry Christmas
to him... and a happy New Year.
[children]
Merry Christmas to Mr. Scrooge.
Come now, it's Christmas.
Will we not do justice
to the this day and to
this delightful bird.
[All]
Ohhhhh. Ahhhhh.
[laughing]
Oh, such
a beautiful bird.
The biggest turkey
I've ever seen!
Who could have sent it?
[knock on door]
Now, who could that be?
Father Christmas?
More likely some poor beggar
who smelled our turkey.
If it is. He shall have some.
Cratchit!
What are you doing at home
when you should be working?
But-but, Sir. It's
Christmas Day.
Now, I'll tell you
what, my friend,
I am not going to stand for
this sort of thing any longer.
And therefore. And therefore...
I'm about to... to
raise your salary.
For wha... What's that?
A Merry Christmas, Bob. A merrier
Christmas, my good fellow,
than I have given you
for many a year.
Yes, that's what I'll do.
I'll raise your salary
and assist your, your
struggling family.
Oh, thank you, Sir.
Oh, ho, there, here we go.
♪ Ringle, ringle, coins
when they jingle, ♪
♪ Make such a lovely sound. ♪
♪ Guineas and tuppence and
thruppence and bobs. ♪
♪ Give them away and
nobody can rob you. ♪
♪ Crowns and coppers. Little eye-poppers
were made to pass around. ♪
♪ Let's say a prayer that
the lord never misses us ♪
♪ when he distributes his
blessings at Chrisamas. ♪
♪ Ringle, ringle, coins
when they jingle ♪
♪ make such a lovely sound. ♪
[laughs heartily]
Ha, ha, ha... ho, ho,
You're a child again, Sir.
Ha, a toast!
[all]
A toast!
A Merry Christmas. And
God bless all of you.
God bless us, everyone.
♫ Now, we have a Christmas tree
and on each branch a present. ♫
♪ Some woofle jelly cake,
perhaps, a slice. ♪
♫ And wood on the fireplace. A
home so warm and pleasant. ♫
♪ The woofle jelly
cake is very nice. ♪
[gobble]
♪ And on the tree a star of... ♪
♪  of shining Christmas gold. ♪
♪ A candle in a jar. ♪
♪ Of razzleberry dressing. ♪
♫ We'll have the Lord's bright
blessing, and knowing we're together. ♫
♫ Knowing we're together
heart and hand. ♫
Ah ha
.
♫ We'll make the Whitest Christmas, ♫
[Corus joins in]
♫ the lightest,
brightest Christmas. ♫
♫ A Christmas far
more glorious, ♫
more glorious than ♫
♫ A Christmas far
♫ Grand ♫
[applause]
[applause continues]
[Crowd murmuring]
Haw, Thank you.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen
What a marvelous ovation.
Turn around.
O-Our director.
Let's hear it for our director.
[Director grunts in pain]
Ladies and gentlemen
our director.
[sprong']
[creak]
Oh no.
[Bang]
[Bang Bang]
[Crash, Bam, Boink, Slam...]
Oh, will you listen to that applause.
Oh Magoo, oh you've
done it again.
By George I've brought
down the house!
Ah thank you, Merry
Christmas everyone.
Subtitles By:
MightyMike77020
Using: Subtitle Edit, Google Search
and Windows Speech Recognition.
If you like my Subtitle
Please leave a comment at
http://subscene.com/u/759958/subtitles
It would be greatly appreciated.