IDDY:  Once upon a time
there was a prince
who set out on a long journey
in search of a great treasure.
Though he traveled far
and brought back many gifts,
he began his journey home
looking for something more.
Halt. We shall camp here.
- Your Highness,
- why camp here?
We are so close
to your father's castle.
The men are tired,
and soon it will be dark.
Besides, there's something
about this place.
I don't know what it is.
Is the air more clear?
It is. It is home.
Strange.
I don't remember
this part of the wood.
Let me see the map.
I don't see this place
on the map.
You are right, Sire.
It is not marked.
So close to home
and we've made a discovery.
Watch over the camp.
Make sure the tents
are set before nightfall.
I'm going to scout
this forest.
Your Highness, be careful.
These woods are
full of surprises.
Bewitched men
may be lurking about.
♪ I'm going home
with gold and silver from
all the battles I've won
♪ But even though
I've so many treasures
♪ I have a feeling
I've none
♪ I left Father's kingdom
♪ And traveled away
♪ I crossed
through the oceans
Climbed over mountains
♪ Searched every way
♪ But where am I going?
♪ What do I search for?
♪ And where is my princess?
♪ Where is the one
I long for?
♪ Long for
Where?
♪ Is she there
beyond the river?
♪ Or somewhere
upon its shore?
♪ Is there a path
within these woods
♪ That will lead me
to her door?
♪ The journey is ending
♪ What did I learn?
♪ I still have not found it
Shall I continue?
♪ Shall I return?
♪ Where am I going?
♪ What do I search for?
♪ And where is my princess?
♪ Where is the one
I long for?
♪ Long for
Where? ♪
(SQUAWKS)
A guardian raven.
Fairest beauty.
Are you asleep?
(RATTLING)
IDDY: Left, right.
Left, right.
Forward, men.
Forward.
There she rests,
as perfect as the day
we put her here.
- The spell has
- not been broken.
Look.
BIDDY: Someone has been here.
Somebody is here.
Stand back, enchanted men.
Here lies a true princess.
- We know.
- GIDDY: We put her here.
You knew her?
We took her in.
But the lacing
was too tight.
- We think
- it's a spell.
Shh! Let's start
at the beginning.
Many years ago,
there was a kingdom
ruled by a wise king
and a fair queen.
One clear winter day,
it began to snow.
♪ When the winter wind
starts blowing
All the ladies start to sew
♪ They need clothes
in which to bundle up
To keep them from the snow
ALL:
♪ Let it snow
♪ Out of the clouds
♪ Swirl through the breeze
♪ Cover the treetops
♪ Don't catch a sneeze
ALL:
♪ Whether it's day or night
♪ Cover the world
with white
- ♪ Let it snow
♪ Let it snow
♪ Let it pile up
to the door
♪ We'll sit
beside the window
ALL:
♪ And watch it snow some more
Why is my lady so sad?
- Not sad,
- just dreaming.
About what?
♪ In the morning
when my ladies
sit and sew
ALL:
♪ White linen sew
♪ It makes me dream
I had a child with skin as
white as snow, white as snow
ALL:
♪ As white as snow
♪ I'll cuddle her
in my arms
♪ And teach her
to dance and sing
♪ We'll make a snowman
in the snow
♪ Who looks
just like the King
- ♪ Let it snow
♪ Let it snow
♪ I'll roll it up
in a ball
- ♪ I'll sit
- beside the fire
ALL:
♪ And watch it fall and fall
ALL: Your Majesty.
Shh.
(GASPS)
- My dearest,
- I've frightened you.
Oh, no, my husband,
I was just dreaming.
Your Majesty, your finger.
Put it in the snow.
I, too,
have been having
that same dream.
That we might
one day have
a little child,
with hair as black
as those ebony shutters,
cheeks as red
as that drop of blood,
and skin as white as snow.
- ALL:
- ♪ Let it snow
Let it snow
- Let it snow
♪ Let it snow
Let it snow
- ♪ Let it snow
- Let it snow
♪ Let it snow
♪ Let it snow ♪
(PLAYING FANFARE)
(CROWD MURMURING)
"Hear ye, hear ye,
one and all.
"A beautiful child
has been born
"to their Royal Majesties,
the King and Queen."
(ALL CHEERING)
(INDISTINCT)
(WEEPING)
My love.
(SHUSHING)
Rest, my fairest Queen.
Rest.
Our little one...
She's a beautiful child.
The most beautiful one.
Our people love her already.
- I'm dying.
- No.
She will need a mother.
You must remarry. Please.
Bring her to me.
My baby.
Blackest hair,
reddest cheeks,
skin as white as snow.
Call her Snow White.
(BELL TOLLS)
(LADIES WEEPING)
IDDY:  The King did marry
another queen.
And though
she was beautiful,
she was evil.
But Snow White grew to be
a kind child who loved
her father very much.
♪ Just before
it's time for bed
I rest my head
♪ That's when
I climb right up
to my favorite chair
♪ Where you are
waiting for me
♪ And I sit right on
my daddy's knee
♪ Do you think that
we could dance?
♪ Yes, I think that
there's a chance
♪ Take my hand
and hop, hop, hop with me
♪ Now it's bedtime
♪ I see
♪ But just before
I go I'd like to be
♪ Hop, hop, hop, hop
hopping on my daddy's
BOTH:
♪ Hop, hop, hop, hop
hopping on my daddy's
hopping on my daddy's knee ♪
Enough.
Snow White,
it's past your bedtime.
Your Majesty,
we don't want to be
late for the ball.
I shall be in my room.
Good night, Snow White.
Tomorrow, we are
going to have
a special treat.
What?
We're going hunting.
Hunting, hooray!
Daddy, what was
my real mummy like?
She was a fair queen,
who loved you very much.
Good night, Daddy.
Good night, Princess.
(BLOWS)
(DOOR CLOSING)
KING: You are entirely
too hard on the girl.
- QUEEN: I don't know
- what you're talking about.
You give her entirely
too much attention.
- Really, darling,
- we don't have time
to argue now.
We'll be late for the ball.
I must get dressed.
Shh.
(DOOR OPENS)
(BELL RINGING DISTANTLY)
QUEEN: Well, don't
just stand there,
tie my bodice.
- LADY IN WAITING:
- Yes, Your Majesty.
QUEEN: This blue dress
was the perfect choice.
Lace me tighter,
I want to be the
thinnest at the ball.
Yes, Your Majesty.
(GRUNTING)
- (EXCLAIMS) Are you
- trying to kill me?
Forgive me, Majesty.
I need something in my hair.
Bring me my combs.
I'll take that one.
No. That one.
No, another,
and another,
and another.
- And another,
- and another.
No, another.
I'll take that one.
(EXCLAIMS) You've stuck me
in the head!
- Forgive me,
- Your Majesty.
I never want to see
that comb again.
It's getting late.
Bring me my tiara.
Now leave me.
Mmm!
(ALL EXHALING)
(SHUSHES)
(ALL WHISPERING)
Mirror, mirror,
on the wall,
turn around
and show me all.
Mirror, mirror,
on the wall,
who is the fairest
of us all?
MIRROR: I have viewed
the world and seen,
thou art fairest of all,
dear Queen.
(DOOR OPENS)
(HESITANTLY)
Mirror, mirror,
on the wall,
show around
and turn me all.
Mirror, mirror,
on the wall,
turn around
and show me all.
(WHOOSHING)
MIRROR: A-ha!
What do you want?
I'm Snow White.
I know who you are.
I see all.
Oh.
What do you want?
I just wanted to look.
Well, then,
look.
(WHOOSHING)
(MIRROR VOICES LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
♪ A hunting we shall go
A hunting we shall go
BOTH:
♪ Heigh ho, a dairy-o
A hunting we shall go ♪
Good morning,
Your Majesty.
- Did you enjoy
- the royal ball?
Very much, Princess.
Were all the most
beautiful ladies in
the whole kingdom there?
All except the most
beautiful one.
- Which one?
- This one.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Your Majesty, can I please
get some sleep?
Shh.
(GIGGLING)
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
- They have such
- fun together.
- Was there ever
- such a pretty child?
When Snow White grows up,
she'll be the most
beautiful in the land.
Your breakfast, ma'am.
Take it away,
I'm not hungry.
(DOOR CLOSING)
(HUNTING HORN BLOWING)
(RINGING BELL)
♪ So you think
that she's more
beautiful than me
♪ We'll see
(SCOFFS)  We'll see
♪ It's impossible that
she could ever be
♪ As lovely as me
♪ For years I have
always been the fairest
♪ That's why the King
has picked me for his Queen
♪ Who would have thought
that she would be a beauty?
♪ Who would have foreseen?
♪ It turns me green
♪ So you think
that she's more
beautiful than me?
♪ We'll see, we'll see
♪ How can this possibly be?
♪ That it's she
that it's not me
♪ For one
there's the way
I do my hair
♪ And the way
I do my makeup
with such care
♪ With the gowns I pick
and my furs so thick
♪ Is this a trick?
♪ It makes me sick
♪ I'll have to do away
with her somehow
♪ But how?
♪ The King must not
suspect I was involved
♪ I think it's solved
It may be solved
♪ I'm thinking up
an evil little plan
♪ My hunter will
gladly be the man
♪ For the price
he'll do the job
without a quiver
♪ What will he deliver?
♪ I'll take her liver
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Enter.
The hunter, ma'am.
You may leave us.
(LAUGHS)
Snow White is such
a dear child.
I want you to take
care of her today.
But don't bring her back,
bring me her liver.
No!
I'll have her liver
or your head.
♪ I never want to see
that child again
♪ You see?
♪ Agree
♪ You never want to see
that child again
♪ I see
♪ I agree
♪ Now we'll see
who is more
beautiful than me
(LAUGHS)
♪ We'll see, we'll see ♪
Your Majesty,
I'm afraid the little Princess
won't be able to keep up
with the hunting party.
May I suggest
she ride with me?
We'll fall behind.
Very good, hunter,
but don't fall
too far behind.
Of course, Majesty.
(BLOWS HORN)
(DOGS BARKING)
(DOGS BARKING DISTANTLY)
Aren't we a long way off
from the others?
This is where
the prize game hide.
We shall dismount here.
But l don't see
any animals.
We'll find one.
(SNOW WHITE HUMMING)
(GASPS) Oh.
(GASPS)
Quick! Where are
your best arrows?
Oh, I'm looking for
smaller game here.
- My hunting knife
- will do the job.
Hunter.
It's the Queen's command.
No!
No, hunter!
I must.
- I'll run away into the forest
- and I'll never come back.
(GOAT BLEATS)
The goat will
provide me
with a liver.
Beware of the forest,
it is full of wild beasts.
Go!
SNOW WHITE: Farewell, hunter.
(ANIMALS CHITTERING)
(WOLF HOWLING)
(WOLF GROWLING)
(WOLF WHIMPERING)
Yes. I'm tired, too.
And hungry.
Hello. Is anybody home?
(HICCUPS)
I'm tired.
(SIGHS)
So tired.
♪ I could go to sleep
right here
♪ And not get up
♪ Until next year
♪ This bed is too small
♪ Or maybe
I'm just too tall
♪ But there's another one
right down the hall
♪ This bed seems
to be quite thin
♪ How can I fit in?
♪ After all I'm not a pin
♪ But there's another one
I can fit in
♪ Knock, knock
It feels just like a hard rock
♪ So many choices
Will I find the one?
♪ I wonder who could
sleep in there
♪ Or there or there or there
♪ Is it that one
over there?
♪ Yes, I think l see
one bed that looks right
(YAWNS)
♪ Good night ♪
(DWARFS CHATTERING)
We'll push it
up the tree.
- Okay.
- Onwards.
- Why are we going
- the other way?
- BIDDY: Ow!
- My foot!
FIDDY: I didn't
touch your foot.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
I saw a wolf.
(WHISPERING)
Was that the wolf?
- Wolf?
- I don't see a wolf.
There's a boulder there.
Mind the boulder.
BIDDY: Ow!
You're stepping
on my foot!
IDDY: Forward, men.
Forward.
Hup!
FIDDY: This is beginning
to look familiar.
LIDDY: (PANTING)
I'm tired.
IDDY: Wait a minute.
Who left the door open?
Biddy? Kiddy? Diddy?
KIDDY: No, wasn't me.
Giddy?
GIDDY: Nobody did.
Light your lanterns.
(ALL WHISPERING)
(EXCLAIMS) Who is it?
Shh! It's me!
Oh.
This way.
Come here.
Is there anybody there?
(CRASHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(GROANING)
Quiet, quiet.
There's no one here.
Let's eat.
Someone's been
zooping my porridge.
- Someone's been
- eating my bread.
Who's been
gobbling my wine?
ALL: Someone's been
eating the peas!
Brothers,
let's review the facts.
- The facts.
The door was found open,
(ALL AGREEING)
porridge missing,
peas missing,
bread missing,
wine missing.
In conclusion,
someone has been here.
ALL: Someone has been here.
And furthermore...
ALL: Furthermore?
...someone may be here.
ALL: Be here?
Then let's search the place.
Carefully.
Someone's been
lying in my bed.
Look!
Someone's been
lying here, too.
knocking on mine.
- Oh, yeah,
- they've been here.
And here.
And there it is! Look.
What is it?
It's a sea monster.
It's a donkey.
It's an elephant.
Elephants don't lay in bed.
- Oh.
- KIDDY: It's a dragon.
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
What shall we do?
Let's pull back the sheets.
Good idea. You do it.
No. You do it.
No.
Quiet. I'll do it.
(ALL GASPING)
What is it?
It's a girl.
- I wonder how
- she got here?
What's a girl?
Shh!
Boo!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Let's not awaken her.
Where will she sleep?
In my bed.
- BIDDY: Where
- will you sleep?
In your bed.
My bed's too narrow.
And mine's too hard.
Mine's too soft.
I'll never get any rest
with him in my bed.
No room in my bed.
Quiet.
Liddy will sleep
an hour with each.
(ALL SNORING)
(DWARFS GRUNTING)
- DIDDY: I had
- the strangest sleep.
GIDDY: I remember.
What's your name?
Snow White.
- How did you come
- to our house?
Who let you in?
- Did you eat
- the porridge?
The bread?
- The peas?
- The wine?
My stepmother tried
to have me killed,
(ALL GASP)
but the hunter
let me run away.
IDDY: Hunter?
Yes.
Just before nightfall,
I found this house.
I took just a smidgen
of food from each plate.
- And then
- I felt so tired
that I finally fell
asleep in this bed,
- which was the only one
- I could fit into.
That's my bed.
What's your name?
Liddy.
Thank you, Liddy.
(ALL SNICKERING)
(ALL WHISPERING)
I suppose you'll need
a place to live.
BIDDY: A roof over your head.
FIDDY: Food on your plate.
LIDDY: Your own bed.
Yes, I suppose I will.
Very well, then,
- how would you like
- to take care of our house?
Clean the floors.
Make the beds.
- Cook the meals.
- Wash.
- Sew.
- Knit.
- You'll never lack
- for anything.
Oh, yes.
With all my heart!
Then it's a deal.
ALL: Hurray!
Now you must each tell me
all of your names.
- Come on, men,
- our names.
♪ My name is Iddy
and this is Biddy
♪ And this is Kiddy,
Diddy, Fiddy,
Giddy, Liddy
♪ If you can't remember
who is who, you're not
the one to blame
♪ We easily confuse ourselves
because we sound the same
♪ My name is Iddy
- ♪ My name is Biddy
- ♪ And this is...
- ♪ Kiddy
- ♪ Diddy
- ♪ Fiddy
- ♪ Giddy
♪ Liddy
♪ We're seven men
who dig in caves for
secret treasures that we find
- ♪ Though we're up
- to here in mud
♪ We never mind
♪ I look for rocks
♪ I look for stones
♪ I look for worms
♪ I look for bones
♪ If it's underground
♪ We'll make sure
that it's found
- ♪ I dig for tin
- ♪ I dig for gold
♪ I dig for snails
under the mold
♪ If it's underground
♪ We'll make
sure that it's found
♪ We'll make sure
that it's found
♪ My name is Iddy
♪ My name is Biddy
- ♪ And this is
- ♪ Kiddy
- ♪ Diddy
- ♪ Fiddy
♪ Giddy
♪ Liddy
♪ Might I suggest that
we request if we can
put her to the test
♪ And then we'll see
if it can be that
we are in her memory
♪ Your name is Biddy
♪ My name is Kiddy
- ♪ You must be Diddy
- ♪ No, he's Fiddy
- ♪ I'm Fiddy
- ♪ Who's Diddy?
- ♪ Now do you think
- you've got us straight?
- ♪ I think I'll have
- to concentrate
♪ Then let us
try it once again
♪ We're only seven little men
♪ Biddy, Kiddy, Diddy
♪ Fiddy, Giddy, Liddy
- ♪ Iddy
- ♪ Biddy
- ♪ Kiddy
- ♪ Diddy
- ♪ Fiddy
- ♪ Giddy
- ♪ Liddy ♪
- Then can I stay?
For as long as
your heart desires.
And now,
brothers, to work!
Hut, two, three, four.
IDDY:  Years passed.
The King had been told
that Snow White had been
eaten by wild animals.
He was so grief stricken
that he gave up his kingdom
and died in battle
far, far away.
But Snow White was safe
in the woods with us,
- where she grew up
- in our cottage.
And as for the Queen...
We have this exquisite
material for you, ma'am.
No.
No. Of course not.
(CHUCKLES)
We have this creation
made for you.
(LAUGHS)
You silly boy.
In all the world
there is no other
dress like this.
Oh!
It is glorious.
Isn't it glorious?
If I may say so,
there is no queen
more beautiful to wear it.
♪ Have you got your picks?
♪ Yeah, we got them
♪ Are your shovels sharp?
♪ Uh-huh
♪ Then let's find a cave
♪ On a mountain trail
- ♪ And we'll dig down deep
- ♪ Till we've filled the pail
♪ Let's go!
♪ Every day
we dig, dig, dig
♪ Diggedy, diggedy
dig, dig, dig
♪ The sun may be shining
but we don't give a fig
♪ 'Cause we've got
to get to work
and dig, dig, dig
♪ Every day
we pick, pick, pick
♪ Pickety, pickety
pick, pick, pick
♪ The birds
may be singing but
we don't give a lick
♪ 'Cause we've got
to dig deep
and pick, pick, pick
♪ Here we are
searching near and far
♪ For a glimmer
♪ A glitter
♪ A glow
♪ Here we go
searching high and low
♪ And someday
we'll find it, I know
ALL:
♪ So every day
we tap, tap, tap
♪ Tappety, tappety
tap, tap, tap
♪ We won't dilly dally
and we won't take a nap
We've got to dig, dig, dig
♪ We've got
to pick, pick, pick
We've got to tap, tap, tap ♪
(MIRROR VOICES MUTTERING)
Mirror, mirror, on the wall,
who is the fairest of us all?
MIRROR: You are very fair,
my Queen,
but Snow White is
the fairest that I have seen.
She is dead.
I ate her liver.
With seven dwarfs
Snow White has stayed.
In the forest she survived.
Snow White is alive!
Alive, alive!
MIRROR VOICES: Alive!
This time I'll take
care of her myself!
♪ Every day I dust the books
Neaten the crannies
and sweep the nooks
♪ Hang seven hats
on seven little hooks
♪ When I'm done
how nice it looks
♪ Every day I seem to grow
little by little
from head to toe
♪ Isn't it lucky that
I've learned to sew?
♪ Add another hem
and away I go
♪ Add a hem, add a cuff
♪ Make it bigger
so there's room enough
♪ Hem, hem, hem
Cuff, cuff, cuff
♪ Hem, hem, hem, hem
ALL:
♪ Dig, dig, dig, dig
Dig, dig, dig, dig
♪ Pickety, pickety
pickety, pickety
♪ Tap, tap, tap, tap
tap, tap, tap, tap
♪ Dig, dig, dig, dig
Diggedy, diggedy
diggedy, diggedy
♪ Diggedy, diggedy
♪ Tap, tap, tap, tap
♪ Dig, dig, dig
A diamond!
Dig, dig, dig
♪ Dig, dig, dig
Eureka!
♪ Little friends
when this growing ends
♪ Though I love you
I simply can't stay
♪ Your house is small
soon I'll be too tall
♪ And I'll have to
be on my way
♪ Maybe there's
a castle where
♪ Some nice prince
has room to spare
♪ We'd make a large
but very lovely pair
♪ And I could even
stand up straight
out there
♪ But till that day
I just don't fit
♪ Beds will be made
and lamps will be lit
♪ I'll bend my knees
then my head won't hit
♪ As I keep growing
bit by bit
ALL:
♪ Every day when
work is through
♪ And our little house
comes into view
- ♪ There's something
- special that we like to do
- ♪ We holler
- "Hey, Snow White"
- ♪ She answers
- ♪ Yes, that's right
- ♪ We holler
- "What's to eat?" She answers
♪ Wipe those feet
ALL:
♪ Oh, every day
there's work to do
♪ Looking for gold
♪ And cooking a stew
♪ We've sure been busy
But we're still not through
- ♪ We've got
- to dig down deep
- ♪ I've got to
- sweep, sweep, sweep
♪ We've got
to move this dirt
♪ I've got to hem my skirt
- ♪ We've got
- to dig, dig, dig
- ♪ I'm getting
- big, big, bigger
ALL:
♪ Every day ♪
(SNOW WHITE SINGING FAINTLY)
♪ We'd make a large
but very lovely pair
♪ And I could even stand up
straight out there
♪ But till the day... ♪
Ware for sale.
Fancy things to
make you pretty.
How pretty you are.
Thank you, good woman.
What are you selling?
Oh.
Pretty things.
Lovely things.
- Laces of silk
- in many colors.
Oh! What a lovely dress.
I have just
the bodice for you.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Mmm.
- Wouldn't you like
- to try it on?
Yes, please.
Then let me in,
and I shall lace you up.
Won't you look lovely
laced-up in this bodice?
- Won't she look lovely,
- Peabold?
- (SQUAWKS)
- Oh, it is lovely.
Mmm-hmm.
But it's a little tight.
(GRUNTS) The better
to show off your figure.
But I can't breathe.
(SNOW WHITE GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
She couldn't
resist my bodice.
Now we'll see
who is the fairest.
♪ Every day
when work is through
♪ And our little house
comes into view
♪ There's something
special that we like to do
- ♪ We holler
- "Hey, Snow White"
She answers ♪
ALL: We holler!
IDDY: Come on, gentlemen.
Softly now.
Softly. (SHUSHES)
There she is.
Oh, no!
Snow White.
She isn't breathing.
DIDDY: Check her pulse.
I can hear her heartbeat.
Get the scissors.
- Here it is.
- It's this thing.
Cut it.
(SNOW WHITE GROANS)
She's coming to.
She's breathing.
Her cheeks are red again.
She's alive!
- (ALL CHEERING)
- Let's eat!
(GROANS)
I've had the most
horrible dream.
What's this?
(GASPS) No, it wasn't.
Tell us what happened.
A kind woman came,
selling pretty things,
- and I tried on
- this bodice.
That wasn't a kind woman.
That was the Evil Queen.
And she has found you out.
- But she looked nothing
- like the Queen.
It was a disguise.
And she'll be back.
What will I do?
Don't be afraid.
We will be here
to protect you.
But if we're not here...
- You mustn't let
- anyone in.
No one.
No, I won't,
I promise.
Thank you.
You've all been so kind.
- I've baked
- your favorite cake.
- Let's eat.
- For dessert.
Attar of roses.
Tincture of sandalwood.
Chamomile.
Oil of jasmine.
Milk.
Mirror, mirror,
on the wall,
who is the fairest
of us all?
You are very fair,
my Queen,
but Snow White
is the fairest
that I have seen.
Well, look again.
I laced her up so tight
she'll never take
another breath.
Seven dwarfs
are her protection.
They have scissors
to cut through lace.
It may be that
you are crafty,
but Snow White has
the loveliest face.
(MIRROR VOICES MUTTERING)
QUEEN: An oriental potion
just for the occasion.
♪ If you have lovely hair
♪ You may want
a comb in there
♪ Painted bright
mother of pearl
♪ Just the thing
for a lovely girl ♪
Good day.
Where did you come from?
Far, far away.
I have been traveling
for so long.
(SIGHS)
May I rest here
for a while?
Yes. Yes, of course.
(SIGHS)
Oh! What lovely
hair you have.
You must wear comb
in such lovely hair.
- Thank you.
- But I have no comb.
Oh.
But I have beautiful combs.
May I show you one?
Mmm.
Eeny, meeny, miney, mo.
Oh, here.
Oh, it shimmers so.
Oh!
Let me in and I will
show it to you.
But I don't know you.
And I mustn't let
anyone in.
Oh.
Then open the door
a crack
and I will
pass it to you.
Just a crack.
Oh, so...
Oh,
it's beautiful.
Mmm.
- But I have no one
- to comb my hair.
Oh.
You must let me
comb it for you.
For once.
For good.
Would you? Could you?
Mmm.
But I can't.
I'm not allowed
to let anyone in.
Oh!
Then I shall just stand here.
Now turn around.
Yes, this is all right,
- as long as
- I don't let anyone in.
- I've seen that comb
- somewhere before.
But you'll never
see it again!
(LAUGHS)
BIDDY: Snow White!
Snow White, wake up!
- KIDDY: Check the lacing.
- FIDDY: Get some water.
GIDDY: I can't feel her pulse.
BIDDY: Look!
LIDDY: What is it?
IDDY: A potion. Ugh!
GIDDY: A potion?
(GROANS)
Snow White, Snow White,
tell us what happened.
A woman came,
selling combs,
and I didn't let her in.
She stayed right at the door.
KIDDY: It was the Queen.
LIDDY: Not again.
But she looked nothing
like the last time.
- All the same,
- it was her.
I should have known.
GIDDY: And she'll be back.
Lock the door.
- And don't open it
- for anyone.
No, I won't.
Not for anyone, I promise.
Then you'll be safe.
- Agreed?
- Agreed.
ALL: Agreed!
Then let's eat.
MIRROR: Thou art most fair,
my dearest Queen,
but Snow White is
the fairest that I have seen.
She is not.
She is, too.
- Is not.
- Is, too.
- Too!
- Not. Not.
- Too. Too.
But she is dead.
She is not.
The dwarfs are smart.
They know your plan.
They'll save the girl
if they can.
A poisoned comb
cannot subdue Snow White.
She is more fair than you.
Poisoned crown? No.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Who is it?
- LADY IN WAITING: It's your
- evening refreshment, ma'am.
I've brought you
some delicious apples.
Freshly picked.
Go away!
Leave it at the door.
Delicious.
Irresistible.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Sounds like rain.
Dirty Deeds. No.
Wickedness. Evil Potions.
The Poison Cook Book.
(CHUCKLING)
Poison bread,
poison fish,
poison fowl.
Poison fruit!
(LAUGHS TRIUMPHANTLY)
Poison apples!
(STRAINING)
That worked.
And now for the worm.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
Sealed.
ALL: We're through.
Stack the plates,
there's work to do.
We'd love to stay
and be with you.
IDDY: But grab your hats.
ALL: There's work to do.
Wait for me by the door.
Fiddy, that's enough.
You'll be late for work.
IDDY: We're off to the mines.
I'm coming.
Off you go, Fiddy.
And remember,
don't open the door
for anyone.
I won't.
All right. (LAUGHS)
Not a soul.
I promise.
Bye.
Oh!
We're off to the mines.
(CHUCKLES)
Today we'll find gold.
Good-bye!
(LAUGHS EXCITEDLY)
(GIGGLES)
Fiddy emptied the pot.
Not a single berry?
QUEEN:
Apples from my farm.
Fresh picked today.
Who will buy my apples?
- (GASPS)
- Sweet apples.
Juicy and delicious.
Will you buy
my apples today?
No, thank you.
They're the best
of the season.
Sweet and juicy.
I can't. I'm not supposed
to let anyone into the house.
Then come to the window,
and I will show one to you.
Good day, kind child.
Hello.
Oh.
It's been a terrible season
on the farm this year.
But there's one
very special tree
that's grown the best
apples I've ever seen.
They look so strange.
That's because
it's a special tree.
Why don't you buy this one?
No, I mustn't.
The dwarfs would be cross.
Oh, we wouldn't want
to make the dwarfs cross,
would we?
Here then,
take it as a gift.
You're so kind.
It is such a
nice-looking apple...
But I shouldn't.
You're not afraid
that I'm going to
poison you, are you?
Here, I'll cut it
in half,
and I'll take
the white half
and you take
the red half.
It's the most delicious
and sweetest.
No. I'd prefer the white.
Oh. As you wish.
(GASPS)
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
Oh. That's just
a naughty little milk worm.
Here.
Mmm.
That's delicious.
Why, it is delicious.
(GROANS)
See if the dwarfs
can save you now!
(LAUGHS)
Now, my Queen,
I tell you true,
there is none fairer than you,
you, you!
Now, it's finished.
The game is done.
Snow White has lost
and I have won.
Won.
(LAUGHS)
I have won!
I've won!
Snow White,
open up. It's us.
We're home.
It's still bolted.
She must be in there.
- Get a log,
- we'll break it in.
- Get a log.
- Good idea.
Get a log!
BIDDY: All right, men.
Heave!
(ALL SHOUTING)
How did that...
Look!
BIDDY: She's been here again.
IDDY: Check her laces.
BIDDY: She has no laces.
KIDDY: No pulse.
Well, check the comb.
But there is no comb.
Poison!
ALL: Poison?
Is she dead?
(WHIMPERING)
But she doesn't look dead.
KIDDY: She looks so alive.
GIDDY: We can't bury her.
She looks too perfect.
- BIDDY: She must
- be under a spell.
We'll keep her
in a glass coffin.
But who will protect her?
The birds.
(HOOTING)
IDDY:  So we made
a glass cover
for Snow White.
There she lay
for a full year,
watched over
by a wise owl,
a crafty raven
and a dove of love.
Until you discovered her,
she has been here.
And there she rests,
unchanged.
- She must be
- under a spell.
PRINCE: You were the one.
It seems that
I have arrived
too late.
Is there no hope?
I shall spend my entire life
in mourning for her.
We shall not rest
until the Prince is found.
- I fear a storm
- is brewing.
Good little men,
let me take her home
where she may rest
in a royal palace
truly befitting her.
But she should
stay here with us.
Brothers, Snow White
has been with us
for many years.
She took good care
of us all that time.
Now we can no longer
care for her.
Someone may find her
while we're away.
I shall neither
eat nor sleep
until I know
this fairest one is safe
within the palace walls.
You hear how he mourns
for her, brothers?
Iddy's right,
we should let her
go with the Prince.
He may be the true prince
that was meant for her.
Yield, enchanted creatures.
Your Highness,
we feared for your safety.
Hold.
These are my friends.
They have allowed me
to take back the greatest
treasure of our long journey.
Behold.
She is most fair.
Send word to my father,
the King.
We are returning home.
The rest of you, help me
to carry the Princess
back to our camp.
We leave immediately.
You, there.
Watch that wagon.
(HORSES NEIGHING)
Look out!
Princess.
(COUGHS)
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROANS)
Snow White.
Where am I?
Arise, my beloved,
and be my queen.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
Father, this is Snow White,
my bride-to-be.
Your Majesty.
It is true, son.
- She's the fairest
- treasure in the world.
Send a royal proclamation
throughout the land.
In a fortnight,
we shall celebrate
their wedding day.
Bless you.
Your Majesty,
this invitation
has just arrived
from the neighboring
kingdom of Gladonnia.
Ah! This is interesting.
"The Prince has traveled
the entire known world
"and has found
the fairest princess,
"whom he will marry
on the night of..."
I wonder who she is.
This wedding will be
the event of the season.
Fetch me my finest gown.
This princess may be fair,
but we'll see
who is the fairest.
(ORGAN PLAYING)
- Mirror, mirror,
- on the wall,
who is the fairest
of us all?
You have been most fair,
'tis true,
but the Prince's bride
is more fair than you.
No!
That can't be!
(MIRROR VOICES SCREAMING)
Call my carriage!
Hurry!
Faster!
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
(ORGAN PLAYING)
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered
here today
- to witness the wedding
- of this couple.
If there be anyone
who would speak
against this union,
may he now speak
or forever hold his peace.
DRIVER: Whoa!
- (LOUD SNAPPING)
- (GROANS)
Please repeat after me.
You are sacred to me...
...in life and in death.
(ALL MURMURING)
In sickness and in health.
PRINCE: In sickness
and in health.
For better or for worse.
- You may now
- kiss the bride.
(HOARSELY) Snow White.
(ALL GASPING)
- SNOW WHITE:
- That's the Evil Queen.
(ALL MURMURING)
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Now you are safe.
IDDY:  The Queen could
not bother them again.
We remained in the forest
and continued to work there.
Snow White ruled
with the Prince.
They had many children
and they lived happily,
happily ever after.