♪
♪ Come hear the genuine
come hear the genuine ♪
♪ The one and only
the one and only ♪
♪ Come hear the hullabaloo
tickety-boom, tweedle-Dee-Dee
plinkity-plink ♪
♪ Better get ready to hear
and better get ready
to cheer ♪
♪ The one and only, genuine
original family band ♪
- Play it loud!
- Play it proud!
- ♪ for together here we stand ♪
♪ The one and only, genuine
original family band ♪
♪ Come hear the hullabaloo
of our tuba ♪
♪ Hear the tickety-boom
of our drum ♪
♪ Hear the tweedle-Dee-Dee
of our woodwinds ♪
♪ Hear our plinkity-plinkin'
banjo strum ♪
♪ And when the razzamatazz
of our brasses ♪
♪ Begins to bezaz in the air
something grand ♪
♪ Better get ready to hear
and better get ready
to cheer ♪
♪ The one and only, genuine
original family band ♪
♪ We can play
with virtuosity ♪
♪ Waltzes, marches
polkas and mazurkas ♪
♪ We can play them
sentimentally ♪
♪ Or just like the music
of the circus ♪
♪ And when the razzamatazz
of our brasses ♪
♪ Begins to bezaz in the air
something grand ♪
♪ Better get ready to hear
and better get ready
to cheer ♪
♪ The one and only, one and only
one and only, one and only ♪
♪ One and only, genuine ♪
♪ Original, original
family band ♪
♪ [ One note ]
[ Children laughing ]
Ya done it again.
Ya booped when ya should
have oompahed!
I'm sorry, grandpa.
Can you just go on without me?
Mr. hodgkiss just arrived
with the mail.
Uh, yeah, that's about
enough for me too.
I, uh, promised
I'd turn sod for
Katie's flower bed.
Uh, yes, I'll show you
where I had in mind, dear.
My lip's tired.
There, ya see?
You need practice.
Build it up!
And I sort of promised
Hank winters I'd come by
this mornin'.
Oh. All right.
All right.
If nobody else wants to get
the invite to St. Louis,
I sure don't care.
I want to go, grandpa!
Me too!
Well, means nothin' to me,
ridin' on a train,
stayin' in a hotel,
eatin' in fancy
restaurants,
maybe even playin'
for the president
of the United States.
All I said was
"my lip's tired"!
Play! Come on, please!
[ Girl ]
Hey!
Alice got her letter
from Joe carder!
You can tell the way
she goes off by herself
to read it.
It ain't a fittin' thing
for a young lady writin'
to a man she ain't never met!
Well, papa says
you were all for Joe carder...
Until you saw a copy
of his newspaper,
found out he's a republican.
No such thing!
That's got nothing
to do with it!
I bet she's gonna
marry Mr. carder!
♪ What will he see
when he looks at me ♪
♪ For the very first time
in his life ♪
♪ Will he see just another
country-bumpkin girl ♪
♪ Or the woman he will want ♪
♪ For his wife ♪
♪ Can my smile say, wordlessly ♪
♪ Things that
I couldn't ever write ♪
♪ Will it go all wrong
for me ♪
♪ Or will I be all right ♪
♪ What will I say
to the man of my life ♪
♪ When the man of my life
holds my hand ♪
♪ Will I just babble
unable to stop ♪
♪ What if I stupidly
stand there ♪
♪ For I have been saving
this part of my life ♪
♪ 'Til the heart of my life
would arrive ♪
♪ And seeing him there ♪
♪ May be too much to bear ♪
♪ For the happiest girl alive ♪
♪ Letter by letter
my heart has learned ♪
♪ He's gentle and loving
and kind ♪
♪ And letter by letter
my heart has yearned ♪
♪ 'Til I'm nearly
out of my mind ♪
♪ To meet him ♪
♪ How will I seem
to the man of my dream ♪
♪ When the man of my dream
says hello ♪
♪ Will I seem foolish
or will I seem wise ♪
♪ What if he just
doesn't know yet ♪
♪ That I have been saving
this part of my life ♪
♪ 'Til the heart of my life
would arrive ♪
♪ Can I make it clear ♪
♪ That because he is near ♪
♪ I'm the happiest girl ♪
♪ Alive ♪
I don't see no good reason
why we should get all head up...
Over somebody we
never met before...
Rose, stop squirming!
And we'll never see again.
How can i...
you look lovely, dear.
I'll take
that brush.
Try to stay clean.
Here, let me help ya.
I can't do
one of these.
When I was your age,
I could tie 'em.
[ Katie ]
Just fine.
And you look gorgeous.
Now please, try
to remain clean.
How about this one?
[ Alice ]
Do you like it better
than the green one?
Oh, yes, dear!
It's just fine.
I always did love that dress.
I didn't see nothin' wrong
with the white one you had on
in the first place.
Oh, grandpa,
do you really like that
one better than this one?
I mean, do you think
it looks better on me?
Honey,
you'll have 'im bug-eyed
and breathless no matter
what dress you're wearin'.
I just didn't want to see her
get her heart broke.
But anybody that twists
the truth around the way
he does in his newspaper...
I sure wouldn't believe
nothin' he wrote in the letter.
[ Girl ]
Here he comes!
He's turning at the gate!
[ Children gasping ]
[ Children clamoring ]
Look it!
[ Indistinct talking ]
Get away!
Get away from the window!
Come on!
Oh, look it!
- Girls, get away
from that window.
- [ Groaning ] Do we have to?
Calvin, please.
What's he like?
He doesn't look
much like his picture.
He's grown a moustache!
Oh!
[ Door closes ]
[ Children oohing ]
Grandpa,
he'll see you!
Say, look at 'im.
He sure thinks
he is somebody.
Got a big, gold watch chain.
Got to show how
important he is.
Boys.
He don't look like
he's got sense enough
to pound sand in a rat hole.
You can sort of tell
by looking at him.
He's just the type
that would put out
a republican newspaper.
[ Children protesting ]
[ Doorbell rings ]
[ Clearing throat ]
How do you do?
I'm Alice.
- Uh, won't you come in?
- Thank you.
[ Door slams ]
Uh, may I take your hat?
Well, at least it's turned
out to be a pleasant day
after the rain.
[ Sighs ]
I hope you had a nice trip.
Yes, quite nice.
I-I don't... I don't think
I would have recognized you...
If we'd met on the street.
It's probably your moustache.
It...
Well, it-it makes you
look so different.
Oh?
Um, would you
have recognized me?
Well, I, uh...
I don't quite recall...
Well, from my picture, I mean.
Oh.
[ Laughs ]
Well, I-i know
it wasn't too good of me.
[ Laughs ]
Well, there've been
so many things lately...
And I-i guess I don't have
the best memory in the world.
[ Laughing ]
My wife tells me
what I should do...
Your wife?
Look, am I in the wrong house
or something? I wanted to see
a "rensselaer bower."
Now they told me...
Rensselaer?
Well, that's my grandfather.
[ Sighs ]
You mean
you're not Joseph carder?
[ Laughs ]
I'm Henry white...
Of the Democratic
national committee.
Oh! [ Laughs ]
Mr. bower has corresponded
with postmaster Dickinson.
Something about a campaign
song he's written...
And a family band he'd like
to take to the convention
in St. Louis.
Strange.
Grandpa? Grandpa,
this man is here to see you.
[ Scoffs ]
He's from the Democratic
national committee!
That must mean
they're interested.
We're just as good
as on the train to St. Louis.
[ Children cheering ]
It's sure nice of ya to come.
Mighty glad to see ya.
I promised
postmaster Dickinson.
Well, eh, what I had in mind
was the reason I writ down.
You see, I made up
a campaign song
for president Cleveland.
I know.
And what I thought
might be a good idea...
To take the family band
to St. Louis...
And sort of introduce it
right there
at the convention.
Put on a whole musical show
if ya want.
I read the letter.
Well, first thing,
of course, before ya decide,
maybe you'd like
to hear the song?
We do feel that a good,
stirring song might inspire
party workers...
To greater effort and devotion.
You sure come
to the right place!
Been a lot of dirty,
underhanded politics.
Republicans making a play
for the undecided voters,
the fence straddlers.
Trying to tell them grover
Cleveland hasn't lived up
to his campaign promises.
Shh. My daughter-in-law, Katie,
don't like politic talking
in the house.
Out to the barn, everybody!
We're gonna play our campaign
song!
[ Children cheering ]
Hurray for grandpa!
[ Cheering continues ]
I took a lot of time
writing this.
I want you to meet
my daughter-in-law, Katie.
How do you do?
My son, Calvin.
[ Children clamoring ]
♪ [ Warming up ]
Sit right down there.
Now, right here, I'm sure
you'll be comfortable.
Yes, sir, I think
you can see much
better here.
♪ [ Instruments warming up,
cow mooing ]
- [ Laughing ]
- When I need any help
out of you, I'll ask for it.
Come on now.
♪
♪ In the frozen winter
of '76 in a place
called valley forge ♪
♪ Came a time for a man
of destiny and his name
was general George ♪
♪ 'Twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
♪ 'Twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
♪ In 1861 our ship of state
was sinkin' ♪
♪ Again came a man of destiny
a man by the name of Lincoln ♪
♪ 'Twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
♪ 'twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
♪ In our land today
there's a man who's
tried and true ♪
♪ He's what this country needs
but it's up to me and you ♪
♪ Stephen grover Cleveland is
the man this country needs ♪
♪ Let's put it over
with grover ♪
♪ Don't rock the boat
give him your vote ♪
♪ Let's keep our country
in clover ♪
♪ It's up to you
he'll follow through ♪
♪ He made the white house
shine like a lighthouse ♪
♪ Over our 38 states ♪
♪ 1889 is the time
to fall in line ♪
♪ Behind one of destiny's ♪
♪ Greatest statesmen ♪
♪ Stephen grover Cleveland is
the man this country needs ♪
♪ Let's put it over
with grover ♪
♪ Don't rock the boat
give him your vote ♪
♪ Give your vote to a man
who's a leader of men ♪
♪ Let's put grover
over again ♪
♪ let's put it over ♪
- ♪ With grover ♪
- ♪ don't ♪
♪ rock the boat ♪
♪ Give him your vote ♪
- ♪ Give your ♪
- ♪ vote to ♪
♪ a man who's a leader ♪
♪ Of men ♪
♪ Let's put grover ♪
♪ Over again ♪
The bower family band
presents a glorification:
American patriots
in living pictures.
♪ Lexington and bunker hill
were only weeks away ♪
♪ When Patrick Henry
said these golden words
that live today ♪
"I know not what course
others may take.
"But as for me,
give me Liberty
or give me death."
♪ He stood proudly
when he heard his
fatal sentence read ♪
♪ And then with glory
in his voice, young
Nathan hale said ♪
"My only regret is
that I have but one life
to give for my country."
♪ His words rang out
across the land
and we recall with pride ♪
♪ A silversmith
named Paul revere
who took that midnight ride ♪
"The British are comin'!
The British are comin'!
The British are comin'!"
♪
♪ Christmas day in '76
with courage brave and rare ♪
♪ The father of our country
crossed the icy Delaware ♪
♪ 'Twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
our grand finale!
♪ Stephen grover Cleveland is
the man this country needs ♪
♪ Let's put it over
with grover ♪
♪ Don't rock the boat
give him your vote ♪
♪ Give your vote to a man
who's a leader of men ♪
♪ Let's put grover
over again ♪
♪ It's the time for a man ♪
♪ And Cleveland's the man
for the time ♪
It'll do it, I tell you.
It's got enough zip
and zing and lilt to it.
It'll bring down the house.
Yes, sir, it'll put grover over
again. No doubt about it!
Put grover over again.
No doubt about it!
[ Family cheering ]
[ Laughing,
cheering continue ]
No doubt about it!
[ Clamoring continues ]
You know, there's somethin'
else I was thinkin'.
It'd be kind of nice if they
took us back to Washington
to play at the inauguration.
You know, when he's swore in
again. Old grover would sure
get a kick out of that.
[ Laughing ]
We, um...
We've quite a few Bridges
to cross before then.
One thing I will say
about the song though,
it really gets to you.
Makes you proud
to be a democrat,
doesn't it?
Well, I guess
it would, if I was.
He weren't never too bright,
even as a boy.
Then he growed up
to be a gol-darned republican.
Do you mean,
you could sing that
the way you did
and still...
Who'd sing your part
if the rest of you came
to St. Louis?
Nobody's takin' off
and leavin' me home,
not as long as there's
a place to go and a way
to get there.
A republican singing
at a Democratic convention.
It just didn't seem
the kind of a song...
They'd appreciate
at a republican
convention.
[ All laughing ]
Actually, to me,
music stands above
all this anyhow.
You don't have to be
a southerner to sing,
"the yellow rose of Texas"...
Or a sailor to dance a hornpipe.
You see, sir, Calvin isn't
just a rockbound republican.
Mostly he votes for the man.
What's the man
got to do with it?
[ Chuckles ]
Well, I want to thank you,
all of you, yes.
I'm going to recommend
that you be brought
to St. Louis.
[ All cheering ]
[ Children clamoring ]
You'll hear from me shortly.
Great meeting all of you.
[ Children ]
Bye, Mr. white.
I always told you
you could buy anything
with a song.
There's no door you
can't open with music!
♪ Who invented music ♪
♪ We'd like
to shake his hand ♪
♪ 'Cause music
casts a spell on us ♪
♪ That we can't
understand ♪
♪ must be some magician
designed the magic plan ♪
♪ He changed his wand ♪
♪ To a Baton ♪
♪ And that's how
it all began ♪
♪ When the rhythm pounds
and the Harmony sounds
and the melody rolls around ♪
Presto-chango!
♪ We're 10 feet
off the ground ♪
♪ And when the rhythm pounds
and the Harmony sounds
and the melody rolls around ♪
♪ Right from the downbeat
we can be found
10 feet off the ground ♪
♪ When everybody
puts his heart in it ♪
♪ Everybody
plays a part in it ♪
♪ That's how music magic
is made ♪
♪ Everybody's toes get tappier
everybody's feelin' happier ♪
♪ Lighter than air
out of his chair
ten feet off the ground ♪
♪ When the rhythm pounds
and the Harmony sounds ♪
♪ And the melody rolls around ♪
Presto-chango!
[ Group ]
♪ he's 10 feet off the ground ♪
♪ Who invented music
we'd like to shake his hand ♪
♪ That's how music magic
is made ♪
♪ Oh, 10 feet off the ground ♪
♪ That's how music ♪
♪ Magic is made ♪
♪ Ia-la-la-la, la-la la-la-la ♪
♪ Ia-la-la-la-la ♪
♪ Lighter than air ♪
♪ Out of his chair ♪
♪ Ten feet off the ground ♪
♪ Oh ♪
[ Gasps ]
♪ [ Stops ]
Oh!
[ Gasps ]
Oh, how do you do?
You must be Mr. carder.
Yes. Mrs. bower? Joe carder.
We were just having
a little celebration.
Would you excuse me,
please?
Oh, of course. It's...
No! Go away!
Alice, it's me,
Joe carder!
Just leave
me alone!
Go away!
Please!
[ Screams ]
Whoa!
Alice.
I can't imagine
what you must think.
Then I'll tell you what I think.
I think you must be a lot
more fun than I ever realized,
than I even dared to hope!
The way you were doing that,
you were...
What I mean is,
I've never seen anyone
clown around like that...
And look beautiful
all at the same time.
You want to know something?
I-I haven't slept in a week.
J-just thinking about what
I would do, w-what I would
say when we first met.
I was afraid it would all
be so formal like your letters.
And I-i wouldn't know
what to say, I would j-just...
i wouldn't think of anything.
Or maybe I'd...
And I would just start
jabbering and not have
enough sense to stop.
That's silly.
Why would anybody
feel like that?
[ Giggles ]
Actually, I was the one
who found the name
of your newspaper.
I asked Alice to send
that first letter.
[ Giggles ]
Well, I must not have
done a very good job,
selling you on Dakota.
Well, uh, it isn't
always that simple.
You see, a family
the size of ours, we put
down a lot of roots.
But if you could just realize
the opportunities there are
in Southern Dakota.
We're about to become a state,
you know?
Must be beautiful
in the black hills: Trees,
lakes, little streams.
Oh, I'm sure it's very nice,
but we have a good life here...
And a lot of wonderful friends.
Yep, guess I'll have
to go along with that, but...
I always keep thinking
there might be someplace out
west just a little bit better.
We've been lucky every time
we've moved,
and a man hates to quit
when he's winning.
No place ever gonna be so
wonderful that you couldn't
dream up something better.
But you wouldn't say that,
Mrs. bower, if you'd just
seen the black hills.
The air has a snap to it!
It's the scent of the pines.
And the sky's so blue...
You almost can't believe it.
I know what would be fun!
Why don't you and papa
come along to the meeting?
Hear his lecture.
Oh, and, um,
grandpa, you can come too,
if you'd like.
[ Katie ]
Uh, well, I-i don't really know.
I'd be very flattered
if you would come.
Have you gotten
many people to move
to Dakota?
Well, not just people,
Mr. bower, but the right people.
You see, the thing that first
interested our state chairman,
he found that you're...
Almost 100 percent republican
through this whole area.
Oh? That's mostly what
you're interested in,
ain't it?
Gettin' Republicans
to move up there?
That's right, sir. You see,
Mr. bower, this past year we've
had almost a tidal wave...
Of shiftless, irresponsible
democrats moving in.
A bunch of shysters and quacks
and usury-type moneylenders.
And if we don't do something
about it soon, they'll have
us outnumbered!
Well, let me tell you somethin',
young man. You're trumpetin'
a flat tune on a worn-out horn.
'Cause you can't turn back
a tidal wave,
not by puttin' out
a rabble-rousin',
ragtag newspaper.
And not by speech-makin'
to a bunch of poor, misguided
Republicans! And furthermore...
That's enough, grandpa.
Now stop it.
We have a very special little
rule that I have to invoke,
Mr. carder,
to, to make life bearable
around here.
We do not discuss,
we do not even mention
politics in this house.
And the summer kitchen,
I consider part of the house.
I'm sorry, Mrs. bower,
I didn't know.
Oh, it's all right.
Oh,
it's all right.
I don't blame you.
And I certainly didn't mean
to offend you, Mr. bower.
- I just naturally assumed
that you were republican too.
- [ Scoffs ]
Alice never happened to mention
anything to the contrary
in any of her letters.
Well, now that's all settled.
We'd be very happy to attend
your meeting, Mr. carder,
if you really want us there.
Come, Alice. Let's give
Mr. carder a nice piece
of chocolate cake.
And another consideration.
There's enough land in Dakota
so that each of your sons,
as he comes of age,
can take up a homestead,
start out in life owning
a good piece of land,
instead of working
all his life trying to get it,
trying to pay off a mortgage.
Now, let me tell you
something, truthfully.
You're the kind of people
we need in Dakota.
Solid, decent,
hard-working people,
who will help to build,
who'll always belong.
Who'll share in the golden
future of a glorious land!
[ Crowd murmuring ]
Up in my neck of the woods,
in the black hills,
you'll find rivers, lakes
and babbling streams.
And that's sweet music,
my friends.
Sweet music when you're
reading about another drought
spreading across the plains.
Now that's why this whole
westering movement...
Appeals to thoughtful,
far-seeing men, who want a
better life for their families.
[ Crowd murmuring ]
[ Man ]
What are we waitin' for?
I'm gonna go home
and start packing!
[ Murmuring gets louder ]
Don't forget to take along
your snake-bite remedy!
- Do ya have snakes in Dakota?
- No more than most places.
And your frostbite
remedy too. Ya might
need that even worse!
How cold does it get
in the winter?
That depends. We're
a very large territory.
Ain't nobody really knows.
Thermometers always freeze up
and bust!
[ Laughing ]
[ Crowd murmuring ]
I remind you, all of you,
that Mr. carder is here
as an invited guest!
And we're gonna listen
to him tell us about
Dakota in his own way.
Without interruption!
[ Crowd cheers, applauds ]
I'd be glad to tell you
some more about Dakota...
Without interruption.
♪ Where the roots grow deep
and the winds blow clean ♪
♪ Where the air is sweet ♪
♪ And the summer's green ♪
♪ Where virgin fields
await the plow ♪
♪ A great tomorrow ♪
♪ Is dawning now ♪
♪ Dakota, Dakota ♪
♪ Where a man stands tall ♪
♪ Where there's land
for all ♪
♪ Rolling rivers
embrace the plain ♪
♪ Where some day
there's gonna be ♪
♪ Golden oceans
of blowing grain ♪
♪ Just as far
as your eyes can see ♪
♪ The black hills
the blue skies ♪
♪ Of the shining west ♪
♪ Dakota, oh, Dakota ♪
♪ By the heavens ♪
♪ Blessed ♪
♪ Where the roots grow deep
and the winds blow clean ♪
♪ Where the air is sweet
and the summer's green ♪
♪ Where virgin fields
await the plow ♪
♪ A great tomorrow
is dawning ♪
♪ Now ♪
♪ Dakota, Dakota ♪
♪ Where a man stands tall ♪
♪ Where there's land
for all ♪
♪ Rolling rivers
embrace the plain ♪
♪ Where some day
there's gonna be ♪
♪ golden oceans
of blowing grain ♪
♪ just as far
as your eyes can see ♪
♪ The black hills ♪
♪ The blue skies
of the shining west ♪
♪ Dakota, oh, Dakota ♪
♪ By the heavens ♪
♪ Blessed ♪
♪ Dakota, Dakota ♪
♪ Where a man stands tall ♪
♪ Where there's land for all ♪
♪ Rolling rivers
embrace the plain ♪
♪ Where some day
there's gonna be ♪
♪ Golden oceans
of blowing grain ♪
♪ Just as far
as your eyes can see ♪
♪ The black hills
the blue skies ♪
♪ Of the shining west ♪
♪ Dakota, oh, Dakota ♪
♪ By the heavens ♪
♪ Blessed ♪
Boys take two,
girls take one now.
Okay.
Okay, grandpa.
I'll race
you back!
Okay!
[ Children laughing ]
[ Katie ]
The first thing we do,
we'll make a list
of all the things
we want to take with us.
Then try
and sell off everything else.
[ Calvin ] We can't do it.
Can't do it?
Not this year.
Maybe later on
if things work out.
[ Katie ]
But now, Calvin, you know very
well that the very best land...
Will go to the first
homesteaders that get there.
Yeah, that sounds logical.
And if we wait a whole
year, all the good land
will be gone.
[ Calvin ]
You've got to remember
all the plotting and planning...
And scheming that went into it,
to make this St. Louis trip
possible.
We can't give it up now.
Well, we're not going
to St. Louis...
Just so the children
can get a ride
on a train.
It's not the children
I'm thinking about.
They've got their whole
lives ahead of 'em.
But what about grandpa?
When's he ever gonna get
another chance like this?
We're not gonna have him
with us forever, you know?
[ Katie ]
Yes, I know.
[ Calvin ]
don't you worry.
We'll work it out.
I think we'd be a lot
better off, all of us,
movin' to rapid city,
like your papa wanted to
all along.
[ Groaning ]
What fun's a little
old mud-street town
like rapid city?
And ridin' on a wagon
and gettin' a side ache
instead of...
I wanna ride on a train!
I want to ride on a train too!
We want to go
to St. Louis!
Shh, shh, shh!
Now, will you let me
say what I'm gonna say?
I'll talk to Alice.
She'll be disappointed,
but she'll understand.
I wish I'd thought ahead
a little bit before
talking to Sidney...
About him taking up
his own homestead, later on.
It might be still possible
that we get there next year.
Just suppose we don't
get the best...
♪ [ children singing ]
♪ Where the roots grow deep
and the winds blow clean ♪
♪ Where the air is sweet
and the summer's green ♪
♪ Where virgin fields
await the plow ♪
♪ A great tomorrow
is dawning now ♪
♪ Dakota, Dakota ♪
♪ Where a man stands tall ♪
♪ Where there's land for all ♪
♪ Rolling rivers
embrace the plain ♪
♪ Where some day
there's gonna be ♪
♪ Golden oceans
of blowing grain ♪
♪ Just as far
as your eyes can see ♪
♪ The black hills
the blue skies ♪
♪ Of the shining west ♪
♪ Dakota, oh, Dakota ♪
♪ By the heavens ♪
♪ Blessed ♪
[ Joe ]
♪ rolling rivers
embrace the plain ♪
♪ Where some day
there's gonna be ♪
♪ Golden oceans
of blowing grain ♪
♪ Just as far
as your eyes can see ♪
[ Joe ]
♪ the black hills ♪
[ Chorus ] ♪ the black hills ♪
♪ The blue skies ♪
♪ the blue skies ♪
♪ of the shining west ♪
♪ Dakota ♪
♪ oh, Dakota ♪
♪ By the heavens ♪
♪ Blessed ♪
[ Crowd cheering, applauding ]
Now we met and we surpassed
every requirement...
Congress could
set forth.
[ Crowd ]
Right!
But do they Grant us
statehood?
[ Crowd ]
No.
Do they take us
into the union?
[ Crowd ]
No!
Do they live up
to their end of the bargain?
[ Crowd ] No!
And why not?
Why not, I ask you?
What's wrong with us?
- Maybe you talk too much!
- [ Crowd jeering ]
Well, then they'd better
get used to it...
Right!
'Cause there are a lot
of things that need to be said.
[ Crowd agreeing ]
I'll tell you
what the trouble really is.
They're afraid of us.
Who's afraid of you?
Because they know that
when north and south Dakota
become states,
and we send our senators
back to Washington, we're
gonna send Republicans, right?
- [ Booing ]
- Sit down,
you silly republican!
Why don't you be quiet,
you dumb democrat?
And that just might
break the stranglehold...
That grover Cleveland and his
Democratic congress have held
upon this great country of ours.
That Joe gets
himself wound up,
don't he?
Yeah!
[ Laughing ]
[ Joe ] We'll declare ourselves
the free and sovereign states
of north and south Dakota!
[ Crowd cheering ]
One thing, they got a pretty
good crowd out to cheer us
across the finish line.
Really, grandpa?
Why do you always have
to spoil a good story...
By asking,
"really, grandpa?"
[ Laughing ]
[ Crowd cheering ]
Isn't that Joe carder?
Right? We're free men.
We're free men.
We'll hold our own elections!
[ Crowd agreeing ]
We'll draw up a constitution
for the sovereign states
of north and south Dakota!
[ Crowd cheering ]
Now, grandpa,
you're not gonna get
into a political squabble...
Before we even got our feet
on the ground.
You know what they're trying
to do? They're trying to
divide Dakota into two states!
The only reason's so they can
send four republican senators
back to Washington...
Instead of just the two
they're supposed to have!
Now, take it easy.
Hey, Mr. carder!
We made it!
[ Children ]
Hello, Mr. carder!
- Another good republican
family come to join us.
- [ Crowd booing, cheering ]
[ Crowd murmuring ]
Oh. Oh.
Why, thank you, sir.
Ah, Ernie stubbins
at your service.
Alice.
Oh!
[ Giggles ]
You made it.
Good.
Oh, how are you?
Alice, uh, this is Ernie
stubbins, one of our local...
yeah.
We already swapped names
and done our howdies.
Alice, uh, Mr. wrenn,
the president
of the school board.
I told Mr. wrenn that
you might be interested
in a teaching position.
Miss bower, it's a pleasure.
If you'll come this way,
my dear,
I'll see that you're signed up.
Oh, well,
we just got here...
And I haven't even, uh...
Miss bower,
our school is closed for lack
of a teacher. We can't afford
to waste another day.
Oh, excuse me, Mr. wrenn.
Uh, Mr. and Mrs. Calvin bower.
How do you do?
[ Both ]
Mr. wrenn is president
of the school board.
Oh, and their family.
[ Children ]
Hello, Mr. wrenn.
I've located a house
for you, Mr. bower.
Good.
It's out on rapid creek.
It's not new, but it's big.
So, I guess you'd better
get signed up here in town.
Save a trip back, huh?
This won't take long. Then
I must get word to the children
that school opens tomorrow.
[ Children groan ]
Would you wait just a minute,
Mr. wrenn? I'll be right back.
♪ [ Banjo ]
Frank?
Yeah? Yeah?
Carry on for a few minutes, will
you please? I'll be right back.
Who, me? All right.
All right, all you children
wait here with grandpa.
[ Children ] All right.
But let's just look
at the national situation and
consider where we're drifting...
If something
isn't done to clear up
the mess in Washington.
[ Crowd ]
What mess?
What are ya talkin' about?
Let me ask you.
What has grover Cleveland
ever done to reduce
the federal surplus?
[ Crowd ] Yeah!
[ Frank ]
He just goes on...
Collecting his tariff
and piling more and more
dollars into the treasury.
[ Crowd ]
That's right!
[ Frank ]
Think what it will be like
in another 50 or 75 years.
Right. Every dollar
in the United States
piled up in Washington!
[ Crowd yelling ]
We're gonna have
the richest government...
And the poorest people
in the history of the world!
[ Crowd agreeing ]
We've got to remember to
send men back to Washington...
Who aren't too tightfisted
to spend a dollar
now and then. Right?
♪ [ Band playing ]
♪ [ Continues ]
♪
♪ In the frozen winter of '76 ♪
♪ In a place
called valley forge ♪
♪ Came a time
for a man of destiny ♪
♪ And his name
was general George ♪
♪ 'Twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
♪ 'twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
♪ In 1861, our ship
of state was sinkin' ♪
♪ Again came a man of destiny ♪
♪ A man by the name
of Lincoln ♪
[ Cheers ]
♪ 'Twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
♪ 'Twas a time for a man
and he was the man
for the time ♪
♪ In our land today
there's a man
who's tried and true ♪
♪ He's what this country needs
but it's up to me and you ♪
- ♪ Stephen grover Cleveland is
the man this country needs ♪
- [ Crowd disagreeing ]
♪ Let's put it over
with grover ♪
♪ Don't rock the boat
give him your vote ♪
[ Crowd clamoring ]
♪ Let's keep our country
in clover ♪
♪ It's up to you
he'll follow through ♪
♪ He made the white house
shine like a lighthouse ♪
♪ Over our 38 states ♪
♪ 1889 is the time
to fall in line ♪
♪ behind one of destiny's
greatest statesmen ♪
♪ Stephen grover Cleveland is
the man this country needs ♪
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Hold it down!
Get down from that wagon!
Look, there's no reason
to get upset.
[ Crowd ] Oh, yeah?
This is all just
kind of in fun.
[ Crowd disagreeing ]
Wait a minute!
Look, this is a real
fine, talented family:
The bowers.
[ Crowd clamoring ]
Now wait!
They've had a long trip.
And, as I've told
you before, they're gonna
be settling down here.
- Gonna be our neighbors.
- That's a mighty odd
sense of humor!
Come to a statehood rally
in Dakota and sing
about grover Cleveland!
[ Clamoring ]
You own the streets here, do ya?
Keep 'em reserved just
for speeches by Republicans?
[ Crowd laughing ]
I kind of thought
this was a free country!
[ Crowd agreeing ]
Yeah, that's a good one.
"I thought this was
a free country."
That's a good way to put it!
[ Crowd clamoring ]
- All right, grandpa. don't you
think you've said enough?
- No, not nearly enough!
I'm gonna find out if we're
still in the United States
of America,
or if we made a wrong turn back
there somewhere!
[ Man ] You should have turned.
Now turn around
and go back home!
We don't want ya here!
It isn't going to do any harm
if they sing a little song
about grover Cleveland.
[ Crowd disagreeing ]
Do you think that's all
it would take to get him
reelected?
[ Crowd ]
No!
Let me tell you somethin'!
Grover Cleveland's gonna
be reelected by the biggest
landslide in history!
[ Crowd scoffing, cheering ]
Well, that's what
makes horse races.
Well, I'll bet ya!
I'll bet ya!
[ Crowd clamoring ]
I'm not a bettin' man.
Aw, come on!
Come on!
Wait a minute.
In the newspaper business,
you can't afford to be.
- Wound up, I'll tell ya that.
- All right,
I'll tell ya what I'll do.
I'll give you a free ride
down this here street
in a wheelbarrow...
If Benjamin Harrison wins.
[ Crowd laughing ]
[ Crowd clamoring ]
That's right.
But now, listen, listen!
But you give me a ride
if grover Cleveland wins!
- [ Crowd laughing ]
- You can afford that,
can't ya?
[ Crowd ]
Come on, carder!
Come on, Joe!
All right, Mr. bower!
I'll take ya up on that!
[ Crowd cheering ]
Oh, mama,
I feel terrible not helping
you with all these things.
It's just so hard to get ready.
Don't worry about me, dear.
I'm getting along just fine.
Grandpa's using your
dresser mirror to shave.
[ Children talking ]
I hope we make
a lot of friends.
Me too.
You're just starting
to put on your hat?
Why don't all of you
go on ahead?
Don't worry about me.
I'll be there.
Yes, Alice, dear,
I think that's a very good idea.
Come on, children, now.
Off to school. Come on now.
Good-bye, mama.
Got your lunch?
Got your handkerchief?
Bye, mama.
Good-bye. Oh, Quinn,
do stop eating.
Bye, mama.
Good-bye, darling.
Bye.
Good-bye. Now, mind
your manners. Bye.
[ Children laughing ]
[ Sighs ]
Say, I'm all done
with that mirror now,
if you want it.
No, grandpa.
This is all right.
It's fine.
Say, this thing Joe carder's
talkin' about yesterday,
that they gonna set up
their own state government...
If the president
and the congress
don't do it for 'em.
Grandpa, please, not now.
Now, you best listen 'cause
something's being started...
That could hurt
a lot of people.
A person, place or thing:
Boy, dog, St. Louis, chair.
Anytime men think they're gonna
turn agin the president...
And the congress, take the law
into their own hands...
A pronoun replaces a noun:
And set up
their own government,
he, him, she, it, they, us.
Then there's gonna be trouble.
A verb is a word
that denotes action
or state of being.
Grandpa, that will do!
Well, I'm just tellin' her
for her own good.
Better off
if she got somebody else.
Ah, say,
that young cowboy that held
that horse for ya yesterday.
What's his name again?
Um, Ernie stubbins?
[ Chuckles ]
You remember his name, huh?
[ Laughing ]
Sure is a handsome devil,
ain't he?
Well, I don't know.
Yeah. Big he-man type.
You know, I like that.
Um, final
inspection.
Oh, just lovely, dear.
Wish me luck, mama.
Oh,
you'll be fine, Alice.
Grandpa, I love you.
Thank you.
If I said anything
that upset ya,
I didn't mean it.
I just don't want to see
ya get in over your head
before ya realize it.
[ Knocking ]
Oh.
Oh, I'm glad
I caught you.
Good morning,
Mrs. bower. Mr. bower.
Alice, there's been
a little problem come up.
It's a technicality, really,
about your credentials.
The school board wants to meet
with you and ask a few questions
before you start teaching.
Before I start teaching?
Well, that's less than an hour.
[ Joe ]
You'll have to call off
school, just for today.
I don't understand.
I thought everything
was taken care of yesterday.
They told me that...
By now the children
are probably on their way.
Mr. bower, uh, you know
where the schoolhouse is,
don't you?
Say, this thing you
were talking about
yesterday...
About how you were going to set
up your own state government...
grandpa, same rules as before.
There'll be no discussing
politics in this house either.
Do you think you could
go to the schoolhouse
and send the children home?
Tell them there won't be
any school today after all.
Do I think...
Thank you, sir.
Ah...
I'll bring her back, Mrs. bower.
And it's nothing to be concerned
about, just a technicality.
All right.
Whoa. Whoa.
I just want to show you
the place I wrote you about.
Remember?
But I don't think
we should if the school
board is waiting.
Alice, there are
a couple of ladies
on that school board...
That wouldn't get
to a meeting before
10:00, no matter what.
It's the "what"
I'm worried about.
Look, it's nothing, believe me.
Mr. wrenn happened to hear
about the ruckus in town
yesterday...
When your grandfather
sang his grover Cleveland
song.
Oh, what's that
got to do with me?
I guess he wants to talk to you.
Just to make sure
that you're not inclined
to stir things up.
Well, that's a very odd thing.
Maybe he wants to make
sure it doesn't run
in the family.
Oh?
[ Laughs ]
Come on!
Wait.
There.
Oh, it is
beautiful.
But let's come back
some other time.
Why?
Well, we want to be there
when the school board is
ready to meet.
[ Stammering ]
Then I have to get back
and help mom unpack.
Well, 'cause there are
floors to be scrubbed
and dishes to be washed...
And-and-and...
I want to plan more for
my first day at school.
[ Giggles ]
And...
♪ 'bout time
'bout time ♪
♪ We had a little taste
of wastin' time ♪
♪ Like lovers do ♪
♪ I'll waste a little time
alone with you ♪
♪ 'Bout time we two ♪
♪ Were livin' out a lovely
dream come true ♪
♪ 'Bout you, 'bout me ♪
♪ 'Bout love ♪
♪ 'Bout time, 'bout time ♪
♪ We spent a little time
with no one near ♪
♪ To watch me while ♪
♪ I say a little somethin'
in your ear ♪
♪ 'Bout how I care ♪
♪ 'Bout how I want
to make my feelings clear ♪
♪ 'Bout you, 'bout me ♪
♪ 'Bout love ♪
♪ We're in deep water, darlin' ♪
♪ Clear over our head ♪
♪ 'bout time to either
sink or swim ♪
♪ let's swim ♪
♪ 'Nuff said ♪
♪ 'Bout time, 'bout time ♪
♪ We didn't have
to always steal a kiss ♪
♪ 'Bout time, 'bout time ♪
♪ I had my arm around
your waist like this ♪
♪ My whole life through ♪
♪ I wanna make you feel
the way I do ♪
♪ 'Bout you, 'bout me ♪
♪ 'Bout love ♪
♪ We're in deep water,
darlin' ♪
♪ Clear over our head ♪
♪ 'Bout time to either
sink or swim ♪
♪ Let's swim ♪
♪ 'nuff said ♪
♪ 'Bout time, 'bout time ♪
♪ 'bout time, 'bout time ♪
♪ We should be pickin' out
a weddin' day ♪
♪ July ♪
♪ no, June ♪
♪ My folks were married
in the month of may ♪
♪ 'Bout now, 'bout all ♪
♪ That's left to do
is let the secret out ♪
♪ 'Bout you, 'bout me ♪
♪ 'Bout us, 'bout we ♪
♪ 'Bout your love ♪
♪ And mine ♪
'Bout time.
[ Giggles ]
[ Grandpa ] So, there's
gonna be no school today and
ya might as well all go home.
[ Children cheering ]
[ Children laughing, shouting ]
[ Laughing, shouting continues ]
What's the matter, honey?
You get hurt?
Somebody bump you?
What's your name?
Edna.
What are you crying for, edna,
if you haven't been hurt?
I memorized a piece to speak...
And got dressed up...
And I slept all night...
With my hair put up in rags...
And now...
There's gonna be no school.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Chuckles ]
Why don't you speak it for me?
'Cause we ain't in school.
That's what I learned it for.
Well, now, wait a minute.
There ain't no reason
why we couldn't have just
a little bit of school.
But you said, "go on home."
What I meant...
I didn't mean right now.
I didn't say,
"go home right now."
I never said that.
[ Children laughing, shouting ]
Hey!
Come on back here, all of you!
Where you goin'?
Get back here!
Don't go tryin' to sneak off...
The minute my back is turned!
You told us to go.
You said there wouldn't
be any school today.
Yeah!
I was just testin' you,
that's all.
You gonna believe anybody
that comes along, no matter
what they tell you?
[ Grandpa laughing ]
You got a lot to learn, boy.
You better stay around.
[ Ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
[ Children chattering ]
[ Chattering continues ]
All right, sit down now.
Come on. Sit down.
Come on, get your seats.
Sit anywhere.
Hey!
Well, now, this here,
as most of you know,
is the first day of school.
[ Children booing ]
And, for the time bein',
I'm gonna be your teacher.
[ All ]
What?
Now, we're gonna have...
Just a few little things,
and then I'll let you go home.
[ Cheering ]
Now, little edna here,
she's learned a piece to speak,
and she's gonna come
right up in the front,
and she's gonna speak it.
And you're gonna pay attention.
You don't need to wave good-bye.
We ain't goin' no place.
[ Laughing ]
I wanna ask you something.
What's your name, son?
Johnny dejohn.
- All right.
What you want to ask?
- Are you a regular teacher?
Well, no,
my granddaughter Alice, she's
gonna be your regular teacher.
I'm just fillin' in
for the time bein'.
What I want to know...
Would you set yourself down?
Now, you go ahead, honey.
We're all listenin'.
The mountain
and the squirrel
had a quarrel.
The former called the latter,
"little prig."
Bun replied,
"if I am not so large as you,
"you are not so small as I.
"If I cannot carry mountains
on my back,
neither can you crack a nut."
Ralph Waldo Emerson.
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, that's fine!
That's fine.
[ Chuckling ]
Something bothering you, Johnny?
I was trying to find out,
sir... did you graduate
from the eighth grade?
Do you have a certificate
to show you're a regular,
qualified teacher?
Well, now,
I'll tell you this, boy.
If I know something
you don't know, then I'm
qualified to teach you.
Providing, of course,
you got sense enough to learn.
[ Children laughing ]
Could I ask, sir, have you
ever taught before?
Well, yes, you might say so.
I recollect a time
there was about 50 men...
I learned them all to shoot
and take care of their rifles.
I was the only teacher they had.
But in school?
That was in the army.
In the civil war!
Right there's the first thing
I'm gonna learn ya!
The proper name is
"the war between the states,"
'cause that's what it was!
[ Johnny ]
You can look
in the history books.
They call it the civil war.
What about that?
Yeah!
I don't need to look
in no books!
I was there,
Shiloh to appomattox,
and you can take my word,
there weren't nothin'
civil about it!
[ Children laughing ]
That's 'cause you were
a ringtail rebel!
Otherwise,
you wouldn't object to it
being called the civil war!
I done my fighting
for the confederacy...
And general Lee,
if that's what you mean.
I thought so.
I knew it from the start.
The important thing ain't
what you know from the start,
it's what you learn goin' along.
We should have learned
one lesson from that war:
About our country
staying united!
Abraham Lincoln said,
"a house divided against
itself cannot stand."
[ Grandpa ]
Folks from Lincoln's
own party...
Want to divide up Dakota,
the north from the south.
It just don't make sense.
My father says majority rules,
and they voted
to make it two states.
[ Grandpa chuckling ]
You put your finger on it
right there when you says...
They voted on it.
But who's gonna run this state
after us old codgers is gone?
It's gonna be you
young people, that's who!
But anybody ask you to vote?
[ Children shout ]
No!
[ Grandpa ] No, sir.
They try to tell you
they voted on it!
And you got no say-so!
That's your idea?
Just sit back and let them
chop the wagon in two...
When you know it's gonna be you
that's got to drive it?
How can we do anything
about it if we're not
old enough to vote?
[ Children shouting ]
Yeah!
There's always ways
to do things once the body
puts his mind to it.
I recollect a boy, wasn't much
bigger than you are, if at all!
When the war
between the north and south
had only just begun,
a little fella ran away
and joined up with his drum.
♪ He became a drummer ♪
♪ In a rifle company ♪
♪ The youngest
bravest drummer boy ♪
♪ In history ♪
♪ 'Cause he kept ♪
♪ Drummin', drummin', drummin' ♪
♪ While the enemy
kept a'comin' ♪
♪ Drummin'
drummin', drummin' ♪
♪ Unafraid
he held his ground ♪
♪ Drummin'
drummin', drummin' ♪
♪ While the enemy
kept a'comin' ♪
♪ Drummin'
while the shot and shell
was burstin' all around ♪
♪ [ Drumming ]
♪ [ Continues drumming ]
♪ In the middle
of a battle ♪
♪ That looked
like sure defeat ♪
♪ [ Drumming ]
♪ all the ranks
began to break ♪
♪ And someone yelled
"retreat" ♪
♪ But not that
little drummer boy ♪
♪ He stood there
like a stone ♪
♪ And played and played
the battle roll ♪
♪ All alone ♪
♪ [ Drumming fingers ]
♪ [ Drumming continues ]
♪ yes, he kept ♪
♪ Drummin', drummin', drummin' ♪
♪ While the enemy
kept a'comin' ♪
♪ Drummin'
drummin', drummin' ♪
♪ Unafraid
he held his ground ♪
♪ Drummin'
drummin', drummin' ♪
♪ While the enemy
kept a'comin' ♪
♪ Drummin'
while the shot and shell
was burstin' all around ♪
♪ When the soldiers
that were fleeing ♪
♪ drumming ♪
♪ Heard his drum
and saw that sight ♪
♪ drumming ♪
♪ It was almost
like a miracle ♪
♪ drumming ♪
♪ Their fear
it turned to fight ♪
♪ keep it drumming ♪
♪ And how they fought
and how they won ♪
♪ drumming ♪
♪ Is history today ♪
♪ Because that
little drummer boy
showed the way ♪
♪ Yes, he kept drummin'
drummin', drummin' ♪
♪ While the enemy
kept a'comin' ♪
♪ Drummin', drummin', drummin' ♪
♪ Unafraid, he held his ground ♪
♪ While the enemy
kept a'comin' ♪
♪ Drummin'
while the shot and shell
was burstin' all around ♪
They say a rose that
blooms in summertime...
Must die when winter comes,
but the memory
of its perfume lives...
Like the memory of those drums.
Well, now the war
between blue and gray
is fadin' in the past,
but the courage
of that drummer boy...
Is something that will last.
Wasn't that Johnny Shiloh?
Yeah, I guess that's what
some called him after...
he was a yankee.
- He didn't fight
for the confederacy.
- I never said he did.
But he was an American.
He didn't sit around and say,
"I'm only a little boy.
What can I do?"
I'll tell my pa,
"if I'm old enough to help
with the milking,
I'm old enough to have
some say about things!"
[ Children cheering ]
And we gotta keep talkin',
talkin', talkin' like he kept
drummin', drummin', drummin'!
What are you trying
to do, Mr. bower?
Get Alice fired
before she starts?
Oh, hold on...
moving in,
taking over a school.
I didn't exactly take over.
I asked you to send
the children home,
to tell them
there wouldn't be
any school today.
Now, Joe...
the young'uns
were already there.
Most of them
was all gussied up,
bein' the first day of school.
It just seemed a shame
to send them home.
I don't think he meant any harm.
Right while you and I were
meeting with the school board,
giving our word of honor...
That nothing like this
would ever happen!
It won't ever happen again.
I figured if Alice knowed
enough to teach them
for a whole year,
I knowed enough
to teach them for one day;
Just part of a day, actually.
But that's just the point!
You didn't teach them!
Joe, please!
You got them cornered
in the schoolhouse...
And then you delivered
a political oration...
About not dividing Dakota,
about making it one state!
It oughta be one state!
If you had a lick of brains,
you'd see it for yourself!
Grandpa, that's enough!
I'm sorry, Mrs. bower.
Let's just hope none
of the other students
go home and start talking.
I wouldn't figure on that!
Joe! Joe.
After this, if it's anything
to do with my family,
just let me handle it.
[ Sighs ]
Look, it isn't just
about your family.
That's a public school.
I know.
I also know that you don't
know grandpa the way I do.
To you, he's probably just
a cantankerous old man...
That's not the point!
He might be the sweetest man
in the whole world!
But if he's gonna
take over a public school,
inject politics
into the classroom, then...
Then it's not just
a little thing that
you can patch up at home.
I'll say one thing for you.
For a man that goes around
preachin' treason agin our
United States government,
you sure make a big fuss over
a little thing like me teachin'
school for a couple hours.
What do you mean
"treason," Mr. bower?
This business you keep
talkin' about settin' up
your own government,
defying the president
and the congress that's been
elected by the people!
Mr. bower, I don't mind you
arguing politics, so long as you
don't do it in a schoolhouse.
You're entitled to your
own opinion, even if it is
completely ridiculous!
But when you go around, start
accusing people of treason...
Joe, stop it!
Grandpa, get back
in that house!
[ Joe ] I don't care if he is
your grandfather, he's not
gonna accuse me of treason!
It ain't just my idea.
It's in the Democratic digest!
Grandpa!
The president himself
may send troops...
be quiet!
I'm asking you as nicely
as I know how, please leave.
Alice. Alice.
No!
[ Door slams ]
[ Whinnies ]
Best thing could have
happened for Alice,
break it off
with a man like that.
Cause her nothing but heartache
the longer she knowed him.
I... think it's time
for the two of us...
To have a little talk.
In here as good a place as any.
Remember the last time
I took you to the woodshed?
When you fought
that barros boy
and bloodied his nose.
Never forget how you
kept a'wigglin' around.
[ Chuckles ]
I had me a big
old kindlin' stick,
but mostly it kept
a'whangin' away in the air,
never connectin' with nothin'.
And all the time you was
a'howlin' like a banshee.
I'm gonna tell you something.
Most of the time
I was missin' the purpose.
This isn't gonna be easy.
Just don't know how to say it.
"This is gonna hurt me
more than it does you,"
is the customary
way to start off.
Least ways, that's how
I always got into it.
You know, I had a hunch
you never listened to me.
Pa...
I have tried,
all the years that
you've been with us,
to make you feel
welcome... wanted.
And you have been.
There have been times
when, well, I've overlooked
things that you've done...
More than I would
for any other member
of the family.
What kind of things?
But I won't have you making
trouble for Alice and Joe.
Me cause trouble?
Joe carder's
making his own trouble;
More than he realizes.
Thinks just 'cause
he runs that little
no-account newspaper...
I want you
to promise me one thing:
That you will never again
argue politics with Joe carder.
Well, now, it weren't just me.
Don't you ever say one word
to him about whether Dakota
should be one state or two.
Suppose he says something first?
I'm not talking about him,
I'm talking about you.
I'm talkin' about him!
What do you think I'm gonna do?
Just sit like a ninny and not
say nothin' if he pops off?
I've said my say.
You've heard me.
That's the way
it's gonna have to be.
Now, that's the way it
ain't gonna have to be.
I'll tell you that much.
If you think I'm gonna
give up my right
of free speech...
That men fought and died for...
Just so Joe carder can have
everything his own way...
Will you listen to me?
You think I'm gonna sit
like a bump on a log...
Whilst maybe
my own granddaughter
is fixin' to marry some...
Benedict Arnold!
I'll tell you what I think!
If you're gonna remain here
as a member of this family,
then you better
start to exercise
a little self-control...
Just the same as everybody else!
You said that.
If'n I'm gonna stay here?
Every time i...
hello,
grandpa.
Hello, grandpa.
Mine is shinier
than yours.
That has a little
dent on it though.
[ Children continue chattering ]
Grandpa, what are you doin'?
I know when I ain't wanted.
I don't have to be
hit on the head...
With a 10-foot pole.
What are you talking about,
"not wanted"?
I ain't so old or so feeble
or so hard up that...
I have to stay with folks
that don't want me.
Calvin, what's going on here?
I just made a very
reasonable request
of grandpa, no more.
Actually, a lot less than
I might make any day of any
member of this family.
But i...
Excuse me, Katie.
Grandpa, please don't go.
Grandpa, you can't leave!
[ Crying ]
How can we practice
or anything?
[ Children ]
Grandpa, please don't go!
You can't!
Grandpa, please.
Grandpa, please!
Grandpa,
please don't go!
Please, grandpa.
Calvin, what did you do to him?
All I did... I asked him not
to argue politics with Joe.
Then you better get it
straightened out right now,
before he gets his neck
bowed any more than it is.
It took me a long time, Katie,
before I finally got around
to saying anything.
I don't believe
I've been unreasonable,
and I'm not going to back down.
But...
I guess you know best.
[ Children pleading ]
Grandpa, please don't go!
[ Pleading continues ]
Thanks, Katie,
for a lot of things.
I'll be seeing you
again sometime.
Grandpa, please don't go!
Please, grandpa!
Grandpa, don't go!
Papa, you've got to stop him.
You can't let him go.
We love you.
[ Crying ]
Please, grandpa!
Please
don't go.
Grandpa.
[ Calvin ]
Mayo...
Come back here.
[ Crying ]
If grandpa's goin',
then I'm goin' too.
[ Calvin ]
Mayo.
Did you hear me?
I wish we hadn't even
heard about Dakota,
[ sobbing ]
Let alone...
Let alone comin' here.
[ Children crying ]
I don't see any reason
to review what happened
at the school that day.
Indeed, I think some of you
parents have already heard
more than you care to hear.
[ Crowd murmuring ]
I'm going to ask
miss bower...
If she has any statements
she would care to make.
[ Crowd chattering ]
I wish you would
all understand this:
Anything my grandfather did,
he did out of the goodness
of his heart.
He didn't mean
to do anything wrong.
[ Crowd groaning ]
[ Gavel pounding ]
You will all have your
opportunity to speak.
Now, shall we behave
like adults and allow
miss bower to continue...
Without interruption?
[ Quiet murmuring ]
And actually,
I can't see the harm
in anything my grandfather did.
He merely...
miss bower, do you mean that
you approve of what he did?
[ Crowd murmuring ]
I mean...
If we're going
to educate the children,
I don't see why...
I can't see any harm...
In letting them hear
both sides of the question.
What do you mean, "both sides"?
This question of statehood
has already been settled.
[ Loud agreeing ]
We've worked hard
to get it settled.
That's not what
I'm talking about.
[ Wrenn ]
Let me ask you
one thing.
When your grandfather
went there to the school
to poison the minds...
Mr. bower's too much
of a gentleman...
[ Shouting ]
[ Gavel pounding ]
Mr. wampler, sit down!
To poison the minds
of the children,
did he do so
with your knowledge
and consent?
I knew where he was going, yes,
[ crowd murmuring ]
But I don't think
he poisoned any minds.
Now, wait just a minute!
Let me get one thing straight!
I was the one that sent
her grandfather there...
To the schoolhouse
that morning.
[ Crowd ] You were?
Not Alice.
Not miss bower.
Alice?
Joe, you promised.
I'm not gonna watch you
get ripped apart...
For something that
wasn't even your fault.
Don't say another word.
You just don't realize.
Your board questioned
this young teacher extensively.
She assured us that
nothing of thi...
[ man ]
Well, who invited him here?
What's he doing here?
[ Crowd murmuring ]
[ Man ]
Of all the nerve!
[ Murmuring continues ]
Now that Mr. bower is here,
I'd just like to ask him
a couple of questions.
So would we.
Yeah,
we would too.
Isn't it true,
Mr. bower...
no! Stop it!
There's no need to go on
with your meeting any more.
And there's no need to vote
on whether or not to fire me...
Because I quit, as of right now.
[ Crowd ]
Good. That's good.
[ Joe ]
Alice, you're being foolish.
Maybe I don't know your
grandfather as well as you do,
but even he wouldn't
want you to take the blame
for something that he did.
Don't you understand
anything at all?
He left because he thought
we didn't want him...
I'm all for family loyalty.
I think it's a wonderful thing.
But there are limits
to all things!
Including my Patience!
Now, will you just
leave me alone?
Alice, will you listen?
[ Horse whinnies ]
Whoa!
[ Sighs ]
May I escort you
up the street, miss bower?
Delighted, Mr. stubbins.
Until such time as we can
find another teacher,
meanwhile,
the school will be closed.
Now, if there's no further
business to be brought
before the board...
I got something to say.
[ Angry murmuring ]
[ Gavel pounding ]
I will not have this meeting...
Turned into another
political debate
or debacle!
What I got to say,
I don't think anybody's
gonna argue with.
If we was to pick out
the worse thing that
could possibly happen,
that would be to have
that school closed again...
When it just barely got open.
Yeah, that's right.
The point is...
If I'd have took time
to thought about it...
I'd have realized
I was doin' wrong.
Movin' into that school
that way,
passin' on ideas that
I happen to believe in.
Well, I tell you,
that's been one
of my troubles...
All my life.
I don't generally
stop and think...
'Til after it's too late.
But this time I got it
all thought out ahead,
and I'd like to make you
just a little proposition.
What kind
of a proposition?
[ Loud murmuring ]
What kind of a proposition?
Well, you get hold of Alice
and talk her into takin'
the job back as teacher...
And you'll keep
that school open.
[ Crowd ]
That's a good idea.
That's fair.
And I give you
my solemn promise,
I won't say one other word
about politics...
Or whether Dakota
oughta be one state
or two...
Until the whole thing
has been settled
for good.
And then there ain't much use
to say nothin' after that.
[ Crowd murmuring ]
He is absolutely
right!
[ Loud chattering ]
[ Knocking ]
It ain't locked.
Just give a little push.
Just come over
to tell you that both
Katie and I think...
It was a fine,
generous thing
you did this morning.
We were proud of you.
Goin' somewhere?
I thought maybe.
Any place special in mind?
You figure it'd be easier
just to run off...
Rather than to stay here
and face it day by day.
I just wonder what people...
What people might say,
that's all.
You haven't forgotten that
bet you made with Joe carder
the first day we came to town.
Some of the boys have got
a wheelbarrow all decorated up,
ready for the payoff.
Seems like if you left town now,
they might say that you were
running out on a bet.
They probably figured
you were afraid you'd lose.
Afraid I'd lose!
Do you want to know something?
In my whole life
I've never been more...
Well,
I can't discuss that without
gettin' mixed up in something
I promised not to talk about.
Oh, and another thing.
The family band has been
invited to play...
At the rapid city
election carnival,
the night the returns come in.
Trouble is, we haven't had
a band practice since you left.
Confound it, Calvin!
You're supposed to be
the head of the family.
You ought to see to it.
The whole family's been
kind of upset.
Upset or not, that don't matter!
You gonna have a band,
you got to practice,
practice, practice!
Mostly we need you, pa.
Why don't you come home
where you belong?
I know you'd let me
wait my life out,
you'd never give in.
So I'm askin' you.
Please?
For Katie and the children...
And me.
What do you say?
Seems like if we was
to get started instead
of standin' here talkin',
maybe we'd get there
in time for supper.
That election night thing is
gonna be our first real chance
to show off the family band.
♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
[ Hooting ]
♪ west of the wide mo
west of the wide mo ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
♪
[ Hooting ]
♪ You'll work all day
'til sun goes down ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ Then everybody comes to town
west of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ Hoedown music starts to play ♪
♪ You whoop it up
'til the break of day ♪
♪ Then it's back
to stackin' hay ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri
west of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ West of the wide mo
west of the wide mo ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
♪
♪ The gals have eyes
that twinkle and shine
west of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ They kiss as sweet
as dandelion wine
west of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ Eastern ladies may be fine
delicate and feminine ♪
♪ But every gal's
a Valentine ♪
♪ Every gal's a Valentine
west of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri
♪ West of the wide mo
west of the wide mo ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
[ Hooting ]
♪
♪ Love's a treetop
towering thing ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ Every man becomes a king
west of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ Even in a gingham gown
a gal's a queen
without a crown ♪
♪ The day she settles
dilly-aye down ♪
♪ dilly-aye ♪
♪ Dilly-aye, dilly-aye down
west of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri
♪ West of the wide mo
west of the wide mo ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ Fellas don't wear
citified clothes ♪
♪ West of the wide
Missouri ♪
♪ But, oh, they know
their do-si-dos ♪
♪ West of the wide
Missouri ♪
♪ Eastern fellas may be slick
smell as sweet as
a peppermint stick ♪
♪ But the boys that make us
dilly-aye tick ♪
♪ The boys that make us
♪ Are west
of the wide Missouri ♪
♪
[ Crowd hooting ]
♪ West of the wide
west of the wide ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
♪
[ Crowd hooting ]
♪ West of the wide
west of the wide
west of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
♪ West of the wide
west of the wide ♪
♪ West of the wide Missouri ♪
[ Dancers hooting ]
[ Crowd cheering ]
My compliments.
And ours to both of you.
Hey, you might as well give up.
You're never gonna
learn him how to dance!
[ Laughing ]
I think he's sweet.
[ Giggling ]
Aww!
[ Laughing ]
That's enough!
First reports!
[ Crowd cheering ]
They just come in!
First reports!
[ Chattering ]
Just fragmentary,
scattered returns
from New York.
For Benjamin Harrison...
[ Crowd murmuring ]
337.
[ Cheering ]
- For grover Cleveland...
- [ Crowd shouting ]
294.
[ Groaning ]
Delaware, with less than
two percent of the vote in:
Yes? Yes, come on.
- Harrison... 219.
- [ Shouting ] Come on!
[ Cheering ]
Cleveland...
[ Indistinct chattering ]
- 348.
- [ Cheering ]
[ Republicans groaning ]
If Harrison can't even carry
Delaware, he's got no chance!
[ Laughing ]
♪
♪ Let's put it over
with grover ♪
♪ Don't rock the boat
give him your vote ♪
♪ Give your vote to a man
who's a leader of men ♪
♪ Let's put
Stephen grover over ♪
♪ Over again ♪
[ Crowd cheering ]
Never said a word, not a word.
Mr. bower.
Frank. Mr. wrenn.
Ladies and gentlemen.
♪
♪ now, Cleveland says
the future looks bright ♪
♪ Yes, that's right
♪ Ah, that's politics ♪
♪ The dollar is sound
and the market is right ♪
♪ Yes, that's right
the market is right ♪
♪ Ah, that's politics ♪
♪ Harrison says
the market is right
the dollar is sound ♪
♪ The future looks bright ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah
that's statesmanship ♪
[ Scoffing ]
No democrat politician, he.
A great
republican statesman.
An inspiration to us all!
♪ Oh, Benjamin Harrison ♪
♪ He's far beyond comparison ♪
♪ He'll keep our land
a Garrison ♪
[ Booing ]
♪ Of life and Liberty ♪
♪ Cleveland promises
no new states ♪
♪ No new states
♪ Ah, that's politics ♪
♪ No new senators
low tax rates ♪
♪ Low tax rates
♪ Ah, that's politics ♪
♪ Harrison promises
two new states ♪
♪ Four new senators
low tax rates ♪
♪ Ah, ah, ah
that's statesmanship ♪
[ Democrats ]
Ha! Statesmanship?
A giant!
A great man!
The future president
of the United States!
[ Shouting ]
Grover! Over here!
♪ Oh, Benjamin Harrison ♪
- ♪ He's far beyond comparison ♪
- [ Indistinct shouting ]
♪ He'll keep our land
a Garrison ♪
♪ Of life and Liberty ♪
♪ Grover Cleveland
grover Cleveland
grover Cleveland ♪
[ Crowd cheering ]
Harrison says
that his moustache is bright!
[ Angry clamoring ]
Stand back!
More returns!
Wait a minute, wait a minute!
Returns, returns!
[ Crowd clamoring ]
[ Crowd cheering ]
[ Laughing, cheering ]
[ Cheering continues ]
Hey, Joe, come on!
You owe us a ride!
Come on! Get in!
Come on, Joe!
Doesn't mean the end
of our fight for statehood.
We've just begun to fight.
Kind of has a nice
ring to it somehow.
[ Crowd shouting ]
Joe carder!
Shh!
[ Laughing ]
It's about time me and you
went for a little ride.
I'm afraid you're
gonna have to walk!
[ Laughing ]
That's a good one!
"Afraid you're gonna
have to walk"!
[ Laughing ]
I always said, for a newspaper
publisher, you'd make a good
wheelbarrow jockey!
When the official word
comes over the wire,
then we'll start paying
any bets, not before!
[ Groaning ]
No, Mr. wrenn.
I'm ready if you are,
Mr. bower. Come on.
Ya-hoo!
[ Crowd clamoring ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Man ]
Hold everything!
Hold everything.
[ Woman ]
What now?
Harrison won.
[ Democrats scoffing ]
It's Ben Harrison.
Come on,
cut it out.
Elected president.
That ain't even
possible.
[ Man ]
What does it say?
[ Joe ] It's true.
True?
The electoral college...
Has named Harrison president.
What's some college
got to do about it?
What about the votes?
[ Man ]
That's right!
That's not the point.
Our president is always named
by the electoral college.
That don't even make sense!
Right!
If Cleveland got the most votes,
he's got to be president!
[ Men ] Right!
[ Democrats cheering ]
No! No!
That's the way it's set up,
in our constitution!
We won!
[ Indistinct chattering ]
Don't you know anything at all
about American history?
don't you realize...
All I realize
is that the democrats
elect a president,
then the Republicans
cheat 'em out of it!
[ Laughing ]
♪ [ Band playing ]
♪ Oh, Benjamin Harrison ♪
♪ He's far beyond
comparison ♪
♪ He'll keep our land
a Garrison ♪
- ♪ Of life and Liberty ♪
- [ Laughing ]
[ Shouting, laughing ]
All right!
Listen!
We beat you fair and square!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
[ Children shouting, cheering ]
They got Harrison!
All right, let's get Cleveland!
Ah, come on, fellas!
[ Hooting ]
[ Indistinct shouting ]
[ Women screaming ]
♪ [ Band playing
"my country 'tis of thee" ]
♪
[ Crowd quiets ]
♪ [ Continues ]
- ♪ [ Stops ]
- [ Shouting resumes ]
Don't start anything!
I can keep playing
all night if I have to!
♪ [ Band resumes ]
don't start anything!
Apparently, the next
President of the united
states has been chosen.
[ Crowd shouting ]
[ Calvin ]
And the future of Dakota
has been settled!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
And nothing we can
do here now...
Is going to change
things one iota.
[ Man ]
Not one thing.
I know some of you have
been bitterly disappointed.
[ Crowd murmuring ]
I want to pass
along to you...
Something that was told me
many years ago...
By a man whom I have
respected and admired...
More than any man
I have ever met.
A man who never wavered
in his conviction...
That we here together
can build the greatest...
United country
in the whole bloomin' world...
If you'll just
remember one thing.
There's a time
to stand up and fight
for what you believe in...
[ murmured agreements ]
And there is a time
to join hands and
work together,
or all the fighting
doesn't mean a thing.
He's just makin' that up.
Wasn't no important man at all.
Just something I told him.
I know that this man...
Swallowed more disappointment
than any of you did tonight.
This was back in '65...
When he had just returned
home from appomattox.
My father, rensselaer bower.
Where is he?
Here he is!
Here he is.
And so I suggest that this
is a time for joining hands,
a time for making up.
Well, if he's gonna quote
such a good authority,
I guess I can't argue with him.
[ Crowd laughing ]
All right, to lead off,
I'm invitin' Joe carder...
To come and get
his wheelbarrow ride.
[ Crowd cheering ]
Hey, that a boy, Joe!
That a boy!
And I apologize for anything
I might have said that was
out of line, at any time.
[ Crowd cheering ]
[ Horn clattering ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Cheering ]
Alice!
[ Crowd hooting ]
[ Indistinct shouting ]
[ Cheering continues ]
[ Joe ]
♪ we're in deep water, darlin' ♪
♪ Clear over our head ♪
♪ 'Bout time to either
sink or swim ♪
♪ 'Bout time, 'bout time ♪
♪ We put an end
to all our bickerings ♪
♪ 'Bout time, 'bout time ♪
♪ We got around to more
important things ♪
♪ Like golden rings ♪
♪ And pickin' out
the perfect furnishings ♪
♪ For you, for me ♪
[ Joe ]
♪ for us ♪
♪ for we ♪
♪ For your home and mine ♪
- 'Bout time!
- [ Cheering ]
- News! Big news!
Quiet!
Listen, everybody!
News! Big news!
Listen!
Quiet, everybody!
[ Crowd shouting ]
[ Shouting continues ]
[ Crowd chanting ]
Up! Up! Up!
Big news! Listen!
"President Cleveland
announced tonight...
"He will Grant statehood
to north and south Dakota...
Before Harrison
takes office."
[ Cheering ]
People! People!
Listen to me!
This will do it!
Now we can send four more
republican senators to congress
and give Harrison...
The edge he needs!
[ Crowd cheering ]
There's more!
All right, there's more.
Listen!
"He will also Grant statehood
to Montana and Washington."
[ Democrats cheering ]
Washington and Montana!
They'll both go
Democratic!
You send four more
Republicans back to Washington,
we send four more democrats!
Wipe out every gain you've made!
We're right back
where we started!
One thing for grover Cleveland:
He listens
to the mandate
of the people!
Ah, that's politics!
That's statesmanship!
- [ Laughing ]
- ♪ [ Band playing ]
♪
♪ And when the razzamatazz
of our brasses ♪
♪ Begins to bezaz in the air
something grand ♪
♪ Better get ready to hear ♪
♪ And better get ready to cheer
the one and only ♪
♪ One and only, one and only
one and only ♪
♪ One and only, genuine
original ♪
♪ Original family band ♪
Encoded by dw817 (Aug 19th 2015)