NARRATOR: A LONG TIME AGO
IN A SMALL PRINCIPALITY
SOMEWHERE IN THE MIDDLE
OF A HAPPY EUROPE,
THERE WAS A RICH OLD DUKE
WHO LIVED HAPPILY IN A FINE PALACE,
AND A NUMBER OF LADIES AND GENTLEMEN
WHO LIVED HAPPILY
ON THE FASHIONABLE HILL
AND EVERYBODY ELSE WHO LIVED
HAPPILY IN THE VILLAGE.
NOW IT CAME TO PASS
THAT IN THE SPRING,
THREE DAYS OF FESTIVAL WERE DECLARED.
THEY WERE CELEBRATING
THE RETURN OF PRINCE CHARLES,
THE ONLY SON OF THE REIGNING DUKE.
MOST OF THE TOWNSPEOPLE
HAD NEVER SEEN PRINCE CHARLES.
HE HAD BEEN AWAY FOR MANY YEARS,
GETTING HIS EDUCATION
IN THE FINEST UNIVERSITIES,
CAFES, AND BOUDOIRS OF PARIS,
LONDON, AND VIENNA.
WOMAN: NO, NOT THAT WAY!
[LAUGHTER]
WOMAN: OH, LOOK!
NOW IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
SECOND WOMAN: YES, LIKE THAT.
BUT A LITTLE HIGHER, WILLIE.
HIGHER?
I'LL BREAK MY NECK!
WELL, THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE WAITING FOR!
[LAUGHTER]
WILLIE: WELL,
WHERE'S THE HAMMER?
SECOND WOMAN:  OH, IT'S, UH...
OH, OVER THERE!
EDWINA, HOLD THIS, PLEASE.
TIE IT TO THE OTHER ONE.
LOOK WHO'S HERE.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU WANT?
I WANT TO--TO HELP.
I CLEAN UP, EH?
I'LL PICK UP THE ONES THAT DROP,
SO THAT EVERYTHING
BE NICE AND CLEAN.
SHE'S GOING TO MAKE
EVERYTHING NICE AND CLEAN.
I'LL SWEEP THE TORN LEAVES
AND THE LITTLE STRINGS.
SEE?
STAY AWAY FROM ME,
YOU DIRTY THING!
OH, I'M NOT DIRTY!
JUST CINDERS. LOOK!
PLEASE, LOOK!
OH, MAKE HER GO AWAY, WILLIE.
MY MOTHER SAYS
I MUSTN'T SPEAK TO HER.
GO AWAY, CINDERS.
MY NAME IS ELLA, AND I'M NOT DIRTY.
I'VE JUST BEEN CARRYING OUT THE ASHES.
JUST CINDERS AND ASHES.
MAYBE A LITTLE SOOT,
BUT I--
ELLA CINDER!
DIRTY CINDER!
WILLIE:  GOOD-BYE, CINDERELLA.
CINDERELLA!
STOP IT!
NOW LOOK WHAT YOU'VE DONE,
YOU UGLY THING!
I AM NOT UGLY!
YOU ARE UGLY!
YOU SMELL OF BUTTER!
YOU HAVE A BIG FAT BOPU.
AND YOU HAVE A VOICE LIKE A PIG!
AND YOU--YOU--
YOU--
NARRATOR:
SO, YOU SEE HOW IT WAS.
OH, WELL, THEY CAN
SCARCELY BE BLAMED,
FOR SHE WAS NOT PRECISELY
AN AMIABLE CHILD.
THE GROWN-UPS OF THE TOWN
AGREED WITH THEIR SONS AND DAUGHTERS.
THEY'RE SAYING, "TSK, TSK.
DREADFUL, DREADFUL.
"THE GIRL'S A DISGRACE.
"SHE GROWS WORSE EVERY DAY.
LOOK AT HER HAIR."
IT WAS THE OLD STORY
OF THE REJECTED BECOMING
ALL THE MORE REJECTED
BECAUSE THEY BEHAVED BADLY
BECAUSE THEY'D BEEN REJECTED--
ONE OF THOSE, UH, CIRCLES.
AND THERE IT WAS AGAIN,
THE HEAT OF TEARS BURNING
BEHIND THE EYES.
AND SO SHE CAME HOME.
THIS PRIMPING IS IN PREPARATION
FOR THE ARRIVAL OF THE PRINCE,
FOR HE MAY GLANCE THEIR WAY
WHEN HE RIDES DOWN THE STREET.
THESE ARE ELLA'S STEPSISTERS.
THIS IS BIRDENA--
VIVACIOUS, DAZZLING,
BEAUTIFUL AS A ROSE,
AND POISONOUS AS A TOADSTOOL.
AND THIS IS SERAFINA--LANGUID, SEDUCTIVE,
EFFORTLESSLY ALLURING,
AND COLD AS A COBRA.
AND THIS IS ELLA'S STEPMOTHER,
THE WIDOW SONDER.
"STRAIGHTEN UP, ELLA.
"DO THIS, ELLA.
"DO THAT, ELLA.
"PICK UP THE THINGS
YOUR SISTERS DROPPED, ELLA.
"THESE ARE THE PREROGATIVES
OF BEAUTY, ELLA.
"COME, BIRDENA.
"COME, SERAFINA.
"I AM THE MOTHER OF THE PRETTIEST GIRLS
IN THE VILLAGE.
"NOT YOU, ELLA!
"STAY BACK HERE, ELLA.
"DON'T STAND WITH US.
"THE PRINCE MAY
THINK WE KNOW YOU."
[FANFARE]
CROWD:
LONG LIVE THE PRINCE!
MAN:
LONG LIVE PRINCE CHARLES!
DID YOU SEE HIM
LOOK RIGHT THIS WAY?
HE DID, INDEED, LOOK THIS WAY.
HE LOOKED RIGHT AT ME.
AT YOU?
HE DISTINCTLY LOOKED
RIGHT AT ME.
NO, HE DIDN'T!
I SAW HIM.
OH, YOU DID NOT SEE HIM.
YOU WERE WAY BACK HERE.
I DID, TOO.
I SAW HIM.
NO, YOU DIDN'T.
I DID!
VERY WELL. WHAT DID
HE LOOK LIKE?
HE...
WELL, HE LOOKED--
HE LOOKED LIKE
A HANDSOME PRINCE
ON A BEAUTIFUL
WHITE HORSE.
YOU SEE?
THE HORSE WAS BLACK,
BLACK AS NIGHT.
SHE DIDN'T SEE HIM AT ALL.
I DID!
WHAT COLOR WAS HIS HAIR?
IT WAS BLACK,
BLACK AS NIGHT.
WELL, YOU SEE?
WHAT A FIB.
WHO--WHO CARES ABOUT
AN OLD PRINCE, ANYWAY?
I HATE HIM! I DON'T CARE.
I HATE HIM!
WHAT AN UNPLEASANT
GIRL YOU ARE.
I DON'T CARE!
NARRATOR:
THE LITTLE SPIRIT IS STILL DEFIANT
AND DEFENSIVE,
STILL UNBROKEN.
BUT GIVE THEM TIME.
THEY'LL BREAK IT.
A FEW MORE YEARS,
AND SHE WILL STOP FIGHTING BACK
AND WILL NO LONGER
FEEL ANY PAIN.
THE OTHERS WILL THEN
HAVE THE CONVENIENCE
OF AN UNPAID SPINSTER SLAVEY
IN THE HOUSE--
WILLING, DOCILE,
GRATEFUL FOR CRUMBS.
A FEW MORE YEARS,
AND ALL WILL BE PEACEFUL.
HERE WAS HER OWN PLACE,
A PLACE ALL BY ITSELF.
THE SWEET BROOK GLITTERED,
THE FOREST WAS COOL,
AND A MEADOWLARK WAS
CONFIDING ITS HEARTBREAK
TO THE QUIET AIR.
[ELLA CRYING]
WHY ARE YOU CRYING?
WHAT'S THE MATTER,
YOU SWEET, PRETTY CREATURE?
YOU'RE MAKING FUN OF ME.
I'M NOT SWEET AND PRETTY.
BUT IT'S ONLY ASHES.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH ASHES?
VERY GOOD FOR THE CHICKENS.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
ELLA.
BUT THEY WON'T EVEN
CALL ME BY MY NAME.
THEY CALL ME--
EDWARD AND WILLIE
AND ALL THE OTHERS--
BECAUSE OF THE ASHES,
THEY CALL ME CINDERELLA.
CINDERELLA?
CINDER ELLA,
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL WORD.
I LIKE IT VERY MUCH.
THERE ARE OTHER WORDS
I LIKE VERY MUCH,
LIKE WINDOWSILL...
AND ELBOW.
ELBOW.
AND I LIKE
APPLE DUMPLING, TOO.
IT'S A COMICAL WORD.
APPLE DUMPLING.
PICKLE RELISH.
THAT HAS A NICE SNAP TO IT.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOUR HAIR?
I CUT IT OFF.
I--I GOT ANGRY AT IT.
ONE DAY, I HATED MYSELF SO,
I WANTED TO BE DEAD.
BUT I CUT MY HAIR OFF INSTEAD.
AND I FELT MUCH BETTER AFTER.
IT'S GROWING NOW.
SPLENDID.
NO USE COMBING IT
OR ANYTHING.
IT DOES PRESENT
A PROBLEM.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
MRS. TOQUET.
OH, YOU'RE THE CRAZY LA--
I MEAN...YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO LIVES ALL BY YOURSELF?
THEY SAY YOU NEVER COME
INTO THE VILLAGE DURING DAYTIME.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WHY?
BECAUSE I ALWAYS
GO THERE AT NIGHT.
YOU--YOUR SHOES
ARE GETTING WET.
YES. IT'S THE WATER.
OH.
DO YOU LIVE
IN THE VILLAGE?
YES.
WITH BIRDENA, SERAFINA,
AND MY STEPMOTHER.
OH. HOW ARE THEY?
OH, YOU KNOW THEM?
NO. IF I KNEW THEM,
I WOULDN'T HAVE TO ASK.
OH.
WELL, THEY'RE
VERY WELL, THANK YOU.
THEY'RE VERY BUSY NOW.
THEY'RE GETTING READY
TO GO TO THE BALL--
DAY AFTER TOMORROW
AT THE PALACE.
THEY ARE GOING
TO MEET THE PRINCE.
YOU SEE, BIRDENA
AND SERAFINA
ARE THE MOST BEAUTIFUL GIRLS
IN THE WHOLE VILLAGE.
THEY CAN SEW VERY WELL,
AND THEY HAVE FINE MANNERS
AND BEAUTIFUL CLOTHES.
THEY ARE JUST EVERYTHING
THAT GIRLS SHOULD BE.
AND YOU? WHERE ARE
YOUR PRETTY CLOTHES?
OH, I DON'T CARE
WHAT I LOOK LIKE.
THAT'S NO REASON
FOR FRIGHTENING PEOPLE.
IT DOESN'T MATTER.
NOBODY LIKES ME ANYWAY.
I LIKE YOU.
YOU DON'T.
I DON'T NEED ANYBODY
TO LIKE ME.
I DON'T CARE.
I DON'T CARE ONE BIT,
BECAUSE, ONE DAY, I'M GOING
TO LIVE IN THE PALACE.
OH?
IN THE DUCAL PALACE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
A VERY PLEASANT PLAN.
WHO ARRANGED IT?
WELL...
ONE DAY, THERE'S AN OLD LADY
WHO CAME TO SEE MY MOTHER.
SHE WAS A TELLER
OF FORTUNES, THEY SAY.
AND SHE TOLD MY MOTHER
THAT SOME DAY
HER CHILD WOULD LIVE
IN THE PALACE.
AND I WAS BORN
THREE HOURS LATER.
MY MOTHER USED TO TELL ME
THIS STORY VERY OFTEN
WHEN I WAS A LITTLE GIRL.
SHE DIED WHEN I WAS
FIVE YEARS OLD.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT
TO DO IN THE PALACE?
OH. WELL, LOTS OF THINGS.
YOU KNOW.
SOUNDS VERY PRACTICAL.
AND I'LL PUNISH
EVERYBODY I HATE.
NO, YOU WON'T.
OH, YES, I WILL.
I WILL.
HERE.
WHERE'D YOU GET THIS?
OH, HERE AND THERE.
OH, YES, I HEARD
ABOUT THAT.
HERE, YOU'D BETTER
TAKE IT BACK.
OH, THANK YOU,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NEVERTHELESS.
NEVERTHELESS WHAT?
NEVERTHELESS
IS A NICE WORD.
ISN'T IT PLEASANT TO SIT AND
EXCHANGE WORDS WITH A FRIEND?
I NEVER DID IT BEFORE, I MEAN,
JUST SAT WITH A FRIEND AND TALKED.
WELL, WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOUR FRIENDS?
DON'T THEY HAVE
A SITTING PLACE?
WELL, IT'S BECAUSE I...
I DON'T THINK
I HAVE ANY FRIENDS.
I MEAN, I DON'T
THINK I DO.
BECAUSE WHEN
THEY'RE YOUR FRIENDS,
DOES THAT MEAN THAT
YOU CAN TELL THEM
EVERYTHING YOU LIKE
AND WHAT YOU DO
AND WHAT YOU FEEL
AND ALL THAT?
AND THAT THEY'LL ALWAYS
BE ON YOUR SIDE?
DOESN'T IT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
WELL, I DON'T HAVE
ANYBODY LIKE THAT.
YOU HAVE ME.
I'M ON YOUR SIDE.
AND I'M VERY DEEPLY INTERESTED
IN WHAT YOU FEEL AND THINK.
TELL ME.
TELL ME NOW.
WELL...I CAN'T.
IT--IT'S...IT'S ALL MIXED UP.
IT'S JUST A FEELING.
IT'S LIKE WHEN IT'S
BEGINNING TO GET DARK.
YOU KNOW?
AND--AND EVERYTHING
BREATHES VERY SOFTLY
AND THE SKY GETS
VERY, VERY BLUE
AND THEN VERY, VERY PINK.
AND HERE YOU FEEL,
OH, SOMETHING...
HMM. IT--IT'S...
IT'S HARD TO EXPLAIN.
IT'S QUITE CLEAR.
IS IT?
I MUST GO NOW.
I HAVE SOME THINGS
TO PICK UP.
WELL, YOU DROP IN
AGAIN SOMETIME.
OH, WHEN?
TOMORROW PERHAPS AT NOON.
RIGHT HERE, THEN, HUH?
WE'LL TALK AND TELL
EACH OTHER THINGS...
AND BE FRIENDS, HUH?
EXCELLENT.
VERY PRACTICAL.
GOOD-BYE.
WINDOWSILL.
PICKLE RELISH.
APPLE DUMPLING.
CINDERELLA.
GOOD-BYE, CINDERELLA.
THESE HOOPS ARE TOO WIDE.
I'M GOING TO WEAR
THE NARROW ONES.
THE WIDER HOOPS ARE PRETTIER.
BUT THEY'RE NOT THE FASHION.
COUSIN LOULOU'S WEARING
ENORMOUS ONES.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
I HEARD ALL ABOUT
COUSIN LOULOU'S GOWN
THIS AFTERNOON WHEN
I WENT UP TO THE HILL
FOR THE INVITATIONS.
OH! THE INVITATIONS.
WHERE DID YOU PUT THEM?
I GAVE THEM TO YOU.
OH. OH, DEAR.
OH, MAMA.
I PUT THEM DOWN.
AFTER ALL THE TROUBLE
WE HAD GETTING THEM.
OH, I HATE ASKING
COUSIN LOULOU FAVORS.
OH, GO AWAY, ELLA.
DON'T TOUCH THINGS, ELLA.
YOU'RE IN THE WAY, ELLA.
ELLA, GET OFF OF THAT.
YOU'RE GETTING IT
ALL DIRTY.
OH! HERE THEY ARE.
YOU MUST REMEMBER
TO THANK COUSIN LOULOU.
MOTHER, TOMORROW NIGHT
AT THE BALL,
PLEASE DON'T SPEAK
OF WHERE WE LIVE.
I'M GOING TO SAY THAT WE LIVE
ON THE HILL WITH COUSIN LOULOU.
AND WHAT WILL COUSIN
LOULOU SAY TO THAT?
COUSIN LOULOU WON'T HEAR IT.
BESIDES, NO ONE EVER
PAYS ANY ATTENTION
TO THAT OLD CREATURE ANYWAY.
[SCOLDING]
BIRDENA.
DON'T YOU DARE SPEAK
OF COUSIN LOULOU THAT WAY.
SHE'S VERY RICH.
WHAT'S HER DRESS LIKE?
OH, IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
IT'S ALL PINK AND WHITE
WITH ROSEBUDS AND RIBBONS
ALL OVER THE SKIRT.
AND THOUSANDS OF CRYSTALS,
EACH ONE SEWN WITH SILK THREAD.
ROSEBUDS. HA HA!
AT HER AGE.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
STEPMOTHER: YOU MAY TAKE IT
OFF NOW, BIRDENA.
NOW YOU, SERAFINA.
WHO IS MRS. TOQUET?
WHO?
MRS. TOQUET.
ISN'T SHE THE CRAZY OLD WOMAN
WHO LIVES IN THE WOODS?
SHE'S HARMLESS,
BUT SHE STEALS.
HAS SHE ALWAYS
BEEN LIKE THAT?
I MEAN, HAS SHE ALWAYS...
THEY SAY SHE WAS ONCE
A GRAND LADY AND LIVED ON THE HILL.
BUT SHE TOOK TO READING BOOKS
AND WENT FROM BAD TO WORSE.
STUFFED HER HEAD FULL OF IDEAS,
AND NOW SHE'S A BIT ADDLED.
A BIT ADDLED?
OH, MOTHER, SHE'S CRAZY
AS A COCKROACH.
NO, SHE ISN'T.
SHE'S JUST DIFFERENT.
SHE'S FULL OF GOOD IDEAS
AND...AND WISDOM.
FULL OF WHAT?
AND EVERYBODY KNOWS SHE STEALS.
SHE STOLE THE COVER
OFF A GARBAGE BUCKET
FROM MRS. BOWER'S HOUSE.
AND THE NEXT NIGHT,
SHE PUT IT BACK.
SHE ALWAYS PUTS THINGS BACK
AFTER SHE TAKES THEM.
THAT'S WHY NOBODY BOTHERS.
SHE SHOULD BE LOCKED AWAY.
SHE'S MAD.
SHE SEEMED VERY
SENSIBLE TO ME.
OH! SHE SEEMED
SENSIBLE TO ELLA.
AND WHY NOT?
THEY'RE TWO OF A KIND.
YOU'RE TWO OF A KIND.
AND DID YOU TELL HER THAT
YOU WERE GOING TO LIVE
- IN THE PALACE SOMEDAY?
- AND WHAT IF I DID?
HA HA! TWO CRAZY COCKROACHES.
[EVERYONE LAUGHS]
ELLA, STOP IT!
YOU'RE RUINING
MY BEAUTIFUL DRESS!
GET HER OUT OF HERE!
[SLAP]    YOU GO RIGHT OUT AND
FINISH DIGGING THE POTATOES.
Ella: I don't care.
i don't care one bit,
because, one day,
I'm going to live in the palace.
Ms. Toquet: What will you do in the palace?
I don't know....
but, one day, I'm going
to live in the palace.
One day, I'm going
[GRAND MUSIC BEGINS]
[GRAND MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MUSIC BECOMES LIGHTER]
[MUSIC BECOMES LIGHT-HEARTED]
STEPMOTHER:   ELLA!
ELLA! WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
ELLA, BRING IN THE POTATOES!
CHARLES?
OH.
CHARLES.
WHERE IS HE?
MORNING, KOVIN.
WELL, GOOD MORNING,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
IS HE UP YET?
I BELIEVE HE'S STILL
DRESSING, SIR.
CHARLES?
CHARLES, I WANT
TO SEE YOU.
AND WHERE THEY'VE
QUARTERED YOU, KOVIN?
UH, YES, SIR.
IT'S COMFORTABLE?
MOST COMFORTABLE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
GOOD. GOOD, GOOD.
POETRY?
USED TO READ IT MYSELF.
TAUGHT ME A LOT.
CAN'T READ IT NOWADAYS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF OUR COUNTRYSIDE?
OH, VERY BEAUTIFUL,
WHAT I'VE SEEN OF IT, SIR.
EXCELLENT--
EXCELLENT HUNTING.
DO YOU HUNT?
SOME THINGS.
YOU'LL FIND PLENTY
OF THAT, TOO.
GOOD MORNING, FATHER.
WHAT ARE YOU GOT UP AS?
I'M GOING FOR A WALK.
THERE'S A PROBLEM
OF ENTERTAINMENT AT THE BALL.
WHAT BALL?
I TOLD YOU--
THREE DAYS OF FESTIVAL
TOPPED OFF BY A BIG BALL
ON THE LAST NIGHT.
THAT'S TOMORROW NIGHT.
OH, NO.
NOW STOP MAKING NOISES
LIKE A SCHOOLBOY.
YOU HAVE OBLIGATIONS.
THAT'S THE PRICE YOU PAY
FOR WHAT YOU ARE.
AND I DON'T MEAN YOUR TITLE.
I MEAN THE FACT THAT
YOU'RE A GROWN MAN
OF SOME DECENCY
AND INTELLIGENCE.
IT'S TIME HE TOOK
SOME RESPONSIBILITY,
BECAUSE I'M BORED,
UTTERLY BORED WITH IT.
HE'S OF AGE NOW.
IT'S HIS TURN.
I LOVE HIM, KOVIN.
ISN'T HE A CHARMER?
I NEVER KNEW
ANYBODY LIKE HIM.
NOW, THEN,
YOU CONDESCENDING,
DISRESPECTFUL, BLASE,
IMPERTINENT YOUNG RAKE.
WE ARE DEPENDENT
UPON THE GOOD WILL
AND THE COOPERATION
OF THE PEOPLE
OF THIS PRINCIPALITY.
BUT THEY DON'T KNOW HIM,
AND HE DOESN'T KNOW THEM.
WELL, YOU'RE GOING
TO MEET THEM
TOMORROW NIGHT
AT THE BALL,
AND THEY'RE GOING
TO TAKE A LOOK AT YOU.
MAKE FRIENDS.
I'LL DO MY BEST, FATHER,
AND NOT ONLY BECAUSE
YOU'RE SO RIGHT.
I REMEMBER THIS PLACE, TOO.
WHEN I WAS EIGHT,
I RAN AWAY FROM HOME ONE DAY.
I WAS GONE FOR SEVEN HOURS,
THE BEST SEVEN HOURS I EVER HAD.
I DISCOVERED
THE COUNTRYSIDE THAT DAY--
ONE PLACE IN PARTICULAR.
I'LL TAKE YOU THERE.
STRANGE HOW MANY MEMORIES
ARE CROWDING BACK ON ME,
THINGS I HAVEN'T
THOUGHT ABOUT FOR YEARS.
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON,
WHEN WE WERE RIDING THROUGH THE TOWN,
I KEPT REMEMBERING SOMETHING
THAT HAPPENED YEARS AGO.
I'D BEEN HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS
AND WAS LEAVING
TO RETURN TO SCHOOL.
MY CARRIAGE WAS HELD UP
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE TOWN
BECAUSE SOMETHING WAS GOING
ON IN THE STREET AHEAD,
BLOCKING OUR PATH.
IT INVOLVED A CHILD...
A LITTLE GIRL OF ABOUT FIVE.
SHE WAS CRYING IN A SORT
OF TRAGIC FRENZY.
SHE'D RUN OUT OF HER HOUSE
IN THE PATH OF THE CARRIAGE,
AND SOME TOWNSPEOPLE WERE
TRYING TO HOLD HER BACK.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT IT WAS ALL ABOUT.
BUT ONE THING I'VE
REMEMBERED EVER SINCE
IN THE MOST MINUTE DETAIL...
SHE HAD GREAT, AGONIZED,
REBELLIOUS EYES...
FRINGED WITH DARK LASHES,
AND HER CHEEKS WERE WET WITH TEARS.
IT WAS THE MOST TRAGIC
FACE I EVER SAW.
NOT JUST SAD.
IT HAD THE AGONY
OF A GREEK TRAGEDY,
BEYOND HOPE OF COMFORTING.
I'VE NEVER KNOWN SORROW,
NOT REALLY.
BUT EVER SINCE THAT DAY,
I'VE FELT...
I'VE HAD SOME KNOWLEDGE
OF WHAT IT'S LIKE,
OF ALL THE HUMAN SOUL CAN
STAND OF
PAIN AND MISERY.
AND EVER SINCE THAT DAY,
I FIND IT ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE
TO RESIST A WEEPING WOMAN.
AND IF SHE HAPPENS
TO HAVE EYES LIKE THAT,
I'M LOST.
THIS IS THE PLACE
I WAS TELLING YOU ABOUT.
NOTHING HAS CHANGED.
THAT DAY I RAN AWAY
FROM HOME,
I STRIPPED TO THE BUFF
AND BATHED IN THIS POOL.
HOW COLD IS THE WATER?
VERY COLD.
IT'S FED BY MOUNTAIN STREAMS.
MM. I AM NO LONGER
EIGHT YEARS OLD.
YOU MAY FREEZE ALONE.
[RELAXED GRUNT]
HELLO.
WHAT IS IT?
A NIGHTMARE.
THIS IS MY PLACE.
THAT'S STRANGE.
IT USED TO BE PART
OF THE DUKE'S ESTATE.
NOBODY EVER COMES HERE.
WELL, THEY'RE FOOLS
IF THEY DON'T.
YOU DON'T BELONG HERE.
WHERE DO YOU LIVE?
OVER THERE.
THERE IS NOTHING OVER THERE
BUT THE PALACE.
I COULD'VE TOLD YOU THAT.
WHAT OF IT?
YOU CAN'T LIVE
IN THE DUKE'S PALACE.
WHY NOT?
WE WORK THERE.
OH?
YES. I'M THE NEW
RIDING MASTER,
AND HE'S THE SON
OF THE COOK.
SON OF THE COOK?
THE SON OF THE COOK
AT THE PALACE OF THE DUKE.
HAVE YOU SEEN
PRINCE CHARLES?
OF COURSE WE HAVE,
OFTEN.
WHAT COLOR IS HE?
MMM...I'D SAY WHITE,
WOULDN'T YOU?
MM-MM.
I MEAN HIS HAIR.
OH. OH, BLACK.
BLACK.
BLACK AS NIGHT.
YOU SEE?
NO.
NO, I DON'T QUITE SEE.
I TOLD THEM IT WAS BLACK.
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
MM, I JUST KNEW.
YOU'RE CLAIRVOYANT.
NO, I'M NOT.
IT'S JUST ASHES,
AND I DON'T CARE.
YOU CAN CALL ME CINDERELLA,
KOVIN.
KOVIN, THE EYES...
THE SAD, REBELLIOUS EYES.
STOP MAKING FUN OF ME!
OH!
[BOTH LAUGHING]
NARRATOR: THE PRINCE WAS CURIOUS,
SO HE SENT HIS VALET
AND HIS GOOD FRIEND KOVIN
INTO THE VILLAGE TO LEARN
WHAT THEY COULD LEARN
ABOUT THE RAGAMUFFIN
HE HAD MET THAT MORNING.
HE LEARNED THAT
SHE WAS AN UNRULY GIRL,
ILL-MANNERED AND IMPUDENT,
FRIENDLESS,AND EVEN
AN OBJECT OF RIDICULE,
FOR SHE WAS
IN THE HABIT OF BOASTING
THAT SHE WOULD LIVE
IN THE PALACE SOME DAY.
HE LEARNED THAT
SHE WAS A GREAT TRIAL
TO HER STEPMOTHER
THE GOOD, KIND WIDOW SONDER.
ON THAT VERY AFTERNOON,
THE WIDOW AND HER DAUGHTERS
WERE ENTERTAINING
COUSIN LOULOU
WHO LIVED
ON THE FASHIONABLE HILL.
THE BEST ATTIRE
AND THE MOST ELEGANT MANNERS
HAD COME OUT OF STORAGE
AND WERE ON DISPLAY.
EVEN ELLA HAD BEEN ORDERED
TO PUT ON HER OTHER DRESS.
COUSIN LOULOU HAD STARTED LIFE
AS A VERY PRETTY HOUSEMAID
IN THE PALACE OF THE DUKE.
AND BY A NATURAL
SEQUENCE OF EVENTS,
PLUS A SMALL TRACE
OF THREATENED BLACKMAIL,
SHE HAD ACQUIRED JEWELS,
A HOUSE ON THE FASHIONABLE HILL,
AND A MEASURE
OF FINANCIAL SECURITY.
AS YOU CAN SEE,
ELLA WAS NOT PRECISELY
A SERVANT IN THE HOUSE,
BUT SHE WAS ALSO
NOT PRECISELY
A MEMBER OF THE FAMILY.
COUSIN LOULOU WAS RECEIVING
THE BEST THEY HAD TO GIVE
IN THE WAY OF ADULATION, AGREEMENT,
FLATTERY, AND BLANDISHMENT.
SHE WAS BEING OILED AND CODDLED,
SOAPED AND SALVED.
"YES, COUSIN LOULOU.
"YOU'RE SO RIGHT,
COUSIN LOULOU.
"WHAT A BEAUTIFUL GOWN,
"HOW WE WISH WE, TOO,
HAD AN OPPORTUNITY
"TO BE SO PROFITABLY RUINED
WHILE WE ARE STILL YOUNG.
"HOW WE WISH YOU WOULD DROP DEAD
"AND LEAVE US YOUR MONEY.
SOMETHING'S WRONG.
SOMETHING IS NOT QUITE RIGHT.
DOESN'T THE GIRL
EVER WEAR SHOES?
MUST SHE ALWAYS GO BAREFOOT
LIKE A PEASANT?
ELLA!
WHERE ARE YOUR SHOES?
I--I CAN GET THEM.
I FORGOT THEM.
I LEFT THEM IN THE DELL.
I'LL GET THEM MAYBE, HUH?
ARE THESE WHAT
YOU'RE LOOKING FOR?
ALLOW ME.
SIT DOWN.
UH, I'M SORRY I PUSHED YOU
INTO THE WATER.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO HURT
YOUR FEELINGS EITHER.
MAY I SIT DOWN
AND TALK TO YOU?
I HEAR YOU'RE GOING
TO LIVE IN THE PALACE SOMEDAY.
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU'VE BEEN TELLING EVERYBODY
ABOUT IT FOR YEARS.
I KNOW.
I SAY IT MOSTLY
WHEN THEY LAUGH AT ME.
OH, ISN'T IT TRUE?
OH, YES, IT'S QUITE TRUE.
AND IT'S WONDERFUL
TO THINK ABOUT.
YES, I KNOW WHAT YOU MEAN.
IT'S NICE TO HAVE
SOMETHING TO HOPE FOR.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S JUST IT.
LIFE CAN BE PRETTY UNBEARABLE
IF YOU DON'T HAVE ANYTHING TO HOPE FOR.
DO YOU HAVE SOMETHING
TO HOPE FOR?
I THINK I'M BEGINNING TO HAVE.
YOU HOPE TO BE
A VERY GOOD COOK?
A WHAT?
LIKE YOUR FATHER.
OH, YES. YES.
YOU KNOW, IT'S FUNNY.
I USED TO THINK
IT WOULD BE WONDERFUL
TO HAVE SOMEONE
TO SIT WITH
AND TALK TO AND--
AND TELL THEM
WHAT I THINK
AND WHAT I FEEL...
WHAT I LIKE AND ALL THAT.
BUT WITH YOU, I--
I DON'T HAVE TO.
I HAVE THE FEELING
THAT IF YOU WANTED TO,
YOU COULD TELL ME
WHAT I THINK
AND WHAT I FEEL
AND ALL THAT.
AND YOU KNOW ALL
THE WORST OF ME, TOO,
EH?
TELL ME WHAT YOU THINK
ABOUT SO THAT
WHEN I DON'T HAVE
ANY THOUGHTS OF MY OWN,
I--I CAN THINK OF YOURS.
[CHIRPING]
LOOK WHAT I CAN DO!
THAT'S VERY INTERESTING.
HA HA HA.
OHH! OOH!
OOH.
OH, I FORGOT.
I BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
OH?
IT'S AN INVITATION TO THE BALL
TOMORROW NIGHT.
AN INVITATION
TO THE BALL?
OH, WELL, I CAN'T
GO TO THE BALL.
WELL, WHY NOT?
WHAT WOULD I BE DOING
AT THE BALL?
WHERE DID YOU GET IT?
I JUST--OH. OH,
FROM PRINCE CHARLES.
I COOKED A DELICIOUS
POT ROAST FOR HIM,
AND HE REWARDED ME
WITH THIS.
OH.
IT--IT'LL BE NICE TO KEEP IT,
JUST TO LOOK AT IT.
OH, I'D LIKE TO SEE YOU
AT THE BALL.
BUT YOU'D BE TOO BUSY
TO TALK TO ME
WITH ALL THOSE PEOPLE
TO COOK FOR.
OH, YES. I FORGOT THAT.
WELL, THE BALL
WOULD BE A BORE ANYWAY.
YOU WOULDN'T LIKE IT.
BESIDES I CAN'T DANCE.
OH, EVERY GIRL SHOULD
KNOW HOW TO DANCE.
PARTICULARLY A GIRL
WHO'S GOING TO LIVE
IN THE PALACE SOMEDAY.
LET ME SEE. THERE'S A MINUET
AND A POLONAISE.
I'LL SHOW YOU.
COME HERE.
UH, MINUET.
RIGHT FOOT FORWARD.
TOUCH, TOUCH, STEP...
BACK, RIGHT, AND LEFT.
PUT THE LEFT FOOT FORWARD.
TOUCH, TOUCH, STEP BACK,
LEFT AND--
HERE.
MOVE BACK.
THERE.
[HUMMING]
TOUCH, TOUCH,
RIGHT, LEFT, RIGHT.
[HUMMING]
LEFT.
TOUCH, TOUCH,
[HUMMING]
LEFT, RIGHT, LEFT.
RIGHT HAND...
[HUMMING]
FRONT, BACK,
BOTH: 1, 2, 3.
AND OTHER HAND.
OH.
[HUMMING]
1, 2,
5, 6, AND 7, 8.
GOOD!
NOW, UH,
NOW THE POLONAISE.
HOP, STEP, STEP, HOP, STEP, STEP,
HOP, STEP, STEP, CHANGE!
[HUMMING]
HOP, STEP, STEP, HOP, STEP, STEP,
HOP, STEP, STEP, TURN!
[HUMMING]
HOP, STEP, STEP, HOP, STEP, STEP,
HOP, STEP, STEP,
TWO.
[HUMMING]
AAH!
WHOA!
HA HA HA!
[HUMMING]
[PLAYING TUNE
HE HAD BEEN HUMMING]
CLIMBING ROSE
ON THE WALL
PLUCK IT NOW
BEFORE THE PETALS FALL
APPLE RIPE
ON THE BOUGH
TAKE IT, FOR THE TIME
TO TAKE IS NOW
HAPPY DAY
SUN OR RAIN
LIVE IT FOR IT
NEVER COMES AGAIN
LADS HAVE DIED,
YOUNG AND GAY
PRETTY MAIDS
CAN FADE AWAY
NOTHING IS FOREVER
ALWAYS IS A LIE
I CAN ONLY LOVE YOU
TILL THE DAY I DIE
SO, MY LOVE
OH, MY LOVE
DREAM NO MORE, MY LOVE,
AWAKE, MY LOVE
OH, MY LOVE,
TURN TO ME
AND TAKE MY LOVE
YOU'RE NOT WELL, CHARLES.
YOU'RE NOT YOURSELF.
YOU KNOW WHAT AILS YOU.
CAREFUL, CHARLES.
REMEMBER YOUR
SPECIAL WEAKNESS.
SHE'S FRIGHTENED,
SAD, AND HURT.
AFRAID TO HOPE,
EXPECTING RIDICULE.
A TENDER HEART
HALF AFRAID TO LOVE.
OH, CAREFUL, CHARLES.
WHY BE CAREFUL?!
EVERY MAN HAS HIS OWN
SPECIAL VULNERABILITY.
I ONCE KNEW A MAN
WHO COULDN'T RESIST
FAT WOMEN,
WOMEN WITH ROLLS.
ANOTHER WHO FELL
MADLY IN LOVE
EVERY TIME A WOMAN
SLAPPED HIS FACE.
WELL, THIS IS MINE.
WHY GO AGAINST NATURE?
[PLAYING]
[THINKING]
THE SON OF THE COOK
OF THE PALACE OF THE DUKE.
[TRUMPETS PLAY FANFARE]
[SNAPS FINGERS]
[LAUGHING]
[HUMMING]
WHY, MRS. TOQUET!
WHY NOT MRS. TOQUET?
WELL, I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU.
[SOFTENS VOICE]
WE MUST BE VERY QUIET.
THEY'RE SLEEPING LATE
THIS MORNING.
THEY WANT TO LOOK THEIR BEST
AT THE BALL TONIGHT.
THAT'S ONLY
A BROKEN SAUCER.
YES, POOR THING.
LOOK. I'VE GOT SOMETHING
TO SHOW YOU.
LOOK.
IT'S AN INVITATION
TO GO TO THE BALL.
THE SON OF THE COOK
GAVE IT TO ME.
THE SON OF THE PALACE COOK.
I MET HIM IN THE DELL,
AND HE TAUGHT ME HOW TO DANCE.
HE'S VERY BUSY NOW,
YOU KNOW,
MAKING PINK PASTRY
AND EVERYTHING
WITH HIS FATHER
FOR THE BALL.
OH, MRS. TOQUET,
IF YOU COULD ONLY SEE HIM
AND--AND HEAR HIM.
HE'S SO BEAUTIFUL.
I'VE GOT SOMETHING
TO HOPE FOR NOW.
WHAT WOULD THAT BE?
TO BE ABLE
TO SEE HIM AGAIN.
AHH, YES!
WELL, WHEN YOU SEE HIM,
YOU GIVE HIM MY RECIPE
FOR TURNIP FRITTERS.
TELL HIM TO TRY IT
WITHOUT THE TURNIPS.
IT'S BETTER THAT WAY.
SO YOU'RE GOING
TO THE BALL?
ME? OH, NO.
YOU COULD GO
TO THE BALL.
GET PAST THE GATEKEEPER
WITH THAT,
THEN SLIP AWAY
TO THE KITCHEN
AND SEE THE SON OF THE COOK.
THAT'S STRATEGY.
BUT HE'D BE TOO BUSY
TO TALK TO ME.
THEN YOU DO THE TALKING.
HE'LL LISTEN.
I--I REALLY
DON'T WANT TO GO.
YOU COULD BORROW A DRESS
FROM ONE OF THE SLEEPING BEAUTIES.
I MUST BE GOING.
IT'S VERY BUSY OUT.
I HAVE A FEW THINGS
TO PICK UP.
GOOD-BYE, CINDERELLA.
MRS. TOQUET:   DON'T BE
AFRAID TO LOVE HIM.
NARRATOR: AT TWO O'CLOCK
THE STEPSISTERS AWOKE,
AND PREPARATIONS
FOR THE GREAT BALL BEGAN.
RUB, RUB, RUB, AND RUB,
20 MINUTES OF RUB AND RUB
WITH OIL OF ROSES,
BUTTER AND CREAM.
TWO TENDER PORTIONS
OF DEAD WHITE MEAT
WERE BEING CAREFULLY
PREPARED FOR THE DELECTATION
OF HIGH SOCIETY
AND THE VERY ELIGIBLE
YOUNG PRINCE CHARLES.
AND SO THEY WERE
OFF TO THE BALL
TO DANCE, TO HEAR MUSIC,
TO BE ADMIRED,
TO BE BEAUTIFUL GIRLS
LIKE OTHER BEAUTIFUL GIRLS
WHO DANCE, HEAR MUSIC
AND ARE ADMIRED.
[SNIFFLES]
[SNAP]
[DOOR OPENS]
WHO'S THERE?
IT'S ONLY ME.
OH, MRS. TOQUET!
WELL, I'M SO GLAD
TO SEE YOU.
I WAS ALL ALONE AND--
COME IN. SIT DOWN.
NO TIME FOR THAT.
YOU'LL BE LATE FOR THE BALL.
OH, BUT I'M NOT
GOING TO THE BALL.
THEY'VE GONE TO THE BALL.
I, THEY, YOU,
AMO, AMAS, AMAT,
AMAMUS, AMATUS, AMANT.
IT'S ALWAYS THAT WAY.
EVERYBODY'S BEEN THROUGH IT.
YOU DON'T WANT TO GO,
YET WHEN EVERYBODY ELSE GOES
AND LEAVES YOU HOME ALONE,
YOU CAN HARDLY BEAR IT.
OH, BUT I DON'T MIND
BEING ALONE.
I LIKE IT.
YOU LIKE IT, BUT NOT WHEN
EVERYBODY ELSE IS AT THE BALL.
WELL, THAT'S TRUE.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I USUALLY AM,
99 TIMES OUT OF 10.
[SNAP]
OH, IT'S ANOTHER MOUSE.
WE HAVE A GOOD MANY,
YOU KNOW,
BECAUSE I FEED THEM.
THEN I LET THEM GO.
AH. LET'S LOOK
IN THE BACK GARDEN.
FOR WHAT?
I LEFT IT THERE.
A CORSET
IS A FINE THING.
INVENTED BY THE DEVIL,
BUT A FINE THING.
NOW FOR SOME SLIPPERS.
NOW, I JUST HAPPEN
TO HAVE A PAIR THAT I THINK--
PUT IT ON.
OH! ISN'T THAT BEAUTIFUL?
IT'S GLASS!
IT'S VENETIAN GLASS.
MADE BY A GENIUS
IN VENICE,
WHO SOLD THEM
FOR A GOOD PRICE
TO A BAZAAR KEEPER
WHO SOLD THEM
AT A GREAT PROFIT
TO A MERCHANT FROM ROME
WHO SOLD THEM
AT A GREAT PROFIT
TO A SHOPKEEPER IN PARIS,
WHO SOLD THEM
AT A GREAT PROFIT.
EVERYBODY MADE MONEY.
EVERYBODY WAS HAPPY!
THAT'S ECONOMICS.
BUT IT DOES FEEL
STRANGE, YOU KNOW?
DON'T THINK ABOUT IT.
KEEP WALKING.
PRACTICE HELPS.
VINCIT QUI PATITUR.
HE CONQUERS WHO ENDURES.
ALL WOMEN MUST ENDURE
THESE DISCOMFORTS.
WHY?
FOR FASHION.
IT FASCINATES MEN.
MAKES THEM MARVEL
AT WOMEN.
FILLS THEM WITH AWE.
BECAUSE THEY KNOW
THEY COULDN'T STAND IT.
HOW ARE THEY NOW?
THEY'RE MUCH BETTER.
I'M GETTING USED TO THEM.
HEAD UP,
BACK STRAIGHT.
THIS LOOKS FAMILIAR.
PINK AND WHITE...
ROSEBUDS AND CRYSTALS...
OH, DEAR MRS. TOQUET,
WHERE DID YOU GET IT?
I FOUND IT.
NOW, A HEADDRESS.
A LITTLE CROWN
OF SOME SORT.
A DIADEM!
BUT IF THEY SEE ME
WEARING IT--
OH, BUT...THEY WON'T.
YOU'LL BE IN THE KITCHEN.
YES. YES, I'LL GO
STRAIGHT TO THE KITCHEN.
NOW, THE HAIR AND THE ROUGE
AND THE PERFUME.
OH. THIS PRESENTS
SOMETHING OF A PROBLEM.
HEAD UP, BACK STRAIGHT,
AND VERY, VERY, VERY SLOWLY.
[LAUGHING]
HERE'S YOUR COACH.
OHH, MY COACH.
I MADE A LITTLE ARRANGEMENT
WITH THE COACHMEN.
OH, MRS. TOQUET,
NOBODY IN MY WHOLE LIFE
HAS EV--THANK YOU.
YOU'VE ALREADY SAID THAT
A DOZEN TIMES.
I LOVE YOU.
THAT'S VERY GOOD.
WHEN YOU LEARN
TO LOVE ONE PERSON,
IT'S THAT MUCH EASIER
TO LOVE OTHERS.
NOW, IN YOU GO.
DOES SHE KNOW ABOUT
LEAVING AT MIDNIGHT?
AHH, YES.
YOU SEE, HE MUST TAKE YOU
HOME AT MIDNIGHT
SO THAT HE CAN GO BACK
TO THE PALACE IN TIME
TO PICK UP HIS PEOPLE.
THEY'RE LEAVING AT ONE O'CLOCK.
SO IF YOU LEAVE
PROMPTLY AT MIDNIGHT,
NOBODY WILL BE THE WISER
AND NOBODY WILL BE ANNOYED
AND EVERYBODY
WILL BE HAPPY.
THAT'S DIPLOMACY.
I'LL REMEMBER, MIDNIGHT.
THANK YOU.
MIDNIGHT.
[APPLAUSE]
[ALL TALKING]
MAY I HAVE THE HONOR
OF BEING YOUR PARTNER TONIGHT?
I'VE BEEN WATCHING YOU
ALL EVENING.
AND I FIND YOU THE MOST
CHARMING YOUNG LADY HERE.
WOULD YOU CARE TO HAVE
SOME REFRESHMENTS?
WHAT PART OF THE COUNTRY
ARE YOU FROM?
I DON'T BELIEVE SEEN YOU BEFORE.
OH, CHARLES WENT
RIGHT UP OVER THIS HILL
AND AS FAR OUT ON THE ROAD
AS YOU CAN SEE.
AND THEN THE MOST
AMAZING THING--
UH, PLEASE FORGIVE ME.
I WILL BE BACK.
I BEG YOUR PARDON.
SORRY, PARDON ME.
PARDON. PARDON.
OHH! GOOD EVENING,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
GOOD EVENING.
I'M YOUR FATHER'S OLD FRIEND
LOULOU ALTSTERSTRAU.
OH, YES, LOULOU. YES!
SO GOOD OF YOU
TO REMEMBER.
IT WAS YEARS AGO.
I WAS EIGHT YEARS OLD.
HE SENT ME
AWAY TO SCHOOL.
IS IT AS LONG AGO AS THAT?
WELL, WE'RE ALL
GOOD FRIENDS NOW.
THE PALACE
HASN'T CHANGED.
NOR HAVE YOU,
MADAM ALTSTERSTRAU.
AS BEAUTIFUL AS EVER.
OHH, THANK YOU.
[SNAPPING FINGERS]
OH, I SHOULD LIKE
TO PRESENT MY COUSIN MRS. SONDER.
AND HER TWO DAUGHTERS
BIRDENA AND SERAFINA.
CHARLES.
OH, I BEG YOUR PARDON.
IT'S A GREAT PRIVILEGE,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO
HEARING ABOUT YOUR TRAVELS.
OH, YES. WE'RE VERY
FOND OF PARIS.
OH, YOU KNOW PARIS?
OH, WE DON'T
PRECISELY KNOW PARIS,
BUT WE'RE VERY
DEVOTED TO IT,
AREN'T WE COUSIN LOULOU?
IT'S SO FRENCH.
YES. WE MUST DISCUSS IT
AT LENGTH SOMETIME.
DON'T GO AWAY, PLEASE.
[ALL TALKING]
MY CHANCE
WHEN YOU GET BACK.
DON'T BE LONG.
THERE, DANCING
WITH YOUR FATHER.
WE HAVEN'T MET BEFORE,
MY DEAR?
YOU, UH, YOU DON'T LIVE
IN THIS REGION?
I THINK YOU AND I
SHOULD MEET.
I'M YOUR HOST.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
WHERE IS THE KITCHEN?
THE KITCHEN, M'LADY?
WELL, DO YOU SEE
THAT ONE?
OH. WHO IS SHE?
I DON'T KNOW.
COULDN'T GET HER
TO SAY A WORD.
OH. EXCUSE ME.
I'VE A FEELING
WE'VE MET BEFORE.
THAT WE'VE DANCED
TOGETHER BEFORE, TOO.
CINDERELLA.
GOOD EVENING, CINDERELLA.
YES. THERE'S DEFINITELY
A BIT OF EXPLANATION.
I'M AFRAID I TOOK
THE EASY WAY,
WHICH IS UNHAPPILY
THE PATH OF DECEPTION.
I'M JUST VERY GLAD
THAT YOU COULD COME.
I WAS WORRIED YOU
WOULDN'T BE HERE.
NOW THAT YOU ARE HERE,
LET ME EXPLAIN.
[CHATTERING]
CHARMING.
WHO IS THAT
WALKING WITH THE PRINCE?
SHE'S SOMEONE
I KNEW IN PARIS.
OH, I DIDN'T SEE.
DID YOU SEE HER,
COUSIN LOULOU?
NO, BUT THAT DRESS--
THERE'S SOMETHING
ABOUT THAT DRESS.
DIDN'T SEE HER.
I DANCED WITH HER
AND COULDN'T GET HER TO SAY A WORD.
SHE DOESN'T SPEAK
THE LANGUAGE, THEY SAY.
A FOREIGNER.
THEY SAY HE CARRIED ON
WITH AN EGYPTIAN PRINCESS IN PARIS.
EGYPTIAN.
DIDN'T YOU SEE THE HAIR?
EGYPTIAN, OF COURSE.
I'M GOING TO TAKE
A LOOK AT THAT DRESS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
WHAT ARE YOU AFRAID OF?
COUSIN LOULOU,
BIRDENA, AND SERAFINA.
BUT YOU DON'T MAKE SENSE.
OH, YES, I AM. THEY--
THEY MUSTN'T SEE ME.
THIS DRESS, I--I HAVE DONE
A DREADFUL THING. YOU KNOW, I...
[DANCERS APPLAUDING]
OOH! OOH!
SPEAK OF THE DEVIL,
THERE SHE GOES NOW.
WHO IS SHE?
I'LL WAGER YOU'LL KNOW.
ME? OH.
EVERYBODY GUESSING
AND NOBODY KNOWS.
DID YOU DANCE WITH HER?
YES, YOUR HIGHNESS,
BUT SHE WOULDN'T SPEAK.
AH!
NEVER OPENED HER MOUTH.
HA HA!
CLEVER GIRL.
KNOWS WHEN TO HOLD HER TONGUE.
HA HA HA!
WE'VE BEEN TOLD
SHE DOESN'T SPEAK THE LANGUAGE.
THE RUMOR IS
SHE'S EGYPTIAN.
AHH, WELL?
I SEE YOU--AH!
THERE YOU ARE.
PLEASE TELL ME WHO THAT GIRL--
[BELL CHIMING]
[BONG]
[CHIMING CONTINUES]
[BELL CHIMES MIDNIGHT]
NO, YOU DIDN'T DREAM IT.
THE COACHMEN AND I
BROUGHT YOU HOME.
AND THE DRESS,
IS IT ALL RIGHT?
DID I TEAR IT
OR ANYTHING?
IT'S AS GOOD AS NEW
AND BACK WHERE IT CAME FROM.
YOU KNOW, I--I HAVE
A SECRET TO TELL YOU.
YOU REMEMBER THE SON
OF THE COOK, EH?
MM-HMM.
HE'S NOT
THE SON OF THE COOK.
HE'S THE SON
OF THE DOOK!
I MEAN, THE DUKE.
HE'S--HE'S
PRINCE CHARLES.
CAN HE COOK?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T THINK SO.
TOO BAD.
MEN MAKE THE BEST COOKS.
BETTER THAN WOMEN,
THEY SAY.
DON'T WORRY,
PERHAPS HE CAN DO OTHER THINGS.
NOW, GO TO SLEEP.
TOMORROW WILL BE INTERESTING.
GOOD NIGHT, CINDERELLA.
[DOOR CLOSES]
WELL, THAT'S OVER.
COST ME A PRETTY PENNY.
OH, AND THAT EGYPTIAN ONE,
WHO WAS SHE?
THEY'RE SAYING THAT YOU
MET HER IN PARIS.
A VERY NOBLE LADY,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
SHE IS THE DAUGHTER OF A FEZ--
UH, OF A MOSQUE--
OF A SCARAB--UH--
A PASHA.
THANK YOU,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
SHE IS THE DAUGHTER
OF THE PASHA OF GIZA ON THE NILE.
AH! OLD GIZER.
OH, I KNOW HIM WE--
I DIDN'T KNOW
HE HAD A DAUGHTER.
HE HAS THREE,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
BUT THIS ONE IS
THE PRINCESS TEHARA.
TEHARA, VERY BEAUTIFUL.
OH, A LADY OF GREAT VIRTUE.
SPLENDID BLOODLINE!
SHE IS ONE
OF EIGHT CHILDREN.
HER MOTHER WAS
ONE OF 14 CHILDREN.
ALL MALES.
VERY PROLIFIC FAMILY.
EXCELLENT, EXCELLENT.
GOOD STOCK.
GOOD TEETH, TOO,
I NOTICED.
FINE HOCKS
AND SPLENDID WITHERS.
HERSCHEL, BRING ME
MY DRESSING GOWN, IF YOU PLEASE.
OH! I'LL NEVER FORGET
MY FIRST BALL.
I DIDN'T KNOW HOW
TO BEHAVE.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
HOW TO DANCE.
IT'S TRUE. MY FATHER
WAS SOMETHING OF A RECLUSE.
HE TAUGHT ME NOTHING.
I MADE A NUMBER
OF EMBARRASSING MISTAKES.
UH, NOTHING SERIOUS, I TRUST.
FORTUNATELY I MARRIED THE DAUGHTER
OF THE DUKE OF BOMBURG.
MMM. THE ONLY SENSIBLE THING
I EVER DID.
FINE WOMAN. OLD FAMILY.
BOMBURG TITLE GOES BACK
TO CHARLEMAGNE.
PERFECT BLOODLINES.
YES.
FATHER, WHAT IF I WERE
TO MARRY A COMMONER?
PRINCES DO NOT
MARRY COMMONERS.
THAT IS
A WELL-ESTABLISHED FACT.
WITH NOTHING TO SUPPORT IT
EXCEPT THE WILLINGNESS
OF PEOPLE TO BELIEVE IT,
LIKE SOME OTHER
WELL-ESTABLISHED FACTS.
FOR THE SAKE OF DISCUSSION,
WHAT IF I WERE TO FALL IN LOVE
WITH A COMMONER?
DISCUSSION, MY FOOT!
EGYPTIAN PRINCESS.
YOU KNOW VERY WELL
SHE'S A COMMONER!
AND THEY LOVE HER
ALL THE MORE FOR IT.
[LAUGHTER]
ISN'T HE A CHARMER?
LIKE HIS MOTHER,
THE CHARMER.
EVERYBODY'S CHARMING.
LET'S DRINK TO THAT.
PRINCESS TEHARA!
[GLASSES CLINK]
WEDDING BELLS!
[LAUGHING]
THE NEXT MORNING,
THE BUTLER
TOLD THE HOUSEMAID
WHAT HE HAD HEARD.
THE PRINCE
WAS GOING TO BE MARRIED.
THE HOUSEMAID
TOLD HER MISTRESS.
THE RUMOR WENT FLYING
THROUGH THE PRINCIPALITY.
BEFORE THE DAY
WAS HALF OVER,
THE LADIES AND GENTLEMEN
OF THE FASHIONABLE HILL
WERE SELECTING NEW CLOTHES
TO WEAR AT A WEDDING.
EGYPTIAN, THEY SAY.
TEHARA.
IT'S AN EGYPTIAN NAME.
OH, I KNOW.
I SPOKE TO HER.
NO!
WHAT WAS SHE LIKE?
OH, VERY PLEASANT.
ROYALTY ALWAYS IS.
SHE WAS MOST CORDIAL
WITH US.
YES. VERY GRACIOUS.
SHE ADMIRED BIRDENA
AND SERAFINA VERY MUCH.
OH...HA HA.
SHE SPOKE VERY HIGHLY
OF THEM TO THE PRINCE.
HE TOLD ME SO.
YOU SPOKE TO THE PRINCE?
OF COURSE.
WE HAD A DELIGHTFUL
HALF HOUR.
IS SHE BEAUTIFUL--
THE PRINCESS?
OF COURSE.
UH, PASS THE BUTTER.
IS SHE KIND...
AND GOOD?
WHAT DIFFERENCE TO YOU?
FOR THE PRINCE.
IT'LL BE HAPPIER FOR HIM
IF SHE IS--
THE BUTTER.
WILL HE BE GOING
TO EGYPT TO LIVE?
EGYPT IS A WILDERNESS.
THE PEOPLE ALL
RUN ABOUT NAKED!
[ALL LAUGH]
THE RICH ONES
WEAR CLOTHES.
[LAUGHTER CONTINUES]
[THINKING]
HE'S GOING TO BE MARRIED...
TO A PRINCESS.
HE'S GOING TO BE MARRIED.
HE'S GOING TO BE MARRIED!
HE'S GOING TO BE MARRIED
TO A PRINCESS!
I WISH I WERE DEAD.
HE'S GOING TO BE MARRIED!
DID YOU BRING
YOUR LUNCH?
I...
I CAME--
I CAME TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
GOOD-BYE?
NO, I DON'T
CARE FOR IT MUCH.
I LIKE WINDOWSILL BETTER.
BUT IF YOU LIKE GOOD-BYE,
YOU SAY GOOD-BYE,
AND I'LL SAY WINDOWSILL,
ELBOW,
APPLE DUMPLING,
PICKLE RELISH.
I'M--I'M RUNNING AWAY
FROM HOME.
FROM HOME TO WHERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
WELL, YOU'RE GOING TO LIVE
IN THE PALACE SOMEDAY,
SO WHY DON'T YOU RUN
THAT WAY?
NO! THAT IS WHY
I'M RUNNING AWAY.
I CAN'T BEAR TO LIVE HERE...
AND--AND SEE THE PALACE...
AND KNOW THAT HE...
HE'S GOING TO GET MARRIED
TO A--TO AN EGYPTIAN
PRINCESS.
PRINCES ALWAYS MARRY
PRINCESSES.
I KNOW.
IT'S NOT HIS FAULT.
I WISH I WERE DEAD.
YOU'RE SAD.
YOU NEED TO HEAR
A LITTLE PHILOSOPHY.
LET ME SEE, NOW.
I MUST GIVE YOU
SOME HOMELY WISDOM.
TRY THIS.
LIFE IS LIKE YOUR PIPE.
YOU NEVER KNOW WHERE
YOU PUT IT.
DOES THAT MAKE YOU
FEEL BETTER?
NO.
NOT YET, THAT IS.
MAYBE LATER.
TRY ANOTHER.
THE CLOUDS PASS,
THE BLUE REMAINS CONSTANT.
I--I GUESS IT DOES.
[SIGHS]
HMM.
TRY THIS ONE.
LIFE IS MYSTERIOUS,
AND SEARCH FOR CAUSES
OCCASIONALLY BRING ABOUT
STRANGE RESULTS,
JUST AS POTATOES OCCASIONALLY
RESEMBLE EMINENT STATESMEN.
THANK YOU.
WELL, I'M GLAD
YOU FEEL BETTER.
[CHEERILY]
GOOD-BYE.
[SOBBING]
CINDERELLA.
LOOK UP, CINDERELLA.
PERHAPS
YOU CAN HELP US.
THE PRINCESS TEHARA...
WE CAN'T FIND HER.
WE HAVE ONE CLUE.
SHE LOST HER SLIPPER
AT THE BALL.
IT WILL FIT
ONLY PRINCESS TEHARA.
ALLOW ME.
BUT--
I MUST ASK YOU
TO TRY ON THIS SLIPPER.
BUT IT'S MINE.
I LOST IT.
I--I HAVE THE OTHER ONE
RIGHT HERE. SEE?
THAT'S WHAT I THOUGHT.
I WORE THEM AT THE BALL.
I SUSPECTED IT WAS YOU.
YOU...
YOU'RE MAKING FUN OF ME.
[CHEERING]
AND SO THE PROPHECY
CAME TRUE,
AND ELLA WENT TO LIVE
IN THE PALACE.
AS FOR
THE FAIRY GODMOTHER,
AND SHE WAS
THE FAIRY GODMOTHER...
SHE WENT BACK
WHERE SHE CAME FROM.
AND EVERYBODY
LIVED HAPPILY EVER AFTER.