I need backup.
Time out.
[Imitating gunfire]
Dude, I said, "time out."
Oh, what's up, dude?
Hey, buddy.
Hey.
I had a feeling
you'd be coming over...
And I already unlocked
the piano for you.
Serious?
Thanks, Pete, you're the best.
I know.
Time in.
[Imitating gunfire]
[Sighs]
[Orchestra tuning up...]
[Voices vocalizing faintly...]
On my way
Though I don't know
where I'm going
On a road that's dark
And long
On my way
But I'm fearful that
I could be lost
That the path I have chosen
Might be wrong
When will it be clear
Boy: that I
made the right choice?
When can I be sure
Boy: that I know
my own voice?
Both: dream of a day
when I'm free from doubt
And faith wins out
And I overcome my fear
Boy: clear.
[Song ends]
What are you doing?
[Gasps and laughs]
You scared me, I...
I'm Madison Huxley...
Did you hear that?
I'm Madison Huxley,
my father owns this mall.
Oh, yeah, yeah, I totally
know who you are, I'm Ally...
last I heard, this piano
was for official mall use only.
Oh, yeah, I just... I practice.
When there's nobody around,
'cause of the acoustics.
Well, I'm around
Oh, uh, I'm sorry.
I'm getting security to
lock this thing back up.
[Door slams shut]
When will it be clear
That I made
the right choice?
When can I be sure
That I know my own voice?
Dream of a day
when I'm free from doubt
When faith wins out
And I overcome my fear
Clear.
[Song ends]
Boy: she wrote another song?
Is this one finished?
Don't you know by now?
She never finishes any of it
Even half-finished...
her songs are better than
anything I could ever write.
Hey, maybe she's got A.D.D.
I got A.D.D., it can
really impede on one's ability
to complete tasks.
Yeah, and, uh,
one's ability to shut up.
All I'm saying is you should
make your move soon, man.
I sang with her last night.
[Laughs] all right, dude,
so you finally talked to her?
Oh, Joey, man, this is
getting pathetic, dude.
You're, like, playing
the phantom of the mall.
Yeah, dude, rock stars
aren't all timid and shy
It wasn't the right time, Ricky
It's never the right time
Ugh, time, time, time, time...
time!
Well, time don't wait
for no one
No one gets in for free
It's time we got it going
And I can see myself,
I'm a star in a rock band
Signing all them autographs
Just don't you know that...
every 10 seconds,
someone's changing the world
Someone's breaking the rules
and someone gets the girl
Every 10 seconds,
there's a runner crossing over
the line
Sent my application,
I got nothing to lose
Looking at my watch
and it's a quarter to
Everything I want, I can
see it, see it in my mind
It's just a matter of time
(time, time, time)
It's the matter of time
And it takes blind ambition
To rock the industry
I'll make somebody listen
They're gonna play my song,
gonna hear it on the radio
Driving down the freeway,
that's what I say...
every 10 seconds,
someone's changing the world
Someone's breaking the rules,
and someone gets the girl
Every 10 seconds,
there's a runner
crossing over the line
Sent my application,
I got nothing to lose
Looking at my watch
and it's a quarter to
Everything I want, gotta do
what it takes to get mine
It's just a matter of time
Here we go, one, two,
one, two, three.
They're gonna play my song,
gonna hear it on the radio
Driving down the freeway,
that's what I say...
every 10 seconds,
someone's changing the world
Someone's breaking the rules,
and someone gets the girl
Every 10 seconds,
there's a runner
crossing over the line
Sent my application,
I got nothing to lose
Looking at my watch
and it's a quarter to
Everything I want, gotta do
what it takes to get mine
It's just a matter of time
(time, time, time)
(time, time, time).
[Song ends]
[Breathing heavily and coughing]
We are gonna be one
kick-ass rock band someday.
Yeah, as soon as we get
some real instruments...
hey, give it time,
man, give it time.
Yeah, in the meantime,
let's get back to work, alright?
Ugh.
You're gonna keep sleeping here
, you can at least open up
the store on time.
It's not like we got them
busting down the door
to buy stuff.
Just because
it's been a little slow...
"slow" would be an improvement,
Mom, it's like...
[yawns] we went out of business,
and nobody told us.
Doesn't mean we stop
doing our job.
Not that anyone cares.
[Sighs] at least I have three
piano lessons booked today.
Two, Miss Sullivan canceled.
Apparently Megan wants to
"do cheerleading instead."
[Giggles sarcastically]
Your friend Ben said this feng shui
fountain would stimulate wealth.
So far, all it's done
is make me want to pee.
Maybe I'll put you out
in the mall with a hat
to sing for spare coins.
Yeah, right,
why don't you do it?
I mean, you're the one
who's a professional singer.
Yeah.
One record 20 years ago
that no one ever bought.
Any word from Ohio?
Uh, no, not yet.
Mom: well, don't worry.
They'll accept you off
the wait list.
You're got your father's talent
with numbers, god rest his soul.
You'll get into
your first choice.
Huh, uh, yeah, yeah, um...
Ohio's got a great, uh,
business department.
Welcome back, Mr. Huxley.
[Laughs]
Oh, it must bring back
a lot of memories being
back at your very first mall
After having been
away for so long.
Hard at work on
your retail empire.
Huxley: I suppose so.
And how gratifying,
your daughter following
in your footsteps.
She's a, uh, Two-For-One split
off the old stock. [Laughs]
Huxley: Max Huxley.
Ok, that wasn't funny.
That's ok.
What are you doing?
[Tearfully]: I just broke up
with my boyfriend.
I'm a stress eater
Well, my staff is required
to be a size zero.
Or under, preferably, under.
So you choose,
meaningful employment...
or candy-Coated cellulite?
There's my beautiful
college graduate.
Daddy... [laughs]
I'm so glad you're here, ok,
I've got our day together
all planned out.
You're gonna see my little
presentation first...
and then I made reservations
for us at that chic, new sushi
restaurant I was telling you...
Maddy, I'm sorry, but
I can't spend the day with you.
I have to leave in
a few minutes.
Oh.
An opportunity popped up
for me to acquire another mall
And as you know,
business is war.
How 'bout I fly in
next week to make it up to you
We'll have a very special
dinner, just the two of us.
Ok.
Um, you can still see my
presentation, though, right?
Hit me with it.
Ok, ok, um, wait there, um...
[Woman whispering]: Madison.
Madison: you'll find
only the best pieces
From the most
exclusive designers.
[Woman whispering]: Madison.
Demonstrating the most
discerning eye for fashion.
Madison...
expensive, refined, Madison.
So what do you think?
It was nice.
"Nice"?
I'm in stores every day,
all over the country.
And yours looks like
a lot of them.
If you want to succeed in
retail, you have to be
different, unique.
I know that.
I mean, that's why
I did all of this.
I wanted to show you ordinary.
That was ordinary.
Madison's is going to be
cutting-edge.
So you have a plan?
Madison: totally.
You just have to
give me a chance.
I'm sorry, but if you're gonna
a make this meeting,
we have to go.
Daddy?
[Breathes deeply]
Dori, give Madison whatever
she needs to make this happen.
Dori: yes, sir.
Thank you. [Laughs]
I have to go.
Madison: you won't
I know I won't
Um, I'll see you next week
for our special dinner.
Huxley: you will.
[Mouths silently]
Owen.
This, we're playing this.
That's a pretty tune.
Uh...
yeah.
I thought he was in a hurry.
Mom, don't look at me
like that, please.
Come on, give me a chance.
Can never get through to
that woman.
I don't want to talk about it,
what's going on in your life?
Not much, except that I just had
a really weird moment
with Max Huxley.
Oh, and last night,
I had a run-in with Madison.
Uh, she said my outfit
looked like baby vomit.
She's obnoxious,
spoiled, narcissistic...
and she has perfect hair,
I hate her.
[Laughs] control
your hair envy, please.
Before Miss Buzzkill even
showed up, I heard a voice.
Uh, there's medication
for that, bubo.
I'm serious
This guy, I have no idea
who he was, but...
he was somewhere in the mall and
he was singing words to my song.
And they were good?
Yeah.
Yeah, they were, they were good.
It was like he was in my head
reading the lyrics
That were just floating around
that I can't.
Get out.
Wow, he really got to you.
A voice, huh?
I usually go for a nice butt,
but whatever toasts your bagel.
Girl: please, stop, stop,
please?
Please, No-No-No, stop, stop.
Ugh.
[Screaming]
Put me out of my misery.
On the house.
No, Ben.
No-No-No-No-No-No,
one of the many perks
of my new power position.
Assistant manager.
What?
Yeah, and my parents
were worried about my future
after high school.
Girl: at least
you're making progress.
Look, Kira's 15 and she's
already got her own boutique.
Ally: that girl's 15?
I know, and I can't even
get my mom to let me
design for the shop.
I mean, I'm going to
the fashion institute
for a reason, right?
Ben: why, you're 18
and already over the hill.
[Coughs]
My mom's excuse is that
I don't know anything about
plus-sized women's bodies.
And I'm like, " hello.
Inside of every skinny girl,
there's a fat chick just
screaming to come out."
You gotta tell her how you feel.
Says the girl whose mom still
thinks she's going to college
to be an accountant or whatever.
Hey, backspace, that's not fair
I'm waiting.
I mean, what if I don't
get into Ohio State College.
Then maybe my mom will let me
go to New England Conservatory?
To study music? [Laughs]
Are we still talking about
your mother, right, Mia?
Mia?
What?
Sorry, I was checking out
the summer crop of newbie guys.
There's my future Ex-B.F. Now.
Do you know that guy?
No.
But I'm going to.
[Mia grunts]
Ooh, take a number, "next."
[Sighs] whatever.
There's no other cute guy
s here today, anyway.
Hello, what about me?
Whoa, backspace.
Girl: now that's what
I'm talking about
Mia: who are they, why have
we never seen them before?
Ben: they're the night crew
Mia: janitors?
Girl: dirty.
I think they prefer to be called
custodial engineers.
Mia: mm, I call the one
in the garbage can.
[Laughs] I never imagined myself
with a guy who handles
trash for a living.
Me either, but I am now...
you realize that would make
both of you two trash, right?
Whatever, I buy lunch
and I'm ignored
We're not ignoring you
You know, you're
one of the girls.
What?
Whatever, I'm leaving
Ally: Ben, Ben,
come on, come on.
You know how Mia gets.
The only reason she even
works here is to shop for boys.
Mia: hey, look.
People come to the mall
to shop for all kinds of
things, all right?
Why not boys?
The minute I walk in,
there is so much to see
I check out the boys
who are checking out me
Every shape and size,
and I want to sample them all
I see dazzling designs
when I open my eyes
Baby, I can change my world
with these hot dogs and fries
All: stop and take a look,
something special behind
every wall (wall)
At the mall...
hangin' out with your friend,
at the mall...
circulate and spend
You can be real,
loosen up, what's the deal
Hit your stride as you glide
down the hall
At the mall...
at the mall
Help me.
I like those uniforms in gray
and smart and brainy types
At the mall, ooh,
at the mall
And I go a little crazy
for the scrumptious boys
in stripes
At the mall, ooh,
at the mall
Try on the latest in couture
with a wrap that is surreal
At the mall, (fierce), ooh,
at the mall
And some killer
velvet sneakers with a 10-inch
rubber heel
Chorus: at the mall,
at the mall, at the mall
Ben: with an image
that is sharp
With a style that'
ultra-slick
And rock the fast food world
with noodles on a stick
Chorus: at the mall,
at the mall, at the mall
At the mall, at the mall,
Girl: ow
At the mall...
at the mall
(at the mall, at the mall)
At the mall...
at the mall, at the mall,
at the mall...
hanging with a friend
at the mall
Circulate and spend
You can be real,
loosen up, what's the deal
Hit your stride as you glide
down the hall
At the mall
Doing what you please,
at the mall
Possibilities
Lost in a crowd,
all shouting out loud
You can scheme, you can dream
at the call
[Phone rings]
At the mall, at the mall,
at the mall
At the mall, at the mall...
at the mall.
[Song ends]
Daddy's coming in for
the Huxley Mall Summer Slam
So we'll announce
my grand opening then.
Done.
Fantastic.
Hey, should we grab a bite
in the food court before
I show you the space?
Madison: ew.
Even if we did eat lunch,
we wouldn't eat it there,
would we?
Would we, Alexa?
Yeah, barf.
Well, if you don't eat lunch,
then when do you eat?
Mondays and Fridays.
Oh... good.
And let's go see the space.
Mm, great.
Ok.
Thanks.
Turn off the- Oh, bye, Emma.
Open a door
Want a little something
And bought a little...
you wrote lyrics?
That's all I got so far
Shouldn't waste time
trying to finish a tune
I started when you were three.
Well, seems like we both have
a problem finishing
songs we started.
Yeah, well, earning a living
is just slightly more important.
With all these bills...
what is it?
It's from Ohio State
My gosh, open it.
I... got in.
You did.
See, I knew you would,
that's so terrific, ooh...
my high-powered businesswoman.
Yeah.
So the square footage isn't
quite what you asked for, but...
then I want that space too.
But it's occupied.
So?
Well, they're one of
the mall's original tenants.
It's gonna be hard to
convince 'em to vacate, so...
Daddy did say to get me
whatever I want, but...
if you can't handle that...
just... give me a second.
Ok.
Are we interrupting?
This is... Madison Huxley.
Wow, you used to run around
with your father when he
first opened up the mall.
Yeah, anyway, I'm gonna
knock out this wall
And open my new mega-hot
boutique right here.
What?
Um, you can't kick us out,
I mean, we have a lease.
Well, we're not gonna
kick you out, it's just...
You're a little overdue for
a rent increase.
Increase?
We can barely afford
what we pay now.
[Clears throat]
Look, I'm so sorry, but this
is completely out of my hands.
And according to your lease, if
you're late, we have a problem.
But hey, here's an idea.
If you agree to vacate now,
we can offer you a little
compensation.
Which you clearly need,
judging by how busy you are.
We're plenty busy, besides...
We've got lots of new students
just begging for lessons.
Ally?
We're gonna pay the increase
Look.
I want this store.
And I wanted Zac Efron
But you know what, everyone's
So we'll, we'll talk later,
thank you.
Can you?
What, I, ugh.
Ooh.
At the mall
[laughs].
At the mall... do it
Ooh, ooh, how'd it go?
I want them gone.
I guess that means not so well.
We can't force them out
if they're agreed to pay
the hiked-up rent.
Ok.
And get rid of this thing too.
[Screams]
Alexa!
Alexa?
Oh... you poor...
I have to go.
[Sighs]
[Loud buzzing and drilling...]
[Glass shatters]
Woman: I'm sorry, we'll come
back another day.
[Loudly]: oh, were you knocking?
I couldn't hear you
What... what is your problem?
What?
Oh, my goodness.
I hope our construction
isn't disturbing your business
I am so sorry.
[Loud buzzing and drilling]
Bye, bye.
She's right.
If we're late with our rent,
even once, they can kick us out.
Doesn't give us
a lot of options.
There is always
my college money.
No, it's called your
college money for a reason.
You let me
worry about the store.
You just focus on school.
Get a jump on your
future classmates.
Yeah, I'll get right on that.
[...]
When gray
Meets light
It creates new color that
Stay lost
Inside
Till they find
each other, then
[Person vocalizing...]
[Humming]
[Vocalizing...]
[Singing indistinctly]
Ooh, ooh
Are you the voice?
Are you the one
that sang with me?
No.
It is you, isn't it?
Maybe.
How did you know my music?
I... I...
no, I, I can explain this.
Where did you...
my trash can.
No, no.
Well, yeah, it's.
But it's not just yours
it... it's my job
They were in the trash
for a reason.
But they're good
I mean they're really good
I just, I sang with you
that night when I heard you play
I just, I couldn't help myself
And you wrote words to my song?
No, I don't know, it was just
like, in me, I guess.
I heard your music and then I...
it was like you saw what
I was trying to say.
...saw what you were
trying to say.
Yeah.
I'm Joey
Oh, Ally.
Hey.
[Clears throat]
You know, I practically
grew up in this mall
But I've never
been in here before.
It's the secret underbelly.
There's lots of places in
the mall that regular people...
aren't allowed to see.
Yeah, I bet.
You want to see my favorite?
So the guys and I,
we put this band together.
We were just about to
get our big break
Like, with this big A&R guy.
Everything got stolen.
Guitars, our amps, everything.
You know my mom's store
has got all that kind of stuff.
Yeah, I know. [Laughs]
We've had our nose
s pressed against your window
since we started working here.
[Laughs]
We're just trying to
save up enough.
I can tell it's pretty
important to you.
Yeah.
Also, I really owe the guys,
'cause it's kind of my fault
that everything got stolen.
Oh, how?
I was stupid.
Trusted the wrong people.
Boys are dumb.
Yeah.
I want to show you something.
Ooh, yeah
When gray
Meets light
It creates new colors that
Stay lost
Inside
Till they find each other
A world that you
never seen before
Starts moving in slow motion
Both: am I living now?
Out loud
I'm not afraid somehow
To let you see
right through me
Yeah
I must be dreaming
Wide awake
This world
So real
Like a kaleidoscope
made clear
To touch
To feel
What if it
made it disappear?
With just a chance that
you might change
I'd rather
breathe this moment...
am I living now?
Out loud
And I'm not afraid
Somehow
To let you
see right through me
Wait, I must be dreaming,
wide awake
Yeah...
yeah, yeah, yeah
Wide awake, wide awake
Yeah...
yeah, yeah, yeah... yeah
Yeah, yeah
Oh
Am I living now?
Out loud
And I'm not afraid
(I'm not afraid)
Somehow (somehow)
To let you see
right through me, no
Am I living now?
Out loud
And I'm not afraid somehow
To let you
see right through me
I must be dreaming wide awake
(I must be dreaming)
I must be dreaming
wide awake.
[Song ends]
Pete: dudes?
Come on, man,
if Dori catches you,
she'll put my butt in a sling.
It's cool, man
Sorry, Pete.
Yeah, I'm sorry too, you know.
Guys... Joey...
oh, not funny, man.
So...
so, I'll, um, see you tomorrow?
You know where to find me.
Yeah, going through
my trash. [Laughs]
Bye.
All right. [Chuckles]
Actually, wait, um...
[Sawing and hammering]
[Sighs] and you know that
she's only doing it
to force us to leave.
What a total jerk.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know, I mean,
it's becoming serious.
People are starting to
cancel their lessons.
Sorry, what did I miss?
Ben: what took you so long?
Finally, gosh.
Hey, guys.
Hey.
You're been intentionally tryin
to accidentally run into those
janitor guys again, haven't you?
Yes.
Well, did you see 'em?
Oh, my god, I look too fierce...
hey.
Oh, my gosh,
it's a hot janitor guy.
Hi.
Hey, Joey.
Uh, could we join you guys?
Yeah.
Cool.
What, Joey, what?
Oh, my gosh, he is so hot.
Wait, have you been
holding out on us?
Hey.
I don't think he's all that hot
Well, he is.
You need to tell me everything.
Is he a good kisser?
How big are his hands?
Mia...
these are the guys.
Hey.
Guys, you can sit.
Yeah, sit.
I'm Mia
Well, I guess
I'll get back to work.
Yeah, ok.
What's your name?
[Whispers]: dude...
she scares me.
Mind hanging out of
a spare guitar string?
In case yours breaks?
Mm-Hm.
[Laughter]
Yo, Rick, check this out.
[Grunts]
Wow, you're, uh, a real rocker.
Sounds a whole lot
better than my mop.
Some critics might disagree.
Let's see what the critics
have to say about this.
Let's go
Everybody caught up in
the wheel of fortune
Virtual life, well,
it can get so boring
Isolation, suffocation,
we all need a big vacation
Just get lost
in the wall of sound
Music makes us
come together now
Don't you want to get it,
gotta get it before it's gone
Come on, come on,
get your, get your rock on
Don't you want to do it,
gotta do it,
that's what you want
Come on, come on,
get your, get your rock on
get your, get your rock on...
yeah, whoo.
Don't you know it's all about
the liberation?
Gotta use it or lose it,
no hesitation
Take a lesson,
stop the stressing, here'
a cure for your depression
Just get lost
in the wall of sound
Alexa?
...us come together now
Don't you want to get it,
gotta get it before it's gone
Come on, come on,
get your, get your rock on
Don't you want to do it,
gotta do it,
that's what you want
Come on, come on,
get your, get your rock on...
everybody got
their own music
Playing 'round in their head
But when we all
bring it together
Ain't nothing better
Ain't nothing better...
oh, oh, oh
Don't you want to get it,
gotta get it before it's gone
Get what you want,
come on, come on,
get your, get your rock on
Don't you want to do it,
gotta do it,
that's what you want
Come on, come on,
get your, get your rock on
Don't you want to get it,
gotta get it before it's gone
Come on, come on,
get your, get your rock on
Don't you want to do it,
gotta do it,
that's what you want
Come on, come on,
get your, get your rock on
get your, get your rock on.
[Song ends, cheering]
[Screams]: what is
going on in here?
They're all ruined.
Do you know how much these cost?
Yeah, I was the one
who tagged the prices.
Don't be smart.
You have to start thinking about
the consequences of what you do.
Life is not all
singing and dancing, Ally.
Mom, we, we were just
trying to... help.
I mean, did you see all
the people that their music
brought into the store?
Oh, did any of those
people buy anything?
Exactly.
Well...
I'm really sorry if
we upset your mom today.
No, it's, it's not
you guys, it's the store.
Yeah.
And me. [Chuckles]
She tried doing the whole music
thing when she was younger.
Be a professional singer, but...
it didn't work out.
And now we're barely
getting by, and...
she told me that, um...
well, what does that
have to do with you?
Deep down, I think that she
knows that I want to do it too.
And I kind of sort of got into
new england conservatory.
What, are you serious?
That's awesome
To you, yeah, but...
I'm terrified as to
what she's gonna say
when she finds out.
I mean...
she wants me to go to
Ohio State College for Business.
I don't even really know what
studying business means, like...
[sighs]
But just 'cause she didn't?
make it doesn't mean that
you're not going to, you know
You're not her
Plus, you're...
You're pretty talented
I'm sorry, that was way too...
no, no, it, no...
step out of the car
with your hands up.
Joey: Pete,
you're killing me, dude.
Dude, you're killing me
If Dori catches you...
Ally: I'm sorry, Pete.
[Mouthing silently]
[Phone rings]
Hi, daddy.
Ok, so I was gonna wait
and talk to you about this
at our special dinner...
but I just can't wait, I'm gonna
tell you right now, ok.
So what do you think about
putting a Madison'
In every single one
of your malls?
That way we could spend
so much more time together.
That sounds great, sweetie.
You're not coming
for our dinner, are you?
They rearranged my schedule,
and I can't change it.
You're not mad, are you?
No, I know you're busy.
Business is war, Maddy,
and battles rarely happen
when you want them to.
Man: here you go, sir.
I'm coming to the summer slam
and for your big launch,
I'll take you to dinner then.
I promise.
Ok, bye.
[Screams]
Why is it taking you so long
to get me what I want?
I am.
It's only been...
uh, please don't call
your father.
Do I have to do
everything myself?
[Gasps and sniffles]
Surprise.
I thought they took it away.
It was supposed to be
shipped to the main warehouse.
But it got lost in translation.
He means lost in transit.
And you know, I thought
you could use a pick me up.
Ally: yeah.
What's all this for?
Uh, the, uh, Huxley mall
summer slam...
Hey, what's it called, anyway?
The Huxley mall summer slam.
[Imitating cheering]
I've already got the toy number
worked out, I'm the star.
I should enter my designs,
that'll show my mom.
Awesome, hey, I'll model
Yeah, you're really
good at wearing clothes.
Yeah, it's just
the walking you're gonna
have to worry about.
Dude, drummers just
have to sit down.
I can have time
to practice walking.
That's right.
Skylight tonight?
10:00?
10:00.
Hey, you know,
you guys should totally perform
at the summer slam.
You know, everyone loved it
when you rocked out at Ally'
Yeah, they should, as a part of
the "stay tuned" submission.
Get people grooving,
maybe inspire someone
to buy an instrument.
Take up lessons,
bring in business,
yeah, that's a great idea
Yeah, and we could totally
play one of your songs too.
One of our songs.
Joey?
Yeah.
Dori: you're needed
up in store number 63.
Look, can someone else do it,
I, I got plans.
No.
It's kind of
a job security thing for you.
And for me.
What?
Nothing.
Just... get up there.
You're here.
Yeah, so where'd the emergency?
Well, I'm sure you're heard
about my plans for my new store.
Well, this store needs a face.
A face for all of our ads.
A face that makes women
think, "I want that."
Mm-Hmm.
You're that face.
[Laughs] what?
Yeah, I don't know
what you're drinking here
But maybe you should
take it easy, you know?
Eat some bread or something.
"Some bread,"
[laughs], you're funny.
Look, I've heard you sing.
And you're amazing.
And I've got a feeling that
underneath all of this...
you're got the potential to be
a lot more than you realize.
Well, thanks for
thinking of me, but...
I actually gotta
meet someone right now...
So I'm, I'm gonna get going.
What's all this?
Just a little something
I picked up for...
you and your crew.
And with that grand piano
in the warehouse...
yeah, no, I, it was supposed...
keep it, it'll be our secret.
Joey: wait a minute,
you're not just giving this
all to us, are you?
What's the catch?
There's no catch.
Why don't you just think of me
as a patroness of the arts?
Imagine it, your picture
advertising my stores
In every mall
across the country.
That kind of exposure's gonna
a get you and your band noticed.
You'll play in front of
the right people.
Then come the record deals,
the Cd's, the music videos.
Who knows if it'll ever stop?
Come on, you can do all that?
[Chuckles]
My dad is a powerful man
with powerful friends.
I could make you a rock star.
I've got a plan that can
solve all your problems
Just think of me
as your magical wand
You're got a dream,
and I've got connections
And we naturally bond
[giggles]
If you agree, we can go in
as partners
No other team'
ever been quite this hot
You might be scared,
but there's nothing to lose
You can leave if you choose
But I bet you will not
Take a look at the new you
Imagine how it would feel
If what you see
could be real
What you want
could be true...
[phone ringing]
It's the new you (new you)
New you
Hey, uh, it's Ally.
I know you want
all the things I can offer
I see your face
next to mine on TV
Your band will play and
we'll all scream your name
You'll have cash,
you'll have fame
And you'll even have me
Take a look at the new you
Imagine how it would feel
If what you see
could be real
What you want could be true
So take a look at
the new you
Try on the clothes
you will wear
Come take a step,
if you dare
Time to make your debut
Chorus: new you, new you
The new you
New you, new you
Joey?
What?
Pull it together.
Hey, man, what's the matter?
I don't know, dude
I just, I do this and
I get back all the stuff
I lost for you guys.
It doesn't feel right to me
I don't know what to say, man,
but what do you have to lose?
You're a rock star now,
go be one.
Take a look at the new you
Imagine how it will feel
What you see can be real
What you want can be true
Take a look at the new you
How does it feel
to be a star?
take a look at the new you.
[Song ends]
And I was like, " Mom,
what about my designs?"
And she was like,
"your designs might be
better suited for the circus."
[Scoffs] I can't believe
your mom said that.
I know.
Did you get mad?
Please, this was from
a woman who goes to work
in a muumuu, ok?
[Laughs] oh, no, you didn't'
Oh, yes, I did.
[Laughing]
Hey, guys.
Hey.
Where's Joey?
He better have
a really good reason for
standing me up. [Chuckles[
Hello?
Joey, where is he?
Uh, Joey?
Joey who?
Ow, what'd you do that for?
Well, that was
a stupid thing to say.
Now she knows we're covering...
Dude!
Uh, yeah, uh, by covering,
I meant that, uh...
I think he had to go,
uh, um, on vacation?
Yeah, no, yeah, totally.
Yeah, he took a trip, didn't he?
Yeah.
But we don't know
when he's gonna be back
Ok, what happened?
Ally got dumped,
no call, no nothing.
She got a text message.
Ouch.
We don't know if he dumped her.
Maybe there was
a family emergency.
Ok, I've heard that one before.
Or a car accident, you know?
I've heard that one
Yeah, you know, me too, ok.
Running from the f.B.I.
Joining the peace corps,
allergic to my shampoo.
Look, trust me,
I've heard them all.
[Imitates "psycho" music]
Whatever.
Like you're ever even
had a date.
Give me your cell.
Ok, but why?
There's only person
n who knows the answer.
About to find out.
Pen.
I don't thin
k that's a good idea
Yeah, she's already called him
once, you can't call him again.
All right, stop.
[Phone rings]
I found your pants over here.
Hello?
Madison: Joey's sparkling
new phone.
[Gasps]
hello?
Business is war.
What'd you say?
Um, this is Dior.
Boys are dumb. [Chuckles]
The dope has no idea
what he's throwing away.
Thanks, Ben.
All right, come on.
Where are we going?
We're moving on
Show me a little bit of
heart somewhere
So I feel relieved
Show me a little bit of
heart somewhere
So I feel ready
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
That sweet face
ain't gonna turn gray
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
Hey, sugar,
don't care what you say
None of that sweet talk
gonna get me
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
Show me
A little bit of
strength somewhere
So I feel at ease
Yeah
Show me
A little bit of
strength somewhere
So I'll be in peace
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
That sweet face
ain't gonna turn gray
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
Hey, sugar, don't care
what you say
None of that sweet talk
gonna get me
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
Hey, what about me?
Ah... ah-Ha-Ha
Ah-Ha-Ha
A little bit hurt somewhere
Ah... ah-Ha-Ha
What are you looking at,
weiner boy?
Ah-Ha-Ha
Careful, that
Alexi-Lexi's hungry.
No redemption
It's no surprise
Mia: morning after
In morning light
Take my picture
Play your game
No matter how you'll
try to hurt me
It will be in vain, 'cause
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
Your sweet face
ain't gonna tempt me
Hey, sugar, ah, hey
I don't care what you say
None of that sweet talk
gonna get me
Hey, sugar, hey
Sugar, hey...
(hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey)
That sweet face
ain't gonna tempt me
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
Hurts somewhere
Hey, sugar, don't care
what you say
None of that sweet talk
gonna get me
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
That sweet face
ain't gonna turn gray
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey
Hey, sugar,
don't care what you say
None of that sweet talk
gonna get me
Hey, sugar, hey, sugar, hey.
[Song ends]
Wow, he really is hot.
How does her hair
always look so good?
Ally, girl, you really blew it.
Mom: Turn up the volume
Open a door
Want a little something
Then want
a little something...
[machinery buzzing...]
And you will keep working
until it's finished.
Do you hear me?
No food, no sleeping,
no pee breaks.
And you guys are...
hi.
Hi.
Is it weird to be looking at
Joey all model-Y and...
hot.
Hey, how many crunches
do you think I gotta do
to get abs like those?
A million a day?
Nah, dude, abs are genetic.
You either got it or you don't.
Cool, then pass
those nachos, will you?
Madison: Ok, Joey, we still have
a lot to talk about.
The number for the summer slam,
the rehearsal schedule,
your wardrobe...
the way your band mates look.
Hey.
But first, our song.
I saw one here
that is gonna be just...
perfect.
So are we gonna be
using Ally's songs?
Yeah, that doesn't
It's Joey's song too, see?
And I'll give her credit
in the program.
Actually, the guys are right,
maybe it's not cool
Joey...
my dad plays golf with
the presidents of major
record labels.
I'm doing all of this because
I think you're talented, and
I want you to make it.
But if you don't want it
bad enough to do
what it takes, then...
I'm wasting my time.
Joey: Ok, wait.
And the last piano lesson
has canceled.
We officially have no more money
coming in this month.
Let's just go home
Where'd you put the keys, Ally?
Are they in your backpack again?
Where's your backpack?
Mom, wait.
What's this?
When did you audition for
New England Conservatory?
Over spring break.
And why didn't you
talk to me about it?
What about Ohio?
I want to go to New England.
To write songs,
to sing? [Scoffs]
You barely sing in front of me,
how are you gonna do it
professionally?
I thought you wanted to
be a businesswoman.
When... I was 12.
Yeah, maybe, but...
even then, Mom, that was just
'cause I thought that's what
you wanted me to do.
I just want you to have
a, a stable life.
Both: a financially
secure career.
Yeah, yeah, I know.
But I want to do music.
I mean... Mom, it's my dream
Ally, there, there are dreams
and there are pipe dreams, ok?
You don't want to study
business, that's fine.
Just don't go after
something unattainable.
Un-, unattain-, Mom...
I'm good enough to get in
So are hundreds of others
this year
And thousands more that didn't'
make it in music and quit.
Well, they gave up,
I'm not going to
It's not giving up.
It's being practical.
Look, I can't even
pay my rent now.
I don't want you to make
the same mistakes I made
and wind up stuck like this.
Is this, is your life
really all that bad?
Yes, it is.
I'm tired of struggling,
and I don't want that for you
That's why I'm
selling the store.
I'm selling the store
to Madison.
What?
I signed the papers yesterday.
And you didn't talk to me
about it at first?
It's not your
decision to make.
Oh.
Ok, um...
look, it's the best
thing for us.
It'll get us both out of debt
It'll give you the rest of
your college tuition.
This way we're not stuck with
years of student loan payments.
Just because you didn't make it
in the music business
doesn't mean I won't
Your chances of making it
are slim to none.
You don't know, you can't
see it clearly now.
You don't think
I'm good enough, do you?
I didn't say that
But it's true, isn't it?
Ally...
just say it, Mom.
Ally, don't
Or are you afraid...
that I'm gonna succeed at
something that you failed at?
I don't think
you're good enough
Ok?
I don't
I think you're talented
I just don't know if
you're talented enough
It's a good thing it's not
your decision to make.
[...]
When gray meets light
It creates new colors that
Stay lost inside
Till they find each other
A world that you
never seen before
Starts moving in slow motion
Am I living now?
Out loud
Joey: and I'm not afraid
somehow
...right through me, wait
I must be dreaming
wide awake.
[Song ends]
Hello?
Ally?
Oh, hi, Ally,
don't we sound great?
That's my song.
Technically, it's yours
and Joey'
Al, let, please, let me explain.
You add in a couple of
nursery school rhymes
And you think that gives you
the right to steal my song?
That's not how it is.
Oh, well, then,
tell me, how is it?
I happen to think that
Joey's lyrics elevated
what was a mediocre tune.
Maddy, would you cut that out?
[Laughs] what, it's true.
You gave it soul.
Ally: he has no soul to give.
He's already sold that off.
Um, I'm pretty sure she just
called you the devil.
Yeah, I got that, thanks.
[Sighs]
Ok, look, I'm gonna give you
some advice.
You're never gonna get
anywhere in life unless you can
see an opportunity and take it.
See, that's the difference
between me and you.
I would never step on someone
when they were down.
Well, that's exactly why
I'm successful...
and you're stepped on.
[Sighs]
Ally, wait.
Joey, just... let her go.
She's gonna calm down
and she'll realize this is
what's best for everyone
Herself included... ok?
Ok, let's take it again
from the top.
Hello, from the top!
[Sighs]
I just woke up from
a fractured fairy tale
I bought the dream but
didn't read the small details
On which road I should take
I thought I could see
yet you led me astray
And now I feel cheated
I let you break my heart
Invaded my power
But I finally learned that
I hate to lose
Now there's something
I've gotta prove
I'm a survivor (survivor)
Scream it loud and strong
That's right, bring it on
I'm taking back the part
I gave away, yeah
And I'll never do it again
unless it's an even trade
Oh
Oh, I opened my heart,
like a fool
I trusted the light
in the dark
Until you unplugged it
No, left a mark,
but I rise above it
I know it (know it)
Every mistake
that I ever made
Made me who I am today
I'm a survivor
Yeah...
scream it loud and strong
I'm a survivor (survivor)
That's right,
bring it on, yeah
Princess opens up her eyes
Without a kiss
And that she won't forget
Pissed...
holy smokes!
Every mistake that
I ever made
Made me who I am today
I'm a survivor, yeah
Scream it loud and strong
I'm a survivor (survivor),
I'm a survivor
That's right, bring it on
I'm a survivor,
I'm a survivor, yeah
Scream it loud and strong
I'm a survivor,
I'm a survivor, yeah
That's right, bring it on.
[Song ends]
[Phone rings]
Excuse me, I think that's mine.
No, I think it's mine
Oh, maybe it's my ex,
do you think he wants me back?
[Phones ringing...]
[Ratcheting noise]
Madison: ok, people,
let's get a move on.
30 minute warning, people,
30 minutes till curtain.
Madison: oh, no, that's gotta
come down a whole half an inch.
That's way too high,
you've got...
Oh, hi, Daddy.
This is looking good.
Thank you.
We're doing so great,
we are right on schedule
for my big grand opening.
That's my girl.
The next step is just to
get them to move out.
Then we're gonna
knock down that wall
And we're gonna open up
a big Mega-Madison's
Hey, dude, does this outfit
make me look fat?
Oh, no, dude, uh,
your fat makes you look fat.
Ow.
What, fat, portly?
I brought you a little memento.
It's so you'll always
remember this special night.
Open it.
See, it's for you to wear
tonight after the show.
Thanks.
Oh, you're welcome
I better go get the show started
before the natives get restless.
[Applause]
Thank you.
Hi, everyone,
I'm Madison Huxley.
Welcome to the Huxley mall
Summer Slam.
[Laughter]
All right, fellows,
they're out there.
Four major record label
guys here... to see us play.
Awesome.
Oh, I'm gonna be sick.
Hey, I want to see.
Ugh, bucket?
No, drew-fus, the A&R guys,
would you come on, let's go
Joey, you coming?
No, I'll catch up with you.
Hey, one of you guys got a mint?
[Sighs]
I'm sorry I can't save
A heart when it breaks
and scatters
In the wind
How can two words
Cover the healthy others
They're living in...
oh, I never believed
Mm, mm
I'll never need
any more than I did before
When sorry's not enough
There's nowhere left to turn
Too much to forgive
Tell me where is the answer?
How do you
find the strength?
The strength to let it go
You need to just to live
Oh, just to live
And sorry's not enough...
oh, oh, oh
Joey: mm-Mm
Love can fall hard
Fall hard
Leaving a scar
that remembers
How bad it burns
Ooh-Ooh (oh-Oh)
We won't pretend
Where next time begins
Makes us live and learn
Live and learn, no
Only now I believe
Now I believe
I'm gonna say
Whoa
Both: little more than
I did before
Sorry's not enough
There's nowhere left to turn
Too much to forgive
Forgive me
Tell me where is the answer
How do you
find the strength?
The strength to let it go
You need to just to live
Oh, just to live, baby
Both: but sorry'
not enough...
no, there's no going back
No going back
But tomorrow is all...
Is all we could've had,
we could've had
So we will have...
sorry's not enough
There's nowhere left to turn
Too much to forgive
too much to, yeah
Tell me, where is
the answer?
How do you
find the strength?
The strength to let it go
You need to just to live
Oh, just to live, yeah, yeah
Sorry's not enough...
oh, ooh
Ally: mm.
[Song ends]
[Cheering]
I was totally perf
Is Ally in the audience?
Um, no, I didn't see her
[Sighs]
[Cheering]
Watch it, weiner boy.
Want a bite?
[Scoffs] are you insane?
[Applause and cheering]
Hey, hot dog, you're up.
That's me.
Dori: ok, next up...
your lunch.
[Laughter]
I thought we could take a break
and go see the rest of the
summer slam, what do you think?
I think I want to finish here
and then just go home.
That's what I think
And now, fall fashions
from the newest store
To join the Huxley mall
family... Madison.
[Applause]
[Inaudible speaking]
Woman: ok, guys, you're up next
[Cheering and laughter]
[Laughter...]
Are you kidding me?
[Swallows noisily]
Well. [Laughs nervously]
We seem to have
a running theme here.
All right, you can
do it, dude, totally.
All right.
Just remember, man,
right-Left, right-Left.
...the debut collection
by little penny.
Go get ', tiger.
Ow!
[Laughter...]
This is the last one.
Wow.
I had no idea you were
such a master packer.
Guess neither one of us
knew the other as well as
she thought she did.
Ally...
fine, I get it.
You're an adult,
and I have to let you make
your own decisions, I know that.
I should've talked to you first
before selling the store
But you should've talked to me
about new england.
Look...
you're all I've got.
And I just want you to be happy.
I know that.
I know.
[Cheering]
[Applause and cheering]
Yo, Joey, he did it,
man, he actually walked.
[Laughs] I do make
a pretty good supermodel
if I do say so myself.
Shut up.
Better put on your jacket, dude.
Yeah, Madison is P.O.'d
You ok, man?
Yeah, totally.
You know you don'
You don't owe us anything
If you're having
second thoughts about it, man,
just say it, and we walk.
No.
Dude...
we sold out.
Ow, I'm not saying
it's a bad thing, I mean...
Even green day sold out.
Yeah, I mean, I mean, everybody
does stuff that they're not
proud of to get what they want.
Just didn't think the sell-out
phase of our career would happen
Before the "career" phase
of our career phase happened.
Ow, ow...
see, it doesn't
Dude... go.
[Cheering]
Joey?
Where's Joey going,
we're on in a few minutes.
Uh, Joey?
Joey who?
Joey: hey...
so you guys are really closing?
Yeah.
Why don't I just...
Mom?
Too bad you missed our, uh,
Going-Out-Of-Business sale.
We were giving out
a lot of great deals.
Ally, please.
Not that you would
need anything, judging by...
what I saw the other night
at the rehearsal.
Will you please
just let me explain?
[Whispers]: Joey?
What are you doing?
You don't have to, Joey.
She's beautiful and
influential, I get it.
No, it's not about her,
it's about you
People spend their whole lives
trying to find what we found
in each other.
Some people never do.
I screwed up.
Boys are dumb, all right?
[Cheering in background]
Not that's an excuse
for me, just an apology.
A lame one.
I know.
Look, I just...
I hope that when,
if you're ready...
Maybe we can start over.
You know, not many people
get a second chance.
So you should get down there.
It's too big an opportunity
for you to pass up,
so play the song.
Seriously, it's ok, it's yours
Oh, and, uh...
in case yours breaks.
Joey, Joey?
This is far too important
to screw up.
Wish I would've
figured that out a lot sooner.
Joey, Joey?
[Cheering in background]
And now, the moment
you're all been waiting for...
Madison: not yet!
In just a second,
[laughs nervously], so...
...summer slam sounds better
than winter slam.
Look, I know it's not enough
just to say it, but...
I'm sorry.
What is his problem?
Never mind.
We'll do it without him.
Ok, go, go.
Ok and now...
the moment you have
all been waiting. [Laughs]
Hello, places?
Sorry, toots, no Joey, no, go.
What?
We're a band, babe,
we stick together.
So we're not selling out?
Get back here.
Madison.
Don't you dare
walk off the stage.
Get back here, do you hear me?
[Light applause]
Hi.
Man: where's the band?
[Whispers]: six, seven, eight.
When gray
Meets light
It creates new colors that
Stay lost
Inside
[Scattered laughter]
Now who's stepped on?
Hey, what's going on?
Train wreck, dude.
Serves her right.
Slow motion
Am I living now?
[Scattered laughter]
Out...
'cause I can't
hide me from you
And I'm not afraid
Some...
[scattered laughter]
A world that you're never
seen before
Starts moving in slow motion
Am I living now?
Out loud
And I'm not afraid somehow
To let you
see right through me, wait
I must be dreaming
wide awake
wide awake.
[Song ends]
[Applause...]
[Sighs]
Um...
ladies and gentlemen...
Ally Shepherd.
[Applause and cheering]
Hi, uh, everybody.
I guess I'm gonna play a song
that I wrote.
With a friend.
On my way
Though I don't know where
I'm going
On a road that's dark
And long
On my way
But I'm fearful that
I could be lost
That the path I have chosen
Might be wrong
When will it be clear
That I made
the right choice?
When I can be sure
That I know my own voice?
Dream of a day
when I'm free from doubt
And faith wins out
And I overcome my fear
Joey: here...
I don't know
I don't know where to
search for answers
In a world that
Isn't fair...
will I find my strength
And discover who
I've been, yeah?
Or retreat and pretend that
I don't care
When will it be clear...
that I made
the right choice?
When can I be sure...
that I know my own voice?
Both: I dream of a day
when I'm free from doubt
When faith wins out
And I overcome my fear
Clear...
I've been told
That we learn from
our mistakes
But I just don't know
How many mistakes it takes
Oh, I'm trying so hard
To let down my guard
Maybe right now...
right here...
clear...
that I made the right choice
Sure...
that I know my own voice
Praise the day
when I'm free from doubt
When faith wins out
And I overcome
My fear... (yeah, yeah)
Clear...
mm-Mm
Clear, yeah
Clear...
[song ends]
[Applause and cheering...]
[Ally laughs] a lot of you
may recognize this next song.
This one's for you, Mom.
Turn up the volume
Open the door
Want a little something
And want a little
something more
Don't look for easy
Easy comes hard
Take the road less traveled
But don't forget
your own backyard
Rattle some cages
Don't have to play nice
Ask a million questions
Mia: but never ask
the same thing twice
No indecision
that time has passed
Go a little crazy
And find a way to
make it last
You can move right up to
The head of the class
But not if you sit on
your big, fat, whoo
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let 'em know you were here
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let 'em know you were here
If you stop and think
Your chance will disappear
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let them know you were here
More like you mean it
Less like you should
Try a new direction
And that's alright,
that it's all good
No inhibition
Arms open wide
Reach a little higher
Then find some funk down
deep inside
You might wake up famous
And filthy rich
But not if all you do
is sit around and whoo
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let 'em know you were here
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let 'em know you were here
If you stop and think,
your chance will disappear
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let them know you were here
Don't just stand there
If you don'
like what you see
No-No-No-No
Change the channel,
change the channel
Change the world,
change the world
As long as you try
You'll be free
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let 'em know you were here
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let 'em know you were here
If you stop and think
Your chance will disappear
(don't hold back)
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let them know you were here
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let 'em know you were here
Don't hold back,
make some noise
Let 'em know you were here
If you stop and think,
your chance will disappear
Don't hold back
make some noise
Let them know you were,
let them know you were
let them know...
you were here.
[Applause and cheering...]
Don't you want to get it,
gotta get it before it's gone
Come on, come on, get your,
get your rock on
Don't you want to do it,
gotta do it,
that's what you want
Come on, come on, get your,
get your rock on
Everybody got their own music
playing 'round in their head
But when we all bring it
together, ain't nothing better,
ain't nothing better
Don't you want to get it,
gotta get it before it's gone
Come on, come on, get your,
get your rock on
Don't you want to get it,
gotta get it before it's gone
Come on, come on, get your,
get your rock on
Don't you want to do it,
gotta do it
that's what you want
Come on, come on, get your,
get your rock on
[Songs ends]
When gray
Meets light
It creates new colors that
Stay lost
Inside
Till they find
each other, then
A world that you
never seen before
Starts moving in slow motion
Am I living now?
Out loud
I'm not afraid somehow
To let you see
right through me
I must be dreaming
Wide awake
[Song ends]
At the mall
At the mall, at the mall,
at the mall
Hanging with your friend at
the mall
Circulate and spend
You can be real,
loosen up, what's the deal
Hit your stride as you glide
down the hall
At the mall
Doing what you please
at the mall
Possibilities
Lost in a crowd,
all shouting out loud
You can scheme, you can dream
at the call
[Phone rings]
At the mall
At the mall, at the mall,
at the mall