[SINGING]
They called her frivolous Sal
A peculiar sort of a gal
With a heart that was mellow
An all 'round good fellow
Was my gal Sal
Your troubles, sorrows and care
She was always willing to share
A wild sort of devil
But dead on the level
Was my gal Sal
[SINGING]
Watch them shuffle along
See them shuffle along
Go take your best gal, your real pal
Go down to the levee
I said to the levee
And join that shuffling throng
Hear that...
[SINGING "KOL NIDRE"]
[UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE]
[SINGING]
Wonderful pals are always hard to find
Some folks have one
Some folks have none
And I was alone for years
But fate was kind
And in the end
Sent me a friend
Although he's not much higher
Than my knee
Still, he's the greatest thing on earth
To me
Dirty hands, dirty face
Leads the neighbors a chase
But his smile is as cute as can be
Making noise, breaking toys
Always fighting the boys
But his eyes, they're a vision
To see
And when my work is done
Coming home with the setting sun
From the gate he'll start to run
And then I'll kiss my boy
Dirty hands, dirty face
Little devil, that's what they say
But to me
He's an angel ofjoy
Dirty hands, dirty face
Leads the neighbors a chase
But his smile, his little smile
Is as cute as can be
Making noise, breaking toys
[LAUGHS]
Always fighting the boys
But his eyes, they're his mother's
And they're a vision to see
And when my work is done
Coming home with the setting sun
From the gate he'll start to run
And then, oh
I'll... I'll kiss my boy
Dirty hands, dirty face
Little devil, that's what they say
But to me
He's an angel ofjoy
[APPLAUSE]
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
You ain't heard nothing yet.
Wait a minute, I tell you.
You ain't heard nothing.
You wanna hear, "Toot, Toot, Tootsie!"?
All right. Hold on, hold on.
Lou, play "Toot, Toot, Tootsie!"
Three choruses, you understand?
In the third chorus, I whistle.
Give it to them hard and heavy.
Go right ahead.
[BAND PLAYING "TOOT, TOOT, TOOSIE!"]
[SINGING]
Toot, toot, Tootsie, goodbye
Toot, toot, Tootsie, don't cry
The little choo-choo train
That takes me away from you
You don't know
Just how sad it makes me
Kiss me, Tootsie, and then
Do it all over again
Watch for the mail
I'll never fail
If you don't get a letter
Then you'll know I'm in jail, hey, hey
Don't cry, Tootsie, don't cry
Kiss me, Tootsie, goodbye
[WHISTLING]
Get hot.
Goodbye, Tootsie, goodbye
Ah!
Goodbye, Tootsie, don't cry
The little choo-choo train
That takes me away from you
You don't know
Just how sad it makes me
Kiss me, Tootsie, and then, hey, hey
Come do it all over again
Watch for the mail
I'll never fail
If you don't get a letter
Then you'll know I'm in jail
Don't cry, Tootsie, don't cry
Ah!
Goodbye, Tootsie, goodbye
[ROSENBLATT SINGING "KOL NIDRE"]
[SINGING "KOL NIDRE"]
[SINGING]
Blue skies smilin' at me
Nothin' but blue skies do I see
[SCATTING]
Bluebirds singin' a song
Nothin' but little bluebirds all day long
I never saw the sun shinin' so bright
Never saw things goin' so right
Noticing the days hurrying by
When you're in love
Oh, don't they fly?
Blue days, days, days
All of them gone
Nothin' but blue skies from now on
- Did you like that, Mama?
- Yes.
I'm glad of it.
I'd rather please you...
...than anybody I know of.
Oh, darling,
will you give me something?
- What?
- You'll never guess.
Shut your eyes, Mama.
Shut them for little Jakie.
I'm gonna steal something.
[JAKIE LAUGHS]
Oh, Jakie.
I'll give it back to you someday too.
You see if I don't.
Mama, darling...
...if I'm a success in this show...
...well, we're gonna move from here.
- Oh, no.
Oh, yes.
We're gonna move up in the Bronx.
A lot of green grass up there
and people you know.
The Ginsbergs, the Guttenbergs,
the Goldbergs.
A whole lot of "bergs,"
I don't know them all.
And I'm gonna buy you
a nice, black silk dress, Mama.
Mrs. Freedman, the butcher's wife,
she'll be jealous of you.
- Oh, no. No.
- Yes, she will. You'll see if she isn't.
I'm gonna get you a pink dress
that will go with your brown eyes.
What do you mean, no?
Who is telling you?
Yes, you'll wear pink or else.
Or else you'll wear pink.
And darling, oh, I'm gonna
take you to Coney Island.
- Yeah?
- Yes. We're gonna ride the Shoot-the-Chutes.
- Do you know the dark mill?
- Yes?
- You ever been to dark mill?
- I wouldn't.
With me, it's all right. I'll kiss you
and hug you. You'll see if I don't.
Now, Mama. Mama, stop now.
You're getting kittenish.
Mama, listen. I'm gonna sing this like I will
if I go on the stage with this show.
I'm gonna sing it jazzy.
Now, get this.
[SINGING]
Blue skies smilin' at me, me, me, me
Nothin' but little blue skies do I see
[SCATTING]
Bluebirds singin' a song
Nothin' but little bluebirds all day long
You like that slapping business?
Never saw the sun shinin' so bright
Never saw things goin' so right
Noticing the days hurryin' by
When you're in love, oh, don't they fly?
Blue days, all of them gone
- Stop!
- Nothin' but...
Mother, I'm sorry I wandered away
Breaking your heart as I did
Now that I'm grown up
I've come back to say
Things that I felt as a kid
Dear
Mother of mine
When friends all doubt me
I still have you
Somehow you're just the same
Mother divine
With your arms around me
I know I'm not to blame
When skies are sunny
[JAKIE SINGING]
Ain't it funny?
That's when my pals
All haunt me
When things go wrong
And they don't want me
Mother, I still
Have you
Mother of mine
When friends all doubt me
I still have you
Somehow you're just the same
Mother divine
With your arms about me
I know
I'm not to blame
Gee, ain't it funny
When skies are sunny
That's when my pals
They haunt me
And when things go wrong
And they don't want me
Mother
I still have
You
[APPLAUSE]
[JAKIE SINGING "KOL NIDRE"]
[SINGING]
Mammy
The sun shines east
The sun shines west
But I know where the sun shines best
Mammy
My heartstrings are tangled around
Alabamy
I... I'm comin'
Sorry I made you wait
I hope and trust I'm not late
Mammy
I'd walk a million miles
For one of your smiles
For my Mammy
Mammy
My little Mammy
The sun shines east
The sun shines west
But I know where the sun shines best
It's on my Mammy
I'm talkin' about
Nobody else's
My little Mammy
My heartstrings are tangled around
Alabamy
Mammy, I'm comin'
I hope I didn't make you wait
Oh, God, I hope I'm not late
Mammy
Don't you know me?
It's your little baby
I'd walk a million miles
For one of your smiles
For my Mammy