What can I do to make you stay?
(SPEAKS ITALIAN)
Huh?
- You're the light of my eyes.
- Oh!
I bet you say that to all the girls.
Normally I talk about the shiny
hair or... something like that.
(SIGHS)... I don't wanna go home.
Then don't.
I'm starting uni, real life.
But we can make it work. I'll...
Taylor, this is real life.
I love you.
(♪ "HOLIDAY")
(MUTED DIALOGUE)
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(PA ANNOUNCEMENT IN ITALIAN)
Business or holiday?
♪ Holiday
♪ Celebrate
♪ If we took a holiday
♪ Took some time to celebrate
♪ Just one day out of life
♪ It would be
♪ It would be so nice
♪ Everybody spread the word
♪ We're gonna have a celebration
♪ All across the world
♪ In every nation
♪ It's time for the good times
♪ Forget about the bad times
♪ One day to come together
♪ To release the pressure
♪ We need a holiday
♪ If we took a holiday
♪ Holiday
♪ Took some time to celebrate
♪ Come on and celebrate
♪ Just one day out of life
♪ One day out of life
♪ It would be
♪ It would be so nice
♪ Holiday, holiday, holiday
♪ Celebrate, brate, brate, brate
♪ Holiday, day, day, day
♪ Celebrate
♪ We need a holiday
♪ (ALL) Holiday
♪ Holiday, celebration
♪ (ALL) Celebrate
♪ Come together in every nation
♪ (ALL) Holiday
♪ Holiday, celebration
♪ (ALL) Celebrate
♪ Come together in every nation
♪ Whooo
Your first time in Puglia?
No, I was here three years ago.
♪ We need a holiday ♪
T-bag!
T-bag is here!
It's so good to see you.
My little pupalina.
- Ah! Grazie mille.
- Prego.
Come on!
So... how was the flight?
How were the exams?
Is it raining in England? Tell me
it's raining. It's raining, isn't it?
- This place is...
- Wait till you see the inside. Come on!
(SHRIEKING)
Oh, my God!
It's not quite the pensione
I recommended.
Isn't it heaven?
So...
- How are you?
- Fabulous!
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
- What's on your iPod?
- Er... I don't know.
But I can tell you it would not
be "Nothing Compares To You".
Don't tell me you're
actually over Doug?
Doug who? This is the best
holiday ever. I'm in love.
- Puglia's beautiful, isn't it?
- Uh-huh.
I knew you'd love it.
Thanks for flying me out.
Hey, I wanted to celebrate
your graduation.
Congratulations on being officially
the clever one, by the way.
Thank you. You'll always
be better at ballet.
Hmm... true. So bringing you
here was surprise number one.
- Are you decent?
- Who, me?
Lil!
Oh, my God!
My little professor.
Maddie never said you'd be here.
Oh, well, when she told me
Doug had dumped her,
I was like, "Yes,
hallelujah, man-tox time!"
And is there a better way
to spend my book advance?
- Tiziana.
- (TIZIANA) Eh?
(IN ITALIAN)
More Aperol Spritz, please?
Si.
- (CONTINUES IN ITALIAN) And a glass for you.
- Per me?
- (WHISPERS) She's a bit grumpy.
- Nice Italian, though.
Oh, she has got very familiar
with the Italian tongue.
So tell her.
I'm getting married.
Sorry, I thought you said
you were getting married.
Isn't it amazing?
- Oh, my God! Not to Doug?
- Oh, God, no!
But... you're on man-tox.
You're supposed to be finding yourself.
Well, I did. Here I am.
And there he was, so there we are.
Are you crazy? How long
have you known this guy?
Five weeks, but it's enough.
When you know, you know, you know?
You said that about Doug...
and Marcel and Connor.
And Tarquin.
This is different, he's...
sensitive and kind and gentle.
- Definitely not Doug, then.
- He's just the most wonderful thing...
(THUD)
- Grazie.
- Prego.
At least tell me it's
a long engagement.
That's why I had to get you here.
The wedding is in two days.
- That is insane.
- I know!
- Don't look at me. Puglia was your idea.
- I don't remember telling her to...
marry the first man she found
when she got out of the taxi.
He's wasn't the first man.
He was, like, at least the fourth.
- Have you lost your mind?
- Mmm.
Look, T, I was freaked out as well,
but he is a great guy and
you know I never say that.
I just can't believe
he wants to marry me.
Oh, God, please don't
start that again.
(SIGHS)
You know why.
- I do?
- Yes. Because you're a goddess.
(GROANS)
Yes, well, I suppose that must be it.
(♪ "VENUS")
♪ Goddess on a mountaintop
♪ Burning like a silver flame
♪ The summit of beauty and love
♪ And Venus was her name...
Whoa!
♪ She's got it
♪ Yeah, baby, she's got it
♪ I'm your Venus
♪ I'm your fire
♪ Your desire
♪ Well, I'm your Venus
♪ I'm your fire
♪ Your desire
♪ Her weapons were her crystal eyes
♪ Making every man mad
♪ Black as the dark night she was
♪ Got what no one else had...
Tss!
♪ She's got it
♪ Yeah, baby, she's got it
(INAUDIBLE)
♪ I'm your Venus
♪ I'm your fire
♪ Your desire
♪ Well, I'm your Venus
♪ I'm your fire
♪ Your desire
♪ (MEN) Venus
♪ She's got it
♪ Yeah, baby, she's got it...
Ooh... really sorry.
♪ Goddess on a mountaintop
♪ Burning like a silver flame
♪ The summit of beauty and love
♪ And Venus was her name
♪ Yeah, baby, she's got it
♪ She's got it
♪ I'm your Venus
♪ I'm your fire
♪ Your desire
♪ Yeah, I'm your Venus
♪ I'm your fire
♪ Your desire ♪
(SIGHS)
What? What am I supposed
to say? I'm thrilled?
- Well...
- I'm thrilled it's not Doug.
I'll drink to that.
I look forward to meeting him.
Well, you will, tonight. There's a dinner.
You're gonna love him.
Anyway... what about you?
Anything to report?
Finals went OK. I may
have messed up one paper.
No, I don't mean boring stuff.
I meant boys.
Oh, come on! You're out
of the library now.
You've got to let your hair down
and your inner goddess out.
I'm not like you. I don't go all wobbly
every time a boy takes his shirt off.
Maybe she's just saving
herself for her old flame?
Who? What?
- This is where T fell in love too, isn't it?
- Taylor doesn't fall in love,
- she's too sensible.
- OK.
What? I'm your sister and
I don't know this. Hello?
It was just a holiday romance.
Just a holiday romance?
Why didn't you tell me?
You were in the middle of one of
your worst breakups with Doug.
So, what happened?
Nothing. The holiday ended and uni
started and life just got in the way.
This is so exciting! You're back here.
Maybe you could rekindle the whole thing.
No...
He was off to travel the world.
Exs are like fireworks.
Never go back to them.
Either they blow up
in your face or...
Or they go all limp.
I think I might get changed
and pop down to the beach.
See if I recognise any
of the old crowd.
OK.
Taylor!
Oh, my God!
I can't believe you're here!
Three years we've been waiting
for you, We'd given up.
- And you, when did you get back?
- I never left. I couldn't leave Enrico.
What?
Does Raf know you're here?
Ciao, bella!
- What are you doing here?
- Oh, that's nice!
No, no. Dio mio, it's great to see you.
But it's been ages, babes.
- Hello, stranger!
- Hi!
- So, finally you come back, huh?
- Yes. How are you guys?
- Good.
- Molto bene, grazie. Pretty much the same.
- He's still sunburnt.
- Oi! That's a healthy colour, that.
- And you guys are still together?
- Yeah, of course. Nothing changes.
Yeah, but not everything
is the same, you know?
(♪ "HOW WILL I KNOW")
♪ There's a boy I know
♪ He's the one I dream of
♪ Looks into my eyes
♪ Takes me to the clouds above
♪ Oh, I lose control
♪ Can't seem to get enough
♪ When I wake from dreaming
♪ Tell me, is it really love?
♪ Ooh, how will I know?
♪ (ALL) Don't trust your feelings
♪ How will I know?
♪ (ALL) Love can be deceiving
- ♪ (ALL) How will I know?
- ♪ If he really loves me
- ♪ (ALL) I'll say a prayer
- ♪ With every heartbeat
- ♪ (ALL) I fall in love
- ♪ Whenever we meet
- ♪ (ALL) My love is strong
- ♪ But I feel weak
♪ Oh, wake me, I'm shaking
♪ Wish I had him near me now
♪ Except there's no mistaking
♪ What I feel is really love
♪ Ooh, tell me, how will I know?
♪ (ALL) Don't trust your feelings
♪ How will I know?
♪ (ALL) Love can be deceiving
♪ If he loves me
♪ If he loves me not
♪ If he loves me not, oh
♪ How will I know? ♪
Taylor?
- I see you've met my fiancé.
- Your...
What do you think?
A bit too gorgeous, isn't he?
- This is your fiance?
- Yeah. Do you guys know each other?
- Er...
- No! Hi, I'm Taylor, Maddie's sister.
She... she's your sister?
Yeah. Can't you see it?
T and I are like peas in a pod.
What is that?
T is for Taylor.
- T is for Taylor.
- What? Do you know these guys?
No! Hi, I'm Taylor. Nice to
meet you. Hi, how are you?
They're normally much friendlier
than this. Guys, it's my sister.
- Ah-ha! Well, welcome to Puglia, Taylor.
- (ENRICO) Taylor, hi.
Oh, so that's why you're here,
for your sister's wedding.
Yes, yes! And I am just so excited!
I knew you'd approve once
you met him. Isn't he divine?
Yes, er... sorry, sunstroke!
I think I need to go and
lie down in a dark room.
- Well, I'll come with you.
- No, no, no. I'll be fine.
Taylor.
Taylor! Are you all right?
- I just don't want Maddie to know.
- But you and Raf...
A holiday romance, years ago.
It was so totally nothing.
It's better to just pretend it never
happened because it pretty much never did.
OK, if you say so.
- I'll see you at the dinner.
- Yeah.
- (ELENA) Have you got a husband at home?
- (LIL) Several but, none of them are mine.
No, I don't do romance,
marriage or biological clocks.
Oh, Lil, everyone needs
a man sometimes.
I just change the battery.
So, Lil, what do you do?
I write erotic fiction.
Ooh...
If you need any help researching,
I'd be happy to, er...
I'm in Italy, babe. I'm not
ordering the fish and chips.
- (MIKEY) I'm spaghetti bloody vongole!
- I can't believe they're sisters.
Why not?
Er... yeah, like,
you're just... sisters.
What?
Come on, Rafa, speech.
(MIKEY) Give it up for the man
himself, mio migliore amico.
That was beautiful, Mikey. Thank you.
- No, you're beautiful.
I could just stare at him all day.
Er... I'm getting married.
- (ENRICO) Yes, Raf.
- (MIKEY) Hey!
- (RAF) Miss Maddie.
- (MADDIE) Mm-hmm.
My friends can tell you that I don't
really, usually, fall in love so easy.
But... with you it was
truly love at first sight.
What can I say?
You're amazing.
Passionate.
Brave.
Not afraid to show the
world how you feel.
I'm just so lucky you're mine.
- To Maddie.
- (ALL) To Maddie.
All right, babe, your turn.
- Oh, no, no...
- Yeah.
OK, yes, yes, yes.
Er... well, I know that this has come
as a bit of a surprise to some of you,
not least to myself.
Er...
T... Mum's not with us anymore,
but, er... well, you and Lil
are all the family I need.
You were the one who sent me here
and I can't thank you enough
because look what I found.
Er... I've made a lot of
mistakes over the years,
and, Raf, I have to be honest,
when I met you, I thought,
"He's gonna be another
one that won't last.
"It's just another holiday romance."
But then suddenly I knew that some holiday
romances are meant to last forever.
(♪ "THE POWER OF LOVE")
♪ The power of love
is a curious thing
♪ Make a one man weep,
make another man sing
♪ Change a hawk
to a little white dove
♪ More than a feeling,
that's the power of love
♪ Tougher than diamonds,
rich like cream
♪ Stronger and harder
than a bad girl's dream
♪ Make a bad one good,
make a wrong one right
♪ Power of love that
keeps you home at night
♪ Don't need money, don't take fame
♪ Don't need no credit
card to ride this train
♪ It's strong and it's sudden
and it's cruel sometimes
♪ But it might just save your life
♪ That's the power of love
♪ First time you feel it
it might make you sad
♪ Next time you feel it
it might make you mad
♪ But you'll be glad, baby,
when you've found
♪ That's the power,
makes the world go round
♪ Don't take money, don't take fame
♪ Don't need no credit
card to ride this train
♪ It's strong and it's sudden
and it'll be cruel sometimes
♪ But it might just save your life
♪ They say that all in love is fair
♪ Yeah, but you don't care
- ♪ But you'll know what to do
- ♪ What do to
♪ When it gets hold of you
♪ And with a little help from above
♪ You feel the power of love...
Whoo!
♪ (ALL)
Don't take money, don't take fame
♪ Don't need no credit
card to ride this train
♪ Tougher than diamonds
and stronger than steel
♪ You won't feel
nothing till you feel
♪ You feel the power
♪ Just feel the power of love
♪ That's the power
♪ That's the power of love
♪ You feel the power
♪ You feel the power of love
♪ That's the power
♪ That's the power of love
♪ You feel the power
♪ You feel the power of love
♪ You feel the power of love ♪
Taylor.
Hey!
Nice to see you again.
This is crazy, huh?
Yeah, but that's Maddie.
She loves a big show.
I mean, I had no idea
Maddie was your sister.
Yeah, she has been my whole life.
I understand, but...
But if I'd known, I would never...
- But we're in love, so...
- Yes.
And I'm so thrilled. Congratulations.
Thank you, and I'm
pleased you graduated.
That was what you wanted, right?
So, er... congratulations to you too.
Thanks.
- OK, this is weird.
- No, it's not.
It's the opposite of weird,
it's totally 'unweird'.
- We gotta tell her.
- No.
OK, maybe it is a bit weird.
But just because it's weird for us doesn't
mean it needs to be weird for Mads.
- I don't wanna keep secrets from her.
- She's my sister.
She means everything to me. If anyone
deserves to be happy, it's her.
So let's just forget it
ever happened, please,
and keep out of each other's way.
- There you are.
- (BOTH) Hey!
- Getting to know each other already?
- Yeah.
Great, because I have a few wedding-y
things I need you to do for me tomorrow,
like help Raf sort out his suit,
make sure he looks gorgeous for me.
You'll get on like a house on fire.
So much for you to talk about!
Whoop! Whoo!
Hey, guys, I'm coming!
I thought you wanted
to kite-surf the world.
We are. The honeymoon.
Oh, funny. Maddie always
said she wanted Paris.
Would you like to try them on?
Oh, no, no, no.
I'm not the bride, I'm...
It's someone else that
he's marrying. I'm no one.
I'm just a friend. I mean,
the sister of the bride.
I guess what people want can change.
Perfect.
I didn't change, Raf. I just couldn't
drop everything and run off...
- into the sunset with you.
- Yeah, I know. Your "real life", right?
- How's that working out for you now?
- Great!
Cool.
Are you seeing anyone?
- I don't wanna talk about it.
- Oh, sorry.
Why are you sorry?
Well, that's a no, isn't it?
No, actually, it's not necessarily a no.
I just don't wanna talk about it.
I think that sort of thing is private and
doesn't need to be sung from the rooftops.
I forgot. Never say
what you feel, right?
I just don't see why people have to make
such a spectacle of their feelings.
Because if someone sings
it from the rooftops,
you know that they really mean it,
and that's what weddings are all about.
- Buongiorno.
- (SHOP ASSISTANT) Buongiorno.
What do you want me to do,
Taylor? Become a monk?
I don't know, maybe not
fall in love with my sister?
But how could I know she was your sister?
I never met two people less like each other.
What's that supposed to mean?
- Ciao.
- Salve.
(SPEAKS ITALIAN)
You're the one who broke it off,
and you forgot all about me!
I didn't forget about you,
I was working on my degree.
Whatever.
And, anyway, I'm not the one who spends all
his days on the beach with hot girls in bikinis.
Come on! You know I
wasn't interested in them.
I was waiting for you to
come back, like you said,
but then I realised you weren't,
and then I met Maddie,
and she was so open,
so positive, so full of life.
Full of life?
So I'm not full of life?
But... maybe you are,
but how would anyone know?
We shouldn't be listening to this.
Come on, let's go.
"Don't make a spectacle
of your feelings."
Maddie made me happy again, OK?
She brought me back to life.
How many times do I have to
say how happy I am for you?
- Why are you so angry?
- I'm not angry!
(SPEAKS ITALIAN)
I think we're done.
(GASPS)
Oh! Doug!
Oh, you do miss me.
What are you doing here?
I'm hereto rescue you from making
the worst mistake of your life.
That is so sweet.
Only you were the worst
mistake of my life, so...
Mads, Mads, Mads, Mads, come on!
I know we've had our ups and downs,
but that's all part of our thing, isn't it?
It's a ride. It's a great,
fun, sexy rollercoaster.
All right, maybe we've had a big
down these last few months.
You dumped me!
That just means we're due for
a big up. Know what I'm saying?
Bobcat...
Doug, I don't want your great,
big, sexy... ride anymore.
I want to get off.
I should never have let
you go, Madison Jones.
Hmm...
I messed up. I'm man
enough to admit that.
Oh, this again!
Come on, we are incredible together.
You know that.
Just go!
One more chance.
Come on, you owe me that.
I don't owe you anything,
except maybe a smack.
How can you say that?
(♪ "DON'T YOU WANT ME")
♪ You were working as
a waitress in a cocktail bar
♪ When I met you
♪ I picked you out, I shook you up,
and turned you around
♪ Turned you into someone new
♪ Now five years later on you've
got the world at your feet
♪ Success has been so easy for you
♪ But don't forget it's me who
put you where you are now...
- Sorry!
- ♪ And I can put you back down too
- ♪ Don't, don't you want me?
- This is why I don't want to see you.
♪ You know I can't believe it when
I hear that you won't see me
♪ Don't, don't you want me?
The idea that I can't
survive without you!
♪ You know I don't believe you when
you say that you don't need me
♪ It's much too late to find you
think you've changed your mind
♪ You'd better change it back
or we will both be sorry
♪ Don't you want me, baby?
♪ Don't you want me, oh?
♪ I was working as a
waitress in a cocktail bar
♪ That much is true
♪ But even then I knew I'd
find a much better place
♪ Either with or without you
♪ The five years we have had
have been such good times
♪ I still love you
♪ But now I think it's time
I lived my life as my own
♪ I guess it's just what I must do
♪ Don't, don't you want me?
♪ You know I can't believe it
when I hear that you won't see me
♪ Don't, don't you want me?
♪ You know I don't believe you when
you say that you don't need me
♪ It's much too late to find you
think you've changed your mind
♪ You'd better change it back
or we will both be sorry
♪ Don't you want me, baby?
♪ Don't you want me, oh?
♪ Don't you want me, oh? ♪
Which part of "I don't want you"
don't you understand?
The don't.
I've been out with some jerks in my time,
but you are in a class of your own.
Oh, thank you!
Why did I put up with it for so long?
The hope, I suppose, that some day you'd
be the one who'd go down on one knee.
Certainly tried every other position.
Just... leave me alone!
All right, I get it.
Had to try, right?
I'll go.
On one condition:
have dinner with me tonight.
- It's my hen night.
- We'll do it early, very low-key.
- No.
- Come on.
If those five years meant
anything to you, one last meal.
I can wish you well,
show you there's no hard feeling.
And then you'll go?
On my honour.
(SCOFFS)
(SIGHS)
OK.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(SCOFFS)
- What's he doing here?
- Lil...
Oh, you're such a good friend to Maddie. She
always looks so great standing next to you.
And you were always such
a good boyfriend to her,
because she always looked so
young standing next to you.
He's just leaving.
See you tonight... love monkey.
- Tonight?
- It's under control.
It's never under control with Doug.
He's your kryptonite.
And he's a dick.
Hmm...
Mmm...
Aah...
Yeah...
(ELENA) It was horrible hearing
Raf and Taylor fight like that.
They used to be so close.
Is he still hurt that
she didn't come back?
Or is it the stress of us having to
pretend we don't know Taylor?
Or maybe it's just all the
stress of the wedding.
Yeah, could be.
Or could it be that they were
both body-snatched by aliens
and are planning to
take over the universe?
Whatever you think, amore.
Whoa!
I love it when you give
me your attention.
Argh!
(MIKEY)
Outrageous! Wanna play, do ya?
What's your problem?
My problem is that I hate lying and
I'm terrible at keeping secrets.
Ooh, what's the secret?
Er...
I'm pregnant.
Oh, my God! That's amazing.
You're happy, right?
Yeah, yeah, it's just really early days
and we're trying to keep it a secret.
Oh, yeah, of course.
Oh, but, wow!
And you, are you excited?
Still taking it in, really.
God, you guys are gonna make
the most amazing parents.
What you gonna do?
Ow! Please don't! Stop it, woman!
How did you get on?
- It was great.
- Really, really well.
So, Taylor, is there someone you'd
like to invite to the wedding?
How do you mean?
Well, like a plus one.
Oh, no.
Well, what about the guy
from three years ago?
What guy?
Oh, that guy?
Er... no, forget about him.
That guy, he's, er... he's gone.
- I'll go for a swim, hmm?
- OK.
Gone? Gone where?
Just... gone, OK?
Well, does he know how you feel?
If you want someone,
you have to follow your heart.
It might not be part of the plan but you can't
just do nothing, you have to tell them.
(TAYLOR) He moved on. Please.
- Oh, I'm sorry, hon.
- Why? Don't be sorry.
Well, it would be nice for
you to have someone there.
I'm not you. I'm fine by myself.
- No one is fine by themselves.
- Yes, Maddie. You should try it sometime.
Permesso...
I got flowers for Madison Jones.
Oh, gorgeous! Raf knows me so well.
Oh, I love pink roses.
"Looking forward to seeing
you tonight, Doug."
What's he doing here?
He just turned up out of
the blue and hijacked me.
It's just a final farewell.
Well, slamming the door in
his face said it perfectly.
Well, it's nicer this way. Grazie.
- What are you doing?
- Don't worry, I can look after myself.
When? When have you ever
been able to look after yourself?
Like, all the time.
Yes, I'm out there, and yes,
sometimes I make mistakes.
You think?
I know, Taylor, OK?
But I live with those mistakes,
and I don't expect anyone
else to sort them out for me.
It's better than locking your heart
away, too scared of getting hurt.
I've lived with your mistakes.
Where do you think I've been
for the past five years?
And three years before that?
And 18 months before that?
Did it ever occur to you that maybe the
reason I'm not all over guys all the time
is because I've seen what a fool you've
made of yourself again and again and again?
Well, I'd rather be like
that than the other way.
And if I've made you afraid of
opening yourself up to love,
then I'm truly sorry.
Is that my necklace?
Just get off my stuff, OK?
OK, ladies, break it up. Time to go.
- Go where?
- The tomato festival.
- I'm not in the mood.
- That's why you're coming.
Oh, I wish I could, but I have a
team of brilliant people coming
to pluck, wax and tint me
to within an inch of my life.
Well, you're excused.
You're not.
I like tomatoes, I really do.
But a whole festival? It sounds lame.
(♪ "WALKING ON SUNSHINE")
♪ Ow
♪ Ha
♪ Mmm, yeah
♪ I used to think maybe you loved me,
now, baby, I'm sure
♪ And I just can't wait till the day
when you knock on my door
♪ Now every time I go for the
mailbox, gotta hold myself down
♪ Cos I just can't wait till you
write me you're coming around
♪ I'm walking on sunshine, whoa-oh
♪ And don't it feel good?
- ♪ Hey
- ♪ All right now
♪ And don't it feel good?
♪ I used to think maybe you loved me,
now I know that it's true
♪ But I don't wanna spend my
whole life just awaiting for you
- ♪ And I don't want you back for the weekend
- ♪ Not back for a day
♪ Oh, no, no
♪ I said, "Baby, I just want you
back and I want you to stay"
♪ I'm walking on sunshine, whoa-oh
♪ And don't it feel good?
♪ Hey, are you all right now?
♪ Yeah, oh, yeah, now
♪ And don't it feel good?
♪ Walking on sunshine
♪ I feel alive, I feel the love,
I feel the love that's really real
♪ I'm on sunshine, baby, oh
♪ I'm walking on sunshine, baby, oh
♪ I'm walking on sunshine, whoa-oh
♪ And don't it feel good?
♪ Hey, all right, now
♪ I'll say, I'll say, I'll say,
I'll say, I'll say it again now
I'll say, I'll say it again
♪ And don't, and don't, and don't,
and don't, and don't it feel good?
♪ Sunshine
♪ Don't it feel good now? ♪
(SIGHS)
Is that it?
We gotta get clean
before it dries. Come on.
Where?
Oh!
(SIGHS)
Low-key?
You deserve a decent send-off.
You look stunning.
Well, I'm in love.
But then you always look stunning.
Ah, my favourite.
To... new beginnings.
Now, that I will drink to.
Remember the first time we
opened a bottle of this?
We stayed up all night,
watched the sun come up.
You said you could listen
to my voice forever.
No, I probably said it felt like I'd
been listening to your voice forever.
And, if I remember rightly,
you only ever talked about yourself.
No, I don't believe that, baby kitten.
I'm sure you talked about me too.
Oh, God... what am I doing here?
Right.
Come home.
No, here. I'm getting
married in the morning.
Sounds like you're trying
to convince yourself.
No, I'm trying to get it
into your thick head.
Fine, fine. You want to get
back at me. I understand that.
But don't mess things up for yourself
and this poor kid in the process.
Doug, believe it or not,
not everything is about you.
Oh, please! You're only
doing this to punish me.
No, I came here to find myself.
And I did.
In Raf.
I'd like to find myself... in you.
Oh, God...
Come on, Mads. Five minutes
you've known this guy.
Five weeks, and he's got to know me
better than you did in five years.
Do you know why?
You didn't let him do
that thing I wanted?
Oh, you filthy little squirrel.
- He listens to me.
- I listen to you.
- Oh, please, you don't let me...
- I love listening to you.
I... I love listening to...
...those sweet little sighs
you make in your sleep.
That crazy singing of
yours in the shower.
That noise you made that
night at the George Cinq.
I think the whole of
Paris heard that.
It was a wonderful night.
And this is... It's wonderful.
This stuff you're
great at, the chase.
It's the follow-through
that lets you down.
And I wanted more, Doug.
I wanted marriage.
We were perfect as we were.
Why spoil it?
No, do you know what's perfect?
We never have to have this conversation ever
again because I've found true happiness.
That kid will never be
man enough for you.
Raf is young, yeah,
but he's a grown-up.
- You're not young, but you're a child.
- Thank you.
No, that wasn't a... God,
you don't even want to grow up.
- The thing about Peter Pan is...
- He can fly.
(SIGHS)
He ends up alone.
It's beautiful.
(♪ "ETERNAL FLAME")
♪ Close your eyes,
give me your hand, darling
♪ Do you feel my heart beating?
Do you understand?
♪ Do you feel the same?
♪ Am I only dreaming?
♪ Is this burning an eternal flame?
♪ I believe it's meant to be, darling
♪ I watch you when you are sleeping
You belong with me
♪ Do you feel the same?
♪ Am I only dreaming?
♪ Or is this burning
an eternal flame?
♪ Say my name, the sun
shines through the rain
♪ A whole life so lonely,
then you come and ease the pain
♪ I don't wanna lose this feeling
♪ Oh
♪ (CHOIR) Close your eyes,
give me your hand, darling
♪ Do you feel my heart beating?
Do you understand?
♪ Do you feel the same?
♪ Am I only dreaming?
♪ Do you understand?
Do you feel the same?
♪ Am I only dreaming? ♪
I need to know.
(TAYLOR) You can't be here.
- Something happened back there.
- No!
- Tell the truth.
- Truth about what?
Surprise!
Oh, God, it's him!
He was the guy. She's the ex?
Mads, I'm so sorry.
It's all my fault.
- Yeah, but I-I... I can explain.
- Please, I can do this.
He was the guy, a guy.
And I didn't want to tell
you because it was nothing.
But then you just kept going on at
me about how I never let anyone in
and I started thinking,
"Did I make a terrible mistake?"
And then we were on the beach, all covered
in tomatoes, and there was this sunset
and suddenly it was three years ago
and I looked into his eyes and I knew...
I don't feel anything for him.
I never did.
He's been desperate to tell you because
he doesn't want to keep secrets from you.
But I didn't want you to know because
I didn't want to spoil everything and...
...well, you always make such a
huge drama out of everything,
which is why you two
are so perfect together.
But now I'm the one who's ended up
making a huge drama out of nothing.
I know I've been a
really shit sister.
And I'm so, so sorry.
Is this true?
Yes.
And do you still have
feelings for her?
No, I feel absolutely
nothing for her.
(SIGHS)
I'm so sorry.
(LIL CLEARS HER THROAT)
Hen night?
As in girls only.
As in we don't wanna see
you again until the church.
I should probably just go.
Yeah.
Well, what are you waiting for?
It's my hen party already.
You look like shit.
Go and get changed.
Are you sure you want me there?
Don't be stupid, T.
We all make mistakes.
Oh, yes! And tonight I intend
to make a whole lot more.
(♪ "GIRLS JUST WANT TO
HAVE FUN"/ "WILD BOYS")
♪ I come home in the morning light
♪ My mother says, "When you
gonna live your life right?"
♪ Oh, Mummy dear,
we're not the fortunate ones
♪ And girls, they wanna have fun
♪ Oh, girls just wanna have fun
♪ The phone rings in the
middle of the night
- ♪ Your father yells
- ♪ "What you gonna do with your life?"
♪ Oh, Daddy dear,
you know you're still number one
♪ But girls, they wanna have fun
♪ Oh, girls just wanna have
♪ That's all they really want
♪ Some fun
♪ When the working day is done
♪ Oh, girls, they wanna have fun
♪ Oh, girls just wanna have...
♪ Wild boys, wild boys
♪ Wild boys...
♪ Girls, they wanna
♪ Wanna have fun...
♪ Boys...
♪ Wanna have, girls, they wanna
♪ Wanna have fun
♪ Girls, wanna have
♪ Some boys take a beautiful girl
♪ And hide her away from
the rest of the world
♪ I wanna be the one
to walk in the sun
♪ Girls, they wanna have fun
♪ Oh, girls just wanna have
♪ That's all they really want
♪ Some fun
♪ When the working day is done
♪ Oh, girls, they wanna have fun
♪ Oh, girls just wanna have...
♪ Wild boys fallen far from glory
♪ Breathless sense of hunger,
on the razor's edge you trail
♪ Because there's
murder by the roadside
♪ In a sore, afraid new world
♪ They tried to break us
♪ Looks like they'll try again
- ♪ Wild boys
- ♪ (CHOIR) Wild boys
♪ Never losing
- ♪ Wild boys
- ♪ (CHOIR) Wild boys
♪ Never chose this way
- ♪ Wild boys
- ♪ (CHOIR) Wild boys
♪ Never close your eyes
♪ Wild boys always
♪ Shine
♪ (MIKEY) Wild boys always shine ♪
- Hey! You all right?
- Yeah.
- What's up, mate?
- Huh?
Just can't wait for the
wedding to be over.
Just wanna be married already.
- You got a whole lifetime of that, fratello.
- I know.
Enjoy your last night
of liberty, eh? Come on!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Do you, er...
Do you wanna talk about it?
About what?
Look... is this about Taylor?
I've got to ask...
- Have you still got feelings for her?
- No, that would be really stupid. No.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Allora...
Can we duct-tape you
to a pole now, please?
- Yeah?
- In a minute.
(♪ "IT MUST HAVE BEEN LOVE")
♪ (CHOIR) It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ Lay a whisper on my pillow
♪ Leave the winter on the ground
♪ I wake up lonely,
the stare of silence
♪ In the bedroom, all around
♪ Touch me now, I close my eyes
♪ And dream away
♪ It must have been love,
but it's over now
♪ It must have been good,
but I lost it somehow
♪ It must have been love,
but it's over now
♪ From the moment we touched
till the time it ran out
♪ Make-believing we're together
♪ That I'm sheltered by your heart
♪ But in and outside
I turned to water
♪ Like a teardrop in your palm
♪ And it's a hard winter's day
♪ I dream away
- ♪ It must have been love
- ♪ (CHOIR) It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ It was all that I wanted,
now I'm living without
- ♪ It must have been love
- ♪ (CHOIR) It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ It's where the water flows
♪ It's where the wind blows...
(LAUGHING)
- ♪ It must have been love
- ♪ (CHOIR) It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ It must have been good,
but I lost it somehow
- ♪ It must have been love
- ♪ (CHOIR) It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ From the moment we
touched till the time it ran out
- ♪ It must have been love
- ♪ (CHOIR) It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ It was all that I wanted,
now I'm living without
- ♪ It must have been love
- ♪ (CHOIR) It must have been love
♪ But it's over now
♪ It's where the water flows
♪ It's where the wind blows ♪
(RIPPING)
Oh...
You shouldn't be here.
I'm not. You're dreaming.
I'm getting married in the morning.
And I couldn't be happier
for you, really.
Really?
That's what I came to say.
You have my blessing.
Oh... Doug, that's so sweet.
Aah!
- No, no, no!
- What?
What, you think I've
come here for...?
(DOUG SCOFFS)
Although...
...it is your last night
as a single woman.
You could call this my...
wedding gift to you.
Just get us a toaster!
Out!
(♪ "FAITH")
♪ Well, I guess it would be nice
if I could touch your body
♪ I know not everybody
has got a body like you
♪ But I gotta think twice
before I give my heart away
♪ And I know all the games you play,
because I play them too
♪ Oh, but I need some time
off from that emotion
♪ Time to pick my heart
up off the floor
♪ Oh, when that love comes
down without devotion
♪ Well it takes a strong man, baby,
but I'm showing you the door
♪ Cos I gotta have faith
♪ I gotta have faith
♪ Yes, I gotta have faith,
the faith, the faith
♪ I gotta have faith,
♪ Baby, I know you're
asking me to stay
♪ Stay, please, please,
please, don't go away
♪ You say I'm giving you the blues
♪ Maybe you mean every word you say
♪ Can't help but think of yesterday
♪ And another who tied me
down to loverboy rules
♪ Before this river becomes an ocean
♪ Before you throw my
heart back on the floor
- ♪ Oh, baby, just reconsider
- ♪ Your foolish notion
♪ Well, I need someone to hold me,
but I'll wait for something more
♪ Yes, you gotta have faith
♪ I gotta have faith
♪ Yes, I gotta have faith,
the faith, the faith
♪ I gotta have faith,
the faith, the faith...
Ow!
♪ Before this river becomes an ocean
♪ Before you throw my
heart back on the floor
♪ Oh, baby, I'll reconsider
my foolish notion
♪ Well, I need someone to hold me,
but I'll wait for something more
♪ Guess I gotta have faith
♪ I gotta have faith
♪ Yes, I gotta have faith,
the faith, the faith
♪ I gotta have faith,
the faith, the faith ♪
(SIGHS)
(PA) Last call for departure flight 2901 to
London, immediately boarding at Gate 3.
This plane... Onward... Whoa!
Stop, stop.
Doors to manual, emergency.
Hey...
Ciao, bello.
You are in love with him.
Oh, T...
(SIGHS)
I've made a... small fortune
writing books about love.
I feel like I should have
some wisdom to impart.
All I can think is 50
different ways to say orgasm.
Everything I know about real love
I've learnt from you and Maddie.
You know, you've got me
through some really tough times,
and I know you two have
had it tougher than most.
But we've always got
through it together.
We've always had each
other, haven't we?
When your mum died... Maddie told
me that what really broke her heart
was that your mum would
never be at your wedding day.
You've done the hard part now.
Don't you wanna be there for her?
Well, how long have we got?
Shit!
(♪ "WHITE WEDDING")
♪ Hey, little sister,
what have you done?
who's the only one?
♪ Hey, little sister,
who's your superman?
who's the one you want?
♪ Hey, little sister, shotgun
♪ It's a nice day to start again
♪ It's a nice day for a white wedding
- ♪ Hey, little sister
- ♪ Who is it you're with?
- ♪ What's your vice or wish?
- ♪ Hey, little sister, shotgun
- ♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Hey, little sister,
who's your superman?
♪ Hey, little sister, shot...
♪ It's a nice day to start again
- ♪ It's a nice day for a...
- ♪ White wedding
♪ It's a nice day to start again
♪ It's a nice day for a white wedding
♪ It's a nice day for
a white wedding...
Where have you been? Where's Raf?
♪ It's a nice day for a white wedding
♪ It's a nice day to start again ♪
- Where have you been?
- It's my fault.
She had to stop me from performing
an ill-advised aviation stunt,
which is never a good idea after
12 sambucas and a minestrone.
You look beautiful. Just one sec.
(BELLS CHIME)
(SIGHS)
You look beautiful.
Taylor, am I making a
fool of myself again?
Raf's not like those other guys.
He's a keeper. You done good.
And what about you?
Are you... really OK with this?
Come on.
Maddie.
No matter what,
you've never given up on love.
You followed your heart
wherever it leads.
That's how I wanna be.
Christ, don't make me cry now!
I know it's out there for you.
You just have to grab
it when you see it, OK?
- Oh, where's your dress?
- Sorry...
Er... it's not the only
thing that's missing.
Er...
- My thong has gone!
- What?
This is news?
Right. Are we ready?
(MOUTHS) Yeah.
- OK.
- Yes.
You all right, ragazzo.
You look a bit perduto.
No, I'm fine.
I was just running naked down the
street missing my own wedding
cos some idiot left me duct-taped
to a tree with a donkey.
Ah, the donkey!
Please everyone be seated.
Welcome everyone to the wedding
of Madison and Raffaele.
Before we proceed,
I'm obliged to ask...
Does anyone know of any
just cause or impediment
why these two should not be wed?
Oh, sit down, Doug.
- Oh, I think I'm gonna throw up.
- He has that effect on everyone.
Let me ask again
if anyone knows a cause why
these two should not be wed.
Well?
(MADDIE) Wait.
Raf...
Oh...
All my life I've gone from
wrong guy to wrong guy
and now, finally, to have
found a guy who's right...
...who's kind and decent and...
...beautiful inside and out.
Because... you are the right guy.
But it's not right.
Not for me.
I came here to find
myself and I found you.
This is the same thing I always do:
running off into the arms
of a man and losing myself.
Er... it's incredible to me that someone
as amazing as you wants to marry me.
How could I not get
caught up in that?
The big church wedding, this...
It's everything I've ever dreamed of.
Until now.
I'm in love with love.
But am I in love with you?
I don't think that I am.
I'm so sorry.
You deserve to be
loved wholeheartedly.
♪ If I could turn back time
♪ If I could find a way...
(WHISPERS)
♪ I'd take back those
words that have hurt you
♪ And you'd stay
♪ I don't know why
I did the things I did
I said the things I said
♪ Pride's like a knife,
it can cut deep inside
♪ Words are like weapons,
they wound sometimes
(♪ "IF I COULD TURN
BACK TIME" MUSIC STARTS)
♪ I didn't really mean to hurt you
♪ I didn't wanna let you go,
I know I made you cry
♪ But, baby, if I
could turn back time
♪ If I could find a way
♪ I'd take back those
words that have hurt you
♪ And you'd stay
♪ If I could reach the stars
♪ I'd give them all to you
♪ And you'd love me, love me,
like you used to do
♪ If I could turn back time
♪ My world was shattered
and I was torn apart
♪ You took a knife and
drove it deep in my heart
♪ You walked out that door,
I swore that I didn't care
♪ But I'd lost everything,
darling, then and there
♪ Too strong to tell you I was sorry
♪ Too proud to tell you I was wrong,
I know that I was blind
♪ And, darling, if I
could turn back time
♪ If I could find a way
♪ I'd take back those
words that have hurt you
♪ And you'd stay
♪ If I could reach the stars
♪ I'd give them all to you
♪ And you'd love me, love me,
like you used to do
♪ If I could turn back time
♪ If I could find a way
♪ I'd take back those
words that have hurt you
♪ And you'd stay
♪ If I could turn back time...
Turn back time.
♪ If I could find a way...
Find a way.
♪ I'd take back those
words that have hurt you
♪ And you'd stay
♪ If I could reach the stars
♪ I'd give them all to you
- ♪ And you'd love me
- ♪ I'd love you
♪ Like I used to do
♪ (CHOIR) Turn back time...
I love you.
♪ (CHOIR) Find a way
♪ Aah-aah-aah-aah ♪
(BELLS CHIME)
Ah, shake, shake, shake.
Shake, shake, shake, shake.
Amore.
You don't have to pretend
to be pregnant anymore.
- I'm a terrible liar.
- No, my love, you did great.
No.
I'm a terrible liar.
Whoa!
- You're gonna be a papa'.
- But... no, wait, wait, wait!
Weddings, eh? Get everyone
going, don't they?
Do you, er... do you
fancy a cocktail?
No, I'll have a beer, thanks.
Goes better with fish and chips.
(SIGHS)
Mmm...
(TAYLOR) Are you gonna
be all right on your own?
I'm not on my own.
I've got you... and the
best friends in the world.
- Lady cuddle?
- (BOTH) Lady cuddle.
- Oh...
- Ah! Oh, here we go.
The things you do to
keep me interested.
Well, it worked.
(BUCKLE FASTENING)
I don't wanna risk losing you again.
You want to be Peter Pan.
I can help you with that.
(BUCKLE FASTENING)
(CHUCKLES)
What? Never grow up?
(CONTINUES CHUCKLING)
Fly!
(BUCKLE FASTENING)
Whoa!
(SCREAMS)
(♪ "WAKE ME UP BEFORE YOU GO-GO")
- (LIL) Bye!
- (TAYLOR) Later!
♪ Jitterbug
♪ You put the boom-boom
into my heart
♪ You send my soul sky high
when your loving starts
♪ Jitterbug into my brain
♪ Goes a bang-bang-bang
till my feet do the same
♪ But something's bugging you,
something ain't right
♪ My best friend told me
what you did last night
♪ Left me sleeping in my bed
♪ I was dreaming but I should
have been with you instead
♪ Wake me up before you go-go
♪ Don't leave me hanging
on like a yo-yo
♪ Wake me up before you go-go
♪ I don't wanna miss it
when you hit that high
♪ Wake me up before you go-go
♪ Cos I'm not planning on going solo
♪ Take me dancing tonight
♪ I wanna hit that high
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah
♪ You take the grey
skies out of my way
♪ You make the sun shine
brighter than Doris Day
♪ Turned a bright spark into a flame
♪ My beats per minute
never been the same
♪ You're my lady, I'm your fool
♪ It makes me crazy
when you act so cruel
♪ Come on, baby, let's not fight
♪ We'll go dancing,
everything will be all right
♪ Wake me up before you go-go
♪ Don't leave me hanging
on like a yo-yo
♪ Wake me up before you go-go
♪ I don't wanna miss it
when you hit that high
♪ Wake me up before you go-go
♪ Cos I'm not planning on going solo
♪ Take me dancing tonight
♪ I wanna hit that high
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah
♪ Cuddle up, baby, move in tight
♪ We'll go dancing tomorrow night
♪ It's cold out here,
but it's warm in bed
♪ They can dance,
we'll stay home instead
♪ Take me dancing tonight ♪
(SCREAMS)
(♪ "WALKING ON SUNSHINE")
♪ (LIL) Ow
♪ (MIKEY) Ha
♪ (ENRICO) Mmm, yeah
♪ (ELENA) I used to think maybe
you loved me, now, baby, I'm sure
♪ (LIL) And I just can't wait till
the day when you knock on my door
♪ (MIKEY) Now every time I go for
the mailbox, gotta hold myself down
♪ (ENRICO) Cos I just can't wait till
you write me you're coming around
♪ (ELENA)
I'm walking on sunshine, whoa-oh
♪ (ENRICO)
♪ (RAF)
I'm walking on sunshine, whoa-oh
♪ (ALL) And don't it feel good?
- ♪ (TAYLOR) Hey
- ♪ (RAF) All right now
♪ And don't it feel good?
♪ (TAYLOR) I used to think maybe you
loved me, now I know that it's true
♪ (RAF) But I don't wanna spend my
whole life just awaiting for you
♪ (TAYLOR) And I don't want
you back for the weekend
- ♪ (RAF) Not back for a day
- ♪ (ALL) Oh, no, no
♪ I said, "Baby, I just want you
back and I want you to stay"
♪ I'm walking on sunshine, whoa-oh
♪ (MIKEY) And don't it feel good?
♪ (LIL) Hey, are you all right now?
♪ (LIL) Yeah, oh, yeah, now
♪ And don't it feel good?
♪ (ALL) Walking on sunshine
♪ Walking on sunshine
♪ (TAYLOR) I feel alive, I feel the love,
I feel the love that's really real
♪ (RAF) I feel alive, I feel the love,
♪ (TAYLOR) I'm on sunshine, baby, oh
♪ I'm walking on sunshine, baby, oh
♪ (ENRICO)
I'm walking on sunshine, whoa-oh
♪ (ELENA)
♪ (ALL)
I'm walking on sunshine, whoa-oh
♪ And don't it feel good?
♪ Hey, all right, now
♪ I'll say, I'll say, I'll say,
I'll say, I'll say it again now
I'll say, I'll say it again
♪ (ELENA) And don't, and don't, and don't,
and don't, and don't it feel good?
♪ (ALL) And don't, and don't, and don't,
♪ (ELENA) Sunshine
♪ (ENRICO) Don't it feel good now? ♪
Subtitling by Motion
Picture Solutions