ANNIE: (BREATHING HEAVILY) I'm so...
I'm so glad you called.
TED: I'm so glad
you were free.
ANNIE: God,
I love your eyes.
Okay, now what?
TED: Cup my balls.
ANNIE: Okay, yes.
All right. I can do that.
TED: Oh! There it is.
ANNIE: There we go.
(MOANING)
That feels good.
You know what to do.
(LAUGHING)
Okay, you know what?
Slow it down, slow it down.
Okay.
Slow it down.
There we go.
How's that?
That's good, nice and slow.
See? Doesn't that feel good?
Yeah.
No, I want to go fast.
You want to go fast?
Fast.
(GRUNTING)
Yeah. No...
Oh, yeah.
That feels good.
Oh, Yeah.
Yeah.
(MOANING LOUDLY)
Okay. You know what?
I think...
I think maybe we are on
different rhythms here.
(PANTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHING)
(GASPS)
I was having a nightmare.
I was so scared.
(CHUCKLING)
Good morning.
You look beautiful.
No, I'm sure
I look terrible.
I just woke up.
Are you kidding?
I'm sure I'm a mess.
(CHUCKLES)
You slept over.
I did.
I thought we had
a rule against that.
Oh.
I'm kidding.
Oh. (LAUGHS)
That was funny.
I'm kidding.
You're funny
in the morning.
I like hanging out with you.
Oh. Yeah.
I love hanging out with you.
I think we get along really well
and you're so sexy.
I know.
I just have a lot
coming up at work
and I don't want to make
promises I can't keep.
You know what I mean?
I know you do.
Yeah.
We're on the same page.
I'm not looking for a relationship
right now, either. Let's just say that.
Whatever you wanna...
I can do...
I'd rather just... I like simple...
I'm not like other girls.
I'm not like, "Be my boyfriend!"
Unless you were like, "Yeah!"
Then I'd be like,
"Maybe." (CHUCKLES)
Mmm. But let's not.
I don't want that either.
Wow, this is so awkward.
I really want you to leave,
but I don't know how to say it
without sounding like a dick.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Come on! Hands behind your heads!
Let's go! Sit-ups!
You're looking like pieces
of bacon on a plate.
It's disgusting!
I smell the fat!
(GROANING) He scares me.
(GRUNTING) Me, too.
LILLIAN: But he's
an excellent motivator.
That's true.
What are you looking at?
Oh, Shit, he sees us.
Oh, God.
Hey! Hey!
If you want to
take this class,
you're going to
have to pay for it
like the rest
of these bitches!
What, are you dancing?
In the park... Dance class?
You are not dancing.
You are not dancing in the park!
Go, go, go, go!
INSTRUCTOR: Freeloaders!
I'm coming over there.
Is he coming?
INSTRUCTOR: I'm coming after you!
Sorry, Rodney.
We're on a budget.
INSTRUCTOR: Oh, come on!
It's only 12 bucks!
Oh, my God!
Come on!
You fucking freeloaders.
We are out of our minds.
I know.
That's okay.
I'm so glad that we got to do this.
I feel like I haven't
seen you in forever.
Mmm. I've been
in Chicago a lot.
I know.
Sleeping at Dougie's house.
Well, it's just
closer to work.
How is it going
with him anyway?
I don't know.
I mean, it's fine,
but I just feel like
he's been distant lately.
And I don't know...
He calls me
"dude" a lot.
That doesn't mean anything.
I think everything is fine.
I don't know.
Anyway,
what did you
do last night?
Umm...
What did you
do last night?
(GASPS)
You are not
telling me something.
I hung out with
Ted for a little bit.
I knew it!
We had fun.
It was fun.
Here's what I don't like about it.
You hate yourself after you see him,
every time.
And then we go through this,
and then you feel like shit,
and it's almost
like you're doing it
because you feel
bad about yourself.
He called me late,
and we hung out.
It wasn't a big deal.
And you know what? It was fun.
Ew! You had
sex with him.
We had an
adult sleepover.
Ooh. Did you let him
sleep over in your mouth?
Annie!
I'm sorry!
You're unbelievable.
He kept putting it near my face.
They do that,
don't they?
Why do they do that?
Let us offer.
If we don't offer...
Please.
You're supposed to slap it away.
I couldn't.
You don't want to
look right at it.
No.
It's too aggressive.
It's like...
"Hello."
That's my impression.
Those are the balls?
Yeah.
I'm trying to make it round,
but I can't
because I have elbows.
He is so hot, though.
Look, I know you say he's
cute and all that stuff,
but it makes you feel
like shit, you know?
You're a total catch,
and any guy
would be psyched
to be your man.
You should just
make room
for somebody who
is nice to you.
You know what?
He's honest!
He told me that
we are what we are
and we're just having fun.
And I like that.
He also told you that you need
dental work. He's an asshole.
I don't need dental work.
You're right.
There is nothing
wrong with my teeth.
You are so beautiful.
Will you marry me?
Yes.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
I love you.
I don't want to go to work today.
Mmm-mmm.
Let's see how many
times Terry's called me.
Oh! Only 15!
You know what, Terry?
I don't want
to pick up your monkey lamps.
Sorry!
Monkey lamps?
Ugh. I cannot wait to never
work for a psychopath again.
Oh! Annie!
I'm sorry. I should
have gone down Mason.
ANNIE: Well, I'm the genius that
opened a bakery during the recession.
They were good cakes,
Annie.
Thank you.
Come on. Look away,
look away, look away.
Do you have any
ideas of styles?
Oh, I don't know.
What do you think, honey?
Whatever you want.
Look at how you guys are
making this decision together.
That's sweet. You guys
love each other, huh?
Yeah.
Ohh! That's sweet.
That will go away.
(CHUCKLES)
(WHISPERING) You cannot
trust anybody, ever.
Especially someone you're
in a relationship with.
'Cause they're living with you,
you don't
know who you're sleeping next to.
It is scary.
I mean, look at him.
He may not even be Asian.
It is scary.
So did you guys want to look
at these engagement rings?
We're going to browse.
Okay, sure.
I'll be here.
Thank you.
What was that about?
Umm, nothing. They had to run.
They had to go somewhere.
And no wonder.
You're selling lifelong happiness.
You're not telling everyone
about your problems
and how your
boyfriend left you,
and maybe marriage
will work out.
Show me your
"love is eternal" face.
No, that's two years,
four years tops. That is not eternal.
Kahlua, can you come over
here for a second, please?
What's up, Don-Don?
You make up
the best nicknames.
You don't need a nickname
because Kahlua is so delicious.
Don't sue me
for touching you.
Show Annie your
"love is eternal" face.
That looks like you
have menstrual cramps.
Thank you so much,
Kahlua.
Now, why can't you
be more like Kahlua?
Look, I'm trying
really hard.
You've just
got to try harder.
The whole reason you
have got this job, Annie,
is because your mom is my sponsor in AA,
and I'm doing her a favor.
I understand.
Oscar, get back to work.
You shouldn't be
behind the counter.
MAN ON TV: Andrew,
you are not the father!
(WHOOPING ON TV)
(BRYNN GIGGLING)
That's great. Yeah.
Stop that. Don't do that.
(DOOR OPENING)
Hey, Brynn.
Oh, hey, roomie.
Guess what happened to me today.
Hmm. What?
I got a free tattoo.
You did what?
I could not believe it.
The guy said, "Do you want a tattoo?"
Just a random...
Yeah, opened up the side of his van.
No.
He said, "It's for free!"
And I said, "Sure."
You said yes?
Yeah!
Yeah. Look.
See here?
What is it?
See that?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, Brynn!
It's a Mexican drinking worm.
It's a Native American
symbol meaning "wasted."
Okay, Brynn,
just so you know, it's...
Gil, hi.
Hello. How are you?
Have you seen your sister's tattoo?
It's really infected.
Better get
a little bit of ice on it.
Yeah, a little bit.
Stick some
frozen peas on there.
Yeah. It can't hurt.
All right.
So, I just wanted
a quick word.
You know that
tomorrow the rent is due.
I was getting my check,
and I wondered
if I could get
your check, too?
Yes.
I'm getting the money.
It's been
a little slow.
(MOANING)
You have to keep it in the
bag and put the bag on it.
(SIGHING)
So, the check?
Yes. Yes.
Yeah.
Because it's a kind of, like,
"needing it today"-type situation.
It's coming.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
LILLIAN: Who is it?
ANNIE: Me!
Who is it?
Oh, my God. Hurry up,
your creepy neighbor asked me
if I wanted to
watch the news again.
Sorry.
He is so gross.
(IMITATING ACCENT) Please, come on in.
Let me take your magazines.
Welcome to the magazine
and wine party. Ooh!
Have a seat.
I'm very happy
that you are here.
What?
Because I want to eat an apple.
Would you like
some apple?
What is that?
I got engaged.
What?
He asked me last night.
I know!
That's why he's
been acting so weird
'cause he's a terrible liar,
and he thought he was gonna blow it.
He was ignoring
me and I thought
he was going to
break up with me.
Oh, my gosh.
(WHIMPERING)
Oh, my gosh!
I know!
Lil!
I'm shocked, still.
But I'm happy.
Can you believe this?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, I just got hot.
You did?
Are you okay?
Yes. My pits
are sweating.
My stomach hurts. I'm hot.
What does that mean?
Oh, my God!
(EXCLAIMING) What is happening?
I don't know.
I'm wearing a ring.
I can't believe it.
Lil, you're getting married.
I'm getting married.
And you'll be
my maid of honor.
God, of course I will!
It will be super fun.
It's gonna be really fun.
Yeah. You know,
we can plan everything together.
My God!
Planning your wedding...
Are you sure
you're up for it?
I know it's a lot to ask
and to put on your plate.
And you're going through a tricky time,
and you're super-busy...
Stop.
It's a lot to ask.
Okay.
It's fine. And I'm more than happy
to do it, and it's not too much.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh! Look at that.
It's my fiancé calling.
Oh, your fiancé.
Hi, baby,
what's up?
(BOTH CHEERING)
It's Annie. I just told her!
Yeah, she's so happy.
No, I'm not!
"Yay," she said.
(CHUCKLING)
What, baby?
I know,
I miss you, too.
(LAUGHING)
Yeah,
I'll meet you in an hour.
I love you, too.
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
ANNIE: Wow.
Wynonna Judd.
That's really good.
Painting those giant bangs
was a royal pain in my can.
And those teeth!
I should have painted her mouth shut.
Can you just get dressed? We're gonna
be late for the engagement party.
Oh, I forgot to tell you, honey. What?
Forgot to tell you.
What?
I signed up to speak at AA tonight,
and I just have to.
Mom!
No.
I forgot. I'm sorry.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
I keep telling you, you're not
supposed to go to those things.
You're not an alcoholic.
Only because I've
never had a drink.
What?
They are inspiring.
There is this one story I've
just got to tell you. Sit down.
Okay.
This gentleman
who started blow-jobbing to get crack.
His name is Marvin Johnson...
Mom, anonymous. You keep...
It's no names. Okay, okay.
Forget it.
Marvin J. Whatever.
Too late.
Well, he became a gay prostitute.
And he realized that
he had hit his bottom.
And I have been thinking,
honey,
that maybe this
is your bottom.
I'm telling you,
hitting bottom is a good thing.
Because there's
nowhere to go but up.
Right?
Yep. That's what you say.
Yeah, a positive message.
Yeah.
Yeah. Thanks for
the pep talk, Mom.
Honey. Anytime, anytime.
All right. I guess I'm going to
Lillian's party by myself, then.
Don't talk to me
about being by yourself.
I go everywhere
by myself.
Thanks to that
new whore, Barb.
Mom, come on.
No, I don't like to say it.
They've been
married 12 years.
Okay.
But she's still a whore.
I'm sure she greets him in the evening,
beaver first.
I don't want to
think about that.
You sure you don't
want to move in with me?
Mom, thanks,
but no way.
No way in hell.
Yeah?
No, thanks.
Think about it.
Okay.
You don't need
your own place.
Yeah, I kind of do.
Okay.
All right,
I'm going to go. All right.
Holy shit.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Ohh. Valet. Perfect.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Sorry.
Needs a wash.
(ENGINE STALLS)
You have to punch it a few times.
(ENGINE CRANKING)
(GUESTS CHATTERING)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Annie!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God, Lillian.
I know.
This is your engagement party.
Isn't that crazy?
It's so beautiful.
I can't believe Dougie's
boss is a member here.
I know, and his parents, too.
And Dougie, I guess.
Gosh, and me,
I guess, too, now.
Come on, let's go say hi to
the rest of the bridal party!
You remember
my cousin Rita?
Rita.
Annie.
I haven't seen you since
you graduated high school.
She has
three kids now.
Three boys.
LILLIAN: They're so cute.
They are cute,
but when they reach that age,
they are disgusting.
They smell,
they are sticky,
they say things
that are horrible,
and there is semen all
over everything, okay?
Disgusting.
I cracked
a blanket in half.
Do you get where I'm going with that?
I do.
I cracked it
in half.
What?
LILLIAN: Annie, this is Becca,
my friend from work.
We are in
the trenches together.
Hey. It's great to meet you.
Hey, how are you?
Nice to meet you.
This is my husband,
Kevin.
Hi.
"Husband."
I like to say it.
We are newlyweds.
Wow. Congratulations.
Thank you so much.
We went on a sweetheart honeymoon.
Oh.
Where did you guys go?
Disney World.
We finish each other's sentences.
Sorry.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
Is this your husband?
No, no, no, no, no.
I don't know him.
I'm sorry.
Do you want to go
for a walk later?
Oh. I can't.
All right.
I can't. I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I'm not with anybody.
I'm here solo.
Let's start it again.
I'm Becca. Rewind.
This is my husband.
You don't have a husband.
Sorry.
And this is
Dougie's sister, Megan.
Hey.
ANNIE: Hi.
My grandma is not supposed to have wine.
I'll be right back.
Hey.
Hey. How is it going?
It's going great.
It's going great. I'm on the mend.
I just got some
pins in my legs.
Believe it or not, pins in my legs,
I can still do this. Right?
I fell off a cruise ship,
but I'm back.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, "Oh, shit."
Took a hard, hard, violent fall.
Kind of pinballed down.
Hit a lot of railings,
broke a lot of shit.
I'm not going to say I survived,
I'm going to say I thrived.
I met a dolphin down there.
And I swear to God,
that dolphin looked not at me,
but into my soul.
Into my goddamn soul, Annie.
And he said,
"I'm saving you, Megan."
Not with his mouth, but he said it,
I'm assuming, telepathically.
We had a connection that I don't
even know if I can... Jesus.
(MAKING GARBLED SOUNDS)
Hey, shut my mouth.
Look at... Unbelievable.
You must be Annie's fella.
I'm Megan.
It's a pleasure.
He's not... I'm not...
He's not... I'm not with him.
Sorry.
All right.
I'm glad he's single, because I'm
going to climb that like a tree.
Okay. You have
to meet Helen.
There she is. Helen.
LILLIAN: Come here!
Helen, this is Annie.
Hi!
Ohh!
There she is.
Maid of honor.
So lovely to meet
Lillian's childhood friend.
You are so pretty.
You are so cute!
You are so sweet.
Helen is married to Dougie's boss,
Mr. Harris. Perry.
Perry. And they
are so close now,
they are literally
joined at the hip.
Which is good,
because so are we.
I know. I'm so glad you
guys are finally meeting.
I know. Me, too.
I know. It's lovely.
Well, excuse me,
I better go check on the hors d'oeuvres.
But it was great
to finally meet you.
It's a great party.
Enjoy.
LILLIAN: Bye.
Bye.
HELEN: Bye.
She's great, isn't she?
She's awesome.
LILLIAN'S DAD: And I really look forward
to having Doug as part of our family.
So much so that you two
should get married right now
and save me
a shitload of money.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Dad.
Everybody always laughs at that,
but I'm not joking.
(ALL LAUGHING)
I'm not joking.
(CHUCKLING)
Anyway, I want to thank
all of you for coming.
And here's to Doug and
my baby girl, Lillian.
Cheers!
I love you, Dad.
LILLIAN'S DAD: Enough of me.
Let's get the maid
of honor up here.
All right.
Annie?
(CHEERING)
Umm. Hi.
I'm Annie Walker.
Yay, Annie!
I'm not going to go on with a big
speech, so I'll just say this.
I'm so happy to be
a part of this celebration.
And you two
deserve each other,
as well as
a lifetime of happiness.
Thank you.
ANNIE: Cheers.
Love you guys.
GUESTS: Cheers.
Thanks, Annie.
Cheers.
Thank you, Annie.
That was so sweet. Thank you.
Lil, remember that trip we
took to Miami with the boys?
And they were
working the entire weekend,
and we just sat and drank
wine and ate peanut brittle.
And I shared things with you that
I've never shared with anyone.
And you made me realize
how I can trust people again.
So let me just say,
Lillian,
you are my best friend.
(CRYING) And I'm
so proud of you.
Sorry. And, Dougly...
I'm sorry, inside joke.
You better not
keep my Lil on a leash
because I still need my
drunken Saturday nights
at Rockin' Sushi, okay?
(CHEERING)
Everybody raise your glasses
to the couple of the decade,
Doug and Lillian.
(WHOOPING)
(GUESTS WHOOPING)
Have a great night.
Dessert wine is out.
Dessert wine, yummy.
Excuse me.
Umm...
I just wanted to say
really quick that (SIGHING)
you are so special
to me, because...
Well, one of the reasons is because
I've known you my whole entire life.
And you've really
helped shape who I am.
I just want to thank you
for carefully selecting me
as your maid of honor.
I know you had
some other choices,
but you are like my sister,
and I love you.
Well, that concludes
the speeches for the night.
Thank you.
One last thing.
It's rare to meet someone as an
adult who you really connect with,
and that's you, Lil.
I went to Thailand recently
with my husband, Perry,
and there is a beautiful
saying that I learned there.
(SPEAKING THAl)
It means,
"You are a part of me,
"a part that I could
never live without,
"and I hope and I pray
that I never have to."
(THANKING IN THAl)
(BOTH THANKING IN THAl)
And that's it for tonight.
Thank you for coming.
Really quick,
Thank you all for coming.
I just wanted to
say really quick...
Dessert wine is out.
Consuelo?
Really quick.
Speaking of Consuelo,
Lillian and I took
Spanish together in school.
And so, I would just like to say to you,
and to everyone here...
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Thank you.
Thank you. I feel so close
to you and can trust you.
You are my
angel and soul mate.
And I feel I can communicate
with you with simply a look.
Thank you for coming.
Here, I'll take that.
I'll take that.
Yep, I got it.
Lillian...
Keep smiling, keep shining
Knowing you can
always count on me
For sure
That's what friends are for
In good times and bad times
I'll be on your
side forever more
That's what friends are for
That's what
friends are for
(GUESTS CHEERING)
LILLIAN: Man,
engagement parties rule.
It made me feel awesome,
like I can go out and catch
another dude to marry.
So, what's up with her,
anyway? With Helen?
What?
I'm just like...
I don't know.
She's in your wedding
and you've only known her
eight months, though, right?
Come on. Get it out,
get it all out.
I'm just... Like,
the whole gown, and the... thing.
It's just weird, right?
You know what?
She's actually
really cool, Annie.
She's really... She's a good one.
I'm telling you.
Well, I'm sure if you
like her, I will like her.
You have to just
get to know her.
Yeah.
Which I think you really should.
And... Will you
just do me a favor?
Would you just hang
out with her once,
just the two of you.
All right?
As a favor to me.
Okay, I will.
I love you, Annie Lou.
I love you, too.
Bye.
(IMITATING VOICE)
Oh. Hi, I'm Helen.
You live in Milwaukee?
I'm sorry.
Have you met Lillian?
She's my best friend.
Yeah, I know. We've only known
each other for five minutes.
Oh! Oh!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SIREN WAILING)
Oh! Cute.
No. No. Come on.
See? Okay?
I'm not drunk. I told you.
So, you are just
a terrible sober driver?
Ha ha. Very funny.
Can I stop walking now?
You can stop walking when
I tell you to stop walking.
Hey, look.
If I was drunk,
would I be able to do this?
Stop it. Stop it.
Please, stop.
Please, stop. I believe you.
You are not drunk.
But I'm still gonna
have to give you a ticket.
What? Why?
It's a funny thing about brake lights.
You have to have them.
I knew it.
God, those have been out for a year.
I'm so stupid.
Look, please.
Please, I promise
I will get them fixed.
This week, I promise. Please.
Do you have to give me a ticket?
Yes.
License and registration, please.
Thanks.
Look at that,
you live on Wynnewood Drive.
Yep.
We are neighbors.
I just live over on Ashley.
Ahh.
I used to work on Ashley.
You did? Where?
I had a bakery on the main
part of the street there.
Oh. Cake Baby.
You are Cake Baby!
Yeah!
Yeah, you had your sign.
It was your face.
Yeah!
That was you?
That was me.
You made good cakes.
Thanks.
You used to make these
little pastry things,
and you'd put something in them,
like a cream or a custard...
Cream puffs.
Cream puffs,
that's what you call them. Delicious.
I used to get served
by this tall, broad guy,
with, like, a wormy face.
Yeah, that was my boyfriend.
Sorry.
No, no. It was...
He was my boyfriend,
and then he left me
when the business
went under. So, anyway...
You're kidding?
What a dick.
I'm glad
I never tipped him.
You know what?
Let's forget about this.
Let's just forget this one.
Really?
Under one condition.
What? What?
Get your
taillights fixed...
I promise. I promise I will.
I promise. Thank you.
...before you kill someone.
I'm not going to
kill anybody.
All right.
Here, there's your ID.
And I'm going
to give you this.
It's a buddy of mine.
He has a body shop in Milwaukee.
He'll fix those
right up for you.
Bill Cozbi?
Yeah, with a "Z."
Different guy.
Yeah.
And don't mention the whole
"Bill Cosby" thing to him.
It drives him nuts.
I mean it.
Okay, I get it. Thanks.
You know what? If you mention my name,
that I referred you,
he'll give you a particularly good deal.
My gosh. Thank you.
I really appreciate it.
Thanks.
Okay. Well,
I appreciated your cakes.
So, we are even.
That's me, there.
Rhodes. Officer Rhodes.
That's really
nice of you.
Thank you.
(ENGINE STARTS)
We are not all bad.
What?
I was just saying,
we are not all bad!
Oh. Yeah.
Actually, the rest of
them are, but not me.
I'm the best of them.
Okay. Thank you.
Anyway.
Thank you.
I didn't know
you played tennis.
Yeah, I played a little in high school.
I'm so glad we
were able to do this.
I'm really glad we could do this, too.
It's nice we get to hang out.
I know, right?
Yeah.
It's too bad Lillian
couldn't play with us today.
Poor thing, she is so busy.
Ohh. I know.
But she's not really
that into sports.
Even when we were little,
she didn't like anything
that was too competitive.
She certainly enjoys
playing tennis now.
It's funny how
people change, isn't it?
Yeah. I mean, I don't know.
Do people really change?
I think they do.
Yeah, but, I mean, they still
stay who they are, pretty much.
I think we change
all the time.
I think we stay the same,
but grow, I guess, a little bit.
I think if you are growing,
then you are changing.
But, I mean, we are changing from
who we are, which we always stay as.
Not really,
I don't think so.
I think so.
I don't.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Annie! These are my kids.
Step-kids.
Step.
(LAUGHING LOUDLY)
They are so hilarious.
Funny.
Excuse me,
my husband's kids.
HELEN: What are
you guys up to?
Going to the snack bar.
Awesome. You need
a ride home later?
Fuck off, Helen.
Okay. Put a quarter
in the swear-jar.
Good to see you.
They are so cute.
Sweet kids.
(EXCLAIMS)
(GROANING)
Carol!
Get your shit together, Carol!
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SCREAMING)
Yes!
(ANNIE WHOOPING)
I've seen better tennis
playing in a tampon commercial.
Umm...
I've been thinking, and...
Brynn needs to start
paying rent. That's it.
She's been here
long enough.
The three of us live here,
it's not fair for me to be paying half.
We split it three ways.
What do you say?
Well, she can't work.
She's on a tourist visa.
Yeah. So, technically,
I'm only allowed to tour.
Well, you know...
I have no way
of earning money,
unless I just go and
prostitute down on the street.
I don't want you
to do that, no.
"Hello, fellas.
Here I am."
Yeah, but we...
"Put your American sausage
"in my English McMuffin."
No, we did that.
All right.
Okay, I don't even know what
you're talking about anymore.
There's three people living here.
Yeah.
If she doesn't
start paying...
BRYNN: I'm not.
...she has to leave.
Is this about
the diary again?
What diary?
Your diary proved
very interesting to read.
You read my...
You read my journal?
At first, I did not know
that it was your diary.
I thought it was a very sad,
hand-written book.
What? That does not
make any...
But, because of
the deep personal details
and the bits that mentioned Gil
and Brynn... ANNIE: No, no, no, no.
Don't read my journal!
GIL: And the crumbs.
Then...
Don't go in my room!
Well, hello! I think,
before you make those sort of demands,
you need to,
maybe, think about
putting a note on
your door saying,
"Do not come into my room,
read my diary and wear my clothes."
BECCA: Wow, I've never been
to this part of town before.
Look, you can get your
checks cashed next door.
I know it looks a little
scary on the outside,
but the food is really good,
authentic Brazilian.
ANNIE: I'm telling you,
this is where Brazilians come to eat.
I got to say, Annie's
really good at this.
She always drags me
to the weirdest places
and the food is
always incredible.
And plus, you get a lot for
your money, too. So that's good.
All right. Let's do it.
Let's do it.
Whoa! Somebody
likes Brazilian food.
To my bridesmaids.
Cheers.
ALL: Cheers.
Cheers to Lil!
This is such a stone-cold pack of weirdos,
and I'm so proud. (ALL LAUGHING)
And I just want to
toast all of you ladies.
I'm so happy to
get to know you guys,
and happy to say
that I have four new friends.
Absolutely. Cheers.
(WAITER SPEAKING SPANISH)
I hope that you're all hungry for
churrasco Brasil. What would you like?
Yeah, I'll have
some of that, please.
I'll start with this.
I'd say yes.
Hello, chicken.
This is crazy good,
ya'II.
Helen, aren't you
eating any meat?
Oh...
It's not good to eat a
big meal before a fitting.
I feel a bit bloated, so...
Not me.
HELEN: No?
No. Physically,
I don't bloat.
Lucky.
That is lucky.
It's a gift.
I can't wait to be married for
as long as you've been married.
And to have kids.
And be a mom.
Becca?
Yeah?
The other night,
I'm slaving away,
making a beautiful
dinner for my family.
My youngest boy comes in and
says he wants to order a pizza.
I said, "No, we're not
ordering pizza tonight."
He goes, "Mom,
why don't you go and fuck yourself?"
He's nine.
Okay, now that
Lillian's in the bathroom,
I just wanted to talk to you guys
about the shower really quick.
I was thinking it
could be French-themed,
since she's always wanted
to go to Paris her whole life.
So I figured we
could bring Paris here
and have champagne
and little cookies.
They'd say "Lillian
and Dougie" on them.
We can dip them in
chocolate fondue,
and get cheese from
the nice part of the store.
I love that.
Good idea, Annie.
We can have French invitations,
the whole thing.
Don't you think
that'd be nice?
That's adorable!
That's really cute.
Good. Great.
I don't know.
It's really cute.
But I feel like,
personally, the Paris theme's
a bit,
"Been there, done that."
I just feel
like we can top it.
We should throw
some ideas around.
See if anyone else
has a theme they had in mind
or something
they'd been thinking of.
What about
a Pixar-themed shower?
And we all come dressed as
our favorite Pixar character.
That, and I'll just snowball on
top of that, also Fight Club.
Female fight club.
We grease up,
we pull in.
Lillian doesn't know, so it's,
"Surprise! We're going to fight!"
We beat the shit out of her.
She's not going
to forget that.
We just fucking attack.
Can I be honest?
No.
I'm at home with three boys all day,
every day.
What about
the bachelorette party?
That's what's more important.
I've got a new tube top,
I want to cut the tags off.
I'd like to take
advantage of this opportunity.
Where are we going?
MEGAN: I'm going to second her.
We'd better blow this shit out.
Yeah.
That poor girl, Lillian,
who we're all here for,
is in the bathroom probably
bawling her fucking eyes out.
Because she's realizing,
"Holy shit!
"I've got to spend the
rest of my life with Doug."
He's my brother. I love him.
But he is a fucking asshole.
I think we can all
agree on that, right?
We can...
We'll figure it out.
I mean, I can think of stuff,
and it will be great.
We just have to make sure
it's really, really special.
Belle en Blanc? This is the place.
Great job, Annie.
Thanks.
Annie.
Belle en Blanc.
Reservation name?
I don't have one. We're just here to
shop, just to try on some dresses.
Okay. Well, the next
available appointment
for bridesmaids'
fittings is in seven weeks.
Absolutely no walk-ins.
Whitney? It's Helen.
Helen Harris?
Yeah!
Hi!
Hi.
Oh, my God. Hi. Listen,
I'll buzz you right in.
Great, thanks.
Okay.
Hello. Welcome, come in.
You look wonderful.
Great to see you.
Welcome to Belle
en Blanc, ladies.
Welcome to heaven.
LILLIAN: Thank you.
MEGAN: Oh, man!
This is some classy shit here.
(BELCHES)
Jesus, Megan!
I'm sorry,
I want to apologize.
I'm not even confident
on which end that came out of.
Whitney, back to you.
I'm sorry.
Anyway, take a look around.
Get to know the dresses.
If you need anything,
I'll be in my office.
Have fun.
Oh, my God.
It's a Fritz Bernaise.
Ladies, I...
Oh, my God!
I just don't think we can do any better.
This is...
This is beautiful.
That is gorgeous.
It's unique,
it's special, it's couture.
This is made in France.
Helen, this is $800.
Are you kidding?
It's on sale.
LILLIAN: Are you serious? Oh, my gosh.
What a perfect combination.
HELEN: You guys,
it was meant to be.
Oh. That's nice.
There's other dresses
we should be looking at.
Nope, not that one.
Lillian,
Lillian, look at this one.
Isn't this pretty?
Yeah.
It's really pretty
and sweet, and...
We don't want to upstage
Lillian with a big fancy dress.
Maybe we should just get
something kind of simple.
Oh.
Please do not worry
about upstaging me.
Because guess who
Helen is friends with
and who's
designing my wedding dress.
Lady St. Petsois JuJu.
I just sent my
measurements to France, y'all.
RITA: No, you didn't.
Where were you when I
was getting married?
Ladies, let's not decide on this
bridesmaids' dress straight away.
Let's let
our bodies decide.
Try some things on
and have some fun, okay?
Yeah, let's have
some fun, girls.
Ladies,
start your "engines."
RITA: Oh, yeah.
BECCA: Lil, Lil.
LILLIAN: Amazing.
This is so cool.
(STOMACH GURGLING)
(SIGHS)
(CHATTERING)
Ladies. Ladies,
if I may interject.
I just want to say
you all look stunning.
That's a given. Head to toe.
But, sadly,
we need to agree on one.
Well, I mean, ladies,
you all look beautiful.
But I just think, personally,
the Fritz Bernaise is just...
I mean...
It's a Bernaise.
HELEN: This is one of a kind.
I just...
I don't think
there is a question.
No. No question.
There might be a question.
I might...
I might have a question.
I think this dress would
look great on everybody.
It's a great color.
It's a great length.
It's fun. You can twirl.
You can move in it.
You can spread
your legs apart.
And it's a great price.
This is designer as well.
(STOMACH GURGLING)
Is anyone else hot?
It is like an
oven in here.
Okay, well,
maybe this might help you decide.
While you gals were
in the changing room,
I happened to rustle up a two-year-old
Lady JuJu dress in storage.
I had Lillian put it
on so you could see
what you'll be
standing next to.
Lillian, honey.
My God.
(GIRLS GASPING)
Beautiful length.
Breathtaking.
Holy shit!
You look amazing.
That's a dress.
That dress is so pretty
it makes my stomach hurt.
Lillian,
I don't know what to say.
You look... (RETCHES)
Megan, are you okay?
(RETCHING AND FARTING)
MEGAN: I think...
My dress was
probably just tight.
Oh, my God.
You got food poisoning from
that restaurant, didn't you?
No, I had the same thing that she
had and I feel fine. (RETCHES)
Oh, my... Okay.
Oh, no.
Why is this happening?
Nothing is happening.
(FARTING)
Oh, my God.
RITA: I don't really care
which dress we get.
It doesn't matter to me. I just
need to get off this white carpet.
Oh, God. Okay.
No, not the bathroom.
Everybody go outside.
I'm serious!
There is a bathroom
across the street.
I think everybody
has the flu.
Shit!
(RETCHING VIOLENTLY)
I need the toilet!
(GROANING)
No!
No. No, Megan.
No! No!
Look away!
Megan, no!
(GROANING)
You don't look
very well, Annie.
I feel fine.
Are you sure?
It wasn't that gray kind of lamb?
You ate a lot of
that weird chicken.
Was it that?
No. I'm...
I... I feel fine.
I think you'd just feel
better if you threw up.
I don't have...
I don't have to throw up.
(RETCHING)
I am so sorry.
Get away from me!
You're not sick?
No.
No?
In fact, Helen, I'm hungry.
And I wish I had a snack.
You're hungry?
I'm starving.
What did we eat?
The sink is a goner.
What are you doing?
It's coming out
of me like lava!
(RETCHING)
Oh, my God.
Don't you
fucking look at me!
(RETCHING)
(GROANING)
Hmm?
Jordan almonds.
These are great.
Thank you.
Better?
I was...
I was just hungry.
Yeah.
Annie, everybody is really
sick from that restaurant.
(GROANING)
But it wasn't the restaurant.
No, no, no, no.
Lillian, where are you going?
No.
I need a bathroom.
Lil!
No. No.
Lil, where are you going?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN BLARING) HELEN:
Be careful. What are you doing?
It's happening.
It happened.
ANNIE: What are you doing?
No. Don't you
dare ruin that dress!
Ohh. You're really
doing it, aren't you?
You're really
shitting in the street.
(HORN HONKING)
We'll just take five
of the Fritz Bernaises.
Thank you, Whitney.
They really do look better.
Right.
Thank you.
You okay?
I just took a shit in
the middle of the street.
I just shit.
People do that.
I shit... I shitted in
my shorts. I shit myself.
That was fun.
Oh, my gosh.
(SIGHS)
You know what I was thinking?
You should come with me
to Lillian's wedding, maybe.
Not like that.
Not like anything serious.
But just like
a fun time, you know?
We can get dressed up,
and we can go dancing and have a drink.
It'll be fun, right?
(GROANS)
No. I mean,
I don't want to make you have to explain
to all those people
what our relationship is.
That would suck for you.
Right?
Yeah. I guess so.
I'm just thinking of you.
Yeah.
No, it's okay.
I have someone else
I can ask, anyway. So...
(SCOFFS)
Really?
Yeah.
Who?
Umm...
This guy, George.
George Glass.
Okay.
Who is this George?
He is a very hot, nice guy
who likes me a lot,
and would probably love to be my date.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
(MOANS)
Well, let me ask you this.
Can this George Glass
do this to you?
Probably.
You know what?
It's getting really late.
You should probably go.
I'm going to miss you so much.
Oh.
(KNOCKING ON GLASS)
Annie Walker.
Hi.
Hey.
What brings you
in here so early?
I've just had a bad night.
Boy stuff. Ohh.
Do you want me
to arrest anybody?
I could do that.
Actually... No.
Do you want to talk to a cop about it?
We are just like priests.
Except we can tell everybody
about it afterwards.
Oh.
I won't, though.
Doesn't sound very inviting.
You want a carrot?
Right now?
Yeah.
I'll share.
I've got plenty.
Sure, I'll have a carrot.
Yeah?
Okay.
Ohh. Yeah,
that sounds rough.
It's going to
get better, right?
I wouldn't have
thought so.
You know, my sister was a maid
of honor at our cousin's wedding,
and she found it so stressful,
her hair started falling out.
That's terrible.
Yeah.
It grew back,
but it was...
It was pretty gross.
Planning a wedding
should be fun.
You know what?
If I ever had a wedding,
I'd want everybody
to be stress-free.
I'd like it to be
like a carnival.
Like, people win prizes for
guessing the bride's weight.
Dunk tanks.
Yeah.
You know?
Mmm-hmm.
You could have elephants,
and the bride and groom can
walk on a little tightrope.
Okay, what you are talking about there,
that's a circus wedding.
It's a totally different...
Right.
You missed it.
Yeah.
Hey, you know, instead of
stressing out about this wedding,
you know what you
should be doing?
Setting up a new bakery!
(CHUCKLES)
Hmm.
No, I'm kind of
done with that.
What?
I don't do it anymore.
All right.
Ew.
Oh!
You got the ugly carrot.
What?
There is one in every bag.
You have to eat it. It's good luck.
I'm not eating this.
Yeah! I'll eat it.
It's the lucky carrot? No, don't eat it!
Don't eat it. Don't eat it!
Well, don't litter!
I'll fine you. I'm sorry.
You know what?
Actually, I'm going to pick it up.
It really bothers me.
Sorry.
I'm sorry. It's just that I'm
anal about that kind of thing.
I didn't know that you could be a
cop here if you weren't a citizen.
You can't.
No?
No. No, you can't.
But they made
a special dispensation
because I'm so
tough and strong.
Oh. Right.
And handsome.
Okay.
You're pretty...
You're pretty tough.
I am tough. You're tough.
You're a tough cop.
Look. You're saying it,
but you're laughing.
No, you're...
You're...
You didn't let
me flex that time.
That was unfair.
I'm really tough.
So am I.
No.
Yeah. I could be a cop.
You think you could be a cop?
Yeah.
Okay.
Let's see.
You know what?
The sun is nearly up. Let's go and
see if you've got what it takes.
That's right.
Now, plant your feet.
ANNIE: Okay.
Good.
And take aim.
Now, put your left
hand behind your head.
Yeah. And just
drop your left hip.
(WOLF WHISTLES)
I'm kidding.
Put your arms out straight. Okay.
You want to hit the middle
of the license plate.
That's where you get
the most accurate reading.
Okay. Okay, here we go.
You ready?
Okay.
(RADAR GUN BEEPING)
(RADAR GUN BEEPS)
Fifty-eight.
What's the speed limit?
Fifty-five.
Okay, they were all right.
We'll let them go.
You were born to do this.
Look at you.
Okay. All right,
here we go.
(RADAR GUN BEEPS)
Sixty-three.
You are missing
some good ones here.
People are on their way to work.
Why ruin their day?
Okay, watch this. 48.
(RADAR GUN BEEPING)
Forty-eight.
How did you do that?
It wasn't!
Yes, it was.
That's never happened.
Are you serious?
It was 48?
Yes, 48!
Yeah.
I'm so impressed.
I'm pretty impressive.
I'm very impressed by you.
Whoa!
Damn!
That was 91.
91?
Yes. Can we go?
We can go.
Come on, hot dogger.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(SIREN WAILING)
RHODES: Let's get that fucker.
ANNIE: Oh, my God!
(LAUGHING)
Oh, my God!
...family lake house. Perfect.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello? I just got your e-mail.
Lake house?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's
Lillian's parents' house.
We used to go there all the time
in the summers and everything.
It's one of...
A bachelorette in a cabin?
(PHONE BEEPS) Wait. Can you...
Hold that thought. Hold on.
Hello?
Fucking Helen. Hello?
Annie, it's Rita.
Hi.
Listen, I need a trip
that I can fantasize forever
so that I am able to
have sex with my husband.
That's why
I'm thinking Vegas.
Vegas?
Hang on. Hey!
Shut your filthy
fucking mouths! I'm sorry.
I'm surrounded by savages.
(PHONE BEEPS)
You know what? I should probably run.
My other line is ringing.
You know, I can get cocaine
from my hairdresser.
Okay, bye. Hello?
Annie.
Yeah?
I'm so excited. Helen just called.
She said we can go to Vegas.
You know... Yeah, but we have to...
We have to fly there, and...
Okay, Annie, I know
you are afraid of flying,
but I want to see Criss Angel,
but I'm scared.
Which I sort of love.
(PHONE BEEPS) Can you just
hold on for one second?
Oh, sure, sure, sure. I... Thanks.
Hold on. God damn it.
Hello?
Hey, Annie, it's Megan.
Hey.
I just had some thoughts
about the bachelorette party.
Okay, here we go.
Easy-peasy. Vegas it is.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Helen called you,
didn't she?
Yeah, she got the jump on you.
I want balls in my face.
Honestly, I think it's Vegas.
I love puppets.
Balls.
I guess we are undecided.
I feel so bad Annie's
stuck back in coach.
I know, I offered
to pay for her
so she could sit
in first class,
but she said no.
She's too proud.
It was nice of you to offer.
No carry-on, huh?
No.
Yeah, I noticed.
I noticed you didn't put anything
in the overhead bin either.
And I get it.
I get it. I want you to know,
protect and serve
Air Marshal-style.
What?
I don't want to
infringe on your privacy, man.
I just... I really appreciate
what you do for this country.
And I respect
the hell out of you.
That's great.
I'm not an Air Marshal.
I'm going to take a nap.
Awesome.
Cool.
I'll take the first watch.
I'm not an Air Marshal.
You don't need to take a watch.
Okay.
I've got the first watch.
PILOT: Please check
your seatbelts
and that your seat backs are in an
upright position before takeoff.
Gosh.
I am really hoping
this flight is quick,
and we get there on
the ground safely.
I'm not a good flyer,
I'm sorry.
I had a dream last
night that we went down.
Yep. It was terrible.
You were in it.
What?
It sounds like something's happening.
(MOANING)
Annie, what are you
doing up here?
You are supposed
to be in your seat.
I know.
I'm freaking out a little bit.
Ma'am, we're still ascending. You're
gonna need to return to your seat.
Okay, I was just...
Annie, I have something.
Take two, you'll fall asleep,
wake up and we'll be there. Here.
(PLANE RATTLING)
Ma'am, you're going to have to
return to your seat, please.
It's fine.
Okay. All right.
STEWARDESS: Ma'am!
All right. All right.
Oh, my God, I feel terrible.
I should be sitting back there with her.
I shouldn't be up here in first class.
I feel like such a jerk.
Lil, this is
your weekend, okay?
You are treating yourself.
Just relax.
She will be fine.
She will make friends.
There is much more sense of
community in coach, I promise you.
She'll be fine.
I can't believe you've never
been with anybody else.
Just Kevin.
I'm sorry. I just...
Becca, I just can't
help but feel bad for you.
You don't even
know what you want.
I got to know where
you keep the gun, man.
I mean, is it ankle,
hip, lower back?
You don't...
Between the cheeks, do you?
No, I don't stick a gun up my butt.
That's stupid.
I didn't say "up."
I just knew of a guy,
that guy did a lot of undercover work.
And all I know is he had tape
marks all up and down his cheeks.
That can't be true.
People don't keep
guns up their asses
because if you needed to use it,
how are you going to get it?
He cut a hole in his pocket.
What?
In his back pocket.
You have got to get
something out of your ass
and you cut a hole in
the back of your jeans,
you want to tell me
you can't get to something?
I don't have a gun for you to
put up my ass to make your point.
I can put my Nano.
I will show you.
I will...
If you get me scissors,
I will cut
a hole in my pocket.
And you will never find this
again until I want you to find it.
Kevin can only have sex in bed,
in the dark, under the covers,
only after
we have showered
separately.
And sometimes,
by the time we are finished
cleaning ourselves,
he's too tired.
And then I pretend I'm tired, but I'm
not tired. I'm not tired. I'm not tired.
That's why every girl needs
those slutty college years.
To experiment, get it out of your
system, find out what you like.
Excuse me, could I have a glass
of alcohol when you get a chance?
Two double
Seven and Sevens.
Is that...
You will like it.
It's sweet.
I have to go
to the bathroom.
But I heard about a woman who
went to the bathroom on a plane.
She got sucked
into the toilet.
Sucked right in.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Yeah, I just think that what you
gave me didn't really do anything.
I just have too much adrenalin
or something. But, thanks.
Why don't you take
my scotch?
It will just give the pill
a little kick that it needs.
Honestly, I do it all the time.
Yeah?
Yeah, and I'm much smaller than you,
so you'll handle it.
Well, thanks.
Yeah?
Okay.
(EXHALES)
Yummy?
Yeah, it's good.
You should just toss it back.
Don't waste any more time.
Okay.
Ohh. Look at that.
Okay, that'll do it.
That'll do it.
So you don't even
have sex anymore?
No, I have sex constantly.
The sex is constant.
But he hasn't
kissed me in five years.
What are you doing when
you are having sex, then?
Thinking about other things
and wishing it would stop.
You know, sometimes
I just want to watch
The Daily Show
without him entering me.
It's the Wet Republic Ultra Pool.
No.
Are you kidding?
What is it again?
HELEN: There is a bar in
the pool and a tiger.
LILLIAN: What?
HELEN: It's crazy.
It's Vegas at its best.
Wait a minute. Is this that
place that was on The Real World?
Are you kidding me?
Oh, my God. It's...
Hey, buddy.
How you doing?
I'm good. I'm so much more relaxed.
Thank you, Helen.
I just feel like I'm excited,
and I feel relaxed.
(TALKING LOUDLY)
And I'm ready
to party
with the best of them!
And I'm going to
go down to the river
Wow! It looks like somebody
is really relaxing now.
What are you guys
talking about up here?
We are going to a restaurant tonight.
I know the owner, so...
You do?
Ohh. Helen knows the owner.
Uhh!
Big whoop.
Let's go take a nap.
What do you say?
Miss, you cannot be up here.
(IMITATING OLD MAN)
Hello, grandpa.
I'm sorry.
I just want to be here with
my friends,
because I'm with this group.
The sign just went off. Can't she stay
up here for a minute and just talk?
STEWARD: Absolutely not.
Coach passengers are not
allowed up here in first class.
It's policy.
I'm sorry.
Ooh!
This is a very strict plane that I'm on.
(IMITATING GERMAN ACCENT)
Welcome to Germany.
Auf Wiedersehen, asshole.
All right.
Why don't you go lay down?
I'm going to go take a nap.
I'm tired.
I think it's a good idea.
Catch you on the flip side,
motherfuckers.
I'm sorry.
I'm leaving.
Thank you.
This should be open,
because it's civil rights.
This is the '90s.
Right. It's not.
You're in the wrong decade.
You are.
Okay, I am.
Thank you.
Holy shit.
What did you give her?
(SEATBELT SIGN BEEPS)
Miss?
No. It's not me.
Yes, it is you.
Please go back to your seat.
Yes, I am with him.
I am Mrs. Iglesias.
No, you are not.
You were just out here and
you put sunglasses on. Out.
But I don't want to.
Sir, she can
have my seat, okay?
Everyone should experience first
class at least once in their lives.
And Annie shouldn't miss out
just because she can't afford it.
No, ma'am, I'm
afraid that's not allowed.
Help me, I'm poor.
LILLIAN: No, listen,
we're a whole wedding party.
I'm the bride. I'm getting married.
This seat is empty. She's obviously
nervous. We'll calm her down and...
I understand.
But Claire is right.
Everybody,
go back to your seats.
Okay, you especially.
You have three seconds
to get back to your seat.
(GROANS)
You can't get
anywhere in three seconds.
Well, you'd better try.
You are setting me
up for a loss already.
Thank you.
Whatever you say, Stove.
It's Steve.
(RASPING)
"Stove."
What kind of name is that?
That's not a name.
My name is Steve.
Are you an appliance?
No, I'm a man,
and my name is Steve.
You are a flight attendant.
That's absolutely
accurate.
You can close that.
Thank you.
(SIGHS)
Hey, not-Air Marshall Jon.
You want to get back in
that restroom and not rest?
No, I have to get
back to my seat.
Yeah, you gotta
get back on my seat.
(SCATTING TUNE)
You get it?
Yeah, I definitely got it.
Oh-oh. What's that?
I got to get back to my seat.
Could you just move your leg, please?
I got to go.
Oh-oh.
Somebody found a souvenir.
You feel that steam heat coming?
That's from my undercarriage.
That can go up
and higher.
Okay.
Jon, get us a blanket.
No.
I got to take a whiz
and I'll be right back.
Cool.
I don't want you to be
a big fuck-up like me.
How do you think I feel?
Like me.
You can still turn it around.
No, don't.
Stop it!
You are more beautiful than Cinderella.
You smell like pine needles and
you have a face like sunshine.
(EXHALING)
(PLANE RATTLING)
What?
Oh, no.
(INTERCOM BEEPS)
Ladies and gentlemen,
as you can see, the captain has
turned on the "fasten seatbelt" sign.
It appears we've run into
a rough patch of weather...
ANNIE: (ON INTERCOM)
I have an announcement, too.
There is a Colonial woman
on the wing.
There's a woman on the wing.
I saw her.
There's something
they're not telling us!
Steve.
All right.
There's a Colonial woman.
She was churning butter on that wing.
Steve, get her.
She is out there right now.
Shit!
Everyone, remain calm!
I'm an Air Marshal.
Yes! I knew it.
I got your back, Jon!
There is a woman on the wing.
I saw her.
There's something
they're not telling us.
Let's get out!
Let's open the doors and get out!
She is dressed in
traditional Colonial garb.
Say goodbye!
We are going down!
Stay calm.
ANNIE: There is something
they are not telling us.
There is a Colonial
woman on the wing.
I will cover the pilot!
(CLAMORING)
Who is she?
What does she want?
Just let me make it
up to you, please.
I'm telling you,
your shower is
going to be amazing.
I have so many ideas.
I want to talk to
you about the shower.
I feel like
it has been really
overwhelming for you.
It's just starting
to make you crazy.
No, Lil, I'm fine.
I mean...
Lil, I'm fine.
No, you're not fine.
You are not fine, Annie,
and we need things to just
flow smoothly from now on
and Helen just knows
how to do this kind of stuff.
She does it all the time.
She is good at it.
She likes doing it.
This way you don't have to
plan any more
lunches or trips.
You don't have to do anything
you don't want to do.
I get it.
I think it'll be
best here on out
for the shower
and for everything.
Yeah,
whatever you want.
I mean,
it's probably best.
I think so, right?
Yeah.
I just want you to be happy.
I think that will make me happy.
It will be good.
Okay.
Good.
Hey.
Do you want to hang out?
(RHODES LAUGHING)
ANNIE: It's not funny!
Stop laughing.
RHODES: It's a little funny.
None of those girls
are laughing, believe me.
It's not funny.
Have you ever been kicked off a plane?
I can't say that I have.
Thank you.
All of the girls
hate me right now.
You are like
the maid of dishonor.
(GROANS)
I hope Lillian isn't going
to be mad at me for too long.
No, she will be all right.
I don't know,
I just wish things were
the way that they
used to be, you know.
I feel like her
life is going off
and getting perfect,
and mine is just like...
It will turn around,
you know.
I have been hearing
that for a long time.
It's going to turn around.
I just know it.
Anyway.
You got to bake.
I don't really do
that anymore, I told you.
Why?
I don't know,
it's just...
I don't know, after it just went under,
I just, kind of,
stopped, I guess.
It doesn't make
me happy anymore.
Just because you didn't
make any money at it,
doesn't mean that
you failed at it.
I lost a lot of money.
All my money.
But you are so good at it.
Oh, well.
Let's change the subject.
No more baking.
I'm done.
I don't know how
you just can't do it anymore.
If I wasn't a cop anymore,
I would still...
Arrest people?
...go out with
a gun and shoot people.
I probably wouldn't do that.
I'm just trying to make you feel better.
You are okay, you know.
You don't
know me very well.
I know you well enough to
know that you're not so bad.
You got some stuff.
Oh, yeah.
You got bits and
pieces going on.
Thanks.
I have been thinking
about you a little bit.
About me? Really?
There is something
about you.
Something about
you that sticks.
ANNIE: I hate buttons.
(RHODES MOANING)
Where is the bedroom?
(BELL RINGS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Sorry. It's a mountain bike.
Are you okay?
Do you like mountain biking?
Uh-huh.
(BOTH MOANING)
Take this off.
I'm so glad
this is happening.
So am I.
(MOANING)
Hello.
Morning.
Sorry, I didn't
mean to freak you out.
No, it's okay.
I haven't been sitting here that long.
Oh.
(BOTH CHUCKLING NERVOUSLY)
Sorry, I guess I fell asleep.
I didn't mean to sleep over.
Don't be silly.
I made you a cappuccino.
Made it?
Yeah.
So, last night was fun.
It was.
It was very fun.