MAN 1:
Ten-hut!
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
[DOGS BARKING]
MAN 2:
Welcome home, Mr. President.
WOMAN:
Over here, Mr. President!
Good to be home.
Thank you.
- What do you got?
BOB: - Let's go over it again.
ELLEN:
Who do I see first this morning?
WOMAN:
You've got Mr. Crenshaw at 11:30.
I can't do two things at once, you know?
I got NSC at 2:30.
- That'll only take half an hour.
- With Syria?
You've got that radio address
to go over...
...and the Legal Counsel speech
at the Monroe tomorrow night.
- The Monroe?
- Welcome home, Mr. President.
Yes, sir, the Monroe Hotel.
Have you got someone to double
for me there?
ALAN: - We're working on it, sir.
- Good.
Try to find someone
who looks like me this time.
That last guy was a joke.
MAN:
Ladies and gentlemen, here he is...
...the President of the United States.
["HAIL TO THE CHIEF"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
[PIG GRUNTING]
DAVE:
God bless you. Thank you.
Welcome to Durenberger's, Mr. President.
Thank you, one and all.
Let me just say,
from one chief executive to another...
...that there is no Chevrolet
like Durenberger's Community Chevrolet.
Thank you, Mr. President.
- Mom, that's not the president, is it?
- I sure hope not.
I have the feeling that when people
find out about the $500 cash rebate...
...on all Geo Storms
and Geo Storm convertibles...
...that you're going to be even busier
than I am.
MAN:
You said it, Mr. President.
See, I could veto this Simpson-Gardner
thing if I wanted to, but I don't want to.
Do you know why I don't want to?
It's got homeless shelters...
...Head Start centers...
...and, uh....
Hot lunches.
Hot lunches for little kiddies.
If I kill it, I'm gonna
look like a prick.
I don't want to look like a prick.
I want you to look like pricks.
But, sir, we've tried to kill it.
Twice.
I don't think so, Howard, no.
If you'd killed it, it would be dead.
When I kill something...
...it always dies.
- Doesn't it, Bob?
- Always did.
Mr. President, with the work your wife
has done with the homeless...
My wife.
Norman.
I don't want you to do this
because you're forced to.
I want you to do this
because you want to.
I want you to do it
because it's the right thing to do.
I want you to do it because you're acting
in the best interests of your country.
Well, I think that's it.
[WHISTLING]
MAN: 6:30?
DAVE: Oh-ho!
- Perfect.
- Great. I'll see you then.
- How are you? Having fun?
- Hey.
Yes. Good to see you.
Ask me how I did.
- How did it go? Yeah?
- I killed them. It was great.
- See what you can do in here.
- Okay, what's up?
Hey. How are you, Mabel? Hi, Jennifer.
Mabel says it's too far on the bus.
Jennifer's boss tried to hit on her.
And Lola's been in your office crying
for almost an hour.
Lola, what happened?
Oh, Mr. Kovic, it's not my fault.
I learn on the IBM, okay?
- Yeah.
- Then they put me on the Wang.
[SPEAKING IN ITALIAN]
Don't worry. We'll think of something.
Yeah. So tonight's the big night.
Yeah. It's some big secret.
He won't tell me.
Can't get out of it.
It's gonna be fine.
We're gonna fix it.
Honey, call, uh, Murray.
Tell him we're on our way, okay?
It's Wednesday.
Everybody works on Wednesday.
Can I borrow your...? Thanks.
DAVE:
Don't cry. Murray.
Dave, I can't hire anybody else. I can't.
Murray, she flies on an IBM.
I don't have enough work
for the people you already gave me.
She's got three kids.
Her husband's a diabetic. Diabetic?
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]
Just a short-term thing.
Straight temp job.
Please? Murray. Murray.
I'll see what I can do.
DAVE:
Thanks.
You feel okay about this?
Not yet.
You will.
Do you want to go play some ball?
It's the middle of the afternoon.
I'm working.
Me too. Okay, well, um, thanks, Murray.
I'll see you tomorrow.
- Bye, Lola, Kate, Adriana, Pam.
WOMAN: - Bye, Dave.
DAVE [SINGING]:
And the wavin' wheat can sure smell sweet
When the wind comes right behind the...
Aah!
Rain
Oklahoma
Every night my honey lamb and I
Sit alone and talk and watch a hawk
Makin' lazy circles in the sky
We know we belong to the land
And the land we belong to is grand
And when we say
Yeeow! Ayipioeeay, whoo
We're only saying
You're doing fine, Oklahoma
Oklahoma
O-K-L-A-H-O
M-A
Oklahoma
[GASPS
Mr. Kovic?
I'm Duane Stevenson
with the United States Secret Service.
We're with the federal government.
I.... I swear I thought that
was a legitimate deduction.
See, I do impersonations,
so I use that television with my work.
Mr. Kovic,
we're not here about your taxes.
On occasion, for security purposes...
...the Secret Service hires someone
to double for the president...
...at public functions
in exposed situations.
Your government needs your help.
Really?
[CROWD CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY
[POLICE SIREN WAILING
AND HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
I like it.
You look just like him.
- You think?
- Mm-hm.
And the coloring....
- Coloring is excellent.
- You really cut his hair this short?
- It's a perfect match.
- Doesn't come over the ears?
- You understand what you'll be doing?
- Uh, yeah. You want me to wave.
Wave from the door, come down
the stairs, get into the limo.
You know, if you want me
to do other stuff, uh, I can.
- If you want me to talk...
- Don't say a word.
Right.
[BAND PLAYING "HAIL TO THE CHIEF"]
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
the President of the United States.
[CROWD APPLAUDING
AND WHISTLING]
BILL:
Thank you all.
Thank you.
Is there a lawyer in the house?
[ALL LAUGH]
You know...
...just now as I was coming
to the podium...
...I spotted my old friend,
Jordan Blankfort.
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
Now Justice Blankfort...
...who I haven't seen since our
law school days back at Yale.
You know, just seeing him makes me...
...kind of nostalgic
for those innocent days back then.
About the worst thing we ever did...
...was hoist somebody's underwear
up a flagpole.
We need standardized parole criteria...
...that will guarantee a prisoner
will not be returned to the street...
...until he has paid his debt to society.
We need a judiciary
that is sensitive to the needs...
STEVENSON:
Okay, let's go.
...of the average American,
because that's what we were founded on.
BILL:
The dreams...
...the dreams of a few...
...struggling pilgrims...
...who imagined a system of laws...
...of the people, by the people...
...and for all the decent people
of this land! God bless you!
God bless America!
[BAND PLAYING
"FOR HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW"]
Hey.
BILL:
Let's move it up a half hour.
You have the trade negotiations.
It needs to be handled.
He's here.
ALAN:
They weren't very enthusiastic.
BILL:
Of course, they're lawyers.
Jesus Christ.
You're a very handsome man.
Thank you, Mr. President.
Just get rid of the grin.
You look like a schmuck.
He's all right.
Wish me luck.
- Call me if there's a war.
ALAN: - Heh.
Move him out.
You're on.
STEVENSON:
Okay, you ready?
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
MAN 1:
Mr. President?
MAN 2:
President Mitchell!
God bless you! God bless America!
[ALL CHEERING]
Thank you very much!
[GRUNTS]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[LAUGHS
I'm sorry. I just couldn't help it.
I got carried away.
[SIGHS
I was pretty good though, wasn't I?
I guess something important must be going
on for the president to go through all this.
Something top secret.
[BILL AND RANDI MOANING]
Baby?
Hon?
Mr. President?
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO]
ALAN: Doesn't look very good.
They say it hit both sides of his brain.
If he makes it,
he's gonna be a vegetable.
BOB: - I can't believe he'd do this.
- I know.
BOB: - Where's the girl?
- She's a little upset right now.
- We got her upstairs in the laundry room.
BOB: - Some nightmare.
Bob.
At some point, we're gonna
have to call the vice-president.
- Don't call the vice-president.
- What?
Just don't call him, Al.
- The guy's in a coma, Bob.
- I don't give a shit.
- Bob.
- This is mine, Al. It's all mine.
I made him. I built him.
And no Boy Scout is gonna come in here
and take it away from me...
...just because he happens
to be vice-president of the United States.
[STRETCHER CLICKS]
You know, uh...
...if you guys want to do something for his
birthday, uh, I've got some great birthday stuff.
I do this thing, uh....
My friends love this.
[CHUCKLES]
The president and the first lady are
going to Club Med, for their vacation....
[PHONE RINGS]
Yeah.
Oh, sir.
What?
Back to the cottage.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
BOB:
We'll start by going on television.
We'll admit he had a stroke,
but we'll say it was a mild stroke.
- A mild stroke?
- Yes.
And he ought to be up and around again
sometime soon.
ALAN:
Up and around?
How?
You know...
...I'm not scared.
I think I've been pretty cooperative.
I'd just like to know where we're going.
Nice.
ALAN: Dave. I'm Alan Reed,
White House communications director.
And this is Bob Alexander,
our chief of staff.
We met earlier at the hotel tonight,
remember?
Can I get you something to drink?
You sure? Coke, mineral water?
Something like that?
I'm fine.
But Dave, something has come up
and I think we need to talk about it.
I'm so sorry.
I know I wasn't supposed to talk...
- ...but I saw the crowd and I got excited...
- Heh.
No, no, no,
we're not upset with you, Dave.
We think you did a terrific job.
Don't we, Bob?
- Terrific.
- In fact, we think you did such a good job...
...that we would like to...
...extend things a little.
- Extend things?
BOB: - Yes.
Extend them.
Come here.
Try it out.
- Try it out?
ALAN: - Go ahead.
How's that feel?
Well, very nice.
Dave...
...the reason we invited you here tonight
is because...
...something has happened
to the president.
- Oh, my God.
- I know.
I know, it's difficult for all of us...
...but sometimes we need to put
our personal feelings aside and focus...
...on the good of the country.
What happened?
It's actually kind of serious, Dave.
I'm afraid the president's
not in very good shape.
- Will he be all right?
- Oh, yeah.
- Probably.
- We think so.
Yes.
Oh.
Dave.
Sometimes we need our friends...
...and even our enemies, to feel...
...safe and secure.
We need them to feel
like they can go to bed at night...
...knowing that President Mitchell
is fully in control.
We need them to feel like...
...he's sitting right here...
...in this chair.
Hey.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Uh....
What about the vice-president?
Vice-president?
We didn't want to have to tell you this...
...but the vice-president
is mentally unbalanced.
- No.
ALAN: - I'm afraid so.
- Really?
ALAN & BOB: - Yes.
- Crazy?
- Certifiable.
How much do you usually get paid?
I don't know.
Depends. Uh...
Usually it's a barter kind of thing.
Is this legal?
Dave.
Have you ever driven
through a red light, huh?
You know, on an empty road...
...when there's nobody around
and you know it's safe?
I'm not sure. I might have.
Well, let's say....
Let's say your mother
is in the car and you...
...have to get her to the hospital.
You'd do it then for sure, wouldn't you?
Yes, I guess I would.
Now, let's say...
...the whole country...
...is in the car.
The entire United States of America.
- In the car?
- In the car.
I see what you mean.
Dave.
The country is sick.
And you're gonna get it to the hospital.
These are the private quarters.
The president's bedroom is on that
side, the first lady's is over there.
- First lady?
- Don't worry, you won't even see her.
They barely talk anymore.
DAVE: You're kidding.
BOB: It happens.
And this is where you'll be sleeping.
- Hmm.
- You all right?
- It's very nice.
- Come this way.
I'm sure you'll be comfortable here.
We'll be back to get you first thing
in the morning.
The Secret Service man
is right outside the door.
Good night, Mr. President.
Good night.
ALAN:
Sleep tight.
DAVE:
Thank you.
Whoa.
MAN [OVER PHONE]: - Yes, Mr. President.
- Uh, nothing. Good night.
Nothing.
Good night.
ALAN: At 10:45 last night, President Mitchell,
coming home from the Monroe Hotel...
...where he was giving a speech
to the American Legal Counsel...
...suffered what doctors describe
as a minor circulatory problem of the head.
Reports that he had suffered
a severe stroke are erroneous.
Doctors report that he should be up
and back to his normal schedule soon.
Now, let me stress again,
this is a minor medical problem.
The president has complete use
of his faculties...
...and retains full executive authority.
Any questions?
The White House classifies
the president's condition...
...as a slight circulatory problem
of the head.
While technically a stroke...
...White House spokesmen say the
president's condition is far from serious...
...and he should be up and about
sometime soon.
Do you know how many different
kinds of laws we've broken?
It's simple, Alan.
We send the vice-president
to Africa or something.
We dig up some dirt on him
and then we force him to resign...
...and get our president
to nominate a new one.
The whole thing
takes a couple of weeks.
You mean, we get Dave
to nominate you as vice-president?
- I was a senator, you know?
- Oh, I know.
And when our poor president
has another stroke...
...of course this time
much more serious...
...our newly appointed VP becomes....
Jeez.
What about containment, Al?
Thanks.
Okay. We got the nurses for 50 grand
apiece, and the doctors for 100.
- The older guy wanted head of the CDC.
- Is that everybody?
Duane's guys,
he's got them all under control.
Good. What about her?
Her?
Oh, the first lady?
She was giving a speech at Bryn Mawr.
I managed to catch her before she left.
And?
I told her his blood pressure went up
after a little incident at the hotel.
She seems to hate him now
more than ever.
Fine.
Everybody else is buying
the "minor stroke" story.
Let's hope this yutz can pull it off.
DOCTOR: These are amazing results.
I must say, Mr. President...
...even for a man with a minor stroke...
...you seem to have made
a remarkable recovery.
Oh, that's great.
I'm feeling much better.
No signs of paralysis.
No circulatory changes.
Your ECG is completely normal...
...and, uh, your blood pressure
has even gone down.
Have you been exercising recently?
Yes. I mean...
...bicycling and, uh...
...weight lifting.
Looking after the diet. Uh....
Polo, climbing.
Like that.
DOCTOR: Well, judging by these tests,
I see no reason why you can't, uh...
...return to work
within the next couple days.
- Great.
BOB: - Good.
Good.
BOB: Uh, Mr. President.
ALAN: Mr. President.
[DAVE WHISTLES
Hold it.
- Remember everybody's name, faces?
- Yeah.
Keep it simple.
Course. Watch.
- Morning, ladies.
- Mr. President.
Diane.
- Good to see you.
- Well, welcome back, sir.
Good to be back. Just a false alarm.
Nothing to be worried about.
- Clara.
- Good morning, Mr. President.
- Nice to see you.
- You too, sir.
- It's good to be alive, isn't it?
- Yes, sir.
Randi.
Oh, good morning, Mr. President.
I was really worried.
- I didn't know what was going on.
- Heh.
I'm so glad that you're feeling better.
- Why didn't you call me?
DAVE: - Well, uh....
- You really had me worried.
- I'm fine. Well....
RANDI:
I was really worried.
- What's with her?
- Don't worry.
She's emotional.
She's attached to the president.
- Remember, you are the president.
DAVE: - Ah.
Okay, let's get back to work.
Sick time is done.
Let's call the... Whoa.
False alarm. I'm fine. Everything's fine.
He's okay.
BOB:
Let's go over it again, huh?
You met a girl.
You fell in love.
- And we're going away on a holiday.
- For a month.
- A month?
- Right. Don't embellish.
Um, do I need to dial nine?
ALICE:
As soon as we sat down...
...he pulls out this ring
and I got so emotional...
[PHONE RINGING
...that I had to ask the waiter
to bring over another napkin.
Hang on.
Kovic Temps.
Oh, hi, Dave. Where are you?
You met who?
You're going where?
Cancun?
Oh, I think that's great.
She's very special. She's beautiful.
She's a princess.
She's, uh, really exotic and wonderful.
Uh....
She's, uh.... She's Polynesian.
Well, half Polynesian
and, uh, half American.
She's, uh, Amnesian.
Hang up.
Uh, she has a hang-up
about the royalty thing.
BOB: - Hang up the phone.
- Don't talk about that when you meet her.
I gotta go now. The plane's leaving.
Call you later. Bye.
It worked.
He's in love.
Thank God.
President continued his convalescence...
...resting in the White House
for the second day.
His personal physician pronounced
him in perfectly good health.
I have examined him thoroughly...
...and I don't believe that I have ever seen
the president in better shape.
REPORTER [ON TV]: The president was able to
attend to some official business on Wednesday...
...and continues to be briefed
on all areas of national concern.
The upper house and the lower house.
Senators are elected to six-year terms
and congressmen are elected to two.
Judiciary?
ALAN:
Veterans Affairs?
- Mark Davis.
- Agriculture.
Agriculture? Uh, uh, uh....
Cows, cows, calves, Metcalf.
Lawrence Metcalf. He's right there.
REPORTER [ON TV]: So confident is the
White House about the president's recovery...
...that the vice-president has been sent
on a 12-nation African goodwill tour.
This is Sander Vanocur
at the White House.
BOB: First thing we'll go
over is the mannerisms.
Alan has worked out
a sort of training program.
DAVE: Great.
BOB: This is the briefing room.
It's where the president
holds most of his press conferences.
This may seem a bit strange at first...
...but, uh, even professional politicians
have trouble getting used to the...
A teleprompter.
- A teleprompter. Is it hooked up?
- No, I don't think so.
As I was saying, nobody expects
you to be Bill Mitchell overnight.
The most important thing to
remember is his general presence.
- Presence.
- Right.
Now, whenever he stands at a podium...
...President Mitchell always has
one hand in the pocket of his coat.
That's at a press conference. Otherwise,
they're almost always on the podium.
Um, I'm not certain about that.
Remember the convention speech?
"An America,
stronger than the one we were given.
An America,
prouder than the one we found."
Right on the podium.
Except on "America," he points.
You know, that is very good.
Oh, I love that speech.
Thanks. I wrote it.
- You did?
- Yeah.
It's great.
"Somewhere, there is a distant light...
...guiding us through this rocky shoal.
America isn't what we say here tonight.
It's in the faces and the smiles
of a Sunday afternoon.
It's in the gentle kindness...
...of the family kitchen...
...as we gather together...
...when the sun goes down."
Can I keep this?
- Thought I wasn't gonna see her.
ALAN: - It's five minutes.
She walks in, you wave
to the press, she leaves.
The first lady. I mean, uh,
couldn't I start with a cousin?
She hardly ever sees him.
She won't have a chance to tell.
Stop whining.
If you can convince her,
you can convince anybody.
All right.
We're ready for Mrs. Mitchell.
As soon as she comes in, we'll
move you out to the balcony.
All you have to say is,
"Thanks for doing this, Ellen."
- "Thanks for doing this, Ellen."
- Exactly.
She doesn't always like this stuff.
It might soften her up.
"Thanks for doing this, Ellen."
Why can't you die from a stroke
like everybody else?
What are you staring at?
Uh, ah, Mrs. Mitchell,
we're gonna do it right out here.
Who was she?
Another patriotic secretary?
Hmm?
Thank you for doing this, Ellen.
Go to hell, Bill.
- I think we can get started now.
- Oh.
You can tell these two pit vipers
that this is the last one of these...
...I'll be doing for a while.
Okay.
You're doing just fine.
[CROWD APLAUDING
AND CHATTERING]
Wave.
REPORTER 1: Mr. President.
REPORTER 2: Mr. President.
REPORTER 3: Mr. President.
REPORTER 4: Mr. President.
- Mr. President, how are you feeling?
- Fine.
- Ready to get back to work?
ALAN [WHISPERS]:
You bet.
I'm out of here.
Shit.
Will you be making decisions?
Are you back in charge?
REPORTER 5: Mr. President.
REPORTER 6: Mr. President.
- Go!
- Go, go.
Go, go, go.
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
Don't you have anything to say to me?
Thank you for doing this, Ellen.
You don't change, do you, Bill?
She hates me.
[IN UNISON]
Yes.
DAVE:
Wave to the camera. Wave to the camera.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Okay. Okay.
Here we go. First off,
we're gonna talk to Ted...
...on the, uh, new
Land Management Legislation.
- Ted.
TED: - Yes, sir.
I think if you refer to Item 3
on the memorandum...
...you'll be delighted
to notice that the....
MAN:
Mr. President, slip your arms in there...
...and the machine will do
everything your arms do.
[CROWD LAUGHING]
I once caught a fish...
...this big.
This is great.
[SINGING THE KINGSMEN'S "LOUIE LOUIE"]
Louie, Louie
Whoa, baby
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Everybody!
[ALL SINGING] We gotta go
DAVE [IN NORMAL VOICE]: Yeah!
[ALL SINGING]
Aye-yi-yi-yi
DAVE:
Good boy!
Whoa! Ha, ha.
Got you!
This guy has had a rebirth.
This is a different fella in the White House.
It doesn't happen often, Bob,
but you're right.
There's a transformation. Don't know
what they're putting in the water.
Nothing to do the water
or anything else you drank.
He has faced death in the eye
and been transformed by it.
- Your boss looks better since the stroke.
- Thanks, Mr. Speaker.
- He's doing well.
- Thanks.
- Tell him I send my best.
- I will.
- Good luck.
- Good to see you.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING AND APLAUDING]
Let me ask you a question now
right off the bat.
What is with President
Mitchell lately, huh?
Has this guy been having too many
Happy Meals for lunch or what?
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
Let's talk a little bit about desserts.
What you don't want to do
is eat doughnuts.
No doughnuts.
DAVE:
Thank you, Arnold.
Arnold, thank you so much.
- Want to Indian-wrestle?
- Heh.
Whoa!
ANNOUNCER [ON PA]: Throwing
out the ceremonial first pitch...
...the President of the United States.
[CROWD CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
MAN: From the nation's capital,
The McLaughlin Group.
An unrehearsed program presenting
inside opinions and forecasts...
...on major issues of the day.
Here's the moderator, John McLaughlin.
Issue one, the new Bill Mitchell.
Two weeks after his brush with death...
...the president is suddenly bounding
around the country...
...with the energy of a
high-school track star.
Is this merely overcompensation...
...or the indefatigable greatness
of a truly great man?
McLAUGHLIN [ON TV]:
Freddie Barnes?
John, the illness just crystallized
his thinking about his own presidency.
He realized he didn't have
to be a zombie.
He can show some life,
even act like a child.
MAN: He's showing the strength of character
he did after he got elected.
BAENES: The guy got sick, right?
He recovered from his illness.
He is now rejuvenated.
McLAUGHLIN: On a political
rehabilitation scale of zero to ten...
...rate the rehabilitation of our president.
It's an eight. The zombie is gone.
It's a three.
The zombie will return.
McLAUGHLIN: Chris.
CHRIS: I think it's 86.
- He's still out to lunch, but looking good.
McLAUGHLIN: - The answer is eight.
DAVE:
So the, uh...
...first lady and the president....
What is that?
How long has that been going on?
I can't say.
You mean, you don't know
or you can't say?
I can't say.
Ah, can't say.
So, uh, your job is to protect the president
all the time? That's your whole job?
Yes.
- Have a gun?
- Yes.
Ever use it?
Not yet.
You know, I've always wondered
about you guys.
The way they say you'd take a bullet
for the president.
What about it?
Is that really true?
I mean, would you let yourself
be killed to save his life?
Certainly.
So that means now you would
get killed for me too.
ALAN: It would be wonderful for
you and great for the president.
I'm sorry, the only time that I have available
is the 25th.
- You out of your mind?
ALAN: - That's the best I can do.
I'm gonna get back to you.
I gotta go. Bye.
You scheduled a whole
day with the first lady?
- It's a homeless shelter.
- Oh, excuse me.
It's gonna be great.
Caring about his wife,
spending time on her favorite issues.
I don't want him caring about his wife.
What about the vice-president?
The vice-president?
Well, you, uh, remember that First Liberty stuff
we almost got nailed on?
Yeah.
I just dumped it on him instead.
- When does it break?
- Couple of days.
Look at Dave's tracking polls.
They'll burn up in your hands.
Seventy-three percent with seniors,
84 with working mothers.
Alan, we still gotta control this guy.
[SIGHS
Why are you doing this, Bill?
What?
Since when do you care
about the homeless?
- I care about the homeless.
- Oh, yeah.
I'm sure it's keeping you up nights.
[SIGHS
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
CHILDREN [IN UNISON]:
Good morning, Mr. and Mrs. President.
Good morning, kids. How are you?
Thank you for that nice welcome.
They're all kids.
That's right, Bill. Kids are homeless too.
- Where are the parents?
- Hi.
A lot of them are in shelters, but some
of them are still out on the street.
Shake hands with the president.
DAVE: Hi, there.
BOY: How are you?
- Hello, Mr. President.
DAVE: - Hello.
- What's your name?
BRANDON: - Brandon.
How do you do?
One of the things that happens
when kids become homeless...
...is they start to lose
communication skills.
So here at Helping Hand,
they play a lot of games...
...that encourage the kids to relate
to each other and to express themselves.
Oh, no, poor Joe.
He has no hair.
He has no...
CHILDREN:
Eyes.
MRS. TRAVIS: Right. Very good.
Very good. Let's try one more.
Everybody together now.
Everybody pay attention.
Here we go. Oh, no, poor Joe.
- He has no...
CHILDREN [IN UNISON]: - Feet.
MRS. TRAVIS:
Great, great, great. All right.
Hi, there.
What's your name?
- David.
- David?
Great name.
What are you doing over here, David?
Nothing.
Hey, guys. Not now, okay?
Thanks.
Don't you like playing
games with the other kids?
No.
Do you like magic?
It's okay.
Okay.
Watch this.
Where'd it go?
The answer is in this riddle.
What can run all day
without ever getting tired?
Do you know?
I'll give you a hint.
It's not your ear.
And it's not your mouth.
My nose.
Your nose. Exactly.
And look, oh, there it is.
See? It was there all the time.
It went up in the air.
DAVID:
And fell on my nose.
Yeah.
Is the first lady still there?
DAVID:
Mm-hm.
Does she look mad?
DAVID: Hmm, not really.
DAVE: Good.
DAVE: First cover of Time magazine
and I need a shave.
Tough little moment with the dog.
Here you are on the cover.
- Oh, yeah?
- Front page.
- That's you right behind me.
- Where, what?
See? Okay, here's me.
Now look over here.
You see those 20 guys and then, bing,
there you are right behind the machine.
STEVENSON: - That's me?
- Yeah, looking very strong and, uh...
...forbidding.
Have you ever thought
about wearing a sweater?
Just kind of blend in more. Um....
Stand up. There you are again,
coming off the helicopter.
Sweaters make my neck look too thick.
Really? You got a sweater vest?
You could wear a tie.
Think a sweater vest
would look good on me?
Do you have the paperwork
on Simpson-Gardner?
Uh, excuse me.
Yeah, hold on. It's right here.
- Just came in.
- I think he's gonna veto it.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[GRUNTS]
Bill Mitchell...
...votes no.
[HUMMING "HAIL TO THE CHIEF"]
DAVE [SINGING]: Hail to the chief
He's the one we all say "Hail" to
We all say "Hail", because
he keeps himself so clean.
He's got the power
That's why he's in the shower
And he's just
I can't believe you would
do something like this.
- Not even you.
DAVE: - Aah!
How could you?
- How could I what?
- Don't patronize me.
I'm not one of your little bimbos.
And turn around.
I'm talking to you.
Will you please turn around?
Turn around.
You know, if you want
to be the same old selfish...
...bastard, um...
[ELLEN SIGHS]
...go ahead. I've gotten used to that.
But don't put on this "man of the people"
routine and then do something like this.
I don't understand.
You know very well that was
not a Works Bill you vetoed.
That would've given
those children homes.
When I think of that spectacle you put on
with the little boy and the magic trick.
Wait a minute.
What's wrong with the magic trick?
It was some magic.
You made their funding disappear.
Look, if there's been some mistake...
There's no mistake, Bill.
When you veto their funding,
that's not a mistake.
When you hurt someone intentionally,
that is not a mistake.
Look....
Ellen. Ellen!
Ellen. Ellen. Ellen.
Call Bob. Call Alan.
Tell them I want to see them now.
But it's 10:30 at night.
You got it.
What the hell is this?
The New York Times.
No, this.
ALAN:
"President vetoes Works Bill."
We vetoed that?
No.
We didn't veto anything.
Dave, these things get awfully complicated
sometimes, and I think you have to...
That shelter was in this bill.
- Take care of this.
- Believe me, Dave, if we could have...
DAVE:
Lots of shelters were in this bill.
- Listen, you little shit.
- Dave. Dave.
The budget is a very complicated thing.
Even I don't understand it sometimes.
Occasionally, we have to make some cuts.
And in order...
- But we went there.
ALAN: - Dave.
- We saw those kids.
- Yes, you did.
And if you can find a way to cut
$650 million from the federal budget...
...you can keep your lousy shelters.
Okay.
Oh, and by the way...
...don't you ever send for me again.
MAN: - Can I help you?
- I'm here to see the president.
Is that right?
He asked me to come.
- And your name?
- Blum. Blum. Murray Blum. B-L-U-M.
MURRAY: - Come on, Dave.
- Sit down. It's okay.
- Sit down.
- I don't want to sit.
- I don't want to. Please.
- Murray, come on.
Okay, fine.
[WHISPERS]
This place is probably bugged.
It's not bugged. It's okay, Murray.
You could get in so much trouble
if they find out.
- With who?
- The government.
I'm the government.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Wild, huh?
Murray, I can't tell you the whole story.
It's kind of a national emergency thing.
You've gotta help me cut the budget.
[IN NORMAL VOICE
You gotta cut the budget?
Yeah. About $650 million.
You look hungry.
Diane, could you come in here
for a minute?
Just watch.
- Yes, Mr. President?
- Yes, uh, we need two copies of the budget.
And, uh, could you arrange for dinner for two
in the dining room?
Right away, sir.
And we have work to do
so we're not to be disturbed.
- I understand, sir.
- Oh, and, uh....
Do you think they could, uh, rustle up some
fresh bratwurst and some hot mustard?
- I think that can be arranged.
DAVE: - Thanks, Diane.
- I love bratwurst.
- I know.
Dave, I've been over this a bunch
of times. It doesn't add up.
Who does these books? If I ran my
business this way, I'd be out of business.
So, what can we do?
I see a lot of places you could save,
but I can't make those choices.
I'm not the president. I mean....
You know, I mean, I'm not, uh, the one,
you know, pretending to be the president.
Ah.
I understand.
Let me give it a try.
- You?
- Yeah.
Let me try.
- Okay. You want to try?
- Yeah.
All right. All right.
Here's something right here.
Look at that.
[BOB HUMMING
MAN 1:
Good morning, Bob. How are you?
MAN 2:
All right.
Good morning.
Drew.
It's a work of art.
Look at this. "Vice-president's office linked
to S&L scandal." Alan, you're a genius.
We're on our way.
Say, what's with the cameras?
Hundredth cabinet meeting.
It'll be a nice touch.
- Oh, right.
MAN 3: - Morning.
ALL:
Good morning.
Morning.
- Good morning.
ALL: - Good morning, Mr. President.
- How is everyone?
ALL: - Fine, thank you.
DAVE:
Good, ahem.
[DAVE CLEARS THROAT]
Okay. Before we get started, uh...
- ...I'd like to go over the budget.
WOMAN: - Budget?
- Do we have anything on the budget today?
- No, I don't think so.
Now, I, uh....
I think I've found some ways to put back
the homeless section...
...of the Simpson-Gardner Works Bill.
Mr. President, I don't believe
that's on your agenda today.
No, it's a last minute change, Bob.
Uh, now, uh, the way I see it,
we need $650 million in order to, uh...
...keep the project.
Now, some of this can be done.
- Uh, through simple changes...
- It's all right.
...in our cash management.
Uh, for example...
...uh, according to the OMB,
we've got, uh, 17 defense contractors...
...who are delinquent in their contracts.
Uh, now, is this true, Frank?
Uh, I believe so, yes.
So even though they're late...
...we keep paying them on time?
Well, in a sense....
Yeah.
Okay, now,
instead of giving them money...
...for something they haven't finished...
...we could hold back that cash,
stick it in interest-bearing...
Mr. President.
Yes.
Nothing.
Great.
Uh, like I was saying, if we took that cash...
...and stuck it
in even an ordinary savings account...
...we'd be making
$23 million a month in interest.
Well, technically, that's true, but, uh....
Oh.
I suppose it's true.
Okay. Okay.
Okay, so that's $23 million...
...times 12 months.
Okay. Good.
Uh....
Unfortunately, money management's
only gonna get us halfway to our goal.
In order to get the rest of the money,
we're gonna have...
...to start making some tough choices.
Uh, the Commerce Department.
Yes, Mr. President?
Uh, you're spending $47 million
on an ad campaign...
..."to boost consumer confidence
in the American auto industry."
Yes, sir, uh....
It's designed to bolster
individual, uh, confidence...
...in a previous domestic
automotive purchase.
So we're spending $47 million
so that somebody can feel better...
...about a car
that they've already bought?
- Yes, but I wouldn't categorize it that way.
- No, no, I'm sure that's important...
...but I don't want to tell some 8-year-old
kid he's gotta sleep in the street...
...because we want people
to feel better about their car.
Do you want to tell him that?
No, sir.
No, I sure don't.
DAVE: Of course not.
Well, then, that's another 47 million.
So this is good. We're doing good.
We're doing real good. We're on our way.
Okay, let me just add
that, uh, to the tally here.
That'll be plus 47....
Nine.
Five, carry the one...
...makes $656 million...
...which means we can keep the program.
MAN 1: Thank you, sir.
MAN 2: Thank you for your help.
Well done.
Thanks.
Thank you.
JEFF:
Uh, excuse me.
Um....
- Mrs. Mitchell.
- What is it, Jeff?
You're not gonna believe
what your husband just did.
I'm gonna kill him.
[CHUCKLES]
You can't kill a president.
He's not a president.
He's an ordinary person.
I can kill an ordinary person.
- Bob.
- I can kill 100 ordinary people.
Bob.
He's only doing what you told him to do.
What I told him to?
I heard you. You said, "Cut $650
million off the federal budget...
- ...and you can keep your shelters."
- I didn't mean it.
Why would I want
to save a homeless shelter?
He was only doing his job.
His job? His job? It's not his job!
It's my job!
Bob.
Will you calm down?
Was he on the Trilateral Commission?
Was he a senator?
Was he in "Who's Who"
nine years in a row? Hello, Judy.
- Hi, Judy.
JUDY: - Hi.
- I'll destroy him. I'll shred the bastard.
- Don't do this.
- I'll lock him away for good.
- Then we'll all go to jail together.
What do you mean by that?
Just what you think I mean.
Are you threatening me?
Well....
Yeah.
I guess I am.
Thanks, Murray.
You did great.
Hey, maybe you can come back sometime.
We can go to, uh, Camp David or something.
- Camp David?
- Yeah.
Get out of here as fast as you can.
DAVE:
Come on, seven.
Come on, number six.
We both lose.
I saw your light was on, so I just....
Mind if I sit down?
Uh....
No. Please.
Would you like, uh....
No, thanks.
[DAVE SIGHS
That was quite a thing you did today.
Anyone would've done that.
I don't think so.
You helped a lot of people.
You know...
...it kind of reminded me...
...of that thing you did a long
time ago in the state legislature.
Oh, yeah.
Hmm, me too.
You weren't in the state legislature.
Hi, I'm Ellen Mitchell.
Who are you?
Look, I'll make this easy on you.
I never see him anymore.
I barely know him anymore.
I'd just kind of like
to know where he is.
This could get me into a lot of trouble.
Open it, please, Duane.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry, you're not allowed in here.
- Mr. Alexander left strict instructions.
STEVENSON: - I'll explain it to you later.
Oh, no.
What happened?
It was a stroke.
It's pretty bad.
I don't understand.
Is he going to...?
I'm sorry.
You're leaving?
I'm not the first lady anymore.
I shouldn't be here.
Where are you going?
[SIGHS
Home.
DAVE:
Where's home?
ELLEN:
Look, can we stop with the 20 questions?
Because I'm really not in the mood.
Souvenirs. Towels and stuff.
You're leaving too?
I never wanted to hurt anybody.
Heck, I even thought I was helping.
[WHIMPERING]
You know...
...you make this little
deal with yourself that...
...you can put up with
all the other women...
...and you can even do without a life.
You can even do without children...
...because you believe
in what you're doing and you think....
You thought you had a chance
to help people.
How are you gonna get home?
ELLEN:
Um....
[CHUCKLES]
I don't know. I hadn't really...
...thought it out that far.
ELLEN:
Are you sure this goes somewhere?
They say LBJ used it all the time.
[BELL BUZZES]
DAVE: Duane said he'd leave
a car right over there.
When did you, uh, first know?
I mean, about me?
In the car, I think.
On the way to the shelter,
you looked at my legs.
Bill stopped looking a long time ago.
I thought maybe it was in the shower, heh.
No.
[POLICE SIREN WAILS]
Oh, my God.
- What?
- Police.
- What'd you do?
- I don't know.
POLICEMAN: See your driver's license, sir?
DAVE: Here, sir.
And registration.
- Um....
- No, uh, I, uh, must've left it at home.
Step out of the car, please.
- Both of us?
- Yes, both of you, please.
Well, you may not be aware...
...but there is a posted "No left turn"
sign just down the block here.
You went right through it.
DAVE:
Oh.
- I don't know what I was thinking.
- Oh, my gosh.
Oh.
We're look-alikes.
Heh, we don't look like
each other, but I mean...
I know what you think. People hire us to
impersonate the president and first lady.
- We work out of an agency.
- You sure look like him.
Thanks. We work very hard at it.
I mean, uh, she....
She got her hair cut to look...
Perfect match.
We just, uh, played the Sapperstein wedding.
They loved us.
We did.... We did our, uh,
Club Med routine...
...where the first lady and the president
go to Club Med, and there's Bill Mitchell.
He's like, "At 0700,
I want an hour of volleyball.
And then at 0830, I want a complete
briefing on the whole surf situation."
And then the big finale
at, uh, the Talent Club.
[SINGING]
The sun will come out tomorrow
Bet your bottom dollar that tomorrow
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I'm okay.
[SINGING] There'll be sun
Just thinkin' about tomorrow
Clears away the cobwebs.
And the sorrow
Till there's none tomorrow.
[SINGING] Tomorrow, I love you
Tomorrow, it's only a day away
[DAVE SCATS]
[BOTH SINGING]
Tomorrow, tomorrow, we love you, tomorrow
You are only a day away
[CROWD APPLAUDING ]
Thank you. Thanks.
We haven't worked out the final harmony.
- This is a full-time job?
- Uh, yeah, lately.
Lately, it's been, uh, pretty much full-time.
Mr. and Mrs. Kovic,
I'm not gonna give you a ticket.
You're not?
I think you ought to save
all the money you have.
[CHUCKLES]
- Not gonna give a ticket.
- Right.
- Says we should save.
- Thank you.
Thanks. That's very funny, heh.
- Listen, you're very good.
- Right.
- But she needs a lot of work.
DAVE: - Yes, I know. She's kind of new at it.
Now, you drive safely, huh?
Thank you. Thank you, officer.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
Uh, I'm not sure I'm this hungry.
Wait.
This is a very special sandwich.
This is good.
What's in it?
That's a secret.
ELLEN:
You have a lot of secrets.
DAVE:
I guess.
So, what do you do the rest of the time?
You mean,
when I'm not running the country?
Mm-hm.
I run a temp agency.
You know, secretaries and stuff.
- You mean, you find people jobs?
- Yes.
ELLEN:
Hmm.
Is that funny?
It's just more than most people
do around here.
[SCOFFS]
Don't get carried away.
I'm not that good at it.
And your family?
I mean, I assume you're married.
I was.
Once.
It didn't take.
You know, Dave...
It is Dave, isn't it?
I can't keep all of this a secret.
Yeah, I know.
I liked doing it though.
I mean, not the fancy stuff
with all the helicopters...
...and the TV cameras...
...but I liked saving that shelter.
I liked helping people
that I hadn't even met before.
Just then, I felt like I wasn't
pretending anymore.
I don't think you were pretending.
What would you do if
you were still in there?
I mean, if you had one more chance
to be president...
...what would you do then?
Lots of things.
Excuse me. You can't stop here.
Look, there's no visitors at...
- Hi.
MAN: - Mr. President?
- I'm sorry, sir, I didn't realize that...
- Just getting a little fresh air.
MAN:
Certainly, sir.
I was wondering, if you don't mind,
how did you get...?
The president wanted some ice cream.
You make a nice president, Dave Kovic.
Thanks.
See you.
WOMAN: We are delighted you're visiting
the White House.
Let's keep moving, folks. We're walking.
A million visitors go through
the White House every year...
...making it the most frequently
toured home in the country.
We're walking, we're walking
and we're stopping.
Whatever changes
from one administration to the next...
...the White House always maintains
its dignity.
We're walking.
He's walking. He's Bob Alexander,
our White House chief of staff.
I can't believe it!
What an honor, really, for all of you.
We're walking.
Forty-two presidents and their wives
have lived in the White House.
I had nothing to do with this.
He called it himself. I swear to God.
What do you think you're doing?
You mean, the press conference?
I, uh, have a couple of ideas I wanted
to share with the country.
Share?
You don't call a press conference.
I call a press conference.
You're nothing. Do you understand?
You're nobody.
I'm not nobody.
You're lint!
You're a flea!
You're a blip!
Well...
...maybe I am.
But you're fired.
What?
I said you're fired. Go on, get out of here.
- Oh, I'm fired?
- Yup.
You're fired.
- Fine.
- Fine?
Fine.
The whole press corps is right out there.
Should I go tell them?
Or did you want to?
[DOOR OPENS
Darling, they're waiting in the Press Room.
I really think you ought to get in there.
Oh.
Bob.
I'm sorry. I thought we were alone.
I'd like your resignation on my
desk by the time I get back.
Don't touch anything on that desk.
- How are you?
- How you doing?
Hi.
- Hey, guys. What's up?
- It's the vice-president.
- What could it be?
- The ex-vice-president.
He'll be a prison reformer
in Denver in a year.
ALAN:
Okay, they're coming. Let's go.
Good luck.
[CAMERA SHUTTERS CLICKING
Thanks for coming on such short notice.
I, uh....
I'd like to begin with an
announcement that, uh...
I've, uh...
...asked Bob Alexander to resign
as White House chief of staff.
[REPORTERS CHATTERING INDISTICTLY]
Over the last few months, Bob and I
have come to believe in different things.
He thinks this country's fine and we
should go about doing business as usual.
I just don't feel that way.
Not anymore.
Because, hey, things aren't fine.
We've got so many problems, that we
don't even want to look at them anymore.
They just blend together
into this great, big noise...
...and pretty soon we can't even
hear ourselves think.
But that's not even the worst part.
The worst part is that we....
We feel we can't do anything about it.
And that's a tragedy...
...because we can.
But we don't know where to start.
Maybe that's what it is.
But I have an idea...
...of where we can start.
From today...
...I'm gonna make it the responsibility
of this government...
...to find a job for every American
who wants one.
[CHATTERING INDISTICTLY]
Have you ever seen the
look on somebody's face...
...the day that they finally get a job?
I've had some experience with this.
They look like they could fly.
And it's not about the paycheck. It's about
respect. It's about looking in the mirror...
...and knowing that you've done
something valuable with your day.
And if one person could start to feel
that way, and then another person...
...then pretty soon all these other
problems we're facing may not seem so...
...impossible.
You don't really know how
much you can do until you...
...stand up and decide to try.
That's it. So let's get to work.
Thank you.
ALL:
Mr. President.
Thank you, Mr. President.
In the boldest initiative yet of the
new Bill Mitchell administration...
...the president has proposed a
comprehensive full employment program...
...unparalleled since the days of FDR.
The proposal brought swift
reaction, here on Capitol Hill.
President Mitchell's right. Putting people
to work is what we ought to be doing.
Better to have a job
than collecting a welfare check.
We're here trying to carry the water for him.
I've carried water.
And then now to say this.
This guy's out to lunch.
He's, you know.... Somebody's...
The lights are on, but nobody's home.
I love it. It's great.
All we've gotta do is cut Star Wars.
I want to look at Mitchell's proposal.
Like the program I presented
when I ran for president.
Has the president taken leave of his
faculties? I ask you, Eleanor Clift.
This is the definition
of modern leadership.
Set out a bold goal and you don't
say how you're going to get there.
They tried this in Russia
and wrecked the country.
I wonder if the Communists got him.
If you look at a
photograph of Bill Mitchell...
...taken before the stroke
and one right after...
LARRY: - What?
- ...you will see distinct differences.
Are you saying this is a conspiracy?
Yes, I am saying this is a conspiracy.
Do you think you're a little paranoid?
No. Have you compared the photographs,
Larry?
[ELLEN HUMMING "TOMORROW"]
Pfft, this is crazy.
The U.S .News hammered us,
but they're always tough on that.
- Rosenthal loved us in The Times.
- Oh, that's good.
RANDI: Mr. President,
Mr. Nance is waiting for you inside.
- Ah. Who?
- The vice-president.
[BOTH WHISPERING]
- Oh, the...
Nance. I thought...
Uh, get my, uh, I want my ears checked.
Would you do that?
Sorry, I didn't understand.
Ever since the stroke I get a little...
[MUTTERS]
Oh, my God.
Mr. President...
- ...these are a gift from the King of Togo.
- Oh.
- Fertility beads.
- Ah.
These are from the people of Burundi.
Oh.
Thank you.
They know hats in Burundi. Look at this.
Mr. President,
may I speak frankly with you?
Yes, please. Sit down.
It's good to see you.
I know we haven't always gotten along.
I know we've disagreed politically.
And I suppose I know
what you think of me personally.
But I've always tried to respect
the role you wanted me to play.
When I've disagreed with this
administration, I've kept it to myself.
When you wanted my support,
you always had it.
Yes.
Damn it, Bill.
How could you do
something like this to me?
- Do what?
- Come on, we're not children.
I didn't have anything to do with this
First Liberty nonsense and you know it.
- First Liberty.
- All I've got is my integrity, Bill.
Okay?
That's all I have left.
Now, I don't know why you've turned
your attack dogs on me.
- They're not my attack dogs.
- What?
I'll take care of this.
- We made it up.
- What do you mean, you made it up?
Well, we had to, Dave.
The guy's a Boy Scout.
DAVE:
But, Alan, this is wrong.
Wrong?
Oh, I know. It looks awfully bad
and I'm really embarrassed...
...but it was Bob's idea.
[REPORTERS CHATTERING INDISTICTLY]
MAN:
Have you spoken to the president?
When I first began to
look into the allegations...
...concerning First Liberty Savings
and Loan...
...I thought the wrongdoing
was restricted to the vice-president's office.
I think you better take a look at this.
But as I began to investigate,
I realized that this pattern of corruption...
...extended much higher.
I was saddened to discover at least
15 separate acts of intervention...
...by this administration...
...most with the full knowledge of
the president, and all of them illegal.
- Jesus Christ.
- Federal regulators were influenced...
...records were destroyed...
...and pressure was brought to bear...
...by President Mitchell himself.
- Now he's making stuff up about me.
- He's not.
He's not?
You mean, I did all that?
You didn't.
Bill Mitchell did.
This is a mistake.
We shouldn't be doing this right now.
I can't go into hiding.
[REPORTERS CHATTERING INDISTICTLY]
WOMAN 1:
What are you hiding?
MAN 1: Mr. President,
what did you know and when did you know it?
MAN 2:
When will you have a confession?
MAN 3:
Will you answer these allegations?
WOMAN 2:
When will you make a statement?
Is this job stuffjust a smoke screen?
MAN 4:
Mr. President, did you commit the crime?
Mr. President, I don't know any other way
to put it. This dog just won't hunt.
We may be able to hold off on this
First Liberty thing for a little while...
...but if you've been running around
with this new jobs...
Just put us on a spit
and bring in the sauce.
- If you could just wait for a couple months.
- Yeah, wait.
- Yeah.
DAVE: - No.
No, I don't want to wait a while.
We can't.
MAN: Mr. President,
I understand how you feel...
...but we're talking about
obstructing federal regulators...
...violating election laws.
I got people up on the Hill
talking impeachment.
What is with President
Mitchell lately, huh?
I know the president's supposed to serve
four years, but now it may be 15 to 20.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING AND APPLAUDING
But we make fun of the president. We
knock the president. But it's a tough job.
[ON TV] Take today. The president woke up,
broke the law, got caught, he pardoned himself.
That is a full day.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING AND APPLAUDING
ON TV]
- Oh, and now political action groups...
- Mr. President.
- May I come in?
- Oh, heh.
A dirty business we're in, sometimes.
Yeah.
Mr. President...
...whatever happens, I just wanted you
to know that I think your jobs program is...
...a wonderful idea.
Thanks.
Not many people are gonna
pay much attention now, but....
[SCOFFS]
Thanks.
Uh, uh....
Would you like to...
...sit down for a minute?
Sure.
Do you ever, uh....
Ahem.
...think back to how you got started?
Um, heh....
I was a shoe salesman.
But not very happy about it.
One day, my wife says to me:
"Why don't you try running for office?
You know?
You talk about it all the time.
Why don't you just go do it?"
So I tell my boss...
...I have a dentist appointment...
...and I go down
to the Registrar of Voters...
...on my lunch break.
Next thing I know, I'm a councilman.
- Really?
- My wife was my campaign manager.
We had a budget of $2000
with advertising.
[VANCE CHUCKLES]
[VANCE SCOFFS
How about you?
- Me?
- Yeah.
How did you get started?
Kind of the same way.
Vice-president's a good man, isn't he?
Yes.
He's a very good man.
I don't want to lose you.
The president has requested this rare,
joint session of Congress...
...so he can personally answer
the allegations raised by Bob Alexander...
...his former chief of staff.
MAN [ON TV]: Frankly, it's hard to recall
the last time both houses of Congress...
...convened without so much of an idea
of what the president plans to say.
WOMAN [ON TV]: So one Would speculate
that it's about the charges...
...against the vice-president
and president..
Those rumors have been circulating
on Capitol Hill now for several weeks.
It's time to go. Better get inside.
- It's all set with Duane?
- All set.
Everything's here.
Okay, let's go.
Relax.
Right.
- Enjoy the moment.
- Right.
- Hello, Ben.
- Big day, Bob.
- Thanks for coming. Come on in.
- I wouldn't miss it.
- You know the Claghorns?
BEN: - Of course. Of course.
Hey, Bob, what do you think?
Put that away.
Let's wait till the speech first.
The House will be in order.
Mr. Speaker,
the President of the United States.
Thank you. Thank you.
Shh, shh, shh....
Here it comes.
DAVE [ON TV]:
Mr. Speaker.
Vice-President.
Members of the Congress.
Fellow Americans.
I wish I could be here today
under different circumstances.
There are a lot of things about this
country that we should be discussing.
But I realize that's not possible now.
As all of you know, my former chief of
staff has implicated me in a scandal...
...involving
the First Liberty Savings and Loan.
Once people start talking about a scandal,
it's hard to talk about anything else.
So fine, let's talk about it.
Bob Alexander has accused me of....
Let me read this to make sure I get it right.
"lllegally influencing
government regulators...
...on behalf
of major campaign contributors...
...interfering with an ongoing
Justice Department investigation...
...and violating federal election
laws in the area of campaign finance."
Okay, let's get right to the guts of it.
Each one of these charges
is absolutely true.
[BOB CHUCKLES]
Die, you pond scum.
I'm the president, and as they say,
the buck stops here.
So I take full responsibility for
every one of my illegal actions.
But, you see, that's not the whole story.
And I think each one of you
is entitled to the whole truth.
I have here written proof...
...in the form of notes, memoranda
and personal directives...
...proving that Bob Alexander
was also involved...
...in each one of these incidents,
and in most cases, planned them as well.
Alan.
Now, allegations of wrongdoing have also
been made against Vice-President Nance.
Now, as this evidence
will prove, at no time...
...and in no way was the vice-president
involved in any of this.
Bob just made all that up.
Vice-President Nance...
...is a good and decent public servant...
...and I'd like to apologize for any pain
this may have caused him or his family.
[SPEAKING INDISTICTLY]
And while we're on the subject...
...I'd like to apologize
to the American people.
You see...
...I forgot that I was hired
to do a job for you...
...and it was just a temp job at that.
I forgot that I had 250 million people...
...who were paying me to make
their lives a little bit better.
And I didn't live up to
my part of the bargain.
See....
I think there are certain things
you should expect from your president.
I had to care more about you
than I do about me.
I had to care more about....
I had to care more about what's right
than I do about what's popular. Uh....
I ought to be willing to give up
this whole thing...
...for something I believe in...
...because if I'm not....
If I'm not...
[ALL CHATTERING INDISTICTLY]
If I'm not, then...
...maybe I don't belong here in the first...
[ALL MURMURING INDISTICTLY]
Get a doctor! Move it!
MAN 1:
Clear the aisle. Clear the aisle.
MAN 2 [ON TV]:
Calm yourselves.
[CAMERA SHUTTERS CLICKING
[SIRENS WAILING]
MAN:
Let's get him out of there.
Quickly. Quickly.
[ALL CHATTERING INDISTICTLY]
- Mitchell's that way.
MAN: - Stay back.
Well?
You okay getting home?
Yeah, it's not far.
Take care.
Dave.
I would've taken a bullet for you.
Thanks, Duane.
MAN 1 [ON TV]:
The stroke hit at 8:42 p. m...
...just as the president was concluding
his remarks to a joint session of Congress.
Spokesmen of the First Naval Hospital...
...have confirmed
it was a massive edema.
And unlike his previous stroke, it has
left the president fully incapacitated.
WOMAN [ON TV]: The nation mourned
as President William Harrison Mitchell...
...was laid to rest at Arlington
National Cemetery early this morning.
After lingering in a coma
for almost five months...
...the president succumbed Thursday
at 4:20 p.m.
MAN 2 [ON TV]: In a bittersweet ceremony in
the capital, Vice-President Gary Nance...
...was officially sworn in today
as the 45th president of the United States.
Under the terms of the 25th Amendment,
Nance has been acting with full authority...
...since Bill Mitchell's incapacitation.
The new president promises
a leadership of fairness.
VANCE [ON TV]: I plan to continue
Bill Mitchell's call to arms.
This isn't my presidency,
this is his presidency.
And I can't think of a better
way to ensure his legacy...
...than to continue the principles
he initiated.
MAN 3 [ON TV]: Bob Alexander and eight
other members of the Mitchell administration...
...were indicted on 34 counts
of election law violations...
...and obstruction ofjustice.
Ironically, the indictments came
just 48 hours after final passage...
...of the Bill Mitchell Jobs Bill...
...for a comprehensive
employment program.
We have a limited amount of buttons,
so don't put any buttons in the envelopes.
ALICE:
Honey.
WOMAN:
Dave Kobic. Time for a change.
- No, no. Kovic. Kovic.
- Kovic.
Tom. Tom.
We have a limited amount of posters.
Just put them in the really busy places.
She's terrific. She can do anything.
- Just the flyers.
- Okay, well, she's changed.
It's the middle of winter. They're gonna
turn off her heat. She needs a job.
Open. Like this. Like this. Neat. Neat.
ALICE: - Hi.
- No buttons.
Would you like to volunteer?
- Yeah, sure.
- Thanks, you're a good man.
Uh, did you get the fund-raising thing
I sent you? Yeah, City Council.
- We have flyers here.
DAVE: - Thanks. All right.
We're on a roll now.
Karen, you got a job.
WOMAN 3: - Thank you.
- It's Monday.
ALL:
And everybody works on Monday.
DAVE: - Hi.
- Hi, heh.
I understand you find people jobs?
- Well....
- This is great, heh.
Yeah, I'm, uh, running...
You look great.
I saw you on TV at the funeral and....
Well....
That's finally over.
Uh....
Uh, why don't we go into my office?
Excuse us.