(screaming and crying within)
Doktor Gruber!
Herr Doktor!
Herr West!
Raus comen!
(crash within)
Move back.
Mein Gott!
(screaming)
No, you idiots!
You'll ruin my notes!
I have to record his
vital signs!
No!
Doktor Gruber?!
Wie Gehtsen?!
Doctor Gruber?
Er ist tot.
Of course he's dead -
the dosage was too large.
- You killed him!
- No, I did not.
I gave him life.
Alright, we'll zap her again.
Charge up the paddles.
- Come on, let's go!
- Sorry, Doctor.
Hold the compressions.
Clear!
Straight line.
Alright, let's call it.
Cain.
She just needs a little more time
for the drugs to circulate.
Cain, we have done everything
that can be done for this woman.
She has not responded.
She's gone!
Cain, your optimism is touching,
but a waste of time.
A good doctor knows when to stop.
- Doctor Harris..
- Tag her...
...and take her to the morgue.
Gangway.
Mister Cain.
Hey, Ace -
I've got another one for you.
Doc Hill's in the autopsy room.
Thanks.
Don't know why they keep
locked doors around here...
...nobody wants in, and
ain't nobody gettin' out.
Yup.
I'm sorry Dan, I didn't
mean to scare you.
It wasn't bad, Dean Halsey.
I didn't know anybody was here.
You mean anybody else.
Dan, this is Herbert West. He'll be
joining you in your third year.
He was doing independent research
in Switzerland with Dr. Gruber
shortly before he died.
Mr. West, this is Daniel Cain -
- one of Miskatonic Medical's best young
hopes for the future of medicine.
- What were you researching?
- Death.
Ah, Alan! We don't see you
around here much anymore.
I was just showing our newest student,
Herbert West, the not so Grand Tour.
This should interest you, Carl -
he worked with Hans Gruber.
Ah, Mr. West?
This is our eminent brain researcher
and "grant machine"
Dr Carl Hill.
I know your work,
Dr Hill - quite well.
Your theory on the location
of the will in the brain is...
...interesting...
...though derivative of Dr Gruber's
research in the early '70s.
So derivative that in Europe
it's considered plaigerized.
And your support of the 12 minute limit
on the life of the brain stem after death...
Six to twelve minutes, Mister, uh...
- West.
Herbert West.
Frankly, Doctor, uh...
...Hill?...
...your work on brain
death is outdated.
Carl, while I remember
we're having a grand
committee meeting Thursday.
Megan and I would love it
if you came to dinner.
Well, I'd love to, Alan -
looking forward to it.
And looking forward to seeing you
in class, Mister West.
- Hi.
No! No! No!
Yes! Oh! Yes! Oh!
Oh! Rufus!
I have to go.
No, stay.
- Dad knows I'm here.
- I don't care what Dean Halsey knows.
Be resasonable.
If I didn't come home
one night...just one night.
What would he do?
Expell me?
He's out of touch
with the times.
It's just the way he is.
The world's last
living Puritan.
I really hate it.
The day that you graduate...
...the minute you get your
M.D., I'll marry you.
And I'll help you, and
I'll be with you
as much as I can until then.
I promise.
Back to Square One.
Well, at least it gives me a
chance to house break you.
House broken, eh?
I'm going to have to teach
you a lesson, My Dear.
What are you doing?
Yeaaaow!
Dan! (laughs)
Dan, stop! Don't!
(evil laugh)
Dan!
- Stop it!
- Oh, My Pretty!
I don't like that!
No!
Ah, there's not a jury in the
world that will convict me...
(laughs)
Doctor Dan!
Don't! Come on, stop!
- I'm going - I have to go!
- Come here!
Hi. Can I help you?
- You're here about the apartment?
- Yes.
Didn't we meet this morning, ah...
West.
Herbert West.
...West. Excuse me just one second.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
- I startled you.
- Yes, you did.
May I introduce my fiance,
Megan Halsey.
Miss Halsey.
Mister West.
I'm afraid the place is still
kind of a mess, Mr West.
Herbert.
So, you've just come
from Europe?
Switzerland
What was Dr Gruber like?
He was pretty famous.
Yes, pretty famous.
Does this building have a basement?
Oh, yes.
Yes
I think this will be just fine!
I have my things outside.
Shall I move in now?
Ah, look - I have to go.
I think you and Mr West
have a lot to discuss
before you decide anything.
Oh, I've decided!
- Well...I'd like to...
- You'll never even know that I'm here.
- Dan...
- That goes on the first of the month.
Mister West.
Miss Halsey?
You didn't say why
you left Switzerland.
There was no more
I could learn there.
Do we have a deal?
Done
You make the incision at
the base of the skull...
...cutting away enough of the facia...
...to get your fingers in.
And then, grasping firmly
with both hands...
...you pull the skin
forward over the head.
It's very much like peeling
a large orange.
Once the skull is
plainly visible...
...you take the bone saw...
...and you cut around
the perimeter.
And there you have it,
ladies and gentlemen...
...the human brain.
Once the brain stem of
an individual -
- I'm talking about the
reticular activating system -
- heart regulation, respiratory center -
- once these activities cease...
...the brain can only survive an
additional 6 to 12 minutes.
Six to twelve minutes.
Until...
...brain death brings about an
irreversible conclusion.
We all want to retain our
personalities
in some idyllic afterlife.
We all pray for
some miracle...
some drug,
potion, pill...
Perhaps, though,
it takes something else.
Perhaps it takes desire -
- an obsessive desire.
Perhaps it takes...
We will discuss the
location of the will
in the brain structure
at another time.
Mister West!
I suggest you get
yourself a pen!
Class dismissed.
How can you teach such drivel!
These people are here to learn,
and you're closing their minds
before they even have a chance!
What are you here for,
Mr West?!
You know, you should have
stolen more of Gruber's ideas...
...then at least
you'd have ideas!
Mister West!
It is going to be
a pleasure to fail you.
I would like to propose a toast.
To the National
Science Foundation
for recognizing the genius
of Dr Carl Hill...
...and for awarding
Miskatonic Medical School
its largest grant ever!
Your new laser drill is going to
revolutionize neurosurgery.
To the Foundation -
and to Miskatonic!
It's alright, Sweetheart,
you can drink up.
We're celebrating!
I know, Daddy, but
I have to go soon.
After preparing such a feast?
You must be tired.
I have a study date.
With Daniel?
Yes
Daniel Cain?
Uh huh.
Herbert West has moved
in with him, hasn't he?
For the time being.
(doorbell)
Oh, that must be him. Excuse me.
So...your daughter
is seeing Cain, eh?
You think that's wise, Alan?
- Dan!
- Hello, Sir.
Dr Hill.
Would you join us
for a glass of wine?
Actually, we have some
work to do.
Why don't you study here?
I'll have her home soon,
don't worry about it.
Well then...
one last toast.
To Meg...
...my esteemed colleague's
capable, beautiful
loving daughter...
...the obsession of all who
fall under her spell.
Dan...
No.
Please!
- Okay, what is it?
- I don't know, it's...
Look - it's not you, really, it's...
...just a lot of little things.
- Like what?
Well - West is always in his
room with the door closed.
I mean, do you ever see him?
Does he ever eat?
I told you - he's a little cracked!
He bothers you, too.
No, don't be ridiculous.
Rufus is terrified of him.
When West comes in,
he runs and hides!
Rufus runs and hides all the time.
It's standard cat activity.
But not when we're together.
Then he's all over us, trying to
get your attention, and...
Where is he? I haven't
seen him since we got here.
It's okay - he's around here...
I haven't even heard him.
Usually he at least knocks
something over when I'm here.
Rufus... Rufus...Rufus
Come on, you fat cat.
Here. Kitty.
Where are you now,
you mad animal.
Don't you try to hide from me.
Rufus
Where are you, boy?
Here, Kitty!
Rufus! Hey Boy!
Rufus?
Rufus?...Rufus?
Rufus, are you in here?
Here, Boy!
Here, Kitty.
Rufus?
Oh, Dan, I think it's...
What are you doing in my room?
How dare you come in my room!
Dan! Dan!
What's the matter?
I thought I was renting
a private room, Dan!
Meg, what the hell are
you doing here?
Would you please leave - now?!
Easy, Herbert!
Come on.
In the fridge!
I was going to show you.
Shut up.
What happened?
It was dead when I found it.
You killed him.
He hated you!
It suffocated.
It knocked the garbage over
and got its head stuck in a jar.
You weren't home, so I
put it in there.
I didn't think you would want
to find it like that.
I did not want to
stink the place up.
I was going to show you.
You couldn't call or
write a note?
I was busy pushing bodies around -
and what would a note say, Dan:
"Cat Dead - Details Later"?
I knew you were fond of it.
You killed him! I know
you did! He killed him!
Besides, I do not like
people in my room!
Alright, that's enough.
I think you'd both
better leave - now!
- What the hell is this?
- That is none of your business!
Yeah, I think it is!
Just as it is none
of my business that
you're sleeping with
Dean Halsey's daughter!
You know, I would not
want to see a fellow student,
especially one as promising as
yourself, be thrown out of school -
out of the profession -
on morals grounds.
Well, I think Dr Halsey
just might understand.
Oh, do you?
Well, you may well
be right.
Are you sure you
want ot find out?
(cat screams)
Herbert!
You hear that sound?!
West! West!
West, what is that?!
(cat screams)
(cat screaming)
Get it off of me!!
Cain!!
Get out of here!!
Get it off of me!!
- What the hell is it?!
- Later! Later!
There it is!
No!
(cat howls)
Look out!
There it goes!
(cat cries)
Okay, I got it.
I got it.
(cat screams)
How?
Look out!
It's really quite simple -
all life is a physical and
chemical process, correct?
It stands to reason
that if one could
find extremely fresh specimens
and re-charge that
chemical process -
Bang! - we'd have re-animation.
The theory is not new, West.
But my "re-agent" is.
Read!
"With various animating solutions
"I have killed and brought to
animated life a number of
"rabbits and pigs -
cats and dogs."
I have broken the 6 to 12
minute barrier.
I've conquered brain death!
"With the higher animals and the
increased strength of the solution
"the reaction has become
more violent
"and my research has
become more difficult."
Which is why I need
you to help me.
- Help you?
- You are the perfect person to assist me.
You are hard working, bright -
people respect you...
and you have access to
certain authorities.
We can defeat death!
We can achieve every doctor's
dream. You'll be famous...
...and live lifetimes.
You haven't done this on people?!
I've done all I can here.
I'll need new lab space.
You will help me?
- No!
- Why - because it's mad?
No - because I don't
believe you!
How can you say that?
You've seen the results!
No! Rufus wasn't dead
to begin with.
You drugged him and reduced
his vital signs...
...you lowered his body temperature.
He couldn't have been dead!
Do you agree that he's dead now?
Do you agree that he's dead now?!
West, no!
West, stop!
I'll show you.
Then you'll help me.
- No!
- Yes, you will.
That is why I brought the infernal
beast back to life in the first place.
- The brain?
- Of course.
Don't expect it to tango -
it has a broken back.
(cat crying)
God!
Why does it make that noise?
Birth is always painful.
- It was dead!
- Twice.
(Meg screams)
- It's him!
- What are you doing here?
- It's Rufus!
- Come on, let's go upstairs.
Oh, my God!
(cat screaming)
Herbert West has effected
re-animation in dead animal tissue!
Mister Cain...
...I'm surprised.
- No, I've seen it!
He brought back a dead
animal - a cat! Back to life!
I hadn't expected such nonsense
from you, Mr Cain,
but I should have guessed it
when you took up with Mr West.
I know he's unstable, but
I've seen the results -
so has your daughter!
What have you been doing
with my daughter?
She walked into an
experiment.
You've involved Megan
in your insanity?!
I never intended to
involve her.
Tomorrow morning you will
submit to me a written apology
for this entire affair.
These experiments were
clearly beyond the scope
of your legitimate studies.
They have obviously interfered
with your ability to do
your classwork.
If any equipment from the
hospital or the laboratories of
Miskatonic University were
involved in any of this
unauthorized activity, criminal
charges may be pressed!
You will in any case, have
your student loan recinded!
My loan?
I won't be able to
continue school.
As for Mr West, he need submit
no apology - you may tell him
that he may continue with his
research without
the impediment of an education.
As of now, he is no longer
a student at this university.
Sir, can we please discuss this?
I think you're being blinded
by your emotions.
That will be all, Mr Cain.
Don't take this out on Meg.
She tried to stop me.
I said that will be all.
- They just keep on coming, don't they?
- Oh, yeah.
You ain't got my lunch
under there, have ya?
Yeah - one meatball
run over by a semi.
Eeew!
I lost my appetite. You gonna
be around for a while?
- Yeah.
- I might go get me some coffee.
- Take your time.
- Got it.
Meatball?
Put your shoes on.
- If we get caught...
- What will they do...
...embalm us?
Let's go.
"Burn victim."
Here's your meatball.
"Shotgun wound to the head."
Oh, God - he's rotten!
- "Malpractice."
- Shit!
Let's go - we're not
going to find anything!
Wait!...Wait!
Yes, I think you.
How long?
He arrived early
this evening.
"John Doe" - apparently
just dropped dead.
No record of any damage.
Almost perfect!
- Why almost?
- Could be heart damage.
- Just find another one!
- No - we do not have time!
All we need tonight, is a
specific conscious reaction!
He's been dead for hours.
Any evidence of re-animated
consciousness
will justify proceeding!
Start the recorder.
Start the damn recorder!
Make the entry.
October...
- Tenth.
Subject: Male
Age?
Age: early twenties.
- Physical condition?
- No deformities.
Appears to have been in
excellent physical condition.
Cause Of Death:
Uh - What?
- Heart failure.
- Time: 10:33 PM.
- 10:33 PM.
Fifteen CC's.
Fifteen CC's of re-agent
being administered.
- We're getting married!
- He's mad.
I've seen this happen to
medical students before...
...good ones!
Doctor Harris, is Mr Cain
loose in this hospital?
In the morgue, I think, Doctor.
I specifically told Dr Riley
to suspend him
and take him off the floor
if he reported to work!
Dr Riley's been in emergency
surgery for 4 hours.
I haven't seen him.
Time elapsed?
Fifteen seconds.
Something should have
happened by now!
(telephone rings)
It's not working.
Let's get out of here!
Obviously, the human
dosage factor is unknown.
Increasing the dosage -
20 CC's of re-agent.
- Herbert, let's go!
- No!
Ohhh...
Damn!
Page Mr Cain and have him report
to the Level L security desk
and make sure that she
stays right here!
You can't stop me.
I followed you here
and I'm going to follow
you until you listen to me...
- I love him!
- You are my daughter...
and you will do as
you are told!
Sit down, Miss Halsey.
Mr Cain will be up soon.
You can discuss it then.
Don't blame him, Daddy!
We failed!
Come on - let's go! Somebody
could be coming any minute!
He failed!
Not I!
(paging system)
"Mr Cain - Mr Daniel Cain"
"Please report to the
security desk, Level L"
Oh, God!
Cover him up.
Let's Go.
- Let's Go!
- Alright!
Yeeeeeaaaaaahhhh!
Grab him!
Stop!!
He heard me!
Cain?!
Cain, open up this door!
Help!!
Is West in there with you?!
You're in a lot of trouble!
Both of you!!
No!!
Let go of him!
Stop!!
For God's sake, stop!!
Dan...
...look out.
Ohhh!
Come on!
Find the recorder!
Herbert - No!
Did you see him, Dan?
He listened to me!
It made a conscious act!
He heard you as an animal would!
No, no - you can't be serious!
You may be right. It had
probably been dead too long...
...wasn't fresh enough!
We probably only revived
the senses and the instincts -
so come on!
Help me get him up.
- Is he dead?
- Of course -would you give me a hand?!
He interrupted an important
experiment in progress.
Granted, it was an accident, but
this is the freshest body
we could come across save of
killing one ourselves
and every moment that we
spend talking about it
costs us results!!
Now, will you give me a hand?
Dan...
...we can bring him
back to life!
Yes
Now - get the recorder!
Find my serum!
This is a dream.
Fiction
Here - get his other hand.
Oh, good.
Unbreakable plastic...
...one of Man's few durable
inventions.
Certainly more durable
than this.
We need you in the
crash room.
Coming.
Twelve CC's being
administered...
...the dosage lessened in accordance
with the freshness of the subject.
Five seconds.
Come on!
I'll show you.
Fifteen seconds.
I'll show you!
Seventeen seconds!
Re-animation in 17 seconds!
The eyes opened!
Dr Halsey?
You once did me a favor by letting
me into your medical school!
Doctor - welcome back
to life!
Daddy?
Dan?
Damned bitch!
Meg?!
Dan - what is it?
Are you alright?
Dan - it's trying to speak!
The recorder!
Rrrrraaaaahhhh!
No!!
Daddy!
Daddy don't!
No, Meg - don't go near!
What the hell happened here!
Dan, you alright?
Who's that?
Uh...that is Dean Halsey.
You see, I came down here
to visit Mr Cain...
...who was here working
and Halsey entered, and
started ranting at us...
...rather irrationally.
No! He was just angry!
Daddy!
- Who's that over there?
- Uh, just a corpse.
You see, Halsey came in and
grabbed...that thing.
and, well...went crazy.
Dean Halsey?!
Dean Halsey!
(wails)
I'm calling the police!
Oh! Daddy!
(Halsey wails)
Shock.
Don't worry.
(yelling)
Daddy...
He can't hear you, or see you.
That's a one-way mirror.
What is wrong with him, Doctor?
Will he ever be...
Until we know exactly
what happened to him...
...there is no way to determine
his course of recovery.
That's why I need you to
sign a release
so I can perform
exploratory surgery on him.
Is that absolutely
necessary, Doctor Hill?
I know how difficult this
must be for you.
But I'm convinced your father's
problem is neurological.
Of course, we'll take
every precaution.
You must trust me.
I want to take a look at
the right frontal lobes.
- I'll open the skull here...
- I...don't want to know!
Just help him.
Please, Doctor.
Please let me talk to him.
No.
I must insist you leave his
treatment up to me.
I want you to think of me as someone
you can come to with your problems.
Or if you're ever lonely.
I know you're all by
yourself now.
(screams)
I'm going to take care
of him, Doctor.
And I'm going to find out
what happened to him!
What are you doing here?
I've been waiting for you.
I had to tell you about him.
What did you do to him?
What did you and
West do to him?
It was horrible.
I didn't...
What did you do to him?!
He's not insane.
He's dead.
No...No!
You're insane! You're insane!
No, it's true, Meg.
- It's true.
- No!
Daddy!
I'm telling you, Meg.
Everything.
Good evening, Mr West.
What do you want?
I want to know why Halsey's
heart fibrilates.
I don't have to talk to you.
Why his pulse is erratic.
I told everything I know
to the police.
Why he cries out in pain.
You can leave now, Doctor!
When we both know he is
quite dead.
Hmmm...Interesting little
laboratory you have here.
Ah! Mr West!
I recognize this.
What do you want?
Yes...we are both
scientists.
Let us get to the point.
I want your discovery...
...whatever it is that gives the
dead the appearance of life.
It is not the appearance of life -
it is life. This is not magic.
As you say - I am a scientist.
I'll have you locked up
for a madman...
...or a murderer.
You will do...
...what I tell you to do.
Ingenious, Mr West.
Your extention of that old fool
Gruber's work is really quite...
...brilliant!
- Dr Hill examined your father?
- Yes.
He wanted to do exploratory
surgery on him.
He'll find out.
Eventually, he'll find out.
Let us see...
...my new serum at work, eh?
Dead cat tissue.
The re-agent.
Magnificent!
Yes, Mr West...
...I will be famous!
Plagiarist!
Yes...
...parts.
I've never done whole...
West...
Yes, Doctor.
It's Herbert West.
What are you thinking?
How do you feel?
You...
You?
Baaaaastaaaaard!!
(screams)
Dan!
My God! What has Hill
done to him?!
Looks like a laser drill.
Your father's been
lobotomized.
My work!!
- What's going on?
- My work!
It's all gone!
He took my serum - except for
what I have upstairs.
Who!!
What happened here!
Hill.
Hill took my serum, my notes -
everything!
Herbert, you're insane!
What's happened here!
I had to kill him!!
What?
He's dead?
Not anymore.
No, Herbert!
This has got to stop!!
He tried to blackmail me, Dan!
And he wanted you to disappear!!
Oh - that's why he did it.
What - you've seen Halsey?
He lobotomized him.
So he could control him
in case he ever tried
to talk or tell anybody
what happened!
So he could protect
"his discovery".
- Very clever.
- I've got to tell Meg.
What does Meg have
to do with this?
Hill's got this weird file on her -
full of napkins and hair
and photographs
I think he's projected some sort
of psychotic need on to her.
Yes...
Alan...
Yes, Alan...
It's time for you
to come out...now!
Is that you, Dr Hill?
(muffled)
Yes, it's me!
Break time.
(gasps)
That's better!
(knock)
Meg?
It's Dan!
- I'm so afraid!
- What is it?
What's the matter?
I don't know, I'm...
...just worried about you.
Why?
I just feel horrible
about everything.
I guess I'm just
getting paranoid.
It's just...
...so hard to lose you.
You should go away.
Transfer to another school.
Don't worry about me.
You're the one who
should get away...
...go on with your life.
Find somebody.
I tried to hate you.
I wanted so much to hate you.
I love you.
Daddy!!
No, Daddy!!
Oh, no!! Daddy, don't!!
No!!
(screams)
(slow knock)
The door!
Oh, yes, Alan...
Ahhhhh!
Dan?...Dan?...Dan?!
Come on!
Ah, well...you'll be alright.
Meg!
Oh, my God.
Where, Herbert!
At the hospital, I imagine.
Can you stand up?
Let's go.
Meg...
I've always...
...admired your beauty, My Dear.
I think I've always
loved you!
And you will love me!
You will!
Please!
Please stop!
Let me go!
That's it, my dearest Meg...
...more passion!
Yes, my love!
I must say,
Dr Hill...
...I'm very dissapointed in you.
You steal the secret of
Life and Death,
and here you are, trysting
with a bubble headed co-ed.
You're not even a
second rate scientist.
Ah! Mr West!
I'm actually glad to see you!
It saves me the trouble of
having to send for you!
You'll never get credit
for my discovery.
Who's going to believe a
talking head?
Get a job in a sideshow!
Why an intelligent young man
like yourself...
...should make such a foolish,
fatal mistake
of coming here to
challenge me!
Oh...I have a plan.
So do I.
Enough!!
It is I who will show
you power, Mr West.
My discovery...
...a laser surgical drill
makes possible a new
technique in lobotomy
which results in
total mastery
of the human will!
Re-animated subjects
have proven to be the best!
They will give me power!
Undreamed of power!
Stay behind me.
Daddy, listen to me!
It's Megan! Megan!
Help! They'll kill her!
Then I'll give her life!
Look at me!!
Aaahhhh!!
What the f...
Aaaaahhhhh!!
Herbert, come on!
Come on!
Wait! We're not through here!
Meg, no!
No! Let me go!!
Have I told you,
I have a theory?!
Overdose!!!
Herbert!
Look out!!
Daddy!!
Let's go, Meg!
My notes!!
Aaaaaagggg!
Stop it!!
Come on!!
Meg!
My God, Megan!
Take her to
Number Three!
Hurry! Hurry!
Activating.
Air on!
Give it to me!
Okay, everybody out!
Clear!
Nothing!
Putting back air!
The trachea's fractured.
- Pupils dialated.
- No response.
Cain
I love you.
(Meg screams)