[Man]
Welcome to the University of Ithaca.
This is it, right here.
This is what we're talkin' about.
I'm gonna give you
a good tour today.
Show you as much as you need to know,
plus a whole lot more.
So this is the main area
of the university.
You'll be getting used
to this area.
This is where you congregate
with your friends and classmates.
Come in around me, everyone. Keep close.
Don't straggle. I've had problems
with stragglers before, okay ?
They get lost in the back. They get
hit by trucks, okay ? It's not pretty.
It's not pretty when it happens.
This is the--
By the way, this is the Joseph H. Nelson
Memorial Library here, okay ?
It was built, uh--
It was built, uh, in the 1600s.
1600s ? It says 1951 .
[Snickering]
That's the address.
Okay ? Wise-ass.
That's the psychology department.
Each semester you'll
be expected to volunteer...
for some cutting-edge
experimental testing.
Kind of cool. Just a tip.
When it's your turn, remember
to wear loose clothes, no metal,
and be prepared to receive
several heavy doses of electric current.
They're watching us right now.
Over there is the department of English.
I see most of you speak English already,
so we can skip that one.
- How long have you
been going to school here ?
- Eight years.
[ Everyone Laughing ]
You don't seem to know anything about it
here. This is the worst tour ever.
This is the worst school ever.
Doesn't anything cool ever happen here ?
Yeah, I mean,
cool stuff happens here.
This University of Ithaca is
the coolest, coolest place in the world.
That's because he's probably
never been anywhere else.
[ Laughing ]
Go ahead, laugh.
Laugh all you want.
But the fact of the matter is,
this is the setting for
the greatest story ever told.
Okay ?
It's about this guy I knew,
Josh Parker,
and his girl friend, Tiffany.
It's one of the most
Fascinating journeys ever.
Josh and Tiffany were always together,
starting from when
they were really little.
They did everything as a team.
Once when Tiffany was ten years old,
She had her tonsils taken out.
Josh stayed in the hospital
for three straight days.
They were best friends.
And eventually what started out
as friendship...
blossomed into some serious French
kissing and lots of heavy petting.
You know, they spent
so much time together that
even their dogs started dating.
They seemed destined
to be together forever.
But after high school, they faced
their most challenging challenge ever.:
a long-distance relationship.
See, unfortunately,
while Josh was enrolled here
at the wonderful University of Ithaca,
Tiffany went off to
veterinary school in Austin, Texas.
But they made a pact,
a promise to stay true to each other,
to talk every day and maintain
an exclusive relationship.
That turned out to be more difficult
than either of them had imagined.
Tiffany! Hey, baby.
Oh, my God.
You were amazing last night.
- I never ever came like that before.
- Come on.
Seriously ! I had to take
two birth control pills this morning.
You wanna help me study
again tonight ?
Forget tonight. Come over now.
- Let's blow this class off.
- [ Panting ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Line Rings ]
[ Answer Machine ] Tiffany and Carla
can't come to the phone,
but if you leave a message,
we'll call you right back.
Hey, Tif, it's me... again.
Just wonderin' where you are.
Still tryin' to get a hold of you.
Everything's cool, though.
I'm sure I'll catch you later.
Call me back, okay ?
Okay. Bye.
I just wanted to add something
before I sent this video off.
I haven't talked to you
in a few days.
And I'm starting to think you
don't like me anymore. No, I'm kidding.
Hey, guys.
But I am getting a little worried,
so gimme a call when
you get a chance, okay ?
Barry says " Hi."
So gimme a call as soon as
you can, okay ? I miss you.
- Call me, okay ? Bye.
- [ Laughing ]
- What's up, guys ?
- Not much.
- You ?
- Nothing. I was just
finishing my tape to Tiffany.
[Barry]
Hey, Mitch, what are you doin'?
Are you hungry ?
Huh ?
- Are you gonna feed him ?
- No, I'm checking the temperature
inside his cage.
Mitch needs an evenly distributed
85 degrees to survive.
Can I drop a mouse in ?
Sorry. Mitch only eats
once a week, on Saturdays.
Maybe we could cut
a mouse in half,
and we could feed him half now
and the other half on Saturday.
I don't think so.
I thought you had class now.
What time is it ?
Oh, shit !
Can you do me a favor ?
When this is done rewinding,
- will you drop it in the mail for me ?
- No problem. Just leave it there.
- Thanks, man. I'll see you guys later ?
- Bye.
- Can we please feed him now ?
- No.
If you overfeed him,
he could die.
So ? It'll be worth it.
-Josh, hey.
- Beth, hey.
- What's goin' on ?
- Not much.
- Where have you been ?
- Nowhere.
Just studying a lot. I'm starting
to question this whole college thing.
No one told me there was
gonna be this much reading.
- Right. [ Chuckles ]
- Yeah.
- Oh, you going to E.L.'s tonight ?
- Yeah, I'll be there.
[Josh]I gotta run.
Class started five minutes ago.
- I'll see you tonight.
- Yeah. Sorry. Tonight.
So, you have a thing
for that guy now, is that it ?
- It's none of your business, Jacob.
- I can just tell you like him.
-I'm not having this conversation again.
-What conversation ?
You need to stop this.
You and I, we're not a couple.
We've never been a couple,
and we will never be one.
[Professor]
This week I'd like you...
to think about Plato's dialogues
of the middle years,
i.e. The Republic,
Phaedo, Symposium.
Now, this will all be
on next week's midterm, so...
I suggest you read up on it.
Ah, Jacob,
Do you have anything to add ?
Just a reminder.
The midterm will cover all
of the in-class lectures...
as well as all
of the assigned readings.
It will be entirely essay form,
so bring legal pads. I prefer yellow.
It's easier on the eyes.
Okay. Okay ?
Yeah. Thank you,Jacob.
And... see you all
next week for the midterm.
-Josh.
- Yes ?
I saw you hitting on Beth.
Not a good idea. She's spoken for.
-What ?
-She'll come back to me. They always do.
So, Mr. Parker. Do you intend
to be ready for this exam ?
- Yes, sir.
- Well, you better be ready.
Because I was looking
over the books last night,
and you need a "B" on this test
just to pass this class.
Actually, I double-checked that,
Professor. He needs a "B" plus.
- We're not gonna be able
to bend on this.
- Yeah, I got it.
-Just copy off someone.
- I can't. It's all essays and stuff.
If I fail this class,
my average is shot.
I might lose my financial aid. I could
not be allowed back next semester.
Well, you're fucked then. You might
as well come to my party tonight.
Hook up with Beth, and at least
enjoy your last week at college.
I'm not hooking up with anyone.
I made a commitment to Tiffany.
I'm invested
in this relationship.
Invested ? Who are you, Charles Schwab ?
Would you listen to yourself?
I would give my life...
for one evening of consensual sex
with that girl.
I've gone this long without cheating.
I think I can hold out.
You're already cheating !
Any time you pass up sex,
you're cheating on yourself.
Think about it.
You're in college.
The window of opportunity
to drink and do drugs...
and take advantage of young girls
is getting smaller by the day.
- I gotta make a call.
- I'm telling you.
You pass this up, it'll haunt you
for the rest of your days.
Your dick will never
forgive you.
What do you think,
little man ?
Don't you ever want to
experience something new ?
[ Squeaky Voice ]
It ain't easy being Josh's penis.
We've been here over two months,
and I feel like I'm in a coma.
- Stop it.
- I wish I was your dick, E.L.
This is torture.
If something doesn't happen soon,
I'm gonna pack up my balls and leave.
- Enough.
- [ Girl Over Phone ] Hello ?
Carla, it's Josh. I'm sorry
to bother you. Is Tiffany around ?
Tiffany is not here.
She didn't sleep here
last night... again.
And it would be great if one hour
went by when you didn't call.
- Right.
- If she wanted to talk to you,
she'd call you.
Deal with it.
- What a bitch !
- Does she sound hot ?
We've never gone this long without
talking. Something is definitely wrong.
Yeah, she found someone else
like you should do.
The clock is ticking.
Before you know it,
you're gonna be 40
and have to pay for these kind a girls.
*She good-looking
Got a mojo cooking*
* Yeah, wouldn't give me
the time of day*
*But if my occupation was
a star in the constellation*
* We could get together
in the Milky Way*
*And every body
wanna know somebody*
*Everyone wants to drop
your name*
* You need no reservation
No special invitation*
* No college education
if you've got fortune and fame *
Oh, yeah ! Whoo-hoo !
I should really warn you,
though, it's been known...
to severely affect your decision-making
abilities and lowers your inhibitions.
Good. That's the plan.
No, that-that's--
Yes, that is the plan.
- Did you bring some cash ?
- Why ?
- We've got chicks for sale.
- What ?
* Hey, now I'm snappy
Got my mojo track**
Trust me. I've been goin'
to this school for seven years.
And I know the key to
a well-rounded college education...
is experimentation.
Let me show you.
This is an auction.
Remember...
you are not buying the girl,
you are buying her company, and no way
does a sale constitute sexual relations.
-[ Groaning ]
-I know, I know. Believe me, I've tried.
Anyway, without further ado, let's
Introduce you to our first... person.
- Laura !
- [ Applause, Cheering ]
Laura's from Long Island. Her favorite
coloris blue. She likes the outdoors.
She loves good seafood.
Okay, let's start the opening bidding
at five dollars.
Three dollars and fifty cents.
- Good God, moneybags.
She's not a Happy Meal.
-[Laughing]
- Five dollars.
- Okay, we've got five. Do I hear ten?
- Ten bucks.
- [ Auctioneer Calling ]
Who's got fifteen ?
- Fifteen bucks for
a lovely evening with Laura.
- Fifteen dollars.
Okay, we got 15. Who can beat 15 ?
Going once, going twice.
Sold... to the captain.
There you are.
- Hey, what's going on?
- Not much.
- You look great.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Listen, Jacob's here,
and he's a total psycho.
Can you go outbid him?
You know what,
I didn't bring that much money.
You don't understand.
He's obsessed with me.
See? That's fun, right?
Okay, okay. Now, I want you two
to kiss each other.
All right, has anyone seen Beth?
Uh-oh, there she is.
-[Cheering]
-Say hi to the crowd, Beth.
Hi.
Can I hear a five-dollar opening bid
for the beautiful Beth Wagner ?
- Five dollars right here.
- Who can beat five ?
- Six.
-Seven.
- Ten dollars.
- Ten dollars. Going once. going twice--
- Fifteen dollars.
- Twenty.
- Twenty-five.
Twenty-five. Who can beat 25 ?
Going once, going twice.
Twenty-six.
- Twenty-six going once.
- Thirty !
- Okay, can anyone beat $26 ?
- I just said 30 !
- There's gotta be someone
out there who can beat $26.
- Me, right here. Thirty !
Sold! To my man Josh for $26.
-You heard me. I bid $30 loud and clear.
-Your bid didn't count.
- Why?
- Because you're a T.A.
- So?
- So this auction is for students only.
Good-bye.
* On and on
until the early morning*
* They're rockin' on and on
[ Laughing ]
Thanks for doing that.
I owe you one.
- You owe me more than one.
- Do I?
Technically.
Well, are you ready
to collect ?
I think so. Yeah.
We're touching.
It's a lot of fun.
[ Chuckles ]
We're having a good time.
**[Romantic]
Who's Tiffany Henderson?
Just some girl I used to date
since I was like five.
But that's over now.
She blew me off.
Oh, poor baby.
You must be very hurt.
Do you need some
special attention ?
Well, I am pretty upset.
Did that help?
That helped a lot.
I have an idea.
What do you say?
I don't think so.
Come on! It'll be fun.
- I've always wanted to try this.
- No.
Yes. I'm gonna interview you.
Fine.
Okay.
- Okay, Josh.
- Yes.
What do you look for in a girl?
Well, let's see.
She should be smart
and funny and--
That's good too.
Do you feel better yet ?
I feel a little bit better.
Yeah. A little.
What else do you look for?
She should be attractive and...
nice and--
Topless. And topless.
And she should kiss me.
What else ?
She shouldn't stop kissing me.
Why don't you keep doing that ?
*Tiny salmon swimming
in a stream *
*Tiny salmon chasing
that impossible dream *
*The mynah bird says *
- [ Cawing ]
*The chimpanzee says *
[ Making Monkey Sounds ]
*The friendly owl says *
[ Hooting ]
* But the salmon can only say*
[ Blubbering ]
*And it's sad **
** [ Humming ]
* Good morning, everyone *
* How are you and you and you *
What are you so happy about ?
I don't know.
Do I seem happy this morning ?
Well, you're bouncing around here
Like you're Richard fuckin' Simmons.
Yeah, you do seem unusually
Light hearted today, Josh.
Huh. Maybe it's because I had
the best time of my life last night.
Twice! And once this morning.
You and Beth?
- Oh, yeah.
- Shut up. What happened ?
No way! You're lying.
I'm not lying.
You can't make out with someone,
then pretend you had sex with them.
- That's really, really uncool.
- I'm not pretending.
Forget it. I know you're lying.
I guarantee he's lying.
You wanna bet?
Great. I'm gonna bet money
on something you can't prove.
You videotaped it!
No, no, no, I didn't! Gimme that!
Gimme that ! E.L., gimme that.
- No way ! This is amazing!
- I was kidding.
Just give it back to me, okay?
- Gimme the tape.
- Huh? Come on, Josh.
- We're all gonna see it
sooner or later. Huh?
- He's got a point.
[ Barry]
Oh, no! Oh, no!
Give it to me.
No, give it to me.
- E.L, no.
-Josh, please? We need this.
Okay, listen, seriously.
You can never tell anyone you saw this.
Oh, yeah.
Okay. Okay!
Barry, hit the lights.
It's boner time!
Hey, Tif. It's me coming toyou live
from lthaca, New York.
I thought I asked you
to mail this yesterday.
Yeah, it was on your desk.
I mailed it this morning.
Barry, fast-forward
to the horny stuff.
- * I got a girl *
- Is this the kind of shit
you've been sending Tiffany ?
Oh, my God.
* It's you *
Oh, fuck!
Oh, my God!
No, no, no, no.
Oh, God!
W-Wait a second.
Tell me you mailed
the Beth tape to Tiffany.
- Yes!
-[Josh] Shit!
- Oh, no ! Oh, no ! What ?
- Hey, hey.
Did you make a copy ? 'Cause if you
made a copy, we could watch the copy.
- [ Ringing ]
- Don't answer it.
[Answer Machine]
It's Josh and Rubin. Leave a message.
Hi, Josh. It's Tiffany.
Sorry we haven't spoken.
Listen, my grand father
passed away.
I've tried calling you a few times,
but no one picked up.
I didn't want to leave
this message on your machine.
But by now you're probably
a little worried, so--
Anyway, I'm at my parents' house
helping my mom out.
She's really a wreck.
If I don't speak with you, I'll call you
Monday when I'm back at school.
I'll be okay.
I just need some time.
Bye. I love you.
That's not fair.
How come she gets to see
the tape and we don't ?
She gets back there Monday.
That leaves me three days to get there.
Get where ? Austin ?
- That's like 10,000 miles from here.
- Eighteen hundred.
You wanna drive 1,800 miles
in three days ? Just fly.
Do you have money for a ticket ?
I don't.
All right, so we're driving.
- You're coming ?
- What else am I gonna do ?
Stay here and learn ?
Road trip.
[Boy]
Just a minute. Hold on.
He's probably jackin' off.
What do you guys want ?
Kyle, this is an emergency.
Wait. Let me at least
go back and call my dad.
Call your dad ?
Would you listen to yourself?
You're 19 years old,
and you're a fucking sissy.
All you ever do is sit in a library
and play Myst with exchange students.
It's pathetic.
No, no. What he's trying to say is this
is your chance to do something for once.
Be a risk-taker.
Come with us.
You guys are just saying that
Because you want my car.
No ! No,
we've always liked you.
Or you can just give us the car. That
would make him a risk-taker, right ?
Shut up, all right ?
He's coming with us.
Come on, Kyle.
It'll be fun !
Aren't you even curious
where we're going ?
No.
Okay. We're going to the University
of Austin. Sure you don't wanna come ?
I don't like Massachusetts.
Austin's in Texas, not Massachusetts.
You're thinking of Boston.
You've never left this town,
have you, Barry ?
No, not really.
You should look into that. That could
turn into a debilitating phobia.
Okay, I'll do that.
- Can I feed Mitch ?
- Yes, actually you can.
You can feed him.
But not till tomorrow. There's a brown
box full of mice next to his cage.
Give him one tomorrow. And no
messing around, Barry. Okay ? Just one.
- I'll feed him a mouse tomorrow, okay ?
- Okay.
Yeah. You can count on me.
Okay ? I'm reliable.
You guys do good. Have a good trip,
safe trip, safe journey.
Buckle up your seat belt.
I'm gonna feed the snake for you.
[Barry's Voice]
So off they went.
They had 1,800miles to go,
and only three days to do it.
It was a killer journey, and
it was one that changed them forever.
The end.
So we're gonna go look
over here now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
That's it ? This story sucks.
That can't be the whole story.
What happened with the tape ?
Right. The tape.
Well, like I said,
They were on a race against time.
[Male Singers]*Smokestack
spitting black soot into the sunny sky*
* The load on the road brings
a tear to the Indian's eye*
Since we didn't get to see the tape,
- can you at least describe it to us ?
- No.
* The elephant won't forget what
it's like inside his cage*
* Thering master's telling the cows
the scene's on an empty stage*
Admit that Beth is amazing.
- I admit it. She's amazing.
She's perfect.
- There you go.
I don't know why you feel
so guilty. Technically
you haven't cheated on Tiffany.
What are you talking about ?
There are these rules
that guys have,
an understanding as to what
exactly constitutes cheating.
Take your situation, for example.
[ Laughing ]
It's not cheating.
It's never cheating...
when you're in a different area code,
not to mention a different state.
That makes no sense.
Don't look at me, Kyle.
I didn't make up the rules.
This is legit. I've actually
read an article about this.
There's a whole bunch of them.
They're like loopholes. Right ?
For argument's sake,
let's say you were sleeping
with two girls at the same time.
It wouldn't be cheating, because
they would cancel each other out.
- Ahh.
- Exactly!
Or if you're too wasted to remember ?
It is not cheating.
Because if you can't really remember it,
it never really took place.
* Uh-huh*
* Whoo-oo*
I've got one.
Are you ready ?
It's not cheating if you spread
peanut butter all over your testicles...
and let your dog lick it off.
[ Everyone Groaning ]
- Because it's your dog !
-Jesus Christ !
- You know, because it's your dog !
- Yeah, we got it.
* Whoo-oo, uh-huh*
* God damn right
it's a beautiful day*
* Uh-huh
God damn right--**
Somebody's gonna die tomorrow.
That's right.
One of you is marked for death.
And the first thing
tomorrow morning,
a chosen one will
experience nature's wrath...
in all its fury.
*Ah-ah-ah-ah *
Who are you ?
I'm Beth.
Are you here for the feeding ?
Excuse me ?
You're early.
It's not till tomorrow.
You should come back.
It's gonna be a bloodbath.
I think I'll pass.
Have you seen Josh ?
He went to visit his girl friend.
Tiffany ?
I thought they broke up.
I mean, this girl who's
a friend of his. You know what I mean.
Where did he go ?
Austin ?
Austin, Massachusetts ?
You mean Boston,
Massachusetts ?
Yeah, that's what I said.
Boston.
The University of Boston
in Massachusetts.
He is such an asshole.
I can't believe he just lied
to my face like that.
I actually thought he liked me.
How could he do that ?
-Wait, she was standing around topless ?
-Girls don't stand around naked.
Yeah, they do. Okay ? This is my story.
Do you wanna hear it or not ?
- It just doesn't make any--
- Shh. Please, no interruptions.
So this other girl walks up,
totally hot. Naked ! Really naked !
I know guys can be jerks.
I guess I just thought
Josh was different. I liked him.
Sweetie, listen to me.
They're all the same.
All men are perverted pigs.
All they think about,
all they really care about, is sex.
You're so right.
- You should go to Boston
and bust his ass.
- Right ?
Confront him
and his little girl friend.
[Male Singers]*I'm freakin' you
Baby, drivin' me crazy*
*I'm freakin' you, baby
Drivin' me crazy*
Oh ! These too.
*I'm freakin' you, baby
Drivin' me crazy*
Kyle, come here for a second.
Look, we're a little short
on cash right now,
so we're gonna need
to put this on your credit card.
We'll give you the cash
when we get back. I promise.
I can't. It's my dad's.
It's for emergencies only.
Hello !
This is an emergency.
We need this stuff.
You want us to sleep in the dirt ?
*I'm freakin' you, baby
Drivin' me crazy*
* When I get to your place*
*I wanna turn up the highs
and turn up the bass**
[Josh ] Well, I'd say
we're officially in no-man's-land.
We've been on this road
for over an hour.
This is gonna save us five hours
minimum. So thank me later, Josh, okay ?
Maybe we should turn around
and go back to the interstate.
- We're not goin' back.
Have some faith, Kyle.
It's supposed to be a challenge.
That's why they call it a shortcut.
If it was easy,
it would just be the way.
[Josh ]
Damn it ! Fuck !
Yep, I give us about 20 minutes
before our first ass-raping.
What do we do now ?
If we turn around, we're gonna
lose five hours back tracking.
Turn around ? Why ?
Because of this ? We can make it.
Make it ?
You mean jump it ?
- No. Absolutely not.
No way. We're going back.
-[Rubin] It can be done.
This incline is 30 degrees
roughly, right ?
Factory weight of the car is 1,600.
Add our weight plus cargo, 2,100 pounds.
- No, no.
- If we hit this at 50 miles per hour,
our trajectory
will clear ten feet, easy.
No way. Absolutely not.
Kyle, we'll go 60
just to be certain.
[Kyle]
We're goin' back. This is impossible.
You sure ?
Of course I'm sure.
With physics I'm always sure. Yes.
I'm driving.
I don't think you guys heard me.
This is my car, and we're
not gonna be jumping over any rivers.
Kyle, it's ten feet. Bob Hope
could jump this in a golf cart.
Look, I can spit across this gap.
- Yeah. Well, better make it 75.
- Okay.
- Let's do it.
- Trust me, Kyle, it's science.
No, you guys. No.
E.L., get out of my car.
Kyle, in the car.
Come on.
We're okay.
You know we need to hit 60,
right ?
- I'm trying. This car sucks.
- Stop !
[ Everyone Yelling ]
[ E.L. ]
Thank you ! Yes !
What did I tell you ?
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God !
My father is gonna kill me
when he finds out about this.
I only said we'd make it across.
I never said anything
about the wheels staying on.
What the hell
are we gonna do now ?
I'm totally screwed !
I don't have time to be walking
through the woods right now.
Josh, we're gonna call a tow truck.
We'll have the axles fixed.
We'll probably lose halfa day.
It'll be fine. It's just the wheels !
[Beth] The minute I think
I feel something for someone,
they just turn around
and screw me over.
Just something about Josh.
He's just different.
I feel like we had a connection.
I don't think I'll ever
be able to trust a guy.
You shouldn't ! Honey, the last time
I trusted a man was 1 985,
and he took off
with my sister and my van.
It was a regular-size van.
That was before they started
making that minivan crap.
So there's no hope, huh ?
Oh, there's hope.
But it comes with batteries.
[ Buzzing ]
You can keep that.
[ Kyle ]
God. Crap.
Listen, guys,
we're gonna have to be more careful.
We almost died
in that explosion.
- I wish I had died.
- I'm serious. I can't die young.
Something tells me the people
of Earth are gonna need me.
I must live.
Yeah, right.
We all must live.
Before we do that, we must figure out
how to get back on the road.
[Josh ] We shouldn't
be going to sleep right now.
[Phone Ringing]
Let's lay an indication here and there
of some little shadow areas.
[Phone Ringing]
[ Phone Ringing ]
Excuse me.
[Phone Ringing]
I'm sorry,
do you need to get that ?
Do you need something ?
Yeah. This is sort
of an unusual question.
But do you have any marijuana
I might be able to buy from you ?
Our car exploded last night,
And I'm practically out of my own.
Am I a drug dealer ?
No, I am not.
Thank you for asking though.
No ? Okay, that's okay.
Thanks.
Is there anything else
I can help you with ?
Perhaps you'd like an 11 -year-old
prostitute sent to your room.
We can do that.
Or maybe we can off someone for you.
Huh ? How's that sound ?
I've got it.
Why don't we start small ?
Would you like a fresh towel ?
Maybe you could roll that up
and smoke it.
Dick.
By the way, Cheech.
That credit card you guys gave me
last night was maxed out.
So don't go spending all your cash
on needles and guns just yet.
Um, Mr. Earl Edwards ?
I'm sorry, sir.
This card's over its limit.
That's not true. Put it through
your little machine again.
I ran it through three times, sir. It
keeps telling me you're over your limit.
- If you have another card,
I'd be happy to--
- Don't give me any attitude.
You go fix that
little toy back there,
and charge this friggin' meal
to that friggin' card.
We've been coming here
for 20 years.
We've only been open
eight years, sir.
Do it now.
[E.L.]
Relax, it's not that big a deal.
[Rubin]
You don't seem to understand me.
When Josh finds out about this,
he's gonna freak.
You can't rent a car without
a credit card. You just can't.
So, what are we gonna do ?
Tell you what. Stay here.
Take him out for breakfast
or something.
I'll go take care of this.
Earl, Cookie, we have a situation.
Brace yourselves.
The police have found Kyle's car
abandoned in Bedford, Pennsylvania.
It's been blown to bits.
We checked with the university,
and he's not there. He's missing.
Mother of God.
-[Woman] Good morning.
- Hello.
Hi. How can I help you ?
Yeah, hi. I was sent over
to check out bus 1 -11 .
And I'm afraid
I have some bad news.
You seem to be having problems
with the... rotator splint.
Engines have rotator splints ?
Yeah.
She runs good now, but not for long.
- I can have it back to you
as good as newin less than a week.
- Okay.
Let's see. Well,
Jered's still in Aliquippa.
- I take it he called you from there ?
- Mmm, yep.
Five days.
Well, I think we can work that out.
Would you please
not feed my dog ?
I didn't.
You did so. You can't feed
Seeing Eye dogs treats like that.
They're specially trained. So I'd
appreciate it if you left him alone.
Don't roll your eyes at me.
French toast.
Bacon. Good for you.
And scrambled eggs.
Excuse me, but this has powdered sugar,
and I ordered no sugar.
- I really can't have
too much sugar in the morning.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Look at that. You're absolutely right.
I'll tell you what.
Let me take this back and bring you out
a new piece. All right. Great.
Is everybody good ?
Okay, great.
Do you know where my books and
possessions are ? I can't really fii--
Wait, no. They were in the car.
The car that blew up.
That's-- That's hilarious.
All right,
let me warm that up.
- There you go.
- Thanks.
Excuse me. The French toast
will be up in a minute.
- Okay, thank you.
- Okay, great.
French toast, no sugar.
- All right ? Sorry about that.
- No problem. Thank you.
That's a nice guy.
It's good.
[ Tires Squealing ]
Okay !
I don't even wanna know
How you got this.
- I stole it from a blind chick.
- I said I didn't wanna know.
What ? I'm gonna give it back.
Probably.
[Male Singer]
* Going to work, I hate it*
*Shakin' that stick
that drives people crazy*
*Doin' that stuff that you do*
* Quit messin' me up
with your voodoo*
* You drive me crazy with that*
*Boogie-oogie-oogie
oogie-oogie*
* You drive me crazy with that
boogie, boogie, boogie*
* Your lip's are hot and spicy*
*Servin' up baked beans at night*
[ Horn Honks ]
*At midnight
she's hopin' to stomp*
*Makin'love to the gators
in the swamp**
Can we please stop soon ?
I need to use the bathroom.
Actually, I don't have to go yet,
so we'll stop in a couple hours.
Okay.
I'm kidding, Kyle. We'll stop.
Jeez, you have to stand up
For yourself once in a while.
Be a little more assertive.
Okay.
What's your deal anyways ?
Why are you so worried all the time ?
I don't know.
I guess it's my dad.
He's like strict.
He really is gonna kill me
when he finds out about that car.
So you screwed up. Big deal, man.
People make mistakes.
He'll get over it.
Besides, that car sucked anyways.
I really do need
to go to the bathroom.
- [ E.L. ] We're makin' a pit stop.
- [Josh ] Again ?
[ Squeaking ]
You're about to
experience first hand...
exactly what it means to be in
the lower region of nature's food chain.
Mitch is going to bite into you.
He's going to squeeze.
He'll actually start digesting you
While you're still alive.
But don't be scared.
No. No, no.
It'll be a quick death.
Be brave.
You'll barely feel it.
Come on.
[ Banging On Cage ]
You gonna fuckin' eat him ?
Josh, wait up a second.
This is supposed to be
a road trip.
All we're doin' is driving
the whole time.
- It's ridiculous.
- No one forced you to come along, man.
First off, we're making great time.
Second, if Tiffany did see
that tape, it'd be the best thing
ever happened to you.
What is that supposed to mean ?
Beth is like an angel.
She's here to help you change your life.
Besides, did Tiffany ever
Let you videotape her ?
I think not.
It's a sign, Josh.
- [ Phone Ringing ]
- Hello ?
- [Josh ] Professor Anderson ?
- Who's calling ?
Hi, Professor,
it's Josh Parker.
Oh, uh--
[ Deeper Voice ]
Hello, Josh. What can I do for you ?
Well, I was in a car accident.
[Jacob ]
Oh. Oh, my God.
I'm okay. It's just
I'm in kind of a bind.
All my notes and books
were destroyed.
I was wondering if it was possible
to get a little extension.
Maybe take the midterm
a couple days later.
Oh, sure. Yes, it sounds
like an emergency.
How about an extra three days ?
How would that sound ?
- Would that work ?
- Yeah, that would be fantastic.
- Are you sure ?
-Just glad you're not hurt.
I'm marking it down right now.
That is so great, Professor.
Thank you. I'll see you soon.
Okay, good-bye.
Who was that ?
Oh, that-- [ Own Voice ]
That was Josh Parker.
Oh, yeah ?
What did he want ?
He was just calling
to confirm the date of the exam.
Such a worrier.
[Siren Wails]
It's gonna be okay.
I'll find him.
And we'll find whoever did this,
I promise. It's gonna be okay.
If I had to guess, I'd say somebody
was raped and murdered here last night.
What the hell
gives you that idea ?
I don't know.
It's just a feeling.
- Well ?
- Nothing yet.
Good thing is,
there's no evidence of a struggle.
No blood or clothing,
anything like that.
And we haven't found
a single drop of semen yet.
Hi. I'm visiting
my friend from home.
She doesn't know I'm coming.
It's a surprise.
How nice.
How can I help you ?
Oh, I've never been here before.
I don't know where she lives.
What's her name ? I can look it up
in the student directory.
Oh, okay.
Tiffany Henderson.
Do I know you ?
No, you don't.
Actually, I know your boyfriend.
Okay. Who are you ?
I'm Beth.
Could we just sit down for a minute ?
Okay.
Um, this is really hard for me,
but it's definitely
something you should hear.
Your boyfriend is cheating
on you... with me.
We were together
Thursday night, twice,
and once again
Friday morning.
- I thought you should know.
- [ Pencil Snaps ]
[ Yelling ]
Sorry.
Tiffany ! What the hell
Are you doing ?
[ Crowd Gasps ]
- Who's that guy ?
- That's her boyfriend.
That's her boy friend ?
Yeah. He's been cheating on her.
[Boy]
I love you.
[ Moans ]
I-I'm sorry,
but you have
the most beautiful feet.
[Moans]
Would you like a foot massage ?
No, I would not like
a foot massage.
[ Louder Voice ] As a matter of fact,
I would hate a foot massage.
Okay. I'm sorry. Relax.
Are there any guys out there
who are just normal ? Huh ?
- [ Strikes Note ]
- Unleash the fury, Mitch.
- Unleash the fury.
[ Strikes Note ]
- Come on, Mitch.
- [ Strikes Note ]
Eat him.
Please, Mitch.
Go get him, boy.
He's right there. Kill him.
Maim him. Bite him.
[ Strikes Note ]
[ Screaming ] Unleash the fury !
Wow, this is cool.
I've never been
in a fraternity house before.
Is this gonna work ?
Ofcourse it's gonna work.
I know the handshake and everything.
Hi.
- Hi. Can I help you ?
- Yeah.
My name's Rubin Carver. I'm
a Xi Chi brother from Ithaca University.
My friends and I were just passing
through, looking for a place to party,
maybe even a place to crash.
- Xi. Xi. Xi, Xi, Xi.
- Chi. Chi.
Chi. Hmph.
-[Chattering, Dishes Clattering]
- Wow.
[ Chattering Stops ]
[ Clears Throat ]
Uh, everyone, this is Rubin.
Apparently, Rubin is our fraternity
brother from our Ithaca chapter.
These are his friends.
Listen, uh, apparently
we've interrupted your dinner.
- So we're just gonna--
- Hey, don't be crazy !
Listen, there's plenty of food
to go around, all right ?
You guys are
more than welcome to stay.
[Chattering]
You know, this food's
actually pretty good.
Hey, you do realize this is
a national black fraternity ?
They know you're not a member.
I'm sorry. I don't think
about that kind of stuff.
Okay, relax. Okay ?
They're just messing with us.
No way. They're pissed
because he lied.
- I say we get the hell out of here.
- Shhh. Relax.
Someone's got some
serious explaining to do.
- Yeah, look what we found
in this guy's duffel bag.
- What ? What is that ?
No, I've never seen that
before in my life !
What are you guys doin' here ?
Are you in the Ku Klux Klan ?
- Whoa, whoa. That is not ours.
- That is not mine !
Okay, hold on a minute. Uh, th-there's
obviously some explanation for this.
Yeah, there is. See, your boy here's
an evil bigot, and now he's gonna die.
Justice.
[Josh ]
Kyle. Kyle.
Kyle !
There you are. I thought
we lost you there for a minute.
- Am I in the hospital ?
- You passed out.
They were messin' with us,
Kyle. It was a joke.
[ All Laughing ]
Racist ? But I watch
Oprah Winfrey every day.
It was a joke, out tie.
A joke !
- [ Laughing Continues ]
- Yeah, I get it.
Sure, put a Klan hood in my bag.
Yeah. Oh, that's funny.
[ Laughing ]
- Whoa.
- I need a wine cooler.
- Hey, have mine.
- Thanks.
*It's tricky to rock around*
* To rock around, that's right
on time, it's tricky*
*It's tricky
Tricky, tricky, tricky*
*It's tricky to rock around
torock around, that's right, on time*
*It's tricky
Trick-Trick-Trick-Tricky*
*I met this good girlie
Her hair was kind a curly*
* Went to her house and busted out
I had to leave real early*
* These girls are really sleazy
All they just say is top lease me*
*Spend some time and rock around*
*I said it's not that easy*
*It's tricky to rock around
to rock around, that's right, on time*
*It's tricky, it's tricky
Trick-Trick-Trick-Tricky*
*It's tricky to rock around
To rock around, it's tricky*
[ Cheering Continues ]
*In New York the people talk
and try to make us rhyme*
* They really honk
but we just walk*
*Because we have no time
And in the city it's a pity*
* 'Cause we just can't hide*
* Tinted windows
don't mean nothing*
* We know who's inside*
*It's tricky to rock around,
to rock around, that's right, on time*
*It's tricky
Tricky, tricky, tricky*
Isn't he just
the cutest little thing ?
Oh, yeah, Kyle's the man !
* Tricky, tricky
Tricky, tricky**
**[Minnie Riperton.:
"Inside My Love "]
You mean never ? Not even once ?
- Well... I mean, I've had sex before,
-* Two people just meeting*
-just, um, never with a person.
-*Barely touching each other*
- Right.
-* Two spirits*
- Well, I think that's kind a cool.
-* Greeting*
- You do ?
- Yeah.
I mean, you should hold out.
It should be special.
* You are one*
-*And I am another*
- Wait till you're in love.
-* We should be*
- I think I love you.
- You are so cute.
-* One*
*Inside each other*
*If you can see inside me
Will you come inside me*
*Do you want to ride
further up*
*If you can see inside me
Will you come inside me*
*Do you want to ride*
-*Further up**
- I take it you don't have a condom.
Uh... no.
Um, I guess I'm all out.
Well, Lawrence
probably has some.
Why don't you try that drawer ?
Next to the Old Spice,
behind the belts.
* Two strangers*
-*Not strangers*
- Good guess.
* Only lacking the knowing*
*So willing, feeling*
You know what ? Um, I don't
exactly know wh-what I'm doing,
and, um, I'm-- ooh.
Shhh. Relax, baby.
Let Rhonda handle this.
* Time's changing*
*More so each year*
*But the early warning*
* The pimp is here*
*So let it rain*
*And let the guitar rock*
- Good time.
- Take care.
- Stay cool. Hey, Devon.
-*Just drop that top*
-*Hey, hey, hey*
-* Well, well, well*
- What's up ?
-*Hey, hey, hey*
* Well, well, well
well, well*
**[Rap Continues, Indistinct]
Let's go, Kyle.
We want details. What happened ?
Well, we had a few drinks,
danced a little, and, you know--
No, we don't know.
Why don't you tell us ?
- [ Laughing ]
- What the hell is that ?
Did you kill a cheetah ?
What ? No. These are her underwear.
She gave 'em to me.
- [ Sniffing ]
- [ All Groaning ]
I boinked her.
Boinked ?
Yeah, wait. Did you just
say the word "boinked" ?
- [All Laughing]
- Well, Kyle,
I certainly hope you got all
the boinking out of your system,
'cause we got a lot of driving
to do today, guys.
But do not get your hopes up
about visiting Graceland,
'cause right now we're all about
the mission at hand.
-Josh.
- What ?
That sounds like a really good plan,
except for one little thing.
- What little thing ?
- We're out of money.
Okay, before I have you
fill out these forms,
I need to ask you a few questions,
and then, if you qualify,
you can make a sperm deposit.
- Is that understood ?
- Mm-hmm. Fire away.
Now, be honest, because
If you don't tell the truth,
the test will
and you won't get paid.
So, first off, have any of you done
any drugs in the past 36 hours ?
And that includes marijuana.
[ Groans ]
Okay, next.
Have any of you had sex
or masturbated in the past 24 hours ?
Well, I guess I'm out.
Because I had sex
last night... with a girl.
- [ Grunting ]
- That's nice.
I think you'll find everything
you need right here in these binders.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Would you each take a cup ?
- Okay.
- And here's yours.
And I would appreciate it
If you could return those
to the front desk after you're finished.
Okay. Uh, thanks.
Cheers.
[ Sighs, Mutters ]
Excuse me. Do you have anything
with Asian women ?
I have this thing for Asian chicks, and
there seem to be none in this binder.
Sorry. This isn't Peep World.
Our selection is limited.
- You're gonna have to make do.
- Okay. No problem.
You've been more than helpful.
Is something wrong ?
Well, no.
But I just couldn't
help but notice that--
Is there something between us ?
I mean, I was thinking
that maybe you might want to--
I don't know-- help me out with
a little... professional assistance.
Do you need some help ?
Yes, I do.
[Woman On Speaker]
Dr. Morris, dial 1 18, please.
Dr. Morris,
please dial 1-1-8.
The moment I saw you out there,
I thought you were incredible.
I mean, you're not like most of
the girls I know. You're a real woman.
That's fine. Turn around, drop your
pants, put both hands flat on the table.
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, my God.
- This is great. Wow. Like this ?
- Exactly.
[ Sighs ] I have to admit,
I love you in that uniform.
Do hose nylons go all the way up,
or are they like those thigh-high kind ?
I'm gonna perform a procedure on you
called "milking the prostate."
It's an anally-induced
ejaculation.
[ Whispers ]
Anal ?
You're gonna feel strong pressure on the
prostate gland from inside your rectum.
Come on, now. You don't have
to get all scientifiic on me, baby.
I mean, we can just talk--
[ Grunts, Moans, Squeals ]
[ Grunting ]
Stop ! Okay,
keep doin' it. Yeah !
Right there ! Ahhh!
[ Moans, Giggling ]
Oh, my God ! Ohhh !
[ Sighs ]
Okay. All done.
[ Exhales ]
That was awesome.
[ Chuckles ]
Wait. Wait.
Does that work ?
I mean, is it even
medically possible ?
Oh, yeah, it works.
It works like a charm.
But back to our story.
[Barry's Voice]
It was Sunday morning back in Ithaca...
when things suddenly
took an unexpected turn.
I'm a mouse. I'm a mouse.
Eat me. Eat me.
Eat me. Eat me. Eat me.
[ Sighs ]
Come on.
You better eat him,
Mitch, before I do.
[ Panting ]
He's tasty.
He's tasty, Mitch.
[ Moaning ]
- [ Mouse Squeaking ]
- [ Moaning Continues ]
Mmm ! Mmm !
- Mmm !Mmm !
- Why'd you lie to me ?
[ Groans ]
[ Gulps ]
I didn't lie.
You-You told me
That Josh went to Boston.
- No, I didn't. I said Austin.
- You said Boston !
Because of you, some guy's life
is ruined in Boston.
So what ? Besides,
what's the difference ?
Wherever he went,
he went because of you.
- What do you mean, because of me ?
- Look, it's obvious.
Josh likes you.
It's disgusting.
I knew you'd come back.
- What do you want ?
- So, how was your
little get away with Josh ?
- I wasn't withJosh.
- Huh, sure. Doesn't matter though,
'cause Josh won't be back
next semester.
He's about to flunk philosophy.
What are you talking about ?
See, he thinks that he has
an extension on the midterm,
but, thanks to a certain
someone-- me--
he doesn't,:
he's such an idiot.
- You are a psycho.
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
- [ Beth Screams ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Gasps, Groaning ]
- Oh, my God !
-*I wanna rock*
*Turn it down, you say*
*Well, all I gotta say to you
time and time again I say no *
- * No *
-*No, no, no*
*Tell me not to play*
*Well, all I gotta say to you
when you tell me not to play*
* I say no, no, no, no *
* So if you ask me why
I like the way I play it *
*There's only one thing
I can say to you *
- * I wanna rock*
- * Rock*
- * I want to rock*
* I wanna rock**
[Barry's Voice] That night, I set
the guys up at my grand parents' house.
I haven't been to
my grand parents' house in along time.
When I was seven years old
I set their dog on fire,
and I haven't been invited back.
But I hear it's still real nice.
I'm serious. " Please."
"Thank you." "This is delicious."
Those are the only words
you're allowed to say, okay ?
What ? I'm great with old people.
Grandmas love me.
Wait a minute.
Wait, wait. " Manilow."
- Barry's last name is Manilow ?
- Yeah, yeah.
- His name is Barry Manilow ?
- Yeah.
[ All Laughing ]
- [ Together] Hi !
- Oh, my goodness !
Oh, look at you boys.
Jack, they're here !
* I see you, baby
shakin' that ass *
*Shakin' that ass
Shakin' that ass*
Jack, Barry's friends are here.
Come and say hi.
- [ Dog Groans ]
- The boys are here.
- Oh, hey, fellas.
- Hi.
- Hey, how's it going ?
- Wait. Let me get up.
- I'll give you guys the full tour.
- Oh, honey !
Careful. Your boner !
Well, what do you want me
to do, cut it off ?
[ Groans ]
I'll tell you what, fellas,
we'll start the tour by me showin' you
where you're gonna sleep.
[ Chuckles ] I'll show you
what we call the guest room. Come on.
Follow me, boys. The guest room.
[ Muttering ]
Ohhh.
[ Woman On TV] I know y'all know
what I'm talkin' about.
Don't be lookin' at me like that now.
I see ya.
Come on.
[ Rings Bell ]
Excuse me.
You remember this kid ?
No, sure don't.
Fuckin'--
[ Muttering ]
- [ Screams ]
- All right, let me ask you once more.
- Have you seen my son ?
- Ow.
Now that you mention it,
there were a few guys in here.
If you loosen my arm,
I could get their bill for ya.
Use your other arm.
- How many were there ?
- I don't know. A few.
- [ Cracking Sound ]
- Aaah ! Four !
One of'em was in here
trying to score drugs.
Honey, look.
They made two calls to Austin, Texas.
Maybe they went there.
[Door Opens]
Havin' a smoke ?
Uh... yeah, yeah.
[ Groans, Mutters ]
I can't sleep either.
Goddamn Viagra gets my heart
racing like a lab rat.
[ Chuckles ]
Are you okay ?
- You look kind a goofy.
- No. No, it's nothing.
- Come on, out with it.
- [ Sniffs ] Okay.
Well... I almost died
two days ago.
- What ?
- Our car exploded. Yeah.
I could be dead right now.
And since that happened,
I find myself asking, "Why ?"
You know ? Like...
what is my reason for living ?
Are you gonna pass
that doobie, or what ?
Doobie ? Yeah.
Yeah, sorry.
Uh, thanks.
- [ Dog Groaning ]
- You know what your problem is ?
You're all brains.
Not enough cock and balls.
Actually, uh, people have been
telling me that my whole life,
believe it or not.
When I was in the sixth grade,
I got so worried about
the escalating situation in Iraq...
that they put me
on an adult dosage ofXanax.
And by eighth grade,
I was in therapy three times a week.
And the truth is, weed is the only thing
that could ever balance me out.
You know what I mean ? Like--
- You okay over there ?
- Hey, old man.
I got the fuckin' munchies
real bad.
How 'bout you ?
Okay, Tiffany, it's time
to stop being so sad.
Look at all this mail
you got !
Look how many nice people
care about you.
You even got a package
From Josh.
-Really ?
-Shall we open it and see what he sent ?
Yeah, come on, Tif.
Let's open it.
- [ Laughs ] It's a tape.
- Oh.
Well, pop it in.
Maybe I should
watch this on my own.
Oh, come on.
This'll definitely cheer you up.
[ Beth On Tape ]
What do you look for in a girl ?
Um, well, let's see.
She should be smart...
- [ All Giggling ]
- and, um, funny.
And, uh...
that's good-- that's good too.
What else do you look for ?
[Josh On TV]
She should be, uh, attractive...
and, um, topless.
- Uh-huh.
-And she should kiss me.
[ Groans ]
[ Vomits ]
- Bye-bye.
- You boys be good now.
It was great to have ya.
- Bye-bye.
- I'll tell Barry you said hello.
Hey, Jack, have that bitch make me
some blueberry pancakes right now.
*Amour*
*I built a love machine*
*I bow all night long*
*I built a love machine
I bow all night long*
*I put the two dollar in*
* Three on fought frowned*
* Grab a hold of my drummer, baby*
*Everybody watch out*
* Yeah**
[Chattering]
Excuse me.
[ Clears Throat ]
www.episodetwo/spoilers...
back slash--
[ Sighs ]
Okay, look. Some people are here,
and they are being very rude.
Okay. Call you back.
I'm sorry, but we need your help.
- Do you know Tiffany Henderson ?
- Room 109.
Yeah, um, well,
her grandfather died,
and she asked me
to pick up her mail for her.
Oh, how sad.
Do you have the key ?
Well, she-she didn't
bring it to the funeral,
so I was hoping that you could--
Oh, I'm sorry,
but you need the key.
Don't worry.
Her mail will be here, safe and sound.
It's not like that, you see ?
She needs something.
- This is an emergency.
- Let's not make a big deal
out of it, okay ?
Well, it's not a big deal,
but you need the key. Rules are rules.
No one's asking you to do
anything wrong here, man.
Just, you know, look away.
Go have an Eskimo Pie or something.
You guys are gonna
have to leave, okay ?
We're not leaving
without that mail.
I suggest you listen to the man
Before you get some Jackie Chan
happening on your face.
- Come on, fellows. Let's go right now.
- That means now, asshole !
- [ Grunts ]
- Ohhh ! Jesus !
- I think he broke my nose. Oh, God !
- Let me see it.
- Come on, Susie.
- You're a wrestler ?
You bet, Mary. You wanna go ?
- Let me see it.
- Oh, God !
All right.
[ Both Grunting, Yelling ]
- Who's my bitch ? Who's my bitch ?
- What ?
[Josh Groaning ]
[Receptionist]
That's it. No, no, no!
[Yelling Continues]
Okay, everyone, freeze !
This here is pepper spray,
and we will not hesitate to use it.
[ Grunting ]
[ Groaning ]
These guys jumped me.
I was just sitting behind my desk.
- What ?
- Kyle ?
- Dad ?
- That's your dad?
Freeze right now !
Everybody freeze !
- [ Crowd Gasps ]
- Put your weapon down now!
- My son was kidnapped !
- Whoa, whoa, whoa !
- [ Cocks Gun ]
- Who was kidnapped ?
I wasn't kidnapped.
These are my friends from school.
What are you talkin' about ?
We all drove down here together.
What ? Then explain to me
how the friggin' car got blown to hell.
- Well, see--
- It was stolen.
That's right. It was stolen.
Tell him, Kyle. Wasn't it ?
Uh-huh. Exactly.
Stolen ? What about
the damned credit card ?
It was in the glove compartment,
and that was stolen too.
Oh, bullcrap !
This is ridiculous !
Why didn't you tell us
Where you were ?
Because I knew you'd get mad !
See ? Look how mad you are !
I'm not mad ! Come on.
You're going with me.
-Josh ?
- [ Crowd Gasps ]
- Tiffany !
- What the-- What's going on ?
- Nothing.
- Damn, dude, she is hot !
- [ Pager Beeping ]
- Ben, my girl friend's paging me.
Can we let these people go ?
- It's a good idea.
- No one is going anywhere.
- Bullshit, junior. He's comin' with me.
- Get off of me !
I'm going back with these guys.
- You shut your mouth
and don't talk back to me.
- Why don't you shut up ?
What the hell
did you just say to me ?
I said, you shut up.
All my life you've been telling me
to stand up for myself.
Well, now I am.
Leave me alone, you jerk !
Why, you ungrateful little--
[ Screaming, Shouting ]
- What--
- Go this way.
Go away ! Go away !
-[Alarm Ringing]
- [ Coughing ]
What was that all about ?
I mean, Josh, what are you doing here ?
- I just missed you. That's all.
- Well, I missed you too.
But it's crazy for you to drive all
the way over here because you missed me.
What ? I thought
you'd be glad to see me.
I am glad to see you.
But, Josh, you have your entire life
to live up at school.
This isn't healthy.
Besides...
I realized a few things
this past week, you know ?
You did ? Like what ?
Like, we're in college.
The window of opportunity to go out
and have fun and meet new people...
is getting smaller by the day.
- It is ?
- Come on, Josh.
We've been together forever.
I mean...
you're pretty much the only guy
I've ever been with.
What do you mean,
"pretty much the only guy" ?
Well, I was 14, and you were away
at camp. But that was years ago.
Besides, we're
in different area codes.
[ Scoffs ]
You know what ? I've been
thinking a lot about us too.
-[Phone Ringing]
- Um, the real reason
I drove down here, actually--
Hold that thought.
Hello ?
Yeah, he's right here.
Whois this ?
Hold on.
It's for you. It's Beth.
Who's Beth ?
Uh--
[ Sighs ]
- Beth ?
- Hi,Josh.
What are you doing ?
Look, I'm not really sure
what's going on between us,
but I need to tell you something.
I'm actually glad you called,
'cause I wanted to tell you something.
Okay, you first.
I can't really
talk about it right now,
but I promise I'll explain
everything when I get back.
Okay ? Really.
I promise.
Uh, I-I gotta
get going, okay ?
Wait, wait !
Don't you want to hear mine ?
Right. Sorry. Is it good ?
Not really. Jacob lied to you.
There's no extension
on your midterm.
- What ?
- He tried to trick you.
If you don't go back,
you're gonna fail.
- What do you look for in a girl ?
- Shit !
She should be smart and funny.
- Aren't you glad I called ?
- Yes. Thank you, Beth.
- I'll call you as soon as
I get back, okay ?
- All right.
- Okay, bye.
- Is this for me ?
Hmm ? Oh, God, no, no, no !
You don't want--
-What the hell is this ?
-Hey, Rubin, I can see myself on the TV.
- I think the tape must be rewound.
- [ Laughing ]
- It's Barry.
- Hey, look.
Look at that.
I can see my bum.
[ Laughing ]
Why would you send this to me ?
So wait.
You guys broke up,
then you hugged,
and then you left ?
Yeah, pretty much.
Oh, loser ! You always have sex with a
girl one last time before you break up.
Everyone knows that !
It's not like that. I've known her
my whole life. She's my best friend.
So, what do we do now?
- You guys wanna smoke some drugs ?
- Idon't think so, Kyle.
My midterm starts in exactly
46 hours, so I gotta get back.
Although I'm gonna fail anyway,
so it doesn't really matter, but--
- Which class was it ?
- Ancient philosophy.
Well, I can teach you
ancient philosophy in 46 hours.
- You can ?
- I can teach Japanese
to a monkey in 46 hours.
The key is just finding a way
to relate to the material.
Like, okay, you like
pro wrestling, don't you ?
- Who doesn't ?
- Okay.
Socrates-- He was like the Vince McMahon
of philosophy. He started it all.
* Can you hear us
pumping on your stereo*
*Life is a cigarette*
* You smoke till itends*
*But if you rock it a little bit*
* You'll burn all your sins*
*Dry your eyes and take out the lies*
* Yes, it's true *
Oh, what was
the 20-Man Battle Royal ?
Participation explains predication.
Aristotle's "one over many" argument.
- Right.
- You know this.
You'll be fine.
[ Robot Beeping ]
Freeze right there !
Don't move !
Is this philosophy ?
[ Chattering ]
All right, if you hear anything,
give me a call.
Bomb threat is serious business.
A felony. Here, take my card.
- Okay.
-[Sirens Wailing]
[Police Radio, Indistinct]
[Man]
Okay, let's move it.
-What's going on with this bomb threat ?
-I don't know.
False alarm, people.
Everyone, back inside.
We're gonna do this thing.
That's right.
-Josh.
- Beth !
Hey, um...
thanks for calling.
Uh, it's been
a really weird week.
So, how'd you do ?
On the exam ?
Pretty good, actually.
- You did ?
- Yeah.
Were you surprised ?
You weren't back
in time for the exam,
so I, uh, called in
a bomb threat.
You did that ?
[ Laughs ]
That's insane.
I wasn't gonna let Jacob
get you kicked out of school.
Besides, I'm gonna need you
around next semester.
So I did good, right ?
Good ?
That's the coolest thing
anyone's ever done for me.
Mom ?
[ Pants ]
I'm so sorry.
Mom ?
I got carried away
with the story there.
[ Panting ]
So, anyway, Josh got a " B" plus on
his midterm. He got to stay in college.
[Barry's Voice]
And I'm happy to report that
he and Beth are still together.
They're still really into
making their home movies.
In fact, they have about 70 hours
of unedited amateur video.
It's pretty wild.
I know, because I bought
some of it on eBay.
That guy Jacob--
He left school.
He went on to become the leader
of some cult out in Iowa.
Eventually, he tried
organizing amass suicide.
Only problem is,
he drank the Kool-Aid first,
and, well, after wards everyone else
just kinda changed their minds.
Too bad.
As for Rubin--
Remember Rubin ?
Remember how he always claimed that
he was destined for great things ?
Something tells me the people
of Earth are gonna need me.
Well, he was right.
Rubin used cross-pollination
to develop a strain of marijuana...
that is not only
remarkably potent...
but also completely undetectable
by any of today's standard drug tests.
Oh, my God.
He was named High Times'
man of the year.
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
As for E.L., despite
his swinging philosophy on sexuality,
he got pretty serious
with some girl he met.
And you want me to use two fingers ?
I believe she was premed.
Did I say two ?
Better make it three.
Then there's Kyle.
Kyle and his father
reconciled their differences.
Hi, Dad. Merry Christmas.
He brought his new girl friend home
To meet his parents.
Rhonda, this is my father, Earl.
Dad, this is Rhonda.
Merry Christmas, Dad.
Come here.
That's the end
of the tour, okay ?
I, uh, I hope each of you
strongly considers...
becoming part
of the Ithaca tradition...
as we lead future generations
of young men and women...
forward into the new century.
Thanks a lot.
You guys were great.
- Thanks.
- Thank you so much.
- No, it was good. It was fun.
- Thanks.
- I'll see you in the fall.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Yeah.
- Okay. Thank you.
- I'd just like to say thank you.
I mean, uh, that was...
really great.
Thank you.
-*Say that crazy sound*
- Thank you.
-[Boy] Mom ?
*My neighbordigs the flavors till*
-*He's moving to another town*
- Thank you.
*And I don't believe he'll comeback*
-* Goddamn right, it's a beautiful day*
- I'm pumping your mommy.
-* Uh-huh, goddamn right
it's a beautiful day*
- [ Grunting, Moaning ]
* Uh-huh*
* Goddamn right
it's a beautiful day, uh-huh*
-* Goddamn right, it's
a beautiful day, uh-huh**
- [ Grunting Continues ]
* Okay, what is it tonight*
*Please, please tell me
what the hell is wrong*
*Do you wanna eat, do you wanna sleep
Do you wanna drown*
*Just settle down
Settle down, settle down*
*I'll give you candy, give you
diamonds, give you pills*
* Give you anything you want
Hundred-dollar bills*
*I'll even let you watch
the shows you wanna see*
*Just marry me
Marry me, marry me now*
* Oh, hey*
*I'm so sick of you tonight*
* You never stay awake
when I'm at home*
*Is something wrong with me
Something wrong with you*
*I really wish I knew
Wish I knew, wish I knew*
*I'll give you candy, give you
diamonds, give you pills*
* Give you anything you want
Hundred-dollar bills*
*I'll even let you watch
the shows you wanna see*
*Just marry me
Marry me, marry me now*
* Oh, hey*
[Man]
You've become so distant.
Stop touching me!
Are you in love with this guy ?
* When I was young
I learned the game*
* When love and happiness
were the same*
*Now I'm older and I don't play*
*I found out the hardest way*
*I got wasted, she got mad*
*She called me names
and she called her dad*
*He got crazy*
* One and one
I'll torture you*
*I'll give you candy, give you
diamonds, give you pills*
* Give you anything you want
Hundred-dollar bills*
*I'll even let you watch
the shows you wanna see*
*I'll give you anything
anything, anything*
*Anything*
*I'll give you anything*
:)  SiDi  :)