Give her some room.
She needs space! Breathe, girl, breathe!
Does anyone have anything she can eat?
I have some leftover
Halloween candy in my locker.
I may have a juice box.
I'll go get Marley's mom.
ARTIE:
This is bad.
Never in the history
of show choir competitions
has anyone ever fainted.
We got the juice.
No, I'm okay.
Drink the damn juice!
FINN: Marley? Marley, are you okay?
What happened?
JAKE:
She hasn't been eating.
She's been skipping lunch.
Is that because
you've been telling her to?
You trying to turn her
into a damn rexy?
What?
No. Why would I...
why would I want that?
'Cause you're a crazy, evil bitch.
Hey, Marley, you all right?
The nurse is on the way, Mr. Schue.
Santana, Puck, you stay here with Marley.
The rest of you guys,
get back up there.
Leaving the stage
mid-competition,
for any reason, is risking
immediate disqualification.
What?! That-that's a rule?
SUE:
Yeah, it's a rule.
One of the bylaws, actually.
As all of you all were spiraling
into a self-created
K-hole of crazy,
the judges, by unanimous vote,
have declared the Warblers victorious.
Hey, congratulations, Finn Hudson.
For the first time in its charmed,
yet pitiful existence,
the New Directions!
Has lost Sectionals.
But here's the good news.
Christmas came early
for one Sue Sylvester.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
That was Blaine.
They lost.
(gasps) Apparently, the new girl,
Marley, passed out on stage,
and the Warblers won.
Oh, my God. So, wait.
That... that's it then.
What are they going to do now?
I don't know.
I just feel bad for Blaine.
If he was still with the Warblers,
he'd be on his way
to Regionals right now.
You think I should call Finn? If you
think it's gonna make him feel better.
No. I don't, actually.
It'll probably
just make him feel worse.
Imagine coming down
from one loss just to be
reminded of an even bigger one.
Well, our friends' feelings
aside, it's really woken me up
to the idea of making the most
of the chances that you have.
You know? I've got one more
chance of getting into NYADA,
and I can't blow the audition.
It's not your last chance, okay?
I mean, you can still reapply.
No.
I can't live my life chasing
something that the universe
is trying to tell me that I'm
not good enough to achieve.
It's not the universe.
It's just Carmen Tibideaux.
Is there a difference?
Speaking of Carmen,
has she started passing out
her golden tickets
for the Winter Showcase yet?
No, and it doesn't matter,
because I'm not getting one.
Alexandra Blasucci was
the last freshman to get one
in the past seven years,
and she was practically
raised on the Broadway stage.
Wait. How do you even know
about those tickets?
I've become very active
on the NYADA blogs.
I figured, the more I know,
the better I can streamline
my application and audition.
(opera music playing)
The Winter Showcase
is like the NYADA Met Ball.
Ten students are invited to
perform at the showcase a year.
The cream of the cream.
She handwrites and
hand-delivers each invitation.
Just getting invited is an honor.
Former winners have gone on
to win Emmys, Tonys,
Golden Globes and even an Oscar.
But they all agree.
The proudest and greatest moment
of their careers
was when Carmen handed them
that Golden Envelope.
♪
(applause)
(school bell rings)
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wha-What's
happening? What are you doing?
Hey, there, Lumps.
Just taking advantage
of the high ceilings
on this, my new rehearsal space.
It is now the home of my
brand-new French-Canadian,
circus-inspired Cheerios!
Side project, Sue du Soleil.
Get rid of all this sparkly red stuff.
It still smells like
the Glee Club in here.
What are you talking about?
Well, when your season ended,
with your loss at Sectionals,
I filed the appropriate paperwork
so that the Cheerios! Take
full possession of this room,
including everything
in it... your trophies,
your beloved plaque
with the late Lillian Adler.
And I took her inspirational quotation,
and I re-engraved something
for myself here.
"I died a slow, horrible death
choking on the fluid
in my own lungs."
You...
You can't do this.
Oh, I didn't do this.
You did this, and now
if you'll excuse me,
I'm going to take
your Nationals trophy,
and I'm going to run
over it with my Le Car.
Over my dead body.
(grunting)
Figgins' office.
Now!
Door jam?
(school bell ringing)
How could you have let this happen?
It's not rocket science, Will.
When the football team
loses and the season is over,
they are longer entitled
to use the field!
Fine. We'll use
the auditorium.
The auditorium now belongs
to the McKinley High
Drum and Bugle Corps.
What about the Spanish Room?
I've rented it out to the Rotary Club.
The history classroom? Sex
and Love Addicts Anonymous.
You're telling me that there's nowhere
in this school
that the Glee Club can rehearse?
That's exactly what
I'm telling you, Finn Hudson.
It's pure economics.
The district is running
a seven-figure deficit,
and we're sitting on prime real estate.
SUE:
Let's face facts.
The New Directions!
Are finished.
You have no place
to practice or perform.
The only thing left
to do is to hand over
the keys to the choir room
and inform your students
that Glee Club is over for the year.
And if that's too much
for your feeble constitution,
I'm happy to do it for you.
No.
I'll do it.
(school bell ringing)
(sighs)
How does it feel, Coach?
Got to be honest, Becky.
I have looked forward
to this very moment
for a long time.
Now that it's finally here,
I'm left with a strange, empty feeling.
That's how I felt
when I saw Prometheus.
Now, I'd be lying if I said
I wasn't a little concerned
about them, Becky.
(sighs)
Those Glee Clubbers are
so emotionally fragile,
I can't help wonder
what this will do to them.
With their dreams crushed,
where and who will they be
in just a few short months?
I'm a drug mule
in the Lima crack district.
I was forced to sell my legs
to science.
I'm performing
on the bathhouse circuit.
I'm a finance major at Brandeis.
It turns out Glee Club
was really holding me back.
Oh, I wish there was some way
to assuage my guilt.
A sign that I was doing
the right thing.
(knocking)
Sue Sylvester?
I cannot thank you enough.
I can't tell you
how much I hate those kids!
Do you know how demeaning
it is when they just turn to you
and yell, "Hit it!,"
and you're just supposed
to know what song they're gonna sing?
I'm free. Free.
(school bell ringing)
So, that's it?
No more Glee? Until
next September.
Sugar already bailed.
Can I just say
what everyone is thinking?
This is Marley's fault.
New Rachel, my butt.
I knew Rachel Berry.
I was friends with Rachel Berry,
and you, Marley, are no Rachel Berry.
Mm-hmm.
Preach. FINN: Guys,
guys, enough.
It's not like it's over.
The holiday concert is later
this week, and we are
going to be preparing
for it all week long.
If this is our swan song,
let's make it the best one it can be.
You really expect us to go up
in front of the whole school and parade
our loserdom for all to see?
Yeah, Kitty does have a point.
We agreed to do the show
when we thought
it would be on the heels
of another Sectionals victory.
Now it just feels like a pity party.
I love to sing and dance
as much as anybody,
but without a competition
to prep for, it's hard
to get motivated.
I understand that we need
a little shift in perspective,
but let's just enjoy this week,
and look forward
to our big comeback next year.
That's right.
What about those of us
who won't have a next year?
(school bell ringing)
It worked.
You found me.
Did you lay out the
line of cereal for me?
Well, it's Tuesday, and I know
how you forget
to eat breakfast on Tuesdays
'cause the first few days
of the week tend to confuse you.
How did you know that?
You told me.
Is that mine? I think
maybe the reason
why Santana was always
picking on me was because
some part of her knew the truth.
About Area 51?
About that I'm totally into you.
You're, uh, the only person
that really understands me.
It's 'cause you're a genius.
And most people don't
understand geniuses.
Like most people
didn't appreciate Einstein
or the Spice Girls
until it was too late.
And I think that you know that I think
that you are... pretty awesome.
And your impressions are amazing.
(like Elvis):
Well, thank you, Brittany.
(laughs) I'm super bummed
about Glee Club ending,
but I'm most sad
that I never got the chance to
do a real love song with you.
That's why I laid out
the path of cereal...
so you could come in
here and sing with me.
Is that why the band's here?
You figured it all out.
So, will you do me the honor
of singing a ballad with me?
I love this song.
("Something Stupid" begins)
(in harmony): ♪ I know I stand
in line until you think ♪
♪ You have the time
to spend an evening with me ♪
♪ And if we go someplace to dance ♪
♪ I know that there's a chance
you won't be leaving with me ♪
♪ And afterwards we drop
into a quiet little place ♪
♪ And have a drink or two
♪ And then I go and spoil it all ♪
♪ By saying something stupid
like "I love you" ♪
♪ I can see it in your eyes
♪ That you despise the same old lies ♪
♪ You heard the night before
♪ And though it's just a line to you ♪
♪ For me it's true and never
seemed so right before ♪
♪ I practice every day to find
some clever lines to say ♪
♪ To make the meaning come through ♪
♪ But then I go and spoil it all ♪
♪ By saying something stupid
like "I love you" ♪
♪ The time is right,
your perfume fills my head ♪
♪ The stars get red and,
oh, the night's so blue ♪
♪ And then I go and spoil it all ♪
♪ By saying something stupid
like "I love you" ♪
♪ I love you
♪ I... love you.
(whispers):
I can't.
Is it my lips?
No. Your lips are so
soft and horizontal.
I just like you too much
to put you in danger.
Santana broke up with you.
No, it's not just Santana.
It's, like, all the
lesbians of the nation,
and I don't know how they found out
about Santana and I dating,
but once they did, they started
sending me, like, tweets,
and Facebook messages on
Lord Tubbington's wall.
I think it means a lot to them
to see two super-hot,
popular girls in love,
and I worry if they find
out about you and I dating,
that they'll turn on you
and get really violent
and hurt your beautiful face and mouth.
I'm not scared of them.
I know, uh, yeah...
Um, thanks for the song
and breakfast was great,
but I just can't.
(school bell rings)
(sprightly classical piano playing)
♪
Knees back, Schwimmer.
Knees...
Can I go get a sip of water?
Of course.
Of course, yeah.
Stop.
Everybody, stop.
Because that's what happens
when you're thirsty on Broadway.
You see, they stop the show
so that mommy can hand you a sippy cup.
Is this how you respond to
getting a golden ticket?
I'm not being a diva.
I'm just...
I'm dehydrated,
and I've been working
my butt off in this class,
Hmm. And I have gotten better.
Three months in,
you still have no stamina
no precision, and you think
you can outperform Alexandra
Blasucci at the Showcase?
That girl was born in toe shoes.
You won't even be able to keep up.
I've kept up with you.
Oh. All right.
I-I just meant, with everything
that you've thrown at me...
I don't throw things...
I teach.
Nothing I do here is random
or unintentional.
It's not my fault that you
don't understand my methods.
And it's not my fault that you
don't see how good I've become.
Okay.
Would you like to show me
how good you've become?
Show me that I'm not wasting my time?
Fine.
Chicago.
Opening number.
You familiar with it?
Anybody else here can
join in if they like,
but this is between me
and the platypus.
(Rachel laughs)
("All That Jazz" playing)
♪ Come on, babe,
why don't we paint the town ♪
♪ And all that jazz
♪ I'm gonna rouge my knees
and roll my stockings down ♪
♪ And all that jazz
♪ Start the car,
I know a whoopee spot ♪
♪ Where the gin is cold,
but the piano's hot ♪
♪ It's just a noisy hall
where there's a nightly brawl ♪
♪ And all...
♪ That...
♪ Jazz...
♪ Skiddoo ♪
♪ And all that jazz
(faster, brighter): ♪ Slick your
hair and wear your buckle shoes ♪
♪ And all that jazz
♪ I hear that father dip
is gonna blow the blues ♪
♪ And all that jazz
♪ Hold on, hon, we're gonna bunny hug ♪
♪ I bought some aspirin
down at United Drug ♪
♪ In case you shake apart
and want a brand-new start ♪
♪ To do
♪ That
♪ Jazz!
♪ Find a flask
♪ We're playing fast and loose ♪
♪ And all that jazz
♪ Right up here is where
I store the juice ♪
♪ And all that jazz
♪ Come on, babe,
we're gonna brush the sky ♪
♪ I bet you Lucky Lindy
never flew so high ♪
♪ 'Cause in the stratosphere,
how could he lend an ear ♪
♪ To all...
♪ That...
(breathily):
♪ Jazz... ♪
(dancers oohing, aahing)
♪ No, I'm no one's wife
♪ But, oh, I love my life
♪ And all...
♪ That...
♪ Jazz...
♪ That jazz.
(song ends)
Now...
do you see what I'm saying, Schwimmer?
You're not good enough yet.
Maybe you're right.
Yeah, I'm not-I'm not
as good of a dancer as you are.
Oh! Oh, you're finally
learning something in here.
But I'm just as good of a singer,
maybe even better.
You think anyone in here believes that?
Because there's a big difference
between self-confidence
and delusion.
No one else has to believe it.
No one but me.
But... thank you.
You actually did teach me
something, which is that
if I'm going to win this showcase,
the only way I'm gonna do it
is with my voice.
Where are we putting Scott Rudin?
That's where you have him?
You need to put him over here.
As a matter of fact,
you need to redo all of this.
(knock at door)
Madame Tibideaux?
I hope it's all right
that I'm dropping by your office.
I-I'm not sure that
you, uh, remember me...
What can I do for
you, Mr. Hummel?
Oh, uh,
I-I applied for
the second semester...
I received it.
I reviewed it.
And the accompanying video?
Of you doing the acoustic version
of WHAM!'s "Wake Me Up
Before You Go-Go"?
What'd you think?
I thought exactly what I thought
the first time you auditioned
for me last Spring.
"Here's a very talented young man
"who knows how to sell a number,
but who is devoid
of complexity and depth."
What?
You gave me
surface...
when I was looking for soul.
We are training artists
here, Mr. Hummel.
Performers who are not afraid
to show their vulnerability,
and yes, even their heart.
Madame Tibideaux, I-I-I-I-I have
all of those things.
I rarely give anyone a second chance,
and when I do, it is on my terms.
Now, thank you for your
continued interest in NYADA,
but as you can see, I'm busy preparing
for the Winter Showcase.
Good afternoon, Mr. Hummel.
(school bell rings)
Oh, hell no.
What happened to you?
I joined the marching band.
I'm the drum leader.
What happened to you?
We joined the Cheerios!
We had to do something.
It's our senior year.
We wanted to compete.
We want to be part of a team.
And Coach Sylvester just let you?
It was way easier than I thought.
I'm gonna be blunt.
60 Minutes is doing a piece on me,
and that Leslie Stahl is
gonna to bring the heat.
I could use a handsome,
non-flammable gay
to articulate how my defeating
the Glee Club once and for all
and absorbing its budget
was actually the best thing
that ever happened to him.
And my squad's looking
a little pale these days.
Wouldn't hurt to add
a dash of Yellow ♪4
to my championship cheer batter.
I get what you're saying.
It's weird to suddenly feel like
you're not a part of anything.
That's why we joined
the basketball team.
Oh, no,
that's why you joined
the basketball team.
I joined the basketball team
because I'm good at basketball.
Uh...
That's right.
Uh-huh.
I joined the McKinley
Floor Hockey Team.
And when I slip a wig
underneath the face mask,
nobody will be the wiser.
Hallelu.
Who knew this school had so many clubs?
I joined the Interfaith
Paintball League,
where Christians, Jews and Muslims can
shoot at each other safely.
(spattering)
Well, it looks like we've
all sort of moved on,
which just leaves one question:
When are we going to tell Finn?
(school bell rings)
I can't believe it's been,
like, what, two days,
that you've all gone
in completely separate,
and totally insane, directions.
We lost Sectionals.
Our season is over.
You can't be upset that we've moved on.
It's the healthy thing to do.
Is it really?
Is it the healthy thing to do
to take orders from Sue Sylvester
for the rest of the school year?
And Artie, man,
you basically dragged me
out of the tire shop,
telling me that this club was
part of my destiny somehow.
What did you even join?
Your costume is ridiculous.
I looks like a peacock
died on your head.
It's called a plume.
Whatever! Okay, look,
I-I'm not going to waste
all six minutes
I was able to book the auditorium for
yelling at you guys.
Six minutes?
Yeah.
Emperor Sylvester swooped in
and carved the reservation
hours into tenths.
So the only other time
I was able to get
was 9:54, Friday night,
and I'll be here ready to rehearse,
and I hope you will, too.
'Cause if you don't,
I think you're going to regret
missing that opportunity
for the rest of your lives.
I'll definitely be here.
Yeah, well, we'd all be here
if you hadn't face-planted
at Sectionals.
Tina, enough.
(speaking quietly)
(light switches clicking, clanking)
(school bell rings)
Hey.
Oh.
Can I ask you a question?
Oh, The Walking Dead isn't
based on a true story.
I already checked.
That's not what I was
gonna ask, but, oh.
No, thanks.
Are you planning on going
to the holiday concert
rehearsal on Friday?
Why?
Well, I pulled some strings
and I got us reservation
for the VIP booth at Breadstix,
but the only time
they had available was
for the same time as rehearsal.
So, do you want to go?
You mean, like... on a date?
Yeah, well, I was thinking
about what Finn said
about last chances,
Mm-hmm.
And how everyone's
joining all these clubs
because they don't want to miss out,
and the truth is, is that
ever since Santana left,
you're the only person
that makes me smile.
I am pretty
non-stop hilarious.
You make me happy, Sam,
And I don't want to waste any more time
not smiling at your hilariousness.
What about the lesbian
blogger community?
They're not gonna like it,
but the way I figure is that
they know they're my sisters
and love is love.
(like Forrest Gump): I may not be a
smart man, but I know what love is.
(chamber orchestra tuning up)
(instruments quiet)
Welcome to the New York
Academy of Dramatic Arts'
annual Winter Showcase.
While this is a competition,
it is also a celebration.
Each year, our faculty
chooses ten students
who exemplify the best
of what we are trying to achieve.
Our first performer is Alexandra.
Blasucci.
She will be doing Delibes' Sylvia
with variations
by Sir Frederick Ashton.
(applause)
(orchestra playing lively,
dramatic selection from Sylvia )
Hey.
Hey. Hi.
You're nervous.
I was, too, at my first showcase.
Just... remember what I said
when we first met...
you're here
because you're the best of the best.
What?
Well, that's very sweet.
That was a very good pep talk.
I don't know.
I feel like I...
like I got this.
You know?
Look, I-I know I may not be a...
like, a typical beauty, and...
no one's gonna ever pay me to
walk the runway on Fashion Week
or I'm not gonna cure cancer,
write the Great American Novel,
but if you give me a stage to sing on,
I know, in my gut, that there's
no one that can beat me.
I... can't believe
you can be so calm.
(chuckling):
Oh, my God... I'm terrified!
But, um, I know who I am and I know
what I'm gonna do.
I'm just gonna go out there like...
I'm never gonna get
a chance to sing again.
Well, I may not be able to cure
anything either,
but I'm smart enough to know...
never get in the way
of a woman on a mission.
So...
...break a leg.
What was that for?
I think I'm just gonna
start doing things
like I'm never gonna
get another chance to.
KURT:
Hey!
Uh, as sympathetic as I am
at this particular act
of a rom-com,
Rachel, you're up.
Our next performer is
from the freshman class.
Please welcome Miss Rachel Berry.
(applause)
Hi, I'm Rachel Berry, and, um...
I'm just going to...
sing for you.
("Being Good Isn't Good Enough" begins)
♪ Being good
♪ Isn't good enough
♪ Being good won't be good enough ♪
♪ Gotta fly and if I
♪ Fall
♪ That's the way it's gotta be ♪
♪ There's no other way for
♪ Me
♪ Being good
♪ Just won't be good enough
♪ I'll be the best
♪ Or nothing
♪ At all
♪ I'll try
♪ Am I strong enough?
♪ Is there time?
♪ Have I long enough?
♪ Gotta fly
♪ And if I fall
♪ Well, that's the way it's gotta be ♪
♪ There's no other way for me
♪ Being good
♪ Just won't be good enough
♪ I'll be the best
♪ Or nothing
♪ At all.
(cheers and applause)
Encore!
(laughing)
Come on! Encore!
Um, this is my favorite holiday song
that I'd like to sing for you today.
("O Holy Night" begins)
♪ O holy night
♪ The stars are brightly
♪ Shining
♪ It is the night of our dear
♪ Savior's birth ♪
♪ Long lay the world
♪ In sin and error pining
♪ Till He appeared
♪ And the soul felt its worth
♪ A thrill of hope, the ♪
♪ Weary world
♪ Rejoices, for
♪ Yonder breaks a ♪
♪ New and glorious morn
♪ Fall
♪ On your knees... ♪
♪ O hear the angel voices
♪ O night divine
♪ O night
♪ When Christ was born ♪
♪ O
♪ Night
♪ Divine
♪ O
♪ Night ♪
♪ O night ♪
♪ Divine
♪ Oh, oh...
♪ O
♪ Night
♪ Divine.
(song ends)
(cheers and applause)
Rachel, that was wonderful.
No...
it was superb.
And now we're going to have
a brief intermission,
and when we come back,
if he thinks he's ready,
we'll have a performance...
from Mr. Hummel.
Carmen Tibideaux is an insane person.
Asking me to sing
in front of the entire NYADA faculty?
And all those theatrical
luminaries? I mean,
why would she do that?
She's giving you a second chance
at your audition.
She just wants to see how
you perform under pressure.
I'm gonna fail,
that's what's gonna happen.
Uh... I have nothing prepared.
Oh, my God.
You have an entire repertoire.
I guess I could do "Wishing
You Were Somehow Here Again"?
No Phantom, not in front of this crowd.
"With One Look"?
Sunset Boulevard? Same thing.
(sighs) "Being Alive"?
Yes.
Oh, my God, I just got chills.
That's perfect!
There's only one problem...
I think that's a song that Carmen hates
and I can't do it
without a costume or props!
You don't need any of that stuff!
Yes, I do.
You know that I'm at my best
when I have my careful
assortment of bells
and whistles, like steel
scaffolding or my gold lamé pants.
Kurt.
You said it yourself...
that is exactly what Carmen
does not want to see.
You know when you were
your absolute best?
My favorite performance ever?
When you sang "I Want to Hold
Your Hand" in the choir room.
It was so...
just simple
and emotional and...
I don't know, I...
I get chills every time
I think about it.
Do you remember that?
(sighs)
Of course I do.
But things were different...
my dad was in the hospital.
I dedicated it to him.
Who am I supposed
to dedicate this to? Carmen?
To yourself.
(applause)
KURT:
Uh, uh...
Hi. Um...
I'm Kurt Hummel,
and I'll be auditioning
for the role of...
NYADA student.
Tonight I am going to perform a song
that I've loved since I was six.
But, um...
I think for the
first time in my life, I...
finally understand what it means.
("Being Alive" begins)
♪ Someone to hold you too close ♪
♪ Someone to hurt you too deep ♪
♪ Someone to sit in your chair
♪ To ruin your sleep
♪ Someone to crowd you with love ♪
♪ Someone to force you to care ♪
♪ Someone to make you come through ♪
♪ Who will always be there
♪ As frightened as you of being alive ♪
♪ Being alive
♪ Somebody hold me too close
♪ Somebody hurt me too deep
♪ Somebody sit in my chair
and ruin my sleep ♪
♪ And make me aware of being alive ♪
♪ Make me alive
♪ Make me confused
♪ Mock me with praise
♪ Let me be used
♪ Vary my days
♪ But alone is alone
♪ Not alive
♪ Somebody crowd me with love
♪ Somebody force me to care
♪ Somebody let me come through
♪ I'll always be there,
as frightened as you ♪
♪ To help us survive
♪ Being alive...
♪ Being alive
♪ Being alive!
(applause, cheering and whistling)
(phone buzzing)
Rachel, it's Finn.
You butt-dialed me again.
Oh, I... I didn't...
I didn't butt-dial you.
I just, um...
I wanted to hear your voice.
Especially after...
Hearing we lost?
That everyone's giving up
and moving on?
It's over.
We're done competing for the year.
Finn, Glee Club isn't
just about competing.
You kidding me?
You live to compete.
Kurt told me
you were competing tonight.
How'd it go?
I won.
Great.
That's...
Wow, uh... congratulations.
Finn, listen to me.
You know, even if we...
we never won our Sectionals,
or Nationals had never happened...
it still would have been worth it.
I mean, Glee... it's...
it's about the love of music.
It's about people like Puck and Artie
not just singing together,
but actually being friends.
And Brittany and Mike dancing
just for fun
when no one else is around.
It's even about the romances.
You know, they come and go, but...
they're just as important.
Look, those kids...
they respect you so much.
And they look up to you, so...
don't let them give up on their dreams.
Okay?
Promise me one thing.
Don't give up on yours.
Okay?
(beep)
(sighs heavily)
No one else is coming, are they?
I don't think so.
I had some good news for us, but
maybe it doesn't matter anymore.
I found a place where
Glee Club can practice.
It's not great, but
I know for a fact
that no one can kick us out.
(school bell ringing)
(sighs)
FINN:
"Dear Glee Club,
"I realize most of you think
"it's stupid to still call us that.
I mean, our season's over,
so what are we now, really?"
You're all garbage!
FINN: "We lost Sectionals,
so what do we have left?"
You have assassinated William
McKinley all over again!
FINN:
"Nothing. We've got nothing.
"I got a phone call
from Rachel last night.
"She just won
the Winter Showcase at NYADA,
"which is, like, this huge deal.
"Like, not once in history has
it ever gone to a Freshman.
"And she reminded me why.
"I joined Glee Club in the first place.
"It's about music.
"Every one of us loves music.
"And no one can take that away from us.
"I'm not giving up on you.
"Marley found a place
where we can rehearse,
"and I want us to meet there
today after school at 5:00.
I hope I see you all there."
(shivering)
It gets dark so early now.
I'm really sorry, Finn.
Marley, don't.
No, I mean it.
You've being so nice about
this, but it's my fault.
I was...
naive and insecure
and self-centered,
and now Glee Club's over.
Well, you and I are still here, right?
("Don't Dream it's Over"
by Crowded House begins)
♪ There is freedom within
♪ There is freedom without
♪ Try to catch the deluge
in a paper cup ♪
♪ There's a battle ahead
♪ Many battles are lost
♪ But you'll never see the end
of the road ♪
♪ While you're traveling with me ♪
♪ Hey now, hey now
BOTH:
♪ Don't dream it's over
FINN:
♪ Hey now, hey now
♪ When the world comes in
♪ They come, they come
♪ To build a wall between us
♪ We know they won't win
♪ Now I'm towing my car
♪ There's a hole in the roof
♪ My possessions
are causing me suspicion ♪
♪ But there's no proof
♪ In the paper today
♪ Tales of war and of waste
♪ But you turn right over
to the TV page ♪
ALL:
♪ Hey now, hey now
♪ Don't dream it's over
♪ When the world comes in
♪ They come, they come
♪ To build a wall between us
♪ We know they won't win
♪ Only shadows ahead
♪ Barely clearing the roof
♪ Get to know the feeling
of liberation and release ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh-oh, oh
♪ Hey now, hey now
♪ Don't dream it's over
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah
♪ Hey now, hey now
♪ When the world comes in
♪ When the world comes in ♪
♪ They come, they come...
Oh, my God, what happened?
I got my NYADA letter.
I got in.
Oh, my God!
♪ Hey now, hey now
♪ Don't dream it's over
♪ Don't dream it's over.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com