(school bell rings)
(Guys & Dolls' "Sit Down,
You're Rockin' the Boat" plays)
♪ ...thank the Lord ♪
♪ And I said to myself,
sit down ♪
♪ Said to myself, sit down ♪
♪ Sit down,
you're rockin' the boat ♪
(kids laughing)
♪ Sit down ♪
♪ I said to myself, sit down ♪
♪ Said to myself, sit down ♪
♪ Sit down,
you're rockin' the boat ♪
♪ And the Devil will
drag you under ♪
♪ By the scarf in back
of your checkered coat ♪
♪ Sit down, sit down, sit down,
sit down ♪
♪ Sit down,
you're rockin' the boat ♪
♪ Sit down, you're rockin',
sit down, sit down, sit down ♪
♪ You're rockin' the boat ♪
♪ Sit down, you're rockin',
sit down, sit down, sit down ♪
♪ You're rockin' the boat ♪
♪ Sit down ♪
♪ You're rocking ♪
♪ The boat! ♪
(song ends, everybody cheers)
That was the most ghetto
number I have ever seen.
Then just call me
George Jefferson,
because we went from
the ghetto to the penthouse.
National champs, baby!
(whooping, cheering)
This week's assignment is easy.
Graduation is just
a few days away.
There's nothing left
to prepare for.
Our work here is done,
so there's only one thing
left to do:
Say goodbye.
Underclassmen, pick some songs
to say goodbye to the seniors;
seniors, pick a song to say
goodbye to us.
A part of me wants
to lock these doors
and stay in here with
everyone forever.
We can use the wastebasket
for the toilet,
and then we could eat
Joe for the food,
since she's been here
the shortest,
so we know her
the least.
I really hope
you're about to rap.
(laughs)
No such luck.
I'm leading by
example here.
This one...
is for you guys.
(slowly strumming intro to
Rod Stewart's "Forever Young")
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ May the good Lord
be with you ♪
♪ Down every road you roam ♪
♪ And may sunshine and happiness
surround you ♪
♪ When you're far from home ♪
♪ Be courageous and be brave ♪
♪ And in my heart,
you'll always stay ♪
♪ Forever young ♪
♪ May good fortune be with you ♪
♪ May your guiding light
be strong ♪
♪ Build a stairway to heaven
with a prince or a vagabond ♪
♪ And may you never
love in vain ♪
♪ And in my heart,
you'll always remain ♪
♪ Forever young ♪
♪ For... ♪
♪ ...ever young ♪
♪ ...ever... ♪
♪ Young. ♪
When I first got to McKinley, I
was afraid to make eye contact.
I didn't talk
about my politics,
I didn't share
what was in my heart
I... oh, let's just call
the Cadillac pink
and be done with it.
I was in the closet.
And most days,
I was also in the Dumpster.
But McKinley has made me
a stronger,
more socially conscious,
fashion-forward person.
And perhaps
I played some small part
in making it possible for
tadpole gays all over Lima
to be themselves in public.
Not a bad legacy for someone
who once pretended
to be in lust with Rachel Berry
so I wouldn't have to date
Mercedes Jones.
Now if can just get through
the next few days
without turning into a hot mess
teary train wreck.
(school bell rings)
(door opens)
Ted...
why on earth did you want
to meet me in here?
Oh, my God-- my NYDADA letter
came, didn't it?
Not yet.
Sit down.
I want to give you
your graduation present.
Is Elaine Stritch here?
I don't know who that is.
See, this is the problem
with getting you gifts--
I can't make heads or tails
about what it is your like.
Dad, I'm easy.
Just get me something from Tom
Ford's Vanities in Vanity Fair.
Good to know.
So... somewhere around
your seventh birthday,
I lost you.
Before that,
you were a normal kid.
I mean, a kid who
liked to dust, but...
You know, I read you to bed,
I put cartoons on TV
when you were bored.
I taught you how
to ride a bike...
the normal stuff.
And then you turned
seven or eight,
and you start to become this.
And, uh, it was like I was
living with an alien.
I mean, I tried to keep up,
but, uh, you know,
once your mom passed, I...
I really...
I didn't stand a chance.
You did good, Dad.
I am proud of what you and I
did together.
I'm proud of us, too.
Do you remember when it started?
When we turned a corner
and started walking
towards each other,
rather than in opposite
directions?
Tell me.
Aw, screw that,
I'm gonna show you.
It was in the basement
of our old house.
You were wearing
a unitard.
Oh, God, Dad, please
don't do this--
Sit down and accept
your present.
Hit it!
(Beyoncé's "All the Single
Ladies" begins)
♪ All the single ladies ♪
♪ Now put your hands up ♪
♪ Up in a club,
we just broke up ♪
♪ I'm doing
my own little thing ♪
♪ You decided to dip,
and now you wanna trip ♪
♪ 'Cause another brother
noticed me ♪
♪ I'm up on him,
he up on me ♪
♪ Don't pay him any attention ♪
♪ Just cried my tears,
for three good years ♪
♪ You can't be mad at me ♪
♪ 'Cause if you liked it, then
you should've put a ring on it ♪
♪ If you liked it, then you
should've put a ring on it ♪
♪ Don't be mad once you see
that he want it ♪
♪ If you liked it, then you
should've put a ring on it ♪
♪ Uh, oh-oh, oh, uh-uh ♪
♪ Oh-oh, oh, uh-uh-uh ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh, oh-oh, uh ♪
♪ Uh, oh-oh, oh, uh-uh ♪
♪ Uh-oh. ♪
(song ends)
(school bell rings)
It was the best
graduation gift ever.
What about those monogrammed
towels I got for you?
Oh, you didn't have to
get me a gift, silly.
Um... we've been putting
this off for far too long,
but don't you think we
should have the talk?
Can't we just have two
final days of denial?
No, no, we cannot.
This is happening
right now, Kurt.
It's not some far-off
thing in the future.
You're graduating,
I'm not.
You know how hard long-distance
relationships can be.
We both saw The Notebook.
Do you want to know how
I picture the end of my life?
Just like in The Notebook,
I'm sitting in a nursing home,
talking endlessly about
my high school sweetheart--
my first love--
going on and on about
every little detail,
as if they matter.
Only, in my version,
he's there with me,
telling me to shut up
so he can finish watching
the American Cinematheque
salute to J-Lo.
So... we're going
to be all right?
Yes, we're gonna
be all right.
I told you I'm never
saying goodbye to you.
We'll figure out this
whole long-distance
relationship thing.
I promise.
Okay.
So have you decided how you're
going to say goodbye
to everyone else?
(school bell rings)
I wanted to dedicate my
goodbye song to all of you,
but I wanted to mostly
thank the men in the room
who have truly inspired me
and never saw me for the things
that made us different.
You only saw me for the ways
that we're the same.
Because, in this room...
it doesn't matter
if you're gay or straight...
what matters
is that we're friends.
(Madonna's
"I'll Remember" begins)
♪ Say goodbye
to not knowing when ♪
♪ The truth
in my whole life began ♪
♪ Say goodbye ♪
♪ To not knowing how to cry ♪
♪ You taught me that ♪
♪ And I'll remember ♪
♪ The love that you gave me ♪
♪ Now that I'm standing
on my own ♪
♪ I'll remember ♪
♪ The way that you changed me ♪
♪ I learned ♪
♪ To let go ♪
♪ Of the illusion ♪
♪ That we can possess ♪
♪ I learned ♪
♪ To let go ♪
♪ I travel in stillness ♪
♪ And I'll remember ♪
♪ The love that you gave me ♪
♪ Now that I'm standing
on my own ♪
♪ I'll remember ♪
♪ The way that you changed me ♪
♪ No, I've never been
afraid to cry ♪
♪ And I finally have
a reason why ♪
♪ I'll remember ♪
♪ No, I've never been
afraid to cry ♪
♪ And I finally have
a reason why ♪
♪ I'll remember. ♪
(song ends)
(school bell rings)
Hey.
Oh, thank goodness
you guys are here.
Okay, so I called
Pace and NYADA
and they sent out out
acceptance letters this week.
Oh, my God,
that's so exciting.
And, like,
totally terrifying.
We need to make a pact.
When we get our letters,
we open them together,
in the choir room.
These letters, you know,
they're, like our future
so I want to open mine
with my two most
important people.
Deal?
Deal.
Pinkie swear?
Yeah.
All right.
+
(school bell rings)
What is this crap?
Oh, didn't you hear?
Mercedes got a
recording contract.
She's moving to Hollywood
and she's going to be
a superstar by Christmas,
guaranteed.
MERCEDES:
He's exaggerating.
You remember that video that
he posted of me on YouTube,
singing "Disco Inferno"?
Well, this music producer
in L.A. saw it
and he wants to sign her.
As a backup singer
on an indie label.
I'm going to be taking
extension classes at UCLA.
If this was happening
to anyone else, I would be
extremely jealous.
This is really cool.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
(grunts)
And I couldn't have done it
without you.
Oh, did you hear
about Mike?
I was all set to go
to Alvin Ailey,
and then Joffrey in Chicago
offered me a scholarship.
Oh, Mike, that's amazing.
Congratulations.
You must be so excited
to ditch that Cheerios! uniform
and put on the one
for University of Louisville.
Yeah, I... I can't wait.
SANTANA:
This is embarrassing.
I'm a star, so what am I doing
heading to Kentucky?
I'm just as talented
as Mercedes,
Boy Chang, Berry
or Lady Hummel.
Thank God for Mom.
She'll know what to do.
When Santana finally said,
"Mami, papi, I'm gay,"
all I could
think of was,
I should have known.
When she was eight,
she went trick-or-treating
as Uncle Jesse on Full House.
Spent two years
growing out that hair.
"Business in the front..."
BOTH:
"Party in the back."
Ew.
So, you just really didn't care?
I care that my baby's happy.
I wish abuela
felt the same.
I know.
It sucks, mija.
But you don't want a
person in your life
that doesn't support
your dreams.
I don't want to go
to that cheerleading program
at the University of Louisville.
I want to go to New York.
Go to college, Santana.
Do what I never
got the chance to do.
New York will
still be there
after you've earned
your college degree.
Brittany, I understand you
got into Purdue University?
Not the university;
the poultry farm.
Plucker is a steady profession.
But I can't go to either
'cause I'm not graduating.
What?
Yeah.
I was kind of glad
when I found out
that I was flunking
because it'll give me a chance
to do my senior year
all over again.
And way better. I'll show up
to my classes this time.
Plus, I'll get to be a two-term
senior class president.
Why are you pretending
that this is okay?
And why didn't you tell me?
What did you think
was going to happen to me?
I have a 0.0
grade point average.
Well, maybe if Brittany's
staying in Lima,
then I should stay, too.
And now the seniors of McKinley
High School, class of 2012,
are going to sing for you.
This is your glee club.
Take care of it.
It'll take care of you.
One! Two!
One, two, three, yeah!
(New Radicals'
"You Get What You Give" begins)
Hey! Oh! Hey!
♪ Wake up, kids ♪
♪ We've got the
dreamer's disease ♪
♪ Age 14, we got you
down on your knees ♪
♪ So polite, we're busy
still saying please ♪
♪ But when the night
is falling ♪
♪ You cannot find the light ♪
♪ Light ♪
♪ You feel your dreams
are dying ♪
♪ Hold tight ♪
♪ You've got the music in you ♪
♪ Don't let go ♪
♪ One dance left ♪
♪ This world
is gonna pull through ♪
♪ Don't give up ♪
♪ You've got a reason to live ♪
♪ Can't forget ♪
♪ We only get what we give ♪
♪ This whole damn world
can fall apart ♪
♪ You'll be okay,
follow your heart ♪
♪ You're in harm's way ♪
♪ I'm right behind ♪
♪ Now say you're mine ♪
♪ You've got the music in you ♪
♪ Don't let go ♪
♪ One dance left ♪
♪ This world is gonna
pull through ♪
♪ Don't give up ♪
♪ You've got a reason to live ♪
♪ Can't forget ♪
♪ We only get what we give ♪
♪ Don't let go ♪
♪ I feel the music in you ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Health insurance,
rip-off, lying ♪
♪ FDA, big bankers buying ♪
♪ Fake computer crashes, dying ♪
♪ Cloning while they're
multiplying ♪
♪ Fashion shoots
with Beck and Hanson ♪
♪ Courtney Love
and Marilyn Manson ♪
♪ You're all fakes,
run to your mansions ♪
♪ Come around,
we'll kick you down, yeah ♪
♪ Don't let go,
you've got the music in you ♪
♪ Don't give up ♪
♪ You've got the music in you ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ You've got the music in you. ♪
(school bell ringing)
I don't know. I mean, when
you're looking at both of them,
it's really hard to not just
want to go with the Chiavari.
There's $20 difference
between each of those chairs.
That's, like, hundreds
of dollars or something.
We can't afford that.
Look, I compromised on the food,
I compromised on the location,
I compromised
on the flowers.
Does my butt
really have to compromise
on what it sits on?
Maybe what you're
really upset about
is that you're compromising
on your husband.
Please, that
is the one thing
that I don't have
any doubts about.
Really?
'Cause you've been kind of
giving me a weird vibe lately.
No.
You're just projecting,
all right?
You're nervous about
finding out about school,
and you're
putting it on me.
Besides, when
did you become
the one that I
was settling for?
Look, I don't care who
gets in where, all right?
I'm marrying you, and
nothing makes me happier.
Even if we have to sit in
these ugly fold-out chairs.
Okay?
Okay.
+
: I remember the first day
of school this year.
I had no idea what I wanted
to do, who I was.
It wasn't the past
I was scared of.
I'd call my high school career
a total success.
I mean, not in terms
of grades and stuff,
but I won a state title
in football,
a national championship
in Glee Club.
I never hurt anyone real bad,
and it turns out I never
actually accidentally
got anyone pregnant.
It was the future
I was terrified of.
But not anymore.
I'm getting married
to a great girl.
I'm moving to New York
to chase my dreams
with her
and my gay stepbrother.
And how do I know?
InsauditionActors Studio
with the main dude himself.
You're Finn Hudson, and
you want to be an actor.
I was very moved
by your letter
and application, Finn.
You're no doubt aware
that you would be
an exceptional case,
should we accept you.
Yes.
Why don't we start
with your, uh,
dramatic monologue?
Okay.
Yep, fear is no longer
in my vocabulary.
(school bell ringing)
Hey. Just finishing up.
Lay it on me.
"Dear Finn, great knowing you.
Will Schuester."
Are you kidding me?
I'm, like, the best
man at your wedding.
It's not that bad.
And you can't dictate
what I write in your yearbook.
Yes, I can. I want a
little emotion in there.
Some "son I never had"
or "little brother" garbage
or something.
Look, I-I wanted to. I...
I started ten times,
and I couldn't get
two words out
without falling apart.
Well, I don't need a bunch
of "blah, blah" in a book
to remember you anyway.
Finn, wait.
I-I need to tell you something.
Something I would rather
not have
written down anywhere.
Please, have a seat.
Um, when I first
took over the glee club,
we needed a male lead.
I heard you singing in
the shower in the locker room.
♪ I'm getting closer ♪
♪ Than I ever
thought I might... ♪
WILL:
REO Speedwagon.
Yeah, you
were really good.
So I planted the pot
in your locker
and blackmailed you
into joining the glee club.
It was wrong.
Although I can't argue
with the results,
I've always hated myself
for doing it.
I'm very sorry, Finn.
But I-I wanted you
to know the truth
before you left, so...
You are so much cooler
than I ever thought you were.
Get out of here.
I'm going to go.
(school bell ringing)
CAROLE: Your graduation gown
with the extra long sleeves
just arrived.
You know, you can have
that thing if you want.
It's probably
the only thing that'll fit
in your tiny little
New York apartment,
but it's yours to have.
I can't help thinking
I let him down, you know?
I feel like I-I could
have spent more time
writing that letter to the Army,
or I could have wrote 50 letters
to the Army,
or I could have started
one of those
letter-writing campaigns,
like... like they had
for Friday Night Lights
or something.
You did everything
you could do.
Your dad made his choices,
and the Army has rules,
and there's nothing
you could have done
about either one
of those things.
I can't help feeling
like something's not right.
I did a lot
of reseah,
trying to get that
honorable discharge status,
and-and he did a lot
of really great things
in Kuwait, you know?
He pulled two soldiers
out of a burning truck.
He saved their lives.
They have kids now my age.
He's a hero.
And how is becoming an actor...
how is that redemption
for a man who did all that?
(sighs)
Everything seems
like it's fallen into place.
Everything but him.
Okay, seniors, the underclassmen
have something
they'd like to say to you.
Come on.
ARTIE: With all
the dedications
being thrown
around McKinley this week,
there was one that we wanted
to make sure didn't get missed.
Finn.
Right now, you're something
I never thought possible
when I first rolled
down these halls.
You're my friend-- our friend.
Even before Glee Club was
kind of cool, you had our backs.
You were on the
football team.
You were one
of the most
popular kids in school.
You had a lot to lose,
and people forget the
sacrifices you made.
We wanted to thank you.
(The Beatles' "In My Life"
begins)
♪ There are places I remember ♪
♪ All my life ♪
♪ Though some have changed ♪
♪ Some forever, not for better ♪
♪ Some have gone ♪
♪ And some remain ♪
♪ All these places
have their moments ♪
♪ With lovers and friends ♪
♪ I still can recall ♪
♪ Some are dead
and some are living ♪
♪ In my life ♪
♪ I loved them all ♪
♪ But of all these
friends and lovers ♪
♪ There is no one ♪
♪ Compares with you ♪
♪ And these memories
lose their meaning ♪
♪ When I think of love ♪
♪ As something new ♪
♪ Though I know I'll never
lose affection ♪
♪ For people and things
that went before ♪
♪ I know I'll often stop
and think about them ♪
♪ In my life ♪
♪ I love you more ♪
♪ In my life... ♪
♪ I love you more. ♪
(song ends)
Yay!
(bell ringing)
+
Who would have thought
I'd end my McKinley days where
I started... back on top?
I got into the school of my
dreams and we won nationals.
Plus I'm feeling stronger
every day.
Everyone else is so emotional.
But I don't feel that way.
I guess I've cried enough tears
for three graduations.
Or maybe it's just hard
to feel weepy when I look
at my friends.
They've grown into such
incredible people.
Nothing's gonna stop
any of them.
Well, maybe one of them.
Countries of
Central America.
Uh, Costa Rica, Honduras...
Crap, I'm blanking.
Come on!
This ain't beach towel
night at Three Rivers.
This school has given us all
so many gifts, me especially.
And I want my last week here
to be about giving back
a little of what I got.
(bell ringing)
This freshman
just gave me a hug
and told me to never change.
Poor thing is too young
to realize
that change can be so good.
Think...
if we hadn't changed,
we would have never been
friends.
Still so weird having you
call me a friend.
There.
What's this?
A Metro North pass
from New York to New Haven.
I got one for me
into New York.
Everybody keeps talking
about staying in touch,
and I want to make sure
that we do.
Thank you.
It's so sweet.
Although I'm still
not 100% sure
that I'm for
teen weddings,
I'm really happy that you
and Finn are together.
You guys were meant to be.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You know, it's weird
'cause that's how
I always felt
about you and Puck.
Ancient history.
But you know what I mean.
When you two were together,
he was really at his best.
Indian Ocean, show me.
It's no use. My brain is like a
Roach Motel,
once the info checks in,
it never checks out.
I'm out of here.
Don't worry. You still get
your Brownie patch
for trying to help a loser
learn something.
I'm not here for a patch.
I'm here because I love you.
You're my first.
I kind of screwed up
that experience, huh?
No regrets.
Cool. 'Cause I always felt
kind of bad about it.
Feel bad about
a lot of things,
but I was an ass for most
of high school.
I really care about you, Puck.
You know what? I know that after
Beth was born,
we weren't really close.
But when two people go though
what we've been through,
you're bonded for life.
If you ever need me,
you know where to find me...
right here in Lima...
repeating my senior
year forever.
I would have never given
my virginity to this guy.
The Puck I fell in love
with had swagger.
And you know what questions
Miss Duesenberry's
gonna ask you,
so you just need
to get your confidence back
so you can get all
that stuff out
of the Roach Motel.
And how am I supposed
to do that?
Like this.
No, no, wait.
I'm not worth it.
Save it for some
Yale guy
who deserves your help.
There's nobody that deserves
it more.
You just have
to remember
the guy you were
when we first met.
You're the guy who caught
the winning touchdown
the only game
the football team
won sophomore year.
You're the guy
that ate
that shaker of pepper
on a dare.
Didn't even puke.
Will you let me kiss you?
I guess I'd be kind of rude
if I refused.
You know, Puckerman...
you got this.
♪ ♪
Funny thing about a kiss.
If it comes at the right time
from the right girl,
it can be like magic.
It can bring you back to life
like CPR, but with tongues.
It can take away
the doubt and the fear.
It can change you,
even if it's just back
into what you always were:
an all-original,
grade-A, badass.
Get ready test.
I'm about to make Puckerman
your daddy.
(bell ringing)
(inhales deeply)
Well, you stink of chlorine,
Roz Washington,
which means one
of two things:
either you just returned
from the peroxide factory
where you spent the afternoon
having your hair helmet
revarnished,
or you've given up
trying to steal my Cheerios!
and you're back in the pool
where you belong.
I got to hand it
to you, Sue.
National championships
for both the Glee Club
and the Cheerios!
That's quite an accomplishment
for a pregnant woman
who's ass is so old
she went to high school
with Moses.
Well, Roz, if you came here
to find out once and for all
who the celebrity father
of my unborn child is,
I'm afraid you're going
to have to wait
for the graphic birth photos
that grace the cover of
the People magazine
exclusive that hits newsstands
in September.
You and I are never gonna like
each other, Sue Sylvester,
but you and I, we got
something in common.
We both hate the fact
that this school has
an idiot for a principal.
That's why I propose we join
forces and take him down.
Well, you think that over, Sue
Sylvester, while you nurse your
thousand-year-old
vampire baby.
You just be sure
to bottle-feed it
because that baby's gonna use
those sharp-ass teeth
to bite holes in those
saggy old boobs.
Hey, Coach.
It's my Cheerios! uniform,
dry-cleaned and pressed.
You were kind enough
to let me wear it again,
and I figured it was only right
to return it
in case you wanted
to pass it on.
Maybe some underclassman
who's about to be
the new team captain.
You keep it.
I'm retiring this uniform.
Sit.
You know, when I first
laid eyes on you, Q,
I thought you reminded me
of a young Sue Sylvester,
but looking at this
amazing woman
sitting across
from me right now,
I realize I was wrong.
You're nothing
like me.
You're better.
Sure, I'm as smart
as you are
and every bit as pretty,
but somehow you're slightly
less evil.
And I admire that.
I admire you, Quinn Fabray.
I admire your perseverance.
You're gonna go so far, kiddo.
And I'm gonna have
the best time
watching you do it.
And I'm gonna get to say,
"Hey, I remember her
from way back when."
Way back when she was
getting Ryan Seacrest tattoos
and lying about who
the father of her
unborn child was.
(sobs)
I'm gonna miss you!
(voice breaks):
I don't see how
that's possible,
but thank you.
(chuckles)
+
What's going on?
Waiting for Mrs. Duesenberry
to finish grading my test.
If I don't pass, it's open
season on all faculty tires!
What's it say?
C-! It's a Puckerman A+!
I'm graduating!
(cheers)
I'm so proud of you.
(Bruce Springsteen's
"Glory Days" begins)
♪ Yeah, come on ♪
♪ Whoo! ♪
♪ I had a friend,
was a big baseball player ♪
Michael Chang, Jr.
♪ Back in high school ♪
♪ He could throw
that speedball by you ♪
♪ Make you look
like a fool, boy ♪
Quinn Fabray.
♪ Saw him the other night
at this roadside bar ♪
♪ I was walking in,
he was walking out ♪
♪ We went back inside, sat down,
had a few drinks ♪
♪ But all he kept talking
about ♪
♪ Glory days, well, they'll pass
you by, glory days ♪
Mercedes Jones.
♪ In the wink
of a young girl's eye ♪
♪ Glory days, glory days ♪
Yeah, all right, boys,
watch me work it now.
Noah Puckerman.
(cheering)
Thank you.
♪ Whoo! ♪
Santana Lopez.
♪ Think I'm going down
to the well tonight ♪
♪ Going to drink my fill ♪
♪ And I hope when I get old
I don't sit around ♪
♪ Thinking about it,
but I probably will ♪
Thanks.
Kurt Hummel.
♪ Just sitting back
trying to recapture ♪
♪ A little of the glory of... ♪
♪ Well, time slips away♪
♪ And leaves you
with nothing, mister ♪
♪ But boring stories of...
glory days ♪
Whoo!
♪ Glory days ♪
Finn Hudson.
♪ In a young girl's eyes,
glory days ♪
♪ Glory days ♪
♪ Well, they'll pass you by,
glory days ♪
Rachel Berry.
(cheers)
♪ In a young girl's eyes,
glory days, glory days ♪
♪ What about this? ♪
♪ Well, all right! ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ Come on now ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Well, all right ♪
♪ All right ♪
♪ Come on now ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Whoo-ooh ♪
Ladies and gentlemen,
I present you William McKinley
High's class of 2012!
♪ Glory days. ♪
(song ends, cheering)
I'm seriously having
trouble breathing right now.
Are you guys ready?
I kind of want to wait.
KURT:
For how long?
Forever.
Just a couple more seconds,
but this is the last moment
before we know.
After we open those envelopes,
it's-it's gonna change
our entire lives
no matter what's
in it either way.
I just kind of want
another minute with you
guys here like this.
So, who's first?
I'll go first.
I got a good
feeling about it.
Look, no matter
what happens,
we're all here for each other.
I didn't get it.
It's okay.
Please, somebody else
just open theirs. Come on.
I'll go next.
I didn't get in.
Kurt, I'm so sorry.
Your turn, Rachel.
I got in.
+
♪♪
♪♪♪
(horn honks)
Hi.
(chuckles)
Okay, so you have
my dress and my shoes,
and I have my makeup
and my epic love for you.
Let's get married.
Okay.
RACHEL:
My dads are still being
kind of weird
about the wedding.
I brought it up last night
and they were really quiet,
but it's fine.
Are you sure that we're
going the right way?
We're here.
Are you joking?
'Cause it's not funny.
We're gonna be late.
You're on the
4:25 to New York.
Your dads are gonna meet you
there and they're gonna,
they're gonna help you look
at dorms at the new school.
You're gonna spend four
years of your life there
and you've never even set
foot in the place, so...
But I... I have all year
to go and look at it.
You're gonna go
there in the fall.
All right? You're
not deferring.
We're not
getting married.
You don't want to marry me?
I want to marry you so badly
I can't go through with it.
Yeah, but the thought
of you being stuck here
for another year because
of me, it makes me sick.
Then come with me. Okay?
We can get married
in New York
and live in a little
shoebox apartment together.
It'll be romantic.
Do you love me?
Of course I do.
Then tell me the
truth and not just
something you think
I want to hear.
Are you 100% sure
you want to marry me?
N-No-no one is
100% sure of anything.
I am.
I am that sure you're
something special.
That this is just the
beginning for you.
Okay? Th-That you're
gonna do amazing things.
But to get there,
you got to have these
experiences on your own...
Wait a minute.
Listen to me.
You got to have these
experiences on your own.
Wait a minute.
I can't have to be
there with you.
Wait a minute.
Are you breaking up with me?
I'm setting you free.
Oh, my God.
Look, d-do you know how
hard this is for me?
How many times I've
cried about this?
No, I'm not going.
I'm not going,
not without you.
You don't have a choice;
I can't come with you.
Well, then I'll stay here!
I'll go wherever it is
that you're going!
Fort Benning, Georgia?
Look, I-I need a chance to try
and redeem my father, okay?
I-I...
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God,
wait a minute.
You're joining the Army?
Are you insane?
(sobbing): I can't believe that
this is happening right now.
It's also one of the places I
knew you couldn't follow me.
Look, you're-you're
gonna get on that train.
Okay?
And you're gonna
go to New York,
and you're
gonna be a star.
Without me.
That's how much
I love you.
(sniffles)
You know what
we're gonna do?
Surrender.
I know how hard
that is for you
because of how hard
you hold on to stuff.
But-but we're just gonna,
we're gonna sit here
and we're just
gonna let go.
Okay, and-and let the
universe do it's thing.
And if we're meant
to be together,
then we're gonna
be together.
W-Whether it's in a little
shoebox apartment in New York
or on the other
side of the world.
Okay?
(sobbing)
Will you do
that with me?
Will you surrender?
I love you so much.
I love you.
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
♪ So many things to do and say ♪
♪ But I can't seem
to find the way ♪
♪ But I want to know how ♪
♪ I know I'm meant
for something else ♪
♪ But first,
I got to find myself ♪
♪ But I don't know how ♪
♪ Oh, why do I
reach for the stars ♪
♪ When I don't have wings ♪
♪ To carry me that far? ♪
♪ I got to have roots
before branches ♪
♪ To know who I am ♪
♪ Before I know
who I want to be ♪
♪ And faith to take chances ♪
♪ To live like I see ♪
♪ A place in this world for me ♪
♪ Oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ Sometimes I don't
want to feel ♪
♪ And forget the pain is real ♪
♪ Put my head in the clouds ♪
♪ Oh, start to run
and then I fall ♪
♪ Thinking I can't get it all ♪
♪ Without my feet
on the ground ♪
♪ There's always a seed
before there's a rose ♪
♪ The more that it rains,
the more I will grow ♪
♪ Got to have roots
before branches ♪
♪ To know who I am ♪
♪ Before I know
who I want to be ♪
♪ And faith to take chances ♪
♪ To live like I see ♪
♪ A place in this world for me ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ Whatever comes,
I know how to take it ♪
♪ Learn to be strong,
I won't have to fake it ♪
♪ Oh, you're understanding ♪
♪ Oh, the wind can come
and do its best ♪
♪ Roaming north and south,
east and west ♪
♪ But I'll still be standing ♪
♪ I'm standing ♪
♪ If I have roots
before branches ♪
♪ To know who I am ♪
♪ Before I know
who I'm gonna be ♪
♪ And faith, oh,
to take chances ♪
♪ To live like I see ♪
♪ A place in this world ♪
♪ Got to have roots
before branches ♪
♪ To know who I am ♪
♪ Before I know
who I want to be ♪
♪ And faith to take chances ♪
♪ And live like I see ♪
♪ A place in this world ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ I got to have roots
before branches, oh, yeah. ♪
Synced By YesCool
www.addic7ed.com