So, here is What You missed on Glee:
Puck's got a thing
for Lauren Zizes, but she's not
really down with it.
I don't think you're
ready for this jelly.
Finn kissed Quinn, who's
supposed to be dating Sam,
and Rachel kissed Finn too, but
he didn't feel the fireworks.
On the cheek?
Can you believe that?
Sue tried to shoot Brittany out
of a cannon to win Nationals,
but the only thing she won
was Katie Couric's
"Loser of the Year."
I hate you, Diane Sawyer.
And that's what
you missed on Glee.
WILL:
I actually learned something
in my Spanish class today.
"Regresar."
Who knows what that means?
"To come back."
That's right. I realized
the old Will Schuster was back.
Glee Club's going to Regionals.
We got all
of Sue's Cheerios! money.
I'm past Terry. I'm over Emma.
"To come back."
Now, if we're going
to put it in the past...
Will?
It's an emergency.
EMMA: Becky Jackson opened
Sue's journal and found this.
"Good-bye, cruel world"?
She could be dead by now.
Synced By YesCool
www.addic7ed.com
It's weird;
the door's open.
Sue? Sue?
No? All right.
[Will grunting]
Sue.
[gasping]:
Oh, my Lord. Oh!
Oh, Sue. Sue.
Wake up, Sue.
Sue! Wake up!
I don't feel a pulse.
She doesn't have a pulse.
Yeah, I do.
[Will and Emma gasping]
I just stopped my own heart.
That's my CIA training.
These gummi vitamins
didn't work at all.
I was told you take
enough Vitamin A,
and you drift off
into a blissful oblivion.
Instead, my face
just got really hot
and my jaw is sore
from all that chewing.
[annoyed sigh]
I have nothing to live for.
That's not untrue.
Emma, we didn't come here
to give her a pep talk.
I'm sorry, Sue,
but you brought
this on yourself.
I am well aware
of my situation, Will.
After my humiliating failure
to qualify for Nationals,
there is nothing for
me or my Cheerios!
to do for the
rest of the year.
Why don't you do what
other cheer squads do--
namely, cheer for the
teams at the school?
Yeah, like that's going
to happen.
Emma, let's go.
Sue, you are nasty,
manipulative and petty.
Will, you have
more grease in your hair
than the guy behind WikiLeaks.
Oh, I for one, am not
going to play backup
at your little pity party.
Take it easy, Sue.
[bell ringing]
Hey.
Hi.
So I wanted to confirm our date
on Friday at Color Me Mine.
Wait, you were serious
about that?
It's painting coasters time.
So, we good for Friday?
Yeah. I think so.
I mean, I don't think I
have anything else to do.
Cool.
SAM:
Things have been weird
since Quinn got mono
a couple of weeks ago.
Everyone keeps telling me
that she must have kissed Finn,
but I believe it when she
told me what really happened.
I didn't kiss Finn, Sam.
I saved his life.
[gagging]
[screams]
He's not breathing!
[inhales]
I totally almost
choked on a gumball once.
[bell ringing]
I know she's into me.
I just get the feeling
that I'm losing her.
I can't let that happen.
Quinn's the best thing
that's happened to me
since I got to this school.
But how?
Of course.
My dad always said
there are two ways
to get a woman to love you:
take her hunting
and rock 'n' roll.
I knew what I had to do.
I mean, who's more rock
and roll than Justin Bieber?
No one. That's who.
The hair was step one.
Step two was booking
a couple of Bat Mitvah gigs
to test out how my
new one man band would go over.
[feedback squeals]
Hey.
I'm
the Justin Bieber Experience.
♪Baby, baby, baby, oh ♪
♪Like ♪
♪Baby, baby, baby ♪
♪No ♪
♪Like, baby, baby, baby ♪
♪Oh ♪
[girls screaming]
#I thought you'd #
♪Always be mine. ♪
Heads up, Quinn Fabray,
you're about to be
hit head on
with the full blond Bieber.
Hey, Brittany.
We need to talk.
Why are my leg
warmers on your arms?
I got cold.
But, no. We had
a deal, okay?
As I explained,
I am in the midst
of a career
resurgence, okay?
I am done with boys, and
I am concentrating fully
on my career now.
The only way to make
a complete comeback
is to dominate
popular discussion,
maybe launch a
trend or two.
I have you half
of my allowance
so you could take a
signature look of mine
and make it popular.
And we decided tha
legwarmers were more likely
to catch on
than reindeer sweaters.
Yes, precisely,
but it won't work
if you insist on wearing
them incorrectly.
I didn't realize
that there were rules.
Of course there are rules.
They're legwarmers.
Well, can I wear them
that way tomorrow?
I wore a tank top today
because I thought it was summer.
No one ever taught me
how to read a calendar.
Fine, fine.
And when people ask you
who gave you the inspiration
for your new accessory,
you're going to say, "I'm
just copying Rachel..."
I'm just copying
Rachel Berry.
Fantastic.
[bell ringing]
[Sue grunting]
You know how I
feel about hats.
Just 'cause.
None of you should be making
eye contact with me.
Get out! Go!
Get used to this
abuse, Glee kids.
I got nothing but time.
Nothing but time.
WILL:
I think she's dangerous.
Idle hands
are the Devil's playthings.
I mean, Sue's got
nothing to do now,
which means it's only
a matter of time
before she starts coming
after the Glee Club.
Hey... Will, Esmé.
So sorry for not being
sorry for interrupting.
But would you mind
if I borrowed one
of your rafters
so I could hang myself?
I just did a test run
back in my office,
and you know what?
There's asbestos up there,
and that can
kill a person.
Sue? Sit.
Now, I understand
you're upset,
but life is beautiful.
Are you going to tell me
there hasn't been
one moment since
your epic decline
that you haven't
felt yourself
feel good about something?
Well, yes, Will,
as a matter of fact,
there was...
there was one moment.
I was driving to work
this morning in my LeCar,
and Charlene's "I've Never
Been To Me" came on the radio.
And when it got to the chorus,
I just opened my mouth and
belted it out with her.
And I have to say,
it felt really good.
Sue should join
the Glee Club.
I'm sorry?
No, I'd rather be dead.
Yes. She should join--
I mean, you can't join,
but she can sit in.
Yes. Will.
Look, Sue is in a really
bad place right now.
And you're always talking about
the healing power of music.
There are studies that show
it helps with depression,
it elevates mood.
I have a pamphlet.
Uh... Emma, I don't think
this is a good idea at all.
I agree with
SpongeHair SquareChin.
It's a stupid idea.
No, no. The football team
did it for a spell,
and that really
brought people together.
Will, and this is
a great chance
for you to keep
your eye on Sue.
You know, make sure
the old gal's okay.
Well, you know what, folks?
At this point,
to alleviate
my crippling depression,
I'd do anything.
[chuckles]
This cannot be happening.
This seems like a terrible idea.
Guys, it's not up
for discussion, okay?
Now, it's no secret that Coach
Sylvester has taken her licks...
I mean, just wanky.
And I believe she could use
a little sympathy from us.
Sympathy? From us? Uh-uh.
Yeah, all she's ever done
is make our lives miserable.
She got exactly
what she deserved.
You're lucky I left my blowgun
at home, Airbags,
'cause I got a clear shot
at your nonnies.
WILL: Guys, Coach Sylvester
has had her recent setbacks,
but she is a proven champion.
Now, we could do worse
than to have that kindf
a winning record in our midst.
SUE: Let me break it
down for you.
I am no longer a threat
to you people.
All right? I'm just hoping that
your singing and dancing around
will pull me out of
my doldrums and give me
a reason to live.
Is that too much to ask?
Guys, it's settled.
Sue's going to be
with us for the week.
Now... I received an envelope
in the mail today.
[murmuring]
We know that we're facing Kurt
and the Warblers at Regionals.
Sweet Porcelain.
And it looks like this year,
we face Aural Intensity again.
They cleaned our clock
last year.
Seems like
the governing board
has assigned a theme
to this year's Regionals,
and part of our score
will be based
upon how well we interpret it.
This year's theme--
"Anthem." Now, who can
tell us what an anthem is?
The bottom of an ant's pants.
So close.
So close. No.
An anthem is an epic song,
filled with
a groundswell of emotion
that somehow seems
bigger than itself.
Even bigger than the person
performing it.
Mr. Shue?
Oh, hey, Sam, I didn't even
notice your new haircut.
Yeah. I've been working
on a new image to go
with my new one-man band,
The Justin Bieber Experience.
You've got to be kidding me.
Dude. That haircut makes
your mouth look even bigger.
Let her speak.
Look, laugh all you want,
but that kid's an epic talent,
and there's a number
I've been working on
that I've been wanting
to show off.
And I think it
qualifies as an anthem,
because it's
just hugely emotional,
and sums up
our generation.
All right.
Let's hear it, buddy.
[Justin Bieber's "Baby" begins]
♪Oh, whoa, whoa ♪
♪Oh, whoa, oh ♪
♪You know you love me,
I know you care ♪
♪Just shout whenever,
and I'll be there ♪
♪You want my love,
you want my heart ♪
♪And we will never... ♪
This is actually
a really good song.
♪Ever, ever be apart ♪
♪Are we an item? ♪
♪Girl, quit playing ♪
♪We're just friends? ♪
♪What are you saying? ♪
♪Say there's another,
and look right in my eyes ♪
♪My first love broke my heart
for the first time ♪
♪And I was like ♪
♪Baby, baby, baby ♪
♪Oh, like, baby,
baby, baby, no ♪
♪Like baby, baby, baby ♪
♪Oh, I thought you'd
always be mine mine ♪
♪Oh, for you, I would have ♪
[whoops]
#Done whatever #
♪And I just can't believe
we ain't together ♪
♪And I wanna play it cool ♪
♪But I'm losing you ♪
♪I'll buy you anything ♪
♪I'll buy you
any ring ♪
♪And I'm in pieces ♪
♪Baby, fix me ♪
♪And just shake me till you
wake me from this bad dream ♪
♪I'm going down,
down, down, down ♪
♪And I just cant believe ♪
♪My first love
won't be around ♪
♪And I'm like,
baby, baby, baby ♪
♪Oh, like, baby, baby, baby ♪
♪No, like, baby,
baby, baby, oh ♪
♪I thought you'd
always be mine ♪
♪I'm gone ♪
♪Now I'm all gone ♪
♪I'm gone. ♪
[whooping, applause]
Yeah! All right!
The Biebster!
I got to get that girl
on my Cheerios!
[bell rings]
We want in.
In what?
The Justin Bieber Experience.
We want in the band.
But it's a one-man band.
So expand.
I don't get it, you guys were
totally making fun of me
for singing Bieber.
That's because we underestimated
the power of the Biebes.
He's clearly like
a mini-god.
Look how you made
all those chicks melt
in Glee Club;
now think about
the power of four Biebers.
We'd be unstoppable.
All of our relationships
are in the standard
post-Valentine's Day lull.
Are you playing
Angry Birds?
Sorry.
Want me to show
you my abs?
If you want to.
Here's what happens
to the female chemistry.
They get a huge shot
of endorphins
on Valentine's Day,
and everything is heightened
and so romantic--
the problem is,
days later, when they come down
from their See's candy high,
they crash,
and everything else,
by comparison, is humdrum.
We need the sugary sweet jolt
of the Biebes
to get us some action again.
Why do you want in, Puckerman?
I'm at the end
of my Lauren Zises rope.
I'll try anything to get
into those enormous pants.
Uh, what's going on?
ARTIE:
We're joining
The Justin Bieber Experience,
if Sam's cool with it.
And if not, we're
starting our own band.
Bieber Fever.
Wait, you-you guys
do realize that
Justin Bieber sucks, right?
Quinn seemed to be
pretty into him when I
was singing in Glee Club.
Right, well,
I'm gonna spend my time
working on songs that aren't
geared toward 12-year-olds.
Good.
And then you won't
have time to pick up any
other guys' girlfriends.
Hey... back off, man.
I didn't kiss your girlfriend.
She saved my life.
MIKE:
So, what do you say?
Are we in?
Fine. But we need
to figure out
something to do
with Puckerman's hair.
[bell rings]
[indistinct chatter]
Oh, no.
No way.
You're a genius-- they
have changed my life.
I didn't know my arms
could be so toasty.
You're a hero--
you should win
some kind of award.
[whispers]:
What are you doing?
I'm so sorry, Rachel,
it just sort of caught on.
I see that, okay?
That is not what
we agreed upon!
I want my allowance
back right now!
It's already gone.
My uncle lost his job,
and his goat was
going hungry, so...
I spent it on food
for the goat.
I mean, sort of.
The goat just ate the money.
Okay, the-the only way
to proceed is for you to come
to school dressed
exactly like me.
What is that
look called?
Sexy schoolgirl
librarian chic.
All right, you'd better
get a move on, okay?
Kids 'R' Us closes at
6:00 p.m. sharp. Go, Brittany.
Dear Journal,
£ my lust for life is renewed.
I have found myself dropped
behind enemy lines,
poised to destroy
the Glee Club from within.
Schuester and his
guidance counselor Ginger
fell for my pity party
hook, line and sinker,
and now I'm in
and ready to sink them,
once and for all.
Thus begins my plan.
I will pit these Glee Clubbers
against one another,
rupturing the group internally,
until it explodes
like a ripe zit!
[knocking on door]
You wanted to see me?
Yes. Mercedes, have a seat.
So, I've decided I'm going
to sing a song in Glee Club,
and I need your advice.
Now, as you may know,
I have a background in music.
For a brief period, I
was a tambourine player
for Wilson-Phillips.
What I need to
learn from you
is how to be a diva.
Oh. Well, you've definitely
come to the right girl.
I mean, being a diva
is all about attitude,
something I know
you're not short on.
It's all about sassy fingers
and shaking that weave
and generally, taking
no nonsense from nobody.
Dig it, sister.
Well, I have to say
I'm flattered and shocked
that you came to me.
Oh, come, now, "Ra-chelle,"
it doesn't humble me too much
to say I simply
need your tutelage.
Well, I'll say this-- being
a diva is all about emotion.
In fact, you feel
so much emotion
that it cannot be
physically contained.
Sometimes you have
to close your eyes
and turn your head and push,
push your feelings away--
they're that big!
Wow.
Well, that Mercedes
is wrong about you.
What... what
did she say?
Oh, I don't remember
the specifics, just
something about
you're not as talented
as you think you are
and all your ideas
are horrible.
I don't know,
something like that.
She said what?
Yep. Quote:
"Not that talented."
There you are.
I heard what you
said about me.
RACHEL:
I heard what you said about me.
Just when I thought
we were friends.
I guess that will just
never happen, will it?
I guess not.
You know, there's only
one "I" in "diva," Rachel,
and that "I" is me.
Guess we're just gonna
have to settle this
the old-fashioned way.
Diva-off.
Tomorrow, Glee Club.
Why not right now?
'Cause I have to go
get my cross-trainers.
Want to know why?
I'm gonna be
doing some runs.
So... Friday night,
I figured we'd check out
the Sullivan rink.
They have ice rink
bumper cars.
I told you, I haven't decided
what I'm doing yet.
Sweet Jesus, who bought
tickets to crazy town?
WILL:
All right, looks like
the guys here are ready
to give us their anthem.
Everybody, we are
the new and improved
The Justin Bieber Experience,
and we think
this song is an anthem
because everything
Bieber does is epic.
Truth.
Anyway, this song,
like all the songs I sing,
is for my girlfriend Quinn.
Hit it.
[Justin Bieber's
"Somebody to Love" begins]
#Gotta keep it,
feels so right #
#Gotta, gotta, gotta,
gotta keep it close #
#Oh! #
#Feel so right #
♪Oh, for you
I'd write a symphony ♪
♪I'd tell the violin ♪
♪It's time to sink or swim ♪
♪Watch them play for you ♪
#For you I'd be running #
#Whoa, whoa #
♪A thousand miles ♪
♪Just get to where you are ♪
♪Step to the beat of my heart ♪
♪I don't need a whole lot
but for you ♪
♪I admit I'd rather give you ♪
♪The world
or we can share mine ♪
♪I know I won't ♪
♪Be the first one giving you
all this attention ♪
♪Baby, listen ♪
♪I just need somebody ♪
♪To love... ♪
♪I, I don't need too much,
just somebody to love ♪
♪Somebody to love... ♪
♪I don't need nothing else ♪
♪I promise, girl, I swear ♪
♪I just need somebody to love ♪
♪I need somebody ♪
♪I, I need somebody ♪
♪To love ♪
♪Every day ♪
♪I'll bring the sun around ♪
♪I'll sweep away the clouds,
smile for me ♪
♪I would take ♪
♪Every second,
every single time ♪
♪Spend it like my last dime ♪
♪Step to the beat
of my heart ♪
♪I don't need a whole lot
but for you ♪
♪I admit I'd ♪
♪Rather give you the world ♪
♪Or let you share mine ♪
♪I know I won't be
the first one ♪
♪Giving you
all this attention ♪
♪And, baby, listen ♪
♪I just need
somebody to love... ♪
♪Oh, no, no, no, no ♪
♪I don't need too much, just ♪
♪Somebody to love... ♪
♪Oh, I, I don't
need nothing else ♪
♪I promise, girl, I swear ♪
♪I just need somebody ♪
♪To love... ♪
♪Somebody to love ♪
♪Somebody to love... ♪
♪I need somebody,
I, I need somebody ♪
♪I need somebody ♪
♪I swear ♪
♪I just need
somebody to love. ♪
[girls cheering, whooping]
Justin Bieber!
[indistinct chatter]
I need a towel.
Hey!
I... I actually
can't do Friday.
Hey, Lauren.
So, uh,
what'd you think?
Honestly, although
my love would crush him,
I'm totally turned on
by the Biebster.
That is, until I remember
that he looks like he's 12;
then it's sort of creepy.
So if I were gonna give
you a grade: C-plus.
Listen, Zises,
I'm dying here.
You got me
every which way, and we both
know I'm not the brightest.
So, please!-- what do I
have to do to get with you?
I may have
a proposition for you.
I'll keep you posted.
Color Me Mine?
I'll color you
yours any day.
Mm, Sammy Evans!
You are Biebalicious.
How are things going
with you and Quinn?
Fine.
No, they're not.
You and I should,
uh, talk soon.
Sam's an artist, Finn.
An artist?
I guess that's why he's
taking you to Color Me Mine.
I told you I needed time
to figure out
what I was gonna do
with Sam, and I did.
I choose him.
Because of The Justin
Bieber Experience?
Look, I thought it was
gonna be stupid, too,
but he was so... shameless.
He just got up there
and owned it.
It was sexy.
I'm sorry, Finn.
But like I said,
Sam's an artist,
and at the end of the day...
[whispers]:
it really turns me on.
[grunting]
[whistle blows]
Do dudes ever get erections
when they wrestle with you?
Shut it, Puckerman--
we're here to talk business.
Sorry.
Okay, I want to do
a number for Glee Club.
It's stage one
of my master plan.
Shibby. So what, you want me
to back you up on my ax?
Yeah, but I also
need some advice.
I'm a little bit nervous about
singing in front of a crowd.
Up until now, I've only really
sung in the steam shower.
Hot. But ridiculous.
I mean, you're the most
confident chick I know.
Yeah, I know
I'm hot melted butter,
but singing's different,
and I want to be great.
Or at least as good as Barry.
I get nervous
before I sing, too.
But I always overcome.
You want to know my secret?
Yeah.
Oldest trick in the book.
Just picture the audience
in their underwear.
Even the dudes?
It's not about sex.
It's just about
seeing the audience
as more vulnerable
than you.
Trust me.
It works every time.
Can I touch your
knockers now?
Only if you want
to lose a hand.
But you're on your way.
[bell ringing]
Remember, I want this
diva-off to be a bloodbath.
Oh, trust.
It's about to go down.
You look amazing.
I really do.
This look has
to go viral.
Is there any way you can cut
class for the rest of the day,
just so that you could
walk down the halls?
Totally. Most teachers
think by cutting class,
I might improve
my grades.
Great.
TINA: Why are you
dressed like that?
I thought you weren't
into the Biebster.
Well, I wasn't, but
then somebody told me
that Justin Bieber's,
like, the king of YouTube
with over a
billion views.
An anthem is supposed to
appeal to the masses, right?
So before I pick my anthem,
I was working
on my anthem look.
Okay, guys and gals!
And Sue.
It's the moment we've
all been waiting for.
Our next diva-off.
So here they are, sure
to give us a fantastic anthem,
Mercedes and Rachel.
Let's give it up!
[scattered cheers, applause]
Uh, after much argument,
I finally convinced Mercedes
that in order to do
a proper diva-off,
it has to come from
the Broadway catalogue.
Which I think
is safe to say
that that gives me
a home field advantage, so...
Oh, wellyou're about
to get beat on your own turf.
Hit it.
["Take Me or Leave Me"
from Rent begins]
♪Yeah ♪
♪Ooh ♪
♪Every single day,
I walk down the street ♪
♪I hear people say ♪
♪"Baby's so sweet" ♪
♪Ever since puberty,
everybody stares at me ♪
♪Boys, girls, I can't
can't help it, baby ♪
♪So be kind and don't
lose your mind ♪
♪Just remember ♪
♪That I'm your baby ♪
♪Take me for what I am ♪
♪Who I was meant to be ♪
♪And if you give a damn ♪
BOTH:
#Take me, baby #
♪Or leave me ♪
♪Take me, baby, or leave me ♪
♪A tiger in a cage
can never see the sun ♪
♪This diva
needs her stage, baby ♪
♪Let's have fun ♪
♪You are the one I choose ♪
♪Folks would kill
to fill your shoes ♪
♪You'll love the
limelight, too ♪
♪Now, baby ♪
♪So be mine,
and don't waste my time ♪
♪Crying, "Oh, honey bear,
are you still my, my, my baby? ♪
♪Take me for what I am ♪
♪Who I was meant to be ♪
♪And if you give a damn ♪
♪Take me, baby,
or leave me ♪
♪No way can I be what I'm not ♪
♪But, hey, don't you
want your girl hot? ♪
♪Don't fight,
don't lose your head ♪
♪'Cause every night ♪
♪Who's in your bed? ♪
♪Take me for what I am ♪
♪Who I was meant to be ♪
♪And if you give a damn ♪
♪You better take me, baby ♪
♪Oh, take me, baby ♪
♪Or leave me ♪
[harmonizing]:
#Take me, baby #
♪Or leave me ♪
♪Yes, I'm leaving ♪
♪I'm gone. ♪
[song ends]
[cheers and laughter]
Oh, my God.
That was so great!
No, her. What about her?
Me? No, her.
You guys,
that was awesome!
Hey, where's the hate?
Not the point
of Glee Club, Sue.
[bell ringing]
I understand you
wish to see me.
Yeah, Sue, I did.
I saw how you were
in class today.
What are you doing
tomorrow night?
I want to take you somewhere.
No. No. No way.
I don't care how depressed I
am, I will not date a curly.
Not on a date, Sue.
Still probably
not going to go.
You're interested in
making your comeback, right?
Well, I think it's important
that you see something.
Hate 'em.
Hate hospitals, William.
That's why I keep voting
for those death panels.
Sue, I know you.
You crack jokes whenever
you get uncomfortable.
Not really joking, William.
And you have a penchant for
sappy scenarios set to music,
so I demand to know
where we're going.
We're going to the
pediatric cancer ward.
No, no, no-- once a month,
I come down here,
and I sing songs
with some of the kids
getting long-term care.
Yep. No.
No. Sue.
Uh, William...
I know what
you're getting at.
I have been selfish.
Yes, I was ridiculed
on the national stage,
but you're right,
that's nothing
when you compare it to what
many people have to deal with
and come back from.
I should be grateful.
Well, congratulations,
I've learned my lesson.
Then let's celebrate.
Let's sing with some kids.
Look... you're right.
You know, sometimes,
Glee Club is a little silly.
But we push through the weird
to get to the real stuff.
I mean, music can get
at a part of us
that-that's hard
to open up to.
But please...
go there with me.
I think it'll be
good for you, Sue.
No outfits,
no jazz hands.
Just... music.
Fine.
And William, I don't care
how adorable those kids are,
if I hear one song from that
classic rock outfit Journey,
I will start
pulling catheters.
Come on.
Bailey?
Hi, guys!
ALL:
Hi, Will.
Oh, hey. My man.
Hi.
Oh, my God, you're
Sue Sylvester.
I just saw
you on TV.
Oh.
Hey, guys.
This lady was interviewed
by Katie Couric.
Holy sweet
baby Jesus.
What do you say, guys?
You ready
to make some music?
ALL: Yeah!
WILL:
Let's do this thing.
Brought my special
little guy with me.
[all cheering]
Yeah! All right!
[ukulele playing]
All right, and that's
all there is to it.
So, does everyone
know their parts?
ALL: Yes.
Okay. Sue?
My kids are going
to mop the floor with your kids.
Not a chance.
All right,
I'm going to sing
the first two.
And then you guys come in
and join me,
just like we practiced.
All right?
Okay.
[playing
"This Little Light of Mine"]
♪This little light of mine ♪
♪I'm gonna let it shine ♪
[kids join in]:
#This little light of mine #
♪I'm gonna let it shine ♪
♪This little light of mine ♪
♪Let it shine,
let it shine, let it shine ♪
Hide it under a bushel.
♪Hide it under a bushel? ♪
♪No! I'm gonna let it shine ♪
♪Let it shine,
let it shine, let it shine ♪
KIDS and SUE:
#This little light of mine #
♪I'm gonna let it shine ♪
♪This little light of mine ♪
♪Let it shine,
let it shine, let it shine. ♪
[song ends]
[laughs]
Give yourselves a hand.
All right.
Good job.
I'll never forgive you for this.
Deal.
[bell ringing]
Look, Q, I know that we've
had our differences,
but I can't lie-- that
outfit is amazing on you.
It looks good
on everyone.
Penny loafers
and tights?
Genius.
Outrageous.
I mean, my carousel-horse
sweater should make me look
like an institutionalized
toddler,
but no, I look
hot and smart.
I feel like Michelle Obama.
Oh, my God.
You guys look amazing.
Seriously.
She's a genius
and an icon.
Who is?
Brittany.
Who did you think?
Who knew that taking off
that Cheerios! uniform
would turn her
into a fashion
institution?
Is-Is this a joke?
No. That sweater is.
Who wears
a reindeer sweater?
Uh, all three of you.
No, this is a
carousel horse.
If you want
to know what to wear,
just look to Brittany.
Look, she took
the look from me, okay?
I paid her.
You're a terrible
liar, Rachel.
I can't believe you would take
this away from poor Brittany.
It's sad.
You're just sad.
Hey!
I need to talk to you.
I want my money back.
Well, I used it to
pay a publicist.
What?
Jacob Ben Israel
posted a photo and this Web site
called "The Sartorialist"
named me the trendiest
girl in America.
Brittany, I'm trying
to stage a comeback here.
Okay, but what exactly are
you coming back from?
I...
Listen, Rachel.
I'm gonna give you some
tough love right now.
You're not a trendsetter.
When people look at you, they
don't see what you're wearing,
they see a cat getting
its temperature taken,
and then they hear
it screaming.
I'm really sorry,
but I have to go.
I have an interview
with Teen Vogue.
[bell ringing]
All right! Let's get
right down to it.
Starting us off and making
her New Directions! solo debut,
Miss Lauren Zizes.
Uh, so what are you going
to sing for us, Lauren?
Here's how I see it.
I know I'm the hottest bitch
in this joint.
If I was a country,
my flag would be a big fist
giving the rest
of the world a finger,
and this would be
my national anthem.
WILL:
Okay.
Puckerman, grab your guitar.
Tina, Brittany, ready?
Good.
Awesome. Super cool.
[groans]
Okay.
[clears throat]
Two, three, four.
[The Waitresses'
"I Know What Boys Want" begins]
♪I know what boys like ♪
♪I know what guys want ♪
♪I see them looking ♪
♪I make them want me ♪
♪I like to tease them ♪
♪I know what boys like ♪
♪Boys like ♪
♪Boys like me ♪
♪I see you're sad now ♪
#I will let you #
♪Sorry I teased you ♪
♪This time I mean it ♪
#I will let you #
♪Anything you want ♪
#You can trust me #
♪I really want to ♪
♪You can trust me ♪
♪How would you like it? ♪
#You can trust me #
Sucker!
[laughing]
♪I got my cat moves ♪
♪That so upset them ♪
♪Zippers and buttons ♪
♪Fun to frustrate them ♪
♪They get so angry ♪
♪Like pouty children ♪
♪Denied their candy ♪
♪I laugh right at them ♪
♪I know what boys like ♪
♪Boys like ♪
♪Boys like me. ♪
[whooping, clapping]
How frickin' hot is she!
[excited chatter]
[chatter, cheering, whooping]
[bell rings]
[deep voice]:
This morning I woke up,
and decided to
swallow the sun.
That's my James Earl
Jones impression.
First of all, that is offensive;
he shot Martin Luther King.
[deep voice]:
Obi-Wan never told you
what happened
to your father.
Okay, you know what?
Let's just cut to the chase.
Despite the fact
that your mouth-to-face ratio
is, like, way off,
you still somehow
manage to be cute.
But make no mistake,
every time you open
your humongous mouth
to do an impression
or moisten
an enormous stamp
for a lazy giant,
you take one step closer
to everyone seeing
that you are
actually a dork.
Which is where I come in.
I hereby offer
my services as a mistress.
I wants on them froggy lips,
and I wants on 'em now.
But I'm dating Quinn.
And this just in:
she cheated on you.
No, she didn't.
Look, I know you're as dumb
as a bag of wet hair,
but you know in your
heart she's lying.
That gumball story
was insane.
You're choosing
to believe it
so you can still
be with her.
But consider my offer.
Not only am I giving you
full visitation rights
to the set of rambunctious twins
that live on my ribcage,
you get the
chance to show
that pastry bag Finn that
he can't mess
with Sam Evans.
And not just because you
can unlock your humongous jaw
and swallow him whole
like a python,
but because you have
some buzz at this school.
Think about it.
[sighs]
Will, you have
a problem.
You?
No. Your Glee kids.
They have no
comprehension skills.
Your assignment
was anthems,
and I'll be damned
as your hairdresser
if any 'em sung
a single one.
Sue, are you trying to tell me
that you want
to perform an anthem?
[sighs]
Well, I'll admit
that your little field trip
to the house was sad;
inspired me a bit.
But I'm not gonna
go it alone--
the whole crew
has to sing it with me.
And here's the catch:
no more Bieber,
no hoodies,
no pocket Lesbian Bieber hair.
Well, that can be arranged.
What's your song?
[My Chemical Romance's
"Sing" begins]
♪Sing it out ♪
♪Boy, you've got to see ♪
♪What tomorrow brings ♪
♪Sing it out ♪
♪Girl, you've got to be
what tomorrow needs ♪
♪For every time ♪
♪That they want
to count you out ♪
♪And use your voice ♪
♪Oh... ♪
♪Every single time you ♪
♪Open up ♪
♪Your mouth ♪
♪Sing it for the boys ♪
♪Sing it for the girls ♪
♪Every time that you lose it,
sing it for the world ♪
♪Sing it from the heart ♪
♪Sing it till you're nuts ♪
♪Sing it out for the ones
that'll hate your guts ♪
♪Sing it for the deaf ♪
♪Sing it for the blind ♪
♪Sing about everyone
that you left behind ♪
♪Sing it for the world ♪
♪Sing it
for the world ♪
[electric guitar solo]
♪Cleaned up ♪
♪Corporation progress ♪
♪Dying in the process ♪
♪Buy yourself the motivation,
generation nothing ♪
♪Nothing but a death scene ♪
♪Product of a white dream ♪
♪I am not the singer
that you wanted ♪
♪But a dancer,
I refuse to answer ♪
♪Talk about the passer ♪
♪Ruling for the ones
who want to get away ♪
♪Keep running ♪
♪Sing it for the boys ♪
♪Sing it for the girls ♪
♪Every time that you lose it,
sing it for the world ♪
♪Sing it from the heart ♪
♪Sing it till you're nuts ♪
♪Sing it out for the ones
that'll hate your guts ♪
♪Sing it for the deaf ♪
♪Sing it for the blind ♪
♪Sing about everyone
that you left behind ♪
♪Sing it for the world ♪
♪Sing it
for the world ♪
♪We've got to see
what tomorrow brings ♪
♪Sing it for the world ♪
♪Sing it
for the world ♪
♪Boy, you've got to be
what tomorrow needs ♪
♪Sing it for the world ♪
♪Sing it
for the world. ♪
[whoops]
WILL:
Yeah!
[whooping, shouting]
[bell ringing]
Hey.
Do you think
I could borrow
one of your T-shirts
to use as a smock tonight,
at Color Me Mine?
Kind of have a thing for
wearing my boyfriend's shirts.
We're not going
to Color Me Mine.
And I'm not your boyfriend.
Wait... Why?
Because you can't
look me in the eye right now
and tell me that you
didn't make out with Finn.
I want to be with you, Sam.
Forget it, okay?
No harm, no foul.
Oel ngati kameie.
Crap. Santana told me
to stop speaking Na'vi.
Since when is Santana
telling you what to do?
Since we started going out.
♪I thought
you'd always be mine... ♪
[sighs]
[bell rings]
♪Our whole life. ♪
When did that happen?
WILL:
All right, I hate to say it,
but I think we all owe Sue
a big thank-you.
She may hate us,
but she did give us
a kick-butt song for Regionals.
Yeah, she did!
[whooping]
That's right.
Mr. Schuester, I think that our
admiration for Coach Sylvester
might just be
a little premature.
While I love
My Ehemical Romance
and I think we
all kicked butt
on that number,
as our team leader
and arbiter of all that is good,
I... I have to say that
I don't think that that song
is good enough for Regionals.
The Warblers have
Kurt and Blaine
as their, like, one-two punch,
and Aural Intensity
kicked our butt last year.
We can't just do
any song to beat
either of those teams.
You mean
a number where you don't
get to sing the entire song.
RACHEL:
Guys, this
isn't about me.
What do you suggest, Rachel?
We need to need
to be bold and epic.
We need to write
our own original music
for Regionals.
We need
an undisputable advantage.
Check out Dwarf
Diane Warren.
RACHEL:
Look, we can't
lose Regionals again
this year, you guys.
Okay? You have to trust me.
I feel really,
really strongly about this.
Let's put it to a vote.
Okay, Rachel?
All those in favor of
doing an original song.
Chemical Romance?
[bell rings]
Hey, there, buddy.
Sue!
You know, I have to
be honest, we missed
you in here today.
Oddly, you're, uh,
kind of a fun addition.
Oh, well, Charles Manson
would have been
a fun addition to
your pack of losers.
Well, looks like you're
back to your old self.
Ah, hardly.
I'm on my way to becoming
someone much better.
And you've inspired me, Will.
You've made me realize
I have more to offer the world
than coming up
with spectacular,
life-threatening
cheerleading tumbles.
I got the music in me.
Sue, that is great.
[chuckles]
I mean, with that attitude, you
are welcome in here anytime.
Oh, I couldn't do that; it'd
be spying on the competition.
What?
No one told you?
I got a part-time gig.
Yeah, I'm the new coach
for Aural Intensity.
That's impossible.
Oh, nothing's impossible, Will,
when you have
a positive attitude.
You taught me that.
Isn't it great?
Geez, I got
my mojo back,
still get to dedicate my life
to destroying yours.
Life's good.
See you at Regionals.
[bell rings]
You must be happy.
Why is that?
Quinn is back
on the market.
She'll be easy pickings
after what Sam did to her.
I don't want to
talk about Quinn.
I want to talk
about you.
You were right
in there today
about that number not
being good enough to win.
We need to write
our own songs.
Why didn't you say that
when I needed you?
It wouldn't have
made a difference.
The only way to prove
it to those guys
is to write a great
song and shove it
down their throats.
Well, do you think that you
and I should do it together?
No, I think you
should do it yourself.
Let's face it, you're the real
trendsetter in there, and...
if someone was gonna write
a song to win Regionals,
it would be you.
Do you really believe
in me that much?
More.
You know...
I really like the Rachel
that I saw in there today.
Reminded me
of the old you.
Focused and
take no prisoners.
I think she might be
making a comeback.
Synced By YesCool
www.addic7ed.com