So here's what you missed
on Glee.
It's springtime in the longest
year ever at McKinley
And it's almost time
for graduation.
Sue's principal
and Becky's her Beckretary,
Get out, bitch!
Which is good
because Becky made it clear
She doesn't ever want
to leave McKinley.
Jake cheated on Marley
with demon hellspawn Bree
And he, like,
didn't even say "I'm sorry"
Which totally hit Marley
like a ton of bricks
That she broke through
with a wrecking ball.
Say what?
And that's what you missed
on Glee.
Hey, Sue, you mind telling me
what's going on around here?
Why, it is the First Annual
McKinley High Career Fair.
Where students come to expose
themselves to the job market
and its entry-level
corporate recruiters.
Who we hope, in turn,
do not, (chuckles)
well, expose themselves
to our students.
But Sue, these jobs
are-are terrible.
It' not the '90s
anymore, William.
When any high-school
dropout could stumble his way
into a six-figure salary
as COO of a dotcom startup.
Upon graduation,
our students will be entering
the most competitive job market
in recent history.
But Sue, the thing
that disturbs me
is I don't see a booth
theater or music or dance.
There is nothing here
representing a career
in the arts!
Well, that's because there's
no such thing
as a career in the arts.
William, I will not encourage
members of this student body
to further endanger their
already uncertain futures
in the unrealistic and
narcissistic pursuit of stardom
when the very best
they're likely to achieve
is coaching a
high school Glee Club
and marrying a redheaded
googly-eyed homo afarensis
with early-onset-dressing-
like-an-old lady disorder.
Not gonna do it.
However, if you would like
to set up a stool in between
Salad Artistry
and... Fecal Sculpture,
well, you're more than welcome
to regale passersby
with your inspiring story of how
you dreamt of Broadway stardom
and ended up rapping
for high schoolers
with a head of hair
that looks just
like Olympia Dukakis's merkin.
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
Hey, guys, in spite
of the complete lack
of representation
at the Career Fair,
I know that a lot of you
are thinking
about a career in the arts.
Well, it's no secret that
Sue Sylvester doesn't believe
that an artistic career
is a very practical idea.
And, for once,
I have to admit she's right.
It's completely impractical.
You know, anyone pursuing
the arts needs to go in
with their eyes wide open.
We're talking
zero job security
and impossible odds. But...
I've always believed that you
have to pursue what you love.
And that's why
this week's assignment
is about a goofy-looking
kid who struggled
for years in the music business.
Finally.
It's Marilyn Manson Week.
Close.
Billy Joel.
- Who?
- Oh, just a musical genius
who's sold over 150 million
records worldwide.
WILL:
That's right.
Billy had to fight every step
of the way in his career.
He had countless failures
and disappointments:
writing songs
that nobody wanted,
playing piano in seedy bars
just to pay the rent,
being told he'd never make it
because he didn't look "right."
Translation: too Jewish.
But he ignored
the haters and he kept
pursuing his dream,
becoming the third
best-selling solo artist
of all time.
I mean, he is
a true inspiration
to anyone pursuing
a career in the arts,
like our very own.
Mr. Blaine Anderson
and Mr. Sam Evans.
(cheering and applause) That's right!
All right,
as some of you may or may not
know, this week is my big.
NYADA audition.
I know.
It's terrifying.
So I'm leaving today
to maybe get some last-minute
tips from Kurt and Rachel.
And I'm going with him
because I have an interview
with the theater department
at Hunter College.
They saw and they loved
my "Tornado of Talent"
impressions reel.
And I'm up
for this awesome scholarship,
the Channing Tatum
Former Male Stripper Grant.
But we spoke to Mr. Shue
and, because we have to miss
this week's lesson,
he thought the least
we could do is maybe...
Kick it off with our very own
take on a classic BJ.
Billy... Billy Joel.
Hit it.
(Billy Joel's "Movin' Out"
begins)
♪ Ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ Mmm, mmm ♪
♪ Anthony works
in the grocery store ♪
♪ Savin' his pennies
for someday ♪
SAM/BLAINE: ♪ Mama Leone
left a note on the door ♪
♪ She said, "Sonny, move out
to the country" ♪
♪ Oh, but workin' too hard
can give you ♪
♪ A heart
attack-ack-ack-ack-ack ♪
BLAINE/SAM: ♪ You ought to know
by now ♪ You ought to know by ♪
♪ Who needs a house out in Hackensack? ♪
♪ Now ♪
♪ Is that all you get
for your money? ♪
♪ And it seems such a waste
of time ♪
♪ If that's
what it's all about ♪
SAM/BLAINE: ♪ Mama, if that's
movin' up then I'm... ♪
♪ Movin' out ♪
♪ Mmm, I'm movin' out ♪
♪ Sergeant O'Leary
is walkin' the beat ♪
♪ At night he becomes
a bartender ♪
BLAINE/SAM: ♪ He works
at Mister Cacciatore's ♪
♪ Down on Sullivan Street ♪
♪ Across
from the medical center ♪
♪ Yeah, he's tradin' in
his Chevy ♪
♪ For a Cadillac-ac-ac-ac-ac ♪
♪ You ought to know by now ♪
♪ You ought to know by ♪
♪ You can pay Uncle Sam ♪ Now ♪
♪ With the overtime ♪
♪ Is that all you
get for your money? ♪
♪ And if that's
what you have in mind ♪
♪ Yeah, if that's
what you're all about ♪
BLAINE/SAM: ♪ Good luck
movin' up 'cause I'm... ♪
♪ And if that's
what you have in mind ♪
♪ Yeah, if that's
what you're all about ♪
BLAINE/SAM: ♪ Good luck
movin' up 'cause I'm... ♪
♪ Movin' out ♪
♪ Mmm, I'm movin' out ♪
♪ Mm-hmm, mmm ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I'm movin' out. ♪
Oh. Ah! Hi! Hi!
Ta-da!
Hi! Wha... Oh, hi! Oh, my God!
What's going on?
Hi! I can't believe you guys are here.
What? You guys are...
Oh, my God. You guys are...
Oh, wow! Hi! Mwah.
Oh, my God. You guys...
(school bell rings)
Hey, Becky.
Hi, hot stuff.
Want to suck face
and look at my boobs?
No. Um, can I ask you something?
What do you plan on doing
after you graduate?
Why? What are you gonna do?
Film school. I'm going
to college in New York.
Ew. Lame.
College is for suckers.
I know college might not be
for everybody, but...
you know, Becky,
when I was looking at schools
that were good for people
with disabilities,
I learned that a lot of them
have programs for
mentally handicapable students.
And I'd be happy to help you
do some research.
SUE:
Oh, that won't be necessary.
Hey, Becky, will you excuse us
for just a sec?
Sure thing, Coach.
(quietly):
What exactly are you doing?
I-I just want to make sure
that Becky was aware
of what all her options are.
She could go to college
and get a job...
Well, she has a job.
She's my Beckretary.
And here
she will remain indefinitely
in a safe and stable
environment,
working alongside someone
who cares very deeply
for her.
I was trying to help.
Well, if you really want
to help, Muppet Stephen Hawking,
you'll stop inserting yourself
into situations
you know nothing about.
(school bell rings)
(sighs)
I'm sorry.
For breaking into my locker?
For breaking your trust.
(groans)
Marley, wait.
Look,
I screwed up.
I made a stupid mistake,
and I want to make it up
to you.
Please just let me say
I'm sorry.
You shouldn't have to.
You are who you are,
and I knew who you were
when I got into this.
It was stupid of me
to try to change you.
I did change.
I'm not that guy anymore.
You are.
You'll always be that guy.
Can I get you guys a refill?
Why are you still working?
Aren't you rehearsing,
like, 24/7?
Fanny Brice was a working girl.
My director and I think
it's really important
to keep the character
as alive and authentic
as possible.
So, did you boys like those
historical sites I recommended?
Um, we checked out
that deconstructed bathhouse
on St. Mark's
where Tennessee Williams
got in that fistfight
- with Tallulah Bankhead.
- Oh, yeah.
- That was awesome.
- Cool.
Uh, but it was mostly
campus visits.
Um, NYU, Columbia...
Why? You're going to NYADA.
I-I need safety schools, Kurt.
I haven't gotten in yet.
But you will
as soon as you audition.
The way I've talked you up
to Carmen Tibideaux,
she's gonna offer you
a spot on the spot.
Which reminds me,
are you up
for a little trial run?
I don't want to send you
into the lions' den
under-rehearsed. Come on.
Yes. Yes.
Come on. Don't worry.
The piano awaits.
Uh, hello, everyone.
Welcome to the Spotlight Diner
and to a very special
performance.
Seriously? You all need
to be stopped.
That's enough. (Bell dings) Now,
you may not know the name Blaine
Anderson yet, but you will
soon when it's lit up
all over Broadway.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
Blaine Anderson.
(applause)
(playing piano)
Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, everyone.
Sing along if you know it.
(Billy Joel's "Piano Man"
begins)
♪ It's 9:00 on a Saturday ♪
♪ The regular crowd
shuffles in ♪
♪ There's an old man ♪
♪ Sitting next to me ♪
♪ Making love
to his tonic and gin ♪
(playing harmonica)
♪ He says, "Son,
can you play me a memory? ♪"
♪ "I'm not really sure
how it goes ♪
♪ "But it's sad and it's sweet
and I knew it complete ♪
♪ When I wore
a younger man's clothes" ♪
♪ La, la-la, la-la-la ♪
♪ La-la, la-la-la ♪
♪ La-la ♪
(playing harmonica)
♪ Sing us a song ♪
♪ You're the piano man ♪
♪ Sing us a song tonight ♪
♪ Well, we're all in the mood ♪
♪ For a melody ♪
♪ And you've got us feeling
all right ♪
♪ Oh, la, la-la ♪
♪ La-la-la ♪
♪ La-la, la-la-la, la-la ♪
(playing harmonica)
♪ Sing us a song,
you're the piano man ♪
♪ Sing us a song tonight ♪
♪ Well, we're all in the mood ♪
♪ For a melody ♪
♪ And you've got us feeling ♪
♪ All right ♪
(playing piano)
(harmonica joins in)
(song ends)
(cheering and applause)
That was incredible!
There's no way you're
not getting into NYADA!
Then all our dreams
will come true!
(whoops) Yeah!
Thank you.
(chuckles)
Hey, Becky?
What do you want, a
threesome with Kitty?
Um... no.
I was doing some research
about those college programs
I mentioned, and,
well, there are lots.
Like, over 200,
all over the country.
Some of them even
have cheerleading.
I can do cheerleading
in college?
You can do anything
you want, Becky.
And I want you to know
that you have choices,
and I'm not gonna
give up on you.
I know I have choices.
My choices is none
of your business,
Artie! I don't want
to go to college, and I don't
want your stupid pamphlets!
Butt out!
(school bell ringing,
Jake breathes loudly)
Dude, what's wrong with you?
Me? Nothing.
Well, there has to be something,
because I can't figure out
why anybody would screw up
the best thing
in their life the way
you just did.
Marley said it herself.
People know who I am,
and they know what I do.
You get involved at your own risk.
Hey!
I can't believe
you could be so stupid.
What do you want from me, Ryder?
We spend every day in that room
telling each other to
embrace who we are.
Do you want me
to be different? To not be me?
'Cause that's never
gonna happen.
So start learning
to like the real Jake Puckerman,
or leave me the hell alone.
(Billy Joel's "My Life" begins)
♪ Got a call
from an old friend ♪
♪ We used to be real close ♪
♪ Said he couldn't go on
the American way ♪
♪ Closed the shop,
sold the house ♪
♪ Bought a ticket
to the West Coast ♪
♪ Now he gives them
a stand-up routine in L.A. ♪
♪ I don't need you
to worry for me ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm all right ♪
♪ I don't want you to tell me
it's time to come home ♪
♪ I don't care
what you say anymore ♪
♪ This is my life ♪
♪ Go ahead with your own life
and leave me alone ♪
♪ I never said you had
to offer me a second chance ♪
♪ I never said you had to ♪
♪ I never said I was
a victim of circumstance ♪
♪ Of circumstance ♪
♪ I still belong
♪ I... still... belong ♪
♪ Don't get me wrong ♪
♪ Get me wrong ♪
♪ And you can speak your mind ♪
♪ But not on my time ♪
♪ I don't care
what you say anymore ♪
♪ This is my life ♪
♪ Go ahead with your own life
and leave me alone ♪
♪ Keep it to yourself,
it's my life ♪
it's my life. ♪
(school bell ringing)
I see your grades have improved
over the past couple
of semesters.
Yeah, I kind of had an, um...
a breakthrough a few months ago,
'cause I'm-I'm not, like, a...
a good student, but I realize
that what I'm really good at
is impressions,
so, I started
to do this impression
of a good high school student,
and it... it's kind of working.
Okay.
Tell me why
you want to go to Hunter.
Um, I-I don't know
that much about it,
except that there... well,
there's more women than guys,
and that's...
that's great for me,
because I'm totally
into feminist issues.
Like, just because
women don't make
as much as guys do
to do the same job,
it's totally not cool
that they aren't given
the same amount of respect.
And, like, why can't...?
Well, why can guys go shirtless
at the beach, but chicks can't?
Oh.
Sorry. Uh... girls can't.
I guess even I have a lot
to learn still.
I'm also super jazzed
to be going to school
in New York City.
♪ Hello. ♪
All the diversity.
Oh.
So, you're black.
That's... That-that must be
interesting.
Do you know...?
This is a shot in the dark.
Do you know Mercedes Jones?
SAM:
Oh, thanks, but I'm...
- I'm not hungry.
- Look, I'm sure
that there are other schools
that have more
specific scholarships
catered just for you.
Can I, um, tell you a secret?
Yeah.
I... I don't
want to go to college.
I hate school.
I mean, I don't...
I don't hate it.
I'm just...
I'm not good at it.
- Well, who says you have to?
- Well, I mean, ever since
I was a kid I've seen
these United Negro College Fund
commercials, and it's, like,
if you don't go to college,
you're letting
your whole family down,
or you're destined for a life
of eating out
of Dumpsters or something.
I don't know. So...
please don't judge me.
Look, in life, it's not about
knowing what you want.
It's about knowing what
you can cross off your list
that you don't want.
But I do know what I want to do.
I mean, it's been my dream
since I was a kid.
Male modeling is pretty much
the ultimate form
of self-expression
as far as I'm concerned.
It's like acting or singing,
but the only tools
you have to perform with are
your striking good looks
and great abs.
There is some truth to that.
All right, I have this vision.
You know, it's just so clear
in my head.
I'm in Hollywood... and
that's at one of those
huge studios where they, uh,
made Transformers and stuff.
This bus pulls up,
and there's a picture
of me on it,
and I'm in my underwear.
Calvin Klein or something.
My junk is as big as a car.
And I look at it,
and it's awesome.
Hey, buddy?
(speaking Spanish)
You probably think
I'm crazy, right?
All right, eat up.
You're gonna need
your strength. We are gonna
have a photo shoot here,
and we're gonna get
some modeling shots
for you to show to agencies.
Do you really think
I could be a male model?
Welcome to New York,
the city where dreams come true.
Quit stalking me, Abrams!
Don't make me get
a restraining order!
I'm not stalking you.
I just want you to chill out a
second and listen to me. (Sighs)
(Billy Joel's "Honesty" begins)
♪ If you search
for tenderness ♪
♪ It isn't hard to find ♪
♪ You can have the love
you need to live ♪
♪ But if you look
for truthfulness ♪
♪ You might just as well
be blind ♪
♪ It always seems
to be so hard to give ♪
♪ Honesty is such
a lonely word ♪
♪ Everyone is so untrue ♪
♪ Honesty is hardly ever heard ♪
♪ And mostly what
I need from you ♪
♪ I can find a lover ♪
♪ I can find a friend ♪
♪ I can have security
until the bitter end ♪
♪ Anyone can comfort me
with promises again ♪
♪ I know ♪
♪ I know, oh, oh, oh-oh ♪
♪ Honesty ♪
♪ Is such a lonely word ♪
♪ Everyone is so untrue ♪
♪ Honesty ♪
♪ Is hardly ever heard ♪
♪ And mostly what
I need from you ♪
♪ It's what I need
from you. ♪
(song ends)
Finally, you are
telling the truth.
You've been in love with me
since kindergarten.
I knew it all along.
Band geeks, get lost!
Artie is gonna show me
his purple mushroom.
No, Becky, you misunderstood.
The song was just
my way of telling you that
you need to be honest with me,
and honest with yourself.
I think you want to go
to college, but you're scared.
And that's okay.
I'm scared, too.
I'm terrified
of the whole thing.
But the only way for us to grow
is to face our fears
and move forward.
Am I right?
Do you want to go to college?
What if I go, and
everybody makes fun of me again?
What if everybody
calls me stupid
like they always used to?
They won't, because you'll have
all these awesome professors
and counselors and new friends
that'll have your back.
And all your old friends will
have your back, too.
Like me.
Are you really my friend?
Always.
Come here.
(sighs)
At first, I was
just hurt and angry
and embarrassed, because
he turned out to be exactly
what everyone said he was.
And then, I was, like,
"Okay, fine, it's over."
But then, he's putting
flowers in my locker,
and then, he's
singing "My Life"
in Glee Club, like
he's the victim.
Mm. It's just all so schizo.
And the worst part is,
I still miss him.
Oh, of course you do.
And I hate it so much!
Yeah.
(sighs)
Oh.
I'm just glad we
didn't end up...
Doin' the humpty-hump?
- Ooh.
- Mom.
(laughs) Mom!
(laughing): Oh, my God,
I'm scarred for life.
Oh, Marley.
(laughing)
You know, when I was your age,
I was... I was like
a bad-boy magnet.
Ooh! How do you think
I met your dad?
Mm.
So, I know why you loved Jake.
You know, but I am glad
that you waited
and dodged that bullet.
You know, your first time
is something
that you can never
get back, honey.
You need to hold out
for a good guy this time.
You know, not just one
you have feelings for, but
someone you can trust.
You know?
Mmm.
Okay, Sam Evans,
this is Barbara Brownfield.
She's our amazing photographer
at Funny Girl.
This is Sam Evans,
my insanely handsome
soon-to-be-supermodel friend.
I'm not gonna lie. I'm really,
really, really nervous. Uh,
I've been pitting out all
my T-shirts. Um, it's just like
my entire future is
in your hands.
You know, just try to hide
all my bad angles.
What bad angles?
(laughs)
Excellent.
I love what you're doing. Yep.
(quietly):
I'm feeling it.
(shutter clicking) We got it.
Great.
You're waiting for the bus.
Look for the bus.
Oh, I love that.
Hey, want a piece of this?
Come on. How about
you're so hot that you had
to take some clothes off?
Okay, strip it off.
Come on, Sam.
Yes!
Okay, let me just put
a little bit of
this oil on you.
Looking great.
Okay.
BARBARA:
Flex, like... (grunts)
Excellent.
Yeah. Mm-hmm.
BARBARA:
There you go.
Super. Thank you.
We got it.
Artie Abrams...
(over speaker):
wheel your butt
into my office, now.
♪
I went to my pharmacy
and took the liberty
of purchasing you a good
old-fashioned ear douche,
because you obviously
didn't hear me
when I distinctly told you,
with perfect diction
and great clarity,
to stop meddling in the affairs
of one Becky Jackson.
(pants)
Principal Sylvester,
Becky told me herself
she wants to go to college,
and there's no reason
why she can't.
How dare you lecture me.
You don't think I know that?
You don't think I've contacted
each and every school
and quizzed them endlessly
about their programs?
Then why aren't you helping her?
Because she's not ready.
Or maybe you're not ready.
I know you love Becky like a daughter,
and you want to protect her,
and I get it, because of
everything you've been through.
But you have to let her go.
There's a really good program
for students with Down syndrome
at the University of Cincinnati,
and I'm gonna take her there
for a tour. Her parents
already gave me permission.
It's only two hours from here, and
it'd be really easy to visit.
Mr. Abrams.
Ask tough questions.
Is there Wi-Fi
on campus?
Do all freshman gain 20 pounds
from cafeteria food?
I want a full report
when you come back.
(school bell ringing)
Go out with me.
Ryder... no.
Look, I'm single, you're
newly single... why not?
I have good family values.
I-I-I go to church.
I've never been arrested.
I'm not ugly.
Now that I can read,
I get good grades, and...
I've always thought you
were the most amazing girl
in the history of the world.
That's...
really sweet.
I just don't think
I want to date anyone right now.
What happened with Jake
was really painful,
and I need
a little break from men.
(sighs) Look, I'm a really,
really good guy, Marley.
I would never hurt you.
All I need is a chance,
and I swear I would
never, ever do to
you what he did.
I'll think about it.
♪ Some people stay
far away from the door ♪
♪ If there's a chance
of it opening up ♪
♪ They hear a voice
in the hall outside ♪
♪ And hope that it
just passes by ♪
♪ Some people see
through the eyes of the old ♪
♪ Before they ever get
a look at the young ♪
♪ I'm only willing
to hear you cry ♪
♪ Because I am
an innocent man... ♪
♪
♪ I am ♪
♪ An innocent man ♪
♪ Oh, yes, I am ♪
♪ Some people sleep
all alone every night ♪
♪ Instead of taking
a lover to bed ♪
♪ Some people find
that it's easier ♪
♪ To hate ♪
♪ Than to wait any more ♪
♪ I know you don't want
to hear what I say ♪
♪ I know you're
gonna keep turning away ♪
♪ But I've been there,
and if I can survive ♪
♪ I can keep you alive ♪
♪ I'm not above
going through it again ♪
♪ And although this is
a fight I can lose ♪
♪ The accused is ♪
♪ An innocent man... ♪
♪ I am... ♪
♪ An innocent man ♪
♪ Ooh, yes, I am... ♪
♪ Oh, whoa-ho-ho... ♪
(song ends)
Marley, will you go out with me?
(sighs)
Yes.
Carmen Tibideaux is a classicist,
so for your audition,
let's try to avoid
shocking patterns,
and anything that says,
"Look at me,
I'm the center of attention, and
this primary color proves it."
Uh, Kurt... wait.
Just stop.
I have to tell you something.
Oh, no.
You've got that look.
That look I saw
the night after callbacks.
If you cheated on me again,
I will not accept
sex addiction as an excuse.
I... don't want to
audition for NYADA.
- Well, you can't get in on reputation alone.
- No, NYADA is
just a performing arts school...
that's all you can study there.
I have other passions,
other... interests
I might want to
explore in college.
- For instance? - I don't know.
You know how much
I love kids, and I'd love to be
a teacher like Mr. Shue, or...
or premed or something.
Of course. How could I forget
the numerous conversations
- we've had about you wanting
to be a doctor. - My passion
for medicine has always
been my secret shame.
My first guy crush
was... George Clooney,
aka Dr. Ross, on ER.
And it's no secret what my
favorite Milton Bradley game is.
Here goes his funny bone.
(buzz) (quietly): Dang.
It's a great relief to be
able to tell you this now.
I'm just glad I did it
before my audition.
What?
We're getting married.
I know you,
and I get it, and this is
a sweet side of you that
I don't get to see very often.
You're scared.
Of what? Look, when
I first moved here,
I-I honestly felt like
I was Crocodile Dundee.
Right, the city's huge,
the buildings are huge.
And everywhere you look, it's, like,
there's all these beautiful people
who seem to have just come
from some secret meeting
where they teach you how
to make it in the big city.
What if I don't get in?
You didn't.
You will. And if you
don't, it won't matter.
You're a performer; you're
gonna find the spotlight.
And you can't shy away
from your greatness
just because you're afraid
you're not great enough.
You have a gift,
and it wouldn't be right
to let you hide that away.
Thanks for knowing me.
I love you.
I love you, too.
And we're in this together.
I can't stop you
from failing, but...
I can promise to make it
safe if you do.
And I think Santana
should do your makeup.
WOMAN:
Becky, our goal here
at the University of Cincinnati
is to make college life
as inclusive as possible.
This is one of our
independent living classes.
Students are working
on bill paying
and budgeting their money.
Everybody, this
is Becky Jackson.
She's thinking of coming here.
BOY:
Don't. This place sucks.
Just kidding.
I love it here.
(laughter) Whoo!
Is that your boyfriend?
Artie? Hell, no.
He's got herpes.
Ew.
Just for the record,
I don't have herpes.
Becky, I think
you're very funny,
and very pretty.
Tell me something I don't know.
Oh, snap.
(laughter)
TEACHER:
Becky, would you like
to stay and watch the class for a while?
BOY: Yeah.
You can sit next to me.
Okay.
Whatever.
So, how is your name
pronounced again?
Because I heard
it was "Bee-shay,"
but now that
I see it spelled out,
it looks like it should be
"Bitch-ette."
Like a little mini bitch.
Is that what your name
means in French,
or Italian,
whatever it is?
I'm... I tend to talk too much.
I'm used to dealing with boys
far prettier
and considerably stupider
than you.
Oh, cool. Look, I
agreed to meet with you
because I trust Barb
Brownfield's eye.
And I must admit,
I do respond to your look.
Your Midwestern eyes
have the vacant stare
of a cow's.
I don't have any of those
on my roster.
And you have a unique mouth.
It's, like, your lips,
they're kind of like...
Trouty.
Yes! That's it.
Trouty mouth.
Can I have, uh, one of these...
No.
So, this is how this works.
These pictures...
- Mm-hmm.
- They're nice.
But you need better.
And you are gonna pay
for those yourself.
Wait, so are you saying
you're gonna
sign me? Because
if you do, I swear,
I won't let you down.
I have been working, like,
- my entire life on different poses...
- Oh, slow down, Midnight Cowboy.
Look, this is how
male modeling works.
Most of what you'll get
will be runway,
and you're not
gonna get paid for that,
but hopefully, they'll let you
keep some of the clothes.
Now, if you book
print work, chances are
you'll be a shirtless pawn,
there to enhance
the real gem of the shoot...
the girl.
You'll be paid enough
to live in the city,
with roommates.
This is not glamorous.
This is not
what you think it is.
You are one of
10,000 beautiful boys
here in New York City,
and the word that you will hear
more than any other
during your brief
career...
will be... "no."
Well, you know, like,
dreams aren't easy,
and, I mean, I come from a place
where even the idea of sitting
in this room with you
would seem impossible.
I mean, I know who I am, and...
I know where I'm
headed in life.
I can take a few no's
along the way.
I do like you, Trouty Mouth.
(giggles)
Well, this is awesome.
Okay, this is so awesome.
I'll get those,
- uh, pictures taken right away.
- Uh, no, no, no, you won't.
You're gonna have to
wait at least a week.
- You got to lose ten pounds.
- Well, ten pounds doesn't really
seem healthy to me...
you think I'm... fat?
Not for Kansas.
- Ohio.
- Look, you are
in the big time now, cowboy.
The camera likes... starvation.
We don't have room for this.
Uh, yes, we do. Right there.
Okay, seriously,
I'm not gonna be able to survive
if you and your Hag
Berry are gonna be
tickling those ivories,
belting out gay hits
from Rent and Showboat all day.
It's a thank you
for allowing me and Sam
to stay here.
- Hey, you guys, I have some bread
here if you want. - No can do.
No, right now I'm just on this
Mentos and flavored air diet.
Sam, that's ridiculous. You
don't need to lose ten pounds.
Yeah, Sam, we all agree.
You don't need to be prison-camp
skinny to be a model.
- I think you should find
another agency. - No,
House of Bichette is, like,
the best agency in town.
You know what I think?
I think that this argument
would be best made in a song.
Yes. SANTANA: Oh, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Do you see this?
This is what's going
to happen from every argument
or discussion or meal
from now on.
It's gonna end
in a freaking sing-along.
It's bad enough we need
to be singing waiters, okay?
I can't have this in my home.
I need my peaceful place.
You don't have to sing, Santana. (Billy
Joel's "Just the Way You Are" begins)
But I dare you not to.
♪ Don't go changin' ♪
♪ To try and please me ♪
♪ You never let me down before ♪
♪ Mmm, mmm ♪
♪ Don't imagine ♪
♪ You're too familiar ♪
♪ And I don't see you anymore ♪
♪ I would not leave you ♪
♪ In times of trouble ♪
♪ No, we never
could have come this far ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
BLAINE/RACHEL:
♪ I took the good times ♪
♪ I'll take the bad times ♪
♪ I'll take you
just the way you are ♪
♪ I don't ♪
♪ Want clever ♪
♪ Conversation ♪
♪ I never ♪
♪ Want to work that hard ♪
♪ Mmm ♪
KURT/SAM:
♪ I just want someone ♪
♪ That I can talk to ♪
♪ I want you just ♪
ALL:
♪ The way you are ♪
♪ I need to know
that you will always be ♪
♪ The same old someone
that I knew ♪
SANTANA/SAM:
♪ Oh ♪
♪ What will it take ♪
♪ Till you believe in me ♪
♪ The way that I believe ♪
♪ In you? ♪
KURT/BLAINE:
♪ I said I love you ♪
♪ That's forever ♪
♪ Forever ♪
♪ And this I promise
from the heart ♪
♪ Mmm, mmm ♪
SAM/RACHEL:
♪ I couldn't love you ♪
♪ Any better ♪
ALL: ♪ I love you just
the way you are... ♪
♪ I love you just the way ♪
♪ I love you
just the way you are. ♪
(school bell rings)
Good night, Coach.
That's it?
Don't let the bed bugs bite?
You've been sitting out there
all day long
with little dream bubbles
floating over your head
and not once
have you come in here
to tell me how your trip
to college went.
I don't want to hurt
your feelings, Coach.
I don't have
any feelings, Becky.
It was okay, I guess.
I don't have to take math.
Someone takes notes for me.
I can learn photography.
Well, that sounds better
than okay to me.
To tell you the truth,
it was awesome.
(clicks tongue) Are you sure
you're ready for this, honey?
I never thought to say this.
I've outgrown
these... high school bitches.
Mmm.
You're not sad, are you, Coach?
I'm sad to be losing
the best damn secretary
since the pre-collagen injected
Melanie Griffith
in Working Girl.
(sighs)
But I'm more proud
than I am sad.
Think I can help you
write your application essay?
Sure, Coach.
Let's see what you got there.
(sighs)
Okay, well, you can't say that.
And you can't say that.
I can't say "crap" or "douche"?
Even if you're talking
about Graydon Carter.
(school bell rings)
(clears throat)
Check your Instagram.
O... kay.
(chuckles)
When did you do all that?
Uh, last night.
After I dropped you off.
I kind of couldn't stop
thinking about you.
Oh...
Look, I don't want to freak
you out and move too fast
or anything, but I'd
love to do it again.
Like, maybe tonight?
So, you guys are, like,
really a thing now?
Yeah?
It's, uh, none
of your business anymore.
Cool.
Well,
congratulations.
Duty calls.
Okay, if I'm going
to be honest here,
just because we go out once
doesn't mean that we're...
going out.
Oh.
I still just need time for me.
Sure.
Are we done, Coach?
Oh, not quite yet, Becky.
We're gonna drench this
whole thing in glitter and hoist
three dozen rainbow flags.
Got it, Coach. Go Bearcats!
Go Bearcats.
So you finally came around.
What made you see the light?
Well, Butt Chin, in the words
of Civil Rights leader.
Genghis Khan,
everyone deserves a shot
at their dreams, and
I suppose that includes
your hopelessly
misguided teen hobgoblins.
Now, don't forget to remind them
about the myriad
of show business legends born
and bred right here in Lima.
And that would be
a total of one,
Ms. Phyllis Diller.
You know, in a few decades,
when the New Directions are all
on unemployment
and sexually pleasing
some horny old casting assistant
just so they can be extras
on season 33
of The Bachelorette,
they'll look back on this
time and remember you fondly.
TINA: That's not
true, Sue Sylvester!
One day, we're gonna be
big, big stars.
SUE: Well, of course
you are, my dear.
Isn't that right, William?
Blam!
They're back! ARTIE: Yo, dawgs,
tell us everything. SAM: Fact:
Blaine thought he wanted
to be a doctor for a minute
and then Kurt talked him
out of it
and then he went to NYADA and
he crushed his NYADA audition.
Sam, that was my news.
Oh, and, uh, Mr. Shue,
did you know
that Billy Joel never went
to college?
Fact: he didn't, and I
think you forgot to tell us
about that. So I'm gonna
skip college, too,
- and become a male model.
- Impossible. You're too fat.
No, I'm not. And I don't care
what you or Ms. Bichette
or anyone says.
I like me just the way I am,
and I'm not gonna
- change for anyone.
- Well, that is
just the screw-you spirit
employers love.
Honest to God,
I cannot imagine what goes on
in your lumpish,
sexually ambiguous heads.
'Cause they're nuts.
Every one of them
is crazy!
Becky, you may be right.
- We may be crazy.
- Oh, no,
no, no, no. Don't you dare.
Over my dead body
will you inexplicably
shoehorn in another
Billy Joel song
just to punctuate one
of your weekly lessons
that inevitably veers off into
a saccharine barrage of angst
and affirmation. (Billy Joel's
"You May Be Right" begins)
(cheering)
♪ Friday night
I crashed your party ♪
♪ Saturday I said I'm sorry ♪
♪ Sunday came
and trashed me out again ♪
ARTIE/KITTY:
♪ And you told me not to drive ♪
♪ But I made it home alive ♪
♪ So you said that only proves ♪
♪ That I'm insane ♪
ALL:
♪ You may be right ♪
♪ I may be crazy ♪
♪ But it just may be a lunatic ♪
♪ You're looking for ♪
♪ Turn out the light ♪
♪ Don't try to save me ♪
♪ You may be wrong ♪
♪ For all I know,
but you may be right ♪
(whooping)
♪ Now think of all the years
you tried to ♪
JAKE/RYDER:
♪ Find someone to satisfy you ♪
♪ I might be as crazy
as you say ♪
KITTY/ARTIE:
♪ If I'm crazy then it's true ♪
♪ That it's all because of you ♪
♪ And you wouldn't want me
any other ♪
♪ Way ♪
ALL:
♪ You may be right ♪
♪ I may be crazy ♪
♪ Oh, but it just may be
a lunatic ♪
♪ You're looking for ♪
♪ It's too late to fight ♪
♪ It's too late to change me ♪
♪ You may be wrong
for all I know ♪
♪ But you may be right ♪
♪ You may be right
♪ You may be right ♪
♪ I may be crazy
♪ I may be crazy ♪
♪ Hey, but it just may be
a lunatic ♪
♪ You're looking for ♪
♪ Turn out the light ♪
♪ Oh, don't try to save me ♪
♪ No, no, no, no ♪
♪ You may be wrong
for all I know ♪
♪ You may be right ♪
♪ You may be wrong ♪
♪ But you may be right ♪
♪ You may be ♪
♪ Wrong ♪
♪ You may be wrong ♪
♪ But you may be right ♪
♪ You may be wrong but you may be
right ♪
♪ Hey, you may be wrong ♪
♪ You may be wrong
but you may be right... ♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com