♪[Piano and drums playing]
[People chattering]
[Man]
Guys, could you get
up on stage, please?
[Man #2]
Hi, how are ya?
God, it's good
to see ya.
How ya been?
[Woman laughing]
[Laughing]
How you doing?
♪[Piano playing]
[Man #3]
♪ da, da, da,
da, da ♪
Ok, a little bit-- a
little bit quicker.
A little bit quicker.
A little punchier.
♪ Da, da, ba,
ba, da, da ♪
♪ ba, da, da,
ba-Dee-ya ♪
1 more time. 1, 2...
[Cars honking]
[Larry]
Pivot, step,
walk, walk, walk.
The next part is
pivot, step,
walk, walk, walk.
Hold on till
the end and
5, 6, 7, 8.
♪[Drums playing]
Ah-ah!
Again.
Step, push, step,
step, touch, kick.
Again. Step,
push, step, step.
Strong arms.
Again.
Step, push,
sharp pivot,
touch, kick.
Good.
Bob it.
Right. Back,
connect, swift.
Turn, turn,
right and left.
Hop, step,
pivot, step.
Touch, kick,
and down.
You got it?
Going on, and
turn, turn,
right and left.
Chest, step.
5, 6, 7, 8.
Turn, turn,
right and left.
Chest, step.
5, 6, 7, 8.
Turn, turn,
right and left.
Chest, step,
pivot, step.
Walk, walk, walk.
The last part is
pivot, step,
walk, walk, walk.
Going to
the end, and
5, 6, 7, 8.
Ok. You,
girl in the white,
girl in the blue,
boy in
the green,
Cheryl, Greg,
boy with the
headband, deanna,
yellow sweats
and the pink,
stage left.
The rest,
thank you
very much.
Next group. 2nd
combination.
Oh, boy.
Let's go!
5, 6, 7, 8.
Again.
♪[Clapping]
Reviewing from
the last turn.
5, 6, 7, 8.
♪[Stomping]
Again.
Left, right,
point, turn.
Clap, point.
Ok, left, right,
up, down.
Look, look.
And move. 1,
2, turn, turn,
and up.
Ball change.
Left, right,
leap, cross.
Contract.
Ok.
Connie, girl
with the red
headband,
girl in gray,
stage left.
The rest, thank
you very much.
Next group.
[Woman laughing]
Great.
138, boy.
[Woman]
We could never
tell him--
139, girl.
What's he
looking for?
Baryshnikov.
[Chattering]
Don't worry.
You're going
to be terrific.
[Scoffs]
[Man]
Ok, move along.
Ok, ok,
that's enough.
Now, as soon as you get
inside, pick up your
numbered card.
[Larry]
Step, stretch, kick.
Shoulders back.
Gentlemen, get ready.
Girl here in the pink,
Sheila, stage left.
The rest, thank
you very much.
First group
of guys.
[People groaning]
5, 6, 7, 8.
Step, kick,
and down.
Come on, make
it strong, guys.
Step, kick.
Strong arms!
[All grunting]
Turn, turn,
right, left.
Push.
And down.
[All grunting]
You, in
the blue,
yeah, you got
to hit it on 6.
That's it.
Great little
body, huh?
[Chattering]
Hi.
[Larry]
All the way
to the floor.
[Cars honking]
Oh, come...
Hold it.
This is all wrong.
Everybody back it up.
You, in the green.
You. You,
honey. Come on.
Watch this.
This is right.
5, 6, 7, 8.
Hit it. Hit it.
Down. Up.
Push it!
Back!
Ok. See what
I'm saying?
Just like that.
Everybody, from
the last section.
6, 7, 8.
Al, guy on
your left.
Girl in green
in the center.
You, boy in the
blue in the back.
Stage left.
The rest, thank
you very much.
[People moaning]
I've never been
cut this soon.
Zach!
That's it.
That's all of 'em.
Ok, everybody
on stage.
Let's do the whole
combination, from the top.
[Larry]
Let's go!
Right! I want
it strong.
Make it sharp.
Take it on
the downbeat.
Ready and
5, 6, 7, 8.
[All clap]
[All snap fingers]
[All snapping fingers]
[All clapping rhythmically]
[All grunting]
[Man]
Awoo!
[All]
Uh!
[Woman]
Huh!
[Man shrieking]
[All clapping]
[Man cheering]
[Woman screams]
[Man]
Whoo!
[Men barking]
[All grunting]
[Larry]
5, 6, 7, 8!
[Woman]
Huh!
[All]
Oh!
[Whistle blowing]
Larry.
[Man]
Uh-oh.
[Chattering]
Honey, you
were great.
[Laughing]
Whoo.
[Speaking Spanish]
[Man gasps]
[Man coughs]
Clear stage,
please.
I'm gonna put
you into groups.
So listen up for
your number.
First group is
upstage, right.
That is,
number 4--
oh, I forgot
my number.
When I come to a
number without a name,
that'll be you.
Right. 12.
Here.
19.
Yes.
228.
131.
Here.
32.
Right here.
46?
Yes.
41.
Yeah.
29.
Here.
52.
6.
Yeah.
♪ God, I hope
i get it ♪
♪ I hope I get it
[women]
♪ how many people
does he need? ♪
[Men]
♪ how many people
does he need? ♪
♪ God, I hope
I get it ♪
[Chorus]
♪ I hope I get it
♪ how many boys,
how many girls? ♪
how many... ♪
101.
Yes.
23.
23!
Judy Monroe.
5.
Yeah.
25.
Here.
40.
Yes.
2.
243.
Yes.
13.
Yo.
128.
[Chorus]
♪ look at all the people
♪ at all the people
♪ how many people
does he need? ♪
♪ how many boys?
♪ How many girls?
♪ How many people does he
♪ I really
need this job ♪
♪ please, God,
I need this job ♪
♪ I've got to
get this job ♪
[Larry]
Ok, first group,
ballet combination.
Everybody else,
clear the stage.
2nd group, be ready.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
Morales, you're
dancing with your
tongue out again.
Aw, shit.
Next group.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
The girl in the
yellow trunks.
Who, me?
Yes. Any ballet?
No.
Don't dance.
Don't dance!
[Music stops]
[Sobs]
[Larry]
Come on.
[Microphone feedback]
Larry, let's go.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
Sounds like God got out
of the wrong side of
bed this morning.
I hate his
auditions.
I don't mind
being treated like
puppets, but worms?
Or merchandise.
Personally, I
wouldn't mind him
being such a shit,
if he wasn't so
goddamn talented.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
Boy in the
headband,
head up.
Headband,
head up!
Say, how long is
he gonna keep us?
Long.
My day job
starts at 4:00.
Well, you better
call in sick.
Make 'em sharp.
[Larry]
Next group of girls,
jazz combination.
♪ God, I really blew it
♪ I really blew it
♪ how could I do a
thing like that? ♪
[Men]
♪ how could I do
a thing like ♪
[Chorus]
♪ now, I'll never make it
♪ I'll never make it
♪ he doesn't like
the way I look ♪
the way I dance ♪
♪ he doesn't like
the way I-- ♪
Blond girl in the front,
that's much better,
but still too
much tension.
Relax.
[Fingers snapping]
[Car honks]
I'm sorry.
[Baseball game on t.V.]
Hi. Uh, I know there's
an audition going on,
but is there
any way possible
I could see
the director
for a minute?
You can leave
him a note.
[Tv announcer]
...Drops in, a run scored!
[Crowd cheering]
[Larry]
Ok, let's try
it under tempo.
Out. In.
Push. Reach.
Now, take your time,
and snap.
Walk, walk, out.
Walk, walk. Good.
With tempo. 7, 8.
Left, right.
Around. Clap.
Big step, big step,
and down.
Right, next
group of girls.
Ok, hope
everybody was
listening.
I don't want to
go through the
same thing twice.
Ready?
5, 6, 7, 8!
[Fingers snapping]
Hold it,
hold it.
Sheila, do me a
favor. Dance upstage.
And you, in the
peach, downstage.
5, 6, 7, 8.
[Fingers snapping]
Ok, next
group of boys.
Don't you know the
combination, Sheila?
I knew it when I
was in the front.
Next group.
Chewing gum?
Get rid of it.
6, 7, 8.
I'll pick it up
in 15 minutes.
Uh, it's, uh,
really important
I get this to the
director, right away.
Um, I'm his secretary.
Can I help you?
Sammy, Sammy.
The messenger
is going to
pick this up.
Uh, could you
give this to
Zach, please?
Yes. What is this
in reference to?
Just tell him
that Cassie wants
to see him.
Cassie?
Didn't you used
to be a dancer?
I saw you. It was
in this theater.
You stopped
the show.
God, I was in
High School.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to
say it that way.
That's not
what I meant.
I'll get this to
Zach, right away.
Thanks.
[Laughs]
My God.
I don't
believe it.
Come on.
What are you
doing here?
Did anybody know
you were coming?
No. I just came right
from the airport.
Hang on.
Zach?
Look who's here.
Hi, Cassie.
[Laughing]
I'm sorry to bust
in on you like this.
No, it's good
to see you.
We're running late.
I'm gonna have
to call you.
Zach, it's really
important that I see you.
I'll call you,
Cassie. Leave your
number with Larry.
[Paper shuffling]
Thank you.
[Larry]
Cass, wait.
Hang around till
the first break.
You know how Zach--
Larry, let's go.
5, 6, 7, 8.
♪[Instrumental pop
music starts]
[Inaudible]
[Larry]
Give me the last
group of guys.
5, 6, 7, 8.
[All grunting]
[Fingers snapping]
[All cheering]
Uh...
You're doing
just fine. Bring
it down a bit.
Bring it down?
Yeah.
[Laughing]
♪[Music playing in distance]
[Larry in distance]
Come on, make
it strong, guys.
Step, kick.
Strong arms.
Turn, turn, right, left.
Push.
And down.
[Cars honking]
[Larry]
You came down a
little hard on Cassie,
don't you think?
Thanks, Kim.
Ok, we're
eliminating down.
When Larry calls
your number,
please stand
in the line.
Ok, girls first.
14.
19.
12.
364.
23.
23!
496.
43.
10.
[Gasping]
The other girls,
thank you very much.
[Women sighing]
[Murmuring]
Come on.
[Larry]
Now boys.
18.
45.
44.
17.
That's me.
16.
53.
Excuse me.
[Sighs]
365.
146.
[Zach]
The rest of the guys,
thanks a lot.
[Men murmuring]
[Chorus]
♪ God, I really got it
♪ I really got it
♪ I knew he liked
me all the time ♪
[All]
♪ I knew he liked
me all the-- ♪
Listen up, everybody.
We're running late,
and we've got a
lot to do before
the next elimination.
Would you all get your
pictures and resumes
and give them to
Larry? Thank you.
[Woman]
♪ what's coming next?
[Chorus]
♪ it isn't over
[man]
♪ what happens now?
[Chorus]
♪ I can't imagine what he--
♪ God, I hope I get it
♪ I hope I get it
♪ I've come this far,
but even so ♪
♪ it could be yes,
it could be no ♪
♪ how many people does he--
♪ I really need this job
[man]
♪ my unemployment is gone
[chorus]
♪ please, God,
I need this job ♪
[Woman]
♪ I thought I had
it from the start ♪
[Chorus]
♪ I've got to get this job
Larry, would you
collect them?
Kim, would you
pick them up, please?
[Whispers]
Thank you.
♪ Who am I, anyway?
♪ Am I my
♪ resume?
♪ That is a picture
♪ of a person
i don't know ♪
♪ what does he
want from me? ♪
♪ what should
I try to be? ♪
♪ so many faces
all around ♪
♪ and here we go
♪ I need this job
♪ oh, God, I need
♪ this show
Zach?
Cassie, please,
we're running late.
I'm here to
audition, Zach.
Aw, come on, it's
nothing but chorus.
Ok, fine, I'll
audition for chorus.
Oh, Cassie, come on.
Ok, Larry, line 'em up.
Let's continue, please.
Starting from stage
right. Step forward,
tell me your real name,
your stage name
if it's different,
where you were born,
and how old you are.
Cassie.
First, please.
Uh, my real
name is, uh...
Cass,
what's all this
about the chorus?
Cass, what's all
this chorus stuff?
Uh, is Tina Mason
still in that
apartment on 85th?
Tina Mason? Honey,
she hasn't been
here for years.
Yeah, I'd like to make
a credit-card call to
Los Angeles, please.
She went
home to teach
or something.
213-555-8535.
[Man]
Larry, come here
a minute, will ya?
Yeah, sure.
No, that's 213-
555-8535-7298.
[Woman]
Ok, hold the line.
Thank you.
Hang on.
Ok, I'll
wait, ok.
[Zach]
Next, please.
Maggie winslow.
Sometimes known
as Margaret,
Margie, Peggy.
I was born
in San mateo,
California,
on a Thursday
evening at
10:40 P.M.,
August 17th, 1965.
Mike cass,
but not always.
Used to be
Timothy Michael
cassideo donahue,
in Trenton, new
Jersey, where I was
born July 9th, 1960.
Connie wong.
Always wong,
never wight.
Bad joke.
I was born
in Chinatown,
lower east side.
How old are you?
I was born
December 5th,
4642, the year
of the chicken.
My real name is Sidney
Kenneth bechenstein.
My jewish name
is rachmelev
benyukov meyer
bechenstein.
And my professional name
is Gregory gardner.
Very east side, and
I do not deny it.
I happen to be a
mere 28 years old.
Sheila Bryant.
Born Colorado
Springs, Colorado.
But I've always felt
more like park Avenue.
[Laughing]
Oh, yes. I'm going
to be 30 real soon,
and I'm real glad.
[Woman]
You want to rent
for 3 months?
Right.
We do have
some furnished
studios available.
I'm Robert Charles
Joseph Henry mills III.
That's my real name, too.
I come from upstate
New York, near Buffalo.
I can't remember
the name of the town.
I blocked it out.
Age?
Tell him,
Bobby.
Why should I lie?
Age is only a
state of mind.
What age do you
want me to be?
Bobby, how old are you?
Twenty...Five.
[Softly]
My name is bebe--
louder please.
My name is
bebe Benson.
Beatrice
Ann Benson.
Washington, d.C.
I'm 19
years old.
My name is
Judy Monroe,
but my real name
is Marilyn Monroe.
[All laughing]
No, no, no. Uh,
it's always been
Judy Monroe.
I'm 22 years old,
and I'm from El Paso.
[Southern accent]
El Paso, Texas.
Hi. My name is
Richie Walters.
21 years old.
I was born on
a full moon
in herculaneum,
Missouri.
And I'm black.
Uh, we've met
before, Zach.
Alan deluca.
28 years old
from the Bronx.
Go ahead.
I'm kristine erlich.
Kristine Evelyn erlich.
I'm 18 years old.
Well, in last
September.
Tell him where
you're from.
Oh.
I'm from
St. Louis...
Missouri.
Oh, and--
wait.
My married
name is deluca.
That's great.
Congratulations,
Al. I didn't know.
Thanks.
[Laughs]
Hi.
As far as
I'm concerned,
I'm Valerie Clarke,
but my parents seem
to think I'm Margaret
Mary hoolihan.
Couldn't you just die?
I was born in the
middle of nowhere.
I mean, it wasn't
even a town, really.
Near Arlington,
Vermont.
How old are you?
Old.
24.
[Laughing]
And a half.
Uh,
mark Antony,
I think, is going
to be my stage name.
I'm really mark
Philip tobori,
from tempe, Arizona.
I'm 17 years old,
and if I get this show,
I'll work real hard.
Jesus.
Paul San Marco,
that's my stage name.
Sorry to
bother you.
My real name is
ephram Ramirez.
I was born in
Spanish Harlem--
could you hold
it a minute?
[Mumbling]
Sorry. Uh,
Paul, was it?
Paul San Marco.
That's my
stage name.
My real name is
ephram Ramirez.
I was born in
Spanish Harlem,
and I'm 22
years old.
My name is
Diana morales.
I didn't
change it,
'cause I figured
ethnic was in.
Born 4-10-62,
on a Hollywood
bed in the Bronx.
Go on, Diana.
Go on, what?
I just gave
you a picture
and resume.
Everything's
on the back.
Now tell me
what's not on it.
Like what?
Tell me about
the Bronx.
What's to
tell about
the Bronx?
It's uptown
and to the
right.
What made you
start dancing?
Who knows?
I'm puerto rican.
We jump around a lot.
Look, you want to
know if I can act?
Give me a scene
to read. I'll act.
I'll perform.
But I can't
just talk.
Please, I'm
too nervous.
You want the
job, don't you?
[Whispering]
Of course I
want the job.
Back in line.
Before we do any
more dancing--
we're gonna be doing
a lot of dancing later,
let me explain
what I'm doing.
This is not gonna be
like other auditions.
We're looking for a
strong dance chorus...
I'm sorry, what?
People who can work
together as a group,
but I'm gonna try
to shake you up,
see who you really are.
We've got some small,
but important, parts
to be played by
people in the chorus.
Since I need great dancers,
i can't expect you all
to be great actors.
So I don't want anybody
to try to act.
You understand?
Just to be exactly
who you are,
which is just as
important to me
as how well you dance.
I'm gonna ask you
some questions.
What I want to know, is
details about yourself.
Things you're proud of,
things you're ashamed of.
So if anybody
can't handle it
and wants to leave,
right now is the time
to make up your mind.
Honey?
What?
Could we
please go?
We're gonna
be fine.
Ok.
[Speaking Spanish]
Screw him.
If I could think
of anything I
was ashamed of,
I'd have tried
it years ago.
Zach?
Look, Zach, I just
need a minute.
[Inaudible]
[Mark]
Uh, how many
jobs are there?
4 and 4.
[Judy]
44?
[Sheila]
No, 4 and 4.
4 boys, 4 girls.
Need any women?
[Larry laughing]
Cassie.
Dick? I'm gonna
need the spotlight.
Could you set it
up for me, please?
[Man]
You think he's going to
keep us here much longer?
I'm really sorry,
but Zach said
he'll call you
as soon as he can.
And he told me to
ask you in a nice way
if you'd...
Would you
mind leaving?
[Door slams]
Shit.
Taxi!
Cassie!
Oh! Oh!
Honey, you all right?
That was a
hell of a fall.
You ok?
I'm fine.
[Woman]
Taxi.
Bloomingdale's.
Jesus.
Thanks a lot.
Ok, Mike, I'll
start with you.
Me?
Aren't you supposed
to start at the end?
So what would you
like to tell me?
Well, I'd like to
tell you to start
at the end.
You can wait in
the musicians' room.
[Mike]
What would you
like to know?
Oh, come on, Larry,
what am I doing here?
He told me
to leave.
I don't care if
there's a tornado
out there.
Shut up, will you?
Come on. I'm sorry.
You all right?
I'm fine.
You want to
put some ice
on that elbow?
I look like
a drowned rat.
What made you
start dancing?
Because of
my sister.
She was a girl.
So, my mom decided
she's the one
to get all the
dancing lessons,
so, every Saturday, my
mother would take her.
And once in a while,
she'd take me along.
And how old were you?
4, 5.
I'd sit there
all eager, and
♪ I'm watchin' sis
go pit-a-pat ♪
♪ said, "I can do that
♪ "I can do that"
♪ knew every step
right off the bat ♪
♪ said, "I can do that
♪ "I can do that!"
♪ One morning,
sis won't go to
dance class ♪
♪ I grabbed
her shoes and
tights and all ♪
♪ but my foot's
too small, so ♪
♪ I stuffed
her shoes with
extra socks ♪
♪ ran 7 blocks
♪ in nothin' flat
♪ hell, I can do that
♪ that I can do!
♪ Give a man some room
[all laughing]
Yeah!
Meow!
Huh!
Safe! Yeah!
[Whistle blowing]
Huh!
[Woman laughing]
Huh! Huh! Huh!
[Karate yell]
Whoa! Aah!
[Fingers snapping]
[Women giggling]
[Man]
All right.
[Tarzan yell]
Ahh!
♪ All thanks to sis
♪ I can do that
[all murmuring]
Bobby.
You got any
ice for my ego?
It hurts worse
than my elbow.
What the hell
do you expect?
You know what
Zach's like when
he's workin'.
You keep
interrupting
him again--
hey, what are you
talking to me like
I'm a grownup for?
Just stay put.
And keep that ice
on your elbow.
Larry.
Does Zach
still think I...
Cassie, let's get
one thing straight.
You can stay with me
till you find a place,
but as far as you
and Zach are concerned,
I'm not gettin'
in the middle here.
[Bobby]
...The circumstances
of my birth.
It's nothing short
of a miracle.
But actually,
I don't know
how I turned out as
heavenly as I did.
Are you gonna
do a routine?
No, no. Moving
right along.
Start with your family.
Do you want to know
all the wonderful
and exciting things
that have happened to me,
or do you want
the truth?
I'll, uh, I'll
take the truth.
Well...
Uh, my mother had a
lot of card parties
and was one
of the foremost
bridge cheaters
in America.
My father
worked for this
big corporation.
They used to send him
out into the field a lot.
To drink.
But they were ok.
I was the strange one.
How strange?
Real, real strange.
Bizarre.
[All laughing]
[Laughing]
As I got older,
I got stranger
and stranger.
That's when I
started breaking
into people's houses.
I didn't steal anything.
I'd just rearrange
their furniture.
[All chuckling]
I went to this very
expensive private school
for the exceptionally stupid.
Jock city.
I was a kid who
was always getting
slammed into lockers.
Not only by the students,
by the teachers, too.
[All chuckle]
I couldn't catch a ball
if it had Elmer's
glue on it,
and wouldn't my
father have to be
this big ex-football hero.
Well, he was so humiliated,
he didn't know what
to tell his friends,
so he told them
all I had polio.
On father's day, I
used to limp for him.
[All laughing]
Oh! And I was
always thinking up
these spectacular ways
how to kill myself.
But then I realized,
to commit suicide
in Buffalo
is redundant.
Ok, Bobby.
Exactly what you
don't want, right?
Exactly.
Dick...
Give me the
spotlight,
will you?
Back to the left.
A little more.
Hold it.
Sheila.
Yes?
Is there anything
you want to tell me?
What do I want to
be when I grow up?
Ok.
Young.
That light...
Don't you have
anything softer?
Come closer.
Can I sit
on your lap?
Do you always
come on like this?
No. Sometimes
I'm aggressive.
[All chuckling]
All right, Sheila.
Tell me about
your parents.
My parents?
Tell me about
your mother.
My mother.
My poor,
dear, sweet,
gray-haired,
darling old mother.
She was raised in
an orphanage...
By nuns.
They wouldn't
let her go out--
goddamn it! Now, can't
anybody up there hear me?
Just let your hair down!
Ooh.
Can't you talk?
All of you,
just talk to me,
to each other.
Jesus Christ.
Better?
Your mother.
Right.
My mother
was kind of...
Middle-aged
and frumpy.
Whose isn't?
At 14, she was
middle-aged
and frumpy.
[Men chuckle]
Is that the kind
of woman your
father liked?
No. My father
liked them very
young, tall,
and filled out in
all the right places.
Anyway, uh,
God knows why, they
had this daughter.
Me.
And just to get away
from her frumpy,
middle-aged life,
she used to take me
to every ballet
that came to town.
I think, probably
because it was cheaper
than getting
a baby-sitter.
But that's when I
saw that movie...
The red shoes.
[Diana]
You, too?
It changed
my whole life.
I saw that
movie 112 times.
I swear on
the grave of
my mother.
Go on, Sheila.
Well, let's
face it.
My family
scene was, uh,
not good.
♪ Daddy always
thought that he
married beneath him ♪
♪ that's what he said,
that's what he said ♪
♪ when he proposed,
he informed my mother ♪
♪ he was probably
her very last chance ♪
♪ and though she was 22
♪ though she was 22
♪ she married him
♪ life with my dad
wasn't ever a picnic ♪
♪ more like a
come-as-you-are ♪
♪ when I was 5, I
remember my mother ♪
♪ dug earrings
out of the car ♪
♪ I knew that they
weren't hers ♪
♪ but it wasn't
something you
wanna discuss ♪
♪ he wasn't warm
well, not to her.
Well, not to us.
♪ But everything
was beautiful ♪
♪ at the ballet
♪ graceful men lift
lovely girls ♪
♪ in white
♪ yes, everything
was beautiful ♪
♪ at the ballet, hey
♪ I was happy
♪ at the ballet
that's when
I started
ballet class.
♪ Up a steep and very
narrow stairway ♪
♪ to the voice
like a metronome ♪
♪ up a steep and very
narrow stairway ♪
♪ it wasn't
paradise ♪
♪ it wasn't paradise
♪ but it was home
♪ mother always
said I'd be very
attractive ♪
♪ when I grew up,
when I grew up ♪
♪ different, she said,
with a special something ♪
♪ and a very, very personal
♪ flair
♪ and though I was 8 or 9
♪ though I was 8 or 9
[crying]
♪ I hated her
♪ now, different is nice
♪ but it sure isn't pretty
♪ pretty is what it's about
♪ I never met anyone
who was different ♪
♪ who couldn't
figure that out ♪
♪ so, beautiful
♪ I'd never live to see
♪ but it was clear
if not to her...
Well, then to me.
♪ That
♪ everyone
♪ is beautiful
♪ at the ballet
♪ every prince
♪ has got to have
♪ his swan
♪ yes, everyone
♪ is beautiful
♪ at the ballet
♪ ah
♪ I was pretty
♪ at the ballet
I was born to save
their marriage,
but when my father came
to pick me and my mother
up from the hospital,
he said, "well,
I thought this
was going to help,
"but I guess not."
A few months
later, he left and
never came back.
Anyway, I had
this incredible
fantasy life.
I used to dance
around the living
room with my arms up,
like this.
And in my fantasy,
there was this
Indian chief.
And he'd say to me,
"Maggie,
"do you want to dance?"
And I'd say,
"daddy,
"I would love to dance."
♪ Yes, everything
♪ was beautiful
♪ at the ballet
♪ raise your arms
♪ and someone's
always there ♪
♪ yes, everything
♪ was beautiful
♪ at the ballet
♪ the ballet
[women]
♪ yes, everything
♪ was beautiful
♪ at the ballet
♪ hey
♪ I was pretty
♪ I was happy
♪ I would love to
♪ at the ballet
where the hell
is that resume
of that blond
girl in the
2-piece?
This one?
Bebe Benson.
[Man clearing throat]
Can we smoke?
Can the adults
please smoke?
No break,
Sheila.
Well, then, can
I discuss that
with my kidneys?
[All chuckling]
Fine.
Thank you.
Kristine.
Me?
I don't know
where to begin.
[Whispering]
Tell him how you
got started dancing.
Oh, um...
Well,
it was when this
man came around
to my home,
selling...
Lessons.
Yeah, um, lessons.
Um, dancing
lessons.
And, well,
ever since
then,
I watched
everything
on television
that had any
dancing on it,
especially...
Oh, God, um,
what do you
call them? Um,
[whispering]
Variety
shows.
Right.
Variety shows.
Specials.
I can't remember
what I was
talking about.
Variety shows.
No. Uh, no.
I wasn't--
I wasn't...
Oh, the
specials.
The specials.
Right.
Um, specials.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry. Um,
it's just,
I'm really
nervous.
Want to take a
minute and pull
yourself together?
Ah, Zach,
for her,
this is
together.
[Kristine]
So, anyway...
Robbie,
they're in a
suitcase over
there, somewhere.
Cass--
Sheila, get
your ass up
on stage.
Ooh.
Why is it
only my ass
that ever gets
invited places?
Al, your turn, please.
Uh, the
costumes are
in there. Uh...
Hats should
be in this one.
[Sighing]
Listen,
go up to the
prop room on
the 3rd floor.
We've been
using it for
an office.
I think you
better stay out of
sight for a while.
Larry, I know
I'm putting you
on the spot,
but I need a job.
I really do need--
hey, hey, hey.
I'll talk to
Zach, but you
gotta stay put,
will you, for Christ's sake?
No more interruptions, ok?
You promise?
Say, "I promise."
[Laughing]
I promise.
Ok.
But I'm straight.
I'm not too bright,
but I'm not too dumb.
And, uh,
I'm not too talented.
But you know
me, Zach.
You show me
what to do,
and I'm gonna do
the exact same way,
8 shows a
week, forever.
Uh, c-can
I go next?
Well, I don't
really have
anything to say,
it's just that--
well, it's this
waiting. It's
killing me.
Ok.
Why don't we, uh, start
with your childhood?
It was
terrible.
Just like
everybody
else's.
All of it?
Well, none of
it, really.
But, I mean, who wants
to admit you had a
happy childhood?
How about sex?
Sex?
Oh, sex.
Now--now,
that, that was
really terrible.
[Woman laughing]
How?
Well,
I was 12 years
old and...
Well, I didn't
really know
much about it.
So I went to
the library
and I took out
this medical book
with pictures of
the...The male and
female anatomy in it.
And, well,
I thought that was
pretty interesting.
And, oh, I used
to read that
book a lot.
Well, were you
interested in medicine,
or did you just want to
look at the pictures?
Well, I--I knew
what I wanted to do--
♪ hello, 12
♪ hello, 13
♪ hello, love
well, anyway, after
I had my first...
Wet dream,
I went straight
to the medical book
and looked it up.
"Milky discharge."
Oh, my God!
Gonorrhea!
♪ Changes, oh
♪ down below
♪ up above
I couldn't even
imagine asking
my dad about it.
I mean, well,
I was in shock.
I mean, golly, I...
Well, I didn't have
anybody to talk to,
so, well, I went
to the priest.
And, well, I told
him I had gonorrhea.
Oh, was he in shock.
♪ "Who have you been
with, my son?" ♪
Nobody.
Uh, nobody.
♪ "Then how can you
have gonorrhea?" ♪
Well, finally I
told him about
the book, and,
well, he set
me straight...
Which is the only
time the church
ever helped me out.
♪ Time to doubt
♪ to break out
♪ it's a mess
[chorus]
sex happens to be
the one subject I
can speak about
with absolutely
no authority
whatsoever.
♪ Too young
to take over ♪
It took me 5
years of...
♪ Too old
to ignore ♪
Finally I got a girl
who was actually
willing to do it.
So there I am,
making out in the back
seat with Sally ketchum.
A little of this,
a little of that.
Very little of that.
[All laughing]
Well, after about an
hour of this, she said,
"don't you wanna
do anything else?"
[Laughs]
I suddenly
thought to myself,
"no,
"I don't."
Did this come as a
big surprise to you?
I guess.
Yeah.
It was the moment I
realized I was gay.
♪ Hello, 12
♪ hello, 13
[chorus]
♪ hello, love
talk about love.
Man, my first
time was with
this girl, Paulette.
Forget about it. We
did it in a graveyard.
♪ The first time
we made love ♪
♪ it was a great
big deal ♪
♪ I was too scared
♪ to feel
♪ nervous from tryin'
♪ next time we
made love ♪
♪ still we were not
♪ a hit
♪ oh, I thought
if this is it ♪
♪ everyone's lyin'
♪ but then we
did it again ♪
♪ and I forgot to
be scared, I guess ♪
♪ 'cause when we
did it again ♪
♪ I closed my eyes
♪ surprise
♪ sweet, icicle hot
♪ smooth as a
lemon pie ♪
♪ sailing across
the sky ♪
♪ into the ocean
♪ we liked it a lot
♪ you can imagine why
♪ we had begun to fly
♪ feelings in motion
♪ and then we
did it again ♪
♪ I'm thinkin', was
it beginner's luck? ♪
♪ or is it wonderful once
♪ in each 3 tries?
♪ Surprise!
[Chorus]
♪ surprise
♪ first time
♪ love
♪ again
♪ so I
♪ closed my
♪ eyes
♪ it was a
sweet surprise ♪
♪ icicle hot
[men]
♪ huh
♪ smooth as a
lemon pie ♪
[Woman]
♪ huh
♪ surprise, surprise
[chorus]
♪ huh
♪ surprise
[cars honking in distance]
[Cars honking]
I mean it.
How would you like
to stay 12 years
old all your life?
My last show, I
played a 14-year-old,
and I just turned 23.
The year of the chicken?
[Giggles]
Caught.
Hey, didn't you go
to the High School
of performing arts?
[Gasps]
I thought you
looked familiar.
Do you remember
Mr. karp, the
acting teacher?
[Laughing]
Oh, yeah.
"In order to be
a real actor,
"it is not enough
to act like a king.
"You also got
to act like a
throne."
[All chuckle]
Tell me about him, morales.
Well, on the first
day of acting class,
Mr. karp puts
us on stage
with our legs
around each other,
one in back
of the other,
and he says,
"we're going to
do improvisations.
"You're on a bobsled.
"It's snowing out.
"And it's cold.
"Ok. Go."
♪ Every day
for a week ♪
♪ we would
try to feel ♪
♪ the motion
♪ feel the motion
♪ down the hill
♪ every day
for a week ♪
♪ we would try to
hear the wind rush ♪
♪ hear the wind rush
♪ feel the chill
♪ so I dug right down to
the bottom of my soul ♪
♪ to see what
I had inside ♪
♪ yes, I dug right down
to the bottom of my soul ♪
♪ and I tried
♪ I tried
and everybody's going,
"whoosh! Whoosh!"
"I feel the snow."
"I feel the cold."
"I feel the air."
And Mr. karp
comes up to me,
and he says,
"ok, morales,
what did you feel?"
And I said,
♪ "nothing
♪ "I'm feeling nothing"
♪ and he said
♪ "nothing could get
a girl transferred" ♪
♪ they all felt something
♪ but I felt nothing
♪ except the feeling
♪ that this bullshit
was absurd ♪
So I said to myself,
"don't worry about it.
"It's only the first week.
"Maybe it's genetic.
"They don't have
bobsleds in San Juan."
[All laughing]
♪ 2nd week,
more advanced ♪
♪ and we had to
be a table ♪
♪ be a sports car
♪ ice cream cone
♪ Mr. karp, he would
say, "very good ♪
♪ "except morales
♪ "try, morales
♪ "all alone"
♪ so I dug right down to
the bottom of my soul ♪
♪ to see how an
ice cream felt ♪
♪ yes, I dug right down
to the bottom of my soul ♪
♪ and I tried
♪ to melt
♪ and the kids
yelled "nothing" ♪
♪ they called
me "nothing" ♪
♪ and karp allowed it
♪ which really
makes me burn ♪
♪ they were so helpful
♪ they called me
"hopeless" ♪
♪ until I really didn't
know where else to turn ♪
[Crying]
Mr. karp comes up
to me, and he says,
"you know what, morales?
"I think you should
transfer to girls high.
"You'll never
be an actress.
"Never."
Jesus Christ.
♪ Went to church
♪ praying "Santa Maria
send me guidance ♪
♪ "send me guidance
♪ "on my knees"
♪ went to church
♪ praying "Santa Maria,
help me feel it ♪
♪ "help me feel it
♪ "pretty please"
♪ and the voice from down
at the bottom of my soul ♪
♪ came up to the
top of my head ♪
♪ and the voice from down
at the bottom of my soul ♪
♪ here is what it said
♪ this man is nothing!
♪ This course is nothing
♪ if you want something
♪ go find a better class
♪ and when you find one
♪ you'll be an actress
♪ and I assure you
♪ that's what finally
came to pass ♪
♪ 6 months later,
I heard that karp ♪
♪ had died
♪ so I dug way down to
the bottom of my soul ♪
♪ and cried
♪ 'cause I felt
♪ nothing
ok, Todd.
Um,
well, to
be honest,
I've been listening to
these people, all day long,
trying to be honest.
I mean, uh, say I pull
a hamstring, you know?
Let's be honest.
Here today,
gone tomorrow.
You know
what I mean?
Like the couple
over here that just
got married, I mean,
every time I
tell my wife I'm
going to audition--
we-- she's got a
right to, you know?
I mean, uh, what
the hell? It's not
a question of--
you know what
I mean? Uh, I'm a
damn good waiter.
I got 2 kids
and a wife,
and a mother on
social security,
I'm trying to keep
from eating cat food,
so my daytime
job is not a
question of--
look, I'm a waiter.
That's what I am.
On applications it
says, "occupation."
Well, I--I
put "dancer."
Do you know how
many waiter jobs
I'm fired off?
Well, o-one time
late is-- sure.
But, uh, auditions,
never, you know?
One of my kids
sometimes-- like
my wife says--
but come on,
on applications?
Tuesday, Wednesday.
Summer, winter.
I mean, Jesus.
Look, uh,
I'm married to the
sweetest little
wife in the world,
but, uh,
I don't know.
[Sighs]
Listen, um,
before madam
here makes a big
deal out of it,
Cassie's upstairs
in the prop room,
till the rain stops.
I told her to.
What is she
doing this for?
I don't think she's
been working too much.
What do you mean?
She's broke?
Is that it? Does
she need money?
I have no idea.
I don't know.
Talk to her.
[Siren in distance]
Val?
[Sirens wailing]
Goddamn it, Larry! Is
the loading door closed?
I'll get it.
Go ahead, val.
I'm sorry.
First of all,
let's get one
thing straight.
I never heard
of the red shoes,
I never saw
the red shoes,
I don't give a shit
about the red shoes.
I came to New York
because I wanted
to be a rockette
at radio city.
Because there
was this girl
in my hometown,
Betty Lou hyner,
and she'd actually
gotten out,
and she made
it in New York.
She was a rockette.
One Christmas,
she came home
for a visit,
and they gave
her a parade.
A goddamn parade!
[Chuckling]
And I had to
stand outside
and twirl a
friggin' Baton in
the pouring rain
for 2 hours.
Unfortunately,
though,
she got knocked up
over Christmas.
Merry Christmas.
[Laughing]
Anyway, that
was my plan.
To be a
rockette.
But the
problem was
I was so ugly,
you wouldn't
believe it.
I mean, I--I
was homely.
Skinny.
Flat as a
pancake.
But anyway,
there I was.
I got off the bus.
I was wearing my
little white tights,
my little white shoes,
my little white dress.
I looked like
a fuckin' nurse.
[Laughing]
6 months later,
I finally got
my audition
at radio city.
You know what the
man said to me?
[Scoffs]
He said he didn't
like my fan kicks.
I can do terrific
fan kicks.
So I said "screw
you, radio city,
"and the rockettes.
"I'm gonna make
it on Broadway."
But at every
audition,
I would dance
rings around
the other girls,
and I'd wind up
in the alley with
the other rejects.
Until one day,
after an audition,
I swiped my
dance card.
And on a scale
of 1 to 10,
they gave me,
for dance...
10.
For looks...
3.
Well.
♪ Dance, 10,
looks, 3? ♪
♪ and I'm still
on unemployment ♪
♪ dancing for my
own enjoyment ♪
♪ that ain't it, kid,
that ain't it, kid ♪
♪ dance, 10, looks, 3
♪ is like to die
♪ left the theater
and called the doctor ♪
♪ for my appointment to buy
♪ tits and ass
♪ bought myself
a fancy pair ♪
♪ tightened up
the derriere ♪
♪ did the nose with it,
all that goes with it ♪
♪ tits and ass
♪ had the bingo-
bongos done ♪
♪ suddenly I'm
getting national ♪
♪ tours
♪ tits and ass
♪ won't get you jobs
♪ unless
♪ they're yours
♪ didn't cost a
fortune, either ♪
♪ didn't hurt my
sex life, either ♪
♪ flat and sassy
♪ I would get the
strays and losers ♪
♪ beggars really
can't be choosers ♪
♪ that ain't it, kid,
that ain't it, kid ♪
♪ fix the chassis
♪ how do you do?
♪ Life turned into
an endless medley ♪
♪ of, "gee, it
had to be you" ♪
♪ why? Tits and ass
♪ where the cupboard
once was bare ♪
♪ now you knock,
and someone's there ♪
♪ you have got 'em, hey!
Top to bottom, hey! ♪
♪ it's a gas
♪ just a dash
of silicone ♪
♪ shake your new maracas
♪ and you'll find
♪ tits and ass
♪ can change your life
♪ they sure
♪ changed
♪ mine
you're all looking
at my tits now,
aren't you?
[All chuckling]
I'd settle for
just one of yours.
[Man]
Ooh...
Well, go out
and buy them.
♪ Have it all done
♪ honey, take my word
♪ grab a cab, come on,
see the wizard ♪
♪ on park and 73rd
♪ for tits
♪ and ass
♪ orchestra
♪ and balcony
♪ what they want
is what you see ♪
♪ keep the best of you,
do the rest of you ♪
♪ pits or class
♪ I have never
seen it fail ♪
♪ debutante or
chorus girl ♪
♪ or wife
♪ tits
♪ and ass
♪ yes, tits
♪ have changed
♪ my
♪ life
[laughing]
Thank you, val.
Paul.
Sir?
When did you
start dancing?
Not until pretty late.
Why?
I don't know why.
I just didn't.
What did you do?
Nothing much.
What was your
family like?
We were close.
Any brothers and sisters?
2 sisters.
One died when
I was 14.
How?
I really don't want
to talk about that.
I mean, why do we have
to talk about that?
Ok, Paul. Thank you.
Back in line.
[Whispering]
Can he keep us
standing here
this long?
Zach,
we've been
standing here
for quite a while.
So, maybe we
could take a 5?
Take 5, everybody.
[Larry]
5 means 5, guys, not 15.
Stanley, can I hear
the "one" routine,
starting after the insert?
♪[Piano playing]
♪[Piano playing in distance]
[Footsteps approaching]
Uncle Larry's
heartburn kit.
One totally
indigestible,
cold hot-pastrami.
One lukewarm
celery tonic.
I'm going back
on a 6:30 plane.
Naturally, since
you just got here,
and I just
talked to Zach.
Oh, come on, Larry,
what's the point?
He doesn't think I
came in for a job. He...
Larry, the truth.
When I left, how
did he take it?
[Sighing]
You know how I know how
bad he wanted me back?
'Cause he didn't
call me once.
Not once to beg me
"please come back."
[Scoffs]
As if I would,
of course.
It's not that he can't
be sweet and funny
and even warm, but I--
look, Larry, do me
a favor, will you?
I mean, he is what he
is, and that's that,
so just stop talking
about him, ok?
Cassie, Zach asked me
to give you this.
It's the telephone number
of his business manager,
in case you...
Well, he thought
you might need--
some money?
Cassie, he didn't mean--
money?
If I need some money!
All he meant was--
please.
If you change
your mind about
going back...
[Laughing]
Well, my sister
was such a
little brat,
was the reason.
But still, I
guess it was a
little extreme
shaving her head.
[All laughing]
Would you like
to hear about
the first time
I saw a dead body?
[Men laughing]
I guess I
was 6 or 7.
Larry!
[Woman]
Oh, yes! I
even tried--
where the hell
is Larry?
[Woman]
...My best friend.
Larry, do me a favor,
everybody go downstairs
and learn the lyrics
to the "one" routine.
[Larry]
Ok, let's go.
Kill the rail
and hit the work
lights, please.
Cassie,
I'm trying to work.
Me, too.
That's what I'm
trying to do.
I don't need
a handout.
I need a job.
And goddamn it,
it's my turn to
audition now, like
everybody else!
No. No, you shouldn't
have come.
And if you'd called me,
I could have saved
you the trouble.
This is for chorus.
It's not for you.
But this is the only
place there is for me.
Oh, Zach,
I'm a gypsy.
I never had an
apartment in my life
that wasn't a sublet.
[Laughing]
All I know how to do
is to point my
toes and leap.
♪ I
oh, Zach.
♪ I'm a dancer
♪ that's who I am
♪ what I do, ahh
Cassie!
♪ I
♪ I am a dancer
♪ give me the steps
♪ I'll come through
♪ give me somebody
to dance for ♪
♪ give me somebody to show
♪ let me wake up in
the morning to find ♪
♪ I have somewhere
exciting to go ♪
Christ, Cassie,
how can I put
you in the line?
You don't fit. You're
too goddamn good.
You bet I am.
And I'm so good,
I can dance any
way you want me to.
♪ Let me dance for you
♪ let me try
♪ let me dance for you
♪ we made a lot of music
dancing, you and I ♪
We? You talking
about us?
No, Zach,
I'm talking
about a job.
I haven't
worked in
over a year.
♪ Please
♪ give me an answer
♪ give me a place
♪ to begin
♪ I
♪ I am a dancer
♪ I have come home
[gasps]
♪ Let me in
♪ give me somebody
to dance with ♪
to be! ♪
♪ let me wake up
feelin' terribly proud ♪
♪ that the girl
in the mirror ♪
♪ is me
♪ let me dance for you
♪ let me try
♪ we made a lot of music
dancing, you and I ♪
[Inaudible]
[Crying]
♪ let me dance for you
♪ let me try
♪ we made a lot of music
dancing, you and I-- ♪
Cassie!
[Gasps]
All right.
Go down with the others
and learn the lyrics.
We'll see.
[Gasps]
Hello?
Yes, Paul?
I just wanted
to ask,
if I can't talk
about myself,
I'm out?
Well, I think you're a
hell of a dancer, Paul.
I can't do it.
I wish I could.
I just can't.
Could I ask you
something?
I'm curious.
If you're gonna
change your name,
why do you go from
puerto rican to Italian?
Well,
people always used
to say I don't look
puerto rican.
So you figure
you look Italian?
No.
I just wanted to
be somebody new.
So I became
Paul San Marco.
But why would you want
to be somebody new?
I don't know.
I'm not too proud
of myself, I guess.
When did you decide
to become a dancer?
My father
loves movies.
When I was a kid,
he'd take us all the
time to 42nd street.
The ones I loved
were the musicals.
How old were you?
10 or 11.
On 42nd street,
with all those crazies?
Well, he didn't
know that.
It was cheap, and...
Anyway,
because of my eyes,
I wear contacts now.
I'd have to move
down front by myself,
so I could see.
And, well, these
strange men
would come and
sit beside me...
And play with
me, you know?
Look, Paul, if this
is too rough, uh--
no. I mean, I
knew I was gay.
In school, they'd whistle
at me in the halls,
and everything.
But what really
bothered me
was I didn't know
how to be a man.
What, uh, what was
your first job
as a dancer?
At the jewel box
revue. The drag show.
I was 15.
I went to audition,
but they weren't
interested in my dancing.
They said, "show
us your legs,"
and they took me
upstairs to this
filthy rat hole.
And they
shaved my legs
and put a pair of
nylon stockings on me,
and high heels.
There I was,
in show business.
The asshole of show
business, but a job.
What did you tell
your parents?
I was a dancer
in a show.
Not what kind,
of course.
They couldn't
stop bragging.
Go on, Paul.
Then the show was
going to Chicago,
and my parents
wanted to bring
my suitcase
down to the
theater after
the show,
to say
good-bye, and...
I don't know why,
I said, "ok."
Well, we were
doing this
oriental number,
and I was wearing
this slinky
oriental dress
and this enormous
headdress
with gold balls
hanging all over it.
And I was going
down the steps
for the finale,
when I saw
my parents by
the stage door.
They got there
too early.
I freaked out.
I didn't know
what to do.
So I ran past them
as quick as I could,
hoping they wouldn't
recognize me.
But the minute I passed,
I heard my mother say,
"oh, my God."
I died.
After the show,
I took off my makeup
and put on my clothes,
not knowing if they'd
be downstairs or what.
But there they were,
standing in the middle
of all these freaks.
You should've
seen my parents.
They didn't know
where to look.
My mother had the guts
to look me in the eyes.
I could tell
she'd been crying.
"Make sure you
eat good," she said.
But then my
father couldn't
even look at me.
"Take care of
yourself," he said.
And they started out.
But then my father
turned around
and went over
to the producer.
[Crying]
"Take care of my
son," he said.
And that was the
first time he ever
called me that.
Come on.
Zach?
You ok?
Go grab a hat.
Let's go, Larry.
Let's bring them in.
[Larry]
Ok, everybody,
we're back up onstage!
Let's go!
♪[Woman singing]
[Man]
You can, you
can, you can.
[Woman]
♪ one smile...
[All chattering]
[Larry]
Take one that fits.
Don't keep him waiting.
[Man]
All right.
[Zach]
All right, let's go
over the combination
that goes along with the
lyrics you just learned.
Everybody on stage,
and spread out.
[Larry]
Kill the work lights and,
uh, hit the rail, please.
[Man]
Is this where
he picks the 8?
This is important. I want
to see unison dancing.
Every head, arm, body
angle, exactly the same.
I don't want anybody
to pull my focus.
Ok, Larry.
[Larry]
Ok, let's review it.
Starting position
is upstage,
just to
remind you--
♪[piano playing]
Chin up,
hat down.
Pop the
right heel.
Reverse
directions.
5, 6, 7, 8!
[Chorus]
♪ one
♪ singular sensation
♪ every little
step she takes ♪
[Larry]
Ok, hold it. Hold it.
[Chorus]
♪ one...
You with us? Ok.
On "singular
sensation,"
make sure your arm
goes all the way
across your face
and back to shoulder.
3, 4!
[Chorus]
♪ singular sensation
♪ every little
step she takes ♪
♪ one
♪ thrilling combination
♪ every move that she makes
[larry]
6, 7, 8.
[Chorus]
♪ one smile and suddenly
nobody else ♪
Oh! I'm sorry.
♪ Will do
♪ you know you'll
never be lonely ♪
♪ with you-know-who
♪ one
ok, hold it.
Hold it. Let's go on,
away from the mirrors.
Excuse me.
Yeah?
After the grapevine,
when do we pop the chin?
Pop the chin on 2.
And when does
the hat go up?
Hat goes up on 5.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
Ok, listen up.
Larry's got the
exact style I'm
looking for. Very '30s.
Everybody, just keep
your eye on Larry.
Let's continue now from
"moment in her presence."
And 5, 6, 7, 8!
[Chorus]
♪ one
♪ moment in her presence
♪ and you can
forget the rest ♪
[Man]
♪ rest
♪ for the girl
is 2nd best ♪
♪ to none
♪ son
♪ ooh, sigh
♪ give her your attention
♪ do I really have
to mention ♪
♪ she's the
[out of sync]
♪ one?
[Larry]
Ok. Let me see you in
your groups of 4.
All right, this time I
want to hear the lyrics
from each group.
And 5, 6, 7, 8.
[Group 1]
♪ one
♪ singular sensation
[Group 2]
one, turn, up, down.
♪ Every little step
she takes... ♪
[Group 3]
One, turn, up, down,
spot to the right,
toe out, toe in.
Step back--
♪ one thrilling
combination ♪
♪ every move
that she makes ♪
5, 6, 7, 8.
♪ One smile,
and suddenly ♪
♪ nobody else
will-- ♪
Spot to the front,
sharp, hat.
1, 2, 3, 4,
swing around, 1, 2,
♪ you-know-who
♪ one
♪ moment in
her presence ♪
♪ and you can
forget the rest ♪
Stand in place.
♪ For the girl
is 2nd best ♪
Hat down,
turn, down,
ball change, knee,
ball change, hip,
ball change,
knee, and kick.
♪ Ooh, sigh
♪ give her
your attention ♪
♪ do I
♪ really have
to mention ♪
♪ she's
♪ the
♪ one?
[Larry]
Ok, girls.
Just the girls,
from the 2nd section.
Here we go.
5, 6, 7, 8.
[Girls]
♪ one
♪ moment in
her presence ♪
Cassie, don't roll
the shoulders.
♪ And you can
forget the rest ♪
♪ for the girl
is 2nd best ♪
Diana, sharp
in with the leg.
♪ Son
♪ ooh, sigh
♪ give her
your attention ♪
♪ do I
♪ really have
to mention ♪
♪ she's
♪ the
♪ one?
Cassie, there is no
release in the head.
[Larry]
Boys, from the top.
5, 6, 7, 8.
♪ One
Cassie.
♪ Singular sensation
do it again
with the boys.
You're still
doing too much.
♪ One
don't pop the
head, Cassie.
♪ Every move that she makes
♪ one smile, and suddenly
♪ nobody else
♪ will do
♪ you know you'll
never be lonely ♪
♪ with you-know-who
♪ one
Cassie, this
isn't Vegas.
♪ ...presence
♪ and you can
forget the rest ♪
♪ for the girl is 2nd best
[zach]
This isn't a solo,
Cassie. Look around.
Get your kicks even.
♪ Ooh, sigh
♪ give her your
attention ♪
♪ do I
♪ really have
to mention ♪
Goddamn it, Cassie,
you distorted
the combination!
Now pull it in!
♪ One?
[Larry]
Ok, everybody,
from the top.
Here we go.
5, 6, 7, 8.
♪ One
♪ singular sensation
♪ every little
step she takes ♪
♪ one
♪ thrilling
combination ♪
♪ every move
that she makes ♪
♪ one smile,
and suddenly ♪
♪ nobody else
♪ will do
♪ you know you'll
never be lonely ♪
♪ with you-know-who
♪ one
♪ moment in
her presence ♪
♪ and you can
forget the rest ♪
♪ for the girl
is 2nd best ♪
♪ to none
♪ son.
Ooh, sigh ♪
Cassie!
♪ Give her
your attention ♪
Come down here!
♪ Do I really have
to mention ♪
♪ she's
♪ the one?
♪ One smile, and suddenly
♪ nobody else
♪ will do
♪ you know you'll
never be lonely ♪
♪ with you-know-who
turn around
and look at
the routine.
Is that what
you really want?
♪ One
♪ moment in her presence
♪ and you can
forget the rest ♪
♪ for the girl is 2nd best
♪ to none
♪ son
♪ ooh, sigh
♪ give her your attention
♪ do I
♪ really have to mention
♪ she's
♪ the
♪ one?
♪ One!
♪[Piano playing]
That's who I am.
No, you're not!
You're special!
Zach, we're
all special.
Paul is special.
Bebe, Sheila,
everybody up on that
stage is special.
Goddamn it!
You know what
I'm talking about.
Look at them.
Look at them!
Why did you
leave me?
Why, Zach,
you noticed.
You at least could
have told me about
the job in Hollywood.
And what would
you tell me
if I told you?
"Take it," right?
Well, I didn't
want you to tell
me, "take it."
What are you
talking about?
You took it.
That's one thing,
my taking it.
Your telling
me "take it" is
something else.
Anyway, you're
the one who
left, not me.
Months before
I ever went
to Hollywood.
I left? We were
living together.
Sharing the same
apartment, maybe,
but when did I
ever see you?
Now what are
you giving me?
The neglected-
woman bullshit?
You jealous
of my work?
You acted so proud
of what I was--
oh, Zach, I was
proud. I still am.
And I know that
directing a show
takes 24 hours a day,
which I wanted for
you as much as--
as long as I spent
an equal 24 hours a
day with you, right?
Exactly. That's
all I wanted.
And you're going to
tell me exactly how I
could have done that?
Well, if I knew that,
then I'd be the hit,
and you'd be asking
me for a job.
[Laughs]
Cassie.
Jesus.
Don't you know
why I took that
job in Hollywood?
Not for me. For you.
It was the
only way that I
could hold you,
I thought,
was to be a
star, like you.
Make you want me again.
[Crying]
Treat me important.
Ready, Zach?
Who do you
want to pick?
I don't
know yet.
Let's do the tap
combination.
Start matching 'em up.
Ok, everybody,
for the tap
combination,
we're going to
start after the
2nd 8-count.
Girls, downstage,
boys, upstage.
Nice and easy.
And 5, 6, 7, 8.
♪[Piano playing]
♪ Kiss today good-bye
♪ the sweetness
♪ and the sorrow
♪ wish me luck
♪ the same
♪ to you
♪ but I can't regret
♪ what I did for love
♪ look, my eyes are dry
♪ the gift was ours
♪ to borrow
♪ it's as if
♪ we always
♪ knew
♪ and I won't regret
♪ what I did for love
♪ gone
♪ love is
♪ never gone
♪ as we
♪ travel on
♪ love's what we'll remember
♪ kiss today good-bye
♪ and point me
♪ toward tomorrow
♪ we did what we had
♪ to do
♪ won't forget
♪ can't regret
♪ what I did
♪ for love
♪ what I did for
♪ love
♪ what I did
♪ for
♪ love
[feet tapping]
Ok.
We're going to
put you into
groups of 4...
2 and 2.
Let me see.
Mike,
Maggie,
Paul,
Connie.
Girls, downstage,
boys, upstage.
Let's go.
Ready?
5, 6, 7, and 8.
♪[Piano playing]
Connie, smile
bigger if you're
going to fake it.
Tapping's not my
strongest point.
What?
Tapping's not my
strongest point!
I see that.
Be right back.
Ohh!
[Man]
You all right?
[Larry]
Don't move him!
Don't move--
Larry, call
Dr. rhodes.
838-1393.
[Diana]
It's his knee,
the cartilage.
He had it
operated on
last year.
Don't move him.
Maybe we should
prop something
under his knee.
[Zach]
Get his dance bag.
It's ok, really.
I just twisted it.
Does anyone
have any darvon?
Valium?
I do.
[Woman]
Somebody get
some water.
[Man]
I'll get it.
[Mark groans]
It's already swelling.
You're going to be ok,
Paul. You're going
to be just fine.
You think we should
give him that?
I mean, we don't
know what's wrong.
Please. I've had
3 already today.
Since lunch.
[Man]
It's just a muscle relaxer.
[Larry]
Zach. Rhodes is
at St. Joseph's.
He said bring
him to emergency.
He'll be waiting.
[Woman]
Where's his
dance bag?
[Diana]
Oh, I'll get it.
[Zach]
You got the knee?
Yeah, I got it.
Ok.
Paul, you're going
to be all right.
Rhodes is the
best knee doctor
in the city.
[Diana]
Paul, I got your bag.
[Man]
Good luck, Paul.
Call me from
the hospital.
Do you ever
think about what
you're going to do
if you stop
dancing?
For me?
Yeah.
Real life, I guess.
Well, what?
Getting married,
having babies?
Go off my diet.
[Women laughing]
What about you, mark?
You want to
spend your life
dancing in
the chorus?
Well, I'd
just like to
get in one.
You don't remember,
but we were in a
show together,
in a chorus, about
a hundred years ago.
Of course I remember.
You were a
rotten dancer.
[All laughing]
Why do you
think I became
a choreographer?
How you been,
Sheila?
God, since then,
I don't know.
Good, terrific,
[laughing]
Ok, so-so.
You know, I actually
found the glass
slipper once,
and it fit.
Then it broke.
I have a daughter.
She's 9.
She loves me a lot,
hates me a lot.
[Crying]
And, uh...
[Chuckles]
God help her,
she wants to
be a dancer.
[Diana]
What's so wrong
about that?
How can anybody
in their right mind
want to be
anything else?
I remember I
used to stand
outside the
stage door
and watch the
girls come out
and think, "God,
"can anything
like that ever
happen to me?"
But now, I
meet somebody,
and they say,
"wow, you dance
on Broadway?
"You got somewhere.
You're something."
[Sirens wailing in distance]
Hell of a day, huh?
Yeah.
A few months ago,
the night before I
was going to audition
for a new show,
I--I had a
kind of breakdown.
I started crying,
and I couldn't stop
for about 2 weeks.
I just now got out
of the hospital,
and my doctor
told me it was too
soon to try again.
But I did.
And now,
even if I lose,
I've won.
[Sighing]
Hell of a day.
Larry.
Line 'em up, Zach?
Yeah. Line 'em up.
Ok. Everybody
on the line.
Before we start
eliminating...
You're all terrific
and special.
Very special.
I wish I could hire
you all, but I can't.
So will the
following people
please step forward?
Judy...
[Laughs]
Don...
[Sighs]
Greg...
Sheila...
Al...
Diane.
No. Excuse me.
Diane, could you get
back in line, please?
Kristine...
Connie...
Maggie.
Front line, thank you
very much. I'm sorry.
Rehearsals will
begin September 22nd.
We're going to
rehearse for 6 weeks,
2-week out-of-town tryout,
either in Boston
or Philadelphia.
The New York opening
will be sometime
in mid-January.
Be prepared to sign a
standard minimum contract,
with a 6-month rider.
Check with Larry
to set up an appointment
for costume measurements.
Bring a dance pair
of shoes and sneakers
to all rehearsals.
Please...
Do not-- I repeat-- do
not change your hairstyle.
I'm really happy to
have you working here.
I got to say,
i'm very excited.
[Zach speaking inaudibly]
Thank you.
Very much.
Dick?
That's it.
Thanks a lot.
[Laughs]
[Zach]
Cassie.
How you dress!
You know,
you can get arrested for
wearing those colors.
[Laughing]
♪[Percussion playing]
[Chorus]
♪ one
♪ singular sensation
♪ every little
step she takes ♪
♪ one
♪ thrilling combination
♪ every move that she makes
♪ one smile, and suddenly
♪ nobody else
♪ will do
♪ you know you'll
never be lonely ♪
♪ with you-know-who
[women]
♪ she walks into a room
♪ and you know she's
uncommonly rare ♪
♪ very unique, peripatetic,
poetic, and chic ♪
♪ she walks into a room
♪ and you know
from her... ♪
♪ maddening poise,
effortless whirl ♪
♪ she's a special girl
[man]
♪ strolling
[men]
♪ can't help
♪ all of her qualities
♪ extolling
[all]
♪ loaded with charisma is
my jauntily sauntering ♪
♪ ambling shambler
[men]
♪ one
[women]
♪ she walks into a room
♪ moment in her presence
♪ and you know you must
♪ shuffle along,
join the parade ♪
♪ she's the quintessence
of making the grade ♪
♪ for the girl
is 2nd best ♪
♪ to none
♪ so, strut your stuff
♪ son
♪ can't get enough
♪ ooh, sigh
♪ of
♪ give her your attention
♪ her
♪ do I
♪ love
♪ really have to mention
♪ her
♪ she's
♪ I'm a son of a gun
♪ the
♪ she is one of a
♪ one
♪ kind
[chorus]
♪ one
♪ singular sensation
♪ every little
step she takes ♪
♪ one
♪ thrilling combination
♪ every move that she makes
♪ one smile, and suddenly
♪ nobody else
♪ will do
♪ you know you'll
never be lonely ♪
♪ with you-know-who
♪ one
♪ moment in her presence
♪ and you can
forget the rest ♪
♪ for the girl is 2nd best
♪ to none
♪ son
♪ ooh, sigh
♪ give her your attention
♪ do I
♪ really have to mention
♪ she's
♪ the
♪ one?
♪ One
♪ moment in her presence
♪ and you can
forget the rest ♪
♪ for the girl is 2nd best
♪ to none
♪ son
♪ ooh, sigh
♪ give her your attention
♪ do I
♪ really have to mention
♪ she's
♪ the
♪ one?