(♪ BAND WARMING UP)
(PEOPLE TALKING)
(MAN)
Okay, one more time from the top.
Six beats, all right?
One, two, three, four. One, two...
(♪ UPBEAT JAZZ)
(♪ ENDING FLOURISH)
(MAN COUGHING)
(♪ VIVALDI: "CONCERTO IN G MAJOR")
(MAN) To be on the wire is life.
The rest is waiting.
(WOMAN)
That's very theatrical, Joe.
- (JOE) Yeah, I know.
- Did you make it up?
I wish I had.
- Do you like it?
- Well, it's all right.
It's showtime, folks!
(♪ "ON BROADWAY")
♪ They say the neon lights
are bright on Broadway ♪
♪ They say there's always
magic in the air ♪
♪ But when you're walking
down that street ♪
♪ And you ain't had enough to eat ♪
♪ The glitter rubs right off ♪
♪ And you're nowhere ♪
(♪ VOCALIZING)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
♪ They say the women
treat you fine ♪
♪ On Broadway ♪
♪ But looking at them ♪
♪ Just gives me the blues ♪
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
♪ 'Cause how you gonna
make some time ♪
♪ When all you've got
is one thin dime ♪
♪ And one thin dime
won't even shine ♪
♪ Your shoes ♪
(♪ VOCALIZING)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
♪ They say that
I won't last too long ♪
♪ On Broadway ♪
♪ I'll catch the Greyhound bus
for home ♪
♪ They all say ♪
♪ But they're dead wrong
I know they are ♪
♪ 'Cause I can play
this here guitar ♪
♪ And I won't quit till I'm a star ♪
♪ On Broadway ♪
(♪ SCATTING)
(♪ SCATTING CONTINUES)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
♪ They say that
I won't last too long ♪
♪ On Broadway ♪
"Autumn." Is that your real name?
Yes, sir.
Sure you don't want to change that?
Well, if you give me the job,
I'll change it.
♪ But they're dead wrong
I know they are ♪
♪ 'Cause I can play
this here guitar ♪
♪ And I won't quit
till I'm a star ♪
"Victoria Porter."
Is this your, uh...
your home phone?
♪ Till I'm a star ♪
♪ On Broadway ♪
♪ No, no, no, no, no ♪♪
You were in The Wiz?
I've never been
in any show in my life.
I had to put something.
I really need a job, so I lied.
That's all right.
I lie all the time myself.
Oh, fuck him. He never picks me.
I did fuck him,
and he never picks me either.
- You were in Traffic Jam?
- Yes, sir.
Who was the director
of Traffic Jam?
- You were, Mr. Gideon.
- Oh. How was I?
- Terrific.
- And who was the choreographer?
- You were, Mr. Gideon.
- How was I?
- Fantastic.
- That's how you get a job.
God! I hope he doesn't pick her.
She's uglier than a witch's tit.
The expression is
"colder than a witch's tit."
How would you know?
You've never seen a woman's tit.
Shh! Be quiet.
Okay. Thank you all very much.
It was a terrific audition.
Just stay in line. (GROANS)
(♪ VOCALIZING CONTINUES)
(JOE) Now, that's what I call
a real drinker's nose.
And you should know, because
you're a real drinker, aren't you?
Yeah.
- Also heavy into speed, aren't you?
- Yeah.
Also sleep with a great many women.
Real turn-off, huh?
Just the opposite.
I'll make up my mind about the men later,
but I know which girls I want now...
Candy, Casey, Rima, Jennifer,
and Victoria Porter.
- In the shocking pink leotard?
- Yeah.
See if any are willing
to be swing dancers.
- She's tone-deaf, Joey.
- With those legs, who cares?
Joey, I know you're in a hurry.
- I just want to check your schedule.
- Same as always.
Joey? Joey, can we talk
a minute, please?
(COUGHING)
- Joey...
- What is it?
- What about Diane?
- You left me without a soprano again!
Paul, please, please,
will you let me handle it?
- What about Diane?
- I've had her in three shows. She's wonderful.
- She's wonderful.
- He needs a soprano.
- You left me without a soprano.
I gotta have a soprano!
Gentlemen,
Mr. Gideon will make up...
The tall dancer on stage right...
with the blue eye shadow...
he'll hit the high notes.
Tovar, Narin-Smith...
The five Murray is talking to are
the girls I want. Okay with you?
(GIRL) The tall girl, Victoria...
I like her, Daddy.
Mm, she's all right.
Oh, I really screwed up
that marriage.
Because I cheated. Oh, man,
I cheated every chance I could get.
Okay with you, Audrey?
Sure, fine with me. What about
this weekend with Michelle?
Oh, Jesus! I forgot.
I gotta work this weekend.
Oh, Joe, you promised her!
I know I promised,
but what am I gonna do?
That's okay.
- I'm sorry, Michelle.
- That's okay.
If you want me,
I'll be in the cutting room.
He promised me.
Some fucking father!
- Family?
- (JOE) Screwed up.
- Work?
- All there is.
If I were God, man...
- sometimes I think I am...
- (AUDIENCE CHUCKLING)
Depends on the shit you're smoking.
Mm, okay.
If I were God, man...
everybody would live forever.
No death, man!
(IMITATES TRUMPET FANFARE)
No pennies on the eyes for anybody.
Well, there are a couple people, like my
agent, who booked me into this toilet.
Why is he mumbling like that?
I'll tell you why: 'Cause I'm the
dummy who let him mumble like that.
- Right.
- Shh!
- death and the clap.
- (AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
- So far I've managed to avoid one of them.
You know, man, death is
really a hip thing now.
But we all have very
different feelings about it.
For instance, to a Catholic,
death is a promotion.
- (AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
- Excuse me, Stacy.
Women.
Uh...
hope?
There's all this bullshit
about death with dignity.
You know what death with dignity is?
You don't drool.
Change-of-pace time.
Request. Here we go.
Vic O'Dante. Hey!
Beauty?
- (CHUCKLES) You're a flirt.
- Mm-hmm.
♪ Death is in, death is in ♪
♪ Hear them church bells ring ♪
Ah, I love it, I love it, I love it.
Books, magazine articles,
TV shows...
Ken and Barbie dolls
who have a mutual suicide pact.
How many times do we have
to look at the same thing?
Until he gets it
the way he wants it.
There's a lady in Chicago, man,
wrote a book...
Dr. Kubler-Ross, with a dash.
This chick, man...
without the benefit
of dying herself...
has broken the process of death
into five stages...
anger, denial, bargaining,
depression, and acceptance.
Sounds like a Jewish law firm.
(IMITATING RECEPTIONIST) "Good morning. Anger,
Denial, Bargaining, Depression, Acceptance."
Anger.
"Jesus Christ!
Goddamn son-of-a-bitch
pig-fucking bastards!
- Oh, poo!"
- (MOCK SNORING)
Bargaining.
What did I say? Anger, denial,
bargaining, depression, acceptance.
If you happen to get to denial...
denial... "No.
No, that's not me, man. No.
Oh, ho-ho!
Somebody else, maybe,
but not me. Oh, no.
You got the wrong...
How about my mother, man?
She's old, I'm weaned, I'm toilet-trained.
I don't need her anymore.
'Bye, Ma. You've been terrific.
I love ya, but not me!"'
(WOMAN) Mother.
Kind of chubby. And jolly.
And sexy.
- Bargaining! Remember her?
- (AUDIENCE CHEERING)
"Can we sit down and talk
about this like businessmen?
A negotiation, okay?
No more hard drugs.
A little grass, maybe,
but that's it.
Okay? Look, I promise I won't
flash on subways anymore, okay?"
Cat drives a hard bargain.
Depression.
Hi, Katie.
"I'm dying!
Oh, God, am I dying!
Do you want to have dinner together
before I go to the theater?
- I can't.
- The doctor's not dying!
Should I come over
to your apartment later?
- Yeah, sure.
- (WOMAN) Father?
Liar, cheat, womanizer.
You would've liked him.
Wait a minute. We may be
working very late tonight.
- That's okay.
- Yeah.
- (COUGHS) We'll talk later.
- ...for this hospital room!
- (MOUTHS WORDS)
- At those prices, man, who can afford to live?
So...
acceptance.
- "I accept..."
- Hold it.
- Hold it, Irv.
- You finished, or run it again?
No, I do not want to run it again,
thank you. We are finished.
- Thank you, Irv.
- Anybody have any ideas?
I like it, Joe.
I think it's really funny.
Who asked you, Stacy?
It's too long. I don't know.
Maybe we can get away with it.
Do you suppose Stanley Kubrick
ever gets depressed?
- (MAN) You want to work tonight, Joe?
- (JOE) No. I wish I could...
but I gotta work on the show.
(♪ ACOUSTIC GUITAR)
♪ It's the perfect ♪
- You have really got something special.
- ♪ Way ♪
All right.
I want so to be a movie star.
Oh?
Ever since I was a little kid...
I wanted to see
my face on the screen...
40 feet wide.
Oh, yeah?
♪ It's the perfect way ♪
(SOUTHERN ACCENT)
"I have always depended...
on the kindness of strangers."
You're looking at my nose,
aren't you?
- Hmm?
- It's crooked.
It goes to the left. See?
I mean, like, I could always
have it fixed, like that.
Do you think I could be?
- Huh?
- You know.
A movie star, I mean.
In the movies.
Well, that's...
I don't know anybody that
could answer that question.
It's...
It's a very freaky business,
you know?
Yeah, I know all about that,
but, like...
I want to know what you think.
Do you think I could be
a movie star?
No.
Even with a nose job?
Well, that's fair.
(CHUCKLES) Like you said,
it is a freaky business, though.
You know,
you could be wrong, right?
Right.
I don't dance so hot either, do I?
You will. I promise you.
You want to go to bed?
Yeah.
♪ To end a perfect ♪
♪ Day ♪
(BUZZING)
♪ It's the perfect ♪
♪ Way ♪
♪ Yay-yay ♪
♪ To say ♪
♪ I... ♪
♪ Love you ♪♪
(DOG BARKING)
- I'm sorry.
- (DOG WHINING)
- Oh, am I sorry.
- Katie!
I should have called first.
Oh, shit!
Did I, like, screw anything up?
No.
I screwed it up.
Oh, I meant to call her.
Oh, boy, you are really something.
(LAUGHING)
(♪ BURLESQUE)
I'm Joey's mother.
Ever since he was so high,
he's had such a crush on you!
(CHUCKLES)
I've always been fond of Joe too.
(MOTHER) Of all the children,
he was the least worry.
He worked in all those
cheap burlesque clubs.
Always around stark-naked girls.
(LAUGHS) But did it bother him? No.
He never paid any attention.
Never even looked at them.
Amatis: "you love."
Amant: "they love."
Amo, amas, amat...
amamus, amatis, amant.
Hey, kid.
What kind of language is that?
Oh, it's not a language.
Just some jokes I'm working on.
Some crazy jokes.
(♪ BURLESQUE CONTINUES)
"Pu..." "Pu..."
Puella. "Girl."
Oh.
First-year Latin?
It's my kid brother's.
- How old are you?
- Nineteen.
Uh-huh. What year were you born?
Uh, 19... uh... 30...
Try 1934.
- Right. 1934.
- 1935?
(LAUGHING) Yeah, 1935, yeah.
Now try 1492.
See ya around, kid.
Maybe we could have a drink
together sometime.
Oh, sure.
You notice we have these small
waitresses here, right?
You know why?
Make the drinks look bigger.
- That's my favorite one...
the one with the big tips.
- (♪ RIM SHOT)
I got problems too. The other day
I went to see my psychiatrist.
I told him I have suicidal tendencies.
He says, "From now on, pay in advance."
- (♪ RIM SHOT)
- I don't have to do this for a living.
I have four chinchillas
at home in heat.
I make a lot of money
I just have trouble passing it.
Is this on?
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
First-year Latin!
It's 3:00 in the morning.
Isn't it past your beddy time?
I don't look for big laughs.
I'll settle for intelligent nods.
Anything. Wink.
You'd better stop lying
or your nose will grow.
Ooh! Something's growing.
The drummer's not really with the band,
but he has the car. Married 14 years.
Fourteen years. No children.
Strict mother-in-law.
Let's continue on. Right
now, ladies and gentlemen...
here he is, tops in taps...
may we present Mr. Joe Gideon!
- (♪ UPBEAT)
- You're on.
(MEN LAUGHING)
(♪ ENDS)
(♪ REPRISE)
Joey's never done anything
to disappoint me.
(♪ VIVALDI: "CONCERTO IN G MAJOR")
(SIGHS)
It's showtime, folks.
- Do you believe in love?
- I believe in saying "I love you."
Helps you concentrate.
(KATIE) Joe, they've asked me
to go on tour with the show.
How long?
Six months. What do you think?
- And you say it all the time.
- (CHUCKLES) I say it a lot. A lot.
- When?
- When it works.
You know I love you, Katie...
but I think you have to do
what's best for you.
Just what do you mean?
Sometimes it doesn't work.
I mean, for your sake...
I think you should go.
Hello, Michael? It's Katie.
(CHUCKLES) So...
did you mean it about dinner?
Wally's at 11:00? You're surprised?
I'm a little surprised.
(CHUCKLES) Thank you.
Okay, Michael. Bye-bye.
I'm a little surprised too.
Isn't that nice?
Now we're all a little surprised.
- Who was that?
- Michael Graham.
- Who is Michael Graham?
- A dancer in my ballet class.
Straight? Or gay?
- What do you mean?
- (CHUCKLES)
I mean,
is he looking to get laid...
or is he looking for Mr. Right?
He's straight.
And tall.
"Michael Graham"
is a very tall name.
(ANGRY CHORTLING) Goddamn it!
How dare you use my phone...
my telephone...
to call somebody who's not gay?
I... You can go out with any girl...
any girl in town.
That's right.
I go out with any girl in town.
- I stay in with you.
- Joe, it's not... oh, shit!
I'm spilling everything...
the coffee... It's all wrong.
Everything is all wrong.
(CHUCKLING) That's some set
of rules you had for her.
Yeah, I know. I know.
As long as you could
get away with it, right?
Right.
I don't want to go out with Michael
Graham. I don't want to date.
I have no more small talk left.
I don't want to fool around...
I don't want to play games,
and I don't want to fight.
I just want to love you.
Katie...
I try to give you
everything I can give.
Oh, you give, all right...
presents, clothes.
I just wish...
you weren't so generous
with your cock.
That's good!
Maybe I can use that sometime.
(♪ OFF)
Katie, about the goddamn tour...
I don't think you should go.
Wrong reading.
(SNIFFLES)
Softly and with feeling.
Don't go.
Please?
(JOE) Why do you suppose
she put up with it?
Oh, I can think of many reasons
for wanting to be with you.
Now, don't bullshit a bullshitter.
(♪ JAUNTY)
♪ Take off with us
Take off with us ♪
♪ We're warming up
so take off with us ♪
♪ N.Y. to L.A.-yay-yay ♪
♪ Goin' all the way-yay-yay ♪
♪ Won't you climb aboard ♪
♪ You'll ride as smooth as glass ♪
It's perfect! Didn't I tell you?
♪ Up there where
the clouds are pillow-y ♪
♪ You're as close to heaven
as you'll ever be ♪
♪ Lean back, relax
Here come the snacks ♪
♪ Drop your diet
Have a ball ♪
♪ Don't stop with one ♪
♪ Try 'em all ♪
♪ Music's ready to begin ♪
♪ Take out your headset
Plug it in ♪
♪ What's your answer, chu-u-um ♪
- Just what the show needs.
- ♪ Are you gonna co-o-ome ♪
♪ On the coolest, hottest trip ♪
♪ That's ever been ♪♪
- (♪ PIANO GLISSANDO)
- (PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
Whoa! It's very, very good!
I think we might even get a
commercial tie-in with the airlines.
- (OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
- Audrey?
Uh, ask, uh...
Yeah, it's okay. Uh...
let me see what I can do with it.
I think it's just what the show needs.
It's catchy, it's bouncy. Right, Ted?
Yeah, it's very bouncy and catchy.
- Could we hear it again?
- (TED) I'd love to.
- Oh! Arnie...
- (♪ RESUMES)
Turn. That is some fucking music.
Turn back.
Arch your back.
Extend the right leg.
Ease your partner down gently.
Slide. Slide.
Slide!
(JOE) Have you ever slept
with another woman?
I once tried living with two
girls... two girls at once.
We lived together.
- Laughed together.
- Drank together.
Smoked together.
- (♪ UPBEAT)
- Slept together.
- Woke up one morning...
- (♪ SLIDE WHISTLE)
one of them was gone.
On the bureau, she left a note.
I'm sorry.
I cannot share you anymore.
I want you all to myself...
or not at all.
Please. Please try to understand.
I not only understood, I...
I was flattered.
I was flattered that she felt
so strongly about me.
How did you know
the note was to you?
(CHUCKLING)
(COMEDIAN) "No. No, that's
not me, man. No. Oh, ho-ho!
Somebody else, maybe, but not me."
- What is this, Eddie?
- Got me. Talk to him.
Joey, I gotta talk to you
about these time sheets.
Three weeks now
we've been on triple-time.
The brass is eating my ass out!
You shot 82 days
on a 65-day schedule.
On a four-month editing schedule,
you've gone seven months.
We're already two million, two
over the original budget.
Joey, God made
the entire world in six days.
He didn't go on overtime once.
You can't even cut
an hour-and-a-half movie...
in seven months, on triple-time?
Joey, I hate to do this.
I'm usually a very calm man...
but this whole thing
has got me terribly crazy.
I must put my foot down.
The whole thing has gotta stop.
It has to stop. It's got to stop!
It just simply must stop!
Josh, I made a few changes in the
monologue. I think you'll like it.
I have to go to rehearsal.
- At those prices, who can afford to live?
- See you at 5:30, Eddie.
Nice talking to you, Josh.
So I accept!
Oh, my God. It is better.
- God help us all.
- Wait a minute. Real dead body.
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
It's better.
Okay, that looks good. I like it.
Everybody down, in a straight line.
Come on. Here we go.
Move down, move down.
Move down, Victoria.
And sing it out. Here we go.
Five, six, seven, eight.
♪ And any seat ♪
♪ You grab will be first-class ♪
Two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight. And I don't like it.
(♪ SYNCOPATED ELECTRONIC BEATS)
(DRUMMING ON THIGHS)
Uh, double that.
- Which button?
- The white one. Down.
- (♪ BEAT ACCELERATES)
- (DRUMMING ON THIGHS)
That stinks. Let's try something
else. Do me a favor.
Take off your shoes.
What's that?
- It's a mint.
- Can I have one?
No. Come on. You wouldn't like it.
Let me try this.
Here, you stand over here and
then jump up on my shoulder.
(GROANS) God, you're getting heavy!
Put your leg in an arabesque.
There we are.
- How are things at home?
- Pretty good.
All right.
All right, watch your back, now.
- Anything you want to tell me?
- I promised Mom I wouldn't bring it up.
(LAUGHING) But you're gonna
bring it up anyway.
Sit down, Michelle.
You can tell me anything.
Gimme your wrists. Ready, and...
jump!
It's just that
I keep wondering, Dad...
Bend your knees.
What is it you keep wondering?
Why don't you get married again?
Do a head roll.
I don't get married again
because I can't find anyone...
I dislike enough...
to inflict that kind of torture on.
Hey, why don't you marry Katie?
She's terrific.
Keep rolling your head.
Straighten your leg.
Yeah, you're right. She's terrific.
That's exactly why
I don't want to marry her.
(COUGHING) Run off in the corner
and jump, and I'll catch you.
What about Victoria?
You're not too crazy about her.
Just run and jump. Never mind that.
Come on. And... (GRUNTS)
- What about the blonde?
- What blonde?
The one in Philadelphia
with the television show?
You know, the one
Mom keeps talking about.
- Oh, yeah. That blonde.
- Mm-hmm.
Jump up and wrap
your legs around me.
Wrap around. That's it.
Why is it so important to you that...
Follow my hand.
Why is it so important
that I get married again?
'Cause then you'd settle down
and stop screwing around.
Hey! Watch your language.
- (LAUGHING)
- Oh, shit!
- Look at the time.
- Can't we stay a little longer?
- No, your mother will kill me.
- It's so much fun!
- No. Absolutely. Come on.
- Just five minutes!
Stop flocking your legs. Come on!
- I'll get you home.
- Please?
No, no, no, no.
Besides,
if you got married again...
maybe you'd have a baby,
and I'd have a little brother.
I'll call Hertz
and rent you a brother.
- Very funny.
- Oh, everybody's a critic.
(COUGHING)
(♪ "TAKE OFF WITH US")
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
(♪ VIVALDI: "CONCERTO IN G MAJOR")
Showtime, folks.
Showtime.
- Five, six, seven, eight.
- (♪ UPBEAT JAZZ)
Stop smiling. Lay back.
Lay back!
Hold it, hold it, hold it.
Candy, Casey, very good.
You're gonna do it again, Victoria.
Gary, Danny, let's go.
Stop smiling.
It's not the high-school play.
- Count.
- Five, six, seven, eight.
- (♪ RESUMES)
- Hold it.
(♪ STOPS)
Stand on your right foot.
Point your left toe.
Drop that shoulder.
Now, that's not too hard, is it?
Again. (COUGHS, SNIFFLES)
- Five, six, seven, eight.
- (♪ RESUMES)
Lay back, Victoria.
Lay back! Lay back!
- Hold it, hold it.
- (♪ STOPS)
(SOBBING)
- I'm sorry.
- No, you're right.
I'm terrible. I know I'm terrible.
I look in the mirror,
and I'm embarrassed.
Maybe I should quit.
I... I just can't...
seem to do anything right.
Listen, I can't make you
a great dancer.
I don't even know
if I can make you a good dancer.
But if you keep trying
and don't quit...
I know I can make you
a better dancer.
And I... I'd like
very much to do that.
Stay?
Are you gonna keep yelling at me?
Probably.
Five, six, seven, eight.
One and two...
Three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, one, two.
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, one, two.
(♪ ENDS)
(COUGHING)
- Better. (COUGHING)
- (WOMAN) All right!
(ALL CHEERING)
Breathe deep. Again.
(HACKING COUGH) Hold it.
All right, you can turn around now.
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
Breathe deep.
Again.
All right, you can put
your shirt on now.
Well, Doctor? Does he pass?
(HACKING COUGH)
Good.
Now I'm worth a million dollars.
That's only if you die
before February 1.
Schedules, Goldie...
always schedules.
Can we take you to lunch, Doctor?
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
(CHUCKLING)
♪ And any seat ♪
- ♪ You grab will be first-class ♪
- One, two, three, four...
- five, six, seven, eight.
- (♪ ENDS)
Nah, that's no good either.
Let's try this.
(PHONE RINGING)
- There's your 412th.
- I do the same as before?
Yeah, same thing,
only I'll be behind you. Ready?
♪ And any seat you grab ♪
♪ Will be first-class ♪
Two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
(COUGHING)
All right, let's everybody try it.
Grab a partner.
Sandahl, you do it alone.
Okay, here we go. Ready?
Five, six, seven...
♪ And any seat you grab ♪
♪ Will be first-class ♪
And feet together.
Five, six, seven, eight.
(♪ ENDS)
Do it again.
Once more, everybody.
Ready? Five, six, seven...
♪ And any seat you grab ♪
♪ Will be first-class ♪
Three, four, five,
six, seven, eight.
(♪ ENDS)
(COUGHING)
Okay.
Okay, once more, everybody.
I gotta get out of here.
I'll be back later. (COUGHING)
(♪ MID-TEMPO)
- How does this look, Paul?
- I love it. Love it.
No. It's too cute.
(PAUL EXCLAIMING)
(GASPS) Oh, shit! (INHALES SHARPLY)
(COUGHING)
I can't go back to that room.
I can't face those dancers.
I'm stuck.
They keep staring at me,
and nothing's coming out.
- Oh, boy, that number's lousy!
- (PAUL) My song? Lousy?
No, not the song. Me, me.
The way I'm staging it.
- Maybe we should cut it.
- (PAUL) "Cut it"?
I think I'll leave.
Paul, sit right there.
Go back to bar 17.
- And...
- (♪ RESUMES)
Did you hear what I said?
Nothing is coming.
Don't worry, Paul.
He always says the same thing
about every number in every show.
How the hell do you know
what I always say?
(PAUL) Don't you think it would
be better if I stepped outside?
Keep playing, Paul.
I'm only doing this show because you want
to play that stupid 24-year-old girl.
(SARCASTIC LAUGH)
I knew sooner or later
you'd say that.
You do think
I'm too old for the part.
Well, you're wrong.
I can play 24 years old...
and I'll damn well prove it.
You want to quit the show?
Quit the show.
You don't have to do
anything for me...
but just don't kid yourself
that you're doing this show...
for any other reason
except guilt about me.
Guilt? What guilt?
For never going one day
when you were faithful to me.
Oh. That guilt.
Faithful, faithful!
You're always talking
about being faithful.
Audrey, why do you think so small?
Besides, how do I know
you were faithful to me?
Oh, you know I was.
That's right. I know you were.
Oh! You meant to do that.
Yes, I did.
You kept me working all the time.
I never had a chance to cheat.
What is this big hang-up
you've got about fidelity?
What makes you think
that being faithful...
is the greatest friggin' virtue
in the world?
Excuse me. Well...
it is a great deal better
than those...
meaningless affairs
you keep tap-dancing through...
those Stacys, those Victorias.
You're not even fooling Michelle
with Victoria, you know.
Straighten that leg.
(LAUGHING) It is as straight
as it's ever going to get.
Oh! The Boonies...
the Wendys, the Debbies,
the Donnas...
I can't even remember all their
names. Give me a hand.
Keep playing, Paul.
Bet you can't either.
Quick, tell me: What was the name
of the girl in Philadelphia...
the blonde
with the television show?
Ah. The blonde
with the television show.
The blonde in Philadelphia?
I remember that girl's name.
I remember because
that girl meant something to me.
The blonde with the television
show, her name was Sweetheart.
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
- Honey?
- No.
Baby?
I can't remember her name.
(WHISPERS) Dorothy.
- Dorothy.
- Who cares?
I can't remember her name.
The number's looking good.
Keep working.
- Is he gonna cut the number?
- (LAUGHING) No, I don't think so, Paul.
He's gonna cut it.
Oh, God, that man!
He's gonna drive me crazy.
(♪ VIVALDI: "CONCERTO IN G MAJOR")
It's showtime, folks.
(INDISTINCT)
It's, uh...
It's not quite ready yet.
And, uh, Paul...
it's not exactly the way
we talked about it.
- Hmm?
- It's a little different.
- You mind doing that somewhere else?
- Sorry.
If you want to come in,
I'll show you in five minutes.
I want to get a drink of water.
(RETCHING)
(♪ DRUMBEAT)
(♪ WHISTLING)
(♪ PIANO RIFF)
♪ Take off with us-s-s-s-s ♪
- ♪ We're warmin' up, so ♪
- ♪ We're warmin' up ♪
♪ N.Y. to L.A.-yay-yay ♪
♪ Going all the way-yay-yay ♪
♪ Won't you climb aboard ♪
♪ You'll ride as smooth as ♪
♪ Glas-s-s-s ♪
♪ Meet our friendly eager crew ♪
♪ They only live to service you ♪
- ♪ Service, service, service, service ♪
- ♪ Service you, service you ♪
♪ This flight
This flight comes complete ♪
♪ With your choice of seat ♪
♪ And any seat you grab ♪
♪ Will be first-class-s-s-s-s ♪
♪ Up there
where the clouds are pillow-y ♪
♪ You're as close to heaven
as you'll ever be ♪
♪ Lean back, relax ♪
♪ Here come the snacks ♪
♪ Drop your diet
Have a ball ♪
♪ Don't stop, don't stop
don't stop with one ♪
♪ Try 'em all ♪
- ♪ Try 'em all ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Music's ready to begin ♪
♪ Take out your headset
Plug it in ♪
♪ What's your answer, chu-u-um ♪
♪ Are you gonna co-o-ome ♪
♪ On the coolest, hottest ♪
♪ Coolest, hottest ♪
♪ Coolest, hottest trip ♪
- ♪ That's ever been ♪
- ♪ Don't you, don't you, don't you,
don't you wanna go higher now ♪
♪ Don't you, don't you, don't you
- ♪ Fly, fly, fly, fly ♪
- ♪ Don't you, don't you, don't you,
don't you wanna go higher now ♪
♪ Lean back, relax ♪♪
Thanks, thanks a lot,
but it's not exactly over yet.
- Murray?
- Smoke, smoke...
- smoke, smoke.
- (PEOPLE COUGHING)
The lights go down, and a
light comes up over there.
- (♪ SLOW BASS)
- Welcome.
Welcome aboard Airotica.
(SEDUCTIVELY) ♪ Take off with us ♪
Flying not only coast-to-coast...
(WOMAN) But anywhere your desires
and fantasies wish to take you.
♪ Take off with us ♪
Let us all get to know one another.
(WOMAN) Remember:
We can take you anywhere.
- (JONESY) They're taking their clothes off.
- (JOE) Mm-hmm.
Just reach out your hand
and introduce yourselves.
- My name is Sandahl.
- My name is Autumn.
- My name is Jennifer.
- My name is Rima.
- Gary.
- John.
(♪ DRAMATIC)
Uh-oh.
I think we just lost
the family audience.
- My name is Candace.
- My name is Jennifer.
- My name is Rima.
- My name is Danny.
- My name is Autumn.
- My name is Sandahl.
- My name is John.
- My name is Gary.
(♪ PERCUSSIVE BEAT)
And don't forget about our
group fun-fun-fun plan.
(GROANS)
Now Sinatra will never record it.
(♪ ENDS)
Then an actor comes out from the
side of the stage and says...
"Not once during any of our
flights..." (CONTINUES, INDISTINCT)
- Good-bye.
- See you around.
- Hope to see you again soon.
- It was nice to have met you.
- You mean a lot to me.
- Well, uh...
- Good-bye.
- "Our motto is...
'We take you everywhere
but get you nowhere."'
(♪ CACOPHONOUS)
(JONESY)
I hate to hurt his feelings...
- but we can't have that on a stage.
- (MURRAY) Take five?
- (JOE) Sure.
- Take five.
(COUGHING)
Well?
Eh, it's, um...
It's, uh...
interesting.
Mm, yes. Very interesting.
Did you like it?
- It's unusual.
- Mm-hmm. Very unusual.
Ooh, I don't think they liked it.
What do you think?
I don't know about the audiences...
but I think it's the best work
you've ever done.
You son of a bitch.
Jesus Christ! Sex, sex, sex!
Can't he ever think
of anything else but sex?
(TED) It's a sickness.
Nah. Nothing I ever do
is good enough.
It's not beautiful enough,
it's not funny enough...
it's not deep enough,
it's not anything enough.
Now, when I see a rose,
that's perfect.
I mean, that's perfect.
I want to look up to God and say,
"How the hell did you do that...
and why the hell can't I?"
That's probably
one of your better con lines.
It is, but that doesn't mean
I don't mean it.
- (PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
- (COMEDIAN) If I were God...
sometimes I think I am...
Depends on the shit you're smoking.
If I were God, man...
everybody would live forever.
No death, man. No pennies
on the eyes for anybody.
You know, man, death is
really a hip thing now.
Death is in.
- Books, magazine articles, TV shows...
- It's terrific!
Ken and Barbie dolls
who have a mutual suicide pact.
Bury them in a little shoebox.
Knew a guy who bought a pair.
- He was into doll necrophilia.
- (PEOPLE LAUGHING)
If it cooks!
All right, little thing! Whoo!
It's terrific!
There's a lady in Chicago, man,
wrote a book...
Dr. Kubler-Ross, with a dash.
This chick, man, without the
benefit of dying herself...
has broken the process of death
into five stages...
anger, denial, bargaining,
depression, and acceptance.
- That's it. Eddie.
- Kill it, Irv.
- Got time to make some changes?
- Not and make the screening tonight, no.
- I cannot believe people are gonna see this.
- (WHISPERING) Neither can I.
- It's a bomb.
- Really?
Yeah, really. You're gonna
have to make a speech.
Tell 'em it's a rough cut,
we're not finished yet...
- or any excuse you can think of.
- Why don't you tell 'em?
- I'm not gonna be there.
- You're not coming to the screening?
- Where you gonna be?
- Hiding someplace.
Probably vomiting or
drinking... or both.
We'll start recutting
Monday morning.
They really bought that love story?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I wasn't answering the phone.
I think they told me they liked it.
Just wasn't answering the phone.
Come on.
Don't bullshit a bullshitter.
No, I don't believe you would.
I'll have her home by 10:30.
Don't worry.
- Bye.
- (PHONE HANGS UP)
- (PHONE RINGING)
- Oh, shit!
Hello. Stacy?
Oh, listen. I'm sorry.
I'm in a meeting.
Just don't panic on the staircase.
At least three people said how
much they liked the screening.
(BOTH CHEERING)
One was my producer...
one was my lawyer,
and one was Michelle's mother.
(KATIE) Joe, everybody loved it.
We tried to tell you that last
night. You wouldn't listen.
That was the first R-rated movie
I ever saw, and I loved it.
- Did you understand it?
- Well, I understood everything...
except the part where the two girls
were in bed together kissing.
What was that supposed to mean?
- Is dinner ready yet?
- No.
- What was that supposed to mean?
- Well, Michelle...
uh, there are certain women who...
- Who...? (SNICKERS)
- Thanks a lot.
Yeah. (LAUGHING)
There are certain women who just...
don't relate to men, so they...
I think lesbian scenes
are a big turn-off.
(LAUGHING)
You're right: I should've cut it.
- What's goin' on here?
- Never mind. You'll find out.
- Couldn't I be doin' something?
- Just sit there and turn off
the lights when we tell you.
- Turn on the phonograph when we tell you.
- Yes, ma'am.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, no! No, don't...
- Where'd you get those hats?
- We're not telling you.
- That's for us to know and you to find out.
- Get back!
- The lights!
- Joe, could you turn off the lights?
Now turn on those
whatchamacallit lights.
Yes, ma'am.
(♪ BOTH IMITATING DRUMROLL)
Crash! Ladies and
gentlemen, in honor...
of "el stink-o,"
"el blotto" screening...
of Joe Gideon's new film,
The Stand-up...
we are proud to present...
those two dancing sensations,
Jagger and Gideon...
- Gideon and Jagger!...
give us our music, Joe...
in an under-rehearsed tribute.
- Sit down, Joe.
- Sit down, Daddy.
- (AUDIENCE CHEERING)
- (♪ PIANO: JAUNTY)
And... go!
- I'm nervous.
- I'm nervous too.
- Wait for it.
Let's go, let's go!
(MAN) ♪ When trumpets were mellow ♪
♪ And everyone
only had one fellow ♪
♪ No need to remember when ♪
♪ 'Cause everything old
is new again ♪
♪ I said everything old
♪ Dancin' at your Long Island
jazz-age parties ♪
♪ Waiter, let me have
some more Bacardis ♪
♪ Let's order now
what they ordered then ♪
♪ 'Cause everything old
is new again ♪
- ♪ Get out your white suit
your tap shoes and tails ♪
- Scoop, scoop.
- ♪ Let's go backward when forward fails ♪
- Great timing. Strut.
- I know.
- ♪ Movie stars that you
thought were long dead ♪
- Look familiar, Joe?
- ♪ Now are framed beside your bed ♪
♪ Don't throw the past away ♪
♪ You might need it
some rainy day ♪
♪ Dreams can come true again ♪
♪ 'Cause everything old
is new again ♪
♪ I said everything old
♪ Get out the tap shoes
the tap shoes and tails ♪
- ♪ Let's go backward when forward fails ♪
- Hop! Hop! Hop!
- ♪ Leave Greta Garbo alone ♪
- Strut! Strut!
- Go get him!
- ♪ Be a movie star on your own ♪
♪ And don't throw ♪
♪ Don't throw the past away ♪
♪ Oh, we're all gonna need it
some rainy day ♪
♪ Dreams can come true again ♪
♪ When everything old
is new again ♪
- ♪ I said everything old is new again ♪
- Pretty pictures.
♪ I might fall ♪
- ♪ In love ♪
- Watch your feet.
♪ In love ♪
♪ With ♪
♪ You again ♪♪
- (♪ ENDS)
- (AUDIENCE CHEERING)
- (MICHELLE) Can we do it again?
- I don't want to!
(♪ VIVALDI: "CONCERTO IN G MAJOR")
(COUGHING) It's showtime, folks.
And these two columns revolve
New York to L.A.
And over here on the other side,
the same thing.
Two staircases come down here...
and two more come back
into the orchestra.
Oh, and this centerpiece
moves out...
for the interior scenes...
and up there, that's Stan.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
But you'll get familiar with it
when we start.
Okay, now, all I want to do now...
is to read easily
through the script...
and frankly, I'm not too
familiar with it myself.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(COUGHS) So if we go through it...
you'll give Paul and me some
rough idea of what we've got.
Okay. No acting.
Everyone just take it easy. Easy.
All right, lights up.
Audrey, you have
your first number...
and then you begin reading
on page two.
"You see, Sammy, in California,
everybody needs a car.
I got a friend who bought a Mercedes
just to get to the bathroom."
(LAUGHTER FADES)
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(SCRAPING ON METAL)
(WATCH TICKING)
(AUDREY)
"I guess only in America...
can a 24-year-old girl like me...
own a house like this
in Beverly Hills."
Thank you all very much.
You've done a wonderful job.
Take an hour and a half
for lunch. Back at 3:00.
Don't forget to sign
the Boston hotel list.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
- Excuse me.
- Anything wrong?
No, no. Nothing.
- There's no use to panic till
we find out what it really is.
- Would you stop that?
(MAN) Dr. Ballinger is looking at him now.
Ballinger is the best there is, Audrey.
- Dr. Hyman, we just left him.
- About half an hour ago.
- And he seemed fine.
- Just fine.
Well, he called. He said he had
chest pains. His left arm was numb.
(DR. HYMAN) I'm bewildered myself.
I checked him about a month ago.
All right, who's in charge
of this all-important...
million-dollar show that
Mr. Gideon keeps talking about?
(JONESY) I guess I am.
Mr. Gideon is having attacks of angina
that could lead to a massive coronary.
Ah, shit! I gotta get back.
I'm fine. What do doctors know?
About angina, just a little
more than show people.
If you want to leave, fine, but I
think you'll die. Can I see you?
(JOE) Dr. Hyman?
The pain is gone. Nothing wrong
with me a rewrite wouldn't cure.
- Couple of good jokes is what I need.
- You can't leave now.
- Yes, I can.
- Damn it, Joe!
Didn't you hear
what the doctor just said?
Please, stay.
Joey, I've been talking
to Dr. Ballinger...
Jonesy, wait a minute.
Let me talk to the star here.
If I stay, how much time
are we talking about?
At least two or three weeks.
You've got to be kidding!
I got a show to put on!
For chrissakes, will you
talk to these people?
They don't understand anything!
Oh, Jesus.
- What's wrong?
- Miss Collins.
- All right, easy.
- Damn it.
You guys are doing this to me.
I wasn't sick until I got here.
- What's wrong with him?
- It's exhaustion.
You're lying to me.
Yes.
(KATIE) Uh, no, I'm not a member
of his immediate family.
I'm, uh... I'm his girlfriend.
Well, could I leave a message
for him, please?
- (♪ UP-TEMPO)
- Could you tell him that... Hello?
(JONESY)
It was just simply exhaustion.
He just tried to do too much.
Anyway...
we've made a decision to postpone
the show for four months.
- The doctors assured us Joe will be fine.
- There goes my new apartment.
Therefore the show will
definitely be done. I promise.
(SCATTERED APPLAUSE)
Now, we're aware of the...
- financial burdens this might impose...
- I gave up a TV series.
- On some of you, and...
- What a dummy.
We're prepared to try to get you...
temporary jobs,
or even lend you money.
Jonesy, easy on the money,
easy on the money.
All right, Larry. All right, okay.
We don't have
a lot of cash available, but...
what I'd like to say to you is...
I... we...
think of you all as family.
- Bullshit.
- And we want to do...
everything we possibly can...
to keep you all together.
(AUDREY'S VOICE) I was with him last
night. Already he's much better.
- (MOUTHS WORDS)
- I just left him an hour ago.
He was in a great mood...
making jokes...
- making passes at all the nurses...
- (PEOPLE LAUGHING)
and he told me to tell all of
you he has a terrific idea...
- for a new hospital number.
- Hold it, Audrey!
Hospital number, hospital number!
Just give me a minute. Stan,
will you give me some room?
- How does the title "Hospital Hop" grab you?
- It grabs me.
- Great, great.
- (♪ JAUNTY PIANO)
- I think I got it. I got it!
- I think he's got it!
Stan, help me out, please.
Clap your hands!
- Cheer up!
- (CLAPPING CONTINUES)
Let's go! Everybody!
- (♪ ENDS)
- (JONESY) And Lucas...
they are without question
an absolutely...
marvelous cast.
Now we gotta wait around
four months.
Maybe even lose them.
I can see where it'd be difficult
to hold a cast like that together.
It's really a shame.
And, of course,
even after four months...
a heart attack... (CHUCKLING)
There's no guarantee
that he'll be able to work.
None.
Jules, it's still too bright.
- Take number seven down to five...
- And he's the greatest.
- And eight down to two.
- Hmm.
And Lucas,
I think we have a sure hit.
A sure hit.
Reads like a dream.
I'd love to read it sometime.
I'll get a copy to you
this afternoon.
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, I forgot. Wait a minute.
- I've got one right here with me.
- (BOTH CHUCKLING)
Dimmer five up to three.
Hold that. That's good.
I know you couldn't care less
about the money.
- Hmm?
- What do you think about this, Lucas?
Is it any better?
No. No, no.
It needs to be more... shadowy.
We talked about this, Jules.
It's a seduction scene.
Take the shadow lights to half.
How much, uh... is Joe getting?
Five percent of the gross
until payoff.
Then he goes to six percent. Twenty
percent of subsidiary rights...
- including a movie sale.
- (JULES) Thanks. That's good.
(EXHALES FORCEFULLY) Well...
of course my schedule's
impossible, but, uh...
you know how I feel
about you, Jonesy.
You've been like a father to me.
And you a son to me.
(JOE) I always look for
the worst in people.
A piece of you in them?
Yeah. A piece of me.
And generally, I find it.
Well, it may take you years,
but you'll find it.
(GIGGLES)
Oh, you're cute. You are cute.
It's looking better.
I think we'll move you upstairs
to a private room.
Oh, yeah.
But you better rest. If you
don't, you're in for trouble.
Oh, I will, Doctor.
I promise. I will.
- (♪ ROCK)
- (NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
Mr. Gideon!
Mr. Gideon, what are you doing?
Oh, this?
I was just getting rid of it.
I caught someone smoking and told
him a man in my condition...
shouldn't even be around smoke.
(♪ UP-TEMPO)
I'm telling you, Gideon,
I got real insight into you.
There's a deep-rooted fear
of being conventional.
Right.
Your blood pressure
is higher than we hoped.
Your cardiograms
haven't improved one bit.
If you don't give a damn,
it's hard to expect us to.
Mr. Gideon!
I'll leave these menus with you.
Please check off what you want
for the coming weeks, okay?
Monday, I'll have roast beef. Tuesday,
chicken. Wednesday, steak.
Thursday I plan to be dead, so...
I'll just have something light.
Mr. Gideon!
(♪ CONTINUES)
She wrote a little note on the back.
She said you'd understand.
"Dear loving, giving, generous"...
underlined four times... "Dad...
I hear nurses are nice people.
Hint, hint.
Your poor, brother-less daughter."
Joe, what does it mean?
It means she's inherited
her mother's determination.
That's what it means.
(♪ SCATTING)
- (♪ ENDS)
- (AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(MAN LAUGHING)
Oh, no. Thank you. No, no, no, no.
You're wonderful, wonderful.
The word "superstar"...
is greatly overused
in this business.
- Mm.
- But for my next guest...
the word "superstar"
is totally inadequate.
Whenever I do a benefit... and I've
done 150, 160, 170 this year...
all for very worthy causes...
I can always count on this dude...
to be right there with me.
I feel humbled in his presence.
From deep, deep in here,
ladies and gentlemen...
- let me lay on you...
- A great entertainer.
- A great entertainer...
- A great humanitarian.
- A great humanitarian...
- And my dear friend for 25 years.
And my dearest, dearest friend
for20years...
(CHUCKLES)
You missed by five years.
Oh, boy, do I hate show business.
Joey, you love show business.
That's right. I love show business.
I'll go either way.
- (♪ UP-TEMPO)
- (NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
I got insight into you, Gideon.
You know what's underneath?
The dreadful fear
that you're ordinary...
not special.
Right.
(MOANING) I think...
I think...
I'm getting an erection.
Oh, Mr. Gideon, don't...
don't do that!
That sex thing... Jesus!
Listen, I wouldn't say
you were a faggot...
but you do have a lot
of feminine characteristics.
Right?
Right.
(♪ CONTINUES)
You are foolishly and childishly
flirting with disaster.
(WOMAN) Joe, what are you doing?
You're really crazy! What do
you want to do, kill yourself?
Dr. Ballinger told me
to get a little exercise.
Everything he does seems to be
a denial of his condition.
Dr. Ballinger, every time I've
seen him, I get the impression...
that he doesn't care
whether he lives or dies.
Yes, I know.
But I think he cares a lot.
Starting now, we'll limit his
visitors to no more than two.
(JOSH) Joe, I wish
you could have been there.
9:30 this morning, before a
single review was out...
the line at Cinema One
was around the block.
The people know.
I mean, the people know!
This broke every first-day record.
It's a blockbuster. A blockbuster.
I mean a blockbuster!
And those guys in California...
You wouldn't believe
the telephone calls.
"Congratulations," they say.
"We're glad you took your time.
It was worth it.
Every dollar we put in that film
is up there on the screen."
I'm telling you, they're talking about
a $ 3 1/2 million advertising budget.
Three and a half million dollars!
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
Do you believe that?
Three and a half million dollars!
This picture is going
right through the roof.
Right through...
the roof!
Look at those reviews.
See? We did it.
Joe, we did it!
Where are the bad ones?
There are no bad ones.
Josh.
There were a couple that quibbled
a little. I left them at the office.
I want you to do me a favor:
Don't show them to me.
Never.
- How were the television reviews?
- I think we got Leslie Perry.
At the screening,
she told me she loved it.
Following Joe Gideon's triumphant
directorial achievement...
with Fifty Beautiful Girls, Fifty...
when he won every possible award...
it would be nice to report that
Mr. Gideon's latest effort...
The Stand-up, starring
Davis Newman...
was a better film.
- Oh, boy. Here it comes.
- The Stand-up, however,
does not quite stand up.
- Joey, turn it off, please.
- Leaning toward the frenetic, Gideon falls...
into his characteristic weakness
of trying too hard...
- to please, to entertain.
- I'm gonna turn that off.
- Josh, no. I want to hear it.
- Slickness obscures reality.
- The old razzle-dazzle obliterates drama.
- (JOSH) What the hell does she know?
She never gave anything
a good review.
That woman is totally unqualified
to criticize anything.
She doesn't know
a goddamn thing about film.
- Or anything.
- She's not even reviewing a film.
She's telling you
how clever she is!
where the has-been comic, played
impeccably by Davis Newman...
demonstrates
his former brilliance...
in a monologue where clearly...
director Gideon gave
Mr. Newman free rein.
Rising above
rather commonplace material...
- the actor creates a classic comic aura...
- I don't care what she says.
I guarantee this picture will do
30 million domestic, at least.
- One of you better get somebody.
- (KATIE) What?
I think I'm in trouble.
- (JOSH) I'll get somebody.
- ...chopping offends of scenes
before the drama has played out...
left this reviewer
with bewilderment...
and a four-aspirin headache.
Using my four-balloon
rating system...
I give The Stand-up half a balloon.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
- (MAN) How are you feeling?
- The truth?
I'm scared.
(WHIRRING STOPS)
Roll 'em. Action.
Oh-ho-ho-ho, my God.
(♪ DRUMROLL, CYMBAL CRASH)
Ladies and gentlemen, the doctors.
I'm Dr. Hyman, the internist.
I'm Dr. Garry, the surgeon.
- I'm Dr. Ballinger, the cardiologist.
- Five, six, seven, eight.
ALL EXPLAINING CARDIOLOGY:
VOICES OVERLAPPING
- (♪ RIM SHOT)
- Huh?
- That means he had total blockage...
- (♪ SLIDE WHISTLE)
- in... two arteries.
- (♪ PERCUSSION FLOURISH, CYMBAL CRASH)
Oh!
This is the man
who would be my first choice...
as a modern-day saint.
When I was in those marches,
like Selma...
this brother was shufflin'
right alongside me...
long before those other cats who thought
civil rights was a hip scene...
and jumped on the "blackwagon"...
The blackwagon!
(LAUGHING)
Ladies and gentlemen,
let me lay on ya...
- A great entertainer.
- a great entertainer...
- A great humanitarian.
- a great humanitarian...
- And my dearest friend.
- and my dearest, dearest friend...
- For (MUFFLED) years.
- for 17years.
- Let's hear it...
- (CLICKS OFF)
- See how much I learn from you?
- I'm afraid you've learned too much.
There you are, Mr. Gideon.
This is one of my...
A1, first-rate, top-drawer jobs.
That's it.
Good luck tomorrow.
Wh-What did you mean,
I learned too much from you?
You're gonna make it.
I'm hardly ever wrong.
Thanks.
You remember last Tuesday night?
It was raining...
very hard.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, it was raining.
What about it?
I called you at midnight.
I must have been walking the dog.
I don't have time
for this sort of thing.
You were with someone.
Yes.
And you made love to him.
Yeah.
Well, that's it, huh?
- We're finished?
- I don't know.
How do you feel about me?
I love you.
Then I guess we're not finished.
(CHUCKLES)
Be-Because I really do
love you, Katie.
- (WOMAN'S VOICE) You mean that?
- (JOE'S VOICE) Ah, hell, no!
I was pissed off at her.
I don't know.
Yeah, I did mean it. Sort of.
Sometimes I don't know where the
bullshit ends and the truth begins.
I just wanted to say
something nice to her.
Why?
(CHUCKLES) In case, uh...
"In case."
In case.
If I die...
I'm sorry for all...
the bad things I did to you.
And if I live...
I'm sorry for all the bad things...
I'm gonna do to you.
as stated in the declarations,
sustained directly and solely...
as the result of injury, sickness,
death of, or permanent disability...
Excuse me, Mr. Clark.
Larry, give me our figures.
Well, on an estimated
production budget...
of $941,000...
with a contingency of 59,000 to
round it out to the million...
so far we're in for at least
two-thirds of the fees.
Design: 8,000. Costumes: 8,000.
Electrics: 4,000.
We're in for the full
director-choreographer: 15,000.
Casting is another four.
Construction of scenery...
where more than half
has been done...
that's 125,000-plus.
Stage manager's about 8, 000.
Press agent: 1,500.
Musicians: about two.
Assistants, secretaries,
et cetera: 3,000.
Rehearsal halls
and auditions: 9,500.
Script and administrative: 1,500.
Managers: I'd say 10.
Advertising and printing:
about 20, 000.
Orchestrations:
so far around 10,000.
Legal: 10,000. Auditing: 2,000.
Payroll taxes: maybe seven.
Well, seven.
Author's advances: 10,000.
Equity bonds: 50,000.
Rehearsal salaries... and we've made
some advances to a few of the cast...
about 43,000.
We're in for about, uh...
$480,500.
Yes.
That's the figure I had here.
And change.
(JONESY) Let me try to understand.
Of that figure,
how much do we recoup?
I'm confused too. Do we get
all of that or part or what?
Simply, here are the options. One:
If Mr. Gideon recovers...
and you resume production
within the 180 days...
we are not liable for any of it.
Two: If Mr. Gideon should die...
and you resume production with another
director within the 180 days...
we are still not liable.
Three, however:
If Mr. Gideon should expire
before February 1...
and you abandon production...
we are liable
for the full million dollars.
This means, gentlemen...
you could make a profit of...
$519,500.
You could be
the first show on Broadway...
to make a profit
without really opening.
Well...
it's all very clear to me.
(COMEDIAN) There's all this
bullshit about death with dignity.
You know what death
with dignity is, man?
- You don't drool.
- (AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
Change-of-pace time.
Request. Here we go.
Vic O'Dante. Hey!
♪ Death is in
Death is in, my dear ♪
♪ Death is the thing ♪
- (♪ CONTINUES)
- Oh, that's very theatrical, Joe.
- Please don't try to talk.
- (COUGHING)
- You want to shoot it now?
- Huh?
I can't understand him.
I think he said "okay."
(MAN)
"Hospital Hallucination," take one.
There's a lady in Chicago, man,
wrote a book.
Dr. Kubler-Ross, with a dash.
This chick, man...
- without the benefit of dying herself...
- (JOE) On your marks, now.
Has broken the process of death
into five stages...
- Ready? And...
- Anger, denial, bargaining...
depression, and acceptance.
- Playback.
- (MONITOR BEEPING)
(♪ SCATTING)
♪ After you've gone ♪
♪ And left me cryin' ♪
♪ There's no denyin' ♪
♪ You'll feel blue ♪
♪ You'll feel sad ♪
- ♪ You'll miss the bestest pal ya ♪
- ♪ Ever had ♪
♪ There'll come a time ♪
♪ Don't forget it ♪
♪ When you'll regret it ♪
♪ Some day ♪
♪ When you grow lonely ♪
♪ Your heart will break like mine ♪
♪ And you'll want me only ♪
♪ After you've gone ♪
- (♪ SCATTING)
- ♪ After you've gone ♪
(♪ CONTINUES)
♪ After you've gone ♪
- ♪ Away ♪
- ♪ Away ♪♪
- Cut!
- (BELL RINGING)
Want to print it?
Jesus, Joe, you're way behind
schedule! You gotta print it.
- Next setup.
- Roll 'em.
"Katie," take two.
Listen, huh?
- Playback!
- (BEEPING)
(♪ SEDUCTIVE VAMP)
♪ You better change
your way of livin' ♪
- ♪ And if that ain't enough ♪
- She's right. Listen.
♪ You better change the way
you strut your stuff ♪
♪ 'Cause nobody wants you
when you're ♪
♪ Old and gray ♪
♪ You better change
your way today ♪
♪ You better change your way ♪
Can you hear me, Joe?
I'm talkin' to ya.
- Ya gotta lay off the booze, Joe.
- Ax the amphetamines.
You gotta stop
screwin' around, Daddy.
♪ You better stop ♪
♪ You better change ♪
♪ You better stop
You better change ♪
♪ You better stop, you better change
You better stop ♪
♪ And change your ways today ♪
♪ I said stop, change, stop ♪♪
- Please?
- Cut!
(BELL RINGING)
- Huh?
- (MUMBLES)
- Print it.
- "Old Friends," take three.
- Playback.
- (BEEPING)
(♪ ORCHESTRAL)
- ♪ Who's sorry now ♪
- It hurts, doesn't it?
♪ Who's sorry now ♪
♪ Whose heart is aching ♪
- Just look at you, Daddy.
- ♪ For breaking each vow ♪
- All those broken vows.
- ♪ Who's sad and blue ♪
♪ Who's crying too ♪
♪ Just like we cried over you ♪
- (KATIE) And we cried a lot.
- (AUDREY) Oh, a lot.
- (MICHELLE) Me too.
- ♪ Boo-hoo ♪
- ♪ Right to the end ♪
- (AUDREY) It's getting close, Joe.
- ♪ Just like a friend ♪
- Where were you, Joe?
We tried to warn you ♪
♪ Somehow ♪
You didn't listen, Daddy.
You didn't listen.
♪ You had your way ♪
♪ Now you must pay ♪
- (MONITOR BEEPING)
- ♪ We're glad that ♪
♪ You're sorry now ♪♪
- Cut!
- (BELL RINGING)
You blew it. You forgot your line.
At the end of this number,
you're supposed to say, uh...
- What's he supposed to say?
- He's supposed to say...
"I don't want to die.
I want to live."
(MUMBLING)
Well, look,
if you can't say it, you can't.
We'll just have to cut it.
Cut it. Take me up. Next setup.
(♪ SULTRY JAZZ)
♪ Some of these days ♪
♪ You're gonna miss me, Daddy ♪
♪ You're gonna feel so lonely ♪
♪ You'll miss her huggin' ♪
(KATIE'S VOICE)
♪ You'll miss her kissin' ♪
♪ You'll miss me, Daddy ♪
♪ If you go away ♪
♪ I'll feel so lonely ♪
♪ Just for you only ♪
♪ For you know, Daddy ♪
♪ You had your way ♪
(BOTH) A lot.
♪ And if you leave her ♪
♪ You know, you know, you're gonna
gonna, gonna, gonna, gonna grieve her ♪
♪ You're gonna miss
your sweet, little, lovin' ♪
♪ Baby daughter Michelle ♪
- ♪ Some of these days ♪
- Don't die, Daddy! Don't die! Please?
- You can't leave this poor
little kid without a father!
- ♪ Some of these days ♪
- She needs ya, Joe! She needs ya!
♪ Some of these days ♪♪
(GROANS) Oh, no.
You don't have any lines here.
(♪ FLOURISH)
(COMEDIAN)
Real dead body Real dead body.
And... sticks.
(WHIMPERS)
Please don't try to talk.
If you want to tell me anything,
just write it on this pad.
(♪ "YOU'RE GONNA MISS ME, DADDY"
CONTINUES, FAINT)
(JOE'S VOICE)
No. No. Come on, not now.
Please leave.
- Please?
- ♪ Who's sorry now ♪
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure. Just go.
"Am I alive?"
All right, Joe.
Yes, you are alive.
- (WHIMPERING)
- (DR. GARRY) This is gonna hurt a little.
Hmm.
That came out nice.
Miss Paris, would you like
to see something nice?
Oh, that is beautiful!
That is an absolutely
beautiful scar, Dr. Garry.
- Mm. Thank you.
- (LUCAS) How soon do you
think he'll be able to work?
(JONESY) Well, he's out of intensive
care, back in a private room.
The doctor says
it's just a matter of rest.
Two months at the outside.
(CHUCKLING)
You know Joey. This morning
he said he could hardly wait.
Said he had a lot of new ideas.
Mm. And not
all that sex stuff, either.
Well, that's terrific.
You must feel really good
about that, Jonesy.
Relieved. We're all relieved.
Check, please.
I did some thinking about your
script and made a few notes.
Ah! My.
Use them, don't use them...
you know, whatever you want.
I hate to bother you,
but are you... Lucas Sergeant?
- Yes.
- Would you mind?
No, no. Not at all.
I'm an actress, and next to Joe
Gideon, you're my favorite director.
I'm so sorry your show was a flop.
- Best of luck with your career.
- Thank you so much.
Lucas, you put in
an awful lot of work on this.
I'm moved.
- (MAN) Yoo-hoo! Teddy!
- For somebody to do something like this just...
just out of friendship,
it touches me.
Listen, what are friends for?
We're all rooting for each other.
I'm just pleased
that Joe is well again.
- Let me get this.
- No, Lucas. This is on me.
I said I'll get this.
(JOE SHUDDERING)
I can't believe it.
Joe, what's the matter?
I'm having a heart attack.
No, that's impossible, Mr. Gideon.
I just gave you your medication.
Goddamn it, he knows the symptoms!
Will you call somebody, please?
He can't be in pain...
- but let me take his pulse.
- How can it be?
Goddamn it, get somebody!
But I just gave you
your medication 20 minutes ago.
You can't possibly be in pain.
(MAN) At least you're getting
use out of the equipment.
That's funny, Doctor.
I gotta tell you,
it hurts like a son of a bitch.
Miss Briggs, two milligrams
of morphine, please.
- What's this?
- That's my name and address.
You can send my check there.
(MAN) Feeling any pain now?
- Bitch!
- What?
- (JOE) No.
But something is... something
is breaking up in there.
Now, that I like.
Something's gone wrong.
All wrong.
No.
- No.
- Oh, my God.
Where's Mr. Gideon?
(COMEDIAN) Anger, denial, bargaining,
depression, and acceptance.
- Anger.
- No. No.
- No! Not now.
- "Jesus Christ!
Goddamn son of a bitch,
pig-fucking bastards!"
- Not now.
- I don't know.
We were busy with an emergency, and the
next thing I noticed, he was gone.
- Denial? Denial?
- (AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
"No. No, that's not me, man. No.
Oh, ho-ho!
No, somebody else, maybe,
but not me. Oh, no.
You got the wrong...
How about my mother, man?
She's old. I'm weaned.
I'm toilet-trained.
I don't need her anymore...
'Bye, Ma. You've been terrific.
I love ya! But not me. "'
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING, CHEERING)
Oh, Jesus, don't take me out now.
What's the matter?
Don't you like musical comedy?
(BEEPING)
Bargaining.
(MAN) Finished,
or do you want to run it again?
(JOE)
Yes, I'd like to run it again.
I'd like to run
the whole thing again.
(COMEDIAN)
"Look, man, can we... Come here.
Can we sit down and talk
about this like businessmen?
A negotiation, okay?
Look, I don't want to haggle.
You'll find me
a reasonable man, man.
The blonde on East 63rd Street
I see on Tuesday nights?
Right? Gone. Finished.
I'll never see her again.
That's it.
All right, no more hard drugs.
A little grass, maybe,
but that's it. Okay?
I promise I won't flash
on subways anymore, okay?
We got a deal? Huh? Huh? Huh?"
Guy drives a hard bargain.
What are you staring at?
I told you guys before...
too much smoking, too much boozing,
too much screwing around,
it'll get you every time.
(CHUCKLING)
I'll be back.
Well, goddamn it, find him!
I want him back in ICU,
and right now! Damn fools!
Depression.
(JOE'S VOICE) And here he is,
ladies and germs, tops in taps...
- Oh, my God! (GASPING)
- tap dancer extraordinaire.
- If I were God...
- "I'm dying!
- And sometimes I think I am...
- Oh, God, am I dying!
- Depends on how much morphine I've had...
- I'm dying! Nobody's dying but me!
- I would spare this terrific tap dancer!
- The doctor's not dying.
He's alive in Florida,
and I'm dying!"
No pennies on the eyes for me.
Please.
Right away, sir. Bye.
(SPANISH)
Come on, we better try
to find this guy.
"Oh, God!
I'm dying!
I'm paying $240 a day
for the hospital room!
At those prices, man,
who can afford to live?"
- (WOMAN GROANING)
- So...
acceptance.
(GROANING) Oh, God!
I think you're the most
beautiful thing in the world.
And I love you.
Just a cut on the head.
Man, I won't have any trouble
at all keeping him here.
He just wants to sit around
and sing old-time songs.
Don't hurry, baby. I'm having
a pretty good time myself.
Now, Mr. Gideon, where were we?
How did you know my name?
Eh, just found out. They're
coming to get you, you know.
I knew they would.
Can I have another?
Oh, help yourself.
Could you do it one more time?
Just for me?
Oh, yeah, I'd love to.
Five, six, seven, eight.
♪ Pack up your troubles
in your old kit bag ♪
♪ And smile, smile, smile ♪
(IMITATES DRUMBEAT) Hey!
♪ Pack up your troubles
in your old kit bag ♪
♪ Smile, boys, that's the style ♪
Here we go.
♪ What's the use of worrying ♪
♪ It never was worthwhile ♪
Juicy!
♪ So pack up your troubles ♪♪
(LAUGHING, SPEAKING SPANISH)
(LAUGHING)
- You got it.
- Five, six, seven, eight.
♪ Pack up your troubles
in your old kit bag ♪
♪ And smile, smile, smile ♪
- Okay, mister, you come along with us.
- Nice and quiet, now.
- Please, don't cause no trouble.
- Everything's going to be fine, all right?
All right. So long, Tiger.
Later, Gideon.
This is just a rough cut, you know.
I don't have the titles in yet...
and the underscoring's not in.
It's not really finished.
- (♪ JAZZY INTRO)
- (AUDIENCE CHEERING)
- (♪ ENDS)
- (LAUGHING)
Thank you, thank you.
Wonderful, wonderful.
Folks, what can I tell you
about my next guest?
This cat allowed himself...
to be adored but not loved...
and his success
in show business was matched...
by failure in his
personal-relationship bag.
That's where he really bombed.
And he came to believe
that work, show business...
love, his whole life,
even himself...
and all that jazz was bullshit.
He became numero uno game player...
to the point
where he didn't know...
where the games ended
and the reality began.
Like, to this cat,
the only reality...
is death, man.
Ladies and gentlemen,
let me lay on you...
a so-so entertainer,
not much of a humanitarian...
and this cat
was never nobody's friend.
In his final appearance
on the great stage of life...
You can applaud if you wanna...
Mr. Joe Gideon.
(♪ INTRO)
(♪ CONTINUES)
(♪ ROCK)
(♪ SLOW, PULSING)
(♪ LYRICAL)
♪ Bye-bye, life ♪
♪ Bye-bye, happiness ♪
♪ Hello, loneliness ♪
♪ I think I'm gonna die ♪
(♪ ORGAN STING)
(♪ RHYTHMIC)
♪ Bye-bye, love ♪
♪ Bye-bye, sweet caress ♪
♪ Hello, emptiness ♪
♪ I feel like I could die ♪
♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, my life, good-bye ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
Two, three, four, five, six.
(RHYTHMIC GRUNTING)
♪ Bye-bye, life ♪
♪ Bye-bye, happiness ♪
- ♪ Hello, loneliness ♪
- ♪ I think I'm gonna die ♪
♪ I think he's gonna die ♪
♪ I think I'm gonna ♪
♪ Die ♪
♪ There goes his baby ♪
♪ With someone new ♪
♪ She sure looks happy ♪
- ♪ I sure am blue ♪
- ♪ He sure is blue ♪
♪ I sure am blue ♪
♪ I think I'm gonna
I think I'm gonna ♪
♪ Bye-bye, life ♪
- ♪ I think I'm gonna, I think I'm gonna ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, happiness ♪
♪ Hello, loneliness ♪
- ♪ I think he's gonna ♪
- ♪ I think I'm gonna, I think I'm gonna ♪
♪ Die ♪
A-one, a-two, three, four!
(♪ TEMPO INCREASES)
♪ Bye-bye, love ♪
♪ Bye-bye, sweet caress
Hello, emptiness ♪
♪ I feel like I could die
Bye-bye, my life, good-bye ♪
♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, my life, good-bye ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
♪ I'm through with romance ♪
- ♪ I'm through with love ♪
- ♪ Oh, yeah ♪
- ♪ I'm through with counting the stars above ♪
- ♪ Forget the stars ♪
♪ And here's the reason
that he's so free ♪
♪ His lovin' baby ♪
♪ She's through with me ♪
♪ Bye-bye, life ♪
♪ Bye-bye, happiness ♪
♪ Hello, loneliness ♪
♪ I think he's gonna die ♪
♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye
Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
♪ Bye-bye, my life, good-bye ♪
♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye
Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
(EXCLAIMS)
This must have cost a fortune!
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(SINGER) Oh! Give it to me!
Oh! Give it to me!
At least I won't have to lie
to you anymore.
Oh! Give it to me!
- ♪ Bye-bye, love ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, bye-bye ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, happiness ♪
- ♪ Hello, hello ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, bye-bye ♪
- ♪ He's gonna die ♪
- ♪ I think he's gonna die ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, bye-bye ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, love ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, happiness ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, bye-bye ♪
- ♪ Hello, emptiness ♪
♪ I think he's gonna die ♪
- ♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
- Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
- ♪ I think he's gonna die ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la,
la, la, la, la ♪
(SOFTLY)
♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ La, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪ Bye-bye ♪
- ♪ My life ♪
- Oh, yeah!
- ♪ Good-bye ♪♪
- (MONITOR BEEPING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(MONITOR CONTINUES BEEPING)
(♪ ENDS)
(♪ RESUMES)
♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪
- ♪ Bye-bye, your life, good-bye ♪♪
- (SINGER EXCLAIMING)
(♪ JAUNTY)
(ETHEL MERMAN) ♪ There's no
business like show business ♪
♪ Like no business I know ♪
♪ Everything about it is appealing ♪
♪ Everything the
traffic will allow ♪
♪ Nowhere could you get
that happy feeling ♪
♪ When you are stealing
that extra bow ♪
♪ There's no people
like show people ♪
♪ They smile when they are low ♪
♪ Yesterday they told you
you would not go far ♪
♪ That night you open
and there you are ♪
♪ Next day on your dressing room
they've hung a star ♪
♪ Let's go on with the show ♪
♪ The costumes, the scenery
the makeup, the props ♪
♪ The audience that lifts you
when you're down ♪
♪ The headaches, the heartaches
the backaches, the flops ♪
♪ The sheriff who escorts you
out of town ♪
♪ The opening
when your heart beats ♪
♪ Like a drum ♪
♪ The closing when the customers ♪
♪ Don't come ♪
(MALE CHORUS) ♪ There's no
business like show business ♪
♪ Like no business I know ♪
(MERMAN) ♪ You get word
before the show has started ♪
♪ That your favorite uncle
died at dawn ♪
♪ On top of that
your pa and ma have parted ♪
♪ You're brokenhearted
but you go on ♪
(MALE CHORUS) ♪ There's no
people like show people ♪
♪ They smile when they are low ♪
(MERMAN) ♪ Even with a turkey
that you know will fold ♪
♪ You may be stranded
out in the cold ♪
♪ But still you wouldn't
change it for a sack of gold ♪
♪ Let's go on with the show ♪
♪ Let's go ♪
♪ On with the ♪
♪ Show ♪♪