Apples!
Buy apples!
Sergeant Kelly.
Lieutenant Moran.
This is indeed
a delightful surprise.
Don't give us no lip.
Were you in Flatbush last night?
Perhaps around and about
the Citizens National Bank?
Flatbush? Me?
I was in Jersey City with my brother.
What are you giving us?
Your brother fried two years ago in Sing Sing.
Who says he didn't?
But he's buried in Jersey City.
- He's clean.
- See that you stay clean.
[Woman]
Apples. Buy apples.
You forgot to look behind my ears.
Apples.
[Chorus Singling]
[Ends]
? You ?
? Send me ?
? Right out of this world ?
? You send me ?
? You give me that kick ?
? I never knew ?
You send me
Right out of this world
? But, darling ?
There Is one thing I hope
you never do
? Don't ever send me away ?
Darling
just let me stay
? Don't send me away ?
? From you ~
[Orchestra Resumes]
Oh. So there you are.
Why weren't you at your table?
- Get Curtaintime Charlie.
- Hey, what's with the suitcases?
We're blowin' to Florida,
maybe out of the country. Cuba.
- Numbers, what happened?
- The state crime investigating committee.
Somethin' new.
They're gonna investigate big gamblers.
Also certain bookies, such as us.
- But why, all of a sudden?
- Yeah, why?
The action got too hot, too open.
They're springin' a public investigation.
Here, day after tomorrow.
We were tipped. They wanna subpoena us.
You too, Yvonne, for being my doll.
So we're hoppin' a train out in 20 minutes.
- Now you see?
- A train? But I'm not even packed.
- Don't worry. You're stayin'.
- Oh, no. You go, I go, anyplace.
Look, Yvonne, this is trouble, big trouble.
Maybe five years' worth.
- You're the only one who can help.
- Help?
- What do you want me to do,
stay here and take the rap?
- No. It's us they're after.
Your nose is clean.
You're gonna get us off the hook.
- How?
- You're stayin' to testify.
- Testify? Me?
- That's right.
You're crazy.
I wouldn't even know what to say.
Yes, you will. It's all here. I worked it out-
what they should ask, what you'll answer.
- Just learn it.
- This whole thing in- in two days?
- How can I do it?
- Curtaintime Charlie.
He rehearses you.
They tell you what to do?
Sure, only I don't know from committees.
I'm a hoofer, Numbers, an actor.
You're also a horse player
and a loser.
You got the three grand you owe us?
Then you'll do it.
- We'll be listening.
- In Florida?
That's right. They're broadcasting
the hearing over the radio.
Yeah, so people out of town
should also dislike us.
Okay, baby?
- I'll do my best.
- Attagirl.
I knew I could depend on ya.
Oh, uh, Tessle, If that doctor calls up
about my allergy tests...
tell him I'm allergic to heat.
Bye, now.
I'm gonna miss that, baby.
Be good.
All right, let's shove.
- Good-bye, Tess.
- [Man] Good-bye, Tess.
[Tessle]
Bye.
[Laughing, Shouting]
[Static]
[Man]
Queen Mary calling America.
Come in, America.
The Queen Mary.
You know where that's coming from?
The middle of the Atlantic Ocean.
Hey! First you get Yokohama,
then the bullfights in Tijuana. And now the ocean.
What's the matter,
you got something against New York?
Then if I was you,
I would get it fast.
- [Static]
- [Man] Tell the committee, Mr. Bennett.
Did you win any money
gambling last year?
[Bennett]
I don't remember.
- [Man] Did you lose any money gambling?
- I don't remember.
I would like to remind you again,
Mr. Bennett...
that the laws of the state of New York
make you liable to a charge of contempt...
for noncooperation with
a duly constituted committee.
And these laws are taken seriously
by the legislature.
- I warn you, sir.
- Proceed, counsel.
How much did you earn last year?
[Bennett]
I don't remember.
Did you declare any winnings
In your Income tax returns?
- [Clears Throat]
- Louder, please, into the microphone.
[Bennett]
Like I said, I don't remember.
How much are you worth in cash?
Well, if you-
- I don't remember.
- I see.
Mr. Chairman,
I have no more questions.
- I wonder what's taking that
Poorly so long. Where is he?
- [Door Opens]
- Here, Numbers.
- ‘‘Here, Numbers. Here, Numbers."
One hour, 43 minutes, 11 seconds
you were gone. Where were you?
I went to the drugstore.
I had to get vitamins, aspirin...
calcium pills, phenobarbital
and one thing and another.
I told you they have
such medicines down in Cuba.
Well, this ain't for there.
It's for on the way.
I'm not well, you know.
She on yet?
- No. Any minute now. Everything ready?
- Gas and oil's on board.
- Good. We might know soon. Wait outside.
- [Gavel Rapping On Radio]
[Man]
The hearing will come to order. Proceed, counsel.
For the last time,
the committee requests...
the following witnesses
to present themselves
- Harry Sammis, also known as ‘‘Poorly" Sammis...
- Here, Your Honor.
‘‘Pittsburgh" Philo Green...
Ropes McGonigle...
Frankie Ferroccio...
Louis Larchmont,
alias ‘‘Lookout Louie"...
Robert Foster,
known as ‘‘Numbers" Foster...
- Miss Yvonne Dugan.
- [Yvonne] Yes?
- Please take the stand.
- [Yvonne] Yes, sir.
You shouldn't have had her around
and about to get picked up.
- She's gonna spill.
- She'll only spill what I wrote and nothing more.
Are you ready, Miss Dugan?
- Well, I wanna help, but I am scared.
- Hmm.
Well, just answer questions,
and don't be scared.
[Yvonne]
Thank you. Thank you, sir.
Well, those gentlemen you named,
I do know them.
They work for Mr. Foster.
- The man known as Numbers Foster?
- Yes.
He handicaps horse races, and they go
to the tracks and make bets for him.
Don't you mean ‘‘take"bets? ‘‘T"?
Oh, no, sir. Make bets. ‘‘M."
Then he doesn't run
a bookmaking syndicate?
Of course not.
Why, that's illegal.
Just playing the horses
is different.
It's- It's like gambling
in the stock market.
Sometimes you win,
and sometimes you lose.
Hmm. According to Mr. Foster's tax returns,
he hasn't won in three years.
- Oh?
- Yet he bought you a mink coat for Christmas.
- How, Miss Dugan?
- On time.
- He's paying it off.
- Mm-hmm.
Tell me, do you know
a Mr. Alphonso Burger...
also known as Little Joe the Jockey?
Yes. Why?
Were you present when he agreed to ride
a crooked race last July 3?
Little Joe? Oh, no.
Why, he never-
Then what was in the package he carried
to your apartment the next day?
- Was it money?
- No!
- Are you sure, Miss Dugan? If you lie, it's perjury.
- Well?
- She sure forgot what to say.
- Charlie, baby!
Oh, I remember now.
It was the Fourth of July.
The Uptown Club was having its picnic.
What Little Joe had in that package was his lunch-
salami sandwiches on rye.
- [Spectators Laughing]
- [Gavel Rapping]
Well, you can ask
anybody who was there.
Is there anything else, Senator?
Since the testimony of this witness
is not furthering our investigation...
and inasmuch as the existence of this committee
as an investigating committee...
is due to expire next Friday,
we declare that this hearing is at an end.
You may step down.
‘‘You may step down, Miss Dugan."
Such fine testimony you write.
Okay, okay, it's over.
You guys get right back. Get things rollin'.
Handle the play.
Only do it careful, you hear?
Me and Poorly will be up Friday.
We're driving.
- Since when?
- Since now. I don't wanna go back too quick.
Won't look good.
Anyway, the ride'll relax me. Go buy a car.
Maybe we can stop off in Texas.
I know a doll there runs a massage store.
When you drive from Florida to New York,
you don't go through Texas, dope.
- Why not?
- Get the car! I wanna leave today.
- What color?
- Go, will ya?
~ [Singing Incoherently]
All right. Can it, will ya?
That's enough already.
- I didn't know you was awake.
- I've been awake for hours.
- Can't sleep. My nerves keep jumpin'.
- Why?
It's all over.
We come out smelling like roses.
- Go ahead and sleep.
- I've been tryin' since we left, ain't I?
Try again.
I won't sing.
Ah, it's no use.
Give me a number.
- Aw, Numbers, not that again.
- Come on. Fast, fast.
- Twelve times 28.
- 336.
Twenty-six times 85.
- 2,210.
- Fifty-two times-
No. That ain't healthy.
You shouldn't strain your head like that.
Why not?
It relaxes me.
Do you know why you do it? No.
Do you know how you do it? No.
Maybe something's wrong with you.
Only machines are supposed
to figure that fast.
- Did you ever ask a doctor about it?
- Yeah, in reform school once.
They took me up to that professor
up at that Princeton College.
- You know, with the bushy hair and the pipe.
- Yeah.
He gave me numbers, I gave answers.
He said I was a something.
A... phenomenal prodigy.
- That's good?
- Who knows?
I broke out of reform school that night
and went to work for Barney the Bookie.
- Give me another number.
- All right.
- Fifty-two times 95.
- 5,044.
335 times 8,567.
2,869,945.
Subtracted, it's 8,232.
Divided, it's, uh...
25.5731 and a little left over.
[Engine Cranking]
- Huh?
- Numbers, we're out of gas.
- Where are we?
- What comes after Florida?
- Georgia.
- Oh.
I thought we was lost.
- How'd we get here?
- I don't know. I followed the road.
- Why didn't you wake me up?
- Oh, you ain't slept for days.
I just couldn't.
Don't blame me.
I didn't wanna drive.
I don't know from drivin'.
- Where are you going?
- To find somebody, get gas.
Think there's people live here?
Ain't no drugstores,
no saloons, no movies.
Ain't even got a candy store.
Who could live here?
- Birds, maybe.
- [Donkey Braying]
Animals.
Yeah, wild animals.
Numbers, let's wait here.
Maybe a cab'll come by.
- ? In the sweet bye and bye ?
- ~ [Singers Joining In]
? We shall meet
on that beautiful shore ?
? In the sweet ?
? Bye and bye ?
We shall meet on
that beautiful shore
? In the sweet ?
? Bye and bye ?
We shall meet
on that beautiful shore
[Hiccups]
? In the sweet ?
? Bye and bye ?
We shall meet on
that beautiful shore
[Growling]
Howdy do.
Uh, it so happened we run out of gas
on the road here...
and I thought maybe you would-
you might help us find some.
- You see-
- That song you sung-
- What was it?
- ‘‘In the Sweet Bye and Bye."
It's- It's beautiful.
I promised my grandpappy
I'd sing it when we buried him.
- Is that what you were doing?
- Yes, sir. He died at sunup.
Too bad.
I'll sure miss him.
Grandpappy was a laughing man.
And most of the bad things
he done was just mischief.
I sure hope the Lord
ain't too harsh on him.
Go ahead, cry.
- You'll feel better.
- Cry?
We never do up here.
We-
Y'all ain't been around these parts much,
I don't reckon.
- Never.
- Y'all from the law?
- [Snickers]
- No.
Hey, we sure hate to ask you
for help, seeing as how you-
Oh, don't feel bad for Grandpap.
He lived mighty full.
And he always said, ‘‘Less'n folks shoot
or cut up we Stackerlees...
we have our fun and we don't crave
no grieving when we goes. "
So I ain't a-fixin' to grieve.
He'd be sod agin it.
I'm Emily Ann Stackerlee.
Who are y'all?
Uh, Smith.
Uh, he's Jones.
Well, I'm mighty proud to make your acquaintance,
and I'll be most honored to help.
Little girl, um, tell me somethin'.
What type dogs are such dogs?
Bloodhounds.
This here's Nip,
and this here's Tuck.
I thought so.
These dogs are dangerous.
- They chase little dolls over the ice.
- [Growling]
- Nip, Tuck, down!
- [Man] Emily Ann.
- Who are they?
- Strangers needing help.
What kind of strangers?
P-Passin' strangers.
They run out of gas.
I hears that before.
Remember?
Oh, no, Crockett.
They ain't what you think.
How comes you so sure?
- Ya search 'em?
- Well, I know, 'cause they told me.
I'll's find out for myself.
Nobody frisks me.
Get your hand out.
I'll count three.
One! Two!
Crockett Pace, don't you dare!
Don't you spill no blood
near my grandpap...
less'n you want for him to rise up
and walk this here mountain.
And Grandpap will.
You know that.
This is burying ground, and it's holy.
So git! Y'all hear?
Git!
Thanks.
Say, you think fast for a little doll.
I'm terribly sorry
he bothered y'all.
- He must be drinking his own liquor again.
- [Chuckles]
- Uncle Old Fella?
- Yes'm?
Ride Nellie down to the valley store
and get these here gentlemen some gas.
Yes'm.
Meantime, I'll fix
y'all up some vittles.
- Y'all like hominy?
- Oh, we can't wait to eat. Thanks anyway.
It ain't fittin' to leave folks go
without eating.
We'll stop someplace on the road.
Oh, I was hoping y'all would stay and eat.
We don't get much visiting.
Oh.
Okay, we'll stay.
Thank you kindly.
Say, Emily Ann.
- How come that cornball fell for that grandpa gag?
- Gag?
Yeah, you know, that trick you scared him
with about him gettin' up and walkin'.
That weren't no trick.
My grandpap would.
I'm sure glad you had your rod on you.
Mine's in the car.
So is mine.
I'll get 'em.
[Growling]
Numbers! Numbers!
Numbers!
The bloodhounds-
Thank you.
Where's you goin'?
No place.
Then what you got your shoes on for?
Well, I got company, ain't I?
You show 'em where
to find the spring?
Yes'm.
You know that big one,
Miss Emily Ann?
- Yes.
- I think he's right purty, don't you?
lf'n you wanna play that machine
afore you go, you better keep on a-crankin'.
- I seen you watching him.
- Now hush up now.
- You give him the sweet eye.
- Little Elida, we ain't friends no more.
[Giggling]
~ [Hillbilly]
~ [Men Singing]
? I wish I was an apple
a-hangin' on a tree ?
? And every time
a sweetie passed by ?
? She'd take a bite of me ?
? Get along home, Cindy, Cindy
Get along home, Cindy, Cindy ?
I'll marry you someday ?
~ [Vocalizing]
~ She told me that she loved me
She called me sugarplum ~
~ She throwed her arms around me
I thought my time had come ~
~ Get along home, Cindy, Cindy
Get along home, Cindy, Cindy ~
- ~ [Phonograph Slowing Down]
- ~ Get along home
I'll marry you someday ~
~ [Normal Tempo Resumes]
~ I won't have a gal at all ~
~ Cindy every morning ~
~ Cindy every night ~
~ [Tempo Increases Rapidly]
[Emily]
Whoo!
~ [Normal Tempo Resumes]
~ [Skipping]
~ [Normal Playing Resumes]
[Ends]
- [Bed Thuds]
- [Both Laughing]
- Now set the table, and no talking.
- Yes'm.
[Knocking]
- lf'n y'all are ready to eat,
just set yourselves down.
- Thanks.
This soap smells good.
What kind is it?
Hog fat and ashes.
I make it myself.
I put your car out in the back,
Mr. Smith.
- The gas is all in.
- Well, good.
- There you are.
- Thank you, sir.
We always pay off. Look us up sometime
when you get to New York.
Yes, sir. Come, child.
It's time I get you home.
Mighty proud to make
y'alls acquaintanceship.
What does New York look like?
- You mean you never been there?
- No, sir.
I ain't never been out of the county.
But I seen pictures.
Buildings with lights and big crowds
and big stores and-
What do folks do up there?
Oh, well, they-
Well, they go to Madison Square Garden
and Belmont Race Track...
Lindy's Restaurant
and Dave the Dude's Nightclub.
- That's'all.
- Madison Square Garden.
Sure does sound pretty.
Do they grow things there?
Sure. Cauliflowers.
[Chuckles]
Uh, I mean in Central Park
stuff grows...
like, uh, trees, bushes
and one thing and another.
It sure does sound fine.
Oh, land sakes.
Here I'm a-talkin',
and y'all ain't eatin'. Try some grits.
- [Gunshot]
- [Gasps]
[Gunfire Continues]
- You all right?
- Yes, sir. Crockett sure must be powerful mad.
- What do we do? What do we do?
- Cover that window. I'll take the door.
- Get down!
- They'll pick you off!
Crockett, these strangers
are my guests.
Now stop this here foolishment,
you hear?
Oh, my!
Now the grits is all ruined.
Well, just set yourselves
down again.
Numbers, I don't like this whatsoever.
Let's blow.
- Ain't y'all gonna stay? There's still fat meat.
- Sure, sure.
- Didn't I tell y'all?
- You can't say that this is holy ground. Get up!
Here. Let's see you belt me
like you belted her, huh?
Good. Now-
- [Loud Thud]
- [Pig Squealing]
- My, my!
- Numbers, I wanna go home.
Mugs.
Let's eat.
Who were those other two guys?
Crockett's brothers-
Theopolis and Foy.
Nobody's never done that
to any Pace boy before...
leastwise to three of'em.
- Yeah, but what were they so sore about anyway?
- It's just Crockett.
He's a-fixin' to marry up with me,
and he gets a mite upset.
- Marry? You?
- [Gunfire]
- Who's shootin' now?
- The rest of the Paces, I reckon.
- You mean there's more of'em?
- Eleven, not countin' the new baby.
- They'll marbleize us.
- Y'all better hurry. Follow me.
[Gunfire Continues]
- Hop in. We'll coast down the hill.
- The dogs-Where are they?
In the back. Some of the pills they ate
were my sleeping pills.
Well, that there's the road
to New York, I reckon.
Well, you sure did
okay for us, Emily Ann.
- T'weren't nothing.
- It was plenty, kid. Plenty.
Go ahead, as much as you want.
- Oh, I can't accept money.
- Don't be bashful. Take.
No, sir, it ain't proper.
But I would be obliged
for a ride to Rooster Creek.
It's about 20 miles
down the road from here...
and that's where I'm a-fixin' to be if'n y'all ever
come visitin' around here again.
- Don't hold your breath.
- Quiet!
- You, uh, mean you're gonna live there?
- For a spell, I reckon.
When the Paces get all riled up,
it ain't no use fightin' 'em alone.
What about this, uh, Rooster Creek?
Got somebody up there?
My grandpa's first cousin,
I think, on his mother's side.
- Well, don't you know?
- No, sir.
I ain't seen him for years,
and he never did like us much.
- You must have other relatives.
- No, sir.
Just him and Grandpap was all.
Oh, now don't you go frettin' none about me.
I'll get along just fine.
Crockett'll simmer down in a spell,
and I can go back and-
Wait here.
Poorly.
- What else can we do?
- You're crazy.
All right, I'm crazy.
But supposin' she can't find that cousin?
And even if she does find him, you heard.
He don't like her.
Then what? She goes back up to those crumbs
so they can get even on her for us?
- You want that?
- No.
But what do we do
with her in New York?
The works.
Send her to school.
Later on, help her
to marry a guy with shoes.
- Is that so much?
- It's a whole lot, Numbers.
We owe her a whole lot.
Also-Well, she relaxes me
when she sings.
Why, I don't know, only it happens.
But where does she live?
Who's gonna take care of her?
Emily Ann, how would you like
to go to New York?
New York? Why?
Well, we can't leave you here.
l-I wouldn't feel right.
- Oh, but what about my farm and all?
- Ah, forget it.
Give it to Uncle Old Fella.
It's not for a little doll like you.
Oh, well,
I hardly know y'all, and I just-
If I say you'll be safe, you'll be safe.
Well?
I'd just love to,
Mr. Smith and Mr. Jones.
Oh, uh, about that.
My name is really Foster.
Robert ‘‘Numbers" Foster.
- He's Harry ‘‘Poorly" Sammis.
- How do you do?
Well-Well, then y'all lied?
Nah.
Just being careful.
If I'm going, I must know
what's truth and what ain't.
From now on, if I say it's the truth-
Okay?
Yes, sir.
Okay.
All right, let's get going.
You drive.
And this time,
stay on the right road.
[Barking]
What are they barking for?
What's wrong with 'em?
It's them pills.
They're on a jag.
- Ain't there some way to quiet 'em?
- I'll do it. I know how.
[Barking Continues]
~ Bye low, bye low ~
~ Sandman's on his way ~
Bye low, bye low
Sleepy time of day
~ Bye low, bye low ~
Time for counting sheep
Time to go to sleep
Hey, how about that, Numbers?
- Let's just let him sleep.
- Okay. Let's go.
Come on, Nip.
Come on.
My, my!
Hey. Wait here.
Don't forget to tell her it wasn't my idea.
Remember that.
[Tussle]
Hold It, hold It! I'm comin'
- What's the big- Numbers!
- Hi, Tess.
What are you doing here?
Everybody's waiting for you at the Dude's.
- Tess, I wanna talk to you.
- Where's Poorly?
Three truckloads of medicine
came for him- collect too.
- Who's she?
- That's my sister 52nd Street Tessie.
Sure must be
mighty rich to live here.
She's got the powder room concession
at Dave the Dude's Nightclub.
- She does?
- Yeah.
- What's a powder room?
- Shh.
Well, why didn't you say that right off?
Of course I'll take care of her.
Well, just look at you,
you poor little thing.
So you're Emily Ann.
Well, come on in, honey.
I want you to know you can stay here
just as long as you want.
I'll catch up with you later.
‘‘Collect."
I know the orphan bit.
It's rough. No laughs.
- So consider this entire place
just like it's yours, and-
- [Dog Whines]
- Hey, what's those?
- Bloodhound dogs. They're hers.
Bloodhounds?
Oh, no.
I'll play mother to the kid,
but there won't be no dog act in this show.
- See? What'd I tell you?
- Don't worry about the dogs, Tessie.
- Poorly'll take care of them.
- Me?
- Every day.
- He will?
- They love him.
- They don't love me. They love my pills.
- Now look, Numbers-
- Stop arguing. They're your department.
I only hope he's allergic to 'em.
Fix her up, Tess.
Spend all you want. Deal?
Deal. So get yourself over to the Dude's.
I'll get the kid set and catch you later.
Am I gonna see y'all?
Why, sure.
Now do everything Tessie tells you.
Yes, sir. And don't you fret none,
'cause I won't be a worry.
Hey, remember, you.
Your friends'll need walkin' twice a day or more.
In the rain too!
[Barks]
Just what I needed.
- Good to see you, Numbers.
- Good to see you, Dave.
- Greetings!
- Hey, Philo! We missed you!
- Darling!
- Wait'll you see what we've done.
And it's such a setup.
Wait'll you see it.
A thing of beauty.
Safe like a bank.
Right next to an undertaker's store.
- We all wear uniforms like citizens.
- All right already! All right!
Why don't you leave us
alone for a minute?
Hey, easy, baby.
Easy. Relax.
Now, you were great.
You did fine with that testimony.
- Honest? Did you think I was good?
- We ain't in Cuba.
Don't even mention that place.
Why do you think I was so nervous on the stand?
I know what those Cuban-type
muchacha girls look like.
I want you right here.
Oh, hey, I almost forgot.
I got this for you in Miami for coming through.
- Here you are. Try it on for size.
- Numbers!
- Everything's okay, huh?
- The heat's on a little, but we're doin' great.
- Such action you never saw.
- The play is bigger than before.
After we get set up, the first call comes in.
A three-horse parlay.
- My bet for a C- note.
- He blew it and give us another marker, okay?
What do you mean, okay?
He don't owe us. We owe him.
- That's all right, Numbers. Glad to help.
- Glad nothin'.
That don't pay off, but I do always.
Scratch him off the books, Poorly.
Give him a grand too.
I'll give you some advice, Charlie.
Put it in the bank, kid, not on the ponies.
- You can't beat 'em.
- Oh, darling!
- Look, everybody! Give a look!
- Did you buy that on time too, Numbers?
My, don't we all look healthy, huh?
All nice and tan.
Been fishin'? Hey, how much you
pay down on that? How much a week?
By the way, Inspector McNamara,
how's your stomach illness these days?
It's been real fine, Poorly, up to now.
You wanna know something?
I was hoping maybe you'd stay away,
maybe you'd learned.
- I guess not, huh?
- I'm clean, Mac.
Is that the Oscar Yvonne won?
Hey, you wanna take
the tin badge off...
go outside maybe, like old times?
I'd like to, boy, but I can't stay.
I'm busy.
Got myself a new job.
Pounding a beat in the Bronx?
No, no. This may surprise you,
but the governor...
was a little disappointed with what
the last crime committee didn't find out.
- So?
- So he's appointed a whole new crime committee.
Gonna have another hearing
next month.
It's gonna be my job
to supply the witnesses.
- That's pretty funny, huh?
- Yeah, that's a very funny joke, Mac.
Yeah. I thought you'd appreciate it.
That's why I wanted you
to be the first to hear it.
[Numbers]
Hey, Mac, wait.
Like they say in Georgia, it ain't fittin'
to let folks leave without eatin'.
Here.
You oughta travel more.
It improves you.
[Apple Crunching]
All right, you heard him.
It ain't the old malarkey either.
From now on, he'll be close by looking
for any angle, waiting for any slip.
We get caught smokin' in the subway even,
it'll come up trouble.
- We'll be careful, Numbers.
- Careful ain't enough. He's too smart.
We gotta check, double check
and triple check!
If there's anything to cover up,
we better do it fast now!
[Apple Crunching]
Hello, McNamara.
Bye.
Look, just take no chances. Do as you're told
and there won't be any trouble, see?
- Hey, could he make any trouble
about the little doll?
- No!
- What little doll?
- Emily Ann Stackerlee. He's nuts.
Hey, wait a minute.
I don't get it.
Look, this party's a child.
You know, like a kid sister.
We brought her from Georgia so's I could
send her to school and watch out for her.
- But why, all of a sudden?
- Because she saved our lives, that's why.
You oughta see her. She never cries.
She ain't scared of nothin'.
There's these three guys down there this big,
see, and with cannons this big.
- And there's this little doll like this, and-
- [Door Opens]
The little doll.
Hey, don't you two guys
know what's playing?
- Little doll, my eye.
Emily Ann here's a grown mouse.
- Howdy, all.
Kid sister, huh?
What else is new?
But she was barefooted
with-with pigtails.
- We thought she was a filly.
- So did I, but I asked her.
She's 20.
- Did you pass McNamara on the way in?
- Yeah.
- Did he see her?
- How could he miss her?
We'll wait outside.
Come on, honey.
She could make Inspector McNamara
a very happy man.
- What are you talking about?
- She's under 21.
You brought her here from Georgia.
That's all.
I had to bring her. I told you why.
She can't go home.
- They're after her down there for saving us.
- So she can't go someplace else?
- Where, tell me?
- I can think of someplace.
If I could figure something
legitimate for her to do...
she'll be just like a million other dolls
in New York.
Emily Ann.
All of us want you to know that we're glad
you're here, and you're welcome to stay.
Oh, thank you.
I was gettin' powerful worried.
But we gotta figure something
legitimate for you to do...
something that'll make you happy.
- Only it's gotta be legal.
- Well, I can sew and cook.
And I can chop wood,
and I plant cotton read good.
Feel!
Look, there's no wood to chop here,
and for us It Isn't Important to cook or sew.
- Well, what do girls do up here?
- They don't plant cotton.
Well, what about my dogs?
They're awful good
at huntin' and treein'.
Chasin' things up trees like squirrels
and possums, even people.
I hired 'em out to the sherlff lots.
Honey, I'm afraid you'd
be out of work somewhat.
You see, there ain't many of
the old trees around anymore.
- Didn't you say she can sing?
- So what?
I don't do that too good,
Miss Tessie.
Honey, with your looks and that build,
who's gonna listen?
You'd be great,
and you can rehearse right here too.
- Why not?
- Yeah. Why not? Sounds okay, huh?
Don't ask me.
I'm just an innocent bystander.
Okay, it's all set.
Charlie!
Hey, Curtaintime Charlie!
He'll train you, see?
When you're ready, we clock you for the Dude
and you're off on a fast track.
- You want me, Numbers?
- Yeah. Meet Emily Ann Stackerlee, kid.
- Dream up a classy act for her.
- She sing?
- Beautiful.
- Dance?
- I used to jig with my grandpap.
- Jig? Oh, no.
That went out with
high-button shoes.
You know somethin'?
High-button shoes are coming back again.
Okay, meet me here
tomorrow morning, 10:00.
- Thank you, Mr. Curtaintime.
- Tessie'll show you around, Emily Ann.
Okay, fellas, that's it.
- Darling?
- Yeah?
- I know why you're doing this, only-
- Only what?
Only I saved you from that committee
for one reason- me.
Okay, let's get goin'.
- Good morning, Charlie.
- Good morning, Mr. Curtaintime.
Hi. Now here's how we'll start.
- Tessie'll do a very simple step.
- Who, me?
- You. You do everything she does
and see if you can follow.
- Yes, sir.
~ [Piano]
~ [Stops]
- [Stops]
- Well, you were just fine, Mr. Curtaintime.
Now can I show you a little step
my grandpappy taught me?
- Yeah, go ahead.
- All right.
[Plano]
[Ends]
- So your grandpap taught you that, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
~ I got a feelin'
you're foolin' ~
- ~ I got a feelin' you're havin' fun ~
- I wasn't, Mr. Charlie.
- ~ I'll get a blow-by when you are done ~
- I was only dancin'.
- ~ Foolin' with me ~
- Tessie, will you tell Mr. Charlie-
~ I got a feeling
you're foolin' ~
- ~ I got a notion it's make believe ~
- Well!
~ I think you're laughin'
right up your sleeve ~
~ Foolin' with me ~
~ Life is worth living
when you are giving ~
~ Moments of paradise ~
- ~ You're such a standout ~
- ~ But, oh, how you hand out ~
~ That hocus pocus
from your eyes ~
~ I got a feeling
you're foolin' ~
~ I got a feelin'
it's all a frame ~
~ It's just the well-known
army game ~
~ Foolin' ~
~ Foolin' with you ~
[Fades]
[Window Blinds Opening]
Good mornin'.
You better get yourself up and get to work.
It's gettin' mighty late.
It's almost 7:00.
- Who-Who let you in here?
- Mr. Poorly.
I figured I'd fix y'all some breakfast
before I went to practicin'.
He's eaten his already.
Emily Ann, uh, girls shouldn't come up
to a gentleman's apartment alone.
Oh, I didn't.
I brought Nip and Tuck along.
But if you say
I shouldn't no more, I won't.
Now don't you let
your eggs get cold. Bye.
[Door Closes]
[Yawns]
I don't get it. What do you mean,
you won't take my laundry?
- What I said- I won't.
- But why, for instance?
Because we do lousy work.
Well, this I never heard before.
- Hey, give me a receipt for this.
- Where's your eyes? Inside.
Oh, pardon me.
Look, lady, why don't you try
that place on 60th Street?
- [Woman] You ever use that service?
- No.
- But we send lots of people there.
- Shreds.
They send everything back in shreds.
Don't tell me about 'em.
I used 'em for Little Alexander,
and what they did-
How about the place on Third Avenue?
Look, explain to me something.
Don't you like me? You think I can't pay maybe?
[Louie]
Listen, lady, I'm only trying to help.
Like I said, we do lousy work here.
Here.
This was once a didy.
[Whistles]
- [Chattering]
- [Phones Ringing]
Okay, Lou, 400.
You got it.
Hula Girl in the first at Pimlico.
Joe's got 800, the cigar store six,
and the barber shop 1,200.
- She's now two to one.
- Let's see. 5,200 if she comes in.
That's too much.
Lay off a G to Jersey, a G to St. Louis.
- We'll hold six.
- Right.
Georgia's Gold, second, Jamaica.
Blinkey's got three grand...
Pete two, George two,
hotel 800 at four to one.
He's only carrying 110 pounds.
Lay off two grand to Very Big Joe in Cleveland.
We'll hold the rest for now.
Jetboy, third at Arlington.
Barber's got a grand, gas station 400...
Sammy 900, Larry 600,
butcher 800, five to one.
Let's see. That comes to-
comes to-
Hey, Numbers, you made a mistake
on Pipjack in the first at Jamaica.
- We laid off more than we got.
- All right! So I made a mistake! Ropes!
- That's all I pay you guys for- to find my mistakes?
- What is it, boss?
Take over.
What's the matter?
Oh, Yvonne called up before.
I told her you was busy.
Don't you feel good?
What hurts you?
Look, you've been like this for days.
Why don't you come see my doctor?
I saw a doctor this morning.
Yeah?
What'd he say?
Organic?
Chronic? Orthopedic?
- He said I'm okay.
- Hey, some doctor.
Tell me the symptoms.
I feel all mixed up.
All of a sudden,
I can't figure numbers.
I don't sleep good.
I keep dreaming...
the same dream over and over.
Hmm.
Psychological.
What's the dream about?
Well, I'm- I'm up
on a mountain walkin'.
Somebody's with me, a-
Yeah, a girl, only I don't know who.
When I reach out, nobody's there.
I try to see her, and it gets dark.
You're not sick.
You're in love.
Numbers, whenever It happens to me,
It's always the same.
I been through this thing
30, 40 times.
I tell you, it's love.
L-U- It's love.
- Ah, your marbles are loose.
- See?
See? That's the clincher.
Now look.
I'm not a citizen what
goes around gettin' spliced.
But in your case, I advise it.
Subconscious, you want to marry Yvonne.
The dream proves it.
- Yvonne?
- Not Yvonne?
She ain't in the dream.
That I know.
- Why? Must she be? There's a law?
- No.
Only she saved our necks.
And get her sore, and-Well, a doll's a doll.
You know, they don't
think like guys.
And on top of that,
the crime committee's coming back.
Aw, can it, you and this- this love.
Your marbles ain't loose, they're cracked.
Take the dogs to the park.
I can't. They go nuts.
They wanna chase things up and down trees.
- It's embarrassing.
- Then walk 'em on the street.
Okay, okay, I'm walkin'.
But you call Yvonne up.
Hello.
My name is Yvonne Dugan.
I've been just dying to meet you all.
- It's too early for comedy. Hello.
- Oh, you remember me?
[Numbers] All right, so I ain’t been
around much lately. You know why.
- Do I?
- Yvonne, you know what I've been doing.
Your philanthropy. Of course. It must be exciting
helping out homeless but beautiful girls.
- Do y'all give autographs?
- Cut it. It ain't funny.
What's been going on
isn't funny either.
Who stuck whose neck out
to get you back? Me.
Do you ever call? Do I see you?
How do you think I feel?
You know how busy it is around here.
It doesn't keep you from working
with that hillbilly every day.
- He was only trying to get her set, Yvonne.
- You keep out of this.
It looks to everyone like you've
thrown me over, that's what. Don't say no.
Why did McNamara come to see me
at the club last night?
- McNamara?
- Nobody else.
And with an investigator
from the new crime committee.
This guy asked me if
I'll, uh, testify again.
- Oh, yeah? And just what did you say?
- Oh, don't look so worried.
I nixed it. After all,
I'm still your doll... I hope.
What do you mean, you hope?
- You are.
- Well, how was I to know?
Things aren't as they were.
We don't go out together
or anything anymore.
- And I miss you.
- Tell you what.
Emily Ann tries out today.
If she's okay, my worries are over.
She'll have a job where I can
keep my eye on her.
So maybe you and me'll do
a little celebrating tonight.
- All right?
- Tonight sounds wonderful. I'd love it.
Bye.
Oh, uh, there's just one thing.
- I don't want her to work at the Dude's.
- Why not?
That'd make me unhappy,
and you wouldn't want to do that, would you?
Tonight, darling.
Now remember, not a word to Numbers.
If he finds out about this,
he'll kill us.
[Knocking]
Well, howdy do.
Come in. Come on in.
My, it sure is mighty neighborly
of y'all to come to visit.
- Come on.
- Uh, we-we were just passing by.
- Uh, is Tess here?
- Oh, no, not yet.
I was just fixing something
to eat before I go to try out.
Here, try some candied yams.
They're awful good for you.
Mr. Lookout, you pass them around.
There are plenty.
I'll go get the pickled spareribs.
She's a sweet doll, Ropes.
Go easy, huh?
Hey, smell this, hey.
Like candy.
I'll have some corn fritters
ready in a minute.
- Try some ribs. Go ahead.
- Emily Ann, look.
We didn't exactly
come up here to eat.
You see, we, uh-
Well, we want you to blow town.
Uh, we-we even made up a nice kitty
for you so that you can travel in style.
You won't have to ride
the rods and such.
- Well, why should I? Is something wrong?
- Oh, oh, no, no.
There's nothing wrong.
It's-Well, you see...
we ain't exactly the type of citizens
that a nice young doll like you...
ought to be running
around and about with-
Some people don't think much of us.
Certain people don't even like us.
Why, they should be ashamed.
Why, you're the nicest-
the kindest folks I ever met up with,
and I'm proud we're friends.
lf'n I could choose kinfolk,
I'd choose all of you.
So don't fret no more.
Eat.
I'll go get the fritters.
Psst!
How'd she take it?
Have a candied yam.
It's good for you.
- Hiya, boy.
- What do you do, come out of holes?
- How do you feel today?
- I feel busy. What's the pitch?
- You know that new crime committee?
- Yeah.
They're gonna reopen
the investigation again in two days.
- So?
- So I was hoping maybe you'd do the right thing.
Don't worry, Mac.
I'm doing fine.
Look, this is your last chance.
Why don't you take advantage of it?
What for?
You've got nothing on me.
Not yet, maybe.
Well, you change your mind,
I'll be downtown, all right?
~ [Humming]
- Get Emily Ann, will you?
- Well, she's getting ready to dress.
- Tell her I wanna see her.
- She ain't got much time. She auditions at 4:00.
There ain't gonna be no audition.
You heard me. Move.
Tessie just says I ain't tryin' out.
That's right.
Well, don't just look like that.
Go ahead, say something.
Cry if you want to.
Oh, I forgot.
You don't cry, do you?
Was it-Was it 'cause
I ain't good enough?
No, it's not that.
It's-
Well, something came up,
something important, and that's all.
Don't ask me what.
It just can't be helped, believe me.
Oh, I do, of course.
Is it for good?
- I have to leave here, huh?
- No. Don't even say that. You're staying.
I'll figure something, some kind of an angle.
Just give me time.
No.
It ain't right.
You shouldn't feel like this.
I don't mind going.
Do you mean that?
No. Only I better.
Says who? Forget it.
Let me think.
Look. It ain't fittin' for me to worry
nobody this way, especially you.
- And I won't, you hear?
- No, I don't hear.
Now listen.
I won't tell you again.
When I owe something,
big or little, I always pay off.
- That's the way I'm built.
- I been paid back more than enough.
- Paid back? How? What?
- Well, a whole lot.
You made me real happy here,
happier than I ever been in my whole life.
And I won't never forget it,
even back home.
Home? Do you think
I could let you go back and marry that-
that cornball with the no-shave
and the tobacco out to here?
- Do you?
- Crockett ain't so bad when he's sober.
Are you out of your mind?
Would I be able to sleep or work
or even relax if I thought of him, of-
of you?
Look, I've got an idea.
You go on up in the house. I'll call you later.
~ [Big Band]
Hey, Numbers, they're all here-
booking agents, producers...
- writers, record company guys, Hollywood scouts-
- Okay, okay, blow.
- I changed as fast as I could.
- Sit down.
Have a drink.
- [Ends]
- For making me happy.
- [Fanfare]
- Hey, what is all this?
Just wait. You'll see.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
that scintillating songstress from the sunny South...
Emily Ann Stackerlee!
[Orchestra]
~ There's a spot
you ought to visit ~
~ If you don't mind hicks ~
~ And if you should ask
where is it ~
~ It's way out in the sticks ~
~ 'Bout 80 miles
outside of Atlanta ~
~ They live in
a lazy kind of way ~
- [Man] Hey!
- ~ 'Bout 80 miles ~
- Sing ‘‘Melancholy Baby."
- Outside Atlanta, G. A.
They never worry
they ain’t In a hurry
~ Because they know
they're gonna stay ~
~ 'Bout 80 miles ~
~ Outside of Atlanta, G.A. ~
~ They got the kind of doors
that never ain't had no lockin' ~
~ All they got they're
perfectly willin' to share ~
They ain't got nothin'!
~ They can't hear
ol' opportunity a-knockin' ~
~ While they're rockin'
their selves to sleep ~
~ In the rockin' chair
In the rockin' chair ~
~ The folks that'll meet you
The people that'll greet you ~
~ They sort of politely
swing and sway ~
~ 'Bout 80 miles ~
~ Outside of Atlanta, G.A. ~
B- C-D- E-F-G-A!
~ 'Bout 80 miles
outside of Atlanta ~
~ They live in
a lazy kind of way ~
~ 'Bout 80 miles ~
~ Outside of Atlanta, G.A. ~
~ The folks who meet ya ~
- Yeah!
- ~ The people who greet ya ~
- Uh-huh!
- ~ They sort of politely swing and sway ~
~ 'Bout 80 miles ~
~ Outside of Atlanta, G.A. ~
~ They got doors
that never had any lockin' ~
~ All they got they're
perfectly willing to share ~
~ They can't hear
ol' opportunity knockin' ~
~ While they're rocking
themselves to sleep ~
~ In that old rocking chair ~
~ They never worry ~
~ They ain't in a hurry ~
~ Because they know
they're gonna stay ~
~ 'Bout 80 miles ~
~ Outside of Atlanta, G.A. ~
~ Gonna leave my cares
behind me ~
~ You can always find me
in Atlanta ~
~ Atlanta ~
~ Atlanta-lanta, G.A. ~
~ G.A. ~
- See why I wanted you to wait?
- Yeah.
- More!
- Come on! More!
- We want more!
- Thank y'all. Thank you very much.
When they want more
you gotta give 'em more.
- More!
- One more!
Well, you're all real sweet,
but it's gettin'-
Oh!
There. Now don't forget:
classy and schmaltzy!
[Orchestra]
~ I wish I knew ~
Someone like you
~ Could love me ~
~ I wish I knew ~
~ You'd place no one ~
~ Above me ~
~ Did I mistake this ~
~ For a real romance ~
~ I wish I knew ~
~ But only you ~
~ Can answer ~
[Chorus Vocalizing]
[Chorus singing]
~ What shall I do ~
~ I wish ~
~ I knew ~
[Chorus, Ends]
- Wasn't she great? She'll get a job anywhere.
- Fine.
Only make sure she gets one
far away- but real far.
- See?
- Yeah.
Oh, were you great!
You killed 'em, honey!
The Ouija board was right.
What'd I tell you?
Here, sit. Did you get
a look at Yvonne? Ho-ho!
Her mouth was down to here.
Did you show her!
- I hope she busts a gasket, the snake.
- That ain't nice, Tessie.
You don't know her.
- That canary hates you.
- Hates me? Why should she?
She thinks Numbers is straying,
that's why. Hold still.
Why he ever went for her,
I'll never know.
You mean him and her,
they're bespoken?
You mean, are they a thing,
a twosome, like we say?
Sure. They been-
Hey, couldn't you tell?
No, I never knew.
Oh, Tessie.
Why didn't you tell me?
Who, me? l- I never spill
nothin' about nobody.
And l-I didn't think that-
Gee, kid, l-I'm sorry.
Honest.
[Knocking]
Get some champagne from Dave.
Well, Emily Ann,
you're really in business.
Broadway show offers, movie tests,
radio, nightclubs- all legitimate.
- Now all you do is just pick the best.
- Can I talk to you for a minute?
After you get the bottle.
Go on.
Now look, kid. Here's how I handicap it.
You'll get a lot of offers, see?
But if I was you I'd take Hollywood.
Just so you don't get lonesome, I'll send Tessie
along with you. How's that sound?
Look, kid, if you don't see it my way,
come on, tell me. It's your life.
- You want me to go away?
- Well, no.
But it's your best bet.
You get set in movies, and your worries are over.
See?
Hey, what's the matter?
Don't all this make you happy?
- I don't want to leave.
- But why?
It's a real break.
Come on. Out with it.
Well-
All right, I love you. And if you wasn't
spoken for, I'd ask you to marry me.
I was going to tonight.
But then I found out about Yvonne.
I'm sorry.
But I had to speak the truth.
Don't fret none.
I'll go.
I'll go anywhere
you think it's best.
- And I'm obliged to you for everything.
- Emily Ann, wait.
Now listen.
You don't love me.
You probably just like me,
that's all.
- Oh, no. I love you.
- But how do you know?
Why, you're just a kid.
All this is new to you. Me, I'm new to you!
You been part of me ever since we met,
every minute.
I even dream about you-
the same dream, over and over.
- You do?
- Every night.
I dream I'm walkin' on a mountain,
and it's beautiful.
- A mountain?
- Sure, a mountain. And you're walkin' with me.
- Are you sure it's me?
- I can see you real plain.
I can reach out, and I touch you.
I'll always love you,
and nobody else.
No. You've gotta find another guy.
I ain't good enough for you.
- Don't say that. You're wonderful!
- You know what I really am?
- I won't listen, you hear?
- It's the truth. I'm nothing but a-
- I won't have anyone say
anything about you, not even you.
- You've got to know.
I'm bad for a square doll, real-
I shouldn't have done that.
- Good-bye.
- That's right.
Fracture him with a kiss,
say good-bye and leave him wanting more.
- That's smart.
- You don't understand.
- Come on outside. I'll explain it.
- Why? Can't she?
Now look, Yvonne, nothing happened.
Don't start anything.
Let her stay, please.
I would like to talk to her alone.
We womenfolk can
settle things the best.
She's right.
Why don't you wait outside?
Stop worrying.
We're both ladies.
Now it's nice and ladylike.
- Start talking.
- Well, what you're thinking,
Miss Yvonne, it ain't so.
I didn't kiss him
to make him want me.
I did it to stop him from saying
awful things about hisself.
- That's truth.
- You don't want him?
When I said good-bye,
that was true too.
I'm going away,
just as soon as I can.
- Uh-huh.
- For good.
- I give you my word on that.
- Swell.
[Lock Clicks]
Now I'm going
to give you something-
a going-away present.
It ain't nice for ladies to hit.
But ladies cry.
I hear you don't.
Please!
Can't we just talk?
Cry, hillbilly, cry.
Yvonne!
Yvonne, don't you hurt her!
I should've told you, I'm an awful good wrestler.
Now can't we just talk?
Emily Ann!
Are you all right?
You double-crossing little- Ow!
Yvonne!
- Yvonne, let her go!
- [Screams]
- You all right? You're sure?
- I'm fine.
- Okay, where's that Yvonne?
- She just left.
Hey, what's with that Yvonne?
She almost ran over me coming out the other door.
- Wait'll I get her.
- No, don't. It ain't her fault.
- She only did it 'cause she loves you.
- Loves?
You know how she spells love?
M-l-N-K. Mink.
You'll see. She won't start
any more rough stuff.
- Are you sure she doesn't love you?
- Sure I'm sure.
- Don't you love her?
- Are you kiddin'? Her?
Then you ain't bespoken no how?
Look, no doll I ever liked
ever thought of getting married...
until you.
- Didn't you ever think of it?
- No.
Well, now that you
ain't really spoken for...
I'd be obliged if you'd think about
marryin' up with me.
'Cause I love you somethin' awful.
Emily Ann, I told you once before.
I'm real bad for-
[Dave]
No wonder Yvonne went to the cops.
She just now flags
a patrol car outside and gets in.
It turns around with the ‘‘sirens" blowing
and heads downtown.
- Headquarters!
- McNamara, who else?
The investigation!
We gotta lam out of town.
Hold it!
Yvonne wouldn't squeal.
But just in case she does-
just in case-we'd better hide out.
- But why?
- If she talks, the cops'll be after us.
[Dave]
I'll open the back door.
- You go to 'em and tell 'em the truth.
- That I'm a bookie?
In some states that ain't legal.
You see, making horse transactions
is somewhat considered a racket.
Tessie, here's the combination to my wall safe.
Get out the books and stash 'em away.
- I'll contact you here.
- Where you going?
Don't worry. This blows over,
I'll come back for you. If not, I'll send for you.
Oh, no, it ain't right. Can't you promise
the law not to do it again?
Look, honey, it ain't just me. I'm mixed up
with the top combination- the big syndicate.
They're big boys.
They don't like trouble.
If they're bad,
then it's all right to tell on them.
That's only part of
what they want me for.
I'd have to tell them about
my income tax returns for the last three years.
If you paid your taxes,
you could stay, couldn't you?
Sure, and have maybe five bucks left.
That ain't the way to live.
Good-bye, doll.
I love you.
Take care of her, Tess,
until you hear from me. Let's go.
- So long, kid.
- Bye.
~ [Radio: Big Band,
Melancholy]
~ I wish I knew ~
~ [Humming]
~ If you don't care ~
Why let me hope
~ And pray so ~
~ Don't lead me on ~
~ If I'm a fool ~
~Just say so ~
~ Should I keep dreaming on ~
~ Or just forget you ~
~ [Clicks Off]
[Sighs]
I know just how you feel, honey.
Well, I guess there's only
one thing left to do. Come on.
‘‘E"-
and another ‘‘E"!
- Again it spells McGee!
- What do you think it means, Tessie?
Who knows? The only McGee I ever knew
was my first husband.
But I don't get the connection.
McGee drowned off Fire Island.
He was running hooch in from Canada and he went
down holding on to a case of bonded bourbon.
Oh, it's no use. The Ouija board can't help,
and the hearing's tomorrow.
Ah, don't take it to heart, honey.
It might work out all right.
I don't know. It seems to me
he's been awful illegal.
Numbers's books!
Hey, why are they out?
I couldn't sleep last night,
so I read 'em.
Cops walk in and find these,
they won't need Yvonne-
- just handcuffs.
- [Rings]
Hello? Yes.
Oh, darling, darling.
I been waiting to hear from you.
Are you all right? Can I see you?
Easy, baby, easy. I'm fine, honest.
There's nothing to worry about.
I can't help it. It's almost tomorrow.
What are you gonna do?
What I'm doing right now: I'll just sit tight.
So will you stop worrying?
Yvonne might only be bluffing
just to get me back.
Yeah. Hey, you still wanna marry me?
Oh, yes, of course I do.
But what if she does tell on you?
I'm ready for that too. There's a tramp steamer
leaving at noon tomorrow.
- A guy I know's the captain.
If I have to, I'll be on it.
- Oh, no!
Baby, will you stop?
It'll be okay. I'll send for you.
Europe, South America maybe.
Yeah, we'll live like kings.
- I brought the loot right with me.
- How're the dogs?
- Listen, Poorly wants to know how the dogs are.
- Oh, Nip and Tuck?
- [Knocking]
- Tell him they're all right.
You know something?
I love you, doll.
I've been missing you like I never missed
anybody else ever before.
Oh, darling.
I miss you too.
Why, Inspector McNamara.
Come in.
Come on in, Inspector McNamara.
Uh, hello, Fannie. Tessie.
How's Clarence?
- The cops are at Tessie's!
- Did you tell her where we were?
No, but they can trace the call.
Let's go!
Yeah. And tell him to take
some bicarbonate, Fannie.
Kiss the baby.
Bye.
- Was that Numbers on the phone?
- Numbers? What, are you crazy or something?
- Yes, sir, it was.
- What did he say?
- You don't have to tell him. You got rights.
- He said he loves me.
That's a good thing to know.
Very good.
So now you know.
So go already.
You love him too, don't you?
- Want to help him?
- Yes, sir, I do.
- So do I.
- Kid, he's a cop.
- I believe him, Tessie.
- You can.
You see, Numbers and I grew up
together in Hell's Kitchen.
We raided pushcarts together to eat.
Matter of fact, we even went
to the reform school together.
When we got out, we-
Well, anyhow, I know him.
The kid's got a lot of good in him-
a whole lot.
And with you to love him,
he can really straighten out.
- He will. I know it.
- Yeah, I'm banking on It too.
Only...
he might have to pay a little-
maybe a year up the river.
A year.
That ain't long, is it?
Maybe it will be
to Numbers and Poorly.
I don't think they'll be very happy
being locked up so long.
You think they'd rather
do five to 10, Tussle?
Look, I just left Yvonne.
She's sore in spades.
So this is it.
Numbers has to be there tomorrow
before she testifies, or else.
lf'n he does, Mr. McNamara,
is that a promise?
Only one year?
Well, I think maybe
I can arrange it.
~ [Melody]
You see, the committee's interested in
the big-time operators- the syndicate.
Up to now, they haven't been able
to get close to 'em- no evidence.
Numbers talks,
it's our first big break.
~ [Resumes Melody,
Key Broken]
Well, if he does decide to talk,
tell him to bring his books along, huh?
For proof.
The meeting’s set for tomorrow at 100.
Yvonne won't be late.
I hope he gets there first-
for your sake too.
- Tessie, we've got to find him.
- Where did you say Numbers was calling from?
He didn't say.
The Ouija board was right.
McGee drowned, and now they're going on a boat.
What're we gonna do, Tessie?
Find 'em! Where, I don't know.
It might take some time.
- First we better get Solly the Snatcher.
- Who's he?
Occasionally he kidnaps people.
I'll have him take Yvonne out of town for
a couple of days. We can't take any chances.
Hello, operator?
Oh, uh, just one more thing, Tessie.
Don't try any hipky-dripky
with Yvonne, huh?
We're having her place guarded.
- Find him, Tessie, find him!
- Yeah, yeah. Operator?
[Tussle]
Well, so where'd you look next?
Yeah. You're sure?
All right, all right.
Don't get sore.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'll be here.
8:00.
Only five hours left.
Still no dice. Nobody's seen him
or even heard from him yet.
- They hid out for real this time.
- If we could only-
Oh, how? You heard me
call Harry the Hack. He checked.
They didn't take cabs.
They hoofed it. Didn't leave no tracks.
We ain't playing with kids,
you know.
Look. Poorly's muffler.
Five to one he's got
tonsillitis already.
[Whining]
They miss him a lot.
Go say I'm crazy, but so do I.
After Yvonne testifies,
we'll miss both of them for a long, long time.
No! I'm not gonna let it happen!
I love him too much!
Nip, Tuck! Come on!
Track 'em, boys! Come on! Track 'em!
[Barking]
- [Band]
- One, two, three, four...
- five, six, seven, eight.
- Track 'em!
- Hey!
Track 'em, boys!
[Squeals]
- [Barking]
- Hey!
Track 'em!
[Squeals]
[Barking]
- Track 'em! Track 'em!
- [Barking]
[Calllope]
Hmm.
I got again-what you say- ‘‘ginge."
- [Bell Tingles]
- Oh, customers.
I go now.
How can such a screwball do this to me?
Three blitzes.
Hey, wait'll I see that Lookout Louie.
His grandmother's dishonest.
- Look at this, Numbers- marked cards.
- Hey. Hear anything?
- [Dogs Barking]
- Yeah, it's them. It's Nip and Tuck.
- They tracked us here. How about that?
- Stupid!
Who do you think'll be tracking them?
Yeah, the cops. Come on. Let's go.
Wait a minute.
- Wait a minute.
- Yeah, we finally lost 'em.
Why'd she do it, Poorly?
Why?
Numbers, I don't know.
Come on.
- Where's the ship at?
- Three miles out.
They said the motorboat
would be under the pier.
Poorly, I still don't get it.
Why'd she do it? Why?
[Poorly]
Hey!
Emily Ann and no cops!
Oh, darling, darling!
- Oh, darling!
- Why'd you track us down? What for?
- To find you.
- Supposing the cops followed you!
- I didn't care.
- Didn't care?
- They'd have had us this fast.
Didn't you think about that?
- [Dog Whines]
Numbers, look.
They brought me my muffler!
You go down and get
that boat started!
- Don't be mad at me. Please listen.
- Some other time.
We're in big trouble, kid.
We gotta get away. Go back to Tessie's.
- No, don't leave!
- I told you to go back, didn't I?
- We get caught, you'll be in Dutch too.
- If you run away, I'll just die!
Oh, baby, baby.
No, I'm not leaving you.
You're coming with me.
The captain can marry us,
and we'll have our honeymoon in Europe.
- Let's go.
- I can't do it.
- Why not?
- It's wrong to run away.
When the heat's off and I can
operate here again, we'll come back.
- Until then, we'll live fine anywhere. Let's go.
- Wait.
I saw Inspector McNamara today.
He said if you testified, you'd only get a year.
- What?
- And you can start out fresh.
- You can believe him, 'cause he's honest.
- So what?
Did he tell you how much I'd have left after I pay
the taxes? And what happens when I get out?
What do I do, shovel snow or hack cabs
or press pants maybe?
I wouldn't care, 'cause I love you.
- You love me, and you still want me to go to jail?
- It'll do you good.
- You'll come out honest.
- Yeah? Well, I'm not going to any jail.
I'm going on that boat.
- You coming or not?
- No, and if you go you'll drown.
- Says who?
- The Ouija board. It came up ‘‘McGee."
McGee! That's right,
he drowned not far from here.
This is your last chance.
Oh, please stay.
A year ain't long, and then you won't
have to run no more.
And we can get married
and have babies.
- Yes or no?
- [Sobbing]
- Shove off.
- [Motor Revving]
[Barks]
You know, Numbers, whether it's
a doll or a dog, it's all the same.
When they cry, it just kills me.
Hey, she was crying.
She is crying! Look!
[Loud Sobbing]
[Ship Horn Blowing]
[Screams]
[Chattering]
- No more room inside.
- But they can't start without me.
Start?
They're almost finished, lady.
[Numbers] And that's how I handle the play.
I also have to pay off the syndicate.
Well, tell them the names, darlin'.
There's Liver Lip Louie in Chicago,
Sammy the Shtunk in Newark...
and Very Big Joe in Cleveland.
- They're all listed in the books we gave you.
- Thank you.
- Would you care to say anything about your taxes?
- Well, uh-
They're listed in the books
we gave you too, sir.
He owes $304,000.18.
We got it right here.
It leaves $5.42 left over.
[Sniffling]
Charlie, I've lost him.
You still got me.
So long, boy. I guess I can forget
about you for at least a year, huh?
What's a year? We'll be out before
you can say ‘‘Dave the Dude's."
[Orchestra]
[Chorus singing]
~ They called him Jack O'Diamonds
on the riverboat route ~
~ He was the Jack O'Diamonds
'cause the jacks were his suit ~
~ It was spectacular to see
the way he was dressed ~
~ With diamonds big as buttons
popping out of his vest ~
And you ought to see him struttin' ~
~ With those diamonds
big as buttons popping out of his vest ~
~ He was the king of gamblers
and the kind of a guy ~
~ Who loved to bet a bundle
without battin' an eye ~
~ The gals affectionately
loved to hang on his neck ~
~ But Jack O'Diamonds's heart
was just as cold as his deck ~
~ They loved to see him bettin'
and they loved to have him pettin' ~
~ But old Jack O'Diamonds's heart
was just as cold as his deck ~
~ One night the boat docked
in New Orleans ~
~ And who came aboard ~
~ But Lily the flower of the South ~
~ She was as shy as a violet ~
~ A picture so sweet ~
~ That sugar cane would melt
right in her mouth ~
~ She looked at Jack O'Diamonds
and his heart was aflame ~
~ She smiled at Jack O'Diamonds
and suggested a game ~
~ He opened strong with jacks
but Lily didn't give beans ~
~ She topped his jack of diamonds
with a couple of queens ~
~ And as the crowd gathered round
he started dealing with skill ~
~ Displaying his celebrated art ~
~ And though he pulled every trick
it wasn't long until Lil ~
~ Relieved him of his bankroll
and his heart ~
~ And now with Jack O'Diamonds
facing terrible times ~
~ He's down to penny-ante games
for nickels and dimes ~
~ And as the Mississippi
paddle wheeler departs ~
~ He's left without his glory ~
~ And the moral of the story ~
~ Is that Jack O'Diamonds ~
~ Shouldn't trifle ~
~ With hearts ~
[Orchestra Resumes]
13.16. Right.
- 32.20. Right.
- Hi, darling.
Hey, baby.
Well, better and more beautiful every night.
- [Clears Throat]
- Ooh. 32.80. Right.
Garçon!
Some guy just had his wallet lifted
on table number five.
Do you know anything about it?
Go ahead.
Okay.
Hey!
[Chorus Resumes, Indistinct]
I couldn't help it.
C'est la guerre.
I have to change now.
- Y'all comin' back, ma'am?
- You can lay six, two and even.
- Who with? Very Big Joe in Cleveland?
- No, with Little me right here.
[Chorus singing]
[Ends]