(BAND SINGING)
Is everything
to your liking, ma'am?
It's an unusually cheerful
spectacle, Captain Martos.
When we're becalmed
like this, we might as well
enjoy ourselves.
When I arrive in New Orleans
I shall enjoy myself,
but not until then.
(CHUCKLES)
That pirate, Baptiste,
is an obsession with her.
Every strange sail we sight
calls for a fresh bottle
of smelling salts.
(LAUGHS)
Why, ma'am, you couldn't
be safer if you were
in your own drawing room.
In a calm like this,
no pirate
could ever get to us.
Not even Baptiste.
Fetch me that fiddler, Tom.
He's better
than the one we got.
Aye, aye, sir.
(BELL RINGING)
Four bells and all's well!
MAN: Pirates! Pirates!
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
Baptiste!
Mr. Roberts,
you guard the ladies.
You men, arm yourselves
and get on deck!
(MEN SHOUTING)
(PISTOL FIRES)
Well, thank you, son.
Thank you, son.
Don't let them forget
that China silk, Tom.
Aye.
And did you fetch
along the fiddler?
He went
with the spice bales.
(LAUGHS)
What do you intend to
do with us, pirate?
Set you adrift
in the small boats,
along with the passengers.
Unless there's any
amongst you who
would volunteer?
Think you any of my men
would serve with you?
Well, not a lad amongst us
hasn't served on a vessel
of Alexander Narbonne.
Tell that to your master,
if your small boat's lucky
enough to be picked up.
At the same time
I'll request the privilege
of being present
when Narbonne
has you hanged from
your own yardarm.
Why bother Narbonne?
I'll invite you myself.
(CHUCKLES)
Now, how many men
would rather
transfer registry
than hit the small boats?
Small boats always
make me crazy.
I'll take
the skull and bones.
So will I.
Wise lads, Captain.
(LAUGHS)
Here be one we missed.
Better drag him in.
Easy with them
powder casks.
MAN: Aye, aye, sir!
Strip her rigging clean.
MAN 1: Aye, aye, sir!
Seems like
we're all through.
Scuttler, weigh below
and make sure
she settles fast.
Here's something we found.
Well, a cabin boy, eh?
Well, son,
would you like to sign on
with Frederic Baptiste?
Speak up, can't you...
Well, lower me jib a bustle.
Very nice to meet you.
Is this new gear on
all the Narbonne craft?
How did you get aboard?
It was easy.
But if I'd known
you were going to get
your moldy old ship
captured by a gang
of cutthroats,
I'd have stayed in Boston.
Stowaway, eh?
Put her in the boat
with the other women.
Pulled away.
Then she'll have to go
in the longboat with them.
And get going before
I change my mind and make you
swim back to New Orleans.
Come on, you...
Wait a minute.
I've got two dresses
in that boat and
I'm not leaving without them.
You know, he's making
a big mistake putting one
woman in with all those men.
You wouldn't be thinking...
That she'd be safer with us?
Precisely.
Oh, no, you don't.
It's all for your safety...
No, you don't.
(GRUNTING)
Let me down, you big ape!
(GROANS)
You near scratched
my ear off.
Good.
You just don't know
how to handle a lady.
(SCREAMING)
See what I mean?
If you don't put me down...
Imagine all those
poor defenseless men
alone in a small boat
with a dangerous female
like this?
Here, take her.
When I get down in the boat,
hand her to me.
(SPLASHING)
(LAUGHING)
You just don't know
how to handle a lady.
MAN: Ouch!
Quiet.
Help me, Kryl. Help me.
Keep her quiet now.
(GROANING)
You near bit me ear off!
Ow!
Take her, Kryl! Take her!
You little devil, you...
(SCREAMING)
You think my hand's
a blooming sea biscuit?
Touch me again
and I'll bite your arm off.
We gotta get her below decks
before the other boats
get back.
You and your wonderful idea.
We should've
dumped her overboard.
Ow!
Quiet!
Whatever you have up there,
bring it down here.
(GROANING)
Ow!
What goes on out there?
Let me down. Let me down.
By the Dog Star!
A female.
I've been kidnapped!
And I demand
that you do something
about it.
She was stowed away
aboard the Gulf Queen, sir.
But somehow
she got herself
in our boat, sir.
I'll discuss that
with you later.
Meanwhile, leave her here.
Aye, aye, sir.
With the greatest
of pleasure.
Turn around.
Who are you?
The captain of this vessel.
But I thought...
Then who was the other?
Jared? My mate.
Fortunately, many people
make the same mistake.
Then you must be...
Frederic Baptiste,
the bloodthirsty pirate,
the scourge of
the Mexican government,
that fiend in human shape.
At your service, mademoiselle.
Up to a point.
Somebody's
been exaggerating.
Oh?
Or maybe they haven't.
(TITTERING)
Look what your men
have done to me.
You'll find ointment
in that chest, Miss...
Deborah McCoy.
Debbie, they call me.
Where were you headed,
Debbie?
Oh, New Orleans, Rio.
I wasn't sure.
To visit?
No.
They say that
they're good places for
a girl to earn her living.
And this living,
how did you propose
to make it?
I'm an entertainer.
I sing a little
and I dance a little.
You know, you combine
all the elements
of a first-class problem.
Why?
All you have to do
is put me ashore somewhere.
(CHUCKLES)
And stretch my neck
by doing it?
I know how to
keep a tight mouth.
After all, they say
you only attack the ships
of Alexander Narbonne.
I don't even know who he is.
The richest man
in New Orleans.
Or used to be.
Oh.
He'd be a good one
to know, wouldn't he?
That depends on
one's point of view.
Why do you give his ships
your special attention?
That's my point of view.
Tell me, how long
have you been making
your own way, Debbie?
Too long.
No one to help you?
Too many.
I still can't decide
what to do about you.
The sailors
were given a chance
to sign on with you.
I believe I have
a more practical solution
than that.
I knew
you'd think of something.
We'll maroon you
on a sand spit.
Oh.
I'm sure
you can think of something
better than that.
Why, no.
It's a perfect way
to handle the situation.
We'll pick a sand spit
on the sea lanes
to South America.
If you're picked up,
you'll get to Rio.
And if not, you'll be on
a clean white beach
protected by palm trees.
You'll soon grow to love it.
Finished, captain.
We stripped her clean.
Cargo aboard and stowed.
Not a bad haul
for a ship her size.
Oh. These must be
worth a fortune.
I thought
I ordered you set adrift.
Oh, you did, but somehow
the orders got mixed up.
You'd better find a cabin
for our passenger.
A cabin?
Anything will do.
She'll only be with us
until we sight
a suitable sand spit.
But I thought...
Good night, Debbie.
Sleep as well as you can.
Away with you.
(BELL RINGING)
Another four days
and that girl will have them
wearing lace on their drawers.
Yeah, that's
a fair shame, sir.
It's always been me pride
we had the roughest
and dirtiest crew
in the Mexican gulf.
I can't stand to
look at it anymore.
Good afternoon.
Where did you
get that dress?
Oh, this?
It's just a little old thing
Jared rummaged for me
in a chest.
Jared, eh?
So he rummaged it
for you in a chest,
did he?
Well, take it off.
Oh, were you taking it
to someone?
How awful of Jared
not to tell me.
But, after all,
she won't know, will she?
I will.
But you'll forget.
You'll forget about me
and the dress, these last
few days, everything.
At least I'll try.
While I sit on my sand spit
and remember.
I told you
to take that dress off.
All right.
You needn't shout.
Not here.
(RIPPING)
Now look what you've done
to the hem.
Afternoon, Miss Debbie.
Good afternoon,
Bertram.
He's been telling me
about his sister.
I remind him of her.
He never had a sister.
Oh, the poor fellow.
He's had such a sad life.
He's had the kind of life
he wants.
So have I. Up to now.
Jared!
Now, you mustn't be
angry with Jared.
Miss McCoy, you've teased
and wheedled everybody
aboard this ship.
You've shot all discipline
to shreds and now you tell me
how to treat my crew.
It's time I put a stop to it.
You'd be wanting
to see me, sir?
Cram on full sail.
I mean to be in and out
of New Orleans before dawn.
Aye, aye, sir.
Oh, I hate to think of
your running such a risk
just to take me
where I want to go.
You're not going
ashore. I am.
And the moment I get back
we head for the Tortugas,
where you'll stay
and no doubt do very well.
Now, go to your cabin
and stay there.
And take off that dress!
Keep her steady.
More gray hairs
for Narbonne.
It's a pity you won't be there
in the morning
to see them sprout.
He'll be bald
before I'm through.
(LAUGHS)
Jared, if there's any
trouble with that girl,
I'll hold you responsible.
Oh, you needn't
fret about her, sir.
She's locked in the cabin.
I have the key right here
in my pocket.
Well, I'd better put it
Then I know
she won't cause any trouble.
Aye, aye, sir.
Cast off.
(SINGING)
(SIGHS)
Good morning, Mama.
It's a beautiful morning,
isn't it?
So it's a beautiful morning.
What about it?
You look tired, Mama.
Go inside and rest.
We have no time to rest.
The customers
are already in the market.
We gotta put the rest
of the vegetables on...
No, no, no, Mama.
Later.
Out of my way.
I was wondering when I...
Sorry, but you should
have let me out.
So this is where
you keep her.
Mama, I swear,
I never saw her before.
After 20 years,
you keep a woman
in the vegetable box.
It isn't true!
After 20 years, I didn't!
I never saw your husband
before in my life.
I slept in there last night
because I had no place else
to go.
Liar.
Mama.
Hag.
No, no, no, please.
Mama... Police! Police!
Please, Mama, don't.
Joseph,
hadn't you better go?
If Madame Brizar
will pardon me.
Of course.
Police! Police! Police!
Please, Mama!
I wouldn't have your husband
on a salad with mayonnaise!
He's good enough for me,
but he's not
good enough for you?
Police! Mama!
You know what?
If he's so good
you can have him.
Please stop screaming
for me. I'm here.
Now what is the cause
for this disturbance?
He hid her
in our vegetable closet.
I never saw her before.
He lies.
With my own eyes I saw her.
For 20 years,
she accuses me
of flirting with every woman
who comes to buy vegetables!
Because it took me
20 years to catch him!
Believe me, Mr. Policeman.
I didn't do anything.
I open the closet door
and there she is!
OFFICER: Silence!
I can't hear you
for the shouting.
Go inside.
The rest of you, disperse.
Madame Brizar's
compliments, mademoiselle.
She wants to see you.
Look, I'm in a hurry,
and I'm in trouble enough.
Then you should want
to see Madame Brizar.
This way, please.
Madame Brizar.
Did you want to see me?
Yes.
You could be
very attractive, my girl.
What's your name?
Deborah McCoy.
Stand back a little,
so that
I can see you better.
Hmm.
Not too bad. Not too bad.
There she is!
By the carriage!
Get in, Deborah.
Why?
Because that policeman
is looking for you.
Now drive on.
Do you mind
if I ask a question?
By all means.
Where are we going?
Home.
Come, come, child.
In we go.
You may put
the carriage away.
Yes, madame.
Come, Deborah.
Good morning, Toussaint.
Good morning, ma'am.
Monsieur Narbonne
and Monsieur Patout
are waiting.
Oh. At this early hour?
Well, don't stand there
and gawk. Come in, darling.
Sit down, child, sit down.
(SIGHS)
Monsieur Narbonne.
Such an honor.
Good morning, madame.
I'm giving a soirée
for the Governor
and his wife tonight,
and Patout
has just reminded me
that we have no entertainers.
You remember my secretary?
Certainly I remember
Monsieur Patout.
He always brings the check.
No doubt.
There was
a light-haired girl
last time
who was unusually pretty,
if a bit gauche.
What was her name, Patout?
Cleo, sir.
Ah, yes, one of
my loveliest girls.
Very lovely,
despite her unfortunate habit
of singing off-key.
Oh, that has been overcome,
Monsieur Narbonne.
She no longer sings.
She dances.
Splendid.
Then send her along,
by all means.
Well, and who is this?
Somebody
who should not be here.
Now, make your curtsy, child,
and run along.
Go on, run along.
So you're Monsieur Narbonne?
Well, hello.
Hello.
I've heard a lot about you
from mutual friends.
Really? How nice.
Come, Patout.
9:00 this evening,
Madame Brizar.
You can leave everything
to me, as usual.
I'll send you
a shower of talent and beauty.
"Hello," she says.
Haven't you even
the slightest training?
So far I've always
done all right.
I've never been
so mortified.
Perhaps I've made
a serious mistake.
Perhaps you have.
And then again,
maybe I'm the one
who's made the mistake.
"Hello," she says.
Hmm!
Oh, Toussaint.
Yes, ma'am.
Will you tell Delphine
and Cleo
that I wish to see them?
Yes, ma'am.
I'll tell them.
And don't stoop.
Your posture's
most unbecoming.
What's the matter
with my posture?
Oh, it fails utterly
to suggest the languid grace
of the swan,
or the more piquant movements
of the male partridge.
Huh?
Good morning, madame.
You wanted to see us?
Another affair
at Monsieur Narbonne's.
Delphine, you will wear
the white lace.
But it makes me
look so young.
Well, that's what
we have in mind, darling.
And, Cleo, you will wear
the black dress
and look your best tonight.
Monsieur Narbonne
expressed some interest
in you.
It worked.
I told you,
if I sang off-key,
he'd notice me.
Is he really the richest man
in New Orleans?
He's not only very rich,
he's very single.
Oh, Delphine, Cleo.
This is Deborah McCoy,
who may stay with us.
Now, after I've had
my coffee,
we'll discuss
your qualifications,
and then I'll decide.
Oh, Toussaint?
Toussaint, my coffee
in the study, please.
She can take her time
over that coffee.
I've decided for her.
What a lot of time
I've wasted living in Boston.
Higher, higher, much higher.
Higher all around.
Much higher.
This is for the Seamen's
Fund brawl next Tuesday
night at the Catfish.
Will Monsieur Narbonne
be there?
Monsieur never goes
to brawls.
When do I get to go
where he goes?
Well, after you've had
the rough edges
knocked off.
Another month
and you might be ready
for a gentleman's party.
A man is no different
because of his clothes.
Gentlemen prefer
another type of girl.
A slouchier,
more indifferent type.
Practice looking slouchy
and indifferent.
(CLAPPING)
After your song,
there will of course
be applause,
and then, no doubt,
you will be summoned
to the table of your host,
Captain Kingston.
Now, I will be
Good evening, Captain.
How about buying me a drink?
No. No. No. No.
The approach
is much too abrupt.
Well, it always
worked before.
Well, maybe, in
your prosaic Boston,
but here in New Orleans,
the gentlemen prefer
a more roundabout course.
Especially Captain Kingston.
He's a great favorite
with our first families.
That guarantees
he'll be a first-class bore.
Debbie, Captain Kingston,
as head of the Seamen's Fund,
gives these parties
to entertain
his seafaring friends,
not to entertain you.
Now, you are Captain Kingston.
Observe me.
(SNICKERING) Ah, Captain.
(DELIGHTED LAUGHTER)
The city has been desolate
while you were away.
Fetch me a beer, wench.
The Captain
only drinks champagne.
And remember,
we get an extra five percent
from the management
of the Catfish.
I still think
you're making a mistake
sending me to a fish fry.
My talents belong
in the drawing room.
Ridiculous, child.
You can't fly
until you've walked.
Tonight, you will attend
the party at the Catfish
with the other girls.
Now, once more.
(LAUGHING)
Captain Kingston.
(SIGHING)
And did you have
an interesting trip?
Interesting enough.
Except for a brush
with the pirate Baptiste.
No, no.
You must never mention
anything unpleasant.
Unpleasant?
The very name of that monster
must be avoided
when talking with
seafaring men,
especially Captain Kingston.
He is a privateer
commissioned to catch pirates.
Confine your conversation
to subjects
that are soothing.
I wonder why I am so sure
I am going to
dislike Captain Kingston.
No, don't start that again.
Besides, you've got
to rehearse your song again.
Come along.
Back to work.
Back to the piano.
Now, from the beginning.
Are you ready?
One, two, three.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(MEN CHEERING)
(CLATTERING)
You near bit me ear off.
I only wanted you to
share a bottle with me.
Oh?
Here. Now you have
one all to yourself.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Stop that. Stop that.
Tonight everybody in my place
is supposed to be friendly.
That's just it.
He's too friendly.
I may even report
this to Madame Brizar.
Oh, so you're the singer?
I was. In this air,
I don't know.
Well, you'll get used to it.
Besides, you're late.
Why didn't you come
with the other girls?
BAPTISTE: No doubt
she had something
better to do.
Good evening.
What are you doing here?
That's a fine question,
hey, Captain Kingston?
Asking the host
what he's doing
in his own party.
(CHUCKLING)
Captain Kingston?
At your service,
mademoiselle.
Up to a point.
So now you're here
in New Orleans
to entertain us?
Yes.
Oh, it's such an honor
you have conferred.
I am so gratified
to be at your party, pirate.
Careful.
The city has been
absolutely desolate
while you were away.
Debbie, will you please
remember my neck?
Oh, I shall remember it.
Every moment
while I'm singing.
You won't go away,
will you?
Hardly.
We have so much in common.
So many things
to discuss, uh,
Captain Kingston.
Gentlemen,
attention, please.
We're about to be entertained
by a charming young lady,
who I'm sure will capture you,
as she has captured me.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
It gives me great pleasure
to introduce to you
Mademoiselle...
I do not believe
I know your name,
mademoiselle.
Take a chance.
The first name
you think of.
Ah, yes, my friends,
Mademoiselle Deborah McCoy.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(PIANO PLAYING)
(SINGING) One good look
and you can tell
That I was brought up
very well
(MEN LAUGHING)
An education
gives a girl a certain air
As the French would say,
savoir-faire
You want a song
I have the words for it
Something light
and gay, monsieur
You want a dance
I have the steps for it
Anything you say, monsieur
I've even learned
how to say "no, no"
As every lady should
Yes, everything
I've learned to do
Oui, oui,
I've learned to do good
(MEN LAUGHING)
You want my heart
You're just the man for it
I'm the girl for you,
I'm sure
If you want my song
If you want my dance
If you want my heart
You will have the chance
Monsieur, monsieur
Oh, you have
but to say the word
You want a kiss
I have the lips for it
If you'd care
to try, monsieur
You want my love
I have the arms for it
That's the reason why,
monsieur
Since I was young
I was always taught
A lady must obey
(LAUGHING)
So everything
I'm told to do, I do
Oui, oui, s'il vous plaît
You have a ring
I've got the place for it
And you know the place,
I'm sure
If you want my lips
If you want my arms
I will take the ring
You can have my charms
Monsieur, monsieur
You have but to say the word
(ALL CHEERING)
Charming.
You would've been wasted
in the Tortugas.
You're very kind, sir,
but it's no thanks to you
that I'm not there now.
Just to satisfy
my curiosity,
how did you get here?
There are a few questions
I'd like to ask you, Captain,
just to satisfy my curiosity.
Then I'll strike
a bargain with you.
You ignore my questions
and I'll ignore yours.
If these people only knew
that the great
Captain Kingston
was really a...
I think it unlikely
they will ever know,
unless you tell them.
But the danger,
especially with
a price on your head...
Exists only if,
by an odd coincidence,
somebody who'd been
aboard my ship should turn up
in New Orleans.
And in that event?
I would use every means
to protect myself.
(DRUM ROLL)
As you all know,
our Seamen's Fund
came into being some years ago
when shipping in New Orleans
was at a standstill
and our seamen
were hungry and jobless.
Virtually every
New Orleans shipowner
was ruined
by the barbarous
acts of piracy
of that infamous cutthroat,
Baptiste!
(ALL BOOING)
(HISSING)
Any ship not destroyed
by Baptiste was bought
by Alexander Narbonne,
who soon controlled
all the shipping
in these Gulf waters.
Unfortunately for us,
Monsieur Narbonne chose
to man his fleet
with crews from other ports.
(ALL BOOING)
At this time,
when our situation
seemed hopeless,
a friend and benefactor
came to our aid,
Captain Kingston.
(ALL CHEERING)
Close your mouth, Debbie.
Ye be a friend of
the Captain's, be n't ye?
I be.
Then why sit alone?
Come on and join
some more of his friends.
My friends, you're all
familiar with the terms
of my father's will,
directing that
certain investments
be made
for the benefit
of the Seamen's Fund.
Once more
I bring you good news.
During the past six months
these investments have shown
substantial profits.
Tonight the Seamen's Fund
is in a position
to outfit three more ships,
for captains whose vessels
were destroyed by
the pirate Baptiste.
The gold for this purpose
will be turned over
to the Seamen's Fund
tomorrow morning.
(ALL CHEERING)
To your health, Captain.
Thank you.
And now you are to
entertain me.
Very well.
Do we sing, dance
or fight?
We decide on the way home.
I be just telling
the little lady all about ye.
Yes. He was telling me
that if anyone could
catch Baptiste, you could.
Heaven knows,
I try hard enough,
but he constantly seems
to elude me.
Why don't you try
standing still for a while?
You might catch him.
He's on his way out.
Be ready.
Orlande?
Whip up, Orlande.
(NEIGHING)
No, you don't!
Not a sound out of you.
Hurry up with it!
Ow!
Run for it!
Are you all right?
Thanks to your teeth.
I seem to recall
they're very sharp.
Who were those men?
I don't know.
But I know
what they were after.
My ring, and they got it.
But I doubt
if it'll make the new owner
very happy when he gets it.
Well, you're hurt.
You'd better get to
a doctor at once.
Oh, it's nothing serious.
Debbie, you're out very late,
and apparently
in very bad company.
Good work, Orlande.
And now to Madame Brizar's.
Yes, sir. Giddap.
Easy there.
Those are the first words
you've said all evening
that make any sense.
Why, Debbie, I thought
I'd made everything
very clear.
You certainly did.
As Baptiste you sink ships.
Then as Kingston
you turn the proceeds
into a fund to outfit ships
for people whose ships
have been sunk by Baptiste.
Very clear.
It does sounds
a little complicated.
Suppose we put it this way.
Some people need help,
so I help them.
And in doing it,
I right some old wrongs.
But what if they
should catch you?
Then I should be very sorry.
New Orleans
is such a lovely place,
and the ladies in it
even lovelier.
By the way, Debbie,
if you were a man
wanted by the authorities,
and the secret of
your identity rested
with a certain girl,
would you continue
to worry about it?
I'd say the girl was
the least of my worries.
The others I'm sure
I can handle.
Good night, Debbie.
Well?
There's no
doubt about it.
It's the ring
you gave Baptiste.
Your initials
are on the inside.
So now
we've finished guessing.
The real Baptiste is dead.
And Kingston
must have killed him.
What a pity.
And more the pity
he didn't die quickly
before talking.
Without the ring,
Kingston can prove nothing.
I wish
I could be sure of that.
He flaunted this ring
before me
in my own house.
Whether to inform me
that he had more evidence,
or merely to worry me
that he might have,
I don't know.
If he had more evidence,
he's had ample time
to present it to the Governor.
Unfortunately,
he's much cleverer
than you.
I used the real Baptiste
to eliminate the competition
of Kingston's father
and the other shipowners.
So now Kingston
turns pirate,
calls himself Baptiste,
and employs the same method
against me.
(SCOFFS)
Eight of my ships sunk,
and eight others outfitted.
It's no wonder he prefers
the present situation.
If it continues much longer,
he will have destroyed you
completely.
Unless we destroy him first,
at sea
where he should be destroyed.
You know, Patout,
I rather fancy being a hero,
ridding the seas
of this new Baptiste.
(HUMMING)
Well? Do you approve?
Not bad. Not bad.
A few minor corrections,
and not bad at all.
A little too much rouge,
perhaps.
Monsieur Narbonne
prefers a pale appearance.
It's not rouge, and I don't
intend to stick my face
in a flour barrel
just to please
Monsieur Narbonne.
Debbie, please remember,
when I found you,
you had your face
in a vegetable bin.
Ever since you've been here
I've heard nothing but
"When do I entertain
at Monsieur Narbonne's?"
Now the time is here,
Monsieur Patout
has made a point
of asking for your presence,
you're suddenly
very nonchalant
about the most
eligible bachelor
in New Orleans.
Oh, not at all.
I couldn't be
more interested.
Then you might show it.
Oh, to me, of course,
not to him.
Any more instructions?
Yes.
Stay away from the ladies,
sing your song, retire to
your dressing room...
And be particularly pleasant
to that little worm,
Monsieur Patout.
By all means.
He's very close
to Monsieur Narbonne.
And he can stay there.
I intend to stay close
to Captain Kingston.
Oh.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Good evening.
I'm from Madame Brizar's.
Oh. This way please.
This should convince you
of what
you're missing, Captain.
There's nothing like it
at sea.
Fortunately for my crew.
You can't be
that thirsty, Captain.
Debbie,
what a pleasant surprise.
That makes us even.
I was surprised when I heard
you were going to be here.
Why, I wouldn't miss one
of Narbonne's soirées
for all his ships at sea.
Darling,
you'd better come here
and defend yourself.
Patout's complaining
to Uncle again.
Pardon me, Debbie.
A summons from
His Excellency, the Governor.
We will all be
looking forward
to hearing you sing.
Mademoiselle, the entertainers
wait in another room.
I meant no offense,
Captain.
It's just that
I'm so concerned
about Monsieur Narbonne
and the losses
he has suffered.
A familiar complaint,
Robert. Why haven't
you hung Baptiste?
Ah, Your Excellency,
the ocean is vast,
the sea lanes many.
Where he is, I am not.
Where I am, he is not.
But someday we shall meet.
In the meantime,
Patout here is worried.
It seems that one of
Narbonne's ships
is leaving Spain next week
with a very rich cargo,
and he fears...
Forgive me,
your Excellency,
but I meant that information
to be kept in confidence.
If word should get out...
Well, Baptiste's ear
seems to be in as many places
as his ship.
Of course, Patout,
I understand. Rest assured,
it will go no further.
Not a soul will hear it
from my lips.
Enough of Baptiste.
Let's speak of
something pleasant.
I'll arrange
for the entertainment
to begin.
I noticed you
recognized our singer.
Ah, yes.
And I can recommend
her very highly.
Oh, so that's who
the young lady was.
For a moment
I was almost jealous.
Delightful evening,
Monsieur Narbonne.
It's always a pleasure
to see you, madame.
It worked like a charm,
even better
than we'd hoped.
Oh?
The Governor himself
told him about
our ship from Spain
and I pretended
that the Governor had
breached a confidence.
Splendid. Splendid.
In that case, Patout,
I think we can feel secure
that our three ships
from Paris will arrive safely
in New Orleans.
Has our entertainer
arrived yet?
Yes, and Captain Kingston
seemed quite pleased
to see her,
which Mademoiselle Villon
noticed.
Good. Perhaps tonight
we will kill one bird
with two stones.
Fetch the singer.
Good evening.
WOMAN: Good evening,
monsieur.
Ah, Mademoiselle Villon.
We see far too little of you
when the Captain is away.
And the Captain is away
far too often.
I'll take that
as a compliment, Arlene.
Or is it a warning,
Kingston?
Remember, a fiancée
is not yet a wife.
How very discerning,
monsieur.
And, Robert,
how very true.
(PATOUT CLAPPING)
Ladies and gentlemen, it is
Monsieur Narbonne's pleasure
to present a singer
who comes
highly recommended.
Mademoiselle McCoy.
I trust this girl
can carry an air.
Robert assures me
she's quite good.
There's a song in the air
And you know why it's there
Because you're in love
You're in love
And that's how you know it
(BOTH CHATTERING)
For you took the world
for granted
Now you know that
the world's enchanted
And life was...
What did you do then?
I sent him home,
of course.
There's a cloud in the sky
But it's passing you by
And the sky looks blue
(ARLENE AND DOWAGER LAUGHING)
Dreams come true
Just because he's in love
With you
(HUMMING)
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
So there I was,
without
a servant in the house
and the General calling.
Such a predicament.
Yes, Robert?
(HUMMING)
Because you're in love
What happened then?
You're in love
(ARLENE AND DOWAGER LAUGHING)
For you took the world...
We have so much
to discuss, madame.
Shall we retire
until this
silly entertainment's over?
A splendid idea.
And life
was never like this before
Good evening, monsieur.
And how is Madame Latour?
Very well, thank you.
Come, my dear.
And remind me to tell you
of the time Marshal La Fouche
came to dinner.
He arrived even later
than usual,
full of excuses.
Dreams come true
(ARLENE AND DOWAGER LAUGHING)
Will those two ladies
please get out of here
and stop disturbing my song?
Can that creature
be shouting at us?
I can, and I am!
(EXCLAIMING)
Come.
(PEOPLE MUTTERING)
Since no one is interested
in my song,
I'm sure you'll excuse me.
Never in all my experience
have I seen
anything like this.
Well, what can you expect?
She's from Madame Brizar's.
But surely,
she didn't expect us
to listen to her.
Why did you ruin my song?
Your manners, my girl,
need correction.
Manners?
Is it manners to talk
while you're being entertained
and to walk out
in the middle of a song?
I am not accustomed
to such impudence.
Kindly leave the room.
And I'm not accustomed
to the rude behavior
of an ill-mannered snob.
Get out of here,
you dressed-up
scullery maid.
Oh! So we're going
to talk about clothes,
are we?
Then let's start
with that dress.
How dare you?
Why not? I wore it
before you did.
This dress came from Paris.
So Captain Kingston told me.
But I didn't like it.
Much too gauche.
Liar!
I seem to remember
having put my foot
through the inner hem.
But you'll find it
quite neatly mended.
Guttersnipe!
Cow!
(GASPS)
Oh! Please stop.
No. This is terrible!
(CLATTERING)
You must stop it!
Please!
(WOMEN SCUFFLING)
(PEOPLE MUTTERING)
Good evening,
Monsieur Narbonne. It's been
such a pleasant party.
Debbie...
Excuse me!
Arlene...
Captain Duval?
Mademoiselle?
There is something
I want you to do
for me, Captain,
in your official capacity
as Chief of Police.
Mademoiselle
has but to command.
Permit me to offer you
my apologies, mademoiselle.
The apology, monsieur,
is owed to me
by someone else.
But first, Robert,
you and I are going to
discuss gowns,
specifically this gown.
I assure you, it was all
perfectly innocent.
I can't believe that anything
associated with that creature
was innocent.
And now, Captain Duval,
I would like to resume
our conversation
without interruptions.
My sympathies, Captain.
I'm afraid it has been
an unfortunate evening
for you.
So that's what happened.
I disgraced you thoroughly.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, go on, say it.
The best client
you ever had, and I...
Did just what
I always wanted to do.
Why, madame.
How often,
when I was a young singer,
did I feel just the same way?
But slapping the face
of the Governor's niece...
Oh, no.
Oh, yes.
Well, I don't care
if she's his mother,
she deserved it.
Of course, her being engaged
to Captain Kingston
had nothing to do with it?
That woman, engaged to...
I don't believe it.
Well, for two years,
everybody else
has believed it.
Two years?
Well, he can't love her
very much.
Debbie.
For all our sakes,
forget about Captain Kingston.
And leave him at the mercy
of that ill-tempered witch?
I couldn't.
He doesn't know
what he's getting himself
into.
(SIGHS) Doesn't that apply
to most husbands?
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Who can that be
at this hour?
OFFICER: Open,
in the name of the law!
(KNOCKING LOUDER)
I'll take care of it,
Toussaint.
Open!
Open, I say!
Have pity on my door.
What do you want?
We have a warrant
for the arrest
of Deborah McCoy.
Mercy.
What has she done?
She is charged with assault
on the person of
Mademoiselle Arlene Villon.
Well, she's not here.
Keep them out
as long as you can,
Toussaint.
Run, get out of here.
Where will I go?
What's the difference?
Just make sure
that they don't find you.
Hurry, hurry, hurry!
Open!
Open, I say.
Here, you've no time
to get dressed. Wait.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Here, put this on,
and out of the window.
Upstairs.
Halt! Come back here.
Sorry, I have a
previous engagement.
Ahoy, there! Ahoy!
Who be you,
and what do you want?
Good evening, Jared.
Oh, no. Not you again.
I knew you'd be glad
to see me.
You can't come aboard
in that fashion.
Do you want to start a riot?
I just did.
Is the Captain aboard?
No, and if he was,
he'd probably toss you
back into the sea.
I doubt it. You see,
Captain Kingston and I know
too much about each other.
When he comes aboard,
tell him
I'll be waiting in his cabin.
I warn you,
the master won't like it.
He'll like it.
(PISTOL FIRES)
I wasn't expecting you
before daylight, sir.
What do you think
it is now?
(BELL RINGS)
Daylight.
Make ready to sail!
A Narbonne ship is due!
Aye, sir.
Only there is a lady...
If you're interested
in a lady, you can see her
when we return.
It isn't me, sir.
It's the lady...
Stop chattering about ladies.
I've had enough of them
tonight to last me a lifetime.
Weigh anchor before
we miss the tide.
Aye, sir.
Hands, raise up the sails!
Away, you lubbers!
Aye, sir.
Take the helm.
JARED: Forward, main braces!
Away, you lubbers!
Good morning.
Oh, no.
I hope you enjoyed yourself
at Monsieur Narbonne's.
For hours I've wanted to
get my hands on you.
Why, Frederic!
To choke you.
Why, I've never known you
to be so violent.
Why in the name of
seven red devils did you
have to mention that dress?
I'll answer that
when you tell me
why your charming fiancée
broke up my song.
We are not talking about her.
I am.
And in the days to come,
I'll tell you
many things of her,
each one worse
than the last.
And what makes you think
I'm going to
let you stay here?
I'm afraid you're going to
have to, Frederic.
You see, the police
are after me.
And you, of all people,
wouldn't want me
in the hands of the police.
So now it's blackmail?
Oh, no, Frederic.
Devotion.
I'll have a cabin
prepared for you.
My usual one,
if you don't mind.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Quartermaster,
watch your helm.
Aye, aye, sir.
Bring her to
until she's trim.
Luff a quarter point.
When you raid the ship, Jared,
don't forget
to select a dress for me.
Maybe you'd like to
board her with us
for a fitting?
If this wind holds,
we'll be off the Floridas
in the morning.
We'll lay to and wait.
Are you planning to vote
the Governor
a share of the haul, Captain,
for giving you
the information?
What information?
That's none
of your affair.
When we sight the ship,
you'll go to your cabin
and stay there.
All right,
you don't have to tell me.
I know all about it.
With my very own ears
I heard Monsieur Narbonne
tell Patout
that he was expecting
three ships from Paris.
You heard him say what?
That he was expecting
three ships from Paris.
What a fool I've been, Jared!
What a fool!
They set a trap for me
and used the Governor
to spring it.
Then there's no ship
from Spain?
Of course
there's a ship from Spain.
Probably a converted
man-of-war,
armed to the gallows
and ready to blast us
to the bottom of the sea.
Alter course, Jared.
Narbonne can have his ship
from Spain.
And we'll have
his ships from Paris
and hoist him
by his own petard!
Helm, hard a-larboard!
Hard a-larboard, sir!
Away there! Braces,
topsails and courses!
Watch your wind!
Debbie, remind me
to buy you some earrings
for those sharp little ears
of yours.
I will.
Sail ho!
Where away?
Two points off
the larboard bow, sir!
Make it so.
Prepare for action, Jared.
She's flying
the Narbonne flag.
Aye, sir.
Fore and main braces,
slack all!
Helm a-lee!
Bring her to.
Main braces, let go all.
Show them who we are, Jared.
I'm going below.
Debbie, go to your cabin.
And miss all the excitement?
Not me.
You heard
the captain's orders.
So did you.
Show them who we are.
Hoist the Roger!
Pirates! Man the guns,
and prepare to repel boarders.
Man the guns!
Prepare to repel boarders!
Gun tackles away!
Clear your vents!
Load!
Set and ready, sir.
Prime guns.
Prime guns!
I thought I told you
to go to your cabin.
Who are you supposed to be?
Baptiste, the cutthroat.
We disguise the ship
when we leave New Orleans.
I don't want to
be recognized either.
Then why don't
you stay in your cabin?
Because I belong up here,
but you don't.
Take her as she comes!
Rake her! Fire!
Fire!
Look out!
Boarders, stand by!
Make fast those grapnels!
Prepare to board, lads!
Clear the main decks!
Drive them aft!
Boarders away!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(PISTOL FIRING)
Not bad, Captain.
Daring, but late.
And now, Captain,
we can discuss things calmly.
How long before
they make land?
A few days,
but they're well provisioned.
That's another secret
you've got to keep, Debbie.
I'd lose my standing
as a pirate
if word got around
I spared my victims' lives.
JARED: There she be.
(PIRATES LAUGHING)
That's one for Davy Jones
and two more a-coming.
JARED: And this makes two.
(ALL CHEERING)
And still another
to come.
(ALL CHEERING)
JARED: There she be!
Jared, an extra ration
of grog for the men.
(ALL CHEERING)
Make it three extra rations.
One for each ship.
(ALL CHEERING)
(FIDDLE PLAYING)
Oh, I could use a bit
of grog myself.
I guess I'm not cut out
for this occupation
of pirating.
That part of it's all over.
We sail for Martinique
to sell the cargo,
and then, Debbie,
we go home to New Orleans.
(ALL CHEERING)
Long life to ye both!
No sleep tonight, Debbie?
No.
If you're worrying
about the police, don't.
I can take care of
that ridiculous charge
the moment we land.
What can you do
about this being
our last night out?
All voyages
must end sometime.
Why?
You could just
turn this ship around
and keep on sailing.
You forget my friends
at the Seamen's Fund
and my business with them.
To say nothing of
Mademoiselle Villon, and
your business with her.
That, too, Debbie.
I'd hoped
you'd understand.
I don't at all,
but I know
what you're going to say.
What you've been
leading up to
for the past three days.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but doesn't it go
something like this?
"Debbie,
"this is a difficult moment
for both of us,
but one we have to face.
"Now, being together
these past few months
"has made us forget everyone
but ourselves,
"and led us to believe
that everything has changed.
"But tomorrow
we land in New Orleans,
we meet our old friends,
"and discover
that nothing has changed,
"least of all my feeling
toward Mademoiselle Villon."
That doesn't
sound very pretty.
Perhaps you could
make it sound
more attractive.
No.
No matter what words I use,
the meaning
would be the same.
I'm sorry, Debbie.
I hope you'll forgive me.
And I hope that you...
(BELL RINGS)
That you'll be very happy.
PIRATE: Four bells
and all's well!
That's what you think.
Captain Duval,
there's a Captain Kingston
to see you.
Show him right in.
Welcome home, Kingston.
I hadn't heard you were back.
We dropped anchor
this morning.
Any sign of Baptiste?
None.
Monsieur Narbonne
was not so fortunate.
He lost three more ships.
Bad business.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Well, what brings you here?
I have a small favor to ask.
It concerns a girl.
But you only anchored
this morning.
This occurred
before I sailed.
Some trifling charge.
Assault, I believe.
But I feel
a certain responsibility
in the matter
and promised to help her.
And her name?
Deborah McCoy.
Oh, that one.
Now I understand.
Understand what?
Why the charges were made,
and why they were dropped.
Consider the matter
closed, Captain.
The complainant
requested the same favor.
She did?
Of course,
right after her marriage.
As Madame Narbonne,
she recognized it would be
most unseemly for her
to be jealous of anyone
but Monsieur Narbonne.
You are speaking
of Mademoiselle Villon?
Of course.
Forgive me, Captain,
I assumed you would've been
the first to have heard.
It appears
I've made a dreadful mistake.
Apparently, I have been saved
from making a greater one.
Robert.
This is a surprise.
It is a day
of surprises, madame.
My belated
best wishes to you,
and my congratulations
to Monsieur Narbonne.
No anger, Robert?
That's not very flattering.
At the risk
of upsetting you, madame,
I find myself less angry
than perplexed.
How well you control
your emotions, Robert.
But you did come to see me.
And I must confess
I'm pleased.
A minor confession, madame.
No other is important.
There was always one fault
with being in love with you.
You could do so well
without me.
With Alexander,
it's different.
He needs me.
I have the position to go
with his wealth.
It's a convenient arrangement
for both of us.
And, Robert,
it's an arrangement
that needn't too
much affect you and me.
When last we met,
you were quite violent
about a young lady.
I was just thinking
of the names you called her.
Are you comparing me
to that guttersnipe?
No longer, madame,
the comparison
is too unfair to her.
Then I suggest you leave here
and return to her.
No suggestion
was ever more welcome, madame.
I called to offer you
my congratulations.
I now extend my sympathy.
Get out.
Your husband
will soon discover
you are without honor.
You will soon discover
he is without wealth.
This should be
a happy arrangement
for both of you.
You see,
it has been a day
of surprises, madame.
Patout, is it true
that Alexander
is in financial difficulties?
Captain Kingston
tell you this?
Does it make any difference
who told me?
A great deal, madame,
since it is my belief
he is responsible
for those difficulties.
Kingston?
Or should I say, Baptiste,
since they are one
and the same?
You're out of your mind.
Both your husband
and I have every reason
to believe this.
Then why haven't
you gone to the police?
For one reason, madame.
Because you and
your uncle have
always been his protector.
I would like nothing better
than to see him hang.
If madame
truly feels that way,
perhaps we can arrange
that event.
We have manifests of
all the cargos lost when
Baptiste looted our ships.
If any of these cargos
are found
aboard Kingston's ship,
we have the proof we need.
I see.
Send Alexander to me
as soon as he returns.
Madame, should the charges
be proffered
by the Governor's niece,
Captain Duval would
act even more quickly.
Of course,
and Captain Kingston
would be even more unhappy.
We've had
an anxious day, Captain,
wondering if it would be you
or the police
who would call on us.
I haven't even
let Debbie unpack.
It is safe for her
to do so, but I'm here
to ask her not to.
DEBBIE: Why not?
Does my presence
in New Orleans embarrass you?
On the contrary,
New Orleans itself
embarrasses me.
Therefore
I'm sailing immediately
and want you to go with me.
Won't that be
a little awkward?
You and I and Madame Narbonne?
Then you know?
Yes.
Madame Brizar was
kind enough to tell me.
At which point I discovered
that even a woman
doesn't understand women.
They're very
unpredictable creatures,
as you're about to find out.
Debbie, I don't think
you understand.
There's nothing
to stop us now.
I'm ready
to turn the ship around
and keep on sailing.
So now you're ready?
Well, I'm not.
When you thought
you could have
Mademoiselle Villon,
you didn't want me.
Well, now that you
can't have her,
I don't want you.
I came here, Debbie,
because I discovered that
it wasn't Mademoiselle Villon
that I loved, it was you.
And I've discovered
that I want no part of you.
I wasn't good enough
for you and your friends
last night.
Well, they're not
good enough for me today.
Debbie, stop acting
like a fool.
I wonder what
your high and mighty friends
would say if they knew
that the gallant
Captain Kingston was really
Frederic Baptiste, a pirate.
Why don't you tell them?
Ahoy, Jared!
Answer him.
Ahoy, Captain!
How fitting that
Captain Kingston should
be the first to know
we have captured Baptiste.
She wasted no time
in coming to you, did she?
Did you expect her to?
Secure them below.
(ALL SINGING)
A sailor sails the seven seas
And maybe seven more
But when he's got
his money saved
He's better off ashore
ALL: Oh!
A sailor sails the seven seas
And maybe seven more
But keep your women
locked away
The day he comes ashore
I met a man from New Orleans
one bright and sunny day
He said he'd never leave me
Then he up and sailed away
He was gone for 15 years
I thought that he was dead
But he came back
with bags of gold
And here is what he said
ALL: Oh!
A sailor sails the seven seas
And maybe seven more
Looks like
we're wasting our time.
There isn't going to be
any trouble here.
It's as peaceful
as a clambake.
(YAWNING) The Captain
pays too much attention
to informers.
My sister married Captain John
A handsome sailor boy
They had a happy family
Till he heard a "ship ahoy"
And then
he got the urge to sail
And so he left them all
Now every time
you pass her house
You'll hear my sister call
ALL: Oh!
A sailor sails the seven seas
And maybe seven more
But when he's got
a wife and child
He'll never come ashore
(ALL LAUGHING)
I've known a lot
of sailor boys
The Captain and the crew
I'll eat with them
and drink with them
And flirt with one or two
But never will I marry one
And here's the reason why
The very day I marry one
He'll up and say goodbye
ALL: Oh!
A sailor sails the seven seas
And maybe seven more
And I'll be true to any man
As long as he's ashore
(MEN CHUCKLING)
The town is quiet as can be
But not for very long
The moment
that the ships come in
You'll hear a sailor's song
He's ready for a frolic
So it's up to you and me
To make each sailor wish
that he had never seen the sea
ALL: Oh!
A sailor sails the seven seas
And maybe seven more
And now I go to meet my love
His ship has come ashore
(ALL CHEERING)
Now.
(SHOUTING)
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
I do not condemn
your motive, my son,
only your method.
No other method
would've been as effective.
To live by the sword
is to perish by the sword.
You see
where it has brought you?
If you'll permit me, Father,
I see more clearly
where a woman has brought me.
I have been to see this
Mademoiselle McCoy.
She denies
having betrayed you.
And I believe her.
Father, in your calling,
you're supposed to believe.
Gentlemen, I'm overwhelmed
by this honor.
And well you
should be, pirate,
for Monsieur Narbonne
has come to offer you mercy.
Monsieur Narbonne's mercy
can be more dangerous
than his threats.
I pray
you will be generous, sir.
Monsieur Narbonne
has come as a friend.
And you're badly in need
of friends, Baptiste.
The Governor
has refused to see you.
Your execution
is scheduled for dawn.
It appears that all is fair
in love and war,
and I have lost at both.
(CHUCKLES)
Perhaps not.
I have come to
make you an offer.
Which you are
in no position
to refuse.
I am all ears, gentlemen.
In exchange for
a simple statement from you,
I'm convinced
I can persuade the Governor
to offer you a pardon,
on the condition
that you leave
New Orleans forever.
And what is to be the nature
of this statement?
A simple confession
that the money you turned over
to the Seamen's Fund
for the purchase of
new ships was really mine,
procured by selling my cargo.
The court will then rule
those transactions illegal.
And compel the owners
of these ships
to sign them over to you.
Precisely.
I would like nothing better
than to sign such a statement,
but I'm afraid I can't.
Why not?
You can't deny
that you raided my ships.
I can deny it.
In fact, I will deny it.
Then you'll hang.
Too bad.
It seems
such a ridiculous way to die.
Come, Patout,
we're just wasting our time.
Open.
Monsieur,
my compliments
to your wife.
And my apologies
for finding it
impossible to
replenish
the Narbonne fortune.
She will at least have
the satisfaction
of seeing you hang.
As well as the reward
for having exposed you.
Monsieur Patout!
You will never know
how happy you've made me.
Line up, all of you.
Line up.
What is all this, Sergeant?
The fight at
the Catfish, Captain.
The information you had
was correct.
Lock them up.
Merely a routine brawl.
Bring them along. Open up.
Come along.
Hurry up. Move along.
Go on, get in there!
Now!
Mademoiselle, the keys.
Come on.
JARED: Debbie!
Jared!
Quick, where is he?
In the next cell.
Give me the keys.
Debbie, is it any wonder
I love you?
Hurry, they'll have
reinforcements here
any moment.
If I hang for it,
I'll have a kiss.
There'll be
time for that later.
Come on.
(BELL RINGING)
Eight bells
and all's well.
How right he is.