[ENGINES RUNNING]
[CHEERING]
[CRASH]
VROOM! VROOM!
HANG ON,
WE'RE COMING TO A BEND.
YOU'RE GOING TOO FAST!
WHAT'S THIS HEAP
OF OLD IRON DOING HERE?
I'LL GIVE YOU
10 BOB FOR IT.
THIS WAS ONCE
A GREAT CAR.
WON THE GRAND PRIX
THREE YEARS RUNNING.
SO IT'S A CAR,
IS IT?
IT'S A RACING CAR.
AND WE'RE WINNING.
YOU'RE IN THE WAY.
I'LL BELT YOUR EAR
IF I HAVE ANY MORE
OF YOUR LIP.
I'LL GIVE 15 BOB
FOR IT.
MAKE IT 30.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
SELL HER, ARE YOU?
OF COURSE HE IS.
HE'S NOT RUNNING
A CHILDREN'S PLAYGROUND.
30 BOB.
I'LL PICK HER UP
WEDNESDAY.
BUT YOU PROMISED
WE COULD PLAY IN HER.
I'M SORRY, BUT SHE
AIN'T ANY USE TO ME.
BUT YOU CAN'T
TAKE HER AWAY.
SHE'S NOT JUST
ANY OLD CAR.
SHE'S OURS.
NOT ANYMORE.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
WHAT WILL
YOU DO WITH HER?
WE'LL PUT HER
IN THE CLAPPER
AND CRUNCH HER UP
INTO ONE PIECE OF METAL.
THEN WE'LL PUT HER
IN THE FIERY FURNACE
AND MELT HER DOWN
TILL SHE'S LIQUID IRON.
LOOK WHAT YOU'VE DONE.
YOU'VE FRIGHTENED HER.
SHE SHIVERED.
SHE'S A VERY
SPECIAL CAR.
IF YOU BURN HER,
IT'LL BE MURDER.
IF YOU DON'T
GET OUT OF IT,
I'LL BE GUILTY
OF TWO MORE MURDERS.
GIDDY-UP!
MR. COGGINS, YOU CAN'T
SELL OUR LOVELY CAR
TO THAT NASTY MAN.
I'M SORRY, CHILDREN,
BUT I'M AFRAID
I ALREADY HAVE.
I KNOW!
DADDY WILL
BUY IT FOR US!
PROMISE YOU WON'T
LET IT GO
UNTIL WE COME BACK.
30 SHILLINGS.
NOT A PENNY LESS.
PLEASE PROMISE.
PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT.
I PROMISE.
COME ON, JEMIMA.
OOH!
THAT'S A CLEVER THING
TO DO!
WE'RE SORRY, MISS.
I'M SURE YOU ARE.
WELL!
JUST LOOK AT MY CAR
AND LOOK WHAT A MESS
I'M IN, TOO.
OH, NO.
I THINK YOU'RE
BEAUTIFUL.
AND I LIKE
YOUR CAR.
YOU SHOULDN'T BE RUSHING
ACROSS THE ROAD LIKE THAT.
YOU MIGHT HAVE BEEN KILLED.
ANYWAY, WHY AREN'T YOU
IN SCHOOL?
IT ISN'T A HOLIDAY,
IS IT?
NO, MISS.
DO YOU LIVE
AROUND HERE?
YES, DOWN THE ROAD.
GET INTO MY CAR.
I'M TAKING YOU HOME.
JUST WAIT
TILL DADDY HEARS
WE'VE BEEN
FOR A RIDE
IN A MOTORCAR!
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
I'M JEMIMA.
AND I'M JEREMY.
WHAT'S YOURS?
TRULY.
THAT'S PRETTY.
NOW, WHERE
IS YOUR HOUSE?
WE LIVE IN A CASTLE
ON TOP OF A HILL.
I DIDN'T KNOW
THERE WERE ANY CASTLES
AROUND HERE.
IT ISN'T A CASTLE EXACTLY.
THAT'S WHAT
DADDY CALLS IT.
HE SAYS KING ALFRED
USED TO LIVE THERE.
DOES YOUR DADDY KNOW
YOU AREN'T IN SCHOOL?
HE WON'T MIND.
HE NEVER DOES.
ANYWAY,
HE'S AWFULLY BUSY.
IS HE?
HE'LL HAVE TO
FIND TIME TO SEE ME.
I HAVE A FEW THINGS
TO SAY TO HIM.
EDISON! EDISON!
COME HERE, BOY!
GOOD BOY.
THAT'S DADDY
OVER THERE.
HELLO!
HELLO.
YOU'RE JUST IN TIME.
WHAT IS HE UP TO?
THAT'S HIS LATEST
INVENTION--ROCKETS.
ROCKETS?
STAND BACK.
KEEP CLEAR!
HOORAY!
[ARF ARF ARF]
DOES HE KNOW
WHAT HE'S DOING?
OF COURSE.
WHOA!
WHOA! WHOA! WHOA!
YEEHA!
I DON'T SEE
ANYTHING FUNNY.
SOMEBODY SHOULD
DO SOMETHING.
HOLD ON! HOLD ON!
WAIT! WAIT THERE.
[FIZZLES]
UH!
OH!
WHEW! THANK YOU!
WELL, I SHOULD HOPE SO.
YOU MIGHT HAVE
GONE UP IN FLAMES.
THIS SUIT IS
COMPLETELY FLAMEPROOF.
YOU HAVE JUST SUCCEEDED
IN RUINING
MY PROPULSION UNIT.
HOW WAS I TO KNOW?
DON'T BE CROSS
WITH THE LADY.
SHE GAVE US
A RIDE IN HER CAR.
MR. POTTS,
I NEARLY KNOCKED DOWN
YOUR TWO CHILDREN.
WE SEEM TO BE
ACCIDENT-PRONE,
DON'T WE?
IT WASN'T MY FAULT.
IT WAS NICE OF YOU
TO APOLOGIZE.
TEA TIME, CHILDREN.
DON'T YOU HAVE SOMETHING
TO TELL YOUR FATHER?
DADDY, MR. COGGINS
PROMISED US--
SHE DIDN'T MEAN
ABOUT THAT.
DADDY.
WE DIDN'T GO
TO SCHOOL TODAY.
IT'LL GIVE
THE OTHER CHILDREN
A CHANCE
TO CATCH UP.
RUN ALONG, CHILDREN.
GOODBYE, TRULY.
COME ON, EDISON.
BUT, MR. POTTS--
GOOD DAY.
UNSTABLE.
BUT--
HEY! HEY!
GOOD AFTERNOON, MISS.
SORRY I CAN'T STOP.
I'M OFF TO INDIA.
GOING TO HAVE TEA
WITH THE MAHARAJAH.
CHEERIO.
MR. POTTS.
I'M SORRY
TO PERSIST ABOUT THIS,
BUT PERHAPS
YOU SIMPLY AREN'T AWARE
THAT YOUR CHILDREN
WERE RUNNING ABOUT
IN THE ROAD.
IT'S NOT A PLAYGROUND.
PRESS THAT SWITCH
BEHIND YOU.
ON--ON THE RIGHT.
THE RIGHT?
THANK YOU.
YOU REALLY OUGHT TO
EXERCISE MORE CONTROL
OVER THEM.
I COULD CHAIN THEM UP,
COULDN'T I?
DON'T YOUR CHILDREN
GO TO SCHOOL?
I HAVE IT NOW. YOU'RE
THE TRUANT OFFICER.
NO, I'M NOT.
DIDN'T YOU EVER
PLAY TRUANT?
I MOST CERTAINLY
DID NOT.
HMM. I'LL BET
YOU DIDN'T.
WHAT IS THIS,
THIS, UM...THING?
A LITTLE INVENTION--
CLEANS CARPETS
BY SUCTION.
ALL THAT
TO CLEAN CARPETS?
AWAY WITH SWEEPING
AND AWAY WITH BRUSHING
AND AWAY
WITH DIRTY CARPETS.
[LAUGHING]
IS THAT ALL YOU DO,
MR. POTTS--INVENT THINGS?
OH, AND WHAT'S
THIS GADGET?
THAT'S NOT
QUITE RIGHT YET,
BUT EVENTUALLY
I HOPE TO TRANSMIT
MOVING PICTURES
BY WIRELESS.
OH, REALLY?
YES, REALLY.
AND THIS?
THIS, MADAM,
IS A SWEET-MAKING MACHINE.
IS THIS ONE
OF THE SWEETS?
YES.
IS IT SUPPOSED
TO HAVE HOLES?
NO, ACTUALLY.
I THINK THE PROBLEM--
YOUR SUGAR'S
BOILING POINT
IS TOO HIGH.
WE'RE AN EXPERT
SWEET-MAKER
AND AN EXPERT
ON CHILD WELFARE?
I WAS TRYING
TO HELP.
MAYBE MY CHILDREN
LIKE RUNNING WILD.
DID THAT EVER
OCCUR TO YOU?
HOW MY CHILDREN BEHAVE
IS NO CONCERN OF YOURS,
SO TAKE YOURSELF OFF
IN YOUR FANCY
AUTOMOBILE
AND GO DO GOOD
SOMEWHERE ELSE.
WELL, I'VE NEVER--
BEEN SPOKEN TO
THAT WAY?
WELL, MAYBE IT'S
ABOUT TIME.
MIND THE CABLE!
VICIOUS, INTERFERING...
IF WOMEN
DRIVE MOTORCARS,
THEY SHOULD LEARN
TO OPERATE ONE.
IT WOULDN'T OCCUR
TO YOU TO HELP.
GET IN THE CAR.
PLEASE.
WELL, FOR
A MECHANICALLY
MINDED MAN--
TRY SWITCHING IT ON.
OH.
HMM!
[ENGINE STARTS]
[GRINDING]
OPEN THE THROTTLE!
AND KEEP IT OPEN!
WOMEN!
CONFOUNDED WOMAN!
WHO DOES
SHE THINK SHE IS?
DO I NEED
SOMEBODY TO TELL ME
HOW TO RAISE
MY CHILDREN?
DO I? HMM?
NO,
OF COURSE NOT.
OF COURSE NOT!
WHERE'S MY CARDIGAN?
UNDER YOUR JACKET.
UNDER...YES.
SELF-RIGHTEOUS
BUSYBODY.
WELL, SHE WON'T BE
BOTHERING US AGAIN.
BUT I LIKED HER.
SO DID I.
SHE WAS VERY PRETTY.
SHE CERTAINLY WAS.
DO YOU THINK
YOUR FATHER'S A CRACKPOT?
YOUR CARDIGAN'S
INSIDE OUT.
OH.
DO YOU THINK
I'M A LUNATIC,
WASTING MY TIME
ON SILLY INVENTIONS?
THEY AREN'T SILLY.
THEY'RE WONDERFUL.
NOBODY ELSE
COULD THINK OF THEM.
THAT'S RIGHT. NOBODY ELSE
AFTER ALL, WHAT MAKES
THE BATTLE WORTH THE FIGHTING?
WHAT MAKES THE MOUNTAIN
WORTH THE CLIMB?
WHAT MAKES THE QUESTIONS
WORTH THE ASKING,
THE REASON WORTH THE RHYME?
?? TO ME,
THE ANSWER'S CLEAR ??
?? IT'S HAVING
SOMEONE NEAR ??
?? SOMEONE DEAR ??
?? SOMEONE TO CARE FOR,
TO BE THERE FOR ??
?? I HAVE YOU TWO ??
?? SOMEONE TO DO FOR,
MUDDLE THROUGH FOR ??
?? I HAVE YOU TWO ??
?? SOMEONE TO SHARE
JOY OR DESPAIR WITH ??
?? WHICHEVER BETIDES YOU ??
?? LIFE BECOMES A CHORE ??
??
?? UNLESS YOU'RE LIVING FOR
?? SOMEONE TO TEND TO,
BE A FRIEND TO ??
?? I HAVE YOU TWO ??
?? SOMEONE TO STRIVE FOR,
DO OR DIE FOR ??
?? I HAVE YOU TWO ??
?? COULD BE WE THREE
GET ALONG SO FAMOUSLY ??
?? 'CAUSE YOU TWO
HAVE ME ??
?
?? AND I HAVE YOU TWO, TOO ?
YAY!
OOPS!
[CRASH]
[DING DING]
[TOOT TOOT]
[DING]
AH-CHOO!
?? SOMEONE TO CARE FOR,
TO BE THERE FOR ??
?? I HAVE YOU TWO ??
?? SOMEONE TO DO FOR,
MUDDLE THROUGH FOR ??
?? I HAVE YOU TWO ??
?? SOMEONE TO SMILE
ONCE IN A WHILE WITH ??
?? WHENEVER
YOU'RE LONESOME ??
??
?? I'VE A HAPPY LOT
?? CONSIDERING
WHAT I'VE GOT ??
?? BUT I COULDN'T
DO MORE ??
?? THAN YOU DO FOR
YOUR POOR FATHER ??
DADDY!
?? THINGS GO ASUNDER ??
?? AND I WONDER
WHY YOU BOTHER ??
?? COULD BE WE THREE ??
?? GET ALONG SO FAMOUSLY
'CAUSE ??
?? WE TWO HAVE YOU ??
?? AND I HAVE YOU TWO ??
?? TOO ????
AH!
JEREMY.
OH, GOOD.
DO I SMELL FOOD?
EH?
BRING THE BREAD,
GRANDPA.
YES, SIR!
AND PEPPER
AND SALT, PLEASE.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR!
SAUSAGE AND EGG--
MY FAVORITE!
HOW WAS INDIA?
I SHOT AN ELEPHANT
IN MY PAJAMAS.
HOW HE EVER...
GOT INTO
MY PAJAMAS...
I SHALL
NEVER KNOW.
YOU'VE HEARD IT
BEFORE.
HOW DID
THAT HAPPEN?
COULD WE
ASK YOU SOMETHING?
IT'S ABOUT
MR. COGGINS.
THE JUNKMAN
WANTED IT.
MR. COGGINS
SAYS IF WE ASKED--
HE'S A HORRID
OLD MAN.
MR. COGGINS?
NO. THE JUNKMAN.
HE'S GOING
TO TAKE IT--
AND BURN IT.
IT'S TERRIBLE.
WHAT?
OUR CAR!
YEAH?
THE JUNKMAN'S
BUYING IT.
HE'LL PUT IT
IN THE FIERY FURNACE
AND SKWODGE IT ALL UP
TILL THERE'S
NOTHING LEFT.
OH. WELL,
THAT'S TERRIBLE.
WE CAN'T ALLOW THAT,
GRANDPA.
UH...
UH, NO.
DEFINITELY NOT.
WE KNEW IT.
MR. COGGINS
PROMISED
WE COULD HAVE IT
IF YOU GAVE HIM
30 SHILLINGS.
UH...30 SHILLINGS.
YOU CAN PAY HIM
IN THE MORNING.
WELL, I SUPPOSE
WE CAN
WORK SOMETHING OUT
SOMEHOW.
YAY!
GOOD!
ARE YOU
ALL FINISHED?
YES, DADDY.
I THINK YOU SHOULD
RUN UP TO BED.
GOOD NIGHT, GRANDPA.
GOOD NIGHT,
DADDY.
GOOD NIGHT, DADDY.
YES, WELL,
YOU'VE DONE IT NOW,
HAVEN'T YOU?
YOU THINK COGGINS
MIGHT DO A DEAL?
COGGINS? SURE.
HE'S SO MEAN HE WOULDN'T
LIGHT YOUR PIPE
IF HIS HOUSE
WAS ON FIRE.
[THUNDER]
HEAR THAT? YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS.
I'LL BE UP ALL NIGHT,
RAIN POURING
THROUGH MY BEDROOM ROOF.
WHY DON'T YOU SLEEP
IN THE WORKSHOP?
YOU PROMISED
TO FIX MY ROOF.
I WILL, GRANDPA.
IT'S JUST--
CARACTACUS, PLEASE,
MY BOY, LISTEN.
AT YOUR AGE,
I DID A DAY'S WORK--
FOR A DAY'S PAY,
POLISHING
THE COLONEL'S BOOTS.
I WAS
THE SMARTEST BATMAN.
WHEN MY BRIGADIER
WENT INTO ACTION,
THE FUZZY-WUZZIES
WERE SO BLINDED
BY HIS BOOTS' SHINE,
THEY COULDN'T SEE
TO FIGHT.
[THUNDER]
CATCH ME DEATH OF COLD.
HE DON'T CARE.
NOBODY CARES.
ME OWN SON!
SHE WAS RIGHT.
WHO WANTS SWEETS
WITH HOLES IN THEM?
[TOOT]
OH, EDISON,
STOP THAT WHISTLING.
[TOOT]
[TOOT TOOT]
EDISON, HEY,
DO THAT AGAIN.
[TOOT TOOT]
EDISON,
YOU'RE A GENIUS.
[WOOF WOOF]
THE EMPLOYMENT OFFICE
IS IN THE REAR.
THANK--OH, UH...
I'VE INVENTED
THESE SWEETS.
OH, REALLY.
NAME?
UH, WHISTLING SWEETS.
MR. WHISTLING SWEETS.
I'M NOT
NO. I'M, UH, POTTS.
MMM.
MAY I SEE
THE MANAGING DIRECTOR?
LORD SCRUMPTIOUS
SEES NO ONE
WITHOUT
AN APPOINTMENT.
HELLO, CHILDREN.
JEREMY, IT'S TRULY.
HELLO, TRULY.
GOOD MORNING,
MISS SCRUMPTIOUS.
PHILLIPS.
PLEASE TELL FATHER
I'M HERE.
OF COURSE,
MISS SCRUMPTIOUS.
ARE YOU HERE
ON BUSINESS,
MR. POTTS?
YES, MISS--
UH, FATHER?
TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS.
YOU'RE HIS, UH--
HIS DAUGHTER.
COME ON, CHILDREN.
LET'S GO.
YOU HAVEN'T SHOWN
ANYBODY YOUR INVENTION.
I DON'T THINK
THAT MATTERS.
EXACTLY
WHAT WAS IT YOU--
YOU'VE SEEN THEM.
OH, THOSE.
THEY WHISTLE.
WHISTLE?
THOSE, UH, HOLES.
YOU JUST BLOW
THROUGH THEM.
[TOOT]
WHY, THEY'RE
VERY INGENIOUS.
KIND OF A NOVELTY.
[TOOT]
PLEASE GO IN,
MISS SCRUMPTIOUS.
YOU COME BACK
IN THREE WEEKS.
SHOW MR. POTTS IN,
PHILLIPS.
NOW?
NOW.
BUT HIS LORDSHIP
SAID--
NOW.
VERY WELL.
PLEASE FOLLOW ME.
MAYBE I
SHOULD COME BACK
IN THREE WEEKS.
GO ON, DADDY.
ALL RIGHT.
AND DON'T LET HIM
BULLY YOU.
YES.
MR. POTTS, MILORD.
POTTS? WHO'S HE?
WHERE'S ME DAUGHTER?
SHE INSISTED
ON HIM SEEING YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
DON'T JUST STAND THERE.
WHAT'S IT ALL ABOUT?
SWEETS, SIR.
I HARDLY THOUGHT
IT WAS NUTS AND BOLTS.
LET'S HAVE A LOOK.
HURRY UP!
YES, SIR.
IF I MAY EXPLAIN,
SIR.
YOU HAVE EXACTLY
20 SECONDS.
THE FUNDAMENTAL NOVELTY
OF THESE SWEETS
IS THEIR MUSICAL
QUALITY.
NOT ONLY
ARE THEY TASTY,
BUT DUE TO THE UNIQUE
POSITIONING
OF THESE LITTLE HOLES,
THEY ARE CAPABLE,
WHEN BLOWN THROUGH,
OF RENDERING
A TUNEFUL WHISTLE.
PLACE YOUR FINGERS
OVER THE HOLES
AND BLOW THUS.
[FACTORY WHISTLE BLOWS]
TASTING TIME, MILORD.
TOO LATE.
HAD YOUR CHANCE.
MUFFED IT.
GOOD MORNING.
FOLLOW HIM.
MILORD?
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
SIR?
EXCUSE ME.
SIR, IF I MAY
DEMONSTRATE.
BY BLOWING AIR
THROUGH THIS,
YOU GET A WONDERFUL
SOUNDING--
RASPBERRY?
IT'S MORE
LIKE A TOOT.
[TOOT]
CARE TO TRY IT?
UNDER
NO CIRCUMSTANCES.
HE'S NOT DOING
VERY WELL, IS HE?
ANOTHER
REMARKABLE FEATURE
ABOUT THESE
LITTLE SWEETS--
THROW IT AWAY!
WILL YOU GET RID
OF THIS IDIOT?
THEY ALSO COME
IN STRAWBERRY, RASPBERRY--
ARE YOU STILL HERE?
AND PINEAPPLE.
AHEM.
DON'T WASTE YOUR PUCKER
ON SOME ALL-DAY SUCKER,
AND DON'T TRY
A TOFFEE OR CREAM.
IF YOU SEEK PERFECTION
IN SUGAR CONFECTION,
WELL, THERE'S SOMETHING
NEW ON THE SCENE.
A MOUTHFUL OF CHEER,
A SWEET WITHOUT PEER,
?? A MUSICAL MORSEL
SUPREME ??
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? THE CANDIES
YOU WHISTLE ??
?? THE WHISTLES
YOU EAT ??
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? THE EATABLE,
TWEETABLE TREATS ??
[TOOT]
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? THE TOOT OF A FLUTE
WITH THE FLAVOR OF FRUIT ??
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? NO LONGER NEED CANDY
BE MUTE ??
[TOOT TOOT TOOT]
?? DON'T WASTE YOUR PUCKER
ON SOME ALL-DAY SUCKER ??
?? AND DON'T TRY
A TOFFEE OR CREAM ??
?? IF YOU SEEK PERFECTION
IN SUGAR CONFECTION ??
?? WELL, THERE'S
SOMETHING NEW
ON THE SCENE ??
?? THAT MOUTHFUL
OF CHEER ??
?? THAT SWEET
WITHOUT PEER ??
?? THAT MUSICAL MORSEL
SUPREME ??
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? A BONBON TO BLOW ON
AT LAST HAS BEEN FOUND ??
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? WITH TWEETABLE,
EATABLE SOUND ??
NO! TAKE IT AWAY!
FATHER, PLEASE.
[TOOT]
HE LIKES IT!
[CHEERING]
?? THEIR VALUE
IS INTRINSIC ??
?? SURPASS
ANY MINT STICK ??
?? OR MARSHMALLOW MOUTHFUL
YOU MUNCH ??
[TOOT]
?? THOUGH LICORICE
IS CHEWY ??
?? AND GUMDROPS
ARE GOOEY ??
?? AND CHOCOLATE IS CHARMING
TO CRUNCH ??
[TOOT TOOT]
?? THAT SAVORY FIFE ??
?? THAT SWEET
OF YOUR LIFE ??
?? IT'S CLEARLY
THE BEST OF THE BUNCH ??
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? THAT SAVORY FIFE ??
?? THAT SWEET
OF YOUR LIFE ??
?? IS CLEARLY
THE BEST OF THE BUNCH ??
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? A BONBON TO BLOW ON ??
?? AT LAST HAS BEEN FOUND ??
?? TOOT SWEETS,
TOOT SWEETS ??
?? THE TREAT
THAT'S SO TWEETABLE ??
?? LUSCIOUSLY EATABLE ??
?
?? WITH THAT UNBEATABLE... ?
????
??
[ARF ARF]
????
HEY! HEY!
??
?? SOUND ????
GET OUT OF HERE!
YOU'LL CONTAMINATE
THE CONFECTIONS.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
GET THOSE DOGS
OUT OF HERE!
EDISON, NO!
EDISON!
CHILDREN!
IT'S ENTIRELY
YOUR FAULT.
I'LL SEND
FOR THE POLICE.
AAH!
DADDY.
NOW, WHY AREN'T
YOU TWO ASLEEP?
DON'T BE SAD,
DADDY.
IT WASN'T
YOUR FAULT.
IT WAS ALL THOSE
MEAN OLD DOGS.
CHILDREN...
ABOUT THE CAR.
YOU SEE,
30 SHILLINGS
IS PRETTY HARD
TO COME BY,
AND WHEN I DO
GET ANY MONEY,
I NEED IT
FOR MY INVENTIONS.
THERE ISN'T ANY LEFT.
JEREMY AND I
HAVE BEEN THINKING.
IT'S OUR
TREASURE CHEST.
THESE THINGS ARE
ENORMOUSLY VALUABLE.
LOOK--
AN IVORY TUSK.
THAT MUST BE WORTH
A FORTUNE.
AND DIAMONDS.
AND A GOLDEN
CROWN.
IT'S PROBABLY
KING ALFRED'S.
IT NEEDS
CLEANING UP
A LITTLE.
TAKE THEM, DADDY.
YOU CAN SELL THEM.
AND NEVER MIND
ABOUT THE CAR.
YOU CAN SPEND IT
ALL ON YOUR INVENTIONS.
THANK YOU, CHILDREN.
ALL THESE
WONDERFUL THINGS...
THEY'RE
VERY PRECIOUS.
I'M AFRAID OTHER PEOPLE
WOULDN'T APPRECIATE THEM.
WHY NOT?
BECAUSE OTHER PEOPLE
DON'T SEE THINGS
THE WAY YOU DO.
COME ON, NOW.
LET'S GO TO BED.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
THINGS ARE GOING TO
COME RIGHT SOMEHOW.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
?? A GENTLE BREEZE ??
?? FROM HUSHABYE
MOUNTAIN ??
?? SOFTLY BLOWS
O'ER LULLABY BAY ??
?? IT FILLS THE SAILS ??
?? OF BOATS
THAT ARE WAITING ??
?? WAITING TO SAIL
YOUR WORRIES AWAY ??
?? IT ISN'T FAR ??
?? TO HUSHABYE MOUNTAIN ??
?? AND YOUR BOAT
WAITS DOWN BY THE QUAY ??
?? THE WINDS OF NIGHT ??
?? SO SOFTLY ARE SIGHING ??
?? SOON THEY WILL FLY
YOUR TROUBLES TO SEA ??
?? SO CLOSE YOUR EYES
ON HUSHABYE MOUNTAIN ??
?? WAVE GOODBYE
TO CARES OF THE DAY ??
?? AND WATCH YOUR BOAT
FROM HUSHABYE MOUNTAIN ??
?? SAIL FAR AWAY
FROM LULLABY BAY ????
[MUSIC PLAYING]
ALL THE LOVELY
COLORS--
TWO FOR THE PRICE
OF ONE.
GET YOUR BALLOONS
HERE!
HURRY, HURRY,
HURRY ALONG NOW!
GET YOUR LOVELY
TOFFEE APPLES!
HURRY ALONG NOW!
GET YOUR TOFFEE APPLES!
THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
YOUNG MAN.
ANY MORE
FOR ANYMORE?
WHICH ONE OF YOU LOVELY LADIES
AND GENTLEMEN
WOULD LIKE A SPLENDID
AUTOMATIC HAIRCUT?
I DO NOT
PROFESS TO MAKE
DEAD MEN TALK!
HEY, NOW,
HERE YOU GO, THEN!
ONLY 3 PENCE A TIME!
YOU MAY HAVE LONG HAIR!
YOU MAY HAVE
SHORT HAIR, SIR!
IT MAKES NO DIFFERENCE
TO THE POTTS AUTOMATIC,
HYGIENIC HAIRCUTTING MACHINE!
YOU COULD DO
WITH A HAIRCUT.
CUT ME HAIR?
THAT'S WHERE
ME STRENGTH IS.
YOU LOOK
LIKE A MAN
WHO COULD DO
WITH A HAIRCUT.
GO ON, CYRIL.
YOU HAVE LOTS
OF HAIR.
WOULD YOU LIKE
AN ESTIMATE?
VERY FUNNY.
GET ON WITH IT.
SIT TIGHT WHILE I
LOWER THIS MACHINE.
YOU JUST RELAX.
I FEEL
A RIGHT NANA.
YOU LOOK LOVELY,
CYRIL.
IT'S GOING TO BE
SMASHING.
WATCH THAT GEEZER.
YEAH,
ALL RIGHT, THEN.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
DON'T WORRY,
CYRIL.
DON'T WORRY.
A LITTLE FRICTION TO START.
EH! IT TICKLES!
OH, YOU ALWAYS
SAY THAT, CYRIL.
OH, OH, OH, CYRIL!
YOU'RE SMOKING!
I'M ON FIRE!
STOP IT!
OH! EXCUSE ME!
ME HEAD'S ON FIRE!
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
SIR.
WHAT YOU DONE?
GIVE ME A MIRROR.
LET'S HAVE A LOOK.
A MIRROR? I'LL GO HOME
AND GET YOU ONE.
ME HAIR!
LOOK AT ME HAIR!
WHERE IS HE?
I'LL KILL HIM!
THERE HE IS, MISTER!
I'LL SMASH YOUR TEETH
DOWN YOUR THROAT!
AH, YOU!
YOU'LL DO YOURSELF
A MISCHIEF!
YOU'RE TOO FAT
TO CATCH HIM!
AY, BIG BONCE!
GET OUT OF HERE.
OH!
THERE HE IS!
I'LL KILL HIM!
OY!
HERE, HURRY UP.
WE'RE ON.
GET OUT OF THE WAY!
?? A GENTLEMAN'S GOT
A WALKING STICK ??
?? A SEAMAN'S GOT
A GAFF ??
?? AND THE MERRY MEN
OF ROBIN HOOD ??
?? THEY USED
A QUARTERSTAFF ??
?? ON THE SPANISH PLAINS,
INSIDE THEIR CANES ??
?? THEY HIDE
THEIR RUDDY SWORDS ??
?? BUT WE MAKE DO
WITH AN OLD BAMBOO ??
?? AND EVERYONE APPLAUDS ??
?? 1, 2, 3, 4 ??
?? 5, 6, 7, 8 ??
?? ME OLD BAMBOO,
ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU CAN HAVE ME HAT
OR ME BUMBERSHOO ??
?? BUT YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? WHEN PUNTING
ON THE BEAUTIFUL THAMES ??
?? YOU USE
A STURDY POLE ??
?? TO PROTECT
THEIR FAIR COMPLEXION ??
?? LADIES USE
A PARASOL ??
?? IT'S USEFUL
IN THE UNDERBRUSH ??
?? TO HAVE
A HEFTY SPEAR ??
?? RIGHT! BUT WHAT WE DO
WITH AN OLD BAMBOO ??
?? MAKES EVERYBODY CHEER ??
?? 1, 2, 3, HO! ??
?? ME OLD BAMBOO,
ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU CAN HAVE ME HAT
OR ME BUMBERSHOO ??
?? BUT YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ??
HAVE A GO, MATE!
?? A FLIER
IN AN AEROPLANE ??
?? HE STEERS IT
WITH A STICK ??
?? HE DOES? ??
?? A COLLIER
IN THE PITS OF WALES ??
?? HE LEANS UPON HIS PICK ??
?? THAT'S RIGHT ??
?? NOW EVERY WHEEL
OF AN AUTOMOBILE ??
?? REVOLVES AROUND
A SHAFT, HEY! ??
?? BUT WHAT WE DO
WITH AN OLD BAMBOO ??
?? MAKES EVERYONE
GO DAFT ??
?? HEY! 1, 2 ??
?? ME OLD BAMBOO,
ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU CAN HAVE ME HAT
OR ME BUMBERSHOO ??
?? BUT YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? 1, 2, 3, 4 ??
?? 5, 6, 7, 8 ??
?? AND A-1, 2, 3, 4 ??
?? AND A-5 AND A-6
AND A-7, HO! ??
?? ME OLD BAMBOO,
ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU CAN HAVE ME HAT
OR ME BUMBERSHOO ??
?? BUT YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ??
?? YOU BETTER NEVER BOTHER
WITH ME OLD BAMBOO ????
[APPLAUSE]
THANK YOU.
HERE. THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
THANKYOU.THANK YOU.
[HONK HONK
HONK HONK]
[HONK HONK HONK HONK]
IT'S DADDY!
HE'S GOT THE CAR!
HEY, LOOK! I'VE GOT IT!
THE CAR!
COME ON!
[HONK HONK
HONK HONK]
[HONK HONK HONK]
HELLO!
HOORAY! THE CAR!
HA HA HA HA!
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THIS?
ISN'T SHE A BEAUTY?
OH!
A NICE PILE OF JUNK,
MY BOY.
NEEDS WORK, BUT THERE'S
A FINE ENGINE.
IT DOESN'T GO,
THOUGH, DOES IT?
NOT YET,
BUT IT WILL.
CAN'T YOU
MAKE IT GO?
WELL, I'LL GIVE IT A TRY.
EVERYBODY, PUT
A HAND TO THE WHEEL.
GEORGE, GIVE US A HAND.
WE'RE OFF!
WE'RE OFF! HOORAY!
COMFORTABLE, GRANDPA?
[ARF ARF]
WON'T WORK, OF COURSE.
ANOTHER CATASTROPHE.
LEFT HAND DOWN.
COME ON, GRANDPA,
PUSH!
WATCH IT, JEREMY.
MIND THE BICYCLE.
AH! GOOD.
KEEP COMING, JEREMY.
THAT'S IT.
KEEP COMING.
WATCH OUT, EDISON.
LOOK OUT, EDISON.
GOOD. WHOA!
WHOA!
ALL RIGHT,
GOVERNOR.
MANY, MANY THANKS,
GEORGE. NOW...
CAN WE STAY
AND WATCH, DADDY?
MY DEARS,
WE'D BETTER GO.
YOU KNOW YOUR DAD
WHEN HE'S WORKING.
WE WANTED
TO STAY AND WATCH.
DON'T OVERDO IT,
MY BOY.
RIGHT, GRANDPA.
YOU MIGHT
EXHAUST YOURSELF.
[BANG]
[CLUNK CLUNK]
[CLANG]
[CLANG CLUNK]
[CLUNK]
[SAWING]
COME ON!
"AND THE BIG BROWN BEAR
"CAME LOLLOPING
OVER THE MOUNTAIN.
NO, NO,
THE PRINCESS CRIED-- "
?? DA DA
DEE DEE DEE ??
?? DA DA DA
?? HMM HMM HMM ??
DA DA DEE DEE DEE ??
OH.
[WHISTLING]
?? DA DA DEE DEE
DEE DA DEE ??
?? LA DEE DA
DEE DA DUM ????
"AND THE BIG BROWN BEAR
CAME LOLLOPING
OVER THE MOUNTAIN."
[CLUCK CLUCK]
[TAP TAP TAP]
[TAP TAP TAP TAP]
IT'S AWFULLY QUIET
IN THERE.
BREAKFAST IS READY.
HE'S BEEN THERE
FOR DAYS!
PLEASE COME HAVE
YOUR BREAKFAST.
DADDY SAID IT WOULD
BE FINISHED TODAY.
YOU'LL BE WAITING
A MONTH OF SUNDAYS
BEFORE HE'S FINISHED.
COME ON.
[HONK HONK HONK HONK]
[WHISTLES]
THAT'S DADDY!
HE'S FINISHED
THE CAR!
GOSH!
OOH!
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
SHE'S THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL THING
I EVER SAW
IN MY LIFE!
IT'S WONDERFUL!
DADDY, YOU'RE
SO CLEVER.
OH, YES.
CAN WE GO
FOR A DRIVE?
HOW ABOUT A PICNIC?
A PICNIC!
HOORAY!
GET THE BASKET
OUT OF THE WORKSHOP.
GET IN, JEMIMA.
HURRY!
MIND THE WOODWORK.
DON'T TOUCH THE HORN.
HERE'S THE BASKET,
DADDY.
PUT IT ON THE BACK.
DON'T TOUCH THAT.
GRANDFATHER!
WE'RE GOING
ON A PICNIC.
GET ABOARD, GRANDPA.
IT'LL NEVER GO
IF HE'S HAD ANYTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
IT IS GOING!
HOORAY!
THEN IT'LL
NEVER STOP.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
I'M OFF TO ALASKA,
ME BOY. CHEERIO!
GOODBYE, GRANDPA!
COME ON, DADDY!
COME ON! COME ON!
WE'RE OFF!
READY?
YES!
HERE WE GO!
YAY!
[HONK HONK HONK]
MIND YOUR BACK,
GRANDPA.
BYE, GRANDPA.
HA HA HA!
NASTY, SMELLY THINGS,
MOTORCARS!
[CHITTY CHITTY
BANG BANG]
WHAT A FUNNY NOISE
IT'S MAKING!
IT'S TALKING.
ALL ENGINES TALK.
WHAT'S IT SAYING?
IT'S SAYING, CHITTY
CHITTY, CHITTY CHITTY.
[BANG BANG]
BANG BANG!
CHITTY CHITTY
?? CHITTY BANG BANG,
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OH, YOU,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WE LOVE YOU ??
?? AND IN CHITTY CHITTY
BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WHAT WE'LL DO ??
?? NEAR, FAR,
IN OUR MOTORCAR ??
?? OH, WHAT A HAPPY TIME
WE'LL SPEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? CHITTY BANG BANG,
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OH, YOU,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WE LOVE YOU ??
?? AND IN
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WHAT WE'LL DO ??
?? NEAR, FAR,
IN OUR MOTORCAR ??
?? OH, WHAT A HAPPY TIME
WE'LL SPEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? YOU'RE SLEEK
AS A THOROUGHBRED ??
?? YOUR SEATS AR
E A FEATHER BED ??
?? YOU'LL TURN
EVERYBODY'S HEAD TODAY ??
?? WE'LL GLIDE
ON OUR MOTOR TRIP ??
?? WITH PRIDE
IN OUR OWNERSHIP ??
?? THE ENVY
OF ALL WE SURVEY ??
?? OH, CHITTY, YOU, CHITTY,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WE LOVE YOU ??
?? AND, CHITTY, IN, CHITTY,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WHAT WE'LL DO ??
?? NEAR, CHITTY, FAR, CHITTY,
IN OUR MOTORCAR ??
?? OH, WHAT A HAPPY TIME
WE'LL SPEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED ??
?? FRIEND ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY
BANG BANG ??
?? FINE FOUR-FENDERED
CHITTY CHITTY FRIEND ????
LOOK OUT!
DADDY!
OH!
SQUEEZING THE HOOTER
IS AN EXCELLENT PRECAUTION,
MISS SCRUMPTIOUS.
NEVER MIND!
HOW WILL I GET OUT?
LOOKS TO ME AS IF
YOU HAVE TO WALK,
OR, UH, SWIM.
WHAT? IN THIS DRESS?
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS,
MR. POTTS.
COME ON.
WHAT WILL YOU DO?
CARRY YOU.
OH, DEAR, MUST YOU?
WELL, UNLESS YOU'D
RATHER RIDE PIGGYBACK.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU MAY CARRY ME.
GOOD.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
MY HANDBAG.
OH. OH!
WHOA! OH!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
NOT AT ALL.
WE'RE GOING TO
THE SEASIDE.
COME ALONG.
WELL, I'M HARDLY
IN THE MOOD NOW.
I'LL HAVE MR. COGGINS
TOW YOUR CAR.
WELL, I...
WE'VE GOT
SAUSAGE TARTS.
AND MARMALADE
ROLLS.
I MIXED THEM UP.
[CHITTY CHITTY
BANG BANG]
WHAT AN UNUSUAL CAR.
[BANG BANG]
DADDY MADE IT.
AND IT
ACTUALLY GOES?
IT'S CALLED
CHITTY CHITTY
BANG BANG.
CURIOUS NAME
FOR A MOTORCAR.
BUT THAT'S
THE SOUND IT MAKES.
LISTEN.
[CHITTY CHITTY
BANG BANG]
?? CHITTY BANG BANG,
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OH, YOU,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WE LOVE YOU ??
?? AND OUR
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG
LOVES US, TOO ??
?? HIGH, LOW,
ANYWHERE WE GO ??
?? ON CHITTY CHITTY
WE DEPEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? YOU'RE SLEEK
AS A THOROUGHBRED ??
?? YOUR SEATS ARE
A FEATHER BED ??
?? YOU TURN EVERYBODY'S
HEAD TODAY ??
?? WE'LL GLIDE
ON OUR MOTOR TRIP ??
?? WITH PRIDE
IN OUR OWNERSHIP ??
?? THE ENVY
OF ALL WE SURVEY ??
?? OH, CHITTY, YOU, CHITTY,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WE LOVE YOU ??
?? AND, CHITTY, OUR, CHITTY,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG
LOVES US, TOO ??
?? HIGH, CHITTY, LOW, CHITTY
, ANYWHERE WE GO ??
?? ON CHITTY CHITTY
WE DEPEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? FINE FOUR-FENDERED
CHITTY CHITTY FRIEND ????
[BANG BANG]
HOORAY!
WHOA!
HA HA HA!
[SHIVERING]
HOORAY!
OOPS!
OH!
HA HA HA!
I'M SO GLAD YOU CAME.
IT'S MUCH MORE FUN
WITH TWO GROWNUPS.
TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS.
YOU KNOW, IF WE DIDN'T
KNOW YOUR NAME,
WE COULD HAVE
GUESSED IT.
OH?
YOU HAD TO BE CALLED
SOMETHING LOVELY.
LIKE YUM YUM!
OR ANGEL CAKE.
OR TOOT SWEETS.
YES. TOOT SWEETS.
TOOT SWEETS?
OH, NO.
?? TOOT SWEETS SOUND LIK
E WHAT THEY ARE ??
?? SO DO LOLLIES
IN A LOLLIPOP JAR ??
?? GINGERBREAD MEN
HAVE A GINGERBREAD SOUND ??
?? WE'VE FOUND ??
?? SUGAR PLUM, CINNAMON,
AND LEMON TART ??
?? TELL YOU WHAT THEY ARE
RIGHT FROM THE START ??
?? AND YOUR NAME DOES
THE SAME FOR YOU ??
?? BY COINCIDENCE,
TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?? YOU'RE TRULY,
?? SCRUMPTIOUS AS
A CHERRY-PEACH PARFAIT ??
?? WHEN YOU'RE NEAR US ??
?? IT'S SO DELICIOUS ??
?? HONEST, TRULY ??
?? YOU'RE THE ANSWER
TO OUR WISHES ??
?? TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?? THOUGH WE MAY
SEEM PRESUMPTUOUS ??
?? NEVER, NEVER, EVER
GO AWAY ??
?? OUR HEARTS BEAT
SO UNRULY ??
?? BECAUSE WE
LOVE YOU TRULY ??
OH?
?? HONEST, TRULY ??
?? WE DO ??
DADDY! DADDY!
HA HA HA!
BOO!
?? TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?? YOU TWO
ARE TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?? SCRUMPTIOUS AS THE BREEZE
ACROSS THE BAY ??
?? WHEN YOU'RE SMILING ??
?? IT'S SO DELICIOUS ??
?? SO BEGUILING ??
?? YOU'RE THE ANSWER
TO MY WISHES ??
?? TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?? YOU TWO
ARE TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?? AND I SHAN'T FORGET
THIS LOVELY DAY ??
?? MY HEART BEATS
SO UNRULY ??
?? I ALSO LOVE YOU TRULY ??
?? HONEST, TRULY I DO ????
COME ON.
HEY, WAIT FOR ME!
MR. POTTS.
SOMEBODY CALL?
OH! OOH!
OH! I'M SORRY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
OH, JUST,
UH...TINKERING.
OH.
YOU KNOW, MR. POTTS,
YOU HAVE TWO
WONDERFUL CHILDREN.
WHY, THANK YOU.
I MUST AGREE
WITH YOU THERE.
ISN'T IT BEAUTIFUL?
LOVELY.
JUST LOVELY.
JEREMY, IT'S NOT
NICE TO PEEK.
I'M NOT PEEKING,
I'M LOOKING.
DO THEY LIKE
EACH OTHER?
OF COURSE.
THINK THEY'LL
GET MARRIED?
HAS HE
KISSED HER YET?
NOT YET.
WHEN THEY KISS, THEY'LL
HAVE TO GET MARRIED.
JEREMY, WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
KEEPING A LOOKOUT
FOR PIRATES.
THERE AREN'T
ANY PIRATES,
ARE THERE, TRULY?
OH, I'M SURE
THERE ARE,
HUNDREDS OF THEM.
THIS IS WHERE
THEY BURY TREASURE,
ISN'T IT, DADDY?
MM-HMM.
TELL US A STORY
ABOUT PIRATES, DADDY.
A STORY
ABOUT PIRATES, HUH?
WELL, LET ME SEE.
A BOAT!
I SEE A BOAT!
A BOAT?
DID YOU SAY A BOAT?
THAT ISN'T JUST
ANY BOAT OUT THERE.
NO?
NO. THAT IS
A PRIVATE YACHT
OF THE NOTORIOUS
BARON BOMBURST.
BARON BOMBURST?
YOU HAVE NEVER HEARD
OF BARON BOMBURST,
RULER OF VULGARIA?
THE MOST EVIL MAN
IN THE WORLD!
OH!
GOSH!
HE HAS SAILED
ALL THE WAY TO ENGLAND.
HE'S HEARD TELL
OF A FANTASTIC MOTORCAR
BUILT BY THAT BRILLIANT
INVENTOR, CARACTACUS POTTS.
HOORAY! HOORAY!
HOORAY!
YES, HOORAY!
HE HAS COME
TO STEAL THE CAR
AND TAKE IT BACK
TO VULGARIA.
OH, YES!
AH!
THAT CAR!
OH, YEAH, YEAH.
I WANT IT!
ARE YOU GIVING ME
AN ARGUMENT?
STAND BY THE BOATS!
STAND BY
THE BOATS!
LOAD THE CANNON!
HE'S AWFUL.
HE'S TERRIBLE.
HE ISN'T EVEN NICE.
HE CAN'T STEAL
OUR CAR!
LOOK! THEY'RE
GETTING CLOSER.
WE'VE GOT TO
GET AWAY!
START THE CAR.
QUICKLY, DADDY!
THAT'S EASIER SAID
THAN DONE.
BUT WHY, DADDY? WHY?
WELL, I'LL TELL YOU.
WHAT NONE OF US
HAVE NOTICED,
WHILE WE'VE BEEN
SITTING HERE,
THE TIDE
HAS BEEN COMING IN.
WE'RE COMPLETELY CUT OFF.
OH!
OH! OH!
WHAT ARE WE
GOING TO DO?
HURRY, MR. POTTS!
EVERYONE
STAY CALM!
QUICKLY, DADDY.
QUICKLY.
AH, LOOK!
THEY ARE COMPLETELY
CUT OFF BY THE TIDE.
THEY WILL ALL DROWN!
I HAVEN'T SEEN
A GOOD DROWNING IN YEARS!
HO HO HO!
HA HA HA!
ANYTHING I CAN DO?
PUSH THE THROTTLE!
HURRY, DADDY! HURRY!
QUICKLY!
BEFORE THEY GET HERE!
THE OTHER ONE!
IT WON'T START!
WE WILL
HAVE TO SWIM FOR IT.
COME ON, JEMIMA.
COME ON. COME ON.
OVER THE SIDE.
[BANG]
IT'S STARTING!
EVERYBODY HOLD ON!
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE!
OH, THIS IS
POSITIVELY CLEVER!
WHEE!
THIS IS
IMPOSSIBLE!
YOU BUILT IT!
YOU ALWAYS SAID
IT WAS MAGIC.
I DID?
LIKE A BOAT!
CHITTY SAVED US!
HANG ON, EVERYBODY!
WE'RE OFF!
HOORAY!
A FLOATING CAR?
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THAT?
A CAR FLOATING,
FLOATING ON
THE WATER FOAM.
THIS IN
MY WHOLE LIFE,
IS NEVER COMING
TO SEEN.
YAY!
IT'S UNCATEGORICAL!
HA HA HA!
A FUEL-BURNING ORACLE.
PHANTASMAGORICAL
MACHINE!
?? IT'S MORE
THAN SPECTACULAR ??
?
?? TO USE
THE VERNACULAR ?
IT'S WIZARD!
IT'S SMASHING!
?? IT'S KEEN ??
?? OH, CHITTY, YOU, CHITTY,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WE LOVE YOU ??
?? AND, CHITTY, OUR, CHITTY,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG
LOVES US, TOO ??
?? HIGH, CHITTY, LOW, CHITTY
, ANYWHERE WE GO ??
?? ON CHITTY CHITTY
WE DEPEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND-- ????
[BOOM]
THEY'RE FIRING
AT US!
OH? WE'LL SHOW THEM
SOMETHING.
FOLLOW THAT CAR!
MY WORD!
I WANT THE CAR!
I WANT THAT CAR!
I MUST HAVE IT!
STAY ON THEM!
OH! FOLLOW THE CAR!
STOP THAT CAR!
AFTER THEM!
FASTER!
I WANT THE CAR!
HURRY!
ACTION STATIONS, EVERYBODY.
WE'RE GOING ASHORE!
GET OUT!
WHERE ARE
MY TWO SPIES?
AH!
THERE YOU ARE!
NOW, THEN...
I HAVE A SECRET MISSION
FOR YOU.
YOU WILL GO ASHORE,
AND YOU WILL CAPTURE
THAT MOTORCAR, UNDERSTAND?
GOOD. BUT...
IF YOU FAIL,
I WILL CUT OFF
YOUR HEADS.
OUT.
OH! I WANT THAT CAR!
NOW, THEN...
WHERE ARE WE?
I HAVE HERE
A MAP.
I KNOW WHERE WE ARE,
STUPID!
WE ARE IN ENGLAND!
WHAT DO WE DO?
PLAY CRICKET!
NO. WE DRESS
LIKE ENGLISHMEN.
AHA!
REMARKABLE WEATHER
WE ARE HAVING
FOR THE TIME OF YEAR.
DO YOU NOT THINK SO,
CUTHBORT?
INDUBITABLY, BASIL.
YOU KNOW,
MR. POTTS--
CARACTACUS.
IT'S A PRETTY SILLY
NAME, ISN'T IT?
OH, I DON'T
THINK SO.
YOU KNOW...
I REALLY OWE YOU
AN APOLOGY.
YOU'RE MORE
THAN JUST A FATHER
TO THOSE TWO
CHILDREN.
NURSEMAID, PRIVATE TUTOR,
CHIEF, COOK,
AND BOTTLE WASHER.
EVERYTHING...
EXCEPT WHAT THEY
REALLY NEED.
WELL, IT'S BEEN
QUITE A DAY.
YES, CERTAINLY HAS.
THANK YOU.
SAY GOODBYE
TO THE CHILDREN
FOR ME.
I HOPE
WE'LL SEE YOU AGAIN.
I HOPE SO, TOO.
GOODBYE.
?
?? THIS LOVELY, LONELY MAN ?
?? I'VE ONLY KNOWN A DAY ??
?? I LOOK AT HIM ??
?? AND CANNOT LOOK AWAY ??
?? OH, WHAT A LOVE ??
?? OH, WHAT A LOVELY,
LONELY MAN ??
?? I'VE MET SO MANY MEN ??
?? SO EASY TO FORGET ??
?? I THOUGHT I'D GROWN
IMMUNE TO THEM ??
?? AND YET ??
?? HE'S SUCH A LOVE ??
?? HE'S SUCH A LOVELY,
LONELY MAN ??
?? HOW DID HE
TOUCH MY HEART? ??
?? HOW DID
THIS FEELING START? ??
?? THIS GLOW THAT FEELS
SO WARM INSIDE ??
?? THIS SUDDEN
SUMMER STORM INSIDE ??
?? MY LIFE NOW HAS A PLAN ??
?
?? TO SOMEDAY MAKE HIM SEE ?
?? THAT I NEED HIM AS MUCH
AS HE NEEDS ME ??
?? OH, WHAT A LOVE ??
?? OH, WHAT A LOVELY,
LONELY MAN ??
?? MY LIFE NOW HAS A PLAN ??
?
?? TO SOMEDAY MAKE HIM SEE ?
?? THAT I NEED HIM AS MUCH
AS HE NEEDS ME ??
?? OH, WHAT A LOVE ??
?? OH, WHAT A LOVELY,
LONELY MAN ??
?? OH, HOW I LOVE
THIS ONE AND ONLY MAN ????
QUICKLY!
I'M COMING!
THEY'RE COMING!
COME ON.
HURRY. QUICKLY!
HURRY. COME ON!
THEY'RE COMING!
GET READY.
FIRE!
STOP, STOP, STOP!
THIS WAY.
NO!
STOP!
STOP, STOP.
HUP!
[HORN HONKING]
THEY'RE TRYING
TO GET PAST,
DADDY.
FINE.
GET OVER,
YOU HALF-WIT.
FATHER'S
IN A TEMPER.
THAT'LL BE
A CHANGE.
YOU'D BETTER
LET HIM PASS.
THERE ISN'T
ROOM.
GET OUT OF THE WAY,
YOU IDIOT!
TURN OFF HERE.
[HORN HONKING]
WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
WE'VE GOT HIM!
[BANGING]
DRIVE AWAY!
WHOA!
STOP!
DOWN.HERAUS!
I'LL SEND
YOU NINCOMPOOPS AWAY
FOR THE REST
OF YOUR LIVES.
I SUPPOSE YOU
BLUE-FACED BABOONS
HAVE SOME EXPLANATION
FOR THIS OUTRAGE?
YOU STUPID FOOL!
WHY? WHAT HAVE I DONE?
WHAT HAVE YOU--
AH.
I HAVE AN IDEA.
NOW, REMEMBER.
WE ARE SUPPOSED
TO BE ENGLISH
GENTLEMEN,
SO LET US TRY
AND BEHAVE LIKE
ENGLISH GENTLEMEN.
JA, JA, JA.
SO OPEN THE DOOR!
COME.
"CARACATACACUS POTTS,
INVENTOR."
TYPICAL
ENGLISH ECCENTRIC.
THAT MUST BE
THE INVENTOR.
HMM.
AHEM, AHEM, AHEM.
PARDON ME
FOR PROTRUDING,
BUT HAVE I THE PLEASURE
OF ADDRESSING HERR--
AHEM, MR. POTTS?
YES. THAT'S ME.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
YOU SELLING
SOMETHING?
I DON'T
WANT NOTHING.
EXCUSE ME.
I'M OFF TO AFRICA.
AFRICA.
THAT WAS A RUSE
TO PUT US OFF
THE SCENT.
HE HAS GONE
INTO HIS LABORATORY.
QUICK!
PORTABLE WIRELESS
TRANSMITTER!
JAWOHL.
JAWOHL?
THIS IS
"X" SPEAKING.
SCHRECKS?
NO. "X".
LECKS?
"X" AS IN--
EGGS AND BACON.
SEND TRANSPORT
IMMEDIATELY.
IT'S HERE!
QUICKLY.
QUICKLY!
NO! THAT WAY!
THAT WAY.
QUICKLY!
THIS WAY!
LOWER
THE LADDER.
UP THE LADDER!
WOW!
THOSE SLOBS...
BRING ME UP.
OVER HERE.
WAIT FOR ME!
HELLO!
WHAT'S YOUR GAME, THEN?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
OY, I'M FLYING!
LOOK!
IT'S A ZEPPELIN.
WHAT'S THAT
UNDERNEATH?
THAT'S--THAT'S
GRANDPA'S HUT.
BUT WHAT'S
IT DOING
UP THERE?
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
HELP ME!
I'M BEING KIDNAPPED!
GRANDPA,
COME DOWN HERE!
MY BOY, IT'S ME,
YOUR OWN FATHER!
CARACTACUS!
GRANDPA!
HOLD TIGHT,
BACK THERE.
SIT DOWN,
JEREMY.
QUICKLY!
HURRY, DADDY!
CARACTACUS!
GRANDPA!
HOLD ON, GRANDPA!
WE'RE COMING!
HELP!
COME BACK, GRANDPA!
GRANDPA, WHAT DO YOU
THINK YOU'RE DOING?
I'M BEING ABDUCTED
BY FOREIGNERS!
CARACTACUS!
HEY!
WHERE DO THEY THINK
THEY'RE GOING?
OH, LOOK OUT!
DADDY!
AAAH!
WHERE DO THEY THINK
THEY'RE GOING?
OH, LOOK OUT!
DADDY!
AAAH!
OH.
OH, WHAT'S
HAPPENING?
LOOK.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
OH.
YOU'RE A GENIUS.
IT'S NOTHING,
REALLY.
LOOK!
THERE THEY ARE!
WE'LL CATCH THEM UP.
OH!
WE'VE LOST THEM.
WE'LL FIND THEM.
WHAT ABOUT
GRANDPA?
DON'T WORRY.
GRANDPA CAN
TAKE CARE
OF HIMSELF.
THIS IS LIVING.
THIS IS STYLE.
?? THIS IS ELEGANCE
BY THE MILE ??
?? OH, THE POSH,
POSH TRAVELING LIFE ??
?? THE TRAVELING LIFE FOR ME ??
?? FIRST CABIN
AND CAPTAIN'S TABLE ??
?? REGAL COMPANY ??
?? WHENEVER I'M BORED,
I TRAVEL ABROAD ??
?? BUT EVER SO PROPERLY ??
?? PORT OUT,
STARBOARD HOME ??
?? POSH WITH A CAPITAL
P-O-S-H, POSH ??
WE'RE LOSING
HEIGHT.
WE'RE LOSING HEIGHT.
JETTISON
BALLAST!
JETTISON BALLAST!
?? THE HANDS THAT HOLD
THE SCEPTERS ??
?? EVERY HEAD
THAT HOLDS A CROWN ??
?? THEY'LL ALWAYS GIVE
THEIR ALL FOR ME ??
?? THEY'LL NEVER
LET ME DOWN ??
?? I'M ON MY WAY
TO FARAWAY ??
?? TA-TA AND TOODLE-OO ??
?? AND FARE THEE WELL
AND BON VOYAGE ??
?? ARRIVEDERCI,TOO ??
?? OH, THE POSH,
POSH TRAVELING LIFE ??
?? THE TRAVELING LIFE FOR ME ??
?? FIRST CABIN
AND CAPTAIN'S TABLE ??
?? REGAL COMPANY ??
?? PARDON THE DUST
OF THE UPPER CRUST ??
?? FETCH US
A CUP OF TEA ??
?? PORT OUT,
STARBOARD HOME ??
?? POSH WITH A CAPITAL
P-O-S-H, POSH ??
?? IN EVERY FOREIGN STRAND
I LAND ??
?? THE ROYAL TRUMPETS
TOOT ME ??
?? THE ROYAL
WELCOME MAT IS OUT ??
?? THEY 21-GUN-SALUTE ME ??
?? BUT MONARCHIES ARE CONSTANTLY
COMMANDING ME TO CALL ??
?? LAST MONTH
I MISSED A MUFTI ??
?? WELL, YOU CAN'T
OBLIGE THEM ALL ??
?? OH, THE POSH,
POSH TRAVELING LIFE ??
?? THE TRAVELING LIFE FOR ME ??
?? HA HOMPITY TOMPITY
DI DEE DI DEE ??
?? LIDDLEEDOO, DEE DEE ??
WE'RE STILL
LOSING HEIGHT.
THERE MUST BE
SOMETHING ELSE
WE CAN THROW OUT.
THERE'S
NOTHING ELSE.
THERE'S NOTHING
ELSE WE--HEE HEE HEE.
NO, NO, NO!
AAH!
YOU JUST DROPPED SOMEONE!
I CAN'T SWIM!
COME BACK.
COME BACK!
?? OH, THE POSH,
POSH TRAVELING LIFE ??
?? THE TRAVELING LIFE FOR ME ??
?? FIRST CABIN
AND CAPTAIN'S TABLE ??
?? REGAL COMPANY ??
?? WHEN I'M AT THE HELM ??
?? THE WORLD'S MY REALM ??
?? AND I DO IT STYLISHLY ??
?? PORT OUT,
STARBOARD HOME ??
?
?? POSH WITH A CAPITAL "P" ?
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
START SWIMMING!
I DON'T SWIM.
THEN START
DROWNING!
?? P-O-S-H ?
?
?? POSH ????
HELLO.
WHERE ARE WE?
SOMEWHERE OVER
THE NORTH SEA, I THINK.
DON'T YOU KNOW
WHERE WE'RE
GOING?
NO, I DON'T,
BUT CHITTY DOES.
I THINK WE'RE
IN PRETTY GOOD HANDS.
GOOD MORNING.
THIS IS YOUR
CAPTAIN SPEAKING.
WE HOPE YOU HAD
A PLEASANT TRIP.
WE WILL SOON
LAND IN VULGARIA.
WHERE?
VULGARIA.
PLEASE FASTEN
YOUR SEAT BELTS.
THANK YOU.
THANKYOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
SPEED,
4 KNOTS, SIR.
WIND IS EAST-SOUTHEAST.
BRIGADE,
ATTENTION!
PRESENT ARMS!
WE HAVE A GUEST.
WELCOME HIM.
JAWOHL,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
ORDER ARMS!
AH, PROFESSOR POTTS,
PLEASE, SIR,
WALK THIS WAY.
PRESENT
ARMS!
ON BEHALF
OF HER MAJESTY,
THE QUEEN,
I--
HEY!
EXCUSE ME.
YOU'RE EARLY!
OHHHH...
DOWN THE TABLE
AND IN THE POCKET.
CHEAT,
CHEAT, CHEAT.
AH, PROFESSOR POTTS!
PROFESSOR?
VULGARIA WELCOMES
THE BRILLIANT
PROFESSOR POTTS,
INVENTOR EXTRAORDINAIRE.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
THERE SEEMS
TO BE SOME SORT
OF MISTAKE.
WHAT?
YOU ARE NOT
PROFESSOR POTTS,
THE INVENTOR?
WELL, I--
EXECUTIONER!
EXECUTIONER.
WHAT WOULD
YOU LIKE ME
TO INVENT, SIR?
AH, I WILL SHOW YOU.
MY HORSE!
GET THE HORSE
FOR HIS EXCELLENCY.
UP.
HEY-YA.
HOORAY!
[APPLAUSE]
GIDDY-UP.
HEY-YA!
WHOA! OOH!
HA HA HA!
HOW PROUD YOU LOOK
ON THAT FINE HORSE.
THE MOST BEAUTIFUL TOY
YOU EVER BOUGHT ME.
WHO IS THIS?
THIS IS PROFESSOR POTTS,
FROM ENGLAND.
WE HAVE
A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
HERR PROFESSOR,
COME ON.
ADIEU.
WELL, WHAT
DO YOU THINK,
PROFESSOR?
EVERYTHING
YOU NEED.
AND THESE WILL BE
YOUR ASSISTANTS.
AND HERE, THIS IS
THE BARONIAL CAR.
CAN YOU
MAKE IT FLOAT?
LIKE AMPHIBIAL
ENGLISH MOTY CAR,
OVER THE CRESTY WAVE
OF THE WATER.
NOT WITHOUT
MY LABORATORY.
OH, I HAVE ALREADY
THOUGHT OF THAT.
HERE IS
YOUR LAVATORY.
HA HA HA HA HA HA.
IF YOU SUCCEED
IN MAKING THE CAR FLOAT,
I WILL MAKE YOU
PRIVY COUNCILOR.
HA HA HA!
BUT IF YOU FAIL,
I WILL STUFF YOUR HEAD
WITH SAUERKRAUT
AND FEED YOU
TO THE DOGS!
FEEDY DORRIBLES,
SNARLY [SNORT]
HORRIBOLD.
YOU HAVE
24 HOURS!
24 HOURS AND WORKY NOSY
GRINDSTONE.
HEE. PROPER CARD
HE IS.
ODD SENSE OF HUMOR.
STUFF ME HEAD
WITH SAUERKRAUT.
HA HA!
THE BARON NEVER
MAKES JOKES.
LOOK AT US.
WE'VE BEEN HERE
FOR YEARS
AND YEARS.
I CAME HERE
TO REPAIR
THE TELEPHONE.
THAT WAS
24 YEARS AGO.
THEY HAVE
TERRIBLE
TORTURES.
THE THUMBSCREW
AND RACK.
THEY STRETCH YOU
AND STRETCH YOU!
WHEN I FIRST
CAME HERE,
I WAS A MIDGET.
PHAW!
COME ON.
ME, A FLOATING CAR.
WELL,
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE!
NOTHING'S
IMPOSSIBLE.
THAT'S WHAT
MY SON'S ALWAYS SAYING.
WE'LL
HELP YOU,
WON'T WE,
LADS?
NIL DESPERANDUM.
WE'LL SUCCEED.
YOU'LL SEE.
COURAGE, MAN,
COURAGE.
?? EVERY BURSTED BUBBLE
HAS A GLORY ??
?? EACH ABYSMAL FAILURE
MAKES A POINT ??
?? EVERY GLOWING PATH
THAT GOES ASTRAY ??
?? SHOWS YOU HOW TO FIND
A BETTER WAY ??
?? SO EVERY TIME
YOU STUMBLE ??
?? NEVER GRUMBLE ??
?? NEXT TIME
YOU'LL BUMBLE EVEN LESS ??
?? FOR UP FROM THE ASHES ??
?? UP FROM THE ASHES ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ??
?? GROW THE ROSES ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ??
?? OH, YES ??
?? GROW THE ROSES ??
?? THOSE ROSY ROSES ??
?? FROM THE ASHES
OF DISASTER ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ??
YES. I KNOW,
BUT HE WANTS IT
TO FLOAT.
?? FOR EVERY BIG
MISTAKE YOU MAKE ??
?? BE GRATEFUL ??
HEAR, HEAR.
?? THAT MISTAKE
YOU'LL NEVER MAKE AGAIN ??
NO, SIR.
?? EVERY SHINY DREAM
THAT FADES AND DIES ??
?? GENERATES THE STEAM
FOR TWO MORE TRIES ??
?? OH, THERE'S MAGIC
IN THE WAKE OF A FIASCO ??
CORRECT.
?? IT GIVES YOU THAT CHANCE
TO SECOND GUESS ??
OH, YES!
?? THEN UP FROM THE ASHES ??
?? UP FROM THE ASHES ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ??
?? GROW THE ROSES ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ??
?? GROW THE ROSES ??
?? THOSE ROSY ROSES ??
?? FROM THE ASHES
OF DISASTER ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ??
?? DISASTER DIDN'T STYMIE
LOUIS PASTEUR ??
NO, SIR.
?? EDISON TOOK YEARS
TO SEE THE LIGHT ??
RIGHT.
?? ALEXANDER GRAHAM
KNEW FAILURE WELL ??
?
?? HE TOOK A LOT OF KNOCKS ?
?? TO RING THAT BELL ??
?? SO WHEN IT GETS DISTRESSING,
IT'S A BLESSING ??
?? ONWARD AND UPWARD
YOU MUST PRESS ??
?? YES, YES ??
?? TILL UP FROM THE ASHES ??
?? UP FROM THE ASHES ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ??
?? GROW THE RO... ??
?? GROW THE ROSES ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ??
?? GROW THE RO... ??
?? GROW THE ROSES ??
?? THOSE ROSY RO... ??
?? THOSE ROSY ROSES ??
?? FROM THE ASHES
OF DISASTER ??
?? GROW THE ROSES
OF SUCCESS ????
START THE ENGINE!
SUCCESS!
BATTEN THE HATCHES!
MAN THE SHROUDS!
LIFT THE ANCHOR!
SUCCESS!
DADDY, WE'LL
NEVER FIND HIM.
WE MUST
KEEP LOOKING.
LOOK, LOOK!
WHAT'S THAT
DOWN THERE?
AHA.
LET'S HAVE A LOOK.
LOOK!
THE ZEPPELIN.
WE'VE FOUND
GRANDPA!
NO, NOT YET,
WE HAVEN'T.
OOH,JA, JA, JA.
WHAT'S THAT?
NO, NO, NO.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
YOUR EXCELLENCY!
WE'RE BEING
ATTACKED!
ATTACKED?
THAT WAS
THAT TERRIBLE
BOMBURST.
IT CERTAINLY WAS.
WHERE ARE THEY GOING?
[TRUMPETS PLAYING]
FLOATY IN
THE HEAVENLY ABODE,
FOUR PEOPLEBODES.
FIRE!
YOU WANT TO DESTROY
MY BEAUTIFUL CAR?
OH, THEY'RE
FIRING AT US.
CHILDREN.
THERE ARE
CHILDREN
UP THERE.
WE'D BETTER GET AWAY.
HANG ON.
WE'RE COMING IN TO LAND.
IT'S LANDING
IN THE VILLAGE.
CALL OUT
THE GUARDS!
EVERYBODY,
EVERYBODY, CHARGE!
CALL OUT
THE CHILD CATCHER.
CHARGE.
CHARGE!
[SLAM]
OH.
HEY, HEY, HEY!
LET ME IN!
HOORAY! WE'VE LANDED!
HOORAY!
WE'VE LANDED!
HOORAY! HOORAY!
AREN'T YOU
CLEVER, DADDY!
YES, HE
CERTAINLY IS.
YOU ALL STAY HERE.
I'M GOING UP
TO THAT CASTLE.
WE WANT
TO COME, TOO.
DON'T YOU THINK
WE OUGHT TO
STAY TOGETHER?
YOU'RE RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT,
COME ALONG.
COME ON,
CHILDREN.
I WONDER
WHERE WE ARE.
I DON'T KNOW.
COME ON.
PARDON ME, SIR.
UH, THE CASTLE?
LE CHATEAU?
DER SCHLOSS?
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH HIM?
COME ON.
WHAT ARE THEY
STARING AT?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT SEEMS TO BE
THE CHILDREN.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH THEM?
HAVEN'T THEY SEEN
CHILDREN BEFORE?
HAVEN'T YOU
NOTICED?
THERE AREN'T
ANY CHILDREN.
NOT ONE.
[TRUMPETS PLAYING]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
HEY, YOU.
SOLDIERS! SOLDIERS!
HEY, YOU THERE.
GET THOSE CHILDREN
IN HERE.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
QUICKLY, BEFORE
THE SOLDIERS
GET HERE.
COME, FRAULEIN.
QUICKLY. GET INSIDE.
PLEASE DON'T TALK.
GET THOSE CHILDREN
OUT OF SIGHT.
THE SOLDIERS WILL
TAKE THEM AWAY.
WHY? WHAT FOR?
NOBODY'S ALLOWED
TO HAVE CHILDREN
IN VULGARIA.
NOT ALLOWED?
WHAT ABOUT THESE TOYS?
THE BARONESS,
SHE HATES CHILDREN.
WHO COULD
HATE CHILDREN?
DON'T MAKE A SOUND.
SEARCH EVERY HOUSE
FROM TOP TO BOTTOM!
THE FIRST SECTION,
STEP OUT OVER THERE.
THE SECOND, OVER THERE
AND SEARCH. QUICK!
SECTION THREE,
OVER THERE. QUICK!
SEARCH EVERYWHERE!
GIDDY-UP!
THERE ARE CHILDREN HERE
SOMEWHERE.
I CAN SMELL THEM.
AHA!
CAPTAIN, I THINK
WE'VE GOT THEM.
LIEUTENANT.
YOU TWO MEN,
BREAK DOWN
THIS DOOR.
QUICK!
GET THIS DOOR OPEN.
QUICKLY!
I'M COMING!
BREAK
THE DOOR DOWN!
QUICKLY!
YOU HAVE NO RIGHT
TO COME IN HERE.
SEARCH THE PLACE!
SEARCH!
AHA!
THEY ARE HERE SOMEWHERE.
I CAN FEEL IT
IN MY BONES.
THERE ARE CHILDREN HERE
SOMEWHERE.
CHILDREN?
IN A TOY SHOP?
SUCH A NOTION.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING?
THAT'S SOMETHING
SPECIAL
FOR THE BARON'S
BIRTHDAY.
LET ME TELL YOU,
TOYMAKER.
THIS NOSE OF MINE
HAS NEVER FAILED ME,
AND IF THERE ARE CHILDREN
HERE, MY FRIEND,
YOU WILL DIE.
HEH HEH HEH HEH.
AHA.
OPEN IT UP!
SEARCH THE CELLAR!
THE BARONESS WILL
HAVE YOUR TEETH
FOR A NECKLACE
AND YOUR EYEBALLS
FOR EARRINGS.
NOBODY.
FOOL! IDIOT!
OUT OF MY WAY!
YOU HAVE TO KNOW
WHERE TO LOOK.
LIKE COCKROACHES,
THEY GET
UNDER THE FLOORS,
IN THE CRACKS IN THE WALLS,
IN THE WOODWORK.
I DON'T TRUST A MAN
WHO MAKES TOYS
IN A LAND WHERE
CHILDREN ARE FORBIDDEN.
EVERY TOY I MAKE
IS EXCLUSIVELY
FOR HIS EXCELLENCY,
THE BARON.
CAPTAIN, WE'VE CAPTURED
THE FLYING CAR!
LET'S GO!
UH-HUH!
[HORN HONKS]
TAKE THIS CAR
TO THE CASTLE!
THEY CAN'T
TAKE CHITTY, DADDY.
WHAT WILL YOU DO?
I WON'T
JUST STAND HERE.
ARE YOU GOING TO
TAKE ON
THE WHOLE ARMY
SINGLE-HANDED?
WHAT KIND
OF A COUNTRY
IS THIS?
NO CHILDREN!
EVERYBODY
TERRIFIED.
FRIEND, TAKE
SOME GOOD ADVICE.
TAKE YOUR CHILDREN
AND YOUR GOOD LADY
AND GET OUT
OF VULGARIA.
AND LEAVE GRANDPA
UP IN THE CASTLE?
JUST TELL ME
HOW TO GET THERE.
UNLESS I
FINISH THIS IN TIME
FOR THE BARON'S
BIRTHDAY TOMORROW,
I'LL BE DEAD.
I'LL GO MYSELF.
TRULY, YOU STAY HERE
WITH THE CHILDREN.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE LETTING YOURSELF
IN FOR, BELIEVE ME.
HERE'S ONE FOR YOU,
ONE FOR YOU.
THANK YOU.
KEEP THEM
OUT OF SIGHT.
YOU BE GOOD.
DO WHAT TRULY
TELLS YOU.
YES, DADDY.
WELL,
ARE YOU COMING?
COME.
QUICKLY, QUICKLY,
QUICKLY.
THERE ISN'T
A SCRAP OF FOOD.
MY TUMMY HURTS.
MINE'S MAKING
FUNNY NOISES.
I MUST FIND
SOMETHING FOR YOU,
IF YOU PROMISE ME
NOT TO MOVE FROM HERE
UNTIL I COME BACK.
WE PROMISE.
REMEMBER,
STAY RIGHT HERE.
TO GET IN THAT WAY,
YOU WOULD
HAVE TO BE A MOUSE
OR A MAGICIAN.
WE SHOULD
GO DOWN NOW
BEFORE A SENTRY
SEES US.
COME.
THE FLYING CAR!
AH, THE FLYING CAR!
OH, AT LAST IT'S MINE!
HA HA!
SEND FOR THE INVENTOR!
WELL, THEN, FLY!
YES, FLY.
COME ON, FLY.
[HONK]
FLY, FLY, FLY.
I COMMAND YOU
TO FLY!
BRING HIM
OVER HERE.
WHAT'S THIS
DOING HERE?
YOU'RE
THE INVENTOR.
MAKE THIS CAR
FLY.
MAKE IT FLY.
GO GET IN.
WELL...
[HONK]
STAND BACK,
EVERYONE!
WE ARE
GOING TO
FLY.
YOO-HOO, BOMBIE!
WAIT FOR ME!
EVERY TIME I WANT
A LITTLE FUN,
SHE TURNS UP.
OH.
MY DARLING,
WE'RE GOING
FOR A FLY.
HOW EXCITING.
FLY.
HOW THRILLING.
COME ON.
HURRY UP.
I'M DOING MY BEST,
SIR.
HERE'S ONE
WE HAVEN'T TRIED YET.
HERE WE GO.
HOLD ON!
AAH!
ISN'T IT
EXCITING,
MY DEAR?
OH, HA HA HA HA!
YOU'RE A GENIUS.
BRING MY GUNS!
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL GET YOU DOWN.
I'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR THIS FOR 20 YEARS.
HOLD ON.
ARE YOU STILL THERE?
DON'T MOVE.
[GUNSHOT]
AAAH!
HERE,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
OH, OH, OH.
OH, MY GOD.
MY DIAMONDS.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT,
MY DEAR?
I'M ALL RIGHT,
MY DUMPLING.
GOOD.
NEVER MIND.
I'LL GET HER THE NEXT TIME.
[BELLS JINGLE]
HERE WE ARE, CHILDREN.
COME AND GET YOUR LOLLIPOPS.
LOLLIPOPS.
COME ALONG,
MY LITTLE ONES.
LOLLIPOPS.
ICE CREAM,
CHOCOLATE,
ALL FREE TODAY.
LISTEN.
COME ALONG, CHILDREN.
LOLLIPOPS.
WHAT'S THAT?
CHILDREN, WHERE ARE YOU?
I KNOW YOU'RE HERE
SOMEWHERE.
I'VE LOTS
OF LOVELY GOODIES FOR YOU.
JEREMY,
YOU MUSTN'T.
LOLLIPOPS...
AND ALL FREE TODAY.
CHERRY PIES.
CREAM PUFFS.
ICE CREAM.
TREACLE TARTS.
TREACLE TARTS!
ICE CREAMS.
AND ALL FREE!
COME ALONG,
KIDDIEWINKIES.
COME ON!
BUT, JEREMY,
TRULY SAID--
WE'LL GET TRULY
SOME AS WELL.
[BELLS JINGLE]
MR. MAN!
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
HEY!
WAIT!
CHILDREN!
COME BACK HERE!
WAIT!
COME ALONG,
MY LITTLE DEARS,
MY LITTLE MICE.
COME TO ME.
WHAT WILL IT BE?
ICE CREAM?
YES, ICE CREAM!
STRAWBERRY,
CHOCOLATE,
VANILLA?
STRAWBERRY!
CHOCOLATE!
IT'S ALL INSIDE.
COME ALONG.
NOT A PENNY TO PAY.
GO INSIDE, MY LITTLE DEARS!
AHA HA HA HA!
HELP!
HA HA HA HA!
AAH!
HELP!
CHILDREN!
TRULY!
HELP! HELP!
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
HE TOOK THE CHILDREN!
YOUR EXCELLENCY!
HELP! HELP!
SILENCE!
CHILDREN,
YOUR HIGHNESS.
FOREIGN CHILDREN.
UNIQUE SPECIMENS.
YOU'RE SURE
THEY CAN'T GET OUT?
HA HA HA!
NO, YOUR HIGHNESS.
PERHAPS YOUR HIGHNESS
WOULD CARE
TO EXAMINE THEM.
NASTY
LITTLE CREATURES.
VERY, VERY
TREACHEROUS.
FOREIGN.
AAH! AAH!
WAIT TILL OUR DADDY
HEARS ABOUT THIS.
HE'LL BLOW UP
THE WHOLE CASTLE!
TAKE THEM AWAY
TO THE TOWER.
TO THE TOWER!
YOU'RE A MEAN OLD LADY.
AND VERY UGLY.
[GASP]
OH!
SHE'S GOING!
[WHISTLING]
200 FEET ABOVE US
THROUGH THAT SOLID ROCK
IS THE CASTLE
OF BARON BOMBURST.
THESE ARE OUR CHILDREN.
FOR 12 YEARS,
WE HAVE HIDDEN THEM HERE.
THEY DON'T KNOW
WHAT A TREE LOOKS LIKE
OR WHAT IT IS TO RUN
OR TO LAUGH.
[WHISTLE]
FOOD!
HERE. THERE'S BREAD
FOR EVERYONE.
LIKE LITTLE RATS,
THEY RUN
UP AND DOWN THE SEWERS,
STEALING FOOD
FROM THE KITCHENS.
HERE, CATCH!
SON! SON!
I THINK MY CHILDREN
ARE IN THE CASTLE
WITH THEIR GRANDFATHER.
HAVE YOU SEEN THEM?
A LITTLE BOY
AND GIRL?
YES.
THEY'RE LOCKED
IN THE TOWER.
AND THE GRANDFATHER?
IN THE DUNGEON.
SIR, HAVE YOU COME
TO HELP US?
ARE YOU GOING TO
TAKE US OUT OF HERE?
WHAT'S YOUR NAME, SON?
PETER, SIR.
WELL, PETER, YOU
SHOULDN'T BE AFRAID,
EVEN IN A TERRIBLE
PLACE LIKE THIS
BECAUSE THERE'S
ALWAYS HOPE.
THAT'S WHAT I ALWAYS
TELL MY CHILDREN
WHEN THEY'RE AFRAID.
?? A GENTLE BREEZE ??
?? FROM HUSHABYE MOUNTAIN ??
?? SOFTLY BLOWS
O'ER LULLABY BAY ??
?? IT FILLS THE SAILS
OF BOATS THAT ARE WAITING ??
?? WAITING TO SAIL... ??
?? SO CLOSE YOUR EYES
ON HUSHABYE MOUNTAIN ??
?? WAVE GOODBYE
TO CARES OF THE DAY ??
?? AND WATCH YOUR BOAT
FROM HUSHABYE MOUNTAIN ??
?? SAIL FAR AWAY ??
?? FROM LULLABY BAY ????
IS THAT
YOUR ONLY ADVICE?
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL
DREAM, CARACTACUS,
BUT I DON'T THINK
IT WILL HELP THEM.
WE'RE GOING TO GET UP
INTO THAT CASTLE.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE!
WE'LL SEE.
EVERYBODY LISTEN TO ME.
YOU WANT TO GET
OUT OF HERE?
YES!
TOMORROW IS
BARON BOMBURST'S BIRTHDAY.
BOO!
WE'LL GIVE HIM
A BIRTHDAY PARTY
HE'LL NEVER FORGET.
GATHER AROUND HERE.
I HAVE AN IDEA.
YES, COME IN CLOSER.
ALL RIGHT, QUIET!
?? HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO ME ??
?? HAPPY BIRTHDAY,
DEAR BOMBIE-- ????
OH, DON'T MOVE.
WHAT A PICTURE!
SUCH MEMORIES
IT BRINGS BACK.
[SPEAKING GERMAN]
MY LITTLE DUMPLING!
MEIN LIEBLING!
?? YOU'RE MY LITTLE
CHOOTCHY FACE ??
?? MY COOTCHY, COOTCHY, WOOTCHY
LITTLE CHOOTCHY FACE ??
?? EVERY TIME
I LOOK AT YOU ??
?? I SIGH ??
?? AND YOU'RE
MY LITTLE TEDDY BEAR ??
OOH!
?? MY LOVEY, LOVEY-DOVEY
LITTLE TEDDY BEAR ??
?? YOU'RE THEAPFEL STRUDEL
OFMEIN EYE ??
?? YOUR CHOOTCHY-WOOTCHY NOSE ??
?? YOUR CHOOTCHY-WOOTCHY EYES ??
?? THEY SET MY HEART
AFLUTTER ??
?? YOUR
OOTCHY-COOTCHY WAYS ??
OOTCHY-COOTCHY GAZE ??
?? WILTS ME DOWN
LIKE MELTING BUTTER ??
?? YOU'RE MY LITTLE
CHOOTCHY FACE ??
?? AND YOU'RE
MY TEDDY BEAR ??
?? TOGETHER WE'RE
A CHOOTCHY-WOOTCHY ??
?? OOTCHY-COOTCHY PAIR ??
?? WHATEVER YOU MAY ASK
BECOMES MY HEAVY TASK ??
?? I ONLY LIVE
TO SERVE YOU ??
?? I NEVER WILL DIVINE
WHAT MAGIC MADE YOU MINE ??
?? I ONLY KNOW
I DON'T DESERVE YOU ??
AAH!
HA HA HA HA!
?? YOU'RE MY LITTLE
CHOOTCHY FACE ??
?? AND YOU'RE
MY TEDDY BEAR ??
?? TOGETHER WE'RE
A CHOOTCHY-WOOTCHY ??
?? OOTCHY-COOTCHY ??
??
?? CHOOTCHY
?? WOOTCHY ??
?? OOTCHY ??
?? COOTCHY ??
?? CHOOTCHY-WOOTCHY ??
?? OOTCHY-COOTCHY ??
?? PAIR ????
OH, WHAT A ROTTEN
BIRTHDAY PARTY.
NEVER MIND,
MY LITTLE BOMBIE.
I HAVE
A SURPRISE FOR YOU.
SURPRISES?
I LOVE SURPRISES!
[RAP RAP]
SIT DOWN QUICKLY.
SUMMON THE TOYMAKER!
COME ON! HURRY UP!
DON'T WASTE TIME!
[LAUGHTER]
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
I WISH YOU
ALL YOU WISH YOURSELF.
WHAT HAVE YOU MADE ME?
WHAT HAVE I MADE YOU?
SUCH A TOY!
A WORK OF MECHANICAL
PERFECTION.
WELL, WHERE IS IT?
BRING IT IN!
RIGHT AWAY.
BRING IN THE BARON'S
BIRTHDAY PRESENT!
HERE, HERE.
THIS YEAR,
YOUR EXCELLENCY,
I HAVE SURPASSED
EVEN MYSELF.
PUT IT DOWN THERE.
CAREFUL!
CAREFUL WITH IT!
FOR MONTHS, I HAVE BEEN
WORKING NIGHTUNDDAY
PERFECTING
EVERY LITTLE DETAIL
TO BRING YOU...THIS!
OOH!
OH!
DOLLS?
I HAVE HUNDREDS
OF DOLLS!
OH, NO! DOLLS.
BUT THIS IS NOT JUST
AN ORDINARY DOLL,
YOUR EXCELLENCY.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
OH!
AH!
YOU SEE?
?? WHAT DO YOU SEE ??
?? YOU PEOPLE GAZING
AT ME? ??
?? YOU SEE A DOLL
ON A MUSIC BOX ??
?? THAT'S WOUND BY A KEY ??
?? HOW CAN YOU TELL ??
?? I'M UNDER A SPELL? ??
?? I'M WAITING
FOR LOVE'S FIRST KISS ??
?? YOU CANNOT SEE ??
?? HOW MUCH
I LONG TO BE FREE ??
?? TURNING AROUND
ON THIS MUSIC BOX ??
?? THAT'S WOUND BY A KEY ??
?? YEARNING ??
?? WHILE ??
?? I'M ??
?? TURNING AROUND
AND AROUND ????
OH, WUNDERBAR!
OH!
HA HA HA HA!
HA HA HA!
AH! AH!
OOH!
[MUSIC PLAYS]
?? WHAT DO
YOU SEE? ??
?? TRULY
SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?? YOU'RE TRULY,
TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?
?? YOU SEE A DOL
L ON A MUSIC BOX ?
?? THAT'S WOUND
BY A KEY ??
??
?? HOW CAN YOU TELL
?? I'M UNDER
A SPELL? ??
?? I'M WAITING... ??
?? HONEST, TRULY ??
?? YOU'RE THE ANSWER
TO MY WISHES ??
?? TRULY SCRUMPTIOUS ??
?? THOUGH I MAY SEEM
PRESUMPTUOUS ??
?? TURNING AROUND
ON THIS MUSIC BOX ??
?? THAT'S WOUND
BY A KEY ??
?? YEARNING
?? MY HEART BEATS
SO UNRULY ??
?
?? YEARNING ??
?? BECAUSE I
LOVE YOU TRULY ?
?? HONEST, TRULY, I DO ??
?? TURNING AROUN
D AND AROUND ????
[APPLAUSE]
JUST A MINUTE!
AH-CHOO!
HA HA HA HA!
OH, I'M SO HAPPY,
I COULD JUMP FOR JOY!
OH!
AAH!
COME ON!
CHILDREN!
OH!
[WHISTLE]
OH, NO!
LET ME DOWN!
OH!
AAH!
CALL OUT
THE CAVALRY!
LET ME DOWN!
AAH! OH! OH!
AAH!
JEREMY!
JEMIMA!
THEY COULD BE
ANYWHERE.
YOU LOOK THERE.
I'LL GO THIS WAY.
JEREMY! JEMIMA!
JEREMY AND JEMIMA!
IT'S TRULY!
TRULY!
WE'RE IN HERE!
DON'T WORRY.
WE'LL GET YOU OUT.
HERE! HERE, QUICK.
THEY'RE IN THERE.
CHILDREN, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
GET US OUT
OF HERE!
THEY'RE IN THERE.
HELP ME
BREAK THE DOOR DOWN.
CHILDREN, GET AWAY
FROM THE DOOR.
CHILDREN!
DADDY!
DADDY! DADDY!
AAH!
OH!
LET ME DOWN!
OW!
OH!
MYLIEBCHEN,
ARE YOU HURT?
MY BACK IS BROKEN.
WE MUST ESCAPE
THROUGH THE CELLARS.
VERY WELL. COME ON.
COME ON!
DADDY, LOOK
AT THE CHILDREN.
YAHOO!
YOU STAY HERE.
DADDY!
WHERE ARE THESE CHILDREN
COMING FROM?
WE PASSED A LAW
AGAINST CHILDREN.
THIS WAY.
QUICKLY.
WE'LL GO DOWN HERE.
NO, NO. I'LL GET
MY CLOTHES DIRTY.
DON'T ARGUE.
OH, MY CROWN.
I LOST MY CROWN.
OH, NEVER MIND,
MY LITTLE PUMPKIN.
HERE.
ATTACK!
DADDY!
LOOK! THERE'S CHITTY!
CHITTY'S COME
TO SAVE US! HOORAY!
HELLO--A MOTORCAR.
WHAT'S THAT DOING HERE?
THERE'S GRANDPA.
CARAC--CARACTACUS!
MY BOY!
AAH! AAH! AAH!
OH!
STAND BACK
FROM THE PROPELLERS.
KEEP CLEAR.
BYE!
AND SO, AFTER THAT,
VULGARIA BECAME
A FREE COUNTRY,
AND ALL THE CHILDREN
LAUGHED AND PLAYED
IN THE SUNSHINE,
AND THEY WERE
VERY, VERY HAPPY.
AND CHITTY FLEW HIGH
OVER THE MOUNTAINS
BACK TO ENGLAND,
EVERYBODY SAFE AND SOUND.
AND DADDY AND TRULY
WERE MARRIED.
AND LIVED HAPPILY
EVER AFTER.
YES.
IS THAT HOW
THE STORY ENDS?
IT'S GETTING LATE.
WE BETTER GET BACK.
WELL.
GOODBYE, JEREMY.
GOODBYE, JEMIMA.
WILL WE SEE YOU
AGAIN?
OH, I EXPECT SO.
GOODBYE.
TRULY.
I HOPE THE CHILDREN
DIDN'T EMBARRASS YOU
BY THAT SILLY JOKE
ABOUT US GETTING MARRIED.
YOU KNOW HOW KIDS ARE.
I DON'T THINK
THEY REALIZE
HOW RIDICULOUS
THAT WOULD BE.
RIDICULOUS?
YOU LIVE
IN THAT BIG HOUSE,
YOUR FATHER,
THE FACTORY AND ALL.
IT'S A DIFFERENT WORLD,
TRULY.
IF I SAID THAT,
YOU'D CALL ME
A SNOB.
I DIDN'T MEAN--
GOODBYE.
DON'T YOU WANT
TO RIDE UP FRONT?
THAT WAS
A FINE PICNIC,
WASN'T IT?
SHALL WE HAVE
ANOTHER ONE TOMORROW?
WITH TRULY?
WELL, MISS SCRUMPTIOUS
HAS A LOT
OF SOCIAL ENGAGEMENTS.
ARE WE EVER GOING TO
SEE TRULY AGAIN, DADDY?
WELL, WE'LL SEE.
LOOK, THAT'S
LORD SCRUMPTIOUS' CAR.
I BELIEVE IT IS.
WHAT'S IT
DOING HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
EXCUSE ME.
GOOD AFTERNOON.
ARE YOU--
[SHOUTING]
BOOM! THAT'S WIPED OUT
YOUR DASHED CAVALRY.
I HAVE MY SECOND
INFANTRY BATTALION
ATTACKING HERE
FROM THE REAR.
ATTACKING FROM THE REAR?
THAT'S DASHED UNETHICAL.
ARTILLERY,
PREPARE TO OPEN FIRE.
FIRE!
NUMBER ONE BATTALION,
PREPARE TO ADVANCE!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
AH, THERE YOU ARE,
YOUNG POTTS.
BEEN WAITING FOR YOU.
AHA! WIPED OUT
YOUR ARTILLERY!
YOU'RE A CAD,
POTTS.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
FANCY YOU BEING
OLD BUNGIE'S SON--
BUNGIE POTTS, BEST
BATMAN I EVER HAD.
YOU WERE--
ALLOW ME TO INTRODUCE
MY BRIGADIER.
HOW ABOUT
SOME MORE TEA?
YES, SIR.
RIGHT AWAY, SIR.
YOUNG MAN,
THERE'S A CHANCE
YOU'LL BE RICH.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
THOSE CONFOUNDED
SWEETS OF YOURS.
USELESS FOR HUMANS,
WONDERFUL FOR DOGS.
WOOF SWEETS
WE'LL CALL THEM.
CANINE CANDIES.
DOGS LOVE THEM.
MAKE A FORTUNE.
YOU'VE DONE IT,
DADDY.
IT'S THE POSH LIFE
FOR US NOW, MY BOY.
WE'LL BE RICH!
HOORAY!
I INVENTED SOMETHING
THAT ACTUALLY WORKS?
I'VE GOT A CONTRACT.
SIGN HERE, PLEASE.
WAIT.
I'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
WHAT ABOUT
THE CONTRACT?
DADDY,
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
DADDY!
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH HIM?
WELL, HE'S A BIT
OF AN ECCENTRIC, SIR,
A GENIUS,
OF COURSE,
BUT DEFINITELY
AN ECCENTRIC.
CAN'T IMAGINE
WHERE HE GETS IT FROM.
TRULY, YOU'LL NEVER
BELIEVE IT.
YOUR FATHER
WAS AT MY HOUSE.
THEY TOLD ME
AT THE HOUSE.
WE'RE RICH.
OH!
YOU KNOW,
MORE THAN THAT,
I HAVE SUCCEEDED.
I ALWAYS KNEW
YOU WOULD.
YOU KNOW
SOMETHING ELSE?
THE KIDS WERE RIGHT.
THERE'S NOTHING
RIDICULOUS ABOUT
GETTING MARRIED.
WHOEVER SAID
THERE WAS?
WELL, MR. POTTS.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
NOW YOU'LL HAVE TO
MARRY ME.
SO DREAMS
CAN COME TRUE.
YES, THEY CAN,
BUT YOU HAVE TO
BE PRACTICAL, TOO.
YOU HAVE TO FACE FACTS.
MEN SHOULD SEE THINGS
AS THEY REALLY ARE.
A MAN
WITH RESPONSIBILITIES
CAN'T HAVE HIS HEAD
IN THE CLOUDS.
A MAN SHOULD KEEP
HIS FEET ON THE GROUND.
A MAN SHOULD
HAVE HIS DREAMS
BUT LEARN TO PUT THEM
TO PRACTICAL USE,
NOT JUST SIT AROUND
AND THINK ABOUT THEM
ALL THE TIME.
?? OH, YOU,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WE LOVE YOU ??
?? AND OUR PRETTY
CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG
LOVES US, TOO ??
?? HIGH, LOW,
ANYWHERE WE GO ??
?? ON CHITTY CHITTY
WE DEPEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? IT'S UNCATEGORICAL ??
?? A FUEL-BURNING ORACLE ??
?? A PHANTASMAGORICAL MACHINE ??
?? IT'S MORE THAN SPECTACULAR ??
?? TO USE THE VERNACULAR ??
?? IT'S WIZARD,
IT'S SMASHING, IT'S KEEN ??
?? OH, CHITTY, YOU, CHITTY,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WE LOVE YOU ??
?? AND, CHITTY, IN, CHITTY,
PRETTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG,
WHAT WE'LL DO ??
?? NEAR, CHITTY, FAR, CHITTY
, IN OUR MOTORCAR ??
?? OH, WHAT A HAPPY TIME
WE'LL SPEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED FRIEND ??
?? BANG BANG
CHITTY CHITTY BANG BANG ??
?? OUR FINE
FOUR-FENDERED ??
?? FRIEND ??
?? CHITTY CHITTY
BANG BANG ??
?? FINE FOUR-FENDERED
CHITTY CHITTY FRIEND ????