Ahh, ooh
Cinderella
You're as lovely as your name
You're a sunset in a frame
Though you're dressed in rags
You wear an air of queenly grace
Anyone can see
A throne would be your proper place
Cinderella
If you give your heart a chance
It will lead you
To the kingdom of romance
There you'll see your dreams unfold
Cinderella
In the sweetest story
Ever told
NARRATOR: Once upon a
time, in a faraway land,
there was a tiny kingdom,
peaceful, prosperous, and rich
in romance and tradition.
Here, in a stately chateau,
there lived a widowed gentleman
and his little
daughter, Cinderella.
Although he was a kind
and devoted father,
and gave his beloved child
every luxury and comfort,
still, he felt she
needed a mother's care.
And so, he married again,
choosing for his second wife
a woman of good family,
with two daughters
just Cinderella's age,
by name, Anastasia and Drizella.
It was upon the untimely death
of this good man, however,
that the stepmother's
true nature was revealed.
Cold, cruel, and bitterly jealous
of Cinderella's charm and beauty,
she was grimly determined
to forward the interests
of her own two awkward daughters.
Thus, as time went by,
the chateau fell into disrepair.
For the family fortunes
were squandered
upon the vain and
selfish stepsisters,
while Cinderella was
abused, humiliated,
and finally forced to become
a servant in her own house.
And yet, through it all,
Cinderella remained
ever gentle and kind.
For with each dawn, she
found new hope that someday
her dreams of happiness
would come true.
(TWEETING)
(GROANING)
(CHIRPING)
(YAWNING)
(GIGGLING)
(CHIRPING)
(CINDERELLA GIGGLING)
Well, it serves you right,
spoiling people's best dreams.
Yes, I know it's a lovely morning,
but it was a lovely dream, too.
(SIGHING)
What kind of a dream?
Mmm-mmm. Can't tell.
(CHIRPING)
'Cause if you tell a wish,
it won't come true.
And, after all...
(SINGING) A dream is a wish
Your heart makes
When you're fast asleep
In dreams you will lose
Your heartaches
- (TWEETS)
- Shh.
Whatever you wish for
You keep
(CHIRPING)
Have faith
In your dreams and someday
Your rainbow will
come smiling through
No matter how your
heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
The dream that you wish
Will come true
- (BELL CHIMES)
- Oh, that clock.
Old killjoy.
I hear you. "Come on,
get up," you say.
Time to start another day.
Even he orders me around.
Well, there's one thing.
They can't order me
to stop dreaming.
And perhaps someday...
The dreams that I wish
Will come true
(CHIRPING)
Da dum da da dum
Bum bum bum
La da da da bum dum
Ba dee
(CINDERELLA HUMMING)
Ba dum dum ba dum dum
Ba dee
(SHOOING)
(CINDERELLA HUMMING)
La la la la la la
La la
Ahhh
(HUMMING)
(SHIVERING)
(MICE SINGING)
No matter how your
heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
The dream that you wish
Will come true
(MICE CHATTERING)
- Look what I found.
- Over there, Cinderella.
- (CHATTERING)
- Wait a minute.
One at a time, please.
Now, Jaq, what's all
the fuss about?
New mouse in the house.
Brand-new. Never saw it before.
- Visitor. Visitor!
- Oh, a visitor.
- Well, she'll need a dress...
- (CHUCKLING)
- No, no, no.
- It's not a she, it's a he.
- He, he.
- Oh, that does make a difference.
- He'll need a jacket and shoes...
- Gotta get him out!
- It's in a rat trap.
- Where?
In a trap? Why didn't you say so?
(MICE CHATTERING)
Now, now, calm down, everybody.
Oh, the poor little
thing's scared to death.
Jaq, maybe you better
explain things to him.
Zuk, zuk, Cinderelly.
Now, now. Look, little guy.
Take it easy. Nothin'
to worry about.
(CHUCKLES) We like you.
Cinderelly likes you, too.
She's nice, very nice.
That's better. Come
on, now. Zuk, zuk.
Uh, uh, zuk, zuk.
(EXCITED CHATTERING)
Well, that's better.
Hmm.
Well, let's just
slip it on for size.
(MICE LAUGHING)
Uh-huh. It is a little snug.
But it'll have to do.
Now, for a name.
I've got one. Octavius.
But for short, we'll call you Gus.
Like it, Gus? Like it? Like it?
Gus-Gus. (LAUGHS)
I've got to hurry. See he
keeps out of trouble, Jaq.
And don't forget to
warn him about the cat.
Zuk, zuk. Look, did
you ever see a cat?
Cat, cat?
Cat, cat. Lucifer. That's him.
Meany, sneaky.
Jump at you. Bite at you.
Big, big. Big as a house. (MEOWS)
Zuk, zuk, Lucify?
Duh, Lucify, zuk, zuk.
(SNORING)
(PURRING)
(MEOWING)
Here, kitty, kitty.
(YAWNING)
Come, kitty. Come on.
Lucifer! Come here!
(YAWNING)
I'm sorry if Your Highness
objects to an early breakfast.
It's certainly not my
idea to feed you first.
It's orders. Come on.
Uh, Lucify. Is that Lucify?
Zuk, Lucify. That's him.
(LAUGHING) Gus-Gus take
the Lucify and look at!
No, Gus-Gus, no.
Now, listen here. Lucify not funny.
Lucify mean.
(DOG WHIMPERING)
(GROWLING)
- (WHINING)
- Bruno.
(GROWLING)
Bruno!
Dreaming again.
(GIGGLES) Chasing Lucifer?
Catch him this time? That's bad.
(LAUGHING)
Suppose they heard you upstairs.
You know the orders.
So if you don't want to
lose that nice, warm bed,
you'd better get rid
of those dreams.
Know how?
Just learn to like cats.
(GROANS)
No, I mean it. Lucifer has
his good points, too.
For one thing, he...
Well, sometimes he...
Hmm.
There must be something
good about him.
(LAUGHING)
- (GROWLING)
- (MEOWING)
Bruno!
Oh, Bruno.
Come on, now. Outside.
I know it isn't easy,
but at least we should try
to get along together.
And that includes
you, Your Majesty.
CINDERELLA: Breakfast time.
Everybody up. Hurry, hurry.
Come on, everybody,
breakfast, breakfast.
Come on, let's eat breakfast.
(CHUCKLING)
Breakfast? Ooh, breakfast!
JAQ: Uh-oh, Lucify.
How're we gonna get out?
Let's see.
Listen, ibby-dibby. Got an idea.
Now, somebody's got to sneak out,
get Lucify to chase him,
run over to the corner
and keep Lucify there.
Then we all run out. Zuk.
ALL: Yuk, yuk. Out.
Now we choose the one
to do it. Ibby-dibby hop.
- ALL: Hop.
- Uh, hop.
- Ready, hop.
- Hop.
Hop.
- Now...
- Hop, hop, hop.
Uh, hop.
- (GIGGLING)
- MICE: Shh!
(CINDERELLA HUMMING)
(MICE CHATTERING)
CINDERELLA: Oh, there you are.
I was wondering.
All right. Breakfast is served.
(HENS CLUCKING)
Uh, uh... Take it
easy, cluck-cluck.
Duh... Let go! Let go, now.
CINDERELLA:
Stop that. Go on, shoo, shoo.
Shoo, shoo, shoo!
Poor little Gus.
Here.
Help yourself.
(PURRING)
(GASPS)
(GROWLING)
Hmm. Where's Gus-Gus?
Well, guess he got away.
(PANTING)
- (BELLS RINGING)
- WOMAN 1: Cinderella!
All right, all right. I'm coming.
Oh, my goodness.
Morning, noon, and night.
- WOMAN 1: Cinderella!
- (BELL RINGING)
Coming, coming.
(BELL RINGING)
- WOMAN 2: Cinderella!
- CINDERELLA: I'm coming.
(BELL RINGING)
- Cinderella!
- In a minute.
(BELL RINGING)
Cinderella!
WOMEN: Cinderella!
Good morning, Drizella. Sleep well?
DRIZELLA: Huh. As if you care.
Take that ironing and
have it back in an hour.
One hour, you hear?
Yes, Drizella.
CINDERELLA:
Good morning, Anastasia.
ANASTASIA: Well, it's about time.
Don't forget the mending.
Don't be all day getting
it done, either.
Yes, Anastasia.
(CINDERELLA CLEARING THROAT)
STEPMOTHER:
Well, come in, child, come in.
Good morning, Stepmother.
Pick up the laundry and
get on with your duties.
Yes, Stepmother.
(MEOWING)
(ANASTASIA SCREAMING)
ANASTASIA:
Oh! Oh, Mother. Oh, Mother!
Mother! Mother!
You did it. You did it on purpose.
Mother! Mother! Mother!
- Now what did you do?
- ANASTASIA: Oh!
She put it there.
A big, ugly mouse, under my teacup.
All right, Lucifer. What
did you do with him?
Oh, you're not fooling anybody.
We'll just see about this.
Come on. Let him go.
Now the other one.
Come on!
Oh, poor little Gus.
Oh, Lucifer, won't you ever learn?
STEPMOTHER: Cinderella!
Yes, Stepmother.
- Humph!
- Are you gonna get it.
STEPMOTHER:
Close the door, Cinderella.
Come here.
- You don't think that I...
- Hold your tongue.
Now,
it seems we have time on our hands.
- But I was only trying to...
- Silence!
Time for vicious practical jokes.
Perhaps we can put
it to better use.
Now, let me see...
There's the large carpet
in the main hall.
Clean it!
And the windows, upstairs and down.
Wash them!
Oh, yes. And the tapestries
and the draperies.
- But I just finished...
- Do them again!
And don't forget the garden.
Scrub the terrace.
Sweep the halls and the stairs.
Clean the chimneys.
And, of course, there's the mending
and the sewing and the laundry.
Oh, yes. And one more thing.
See that Lucifer gets his bath.
(KING YELLING)
KING: My son has been avoiding
his responsibilities long enough.
It's high time he married
and settled down.
Of course, Your Majesty.
But we must be patient.
I am patient!
But I'm not getting any
younger, you know.
I want to see my
grandchildren before I go.
- I understand, Sire.
- No.
No, you don't know what it
means to see your only child
grow farther, farther, and
farther away from you.
I'm...
I'm lonely in this
desolate old palace.
I... I want to hear
the pitter-patter of
little feet again.
- (SOBBING)
- Now, now, Your Majesty.
- Perhaps if we just let him alone...
- Let him alone?
(STAMMERING)
With his silly romantic ideas?
But, Sire, in matters of love...
Love. Bah!
Just a boy meeting a girl
under the right conditions.
So, we're arranging the conditions.
But, Your Majesty, if the
Prince should suspect.
Suspect!
Look, the boy's coming
home today, isn't he?
Yes, Sire.
Well, what could be more natural
than a ball to celebrate his return?
(STAMMERS) Nothing, Sire.
If all the eligible maidens
in my kingdom just
(LAUGHS) happened to be there,
why, he's bound to show interest
in one of them, isn't he?
Isn't he?
(STAMMERS) Yes, Sire.
The moment he does...
Soft lights.
Romantic music.
All the trimmings!
It can't possibly fail.
Can it?
(STAMMERS) Yes, Sire. No, Sire!
Very well, Sire.
I shall arrange the ball for...
- Tonight.
- Tonight? Tonight!
- Oh, but, Sire...
- Tonight!
And see that every
eligible maid is there.
Understand? (ECHOING)
Yes, Your Majesty.
(SINGING) The pear-shaped toad
(OUT OF TUNE)
Ooh
Sing, sweet nightingale
High
Above me
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
Sing, sweet nightingale
(CINDERELLA SINGING) High
Above
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
Sing, sweet nightingale
High
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
Sing, sweet
Nightingale
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
Sing, sweet
Sing
Oh, sing, sweet nightingale
Oh, sing, sweet
Oh
Sing
Oh! Oh, Lucifer!
You mean old thing.
I'm just going to have
to teach you a lesson.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Open in the name of the King.
An urgent message from
His Imperial Majesty.
- Thank you.
- JAQ: From the King!
What's it say, Cinderelly?
What's it say, huh?
I don't know.
He said it's urgent.
DRIZELLA: Ohhh
Maybe I should interrupt
the, uh, music lesson.
Sing, sweet nightingale
High
You clumsy! You did it on purpose.
- DRIZELLA: It's her fault.
- Girls, girls. Remember,
above all, self-control.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Yes!
Cinderella! I've warned
you never to interrupt...
- This just arrived from the palace.
- BOTH: From the palace!
- Give it here.
- Let me have it.
- (SHRIEKING)
- I'll read it.
Well, there's to be a ball.
- BOTH: A ball!
- In honour of His Highness, the Prince.
BOTH: Oh, the Prince!
And, by royal command,
every eligible maiden is to attend.
- Why, that's us!
- And I'm so eligible.
- That means I can go, too.
- DRIZELLA: Ha!
Her, dancing with the Prince.
(LAUGHS)
(MOCKING)
I'd be honoured, Your Highness.
Would you mind holding my broom?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Well, why not?
After all, I'm still a
member of the family.
And it says, "By royal command,
"every eligible
maiden is to attend."
Yes, so it does.
Well, I see no reason
why you can't go.
If you get all your work done.
Oh, I will. I promise.
And if you can find
something suitable to wear.
I'm sure I can. Oh,
thank you, Stepmother.
Mother, do you realise
what you just said?
Of course.
I said "If."
Oh. "If."
(SNICKERS)
(CHUCKLES)
Isn't it lovely?
- It was my mother's.
- It's pretty, but it looks old.
Well, maybe it is old-fashioned,
but I'll fix that.
- How do you do it?
- Wait a minute.
There ought to be some
good ideas in here.
Uh-huh. This one.
Oh, very nice. Nice.
- Like it.
- GUS: It'll be easy.
I'll have to shorten the
sleeves, I'll need a sash,
- a ruffle, something for a collar...
- DRIZELLA: Cinderella!
Oh, now what do they want?
ANASTASIA: Cinderella!
Oh, Well.
I guess my dress will
just have to wait.
DRIZELLA: Cinderella!
ANASTASIA: Cinderella!
All right, all right. I'm coming.
Poor Cinderelly.
Every time she finds a minute,
that's the time when they begin it.
Cinderelly, Cinderelly.
SISTERS: Cinderella!
(SINGING) Cinderelly, Cinderelly
Night and day it's Cinderelly
Make the fire
Fix the breakfast
Wash the dishes
Do the moppin'
And the sweepin' and the dustin'
They always keep her hoppin'
She'd go around in circles
Till she's very, very dizzy
- Still they holler
- Keep her busy, Cinderelly
Yeah. Keep her busy.
You know what?
- Cinderelly won't go to the ball.
- What?
- Not go?
- ALL: What did you say?
You'll see. They'll fix her.
Work, work, work. She'll
never get her dress done.
Poor Cinderelly.
Hey! We can do it!
We can do it
We can help our Cinderelly
We can make the dress so pretty
There's nothing to it, really
We'll tie a sash around it
Put a ribbon through it
When dancing at the ball she'll
be more beautiful than all
In the lovely dress we
make for Cinderelly
Hurry, hurry, hurry?
Gonna help our Cinderelly
Got no time to dilly-daily
We got to get it goin'
I'll cut it with the scissors.
And I can do the sewing.
Leave the sewing to the women.
You go get some trimmin'.
And we'll make a lovely
dress for Cinderelly, whoo
We'll make a lovely
dress for Cinderelly
Follow me, Gus-Gus.
I know where to go.
It's gonna be pretty, this dress.
Cinderelly will be surprised.
Surprised, surprised.
Very surprised.
DRIZELLA: And this, too,
my slippers. Don't forget...
- Take my dress.
- Here, mend the buttonholes.
- Press my skirt and mind the ruffle.
- STEPMOTHER: Cinderella?
- Yes?
- When you're through,
and before you begin
your regular chores,
I have a few little things.
Very well.
ANASTASIA: I don't see why everyone
else has nice things to wear,
and I always end up
in these old rags.
This sash! I wouldn't
be seen dead in it.
DRIZELLA:
You should talk. These beads!
I am sick of looking at them.
- Trash.
- ANASTASIA: Oh, I hate this.
(SISTERS COMPLAINING)
Come on and be careful.
Yes, yes, yes. Real careful.
We can use that, Gus-Gus.
- Pretty, pretty.
- Shh.
Look out. Lucify!
(CREAKING)
Oh! Beads!
- Very pretty beads!
- Shh!
(WHISPERING)
(HUMMING)
MICE:
A dream is a wish your heart makes
When you're fast asleep
In dreams you will
lose your heartaches
Whatever you wish for
You keep
(HUMMING)
(TWEETING)
No matter how your
heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
The dream that you
wish will come true
(MICE SINGING)
(CHIRPING)
Okay. One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
Whatever you wish for you keep
(WHISTLING)
All right.
BOTH: Heave, ho. Heave, ho.
- Heave, ho.
- (HUMMING)
The dream that you
wish will come true
Will come true
(CLOCK CHIMES)
- Yes?
- The carriage is here.
Oh.
Why, Cinderella,
- you're not ready, child.
- I'm not going.
Not going? Oh, what a shame.
But, of course, there
will be other times.
Yes. Good night.
Oh, well.
What's a royal ball?
After all, I suppose it
would be frightfully dull,
and boring, and completely...
Completely wonderful.
(CINDERELLA GASPING)
- It's my...
- MICE: Surprise!
- Surprise!
- Happy birthday!
- No, no, no, no!
Well, I never dreamed it.
It's such a surprise.
Oh, how can I ever...
Oh, thank you so much.
Remember, when you're
presented to His Highness,
- be sure...
- CINDERELLA: Wait!
Please, wait for me.
Isn't it lovely? Do you like it?
Do you think it will do?
- Cinderella!
- Mother, she can't.
- Oh, no.
- You can't!
Girls, please.
After all, we did make a bargain.
Didn't we, Cinderella?
And I never go back on my word.
How very clever.
These beads,
they give it just the right touch.
Don't you think so, Drizella?
No, I don't. I think she's...
Oh! Why, you little thief!
They're my beads. Give them here.
Oh, no.
And look, that's my sash.
She's wearing my sash.
- Mine!
- Oh, please.
Please, no.
Thief!
(SISTERS YELLING)
Girls, girls.
That's quite enough. Hurry
along now, both of you.
I won't have you
upsetting yourselves.
Good night.
(SOBBING)
You will lose your heartache
Whatever you wish for
You'll keep
Oh, no. No, it isn't true.
Have faith in your
dreams and someday
It's just no use.
Your rainbow will
come smiling through
No use at all.
No matter how your
heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
I can't believe. Not any more.
The dream that you wish
Will come true
There's nothing left to believe in.
Nothing.
Nothing, my dear? Oh, now
you don't really mean that.
- Oh, but I do.
- Nonsense, child!
If you'd lost all your
faith, I couldn't be here.
- And here I am.
- (GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, come now. Dry those tears.
You can't go to the
ball looking like that.
The ball?
- Oh, but I'm not...
- Of course, you are.
But we have to hurry,
because even miracles
take a little time.
- Miracles?
- Mmm-hmm. Watch.
What in the world did I do with
that magic wand? I was sure...
Magic wand?
That's strange.
- I always...
- Then you must be...
Your fairy godmother? Of course.
Where is that wand? I...
Oh! I forgot.
I put it away.
Look at what she did.
How'd she do it?
Now, let's see. Hmm.
I'd say the first thing
you need is, um,
- a Pumpkin.
- A Pumpkin?
Mmm-hmm. Now, uh, the magic words.
Uh... Oh! (CLEARS THROAT)
Sala-gadoola-menchika-boo-la
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Put 'em together and
what have you got?
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Sala-gadoola-menchika-boo-la
It'll do magic
Believe it or not
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Now sala-gadoola means
Menchika-boolaroo
But the thing-a-ma-bob
that does the job
Is bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Sala-gadoola-menchika-boo-la
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
Put 'em together and
what have you got?
Bibbidi-bobbidi
Bibbidi-bobbidi Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
MOUSE: Oh, looky.
JAQ: Isn't it wonderful?
Oh, it's beautiful.
Yes, isn't it?
With an elegant coach
like that, of course,
- we'll simply have to have
- (COUGHS)
- mice!
- Mice?
FAIRY GODMOTHER:
Oh, this really is nice.
Why, we'll have a coach and
four when we're through.
Just a wave of my stick
and to finish the trick,
bibbidi, bobbidi, boo.
Gracious, what did I do?
I was sure there were four.
There should be one more.
(CHUCKLES) There you are.
Bibbidi, bobbidi, boo.
(WHINNIES)
CINDERELLA: Oh, poor Lucifer.
Serves him right,
I'd say. Now, um...
Where were we? Oh, goodness, yes.
You can't go to the
ball without, um...
a horse.
Another one?
FAIRY GODMOTHER:
But tonight, for a change,
you will handle the reins,
and sit in the driver's seat, too.
For instead of a horse, you're
the coachman, of course.
Bibbidi, bobbidi, boo.
That does it, I guess,
except for... Oh, yes!
The finishing touch.
And, that's you.
Yes, Bruno, that's right,
you'll be footman tonight.
Bibbidi, bobbidi, boo.
Well, well, hop in, my dear.
We can't waste time.
- But, uh...
- No, don't try to thank me.
Oh, I wasn't...
I mean, I do, but...
- But, don't you think my dress...
- Yes, it's lovely, dear, Love...
Good heavens, child.
You can't go in that!
Now, let's see, dear.
Your size and the shade
of your eyes. Mmm-hmm.
Something simple, but daring, too.
Oh, just leave it to me.
What a gown this will be.
Bibbidi-bobbidi. Bibbidi-bobbidi.
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo.
Oh, it's a beautiful dress.
Did you ever see such
a beautiful dress?
And, look, glass slippers.
Why, it's like a dream.
A wonderful dream come true.
Yes, my child. But,
like all dreams,
well, I'm afraid this
can't last forever.
You'll have only till
midnight, and then...
Midnight? Thank you.
Now, now, now, just a minute.
You must understand, my dear,
on the stroke of 12:00
the spell will be broken,
and everything will
be as it was before.
Oh, I understand, but
it's more than I ever hoped for.
Bless you, my child.
I... Goodness me!
It's getting late. Hurry up,
dear. The ball can't wait.
Have a good time. Dance, be gay.
Now, off you go.
You're on your way.
With a bibbidi-bobbidi
Bibbidi-bobbidi
Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo
PAGE: Princess Frederica
Eugenie de la Fontain.
Mademoiselle Augustina DuBois.
Daughter of General Pierre DuBois.
(SIGHS) The boy isn't cooperating.
PAGE: Mademoiselle Leonora
Mercedes de la Tour.
Daughter of Colonel and
Madame de la Tour.
I can't understand it.
There must be at least one
who'd make a suitable mother.
Shh. Sire.
(CLEARS THROAT) A suitable wife.
PAGE: Mademoiselles Drizella
and Anastasia Tremaine.
Daughters of Lady Tremaine.
I give up. Even I couldn't
expect the boy to...
Well, if I may say so, Your
Majesty, I did try to warn you,
but you, Sire, are
incurably romantic.
(LAUGHING) No doubt you saw the
whole pretty picture in detail.
The young Prince bowing
to the assembly.
Suddenly he stops. He looks up.
For, lo, there she stands.
The girl of his dreams.
Who she is or whence she came,
he knows not, nor does he care,
for his heart tells him that here,
here is the maid predestined
to be his bride.
(CHUCKLING) A pretty plot
for fairy tales, Sire.
But in real life, oh, no.
No! It was foredoomed to failure.
Failure, eh?
Take a look at that,
you pompous windbag.
(CHUCKLING) Who is she?
- You know her?
- No, Sire.
I've never seen her before.
KING: (CHUCKLES)
That's one thing in her favour.
The waltz. Quick, the waltz!
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Lights. (WHISTLES) The lights.
(WALTZ PLAYS)
Failure, eh?
- (CHUCKLING)
- (SARCASTIC CHUCKLING)
Well... (YAWNING) Now
for a good night's sleep.
Oh, quite so, Sire.
I believe I, too...
You will stay right here.
See they're not disturbed,
and when the boy proposes,
notify me immediately.
Notify me immediately.
KING: And remember,
if anything goes wrong...
La di da di la di da di
La di da di
La di um um um
Ba dum ba do
Ya dum ba dum dum dum dum
- Who is she, Mother?
- Do we know her?
Well, the Prince
certainly seems to.
I know I've never seen her.
STEPMOTHER: Nor I.
But she certainly is... Wait.
There is something
familiar about her.
Oh.
Ahem.
(CINDERELLA HUMMING)
So this is love
(HUMMING)
So this is what makes life
Divine
I'm all aglow
(HUMMING)
- And now I know
BOTH: The key to all Heaven
Is mine
My heart has wings
(HUMMING)
And I can fly
BOTH: I'll touch every star
In the sky
So this is the miracle
That I've been dreaming of
(CINDERELLA HUMMING)
(PRINCE HUMMING)
BOTH: So this
Is
Love
- (CLOCK CHIMING)
- Oh. Oh, my goodness.
What's the matter?
It's midnight.
Yes, so it is. But why...
- Goodbye.
- No, no, wait.
- You can't go now. It's only...
- Oh, I must. Please.
- Please, I must.
- But why?
Well, I... Oh, the Prince,
I haven't met the Prince.
The Prince?
- But didn't you know...
- (CLOCK CHIMING)
- Goodbye.
- No, wait.
Come back. Please come back.
I don't even know your
name. How will I find you?
Wait! Please wait.
Good bye.
Oh, I say. Young lady.
- Wait!
- GIRLS: The Prince!
(CLOCK CHIMES)
Just a moment.
DUKE: Guard! Guard!
Stop that coach! Close those gates!
Follow that coach!
Open those gates!
(CLOCK CHIMES)
CINDERELLA: I'm sorry.
I guess I forgot about everything.
Even the time, but...
But it was so wonderful.
And he was so handsome,
and when we danced...
Oh, I'm sure even the Prince himself
couldn't have been more... More...
- Oh, well, it's over and...
- JAQ: Cinderelly.
- Look, look! The slippers!
- Yeah, your slipper.
Your slipper, Cinderelly.
Oh.
Thank you.
Thank you so much, for everything.
(CLOCK CHIMING)
Your Majesty, I see no point
in beating about the bush.
I regret to inform you, Sire,
that the young lady
has disappeared,
leaving behind only
this glass slipper.
Yes. I'll do it.
No. I just can't.
(KING CHUCKLING)
(SNORING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
KING: Well, come in.
(SHOUTING) Come in!
- Your Majesty...
- So, he's proposed already?
- Tell me about it.
- Well...
- Who is she?
- I didn't get a chance...
No matter. We've more
important things to discuss.
Arrangements for the wedding,
invitations, a national holiday.
- All that sort of thing.
- But, Sire...
Here. Have a cigar.
Take a few more.
- (CHUCKLING)
- But...
Better practise passing
these out, eh?
(STAMMERS)
But, if you'd only listen.
And for you, my friend.
- Your Majesty, please...
- A knighthood.
I hereby dub you Sir... Um, uh...
By the way, what title
would you like?
- Sire? She got away.
- Sir "She Got Away"?
A peculiar title, but
if that's what you...
She what? Why, you...
You... You traitor!
Now, Sire. Remember,
your blood pressure.
Treason!
No, Sire. No!
Sabotage!
You were in league with the Prince.
I tried to stop her,
but she vanished into thin air.
A likely story.
But it's true, Sire. All we could
find was this glass slipper.
The whole thing was a plot!
But, Sire, he loves her.
He won't rest till he finds her.
He's determined to marry her.
What? What did you say?
The Prince, Sire,
swears he'll marry none
but the girl who fits this slipper.
He said that, did he?
We've got him!
- (WHOOPING)
- (CRASHING)
But, Sire, this slipper may fit
one of any number of girls.
That's his problem.
He's given his word.
- We'll hold him to it.
- No, Your Highness.
I'll have nothing to do with it.
You'll try this on every
maid in my kingdom.
- And if the shoe fits,
- (GULPING)
bring her in.
(STAMMERING) Yes, Your Majesty.
(TRUMPETS BLARING)
Cinderella? Cinderella?
- Cinderella! Where is that...
- Yes?
Here I am.
My daughters, where are they?
- I think they're still in bed.
- (GROANS)
Don't just stand there! Bring
up the breakfast trays at once.
And hurry!
Wow. I wonder what's the matter.
What's the matter with her?
I don't know. Let's
find out. Come on.
(GRUNTING)
Drizella. Drizella!
(YAWNING) What?
Get up. Quick. This instant.
We haven't a moment to lose.
Anastasia.
- Get up, Anastasia.
- (YAWNING)
What for? Why?
Everyone's talking about
it, the whole kingdom.
- Hurry now. He'll be here any minute.
- Who will?
The Grand Duke. He's
been hunting all night.
- Hunting?
- For that girl.
The one who lost her slipper
at the ball last night.
They say he's madly
in love with her.
- The Duke is?
- No, no, no. The Prince!
- (GASPING) The Prince!
- (CRASHING)
STEPMOTHER: You clumsy little fool.
Clean that up, then help
my daughters dress.
What for?
If he's in love with that girl,
why should we even bother?
Now, you two, listen to me. There is still
a chance that one of you can get it.
BOTH: Huh? One of us?
- Why, Mother, what do you mean?
- Just this:
No one, not even the Prince,
knows who that girl is.
We know! We know!
Cinderelly! Cindere...
The glass slipper
is their only clue.
The Duke has been ordered to try
it on every girl in the kingdom.
And if one can be found
whom the slipper fits,
then, by the King's command,
that girl shall be
the Prince's bride.
- His bride.
- His bride!
Cinderella, get my things together.
Never mind her. Get
mine right away.
(SISTERS SHOUTING ORDERS)
(STAMMERS)
What's the matter with her?
- Wake up, stupid.
- We've gotta get dressed.
Dressed. Oh, yes.
Oh, we must get dressed.
It wouldn't do for the
Duke to see me...
Mother, did you see what she did?
- Are you just going to let her...
- Quiet!
(CINDERELLA HUMMING)
So this is love
(HUMMING)
What's she gonna do?
Shh. I don't know.
Gotta watch. Come on.
(CINDERELLA HUMMING)
- Cinderelly!
So this is the miracle
That I've been dreaming of
(EXCITED CHATTERING)
What? (GASPS)
Oh! Oh, no!
No, please!
Oh, you can't, you just can't.
Let me out! You must let me out!
You can't keep me in here!
(SOBBING) Oh, please.
No, no. She can't do it. She
can't lock up Cinderelly.
- I'm gonna...
- Shh.
CINDERELLA: (SOBBING)
Please. Please.
We gotta get that key, Gus-Gus.
We just gotta get that key.
(HORSE TROTTING)
- DRIVER: Whoa.
- (BUGLE SOUNDS)
He's over here, the Duke-Duke.
- Yeah, yeah. Who?
- The Grand Duke, with the slipper.
We gotta get that key quick.
Yup, yup. Key, key. Quick.
Oh, Mother, Mother,
he's here, he's here.
The Grand Duke.
Do I look all right?
I'm so excited,
- I just don't know what I'll do.
- STEPMOTHER: Girls.
Now, remember, this is your
last chance. Don't fail me.
(SOUNDING)
Announcing His Imperial
Grace, the Grand Duke.
You honour our humble home.
Quite so.
May I present my daughters,
Drizella, Anastasia.
Your Grace.
Yes. Charmed, I'm sure.
His Grace will read the
royal proclamation.
(CLEARS THROAT)
"All loyal subjects of
His Imperial Majesty
"are hereby notified by royal
proclamation in regard to a certain
"glass (YAWNING) slipper.
"It is decreed..."
Why, that's my slipper!
(GASPING)
Well, I like that. It's my slipper!
No, no, no! It's
Cinderelly's slipper!
- How can she stand there...
- STEPMOTHER: Girls.
Your manners.
A thousand pardons, Your Grace.
Please continue.
Yes, quite so.
Eh, um... Oh, yes. "It
is upon this day decreed
"that a quest be instituted
throughout... (YAWNING)
"The sole and express purpose
of such quest to be as follows:
"That every maid throughout the
kingdom without exception,
"shall try on her foot
this slipper of glass,
"and should one be found upon whose
foot this slipper shall properly fit,
(DUKE YAWNING)
"such maiden shall be acclaimed
the object of this search
"and shall be looked upon as the
true love of His Royal Highness,
"our beloved son and heir,
(YAWNING) the noble Prince.
(CLEARING THROAT)
"Said Prince will, upon bended knee
"beg, request, or
if need be, implore
"said maiden that he be granted
her hand in marriage. (YAWNS)
"Whereupon, should the
aforementioned maiden
"look with favour, shall the
couple pledge their troth...
(YAWNING)
"And in due course, upon the inevitable
demise of His Majesty the King,
"succeed to the throne
to rule over the land
"as King and Queen of our kingdom.
- (BANGING)
- (SIGHING) "So be it."
You must be quite
fatigued, Your Grace.
May we offer you some tea?
DUKE: What? Tea? (YAWNING)
Thank you, madam, no.
We must proceed with the fitting.
Of course. Anastasia, dear.
There. I knew it was my slipper.
Exactly my size.
I always wear the same size.
As soon as I saw it, I said...
Oh, well...
It may be a trifle snug today.
You know how it is,
dancing all night.
I can't understand why.
It's always fit perfectly before.
I don't think you're half trying.
- Mother, can you...
- Shh.
Quiet, my dear. We mustn't
disturb His Grace.
Young man, are you sure you're
trying it on the right foot?
(SQUEALING)
ANASTASIA:
Oh, it's the right foot, but...
These glass shoes
aren't always reliable.
Come on, hurry.
Up the stairs, up the stairs!
Lucify, Lucify.
(STRAINING)
Up, up, up with it.
Oh!
(PANTING)
Here.
(STRAINING)
(PANTING)
Shh.
Why can't you hold still a minute?
Oh! My word. Enough of this!
The next young lady, please.
Did you hear that, Gus?
- Yup.
- Gotta hurry.
Shh. Come on, come on, hurry.
(STAMMERING)
Gus-Gus, Gus-Gus, come on.
Look, look. Just up there. Come on.
(SOBBING)
(MICE STRAINING)
Us is coming, Cinderelly.
Us is coming.
- I can get you out.
- CINDERELLA: You've got the key!
How did you ever manage to...
(GASPS)
Lucifer!
Let him go, Lucifer.
Please, let him go.
- Let him go.
- Let him go!
Let him go. Let him out, you hear?
Lucify, you...
(YOWLING)
Bruno. Yes, Bruno!
Quick, get Bruno. Get Bruno!
(TWEETING)
(WHINNYING)
Oh! Of all the stupid
little idiots.
I'll do it myself.
Get away from me.
I'll make it fit. (STRAINING)
- There.
- It fits.
It fits?
(GASPING) No!
- (SIGHING)
- Oh, Your Grace, I'm dreadfully sorry.
It shan't happen again.
Precisely, madam.
(PANTING)
(GROWLING)
(MEOWING)
Come on, come on.
Get up, Gus-Gus, get up.
Don't, don't, don't, don't.
Let go, let go.
You are the only ladies in the
household I hope... I presume.
- There's no one else, Your Grace.
- Quite so.
- Good day. Good day.
- CINDERELLA: Your Grace?
Your Grace, please, wait.
May I try it on?
- STEPMOTHER: Pay no attention.
- DRIZELLA: It's Cinderella.
- From the kitchen.
- Ridiculous.
She's out of her mind.
Just an imaginative child.
Madam, my orders
were "every maiden."
Come, my child.
Oh, no.
No, no, no. Oh, no!
Oh, this is terrible.
The King, what will he say?
What will he do?
Perhaps, if it would help...
No, no. Nothing can
help now. Nothing.
But, you see, I have
the other slipper.
(ALL CHEERING)
(RINGING)
Have faith in dreams
And someday
Your rainbow will
come smiling through
No matter how your
heart is grieving
If you keep on believing
The dream that you wish
Will come true