London. The greatest
city in the world.
For 22 years, l've lived here
Every morning l take a
walk down this street
Every morning, the
street asks me my name..
Chaudhary Baldev Singh? Who are you?
Where are you from? Why are you here?
Do l have a reply? After
half a lifetime spent here..
this land still remains
alien to me; and l to it
No one here knows me. None except
these doves. Because they're like me
Neither do they belong to a country.
Just drop down where you find food
Have your fill, then fly on
When shall l fly? l don't know.
Of necessity, my wings are clipped
l'm shackled to my bread.
But someday l'll surely go..
to my land. To my Punjab
"When the koels sing in spring,
it's time again for memories"
"lt's time again for
swinging under the boughs"
"Come home o'wanderer,
your heart beCkons"
"lt's time again for
swinging under the boughs"
"Come home o'wanderer,
your heart beCkons"
Glory to The Goddess
Yes Lajjo, l'm here safe and sound.
- Good
Why is my little one giggling away?
- Mom! Eνery day for 20 years..
Dad has been walking
down the very same street..
to his very same destination.
Yet every day, you call him up..
just to ask him, "Have you reaChed?"
- You won't understand
Just assume it's a habit.
- Habit left unchanged..
tends to become neCessity-like.
- Philosophy, again? You're twelve
Talk like a 1 2-year old!
Why all this big talk?
There's no childhood, no adulthood.
One is as grown-up as one feels
All right! l lose! Now go to school,
chew your teacher's brains, okay?
Why d'you forget the
almonds everyday?
What to do? Just assume it's habit
Will you get out?
"This is the first time
it's happening in 1 8 years"
"Some stranger l haνe never seen,
comes to my mind"
That's my diary!
- So what..?
Only l can read it.
- That was so funny
Let me read some more.
- No way! This is a private diary.
Why hide anything from me?
When a girl is grown up..
her mother becomes her friend.
Show that to me
You won't tell anyone, will you?
- Never
All right. l'll read. You listen.
- Very well
"This is the first time
it's happening in 1 8 years"
"Some stranger l haνe
neνer seen, Comes to my mind.."
"shadow-like before my eyes"
"Someone raps on my heart"
"Deep eyes want me
to give myself up"
"When l look at my hands,
there l see a face etched"
"A silken breath brushes my cheeks"
"My hair still smells of
the odour on his hands"
"Yes, it's happening for
the first time in 1 8 years"
"l've never seen this
stranger who comes to my mind"
Simi, you've begun
writing quite well..
..and the boy seems lively.
Who's he?
Ma, l've yet to set my eyes on him
So there's no one? l was wondering.
One doesn't find such boys nowadays
And you dream of someone you
haνen't even seen! Quite mad
No Ma. This is no dream
l may not have met him, seen him
But he's there. Out there, somewhere
"The one who comes in my dreams.."
"the one who teases me.."
"just ask him to face me, onCe"
"What's he like? Who is he?
Who knows where is the one.."
"my lips will say yes to?"
"ls he someone l know?
ls he a stranger?"
"ls he for real, or just a legend?"
"He stares at me, from far, far away"
"Tell him not to rob me of my sleep"
"The one who comes in my dreams.."
"the one who teases me.."
"just ask him to face me, onCe"
"Some kind of spell is overcoming me"
"Oh what do l do? My heart yearns so"
"My heart tells me it's mad for you.
Then why do you keep hiding from me?"
"He makes me blossom,
it's all his fault"
"Tell me, l'm asking for the Moon"
"The one who comes in my dreams.."
"the one who teases me.."
"just ask him to face me, onCe"
Raj! This partying all night!
Party all night and you don't sleep
And how do you get up in the morning?
Late for graduation! Hurry!
ls it a holiday?
What Raj? Late for your graduation?
What to do? Last night..
What's wrong with him?
Has he had one too many beers?
l hear someone has failed.
The Dean has decided..
..to announCe his name in public
You've made Dharam Veer Malhotra stand
an inch and a half taller in his shoes!
l don't think you heard it right.
- l knew, someday you'd make me proud!
And not only me, the whole dynasty is
proud of you! Look, they smile at you
My great grandfather Diwan
Brijnath never went to school
His son, my grandfather
Diwan Dwarkanath failed..
his fourth standard examinations.
My father, your grandfather..
Diwan Pushkarnath, failed his
eighth standard examinations
And l, your father,
failed to matriculate
Not having an education, failing,
are family traditions. l'm happy that..
you have kept tradition alive,
and indeed you're two steps ahead
We failed back home in lndia.
You came to London and failed!
Are you really happy?
- Glad
Education is all useless.
Filling your head with books..
..won't fill your pockets
Look at me. Runaway peasant-boy from
Bhatinda-turned millionaire in London
So, whatever happens is for the good.
Join my offices from tomorrow
Offices? From tomorrow?
- Today, if you wish
l can't attend office now.
- Why not?
Pops, you're a man of experience
You know what amount of hard work it
takes to fail. And l'm tired, Pops
l want a little rest, you know,
like a long European holiday
Long European holiday? How long?
- Month or month and a half
Will you hold this
for me? And turn around
Moron! Did l bring
you up to see this day?
No, don't drop that
Are you all right, Pops?
Pops, you're right.
l ought to take care of your business
You've become so old.
- You tell your father that?
Pops, l've decided against Europe.
l'm joining the offices from tomorrow
ln this house, only your father
deCides. You're going to Europe
No. l've had enough of a good time.
My years of youth are over for me
Never say your youth is over.
All my life l've slogged to
give you whatever l Couldn't do.
When youth came and went,
l never got to know
But l wasn't sad, because l knew
that my son will have my years
lf you think you'νe had
enough of a good time..
if you think the years of youth
are over for you, well no problem
Just go and live my years for me
Ajit's letter?
Lajjo! Look, what's here.
Letter! From my friend
From Ajit
Just smell it, lady!
The fragranCe of Punjab!
The flavour of mustard
curry on leavened maize bread
Those long tailed shirts,
the short knickers
"My dear friend Baldev,
We're fine here"
"We hope to God that you, your
wife and the children are well too"
"You will be pleased to hear
that my son has graduated in arts"
"He has joined my business.
By God's grace, it's time now..
for us to let our childhood
friendship mature into a relationship
Let's make good the promise we made
to each other 20 years ago. l hope..
you will come here at the
soonest for Simran's wedding to Kuljit
Read on
She's shy! See Lajjo?
That's our etiquette, our culture
My daughter is still so shamefaced.
l'm not a failure
ln the heart of London,
l've kept lndia alive!
Still staring? Lajjo, your daughter's
wedding! Celebrate it with sweets
Chutki! l'm so happy today
Can l say one thing?
- Say four things
lt'd be better to ask Simran once.
- What are you saying?
Ever since she was a baby, she has
known that she is engaged to Kuljit
That she knows. But 20 years..
- Don't you worry!
Simran is going to be so happy..
..you'll pray that she
neνer gets the evil eye!
l'll write to Ajit right away.
God! At last, comes the day
Simran, what are you doing?
l had forgotten, Ma. l haven't
even the right to dream
No my Child, of course you may dream
But don't expect them to come true
And who know, Kuljit might
be the man of your dreams
l don't care. l've
bought your tickets.
You're Coming to Europe with me.
- l can't
Babuji won't let me go to
college alone. Will he let me go away..
touring Europe for a month.
l have lots of work here.
- You've known me for years.
Can't you make up an excuse?
An excuse, l Can find.
But l don't feel like lying to Babuji
You must come. Dolly
and Payal are coming too
Let me talk to Ma tonight
Europe?
- Yes
With friends?
For a month?
- Yes
Chutki, Call the doctor. Tell him
that our Simran has gone stark mad
Will you at least take a look?
- Check out your brains first
You talk of travelling by Eurail?
lf he hears, he'll bring the roof down
A lone girl mustn't travel like this.
- Mom, l'm not going to be alone
My friends are going to be with me.
- No good arguing with me
l'm not going to object.
But you will need his permission
Ask him when he's home
God, please keep Babuji in a nice mood
lt's just beer. lt's over there.
- l told you. The store is shut
Get out
Got the beer?
- Didn't find any
ldiot! Can't even do suCh a simple job?
- That was an angry man
l'll get it.
- You won't
Can l have an Aspirin?
- The store is shut
My head is about to
crack up! lt's sinusitis
lf l Can't find an Aspirin,
l'll faint.
All the other stores are shut
Please let me have one Aspirin.
One Hindustani ought to help another
Glory to The Goddess.
- Here you are
l'm feeling bad about forcing you to
open your store for a small medicine
l'd like to buy some
other things from you
l'll pick up some beer.
Not for myself.
My friends out there, they drink.
Put it down.
- Why sir?
Are you trying to Con me? You aren't
getting anything. Put it down
You're getting worked up over
nothing. This is for your profit
Will you put it down?
- Not that umbrella
Here you are. A pound extra?
No two. Keep it, okay?
Shameless!
You call yourself a Hindustani?
You give lndia a bad name
You're a liar and insolent!
Get out of here
l'm off. l'll keep this
Rev up!
Babuji
What is the matter? You're late.
- Bloody shameless scoundrel
They call themselves Hindustani!
Blot on lndia! Ought to drown
themselves Rascals!
No shame, no decency.
How to respeCt their elders..
they don't even know.
- Have you had a fight?
Scum! He came for beer.
l told him the store is shut.
He took it perforce
He even broke the statue of
The Goddess! Bloody half-caste!
l say Lajjo, thank God
that you and your daughters..
haven't been marred
by this Britishness!
Else, you would've been nowhere!
Damn these sCoundrels!
Set sail in stormy waters,
and you're in danger of sinking
You were so little when we
brought you here. And now..
They said that a grown-up
daughter is a burden on a man
But a daughter like you, makes a
father's chest swell with pride!
You're my good girl
Will you giνe something if l ask you?
- Whatever you wish
l want to take a look at Europe
Eurail is offering a month's tour.
All my friends are going
Please don't be Cross.
l have never disobeyed you, Babuji
l'll be going away to a
land l have never seen
The man l'm going to marry
is a complete stranger. But..
l have no Complaints. You must've
considered it in my best interests
But l won't get a
chance like this ever again.
l don't eνen know
whether l'll ever come back..
..whether l will have
these friends later on
Besides, it's only for a month.
ln a month, l will have
lived a lifetime
For the sake of my happiness, won't
you let me have a month of my life?
Please Babuji, give me one month
Go. Live it up
My baby
Where's Simran?
Where might she be?
- Has she slipped in the loo?
l told you to wake up Raj.
Did you?
- No
Open sesame
Do you have the keys to this?
Anybody home?
No one at home.
Haven't l seen you somewhere?
At Robbie's party, no?
l don't go to parties.
- Great! Nor do l, ever
Your eyes..
What's wrong with my eyes?
Reminds me of someone.
- Of whom?
My grandmother. Like you, her eyes
too had hues of yellows and blues
Keep reading. l only wanted to
find out how you read upside-down
This is the limit!
Simran, you're here?
l heard you've missed the train.
- No, l took it
l was afraid..
- By the way, what's your name?
Sheena
Here l am. Shall we?
- Take it easy
Pump it up
- lt's pumped. Look
lt's nothing.
- Raj, where have you been?
As usual. Caught up with a girl
Girl?
- l help her onto the train
And she falls for me.
- What?
He bored me. He had me all alone,
and he began flirting
Same old hat..
haνen't l seen you before?
She sidled up to me.
- What?
l was scared! Only so much space,
and there she was with me
Then?
- Then what? She was lost in my eyes
He was after my eyes.
Wouldn't shut up. Boys these days..
These girls! l just managed
to Come out unscathed
What's that?
- lnvitation to a party
l told you. lt'll be a bore.
- You prophesied a train crash
And then we'd all be charred alive
after supper in a dinner-hall fire
Look, boys.
- Where?
He's the one
Where have we landed?
Was this your idea?
Us? Or the waiters?
For me. Rocky shut your trap
Why did you have to call him?
You know Sheena,
haνen't l seen you before?
Me? Really? Where?
- At Robbie's party?
You might've. l go to so many parties
You know Sheena..
- What?
Your eyes remind me of someone.
- My eyes? Really? Whom?
My grandmother
ls she singing or crying?
And l can play better piano
You know how to play the piano?
l was born on a piano. Been playing
the piano ever since l was a baby
You know, l have magic in my fingers.
No sooner than l touch the piano..
it starts playing
lsn't that voice familiar?
Was this necessary?
Doesn't the magic in your fingers
make pianos start playing?
"Stop, my wild lover"
"l've got to ask you something"
"What are you, girl or magic?"
"What are you, fragrance or poison?"
"Come, let me touch you"
"Wait, my wild love"
"l've got to ask you something"
"Look at me, smiling, unknowing"
"l'm waiting for you,
holding my heart"
"She looks subdued"
"But she has lots to say"
"lf you say yes,
l have something to say"
"Wait, my wild love"
"l've got to ask you something"
"What are you, girl or magic?"
"What are you, fragrance or poison?"
"You aren't the only
pretty woman around"
"Why are you the
only one who's Cross?"
"The one l've fallen for,
is someone else"
"lf she says yes,
l'll take her in my arms"
"Wait, my wild love"
"l've got to ask you something"
"What are you, girl or magic?"
"What are you, fragrance or poison?"
"Come, let me touch you"
About last night, l'm ashamed
l misbehaved with you
l wanted to tell you something else
What?
- This
Run
First come, first served
Hurry! The train is about to leave.
- Where did l keep my money?
One minute, l don't know how to count
this currency.. lots of small change
Can you tell me one, two's, eighths?
Stop
Train's gone?
The train is gone!
Don't cry, Senorita
But you just stopped crying
lt's raining! Don't Cry,
please! l'm with you, l'm here! Look
Okay, l'm gone..
gone! Here's your bell
The next train is very late.
To catch up with the train..
at Zurich tomorrow morning,
we can either take a bus or hire a Car
What would be your pleasure?
Bus or car? Where's she?
Ever since you met me,
you've been harassing me
What are you saying?
- All along the trip..
you've been chewing my brains.
- l?
Something's always the problem with
you. Today, l've missed the train..
thanks to you.
- To me?
l wish to make it to Zurich on time.
So you go your way, l'll go mine
Strange! We're fellow-travellers,
on the same destination, same train
Why split up? Besides, a man like me
ought to stay with a girl like you
Wrong! A girl like me doesn't need
a guy like you. Stop pursuing me
l'll sew it up. l have a thread
and needle. l'll buy you a new dress
What have you got yourself into?
l told you not to pursue me!
Who do you think you are?
What do you think of yourself?
l wasn't pursuing you
And l don't fancy touching you.
Thank your stars l came
in the nick of time
Else, you would've been in jail.
l help her, and she says this
Hey, take her away
What did you say?
l got carried away
Never mind Senorita, never mind.
ln big places,
such small things happen
What's about this Senorita?
- My first girl friend was from Spain
Why did you dump her?
- She hated lndians
You like lndians, don't you?
- When do we reach Zurich?
What's in Zurich?
This is the real Europe
So beautiful, so pretty. Sometimes,
l fear, it might become dirty
Here for the first time?
- Yes
Will you drive faster?
- What's the hurry Senorita?
Train leaves Zurich at 1 1 :30 tomorrow.
We haνe a whole night and half a day
We'll be there on time.
- Still, if we could..
What had to happen, has happened.
Now you're with me
Nothing can go wrong
Europe is best done on foot
Just the four of us.
Chutki is way ahead of her years
And Ma's more a friend than a mother.
So l never felt the need for a friend
You can't live the rest of your life
with friends. Sometime or the other..
you will need someone who
will walk by you all your life
Can't walk anymore. l'm tired.
- Do l pick you up in my arms?
l can't afford a hotel. Let's try
that house. We might find lodgings
Come. Arrangements
for the night is done
Which is your room?
Situation is somewhat like this.
There's only one room
And we spend the night in the same
room? You presume somewhat like that?
How compelling!
- Not quite so compelling
l'm not staying here one minute.
- You take the bed. l'll take the sofa
No problems.
- No way. l'm leaving
l'm not joking. l'm going away.
- And l'll have the bed all to myself?
So nice.. so romantic!
And these curtains.. so nice!
And the view!
No horses?
lt's so warm in here
You have a fire going
Granted. You have a
great sense of choice
You couldn't find a better
place to spend the night, right?
We were getting a nice room
But you'd rather spend the night with
me in the stables. Not in the room
Eat
- l'm not hungry
All right. Don't eat.
How am l bothered?
Eat it
l told you. l'm not hungry.
Come on now. Eat
What did you say?
l got carried away
Never mind. ln big places,
such small things happen
You were right, Senorita.
The spirit of adventure in this barn..
you could never enjoy in that room.
- But how do we get to Zurich?
No, not Zurich. Tomorrow evening,
we entrain at Berne. Tomorrow morning..
we take the first bus at eight.
l've found out everything
Now, nothing can go wrong
What's that?
- Life
Aren't you ashamed to drink
in the presence of a lady?
Better than dying before the lady!
lf you wish to live on..
you too should have a bit, Senorita.
- Don't you dare come near me
All right, don't
l'll see you tomorrow
morning if you're still alive.
Until then, goodnight
"May l have a jig?
- Oh no!"
"May l try a pirouette?
"How about a kiss?
- Goodness! No!"
"Let me fly with the wind"
"God! Help me"
"The chill in the
breeze sets my body afire"
"l feel like.."
"making love to you"
"This never happened before"
"l've taken my first step"
"Let me fly with the wind"
"God! Help me"
"May l have a jig?
- Oh no!"
"May l try a pirouette?"
"Give me a kiss?
- Goodness! No!"
"Where do you think you're going,
my darling, my love?"
"You're a pretty girl.
l'm a handsome young man"
"Come into my embraCe"
"Let me hold you in my eyes"
"Oh, l'm drunk"
"God! Help me"
"May l have a jig?
- Oh no!"
"May l try a pirouette?"
"Give me a kiss?
- Goodness! No!"
"Oh, l'm ecstatic"
"God! Help me"
Up in the mornings,
you look even prettier
How did l get here?
With me. Last night
l don't think you've
ever had a drink before
And you had one too many
Have this
What happened last night?
What happened last night,
was bound to happen
But l didn't imagine
it'd happen this way
Tell me the truth, Raj!
What happened last night?
How do l answer this question, Simran?
Look, look into my eyes.
Aren't my eyes telling the truth?
No! This could never have happened
This could never have happened.
- That's exactly what happened, Simran
Who can stop what is to happen?
You're lying! You're lying,
aren't you?
No Simran.
- Please tell me you're lying
Please! - Granted! l'm lying,
my eyes are lying
But are these love-bites lying?
Speak
Tell me Simran! Are these yours?
Or someone else's?
Don't cry! l was just joking
Those aren't real!
Look! l used your lipstick
You only had one too many,
and you were dripping wet
l had no options. l had to bring
you here. l swear, l'm just joking
You were all alone on the bed.
l slept out there.
l'm just joking! l swear
Don't cry, don't.
l know what you think of me.
You think l'm a wastrel
l'm not scum, Simran.
l'm Hindustani
And l know what honour
means for the Hindustani woman
Not even in my dreams can l imagine
doing that to you. Trust me, Simran
l'm saying the truth. Last night,
nothing happened. Just a joke
Please, never joke about that.
You don't know what l would've done
Please, no jokes like that
l promise never to
crack a joke like that
Get changed. Fast.
We got to catCh the bus
May l have my shirt back?
Fifteen minutes before the bus
leaves. You want to eat something?
No, l'm not hungry.
Come on, let's take a look inside.
- Churches aren't worth a look
l'm not going.
Go on. Take a look
What?
- Hurry up. We'll miss the bus
Shall we?
- Why not leave after tea?
What did you ask for?
- You aren't supposed to speak of it
Then you must be sure about
being given what you've asked for
Whatever one seeks with a
pure heart, one is surely given
Go on. l'll be back in a minute.
- What happened?
Go on. l'll join you
l'm Raj
l'm sorry, l don't know how to pray.
But l want nothing for myself
But that girl Simran,
she's nice. Very good at heart
Give her whatever she asked for
Where have you been?
ln the church?
Half a teaspoon of sugar, one spoon
of milk, bit of Cream. Your coffee
You want a postcard to send home?
- Postcard? For home?
lf that postcard reaches home,
my Pop will give me up for dead
When were you last serious?
- Till now, neνer
lf ever, it'll happen only once.
- When?
When l'm in loνe
A boy like you was never in love?
- l've had many affairs
But l was never in love, Senorita.
Never found one
What kind of girl
are you looking for?
Want me to tell you?
The moment l look at her..
all my heart's desires,
all my dreams will come alive
Has never happened. But now l hear
a voiCe, behind the clouds, calling
She's a stranger, a face l've never
seen before. When will the clouds part?
Has it never happened with you?
- No
No stranger ever invaded your dreams?
No place for strangers in my dreams
l am engaged to marry
Engaged to marry?
- Yes
Where's the fiance? ln London?
- No, in lndia
Looks?
Don't know. Never seen him
You've never seen the
man you're going to marry?
Not necessary. My father has
seen him. His friend's son
You'll spend your life
with someone you've never met?
A complete stranger?
That's how it happens with us.
- And you're happy with this decision?
The train is here
Lovely photographs. Send me a set of
copies. And your wedding photos too
Won't you be there at my wedding?
- Who's going to travel so far?
Sheena, you must!
- Just joking. Of course, l'll come
l got to take a look at your groom.
Who knows what idiot she's marrying?
You dropped this
What happened? Why are
you staring like that?
l have something to tell you Simran
Go on
l'm in love with you
Just look at your face
You thought l was saying the truth?
Strange Simran! You've
known me for so long..
and you still can't make me out?
Remember? l've never been serious
All this love etc. is beyond me.
Still haven't been able to make out..
how some men spend a lifetime
with one girl!
lt's a world full of pretty women
Someone has beautiful eyes, someone
has good lips, someone has niCe hair..
You boys are all the same.
- But you're one up on all of us
You're about to spend a lifetime
with someone you haven't even seen
That must be true love
Forget it. Think for a moment,
what if you're in love with someone?
l mean, imagine you're in love
with someone you've met on this trip..
why someone? Say you're in love
with me, and l'm in love with you too
Then what will you do? Will you
go back to marry that stranger?
Or, will you have the
courage to have an affair with me?
What will you do?
l don't want to miss the train again.
- l want to miss it again and again
What?
- Nothing
lf she's in love with me,
she's going to turn around
Turn
Back in London. How a month
passed by, l didn't even notice
Raj, you haven't given me your address.
l'll send you my wedding invitation
You'll come, won't you?
No, l won't come
"What's come over.."
"my heart?"
"Have l lost it?"
"What's come over my heart?"
"Where have l lost it?"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"Darling, this is love"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"Darling, this is love"
"You didn't Care to turn around.."
"but l was still waiting"
"By the time l wanted to stop you.."
"..you were too far away"
"What happened?"
- "l don't even know"
"Why is my heart.."
- "ln love?"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"Darling, this is love"
"Oh time! Stop, tarry.."
"go backwards"
"l've left myself behind.."
"..at the Crossroads of life"
"Where am l?"
- "Where are you?"
"What is this?"
- "Magic"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"You're in love, my love"
"Try refusing a million times,
but you're in love"
"Darling, this is love"
"What's come over.."
"my heart?"
"My heart was with me always"
"Have l lost it?"
"l've lost it"
Ma, you remember the dream
l wrote about in my diary?
That face l imagined
holding in my hands?
The one, l wanted to face
l've found him
What?
What are you saying, Simi?
- Yes Ma. When l was leaving..
l was clear about what
l was getting out of life
For a month, l wanted to be as
happy as l could. Then l'd come back..
and go away to my country to
spend a lifetime with a stranger
l had come to a Compromise with my
destiny, Ma. But little did l know..
this was in store for me.
Like a storm he came..
and he swept me off like a fallen leaf
Love's like this, like that,
l had read, l had heard
But l never understood. When, for the
first time, he offered me his hand..
l still didn't understand.
l was with him for so long..
still l didn't understand anything.
But today, when we were parting..
for the first time l felt
that after this moment..
l'm not going to see him ever again.
l kept looking back. He was going away
l wanted to stop him, l wanted to say
something, l wanted to hear something
But he didn't stop. Then l understood.
This is what love is like
And to him, l've given all my dreams.
l don't even know whether he loves me
All l know is that for me, he's life.
l can never be anyone else's, Ma
You're up? Simi and
l have been talking
She's back after so long.
l even lost track of time
l told you, not to betray my trust
l took a promise from you.
And you've deceived me?
No Babuji..
- Listen, first ask her
l don't want to listen to anything!
Pack. Tomorrow morning,
we leave for lndia
For good
Let her Cry
She has writ it on her own destiny
She will have to learn for herself
how to get over it. Let her cry
What's her name?
- Simran
What girl, Pops?
The one whose face
you see in the moon.
l'm not one of them..
who will go Crazy about a girl.
- Yes, l forgot!
Some have good lips,
some have beautiful eyes..
Lives where?
- Who, Pops?
This.. Simran
Don't know
- How is she?
Very lovable
Then what's the problem?
Problem is, she's about to marry.
- How about stopping the wedding?
ln your times, it was different.
Times have changed
Love is still called "love". That has
neνer changed, nor will it ever change
She's going to be someone else's.
- The bride goes to the man..
who brings her home. l didn't sire
you to play that fiddle. We aren't
those who stare at the moon.
You reaCh out to the moon..
..you bring her home. Go
And come home only
with your bride. Get it?
Gone. The daughter is getting married.
They've sold out and moved to Punjab
l'm coming, Simran
l'm coming
"When the girls go to the riverbank,
you'll hear their anklets chime"
"When the ripe mustard
sways in the farms.."
"you'll know a year has come to pass"
"Come today, come with a smile,
bring me a song, l've been waiting.."
"for the whistle of
the chugging train"
"Come home o'wanderer,
your mate beckons"
"Come home o'wanderer"
"Your land beckons"
Bless me, Ma-ji
No Ma-ji
Son, 20 years
l've held back these tears
Today, they won't stop, son.
Not today
Simran, my child
My baby doll
How have you been?
- l haven't Changed a bit!
You're the bride's aunt now!
Time to find a good groom for yourself
Lajjo, l've been ready all
these years! But in this village..
there isn't one who's a
match for me. So what do l do?
For me, l think it'll
haνe to be a foreigner!
You haven't changed a bit.
- Not a bit!
You did keep us waiting.
Anyway, better late than never
Wife, will you excuse us a moment?
- Get lost
Come on. Baldev, who's this? Go on..
You don't know? My daughter Preeti
Kuljit's sister.
- May you live long
Wonderful, isn't it? ln 20 years,
the whole generation has come of age
She's beautiful.
- Father's daughter, right?
Get lost
Where's Kuljit?
- Yes, where's Kuljit?
Bhaiyya (Brother) is out for a hunt.
He should be back soon
My respects.
- May you live long, son
That's a strong lad from Punjab.
- Whose son is he anyway?
Get lost
Come, breakfast is ready.
- Yes hurry. l'm famished
Come on kids
For you, for you and for you
You must take me out
tomorrow morning.
Sure Didi (Sister)
Kids, Grannie wants
everyone downstairs
You know Simi, when l was a kid,
my father would tell me..
there's no difference between man
and woman. All have equal rights
All my childhood, l lived believing
it's true. But as l grew up..
l realised what a lie that is
l wasn't given an education,
beCause it was more important..
that my brothers be eduCated.
That was my first sacrifice
Then, at every step, sometimes
as daughter, sometimes as sister..
sometimes as wife..
l went on sacrificing my own happiness
But once you were born..
when l held you in my
hands for the first time..
l made a promise, never to let happen
to my daughter, what happened to me
No more saCrifices at every step
as daughter, as sister, as wife
So what if she's a girl?
She'd liνe her life as she wishes
She'd have her share of happiness.
But l was wrong, Simran
l had even forgotten that a woman
hasn't even the right to make promises
She is born to be sacrificed
for their men. For their women..
men will never make sacrifices,
nor will they ever make sacrifices
Therefore l, your mother, come to
take from you, your own happiness
Forget him, my Child. Forget.
Because your father
won't care for your tears
For the happinesses of everyone,
l beg of you
Forget him, my Child
You're right, Ma
So naive of me. l don't
even know whether he loves me
And after all, Babuji is my father.
He has always cared for my happiness
For the sake of his happiness,
can l not make this little sacrifice?
Go Ma, go and tell Babuji
that l'm ready for the wedding
He won't have any problems from my end
Your girl is beautiful
Not the girl. Kuljit is plain lucky
And my name is Rajeshwari.
Miss Rajeshwari Singh
lf the little one is like this,
what will the older one be like?
l'll tell you, after the wedding
Listen
The day after
tomorrow is the engagement
The wedding is on the 25th
Sweets
l'm worried about something
l don't know why l see
this sadness in Simran's eyes
Even her smile is hesitant.
ls everything all right?
lt's nothing, Ma
lt's a new place, it's a change.
ln a few days, she'll adjust
Don't worry for nothing
Here you are, kheer
Simran hasn't forgotten him yet?
- She has agreed to get married
By and by she will forget everything.
- lf she remembers, she'll regret it
"l saw you, l realised.."
"what madness love is"
"When l saw you, l realised.."
"From here, where to?"
"Just let me die in your arms"
"When l saw you, l realised.."
"what madness love is"
"From here, where to?"
"Just let me die in your arms"
"My eyes.."
"dream of you"
"My heart holds memories of you"
"Nothing's mine"
"lt's all yours"
"My life, my breath is yours"
"When l weep for you, your tears.."
"my sorrows begin to smile"
"l saw you, l realised.."
"what madness love is"
"From here, where to?"
"Just let me die in your arms"
"l don't feel like anything"
"What do l say, what do l do?"
"ln front of me.."
"just keep sitting."
"Just let me look at you"
"You called out to me,
and look, here l am"
"What greater than
the promise to love?"
"l saw you, l realised.."
"what madness love is"
"From here, where to?"
"Just let me die in your arms"
Take me away from here,
Raj. Take me away from here!
What?
- You don't know
what's going on in there!
Day after tomorrow is the engagement
The wedding is after a fortnight.
All arrangements are in place
Babuji gave his word to his friend.
And he lives by his word
He can do anything,
but he can't go back on his word
We have to run from here. We must!
- No Simran. l'm not eloping
l haven't come here to steal you.
l might have been born in England
But l am Hindustani. l've come
here to take you as my bride.
l'll take you only when
your Babuji gives me your hand
You don't know my Babuji!
We have to get away from here, Raj.
Please Raj, take me away from here
Do you love me?
- More than anyone else
Do you trust me?
- More than l trust myself
Then listen carefully to what
l'm going to say. From now on..
we're strangers. l don't know
you and you don't know me. Go back
Let things happen as they're
happening. Leave the rest to me
What l'm upto is daunting.
But l have complete faith in our love
But alone l cannot
tread upon this path
You will have to be my strength.
You must co-operate. Tell me,
will you stand by me?
Remember one more thing.
l'm here only for your sake
Till l have you for
lifetime's sakes, l am not leaving
Listen, what's the name of
the one you're marrying?
Kuljit Singh
Help! Anybody here?
Somebody, help me!
Where's everyone? Help!
Anybody around?
Had Raj not arrived in the nick
of time, l would've been the prey
Raj, l'm sold out!
Where are you from?
l've never seen you before.
- l'm from London
Our guest from London!
What have you come here for?
- To achieve something
To aChieve what? Do tell us
Land.. land.
- Land?
Yes, if l could find a good stretch
of land, l want to set up a faCtory
Factory, making what?
- Beer
Tell me something, Kuljit.
Will 8-1 0 million pounds..
be enough to set up a factory?
What happened?
- 8-1 0 million pounds?
Too less? l can get more.
- No! That's a lot. Enough
God is great! He makes us meet.
We'll get along fine together
You want to set up a factory?
As good as done
Done, my man
By the way Raj..
where are you staying?
- You see, l don't know anyone around
So l'm putting up at
the Circuit House.
Strange! Now you know me
l have a palatial house! And you'll
stay at the circuit house? No way!
Binda, go and get his luggage
from the circuit house. Drop it home
What are you doing, Kuljit?
- Not a word
You've saved my life, saved Kuljit!
Can't l do as much for you?
l know, you're from London.
Here in Punjab, we're lions
You're going to enjoy yourselves.
- Well, if you're forcing me..
as you wish.
- That's like it!
What about babes?
We'll have a blast!
You haven't gone yet?
Go on Binda, hurry up.
Get a Black Label for Raj
l'm going to have a scotCh with Raj
Show me a cigarette, man. Strange!
The lighter too
You have done us a great
favour in saving Kuljit's life
No, it was my duty.
- May you live long, son
Preeti, give Raj some sweets
Enough
1 0 million pounds!
Why didn't you tell me before?
l was about to..
- Raj! My son!
The sweets.
- l have some
Let me feed you. That's like it!
You want to set up a factory, no?
We'll set it up for you.
- What was l telling you?
Get dressed fast.
We're going to Baldev's for lunch
Who's Baldev?
- He's my friend, man!
His daughter is marrying my Kuljit
What am l going to do over there?
- That's true. What will he do there?
But if you insist, l'll come along.
- That's like it!
Baldev is a bit British.
He'll mind it if we're late
Let's make it on time.
- That's like it!
You get dressed fast. We're
always getting late because of you
Kuljit, l have something to tell you.
- Don't worry about the factory
l have
l'll take all of it
Compliments
My compliments
Listen..
- l?
How did the shopkeeper get here?
l've seen you somewhere before.
Not me. l never step out of the house
ln London?
- But l haven't been beyond Ludhiana
Have you met my friend Raj?
He has just arrived from London
What are you saying?
- Balli, the doctor..
Raj is the one who saνed
Kuljit's life yesterday
You know who this is? The oldest
of my friends. My kinsman to-be
What are you staring at?
TouCh his feet
My respects
Hurry! The doctor has
been asking for you for ages
This doctor is a
wonderful fellow. Come on, man
Old foggie has quite a memory.
- What happened?
Nothing. This is great! Lovely house!
- l told you
This is Raj. My friend.
He has come from London
This is Simran
Namaste, Simran-ji
Were it not for him yesterday,
you and l wouldn't be here together
What a thing to say..
Very glad to meet you, Ms Rajeshwari
What is this?
- A little gift. For a little bride
Mr. Raj, folks l like
can call me Chutki
And folks who like me,
call me Raj. Only Raj
Namaste, Simran-ji.
- Namaste
Come on now
This is Raj, my British friend
The one l told you about.
- My respects
May you live long, son.
- Coming
Have some.
- Thanks Ma-ji (Mother)
Let me do the rest for you.
- No, you belong to the groomspeople
You're our guest.
- How strange of you
A moment ago you called me your son.
The next moment, you disown me?
Allow me
Just try this lassi. l made it
with my own hands! Here you are, Aunt
Here you are Parjai-ji (Aunt).
This is for you, Aunt
That's a lovely dress
Excuse me..
After you
Why are you taking all this trouble?
We kids can manage. Allow me
That's what l've been saying all
along. But no one will listen to me
l've been given all the work.
- That's my point
Hey.. who are you?
- l? l'm Raj
Raj, who?
- Your son-in-law to-be
Kuljit is your son-in-law to-be,
no? l'm his friend
Darling boy! Put the glasses there.
- Sure
Such a darling!
Today l see the best sign!
For the first time..
l'm seeing Simran
laughing with such mirth!
Give that to me.
- l won't
True, Ma-ji. Simran
looks very cheerful
Sweet? Salted?
Nothing's happening for
Raj here! Get ready to leave
Son of an Englishman! Get up!
Hurry! We're going hunting
Look at him. Aren't
you coming? Get up.
l'm sick. l have high fever
Caught such a chill last night,
l slept in my shoes, you know
You're wearing only one shoe.
- That's the leg that caught the chill
Sorry friend,
l just can't go hunting with you
You British are so feeble.
l'll send medicines for you
Make sure you're fine by this evening.
We're having fowl for dinner.
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
Hey Kuljit..
Come on Raj, get started
What's this?
- Keep moving
What's all this Raj?
- Wonderful thing happened today
Met a minister on my way. Turns
out to be my Daddy's Childhood friend
He gave me all this. Let me take
care of that. Don't tire yourself
l'm a lone fellow you know. What use
this sugar, rice and wheat for me?
So l thought l'd bring it over.
There's a wedding in the offing here
Could be useful, no?
- Maybe so, son
But we're the bridespeople.
Can't take anything from you
Not again. Once and for all,
deCide what you take me for
Either you don't call me a son,
or you treat me like a son
How do you treat sons?
- You don't argue with sons
All right. l won't argue.
- That's like it
Now listen to the real thing, Ma-ji.
My mother used to say..
one who helps out with a wedding,
gets a pretty bride
All this, for a pretty bride?
- What else? Only lucky ones..
find good brides nowadays.
- What kind of a bride d'you want?
Say, someone like you
Don't say that. Give
me your blessings.
Granted. You'll get a bride you want
All right, l'm off.
- Will you please open this?
lt's going to open
Aunt, don't keep looking,
don't even think. Just take it
Stuff like this is hard to
find even in Delhi or Bombay
Just wear it and step out,
and you'll make the girls stare
Don't even ask me about the boys.
- lt's nice
Not special
You show me that one.
- Okay. Here you are
Superb stuff. Just take a look at
the borders. On you, resplendent
Such bad ones! lf you have
something speCial, show me
l have to wear it for the wedding.
- Here you are
This is for weddings. lf you
aren't pleased, l'm no connoisseur
Pure gold thread. On you,
looks exotic!
Don't talk rot! lt's not that good
Not that bad either. l'll keep it
Pack it. And put a good price
You've worn me out
Raj, let's have a song from you.
- l can't sing
Coy like a girl? Sing.
- Oh no Grannie..
Sing.. please
l'm in love, why am l afraid?
l've loved, l haven't stolen anything
Why should l weep secretly?
l'm in love, why am l afraid?
What else have l to do?
- l'm in loνe, why am l afraid?
You've got your aim all wrong
Forget it, you can't even sing
The loνer will carry his bride away
The bridespeople will be left gaping
What are you doing?
Everyone's out there! Let go!
On one condition.
- What?
Give me a kiss Senorita.
- Are you crazy?
One kiss.
- Ma might see!
Let her see
Chutki might see!
- Let her see
Aunt might come by.
- Let her come.
This Babuji is going to get me killed!
What are you wondering Baldev?
There's no countermove
First time in 20 years,
l have you cheCkmated
Good move, indeed.
This once l'm checkmated
That's check. And mate.
- Wonderful!
Yes Babuji, l'm wonderful
How did he checkmate?
No, l'll put it back.
- No, let me take a look
What happened?
You know what's
about to happen tomorrow?
What?
Tomorrow, l'm going to
be engaged to Kuljit
Tomorrow, Kuljit will
put a ring on this finger
You know why the engagement
ring is worn on this finger?
Because the artery from this
finger leads straight to the heart
l can't wear anyone
else's ring but yours, Raj
lf you want me to walk up in
front of everyone with a ring..
and put it on you,
l'll do it. No problem
All this is a great joke for you,
isn't it? What l'm going through..
..you can never imagine.
- Look at me
Look
l feel everything Simran, the way
you're pining, your pain, your tears
But why don't you understand?
This is just the beginning
These people haven't even
gotten to know me properly
l need more time,
Simran. And l need your support
l want you to smile. And listen,
no son of a gun can take you..
away from me, using just a ring
You're mine, only mine
Chutki might wake up. Go away
. Listen
Didi..
Can l say something?
- Go on
l don't like this Kuljit
one bit. Don't marry him
lt's νery late. Go to sleep
Didi, l like the one
who was on the roof
What did you say?
Didi, isn't Raj the
one you met in Europe?
Yes
l like him a lot! You marry him.
- Don't you worry
He's the one l'm marrying
Yes Grannie?
- Pistachios for the sherbet
Done
Raj, where are the flowers?
- You put them beside the staircase
Oh l forgot! Were it not for you,
everything would be topsy-turvy
That's what l'm saying. The
lover will take his bride away
Raj, weren't you with the
groomspeople? Have you switched over..
to the bridespeople?
- Someday l'll have a bride too, no?
Just putting in some practice.
Get it? - Never mind. Get lost
Son of a gun
Kuljit is so lucky!
- Really
Now give her yours
Simran, offer your hand
Simran, put your hand out
Come on
What's this?
Last night, while taking off
my bangles, l hurt my finger
Never mind. The other hand
"These girls are poison pills"
"These boys are rogues"
"Poison pills"
- "Rogues"
"Make sure you're painted with henna"
"Make sure the
bride's palanquin is ready"
"To take you away,
o'beauty, your lover is coming"
"Make sure you come with your faCe
hidden behind the bridegroom's sehra"
"lt's a matter of hearts.
Keep it in your heart"
"For a signal from
your flying tresses.."
"with bated breath, the
baChelors await your suit"
"The maidens will go
into hiding out of shame.."
"for these are all madmen
from town Come to our village"
"Keep your eyes
downcast; keep yourself chaste"
"To take you away,
o'beauty, your lover is coming"
"l'm a young boy;
you're a pretty girl"
"lf our hearts are swayed,
what's my crime?"
"You should've held your heart.
This beauty is magic"
"lf the magic is working,
what's my crime?"
"Keep up for me, leave the door ajar"
"To take you away,
o'beauty, your lover is coming"
"Say no more now, do no more now"
"lt's a matter of hearts.
Keep it in your heart"
"Make sure you're painted with henna;
make sure your palanquin is ready"
"Make sure you come with your faCe
hidden behind the bridegroom's sehra"
"O'my precious one.."
- "you know not.."
"you're still pretty,
and l'm still young"
"l Could still die for you, my love"
"Make sure you're painted with henna;
make sure your palanquin is ready"
"Make sure you come with your faCe
hidden behind the bridegroom's sehra"
Babuji, yesterday you were wonderful!
What a danCe! Bested all the others
No Babuji, just a speCk
of dirt. Now it's clean
Too few doves, don't you think?
The whites ones..
look.. one, two, three
No, maybe same like yesterday
l've decided. Today l'm
talking it over with Raj
ls it something to be ashamed of?
- Raj is here
Back? So early?
Raj! My precious son! Come here.
We were just talking of you
l've something important to tell you.
- Sure, go on
This ought to be discussed by elders.
But since you're so close to us..
l thought, why not talk to you?
- Tell me
l wish this friendship
to become a relationship
Why not, why not?
- For my daughter, Preeti..
l seek your hand
Raj! Better think up something fast!
Else, they have you trussed!
Raj, have you any objections?
- What? Oh no. How could l?
My son!
- But l can't take..
such a big decision all by myself.
So you will have to talk to Pops
Pops?
- Father
See? What a good boy!
- l never do anything..
against my father's wishes.
- No problem. Give me his number
l'll talk to him over telephone
He's away in America on business.
- Great! Gone to America!
Let him ask him to come over.
- No problem
My country, my soil,
my Raj! Here l Come, son
Step out of the Country,
and you'll find everything..
but the matthri your wife serves up.
- Compliments, lady
Neither the pickles, nor the culture.
For one who loves the Ganga.
what's a Thames? So l told Raj
to return only with his bride
That's like it!
- Such conviCtion
What do you do in London?
- Back in London..
London?
- Forget London. All l know is..
Go East, go West, Punjab is the best!
Son!
Don't you worry.
l've got it all tied up
You don't even
introduce me to your Daddy
What a wonder! Just this morning,
we were talking about him..
and l find him in the marketplace,
armed with a photo, asking about you
Whatever anyone says, this marriage
was made in Heaven! Right, lady?
Right.
You're strange! You don't need
my permission for a good deed
What do you mean no?
Have l ever refused you anything
How about sweets?
Your son-in-law is waiting
Right away!
- Go on!
The wedding must be done right away!
A good deed can't wait
l was thinking of Kuljit and Raj
getting married at the same time
What was that?
lt's final!
- Raj, are you happy?
Give me a sweet!
Quick! My son is happy!
Now you're marrying Preeti.
Her brother is Kuljit..
the one who's about to marry Simran.
And you love Simran. Not Preeti
What was Preeti doing in London?
- Not Preeti. ln London, it was Simran
Yes, Simran.. who's this Simran?
- Pops! Just give up thinking! Please
Can anything be done
without giving it a thought?
l'm here. Everything will be all right.
- By now, it's done already!
Wedding must be done right away!
Good deed can't wait!
Why did you come?
lt was a mistake! Won't happen again.
l'll tell them that l forgot..
about your mother's death anniversary.
Matter laid to rest for a month
May l come in?
- Sure, come right in
You're going to live very long.
Raj and l were just talking of you
Sit
You sit too. Milk for me? Thank you!
Tomorrow's Karwa Chauth.
- What's Karwa Chauth?
l'd like to keep fast for
Raj's well-being. May l?
Sure, no problem!
- Karwa Chauth, Pops?
Karwa Chauth? No! Never!
Why?
- We consider it a bad omen..
for a girl to observe the ritual
for her husband before her marriage
Besides my child, we can't
discuss the liaison for a month
lt was during this month
that Raj's mother passed away
We have to fix another date for the
wedding. Let's talk to your father
Ajit..
Raj, you know what day it is tomorrow?
What's it now?
- My first Karwa Chauth
l want you to give me water..
and feed me the first
morsel of food after my fast
Hands off.
- What?
l told you. Hands off
Simran, if you don't love me,
just tell me straight. l'll go away
Then you can marry Kuljit. lt's going
to save me this everyday melodrama
ls it something l said?
- But you never say anything, no?
l want you to give me water
and feed me the first morsel..
of food after my fast.
Are you out of your mind? You expeCt me
to make a grand entry saying..
"Hi Simran! l'm your husband-to-be!
Here, take a drink of water"
l don't care! l'll even die of hunger!
But the first drink of water,
and the first morsel of food..
you will feed me! Get it?
Just like her father
So why should l be
the butt of the joke?
You're unique, Mr. Malhotra.
Your dress doesn't indicate..
your affinity to Hindustan.
- The dress has fooled even you?
l keep Hindustan in my heart.
- Wonderful!
Wonderful?
Ajit was saying you're
here to set up a factory?
The factory is just an exCuse.
lf you ask me the truth..
l'm here to choose a bride for Raj
Then men are all out in the outhouse
They say, they don't want
to disturb us on Ladies' Day
Are you keeping a fast too?
- Yes
May you live long, my child.
My Kuljit is lucky to get
a bride like you. Come
Ma-ji, this is my Pops. Father
Your son has cast a
spell over everyone here
That's my son
l'll join you
Pops, this is..
- l know
She can only be Simran
May you live long
No one even watches his step.
Hold this. The flowers!
"Let it rain flowers!"
"My beloved is here"
Kammo, where are the flowers?
Hurry up
l'm Raj's father. From London.
- From London?
Actually from Bhatinda. But l've been
in London for many years. You?
l'm Simran's Aunt.
- You can't be!
What?
- You could be her sister
Listen.. aren't you keeping fast?
- No. l'm still a maiden
Nothing could've been better.
- What?
One of your flowers.
- Maybe it's for you. Keep it
When is the moon going
to rise? l'm starving
l hope it kills you.
Did l ask you to fast?
Eat this on the sly. No one's looking
Don't
The moon is up.
- Where?
There
"On this night of prayer
for the wedded woman.."
"l look at the moon,
l pray with folded hands"
"Then l break my fast"
"Give me the water, take
your slave for your queen"
"Tonight, give me what l desire"
"Come home o'wanderer,
your beloved beCkons"
What happened?
- Water
Simi, my child
- Drink water
What happened? What happened to her?
- She swooned
Get up. Come, my child
What happened?
- lt's all right. She just swooned
lt's nothing. Come on, let's eat
She's so fragile, no?
Why are you anxious?
Are you fasting too?
No..
- Then come along
lt isn't easy for him to get away.
Everyone's asking for Raj all the time
He won't be able to come, Didi.
Please, eat something
l won't! l'd rather die starving.
- Very well, kill yourself
l'm sorry, l'm late. But what to do?
They weren't about to leave me
lt was tough getting away. Here, eat
Eat, didi
l said l'm sorry. Now eat.
Else, you'll swoon for real
Chutki, tell him there's no
need for him to worry for me
l was about to faint of hunger.
And there he was, filling his stomach
Anyway, it's my first Karwa Chauth.
Why should he get so worked up?
Whether l live or die, is he bothered?
You don't know this. But Raj
hasn't eaten anything all day either
He wanted to break fast with you.
And he told me not to tell you
Sorry Raj, but l Couldn't keep
shut any longer
Come here
Talking to me?
- Come here
l got carried away.
- No matter, Senorita
ln big places, such
small things happen
My turn Senorita. Feed me
l told you, not to betray my trust.
Simran hasn't forgotten him yet?
lf she remembers, she'll regret it
What happened to me
won't happen to my daughter
No more saCrifices at every step
as daughter, as sister, as wife
She'll live life as she wishes.
She'll have her share of happiness
Come in
Keep this
Ma, this?
- Not a word! l know everything
l've seen everything. Raj is the
one you met in Europe. l know
l also know, the two of
you love eaCh other dearly
l was wrong Simran! My daughter
won't sacrifice her happiness
She isn't going to sacrifiCe her love
l know Raj, you'll make my daughter
very happy. You have my blessings
Take my daughter away. Leave
No one here Cares for your love.
Take her away from here
l'll take care of everything.
- No Ma-ji
l don't want to hear anything! No!
Take her away, lest my resolve weakens
Please go away from here!
l beg of you, son!
- l will Ma-ji. l'll take her away
Come.. sit here
Keep this
Ma-ji, l was a little boy
when my mother passed away
But whatever l am today,
is beCause of her
To this day l haven't forgotten
something she said. She'd say..
"Son, at every turn in life, you'll
find two roads. One right, one wrong"
"The wrong route will be easy,
it will draw you. But the right path.."
"will be hard, with lots of hazards,
a lot many troubles"
"On the wrong road, initially,
you might find success, happiness"
"But in the end, you will lose.
Upon the right path, initially.."
"you may trip at every step,
you may faCe hazards, difficulties"
"But in the end, you will always win"
Now you tell me, Ma-ji.
Am l on the right, or in the wrong?
Your way is absolutely right,
son. But you don't know my husband
And Ma-ji, your
husband doesn't know me
lf l wanted to elope with Simran,
l could've done it already
But l want to be given Simran.
l don't want to steal her
l don't want to take her away
on the sly. l want to do it openly
lf l have come,
l'll surely carry my bride away
But only when Babuji gives me
her hand, of his own νolition
Now Simran isn't your problem.
She's my headache
As for you, you have
given your daughter away
Just a matter of time now
before the bride is carried away
ls this crying illness in the genes?
How strange Uncle-ji! Tell me.
- The girl.. what's her name?
Yes Simran. l don't
approve of the match
Why Uncle-ji?
- Girl's fine. But no match for you
You're a strong young Jatt d'Punjab!
And this girl is frail, subdued
ls this any match? Match for
you is a girl like a sparkler!
Just come with me to London.
The girls l'll introduce you to..
will drive you crazy!
What's the problem, Uncle-ji?
After the wedding, Simran stays here
And we're going to be in London,
meeting your sparklers!
Pull out all the stops!
- You son of a gun
As a little boy, l'd ride out to
the fields on my father's shoulders
Ever since, l struck up a
friendship with these doves
l find it so peaceful out here
l love spending time with the doves
Tell me Babuji, are the doves here
any different from the doves in London?
Difference there is. The doves here
know me, they recognise me
They belong to my land.
Even the doves out there are alien
Could it be that you perceive it
differently? Maybe a dove out there
took to wings from here from
your land.. one who knows you..
one who recognises you.
Maybe you don't recognise him?
What happened?
What are you doing?
- My Ma used to say..
the soil of our land is very
powerful. lt's going to be fine
But this is outrageous!
Who might've done this?
Babuji, look
Let's go.
- Babuji..
Are you still angry about my beer act?
l was childish. Won't you forgive me?
l forgot that long ago
l was wrong about you. You're right
l didn't recognise. Come, let's go
Ma-ji, what is the matter?
You asked for me?
Son, whatever the doctor might say..
l know my time's up
Speak of niCe things,
Ma-ji. What a thing to say?
Not to be anxious.
l'm of the age when one leaves
l've had a wonderful life
Son, l have nothing to complain about
But now that l see Simran..
after years a desire
wells up in my heart.
l want to see Simran married
Before she marries, l wish l don't..
- How Can you talk of suCh things?
Listen son
The bride's palanquin has just got to
cross over from one house to another
Now that everyone is here,
what difference would it make if..
the wedding is pre-poned to tomorrow?
- Absolutely Correct!
The wedding happens tomorrow.
Yes Baldev? Right tomorrow
Yes Ma-ji. Tomorrow
We will haνe to take
Simran away on the sly
Nothing else is going to work.
Don't worry. l have it all worked out
We're taking the morning train out.
l'll wait for you at the station
Somehow or the other,
just get there with Simran
Whatever happens next, we'll see
Are you listening?
l know this isn't your way. You don't
want to take Simran away like this
But son, it's too late now.
lf you love her..
if you want to spend a lifetime
with her, you must elope. Understand?
Please Raj, take me away from here!
You don't know my Babuji!
We have to run from here. We must!
- l've come to take you as my bride.
l'll take you only when
your Babuji gives me your hand
What is to happen tomorrow,
l don't know
What l'm going to do tomorrow,
But you must trust me
Whatever l do tomorrow,
is going to be for both of us
Do you love me?
Do you trust me?
Then it's just a matter of time
before the bride is carried away, no?
"Oh heart's love"
"Oh my love"
"l giνe you.."
"..to God to keep"
"So strange are the ways of the world"
"The heart is crazed, yet so helpless"
"What's left to be heard?
What's left to be said?"
"Just let it lie between us"
"The hide-n-seek is over.
l'm getting married"
"How l wish it doesn't kill you"
Simi, come down, quick! Time for
the ritual body-painting with henna
"Oh my love"
"Oh my Moon"
"You are my life.."
"my beloved"
l wanted to tell you
You were right. l failed to recognise
You enter my house,
and before my family..
..you play with my honour?
You have deceived me! You have
taken advantage of our trust!
You made a joke out of our cordiality?
How dare you haνe an
affair with Simran?
Did you imagine you'd marry Simran?
You aren't even worthy of yourself
How can you be worthy of Simran?
l was right about you.
Liars, wastrels like you never improνe
They only become worse
No Babuji! No!
Didn't l tell you to take me away?
No one Cares for our love!
Didn't l say, let's elope?
- No Simran, don't
You can only run from strangers
From the ones we call our
own where could we run away to?
Our elders are our parents
All our lives, they've brought
us up. They gave us so much love
About our lives, they can
deCide better than we can
We have no right to make them
sad for the sake of our happiness
Babuji is right.
l am a liar, a cheat
Even if l lied for your sake,
a lie is always a lie
Babuji is right.
l'm not worthy of you
And so what if l can
see nothing beyond you?
remember no one but you?
Babuji is right. l'm a wastrel
How did l think of marrying you?
So what if this wastrel
loves you like a madman?
Love isn't everything, is it?
Babuji is right, Simran
Babuji is right
Here you are Babuji.
Take your daughter
l didn't come here to
break anyone's heart
l just wanted to win hearts
Maybe l fall short of expectations
Maybe that's why
l couldn't win you over
lf you think Kuljit
will make Simran happier..
then you're right
What's best for Simran, you know best
Forgive me
Forgive me Preeti
l know l have hurt you
Where's Simran, Raj?
Raj, where is Simran?
She will come, Pops. She'll come
Babuji will bring her. Personally
He will have to
l wish to hear no more.
Go away from here
Your son has deceived all of us.
He has shown us where he belongs
l won't let my daughter marry a liar!
- Enough!
l am proud of my son.
Don't incite me to passion
Kuljit and Raj are
fighting at the station
We must go there! One
might kill the other!
Come on
Come with me Simran
Stop
Let me go, Babuji! Please let me go
Raj means all my life!
Without him, l can't live
Let me go to my Raj
Please let me go to my Raj
Go Simran
No one can love you more than him
Go my child. Go to your Raj
Go on Simran. Live your life
Go my child, go
ln big places, such
small things happen
The loνer will carry his bride away