[BZZZZZ]
♪ ON THE EDGE
OF OUTER SPACE ♪
♪ SPACE, SPACE, SPACE ♪
♪ SHE'S THE ONE
WITH A SERIOUS FACE ♪
♪ FACE, FACE, FACE
FACE, FACE ♪
♪ WHEN I DROPPED IN,
CHECKED IT OUT ♪
♪ ALIEN GIRLS
WERE ALL ABOUT ♪
♪ EONS SINCE
I HAD A DATE ♪
♪ ANOTHER LIGHT-YEAR'S
TOO LONG TO WAIT ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ARE EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS, SO EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ♪
♪ HEY, THOSE GIRLS
ARE LOADS OF FUN ♪
♪ FUN, FUN, FUN, FUN ♪
♪ EVEN HOTTER
THAN THE SUN ♪
♪ SUN, SUN, SUN ♪
♪ YOU KNOW THAT I'VE HAD
LOTS OF GIRLS ♪
♪ MOST OF THEM
FROM OTHER WORLDS ♪
♪ WHILE TRIPPIN' THROUGH
THE GALAXY ♪
♪ THE VALLEY GIRLS
ARE THE ONES FOR ME ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ARE EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS, SO EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ♪
♪ GIRLS ♪
♪ YOU KNOW THAT I'VE HAD
LOTS OF GIRLS ♪
♪ MOST OF THEM
FROM OTHER WORLDS ♪
♪ EONS SINCE
I HAD A DATE ♪
♪ ANOTHER LIGHT-YEAR'S
TOO LONG TO WAIT ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ARE EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS, SO EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ARE EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS, SO EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ♪
♪ SO EASY ♪
♪ SO EASY, SO EASY ♪
♪ EARTH GIRLS ♪
[DOOR OPENS]
VALERIE.
[HISS]
I'M HOME.
YOU'RE NOT SUPPOSED TO
SEE ME IN THIS
BEFORE THE WEDDING.
IT'S BAD LUCK.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I MEAN, SWEETHEART,
IT'S JUST SOME STUPID
SUPERSTITION ANYWAY.
YEAH, YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE MET
ON FRIDAY THE 13th
AND LOOK
HOW HAPPY WE ARE.
TED, WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU SAID 11:00.
SORRY, VAL. IT WAS
BLOOD AND GUTS NIGHT
AT THE OLD
EMERGENCY ROOM.
AGAIN?
I WISH
YOU'D CALLED ME.
I WOULD HAVE BUT,
YOU KNOW,
FIVE MINUTES
ON THE PHONE COULD, UH,
COST A LIFE.
OH.
I'M READY, TEDDY.
OH, WHAT A DAY.
OH, BOY.
I WAS FLUFFING IT
FOR YOU.
COULD YOU GET
THE LIGHT, PLEASE?
TEDDY...
LOOK WHAT I FOUND.
SWEETHEART,
I'M SORRY.
I HAVE TO TAKE OUT
A GALL BLADDER
FIRST THING
IN THE MORNING.
TOMORROW NIGHT.
I PROMISE.
I WON'T BE HERE.
I'LL BE AT THE NAIL EXPO.
THE CUTICLE CONVENTION,
REMEMBER?
I'LL BE GONE
TILL MONDAY.
WELL, MONDAY, THEN.
I PROMISE.
I WAS READING AN AD
FOR THESE PYRAMIDS
YOU PUT OVER THE BED.
THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO
INCREASE SEXUAL ENERGY.
VALERIE, PLEASE.
GOOD NIGHT,
SWEETHEART.
'NIGHT.
K-EARTH 101
SOUTHLAND WEATHER--
ANOTHER GORGEOUS DAY
IN L.A.
SUNNY AND WARM.
86 DEGREES IN MALIBU.
94 IN THE VALLEY.
88 IN HOLLYWOOD.
THAT'S K-EARTH 101 NEWS.
I'M CLAUDIA MARSHALL.
♪ IT'S THE SUMMER OF LOVE,
LOVE, LOVE ♪
♪ I'M IN LOVE
WITH LOVE, LOVE, LOVE ♪
♪ FOR EVERYONE
TRANSCENDS WHO ♪
♪ I'M THINKING OF YOU ♪
♪ BOY ♪
♪ LOVE ENERGY ♪
♪ IS GIVING US A SHOVE ♪
♪ MAKING THIS
THE SUMMER OF LOVE ♪
HI, MISS LANA.
I'M SO SORRY.
I MISSED
OUR APPOINTMENT.
YOU LOOK SO GREAT.
THAT'S
A GREAT OUTFIT.
THANKS, DEAR.
THAT DOOR IS A REAL BITCH.
HI, VAL.
GOOD MORNING.
IT'S A REALLY
GOOD COLOR FOR ME.
WOW.
YOU NEED A FILL.
UH, MORNING, ALL.
GOOD MORNING.
YOU BETTER HAVE A NOTE
FROM YOUR MOTHER, YOUNG LADY.
♪ HE'S SHOWING OFF
HIS BODY... ♪
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M JUST NOT THAT
TURNED ON BY HER LATELY.
I HEAR
OYSTERS ARE GOOD FOR POTENCY.
I TRIED THAT,
BUT THEY
KEPT SLIPPING OFF.
IF I WAS ANY MORE POTENT,
I'D KILL SOMEBODY.
WHOA!
OH, RIGHT!
I GAVE THIS CUTE
LITTLE NURSE
A RIDE HOME
THE OTHER NIGHT.
AND?
AND NOTHING.
I'M GETTING MARRIED NEXT MONTH.
AND WHY ARE YOU
SO TARDY?
I WAS UP REAL LATE
LAST NIGHT WITH TED.
DR. DOLITTLE
FINALLY CAME THROUGH, HUH?
NO. HE WAS
DEAD ON ARRIVAL.
AGAIN? SANKA?
SURE.
AT THE RATE WE'VE
BEEN HAVING SEX,
WE MIGHT AS WELL
BE MARRIED ALREADY.
IT'S BEEN,
LIKE, A WEEK?
TWO WEEKS.
VALERIE, TED'S OBVIOUSLY
A VICTIM OF PMS.
WHAT?
PREMARITAL STRESS.
OH.
WHAT'LL
SNAP HIM OUT OF IT?
A NEW WOMAN.
THANKS.
WAIT. THAT'S IT!
WE'LL MAKE YOU
A NEW WOMAN.
THIS IS GREAT.
WATCH THIS.
LET'S SEE HOW YOU LOOK
ON THE MAKEOVER MACHINE.
OH, HOUSEWIFE FROM HELL.
MATRON ON DRUGS.
LOOK AT THAT.
THAT'S IT.
WE'LL MAKE YOU BLONDE
WITH BLUE EYES.
MAYBE
WHEN I GET BACK FROM THE EXPO--
SKIP THE EXPO.
STAY HOME
AND AMBUSH TED.
WHAT IF
HE DOESN'T LIKE IT?
AT THIS POINT,
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT TO LOSE?
COME ON. WE'RE
DOING A MAKEOVER.
OOH! OOH!
OH! OH!
OH! OH! OH!         COME ON!
A PERM.
A BUTCH.
A FACIAL.
A BODY WRAP.
GRAVEL SCRUB.
A GRAVEL SCRUB.
BIKINI WAX.
WE'LL DO IT ALL.
ALL RIGHT!
♪ IT'S TIME TO FACE THE MUSIC,
IT'S TIME TO MAKE YOU SEE ♪
♪ THE ROOT OF ALL YOUR PROBLEMS
IS THAT YOU DON'T LOOK LIKE ME ♪
♪ NOW THIS IS GONNA HURT YOU,
BUT I JUST GOT TO SAY ♪
♪ YOUR LOVE LIFE'S GOING NOWHERE
'CAUSE YOU LOOK LIKE DORIS DAY ♪
♪ WHO'S THE ONE
THEY CAN'T RESIST? ♪
♪ THE BRAND NEW GIRL ♪
♪ WHO'S ON
THE MOST WANTED LIST? ♪
♪ THE BRAND NEW GIRL ♪
♪ HONEY,
IF YOU VIXENIZE ♪
♪ GUARANTEED
HE'LL GET A RISE ♪
♪ BELIEVE ME, YOU CAN BE
A BRAND NEW ♪
♪ BRAND NEW ♪
♪ BRAND NEW GIRL ♪
OW!
RRRROWW!
AAH!
♪ YOU'RE CUTE
AND FRESH AND WHOLESOME ♪
♪ BUT SCIENCE HAS A CURE ♪
♪ THE NATURAL LOOK
IS NOWHERE ♪
♪ YOUR HAIRDRESSER
KNOWS FOR SURE ♪
♪ YOU GOT TO LEARN
THE ART OF TEASING ♪
♪ CHANGE YOUR REPERTOIRE ♪
♪ ALL YOU NEED'S
A LITTLE FAITH ♪
♪ AND A SEE-THROUGH
PUSHUP BRA ♪
♪ IF YOU WANT TO BE
A FEMME FATALE ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T REST
ON YOUR L'OREALS ♪
♪ YOU KNOW, I THINK
SHE MIGHT BE RIGHT ♪
♪ GRAB THE BLEACH,
SHE'S SEEN THE LIGHT ♪
OW!
♪ MAYBELLINE ♪
OOH.
♪ REVLON ♪
AAH.
♪ RUBBERMAID ♪
♪ TALK TO ME,
MAX FACTOR ♪
♪ WHO'S THE ONE
THEY CAN'T RESIST? ♪
♪ THE BRAND NEW GIRL ♪
♪ WHO'S ON
THE MOST WANTED LIST? ♪
♪ THE BRAND NEW GIRL ♪
♪ HONEY,
IF YOU VIXENIZE ♪
♪ GUARANTEED
HE'LL GET A RISE ♪
♪ BELIEVE ME, YOU CAN BE
A BRAND NEW ♪
♪ BRAND NEW ♪
♪ BRAND ♪
♪ NEW ♪
♪ GIRL ♪
[STEREO PLAYING
THEME FROM LOVE STORY]
HELLO, DR. GALLAGHER.
SURPRISED?
YES, IT'S ME.
OH! TSK. TSK.
DR. GALLAGHER.
WHY ARE YOU
LOOKING AT ME LIKE THAT?
YOU WANT TO DO WHAT?
OH, NO, NO.
I COULDN'T.
NO.
NO, PLEASE. STOP.
NO, NO.
WELL...
ALL RIGHT.
OK.
LET'S SEE.
NOW, CHAMPAGNE,
FLOWERS,
SUSHI, FEATHERS,
UM, SENSUAL OIL,
RIGHT,
AND INCENSE OR...
LET'S SEE.
"SPRINKLE A LIGHT BULB
WITH YOUR FAVORITE PERFUME
TO SENSUALIZE THE ATMOSPHERE
OF YOUR LOVE TRAP."
[RECORD SKIPS]
[SSSS!]
[POP!]
OH, NO!
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
OH, GOD. HE'S HERE.
WELL, THIS IS
WHERE WE LIVE.
WE?
YEAH. UH, YOU KNOW,
ME AND, UH,
THE CAT BAMBI.
JUST MAKE YOURSELF
AT HOME,
ALL RIGHT?
[RRRR]
[HISS]
"HOW TO DRIVE A MAN CRAZY."
[TOILET FLUSHES]
AAH!
EAT ME,
I'M A COOKIE!
I'M SORRY.
I'M SO EMBARRASSED.
I DIDN'T KNOW
TED HAD COMPANY.
I'M VALERIE.
I DON'T USUALLY
DRESS LIKE THIS.
HERE COMES DR. LOVE.
ALL RIGHT, ROBIN,
A PILEUP.
WHO'S YOUR FRIEND?
SHIT! VAL.
TED, WHAT
ARE YOU DOING?
UH, GEE, NOTHING.
WH-WHAT IS
GOING ON HERE?
YOU BROUGHT HER HOME
TO HAVE SEX?
YOU WEREN'T
SUPPOSED TO BE HERE.
YOU WERE GOING TO
HAVE SEX WITHOUT ME?
OF COURSE NOT.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU TWO HAD IN MIND,
BUT I'M NOT
INTO KINKY SCENES.
BYE.
YOU LOOK INCREDIBLE.
HONEY, SHE DOESN'T
MEAN A THING TO ME.
IF MEANINGLESS SEX
IS WHAT YOU WANT,
WHY CAN'T YOU
HAVE IT WITH ME!
I MADE
A STUPID MISTAKE.
I WANTED A LAST FLING,
THAT'S ALL.
YOU CAN'T EXPECT ME
TO BE MORE EVOLVED.
EVOLVED? I'LL SHOW
YOU EVOLVED.
WAIT A MINUTE.
NO. NOW, DON'T DO THAT.
THAT'S VERY DANGEROUS.
CUT IT--VAL, STOP IT!
CUT IT OUT!
VAL, COME ON!
THE NEIGHBORS
ARE WATCHING!
VAL, OPEN UP.
SWEETHEART,
OPEN THE DOOR!
YOU'RE WANTED
IN EMERGENCY, DR. LOVE.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS TO ME!
I'M A DOCTOR!
HERE! TAKE THESE
WITH YOU, DR. LOVE.
AND DON'T COME BACK!
[MUTTERING]
[CAR STARTS]
TED!
[TIRES SQUEAL]
TED,
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
GO TO BED, MRS. MERKIN!
[ Reverberating ]
MRS. MERKIN! MRS. MERKIN!
[MEOW]
♪ YOU'RE A LIAR,
AND IT TOOK ME FOREVER ♪
♪ TO FIGURE THAT OUT ♪
♪ YOU COULD
SWITCH ON A SMILE ♪
♪ PRETEND TO BE TENDER ♪
♪ BUT I KNOW NOW
WHAT YOU'RE ALL ABOUT ♪
♪ WHAT A NIGHTMARE ♪
♪ MY FRIENDS THOUGHT
YOU WERE A DREAM ♪
♪ YOU COULD
SWITCH ON A SMILE ♪
♪ AND SEEM SO SINCERE ♪
♪ BUT YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS ♪
♪ I DON'T THINK
YOU'LL EVER UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ OOH, DID CHEATING ON ME
MAKE YOU FEEL LIKE A MAN? ♪
♪ I USED TO WORSHIP
THE GROUND YOU WALK ON ♪
♪ I DID ANYTHING
YOU WANTED ME TO ♪
♪ I USED TO WORSHIP
THE GROUND YOU WALK ON ♪
♪ NOW I'VE LOST MY FAITH
IN YOU ♪
[GLASS SHATTERS]
♪ AAH ♪
♪ SUNDAY MORNINGS
I'D WAKE UP ♪
♪ LIE IN BED
WATCHING YOU SLEEP ♪
♪ IT WAS ALMOST RELIGIOUS ♪
♪ HOW I BELIEVED IN YOU ♪
♪ IT HURT WHEN YOU
DESTROYED MY BELIEF ♪
♪ I DON'T THINK
YOU'LL EVER UNDERSTAND ♪
♪ OOH, DID CHEATIN' ON ME
MAKE YOU FEEL LIKE A MAN? ♪
♪ I USED TO WORSHIP
THE GROUND YOU WALK ON ♪
♪ I DID ANYTHING
YOU WANTED ME TO ♪
♪ I USED TO WORSHIP
THE GROUND YOU WALK ON ♪
♪ NOW I'VE LOST MY FAITH
IN YOU ♪
♪ OH, I'VE LOST
MY FAITH IN YOU ♪
♪ I USED TO WORSHIP
THE GROUND YOU WALK ON ♪
♪ DIDN'T THINK
I'D GET BY WITHOUT YOU ♪
♪ NOW I DON'T WORSHIP
THE GROUND YOU WALK ON ♪
♪ AND I'M STRONGER
THAN I KNEW ♪
♪ I'M STRONGER
THAN YOU KNEW ♪
COME HERE, YOU.
NO, DOCTOR.
WHAT ABOUT YOUR WIFE?
SHE'S IN A COMA.
YOU'RE NOT.
NO. OH.
MMM. OH.
JOHN?
UH! OH.
YOU WEASEL DICK!
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HELLO.
OH, CANDY,
THE WORST THING
IN THE WORLD HAPPENED.
NO, BAMBI'S FINE.
IT'S TED.
YEAH. THE BLONDE THING
DID NOT WORK.
IT'S THE SHOW THAT SHOWS
THE INS AND OUTS
OF THE SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
FITNESS CRAZE.
LET'S FACE IT.
INNER BEAUTY IS FOR LOSERS.
OOH.
HA HA HA HA HA!
[BONK]
UH!
WHOA!
MAC!
AAH!
OH, GREAT.
OH, THIS IS TOO GOOD.
THERE'S A GIANT BLOW DRYER
IN MY POOL.
OH, SHIT!
TED, YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
CONTROL MY MIND
WHEN YOU'RE NOT HERE.
OK, JUST RELEASE
ALL OF THIS NEGATIVE ENERGY
OUT INTO THE UNIVERSE.
YOU'RE JUST GOING TO
SWIM RIGHT THROUGH IT.
[THUD]
[POP]
OH, TEDDY BEAR,
YOU'RE BACK.
AAH!
AAH!        AAH!
OH!
WHAT IS THIS?
WHAT'S GOING ON?
THIS ISN'T
WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE, IS IT?
IS IT?              ZIS ZIT?
OH, MY GOD, IT IS.
IT'S A SPACESHIP.
OH, LIKE THINGS
WEREN'T BAD ENOUGH,
NOW I'VE BEEN ABDUCTED
BY A UFO.
YOU'RE JUST GOING TO
DO SOME EXPERIMENTS ON ME
AND LET ME GO LIKE
IN THE NATIONAL ENQUIRER.
RIGHT?
RIGHT?              RIGHT?
OK. OK.
JUST DON'T TAKE OUT
ANYTHING I'LL NEED LATER.
GET IT OVER WITH.
I DON'T WHY
YOU ABDUCTED ME ANYWAY.
I'M SURE YOU'RE LOOKING FOR
SOMEBODY MORE IMPORTANT
LIKE NANCY REAGAN.
I'LL TELL YOU
WHERE TO FIND HER
BECAUSE
I'M JUST A MANICURIST.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT ANYTHING
EXCEPT NAILS.
YOU KNOW, NAILS.
NAILS.
NAILS.      NAILS.
REALLY. I COULD
KEEP MY MOUTH SHUT.
YOU COULD TELL ME ANYTHING.
I'D NEVER TELL.
ASK MY COUSIN.
SHE GOT HER BOOBS DONE,
AND I NEVER TOLD ANYONE.
EXCEPT I JUST TOLD YOU.
OH, MY GOD.
YOU'RE ALIENS.
OOH!
ZEEBO.
IS THAT YOUR NAME--
ZEEBO?
WIPLOC.
WIPLOC. HI.
MAKELSOLAKVEDER.
MAYBE I'LL JUST
CALL YOU MAC. HOW'S THAT?
OH, AND I'M VALERIE.
VALERIE.
WALERIE.    VOLARE.
YOU GUYS AREN'T
GOING TO HURT ME, ARE YOU?
YOUR PLANET IS WEIRD.
WE'RE STILL
IN MY POOL.
OH.
OH!
LISTEN, IT WAS REALLY NICE
MEETING YOU, FELLAS,
BUT I HAVE TO GO.
FEEL FREE
TO USE THE POOL,
BUT YOU'VE CAUGHT ME
AT A BAD TIME.
[SHOUTING]
AAH!
AAH! AAH!
[ALARM SOUNDS]
[ALARM STOPS]
DID I DO THAT?
I FLOODED THE SHIP.
OH, I'M SORRY.
I'M SO EMBARRASSED.
I'M REALLY SORRY,
BUT I'M SURE YOU CAN
FIX IT, RIGHT?
DON'T FREAK OUT.
THIS IS
JUST LIKE THE TIME
I DROPPED MY LADY SCHICK
IN THE TOILET.
AFTER IT DRIED OUT,
IT WORKED FINE.
LET'S GO IN MY HOUSE.
I'LL MAKE SOME LUNCH,
AND I'LL GET
THE POOL DRAINED.
THEN YOU GUYS CAN TAKE OFF
BACK TO YOUR PLANET.
BLAST OFF. POW.
BYE-BYE. BYE-BYE.
¿COMPRENDE?
COMPRENDE.
BE CAREFUL. THIS LADDER'S
A LITTLE LOOSE.
OH, I'M GLAD
YOU CAN BREATHE OK.
THE AIR QUALITY
IS ACTUALLY VERY GOOD TODAY.
[COUGHING]
CAREFUL.
IT'S KIND OF WET.
OK?
WELL, UH, COME ON.
LET'S GO IN THE HOUSE.
THIS WAY.
THOSE ARE LEMONS.
YOU KNOW,
LEMONADE, LEMON PLEDGE.
OH. IT'S OK.
IT'S A SPRINKLER.
EARTH PEOPLE ARE GOING TO
FREAK OUT IF THEY SEE YOU.
NO OFFENSE,
BUT YOU DO LOOK LIKE
WOOKIES OR WEREWOLVES.
PEOPLE WILL WANT TO
SHOOT YOU,
SO JUST BE COOL, OK?
LET'S GO INSIDE.
COME ON. COME ON.
WHAT'S GOING ON
IN MY HOROSCOPE TODAY?
WELL, THIS IS
MY HOUSE.
UM...SORRY ABOUT
THE MESS.
MAKE YOURSELVES AT HOME.
[CUCKOO]
HI. THIS IS
VALERIE GALE.
COULD YOU SEND WOODY
TO DRAIN MY POOL?
YEAH. RIGHT AWAY.
IT'S AN EMERGENCY. I--
[MEOW]
[RRREOW]
[PURR PURR]
WOW!
I'VE NEVER SEE HER
DO THAT BEFORE!
WHAT IS THAT,
SOME KIND OF LOVE TOUCH?
[SPEAKING
ALIEN LANGUAGE]
OH! HI. YEAH.
LISTEN. THIS IS A MATTER
OF LIFE AND DEATH.
I LOST MY CONTACT LENS
IN THE POOL--
NO. SEND WOODY.
HE FOUND IT LAST TIME.
HEY!
THOSE ARE TED'S FISH!
THANKS.
NO. NO. NO. NO.
NOT FOOD!
LET'S SEE.
OH, NOT MUCH HERE,
BUT I DIDN'T EXPECT
I'D HAVE ALIENS FOR LUNCH.
OH, LOOK.
LOW-CAL POP TARTS.
THESE ARE NATURAL.
GREAT.
[SPEAKING
ALIEN LANGUAGE]
OK.
WE HAVE AN ENTREE.
WHAT ELSE?
UH...INSTANT PUDDING!
ADD WATER, HMM...
TOO MUCH WORK.
OH, SPRAY-ON CHEESE!
THIS IS GREAT.
YOU HAVE EGGS
ON YOUR PLANET?
I COULD COOK THOSE
FOR YOU.
UH...
[POP]
[THUD]
[PLOP]
THIS IS WONDERFUL.
[CRUNCH CRUNCH
CRUNCH]
[MEOW MEOW]
[MEOW]
OH, WIPLOC!
NO! NO! NOT THERE!
NO. COME WITH ME.
OK. SO YOU GO
IN THERE...
NO! NO!
COME HERE. NO.
YOU... GO IN THERE...
GO IN THERE...
YEAH...
AND THEN YOU FLUSH.
[WHOOSH]
[SCRATCH]
OH, MY GOD!
WOODY'S HERE!
WHATEVER YOU DO,
JUST STAY INSIDE.
[HORSE NEIGHS]
AAH!
[NEIGH]
[SINGING IN SPANISH]
[CLICK CLICK]
YOU ARE AMERICANS.
YOU'RE THE PRODUCT
OF THE FREEST--
[EEE! EEE!]
[CLICK CLICK]
YOU'RE TEARING ME APART!
YOU SAY ONE THING,
HE SAYS ANOTHER--
A NEW CAR!
A NEW CAR!              AAH!
♪ TAKE
A MIND EXCURSION ♪
♪ IT'S JUST... ♪
HEY! HOW'S IT GOING?
HEY, WOODY.
WHAT'S THAT?
SOME KIND OF GIANT
BOOGIE BOARD?
NO. IT'S MY NEW
POOL PATIO. BITCHIN', HUH?
PRETTY RAD.
[MEOW]
WHOA!
SHOOT THE CURL, KITTY!
THOSE LITTLE GUYS
LOVE THE WATER.
LISTEN, VALERIE,
HOW COME
YOU WANT
YOUR POOL DRAINED?
HOW COME?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU KNOW, THE WATER
JUST SEEMS REALLY STALE.
WE'VE SEEN
A LOT OF THAT.
HOW LONG
WILL THIS TAKE?
UH...ABOUT...A DAY.
WHOA! CHECK OUT
THE SETS.
IF I WAS SIX INCHES TALL,
I'D BE OUT THERE NOW.
THEY WERE PUMPING
LIKE THAT THIS MORNING--
I DON'T BELIEVE THIS.
NO, FOR REAL.
I WAS GETTING BARRELED
IN THIS TOTALLY COOL TUBE.
I HAD JUST SEX-WAXED
MY BOARD.
SOMEONE SHOOTS HIS BOARD,
HITS ME IN THE HEAD.
THIS IS THE WORST.
WOULD HAVE BEEN
THE RIDE OF THE DECADE.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO
DO UNTIL TOMORROW?
WASTE YOUR BRAIN,
WAX YOUR BOARD,
PRAY FOR WAVES.
[WHISTLING
ANDY GRIFFITH THEME]
[SPEAKING JAPANESE]
TRY THIS.
♪ WHAT'LL IT BE? HMM ♪
♪ WHAT'LL IT BE? ♪
♪ HMM ♪
MAKE ME AN ALASKAN
POLAR BEAR HEATER
ON THE DOUBLE.
WE'LL MAKE
OUR OWN MUSIC, GORGEOUS.
YOU AND YOU STAY.
TUBBY, REST YOUR THUMBS.
I'LL DRIVE.
NOW WATCH, BABY.
EVERY MOVE A PICTURE.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
[CLICK]
[TED'S VOICE]
IS THERE A DOCTOR IN THE HOUSE?
LEAVE A MESSAGE
WHEN YOU HEAR THE BEEP.
[BEEP]
VALERIE?
ARE YOU THERE?
PLEASE PICK UP.
I NEED TO TALK TO YOU.
SORRY I WAS
SUCH AN ASSHOLE.
VAL, YOU'VE GOT TO
BELIEVE THIS.
I'VE NEVER EVER
BEEN UNFAITHFUL TO YOU. EVER.
I'M ONLY GUILTY
OF A LITTLE KISSY-FACE
WITH ONE NURSE.
YOU STOPPED ME
FROM MAKING A BIG MISTAKE
LAST NIGHT.
VAL, I'M SO SORRY.
PLEASE FORGIVE ME.
I'LL SEE YOU
WHEN I GET HOME. BYE.
COME BACK TO FINLAND.
COME BACK TO WINTER
ALL YEAR ROUND.
COME BACK
TO PARKAS AND GOAT'S CHEESE.
FINLAND KNOWS
WHAT YOU WANT.
YODEL-AYDI, YODEL-AYDI,
YODEL-AY-HEE-HOO!
HEE-HOO!
[CLICK]
TELEVISION!
[SPEAKING
ALIEN LANGUAGE]
OK. WELL,
WE'RE ALL SET.
FINLAND IS HERE?
FINLAND? NO.
THIS IS THE VALLEY.
FINLAND IS THE CAPITAL
OF NORWAY.
YOU LEARN FAST.
SORRY I WAS
SUCH AN ASSHOLE.
OH! I SEE YOU FOUND
A CABLE STATION.
[IMITATING TED]
VALERIE?
ARE YOU THERE?
PLEASE PICK UP.
DID TED CALL?
I'LL BE OVER
RIGHT AFTER WORK TONIGHT.
OK, HONEY? BYE.
OH, MY GOD!
TED IS, LIKE,
A TRAINED DOCTOR.
ONE LOOK AT YOU GUYS
AND HE'LL KNOW
YOU'RE NOT LOCAL.
IF I ONLY HAD
A ZILLION GALLONS OF NAIR.
NAIR.       NAIR.
NAIR.
♪ I'M A SEX PIXY ♪
♪ IS THAT OK? ♪
♪ DO DO DO DO DO ♪
♪ DO DO DO
DO DO DO DO DO ♪
♪ HEY, HEY,
DO DO DO DO ♪
♪ DO DO DO DO ♪
♪ DA-DO, OH, OH ♪
CANDY, WHATEVER YOU DO,
DON'T FREAK OUT.
VALERIE!
PROMISE ME
YOU WILL NOT FREAK OUT.
STOP! YOU ARE
FREAKING ME OUT!
UM...A UFO LANDED
IN MY POOL,
AND THEY CAPTURED ME,
BUT WE MADE FRIENDS,
AND I FED THEM POP TARTS.
YOU'VE GOT TO
CUT THEIR HAIR.
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
OH, NOTHING.
I'M ON DRUGS.
CANDY, HELP THEM.
WOULD YOU LISTEN
TO YOURSELF?
VALERIE,
NO MAN IS WORTH
GETTING YOURSELF
IN THIS STATE OVER.
MEL GIBSON, MAYBE,
BUT NOT TED!
VALERIE, COME HERE.
JUST SIT DOWN, HONEY.
RELAX.
HAVE A MENTAL MARGARITA.
NOW I'M GOING TO
SHOW YOU SOMETHING
THAT'S GOING TO
CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
IN THAT CASE,
LET ME GET A CIGARETTE.
YOU GOT LITTLE
ALIEN HOUSE GUESTS...
LET'S SEE THEM.
[COUGH COUGH]
SHIT, VALERIE!
THOSE ARE ALIENS!
I TOLD YOU.
OH, GOD! OH, SHIT!
VALERIE! VALERIE!
THOSE ARE--
THOSE ARE BIG...
ALIENS!
WHAT DO THEY WANT
FROM US?
WHAT DO YOU WANT
DID THEY TAKE CONTROL
OF YOUR BRAIN?
OH...I DON'T
THINK SO.
CAN THEY TALK?
♪ WHAT'LL IT BE?
HMM ♪
I ATE ALL
THE FRUSEN GLADJE.
PANTY SHIELDS
MAKE ME FEEL FRESH.
ARE THEY STRAIGHT?
I DON'T KNOW.
THEY'RE ALIENS!
THIS IS MAC,
AND THIS IS,
UH...ZEEBO,
AND THIS IS
WIPLOC.
[COUGH COUGH]
WELL, THEY'RE
JUST DARLING.
GET THEM
OUT OF HERE.
THEY CAN'T LEAVE
UNTIL THE POOL IS DRAINED.
IF TED FINDS OUT
THEY'RE ALIENS,
HE'LL WANT TO
DISSECT THEM.
WE COULD MAKE THEM
LOOK MORE...HUMAN.
I THOUGHT YOU NEVER
WANTED TO SEE TED AGAIN.
I DON'T. I JUST WANT
TO TALK TO HIM.
VALERIE,
THIS IS INSANE.
THEY'RE, LIKE,
THROWING UP ON MY STUFF!
COME ON, CANDY.
WELL, I SEE SPLIT ENDS
ARE UNIVERSAL.
LOST IN SPACE
WITH NO CONDITIONER, HUH?
I THINK THEY'VE
BEEN UP THERE A LONG TIME.
WELL, IT'S ALL DEAD.
IT'S GOT TO COME OFF.
CAN YOU DO IT?
DOES TINA TURNER
WEAR A WIG?
THAT'S A WIG?
THAT'S A WIG.
GREAT!
I'LL GET CLOTHES!
IF I FIND ONE FLEA,
THE DEAL'S OFF!
OK, VAL,
ARE YOU READY?
I THINK
THEY'RE ALMOST DONE.
I GAVE THE RED ONE
THE BLOND-SURFER LOOK.
WOW!
WHICH ONE
IS THAT?
WIPLOC.
WE ARE HUMAN NOW!
I DON'T BELIEVE IT!
HE'S EVEN CUTE!
I KNOW!
BITCHIN', HUH?
VAL, YOU WON'T
BELIEVE THIS.
OK...
SURPRISE!
IS THAT ZEEBO?
[IMITATING CANDY]
OH, MY GOD ! YOU'RE, LIKE, TOTALLY BLACK!
OK...
AND...BEHIND
DOOR NUMBER THREE...
THIS IS...
THE ULTIMATE!
WOW!
YOU'RE INCREDIBLE.
WELL, IT WAS EASY.
I STARTED ON POODLES.
GOOD?
REAL GOOD.
OK. OK.
GROUP PICTURE. COME ON.
COME ON.
GET DOWN THERE.
ALL RIGHT...
NOW SAY,
VELVEETA SLICES.
SL--VEGAKLD.
VEL--SALKSI.
OK, YOU GUYS,
WHAT'S THE PLAN FOR TONIGHT?
WHOA! CANDY,
REALITY CHECK.
WE CAN'T GO OUT.
THEY'RE ALIENS!
SO? THEY CAN STILL
BE DATES!
DO YOU GUYS HAVE MARGARITAS
ON YOUR PLANET?
IT'S NOT SAFE.
I'LL TAKE YOU HOME.
DON'T GET YOUR PANTIES
IN A BUNCH.
WE'RE WITH MAJOR CUTE GUYS.
IT'S SATURDAY NIGHT!
COME ON!
YOU GUYS ARE SO LUCKY
YOU CRASHED IN THE VALLEY.
IT'S THE BADDEST PLACE
ON EARTH.
CANDY, SIT DOWN!
HI, SWEETS.
I THINK WE'D LIKE TO KEEP
A LOW PROFILE, CANDY.
GUYS, WHAT YOU
DOING LATER?
I NEVER WOULD HAVE BELIEVED
THAT THIS COULD HAPPEN.
THAT YOU'D BE CRUISING
WITH SHAVED MARTIANS?
NO. THAT TED WOULD
DO THIS TO ME.
GIVE MEN ENOUGH ROPE,
THEY'LL DIG THEIR OWN GRAVE.
SO TRUE.
HE SAID HE WANTED
ONE LAST FLING.
MAYBE THAT'S NORMAL,
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M SURE
WE'LL BE HAPPY ONCE WE'RE MARRIED,
BUT I CAN'T PRETEND
THIS DIDN'T HAPPEN.
VALERIE, YOU WORK HARD
TO MAKE TED HAPPY.
WHO IS MAKING YOU HAPPY?
WOO!
FINLAND BABES!
YODEL-AYDI, YODEL-AYDI,
YODEL-AY-HEE-HOO!
DIDN'T YOU GO TO
VAN NUYS HIGH?
AREN'T YOU
TERRY HARPER'S BROTHER?
TERRY HARPER'S
BROTHER?
HA HA HA!
SOMEONE SHOULD
HOSE THOSE GIRLS DOWN!
WANT TO PARTY?
COME ON!
WIPLOC!
LOOK! THERE THEY ARE!
OK. DON'T WORRY.
I'LL GO GET HIM.
ME, TOO.
ME, TOO, TOO.
WAIT--
IT'LL ONLY TAKE
A MINUTE.
COME ON, YOU GUYS,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
[TARZAN YELL]
♪ WHEN I NEED SOMETHING
TO HELP ME UNWIND ♪
♪ I FIND A SIX-FOOT BABY
WITH A ONE-TRACK MIND ♪
♪ SMART GUYS ARE NOWHERE,
THEY MAKE DEMANDS ♪
♪ GIVE ME A MORON
WITH TALENTED HANDS... ♪
WHERE DID YOU BUY THOSE?
THEY'RE MY DAD'S.
THOSE ARE FABULOUS.
I KNOW.
♪ ...IN LOVE
TILL WE'RE DONE ♪
♪ THEN THEY'RE
OUT IN THE HALL ♪
♪ I LIKE 'EM BIG AND ♪
♪ STUPID ♪
♪ REAL DUMB ♪
♪ I LIKE 'EM BIG AND ♪
♪ STUPID ♪
♪ WHAT KIND OF GUY
DOES A LOT FOR ME? ♪
♪ SUPERMAN
WITH A LOBOTOMY ♪
♪ MY FATHER'S
OUT OF HARVARD ♪
♪ MY BROTHER'S OUT OF YALE ♪
♪ BUT THE GUY
I TOOK HOME LAST NIGHT ♪
♪ JUST GOT
OUT OF JAIL... ♪
VALERIE! HI!
OVER HERE!
CANDY!
HI!
ARE YOU NUTS?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
HAVING COCKTAILS.
ALASKAN
POLAR BEAR HEATER.
TED IS COMING HOME
TONIGHT,
AND THERE'S A UFO
IN MY POOL. A UFO!
BFD. TED WON'T BE THERE
FOR A FEW HOURS.
JUST CHILL OUT.
LET'S GET
THESE GUYS OUT
BEFORE ANYONE REALIZES
THEY'RE ALIENS.
NO ONE'S GOING TO KNOW
THEY'RE ALIENS, OK?
TANYA!
HI. YOU KNOW VAL,
AND THIS IS MAC,
WIPLOC, AND ZEEBO.
THEY'RE FROM MARS
OR SOMETHING! COULD YOU DIE?
HEY, ZEEBO,
WANT TO DANCE?
GREAT IDEA.
WIPLOC.
SHOULD I DANCE?
SURE.
FINE. HEY,
PARTY DOWN.
WHEN YOU'RE READY
FOR YOUR CHAUFFEUR,
I'LL BE OUT
ON THE PATIO.
WHAT'S HER PROBLEM?
TWO WEEKS?
WHOA!
♪ ...'CAUSE
IT WAS SO STUPID ♪
♪ THE BIGGER THEY COME,
THE HARDER I FALL ♪
♪ IN LOVE TILL WE'RE DONE ♪
♪ THEN THEY'RE
OUT IN THE HALL... ♪
COME ON.
LET'S DANCE.
WOO!
♪ I LIKE 'EM BIG AND ♪
♪ REAL DUMB ♪
♪ I LIKE 'EM BIG AND...♪
HE LEFT?
♪ SHE LIKES 'EM BIG AND ♪
♪ STUPID ♪
[PIANO PLAYING]
YOU, GO REST
YOUR THUMBS. I'LL DRIVE.
YOU COULD ACTUALLY
PLAY THAT?
VALERIE, ARE WE LIMP
AND HARD TO MANAGE?
OH, NO, NO.
YOU'RE FINE.
I'M SORRY.
I JUST DON'T FEEL
LIKE TALKING MUCH.
I FIGURED THAT
EVERYTHING WOULD JUST FALL INTO PLACE
IF I FOUND
MR. RIGHT.
MR. RIGHT?
MR. RIGHT IS
LIKE THE GUY YOU DREAM OF MEETING
EVER SINCE YOU'RE
A LITTLE GIRL.
YOU'D GO ANYPLACE
OR DO ANYTHING
TO BE TOGETHER.
HE FEELS
THE SAME WAY
BECAUSE YOU'RE RIGHT
FOR EACH OTHER.
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE
I'M KIDDING MYSELF.
MAYBE THERE'S
NO SUCH THING.
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
SHAKE IT RIGHT ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE SO FAST ♪
♪ OUT ON THE FLOOR ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
SHAKE IT RIGHT ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE SO FAST ♪
HEY, BABY.
WHY BE WITH A ZERO
WHEN YOU CAN DANCE WITH A HERO?
♪ OH, BABY ♪
♪ YOU GOT TO TELL ME ♪
♪ WHERE IT TAKES US
YOU DON'T CARE ♪
♪ OOH, YEAH ♪
♪ BABY, JUST FIX UP
YOUR HAIR ♪
♪ IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHAT YOU WEAR TO ME ♪
♪ GET YOURSELF BACK
IN YOUR CAR ♪
♪ WE DON'T HAVE TO
GO TOO FAR ♪
♪ TO SEE ♪
♪ OH, BABY ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
SHAKE IT RIGHT ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE SO FAST ♪
♪ OUT ON THE FLOOR ♪
♪ COME ON, NOW, HURRY ♪
♪ THERE'S ALWAYS SOMETHING
WE CAN DO ♪
WHY BE WITH A HERO
WHEN YOU CAN DANCE WITH A ZERO?
♪ DON'T HAVE TO WORRY ♪
♪ AS LONG AS I'M NOT THERE
WITH YOU ♪
♪ OH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ BABY, JUST FIX UP
YOUR HAIR ♪
♪ IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHAT YOU WEAR TO ME ♪
♪ GET YOURSELF BACK
IN YOUR CAR ♪
♪ WE DON'T HAVE TO
GO TOO FAR ♪
WHOA.
BACK OFF, JACK!
THE LUCKY LADY'S
WITH ME,
AND DON'T BE COPPING
MY DANCE MOVES.
I'LL DANCE
WITH YOU BOTH. I DON'T CARE.
NO, NO, NO.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
HE CAN'T DANCE.
ALL RIGHT. I KNOW
HE CAN'T DO THIS.
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
SHAKE IT RIGHT ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE SO FAST ♪
♪ OUT ON THE FLOOR ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
SHAKE IT RIGHT ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE SO FAST ♪
♪ OUT ON THE FLOOR ♪
♪ SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
♪ DON'T YOU
WANT TO SHAKE IT? ♪
♪ BABY GONNA DANCE
ALL NIGHT ♪
♪ COME SHAKE IT, BABY ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
♪ SHAKE IT, BABY ♪
♪ SHAKE IT, BABY,
SHAKE IT ♪
♪ DANCE ALL NIGHT ♪
♪ OUT ON THE FLOOR ♪
COME ON, MAN.
HOT DAMN!
♪ THERE'S NOTHING
I'D RATHER DO ♪
♪ RIGHT HERE
WHILE YOU'RE MINE ♪
♪ BEING HERE WITH YOU ♪
♪ LEAVING IT
ALL BEHIND, BABY ♪
ALL RIGHT!
HEY! WOO!
♪ BABY, JUST FIX UP
YOUR HAIR ♪
♪ IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHAT YOU WEAR TO ME ♪
♪ GET YOURSELF BACK
IN YOUR CAR ♪
♪ WE DON'T HAVE TO
GO TOO FAR ♪
♪ TO SEE ♪
♪ OH, BABY ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
SHAKE IT RIGHT ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE SO FAST ♪
♪ OUT ON THE FLOOR ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
SHAKE IT RIGHT ♪
♪ BABY GONNA
SHAKE SO FAST ♪
♪ OUT ON THE FLOOR ♪
♪ SHAKE ALL NIGHT ♪
DAMN!
♪ BABY ♪
I'M GOING HOME
WITH HIM.
BITCH.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT PLANET YOU'RE FROM.
JHAZALLA.
OH. WE'VE ONLY BEEN
AS FAR AS THE MOON.
YOU KNOW, AT FIRST,
I THOUGHT YOU
KIND OF LOOKED
LIKE A GIANT BIGFOOT
OR SOMETHING,
BUT NOW...
IF I DIDN'T KNOW YOU WERE AN ALIEN,
I WOULD JUST THINK
THAT YOU WERE A REALLY CUTE GUY
WHO, I'M SURE,
HAS A GIRLFRIEND.
NO MR. RIGHT GIRLFRIEND.
YODEL-AY-HEE-HOO!
OH, MY GOD.
THAT'S WIPLOC.
♪ HIT ME ♪
ALL RIGHT!
GIVE ME
YOUR AUTOGRAPH
ON MY FOREHEAD.
SIGN THESE.
CANDY, YOU'RE FRENCHING
AN ALIEN IN PUBLIC!
[SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
YOU OK?
WIPLOC.
I WANT TO BE ZERO.
NO, NO, NO.
CANDY, UH,
I'LL CALL YOU.
OH, WHAT
WAS IT LIKE?
OH, MY GOD!
YOU'RE SO LUCKY!
DID YOU GET
HIS NUMBER?
I WANT HIS BABY.
SWEETHEART?
SWEETHEART,
I'M SORRY.
VAL?
HONEY?
HEY, VAL?
WHAT?
OH, WAIT A SECOND.
THEY SAID THE COMMODORE
WOULD STAND UP TO ANYTHING.
[THUD]
OOH!
BEAMER?
BEAMER.
[MAKING FISH NOISE]
ASTIN, WHERE'S MARTIN?
WHERE'S VAL?
DON'T, DON'T PANIC.
SHE PROBABLY
WASN'T HERE WHEN...
OPERATOR,
GIVE ME THE POLICE.
THIS IS AN EMERGENCY.
POLICE?
THIS IS DR. GALLAGHER.
I'D LIKE TO REPORT
A BREAK-IN
AND...
AND A POSSIBLE KIDNAPING.
OH, GOD.
TED'S HERE.
YOU GUYS,
ACT HUMAN, OK?
JUST ACT HUMAN.
OH, SWEETHEART,
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
OH, I WAS SO WORRIED
ABOUT YOU.
WHEN I CAME HOME,
THE HOUSE WAS WRECKED.
WHO ARE THEY?
WHO?
THOSE GUYS?
YEAH.
A BAND.
BOY,
I'M TOTALLY CLEAR.
[HUMMING]
YOU MEAN LIKE
A ROCK 'N' ROLL BAND?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH A BAND, VAL?
I WON THEM
ON MTV.
I WON AN MTV WEEKEND
WITH A BAND.
HI. I AM, UH, MAC.
HOW IS IT HANGING,
MR. DUDE?
DR. DUDE.
DR. DUDE?
I CAME HOME
TO TALK TO YOU ALONE.
THIS IS PRIVATE.
I'M SURE YOU WON'T MIND
WHEN I ASK YOU TO LEAVE.
THEY CAN'T LEAVE.
THEY'RE SPENDING THE WEEKEND.
THIS IS MY HOUSE.
YOUR HOUSE? WAIT.
I THREW YOU OUT, DR. LOVE.
I'M GOING TO
THROW THEM OUT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF THAT?
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
YES, I AM.
I WON THEM.
WHAT?
YOU'RE TEARING
ME APART!
YOU HAVE NO BUSINESS BEING
WITH THESE WEIRD PEOPLE.
I NEVER WON
A BAND BEFORE. THEY'RE STAYING.
I WANT YOU
TO BE HAPPY, BUT--
YEE-WAH.
AH!
HE WAS GOOD.
YOU ANIMAL!
I OUGHT TO GIVE YOU
A TRACHEOTOMY.
THAT WAS MERCEDES,
MY MOST EXPENSIVE FISH!
HEY, WHAT'S
GOING ON HERE?
BREAK IT UP.
HEY, HEY! COME ON!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHO'S
DR. GALLAGHER?
I'M
DR. GALLAGHER.
UH-HUH.
I'M OFFICER DEMONTE.
THIS IS
OFFICER MURPHY.
YOU REPORTED
A BREAK-IN
AND POSSIBLE
KIDNAPPING?
YES, I DID,
BUT SHE'S FINE.
HOWEVER,
THESE DEGENERATES BROKE INTO MY HOME
AND DESTROYED
MY PROPERTY.
I WANT THEM ARRESTED
RIGHT NOW.
THEY'RE MTV SCUM!
MA'AM, YOU MIND TELLING US
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
THIS MAN DOESN'T
LIVE HERE ANYMORE,
AND HE'S STRANGLING
MY GUESTS.
HE WAS EATING
MY BLUE-GILLED DORKY.
WATCH YOUR MOUTH!
10-13. WE GOT
A FALSE REPORT.
JUST A DOMESTIC
DISPUTE.
HIS GIRLFRIEND
DUMPED HIM FOR A ROCK BAND.
BULLSHIT!
LET'S GO WHERE
YOU CAN COOL OFF.
I'M A DOCTOR!
IF WE BUST YOUR ARM,
YOU CAN PUT ON YOUR OWN CAST.
VAL, I DON'T KNOW YOU.
IF YOU THOUGHT
I'D SPEND MY LIFE
WITH YOU,
YOUR FRIENDS, AND
THAT PSYCHOTIC CAT OF YOURS,
YOU'RE CRAZY!
THE WEDDING'S OFF,
VAL!
COME ON,
BUDDY.
YOU WANT TO DANCE
WITH A ZERO?
I'M SORRY.
I THINK I HAVE TO
GO TO MY ROOM NOW.
[SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
IS TED
COMING BACK?
[SIGH]
NO. TED DOESN'T WANT
TO COME BACK.
[DOOR CLOSES]
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TED WANTS,
BUT IT'S NOT ME.
WHAT DOES
VALERIE WANT?
I DON'T KNOW.
I JUST WANT
TO BE HAPPY.
MAC COULD MAKE
VALERIE HAPPY.
THANKS, BUT I DON'T THINK
ANYBODY COULD MAKE ME FEEL
VERY GOOD RIGHT NOW.
MAC COULD MAKE
VALERIE FEEL
VERY, VERY GOOD.
WAIT A MINUTE.
ARE YOU COMING ON TO ME?
IS THIS A PASS?
BECAUSE IF IT IS,
SEX IS TOTALLY OUT OF THE QUESTION.
WHAT IS SEX?
SEX? YOU KNOW,
MAKING LOVE.
A MAN AND A WOMAN
LIKE EACH OTHER,
AND THEY TAKE
THEIR CLOTHES OFF, AND...
OK.
WELL, NO, NO, NO!
WE CAN'T BECAUSE
ME AND TED ARE, UH...
I GUESS WE'RE NOT,
BUT, I MEAN, UH...
WE CAN'T BECAUSE
YOU'RE AN ALIEN,
AND I'M FROM THE VALLEY.
WE MAY NOT EVEN BE
ANATOMICALLY CORRECT FOR EACH OTHER.
THAT COULD BE
A REAL PROBLEM.
[ZIPPER UNZIPS]
NO PROBLEM.
BUT, I MEAN, UH,
NO, NO, NO.
I MEAN,
IT JUST WOULDN'T WORK.
YOU'RE FROM OUT OF TOWN.
THE PHONE BILLS
WOULD JUST BE HELL...
SHH.
WELL, I JUST DON'T
WANT YOU TO THINK
EARTH GIRLS ARE EASY.
WHAT IS EASY?
THIS IS EASY.
AAH!
AH!
[SIREN]
OH!
YEAH,
YEAH, YEAH!
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH!
I TOLD YOU
NOT TO HAVE FUN.
[RING]
HELP!
TED!
UH-OH.
UH, DON'T GO ANYWHERE.
I'VE BEEN PAGED.
OH, SWEETHEART.
TED.
TED, MAKE IT STOP.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO MY FISH?
TED!
BEAMER!
YOUR FACE!
WHAT HAPPENED?
[RIBBIT RIBBIT]
TED!
STOP IT.
STOP IT! STOP IT!
AAAH!
HI.
GOD.
I HAD THE WEIRDEST
DREAM LAST NIGHT.
ALL I REMEMBER IS--
SHH...
[THUMP THUMP]
YOU HAVE
THE STRANGEST HEARTBEAT.
SOUNDS LIKE
YOU HAVE TWO HEARTS.
YES.
DON'T YOU?
NO. I JUST HAVE ONE.
TELL ME
ABOUT ZIMBABWE.
JHAZALLA?
JHAZALLA.
IS IT LIKE EARTH?
YES.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
SOUNDS NEAT.
IS DRIVING A UFO
A GOOD JOB?
OH, YES.
DO YOU OWN
YOUR OWN HOME?
NO WATER.
COME LOOK.
[SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
HI, GUYS.
HOPE INSTANT DECAF
IS OK.
BREAKFAST IS ON THE WAY.
I'M MAKING PANCAKES
FROM SCRATCH.
YEAH. VALERIE, UH...
WE CAN GO HOME NOW.
OH.
GEE...
THAT'S GREAT.
WOW.
I DIDN'T THINK
IT WOULD BE SO SOON.
YEAH.
THAT'S, UH,
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
YEAH. UH, VALERIE...
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
WELL, I BETTER GO
GET THAT.
POOL MAN!
HEY, DUDES,
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
WOODY.
WHAT IS THIS?
A SPACESHIP?
SPACESHIP?
NO WAY, JOSE.
WHAT IS IT?
A CAR.
THAT'S WHY SHE WANTED ME
TO DRAIN IT.
SHE DROVE HER CAR
INTO THE POOL.
I'M ALWAYS DOING THAT.
PRETTY RAD CAR, THOUGH.
WHERE IS IT MADE?
FINLAND.
FINLAND.            FINLAND.
OH, I HEARD OF THAT.
TED, BRINGING THAT GIRL
HERE WAS INEXCUSABLE.
NOW THAT
I'VE SLEPT ON IT,
I COULD PROBABLY
FORGIVE YOU,
BUT WHAT ABOUT
CALLING OFF THE WEDDING?
SWEETHEART,
I DIDN'T MEAN THAT.
MARRYING YOU IS THE MOST
IMPORTANT THING IN THE WORLD.
I NEED YOU
TO TAKE CARE OF ME.
I WON'T SO MUCH
AS LOOK AT ANOTHER WOMAN,
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
I'M GIVING HER
A PHYSICAL EXAMINATION.
A RELATIONSHIP IS
LIKE A PORCELAIN NAIL--
YOU CAN BREAK IT,
YOU CAN GLUE IT BACK TOGETHER,
BUT IT WON'T BE
AS STRONG AS BEFORE
UNLESS THE PERSON'S
COMMITTED AND NOT BRINGING HOME NURSES.
YOU SHOULD'VE SEEN ME
TODAY, MAN.
NOTHING BUT RADICAL RIPS
ALL THE WAY IN.
YOU WANT
SOME SLUSHY?
I WAS BARELY
OFF MY BOARD
WHEN THE WAHINES
WERE ALL OVER ME.
EW! WAHINES!
WAHINES.
YOU KNOW, GIRLS.
GIRLS?
YOU KNOW GIRLS?
DOES THE WOODBURGER
KNOW GIRLS?
PINOCCHIO GOT
A WOODEN BUTT?
I COULD FIX YOU UP
WITH SOME BODACIOUS CHICKS
JUST LIKE THAT.
YOU DON'T BELIEVE ME?
LIKE THAT.
COME ON. LET'S HIT THE BEACH.
RIDE THE WILD BIKINIS!
WE GO GET CANDY?
CANDY, GUM,
BEER NUTS, ANYTHING YOU WANT.
TWIZZLERS.
I GOT SOME MILK DUDS.
YOU OUGHT TO
LAY OFF COFFEE.
IT'LL KILL YOU
IN A DAY.
I WILL TAKE YOU
TO ZUMA BEACH.
I NEED SURPRISES.
I NEED ROMANCE.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN
SINCE YOU SAID
I LOVE YOU, I NEED YOU,
I'M CRAZY ABOUT YOU?
WELL, TED?
GET IN THE CAR,
WILL YOU?
WIPLOC.
ZEEBO.
[SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
ZEEBO GOING
TO ZUMA BEACH!
[SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
ZEEBO!
WIPLOC!
HEY, DUDES,
I JUST REMEMBERED SOMETHING.
WHAT WAS IT?
AT THE BEACH TODAY,
THEY'RE HAVING
A BLOND-OF-THE-MONTH CONTEST.
BLOND?
YEAH, YOU KNOW,
BLOND BEACH BUNNIES,
CALIFORNIA'S FINEST.
♪ BECAUSE I'M BLOND ♪
♪ I DON'T HAVE TO THINK ♪
♪ I TALK LIKE A BABY ♪
♪ AND I NEVER PAY
FOR DRINKS ♪
♪ DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT GETTING A MAN ♪
♪ IF I KEEP THIS BLOND ♪
♪ AND I KEEP THESE TANNED ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ I SEE PEOPLE WORKING ♪
♪ IT JUST MAKES ME GIGGLE ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I DON'T
HAVE TO WORK ♪
♪ I JUST HAVE TO JIGGLE ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M BLOND,
B-L-O-N-D ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND ♪
♪ DON'T YOU WISH
YOU WERE ME? ♪
♪ I NEVER
LEARNED TO READ ♪
♪ AND I NEVER LEARNED
TO COOK ♪
♪ WHY SHOULD I BOTHER ♪
♪ WHEN I LOOK
LIKE I LOOK? ♪
♪ I KNOW LOTS OF PEOPLE
ARE SMARTER THAN ME ♪
♪ BUT I HAVE THIS PHILOSOPHY--
SO WHAT? ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ I SEE GIRLS WITHOUT DATES ♪
♪ AND I FEEL
SO SORRY FOR THEM ♪
♪ 'CAUSE WHENEVER
I'M AROUND ♪
♪ ALL THE MEN IGNORE THEM ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M BLOND,
NYAH, NYAH, NYAH ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND,
♪ THEY SAY TO MAKE IT ♪
♪ YOU NEED TALENT
AND AMBITION ♪
♪ WELL, I GOT A TV SHOW ♪
♪ AND THIS WAS MY AUDITION ♪
UM, WHAT WAS IT?
OK, DON'T TELL ME.
OH, YEAH, OK.
"DUCK, MAGNUM, DUCK!"
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ I TOOK AN IQ TEST,
AND I FLUNKED IT, OF COURSE ♪
♪ I CAN'T SPELL "VW,"
BUT I GOT A PORSCHE ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND ♪
♪ B-L-O-N-D ♪
♪ DON'T YOU WISH
YOU WERE ME? ♪
♪ I JUST WANT TO SAY ♪
♪ THAT BEING CHOSEN
AS THIS MONTH'S MISS AUGUST ♪
♪ IS, LIKE, A COMPLIMENT
I'LL REMEMBER ♪
♪ FOR AS LONG AS I CAN ♪
♪ RIGHT NOW,
I'M A FRESHMAN ♪
♪ IN MY FOURTH YEAR
AT U.C.L.A. ♪
♪ BUT MY GOAL IS
TO BECOME A VETERINARIAN ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I LOVE CHILDREN ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ 'CAUSE WE'RE A BLOND,
♪ GIRLS THINK I'M SNOTTY
AND MAYBE IT'S TRUE ♪
♪ WITH MY HAIR AND BODY
YOU WOULD BE, TOO ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND,
B-L...I DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ I'M A BLOND,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ YES, I'M A BLOND,
♪ 'CAUSE I'M A BLOND,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH ♪
HEY, DUDES.
DUDES, COME ON.
SNAP OUT OF IT.
WE'RE MAKING
A PIT STOP.
BANG! BANG!
HELLO, OPIE.
BRYAN, COME ON
OVER HERE!
WILL YOU GET
IN THIS CAR RIGHT NOW?
MOM, HE'S GOT
MY GUN!
I TOLD YOU
NOT TO TELL FIBS!
HEY!
LEAVE HOME, KID!
HEY, DUDES! LISTEN.
SINCE I'M SPRINGING
FOR THE GAS,
YOU PICK UP SOME BREWS
AND SOME SANDWICH STUFF.
SOME BREWS
YEAH. LIKE
BREAD AND JUNK.
OK, DUDES?
OK, DUDE.
BREAD AND JUNK.
GIVE US BREAD.
WE NEED JUNK.
DON'T SHOOT. DON'T SHOOT.
I JUST WORK HERE.
I'M AN AMERICAN.
THERE. TAKE IT.
[DING]
TAKE IT ALL.
WHERE IS CANDY?
CANDY? OH!
RIGHT HERE.
TAKE AS MUCH AS YOU WANT.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU TOO MUCH.
[SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
HEY, TROOPS!
HAD TO DRAIN
THE LIZARD!
BE RIGHT WITH YOU.
WHAT DO I
OWE YOU?
GET DOWN!
WHAT?
I WAS JUST HELD UP.
THEY'RE OUT THERE.
THEY GOT GUNS!
GUNS?
MY BUDDIES
ARE OUT THERE.
WHERE ARE THEY?
THAT GREEN WRECK.
EXCUSE ME.
COULD YOU BACK UP?
I NEED TO GET
SOME UNLEADED.
BACK UP.
[DING! DING!]
AAH!
THAT'S MY WAGON!
BACK UP.
♪ COSMIC ♪
♪ I WAS HAVING
THIS OUT-OF-BODY EXPERIENCE ♪
♪ OF ALL THESE
COSMIC THINGS ♪
♪ EVERYWHERE
I WENT UP THERE ♪
♪ THEY WERE SHAKIN'
THEIR COSMIC THINGS ♪
♪ LIKE SOMEONE GAVE YOU
A WILD GOOSE ♪
♪ OR A FREIGHT TRAIN
WITH A LOOSE CABOOSE ♪
♪ YOU BETTER SHAKE YOUR ♪
♪ HONEY BUNS ♪
♪ SHAKE YOUR HONEY BUNS... ♪
WE ARE
PARTY MARTIANS!
WE ARE MTV SCUM!
♪ SHAKE
THAT COSMIC THING ♪
♪ SHAKE THAT THING ♪
♪ SHAKE IT ♪
♪ SHAKE ♪
♪ SHAKE THAT THING
ALL NIGHT LONG ♪
♪ SHAKE IT FAST,
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG ♪
♪ DON'T LET IT REST
ON THE PRESIDENT'S DESK ♪
♪ ROCK THE HOUSE ♪
♪ COSMIC ♪
♪ WOO, COSMIC ♪
♪ COSMIC, WOO... ♪
HEY!
THAT LOOKS GREAT!
♪ SHAKE IT ♪
♪ COSMIC ♪
HEY, GUYS!
BRUNCH IS READY.
COME AND GET IT.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HEY, VALERIE.
IT'S WOODY.
HI.
LISTEN,
YOU KNOW YOUR FRIENDS?
THOSE FINLAND GUYS?
WE WERE HEADING
TO THE BEACH--
WHAT? THEY'RE GONE?
THEY'RE WITH YOU?
NO. THEY WERE.
THEY KIND OF ROBBED
THE MINI MART
WHEN I WASN'T LOOKIN',
THEN THEY TOTALED
THE GAS STATION,
THEN THEY RIPPED OFF
MY VAN!
I'M AT THE MINI MART
DOWN THE STREET.
TOYS 'R' US.
THAT'S IT?
YOU SEEN ZEEBO
AND WIPLOC?
I GOT WATER
IN HERE.
MAYBE THAT'S
ONE OF THEM.
SURE?
NOT REALLY.
GOOD ENOUGH
FOR ME.
SO LOOK--
UH!
WHAT'S GOING ON?
WOODY!
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
I GOTTA GO NOW,
VALERIE.
I'M GETTIN'
MY BUTT KICKED.
♪ WELL, IF YOU PLAN
TO MOTOR WEST ♪
♪ TRAVEL MY WAY ♪
♪ TAKE A HIGHWAY
THAT'S THE BEST ♪
♪ AND GET YOUR KICKS ♪
♪ ON ROUTE 66... ♪
AAH!
♪ WELL, IT WINDS ♪
♪ FROM CHICAGO TO L.A. ♪
♪ MORE THAN 2,000 MILES ♪
♪ ALL THE WAY ♪
♪ GET YOUR KICKS ♪
♪ ON ROUTE 66 ♪
WIPLOC!
♪ WELL, IT GOES
TO ST. LOUIS ♪
♪ DOWN TO MISSOURI ♪
♪ OKLAHOMA CITY,
IT'S OH, SO PRETTY ♪
♪ YOU'LL SEE ♪
♪ AMARILLO ♪
♪ GALLUP, NEW MEXICO ♪
♪ FLAGSTAFF, ARIZONA,
DON'T FORGET WINONA ♪
♪ KINGMAN, BARSTOW,
SAN BERNADINO ♪
♪ WON'T YOU GET HIP
TO THIS TIMELY TIP? ♪
AAH!
♪ AND YOU'LL TAKE
THAT CALIFORNIA TRIP ♪
OH!
♪ GET YOUR KICKS
ON ROUTE 66 ♪
[SIRENS]
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT
TO REMAIN SILENT.
ANYTHING YOU SAY
CAN AND WILL
BE USED...
HEY!
JAIL ISN'T SO BAD.
IT'S WHERE I LEARNED
HOW TO SURF.
HE'S DEAD MEAT.
YOU HANG 10 NOW.
YOU'VE GOT TO
BELIEVE ME.
THIS IS ALL
A MISUNDERSTANDING.
SORRY.
THEN ARREST ME.
YEAH.
STAY OUT OF THIS,
FLIPPER.
YOU DIDN'T
DO ANYTHING.
HEY, LADY!
DON'T DO THAT!
PARAMEDIC UNIT 104.
WE PICKED UP
TWO VICTIMS
FITTING THE DESCRIPTION
OF THE MINI MART
ROBBERY SUSPECTS.
TAKING THEM TO
OUR LADY OF THE VALLEY HOSPITAL.
10-13. COPY.
THAT'S TED'S HOSPITAL.
WE HAVE TO GET THERE.
JOE...
TAKE US
TO HOSPITAL, PLEASE.
HEY, CLOWN,
YOU'RE GOING TO
THE SLAMMER.
WE GO
TO SLAMMER FIRST.
GIVE THEM
THAT LOVE TOUCH,
THEN THEY'LL
COME ON TO ME.
THEY'LL BE PUTTY
IN MY HANDS.
YOU WANT SEX
WITH JOE AND MIKE?
NO. JUST SO WE
CAN GET AWAY. DO IT.
HEY!
HOW ABOUT
THOSE LAKERS, HUH?
WHAT ABOUT
THOSE INCREDIBLE EYES OF YOURS?
WHAT?
THEY'RE JUST THIS FAR
FROM LIZ TAYLOR
VIOLET.
OH, MICHAEL!
JOSEPH.
TWO NEW PATIENTS
IN EMERGENCY...
DR. LOVE.
♪ IT'S THE SUMMER
OF LOVE, LOVE, LOVE ♪
♪ I'M IN LOVE
WITH LOVE, LOVE, LOVE ♪
♪ FOR EVERYONE
TRANSCENDS HERE ♪
♪ I'M THINKING OF YOU ♪
♪ BOY ♪
BYE, YOU GUYS.
THANKS FOR THE LIFT.
I HOPE THINGS
WORK OUT.
BYE.
HAPPY HOUSE HUNTING.
CIAO.
THANK YOU
VERY MUCH.
THEY'RE SUCH
A NICE COUPLE.
BYE.
TOTALLY COOL, TIM.
RIDE COOL RIPS
ALL THE WAY IN.
GREAT.
YOU TWO.
HI, DR. DUDE.
THE PARTY'S OVER.
SETTLE DOWN.
TAKE US
TO VALERIE'S HOUSE.
YOU'RE NOT SETTING FOOT
IN MY HOUSE AGAIN.
WE'RE LOOKING
FOR TWO PATIENTS
WHO WERE
JUST ADMITTED.
THAT'S KIND OF
A NASTY BUMP.
DOES THIS HURT?
AAH!
GOOD.
LET'S JUST HAVE
A LISTEN HERE, SHALL WE?
SURF'S UP.
LEAVE IT ALONE.
BREATHE.
[THUMP THUMP]
AGAIN.
WAIT A SECOND.
BREATHE.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
IT'S AMAZING.
YOU EACH...
HAVE TWO HEARTBEATS.
WIPLOC AND ZEEBO?
WHAT ARE
THEIR LAST NAMES?
THEY DON'T HAVE
LAST NAMES.
THEY'RE PERFORMERS
LIKE...CHER.
OH!
YES. THEY'RE IN
THE EMERGENCY ROOM
BEING EXAMINED
BY DR. GALLAGHER.
OH! HE'LL
DISSECT THEM.
YOU CAN'T GO IN THERE.
MEDICAL PERSONNEL ONLY.
WE'VE GOT TO
GET IN THERE.
I HAVE AN IDEA,
BUT IT MEANS
DOING SOMETHING TERRIBLE
TO AN INNOCENT PERSON.
LET'S DO IT.
WHICH FLOOR?
TWO, PLEASE.
I THINK I'M GOING TO
ENJOY THIS.
FEEL THIS?
IT'S A GUN.
WHAT--
SHUT UP. WALK.
COME IN HERE.
HELP. SHE'S GOT
A GUN.
TAKE OFF
YOUR UNIFORM.
WHAT?
TAKE IT OFF!
QUICK!
I KNOW YOU.
YOU'RE TED'S GIRLFRIEND.
STRIP.
I DON'T WANT ANY PART
OF YOU, TED,
OR YOUR KINKY
SEX TRIPS.
STRIP!
SHE SAID STRIP.
THE CALL BUTTON.
PUSH THE CALL BUTTON.
NUH-UH.
YOU'LL GO TO PRISON
FOR THIS...
EXCUSE ME.
FOR MOLESTING ME,
FOR HAVING A GUN--
IT'S NOT REAL.
YOUR HEART...
EXCUSE ME, DOCTOR.
THIS DOCTOR'S
HERE TO PICK UP THESE PATIENTS.
THESE GUYS AREN'T
GOING ANYWHERE.
I'M ADMITTING THEM
FOR OBSERVATION.
THEY SEEM OK
TO ME.
NURSE, LISTEN
TO THEIR HEARTS,
AND TELL ME WHAT
YOU HEAR.
♪ COVER OF TIME
MAGAZINE ♪
♪ MAN OF THE YEAR ♪
♪ YES, I'LL BE
RICH AND FAMOUS ♪
I'LL BE ON
THE TODAY SHOW.
Shh, Zeebo.
It's me.
HE SOUNDS
PERFECTLY NORMAL TO ME, DOCTOR.
OH, NO.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
THEY EACH HAVE
TWO DISTINCT HEARTBEATS.
TRY ME, DOCTOR.
YES.
I COULD TRY YOU.
THUD! THUD! THUD!
OH, MY GOD!
YOU, TOO.
[DING! DING! DING!]
[BEEP! BEEP!
BEEP! BEEP!]
IT'S MY BEEPER!
NO. MY BEEPER'S NEVER
DONE THIS BEFORE.
[RING]
GET THE PHONE.
WHAT PHONE,
DOCTOR?
HELLO?
DOCTOR, I'M AFRAID
YOU MUST BE
HEARING THINGS.
[RUFF RUFF RUFF]
YODEL-AYDI...
[NEIGH]
YODEL-AY-HEE-HOO!
IS THERE SOMETHING
WRONG, DOCTOR?
OH, HELLO, DOCTOR.
SHOULD I CALL YOU
A DOCTOR, DOCTOR?
MAKE IT STOP!
I CAN'T STAND IT.
[RING!]
[THUD! RING!]
[THUD! THUD!]
YOU GUYS,
YOU CAME THIS CLOSE
TO BEING
A SCIENCE PROJECT.
COME ON.
TED'S CAR! FOLLOW ME.
QUICK! GET IN QUICK!
OH! OH, GOD!
HERE COMES TED!
HIDE!
GET DOWN AND HIDE.
VALERIE?
SWEETHEART, I'M
SO GLAD TO SEE YOU.
CAN WE GO HOME?
THESE LAST TWO DAYS
HAVE BEEN HELL.
SWEETHEART, I ACTUALLY THINK
I'VE BEEN HEARING THINGS.
OH, VAL,
COULD YOU DRIVE?
PLEASE, VALERIE.
OK, TED.
HERE.
GET IN, HONEY.
I'M EXHAUSTED.
I THOUGHT
ABOUT WHAT YOU SAID.
I'VE DECIDED
TO DO SOMETHING IMPULSIVE.
LET'S GO TO VEGAS TONIGHT
AND GET MARRIED.
TONIGHT?
WHAT ABOUT THE CHURCH
AND MY DRESS?
WE CAN DO THE BIG
CHURCH WEDDING LATER.
WELL...
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
I DON'T KNOW...
I'M JUST SO SURPRISED.
COME ON.
YOU WANTED SURPRISES.
TED.
[LOVE STORY THEME PLAYS]
YOU GOT TO BRING
THAT ONE-PIECE
NIGHT THING,
THAT, UH, CORSET
THAT LOOKS
LIKE UNDERWEAR.
WHAT IS IT NOW?
SOMETHING OLD...
OH! THESE PANTYHOSE
ARE OLD.
SOMETHING NEW.
THIS VEIL IS NEW.
DR. TUSHMAN, PLEASE.
HEY, BARBARA, TED HERE.
LISTEN, UH, I NEED
A REALLY BIG FAVOR.
I WANT YOU
TO COVER MY SHIFT
AT THE HOSPITAL TOMORROW.
I'M GOING TO VEGAS.
WELL, I'M GOING TO...
LOSE A LITTLE MONEY,
TAKE IN A SHOW,
AND GET MARRIED.
BARBARA.
BARBARA--
LOOK, JUST BECAUSE
I'M GETTING MARRIED
DOESN'T MEAN WE CAN'T DATE,
ALL RIGHT?
WHAT?
[SPEAKING ALIEN LANGUAGE]
VALERIE.
GOOD-BYE.
BYE.
NICE PLANET
YOU HAVE HERE.
GIVE TANYA MY NUMBER.
TAKE CARE, ZEEBO.
AW, WIPLOC.
I THINK I'LL MISS YOU
LEAST OF ALL.
YOU GOT LIPLOCK
FOR WIPLOC?
VALERIE...
I DON'T KNOW
THE WORDS.
OH, MAC.
I'M GOING TO
MISS YOU SO MUCH.
I'LL MISS YOU, TOO.
SWEETHEART, I BOOKED
THE CAVE MAN SUITE
AT CUPID'S LODGE.
WHAT THE HELL
IS THIS?
OK, TED,
THEY'RE NOT A BAND.
THEY'RE FROM
ANOTHER PLANET.
GO BACK IN THE HOUSE.
I'LL BE IN SOON.
OH, MY GOD!
THEY'RE ALIENS.
ALIENS!
GOT YOU COVERED.
IT'S OK.
TED. TED. IT'S OK.
YOU'RE CONTAMINATED.
I--I HAVE
TO GO NOW.
TED!
I'LL CALL THE POLICE.
TED...
I GOTTA GO.
STOP IT.
GOOD-BYE, VALERIE.
MAC!
IT DIDN'T WORK!
I HAVE TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
I LOVE YOU!
TAKE ME WITH YOU!
TO JHAZALLA?
ANYPLACE!
I AM MR. RIGHT?
YES!
WELL, UH...
GOOD-BYE, TED.
UM, I GUESS
IT WASN'T MEANT TO BE,
BUT, UH, I REALLY
WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR, UM...THANKS
FOR THE, UH...
GOOD-BYE, TED.
MAC!
WAIT, YOU GUYS!
YOU CAN'T LEAVE
WITHOUT MARGARITAS!
VALERIE,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
GOOD-BYE, CANDY.
I'LL MISS YOU.
WELL, GOOD LUCK, VAL.
CALL ME.
[MEOW]
HAPPY TRAILS.
BAMBI, I NEVER KNEW.
WAIT!
HEY!
GIVE MY LOVE
TO FINLAND!
OH! OH! HA HA HA!
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ START A LOVE TRAIN,
LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL
OVER THE WORLD ♪
♪ ALL OVER THE WORLD,
JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ START A LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN, LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ FIRST STOP
THAT WE'LL MAKE ♪
♪ WILL BE ENGLAND ♪
♪ TELL ALL THE FOLKS
IN RUSSIA ♪
♪ AND CHINA, TOO ♪
♪ GET ON BOARD ♪
♪ DON'T YOU KNOW ♪
♪ IT'S TIME
TO GET ON BOARD ♪
♪ TIME TO GET ON BOARD ♪
♪ LET THE TRAIN
KEEP ON RIDIN' ♪
♪ RIDIN' ON THROUGH ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ JOIN YOUR HANDS ♪
♪ AND START A LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY ♪
♪ GET ON THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ ALL OF YOUR BROTHERS ♪
♪ OVER IN AFRICA ♪
♪ COME ON NOW, PEOPLE ♪
♪ TELL ALL THE FOLKS
IN EGYPT ♪
♪ AND ISRAEL, TOO ♪
♪ PLEASE DON'T MISS
THIS TRAIN ♪
♪ AT THE STATION ♪
♪ 'CAUSE IF YOU MISS IT ♪
♪ I FEEL SORRY,
SORRY FOR YOU ♪
♪ SORRY, OH, FOR YOU ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ START A LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ SISTERS AND BROTHERS ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ COME ON ♪
♪ START THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ GET ON BOARD ♪
♪ WELL, YEAH ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ JOIN YOUR HANDS ♪
♪ AND START A LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY ♪
♪ GET ON THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ HEY ♪
♪ FIRST STOP
THAT WE'LL MAKE ♪
♪ WILL BE ENGLAND ♪
♪ TELL ALL THE FOLKS
IN RUSSIA ♪
♪ AND CHINA, TOO ♪
♪ GET ON BOARD ♪
♪ DON'T YOU KNOW ♪
♪ IT'S TIME
TO GET ON BOARD ♪
♪ AND LET THIS TRAIN
KEEP ON RIDIN' ♪
♪ RIDIN' ON THROUGH ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY ♪
♪ AND START A LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ JOIN THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON, COME ON ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY ♪
♪ GET ON THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ YEAH ♪
♪ GET ON BOARD ♪
♪ HEY ♪
♪ WELL, YEAH ♪
♪ NEW YORK,
ARE YOU IN THE HOUSE? ♪
♪ L.A., ARE YOU
IN THE HOUSE? ♪
♪ MOTOR CITY,
ARE YOU IN THE HOUSE? ♪
♪ EVERYBODY ♪
♪ MIAMI,
ARE YOU IN THE HOUSE? ♪
♪ START A LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ ALL OVER THE WORLD
JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ GET ON ♪
♪ ATLANTA ♪
♪ GET ON THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ D.C. ♪
♪ ALL OVER THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY ♪
♪ EVERYBODY
GET ON THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ GET ON THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ AND START A LOVE TRAIN,
LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ EVERYBODY ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ COME ON, COME ON,
COME ON, COME ON ♪
♪ GET ON THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ COME ON, PEOPLE, NOW ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ AND START A LOVE TRAIN,
LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ ALL OVER THE WORLD ♪
♪ PEOPLE ALL OVER
THE WORLD ♪
♪ JOIN HANDS ♪
♪ COME ON, BOYS AND GIRLS,
JOIN THE LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ LOVE TRAIN ♪
♪ DON'T NEED NO TICKET ♪