(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(BIRD CALLING)
(DOGS BARKING)
(CROWS CAWING)
(ROOSTER CROWING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(FIDDLE PLAYING)
TEVYE: A fiddler on the roof.
Sounds crazy, no?
But here in our
little village of Anatevka,
you might say
every one of us
is a fiddler on the roof,
trying to scratch out
a pleasant, simple tune
without breaking his neck.
It isn't easy.
You may ask,
"Why do we stay up there
"if it's so dangerous?"
We stay because
Anatevka is our home.
And how do we keep our balance?
That I can tell you in one word.
Tradition!
(TRADITION PLAYING)
Because of our traditions,
we've kept our balance
for many, many years.
(DUCK QUACKING)
Here in Anatevka,
we have traditions for everything.
How to sleep, how to eat,
how to work,
how to wear clothes.
For instance,
we always keep our heads covered
and always wear a little prayer shawl.
This shows our constant
devotion to God.
You may ask,
"How did this tradition get started?"
I'll tell you.
I don't know.
But it's a tradition.
And because of our traditions,
every one of us knows who he is
and what God expects him to do.
(SQUAWKING)
(EXCLAIMING)
And in the circle of our little village
we've always had our special types.
For instance,
Yente, the matchmaker,
Reb Nachum, the beggar.
(CHUCKLING)
And, most important of all,
our beloved rabbi.
Rabbi, may I ask you a question?
Certainly, Leybish.
Is there a proper blessing for the Tsar?
A blessing for the Tsar? Of course.
May God bless and keep the Tsar
far away from us.
(ALL LAUGHING)
TEVYE: Then there are
the others in our village.
They make a much bigger circle.
We don't bother them,
and, so far, they don't bother us.
And among ourselves,
we always get along perfectly well.
Of course, there was the time
when he sold him a horse
and told him it was only six years old
when it was really 12.
But now it's all over,
and we all live
in simple peace and harmony.
It was really 12 years old.
It was six.
Tevye knows it was 12.
(ALL ARGUING)
Twelve!
It was 12!
(SINGING TRADITION)
(HUMMING)
Traditions, traditions.
Without our traditions,
our lives would be as shaky as...
As...
As a fiddler on the roof.
(LAMB BLEATING)
Mama, Mama!
Yente, the matchmaker, is coming.
Maybe she's finally found
a good match for you, Tzeitel.
From your mouth to God's ears.
Why does she have to come now?
It's almost Sabbath.
Out, all of you.
I want to talk to Yente alone.
But, Mama, the men she finds.
The last one was so old and he was bald.
He had no hair.
A poor girl without a dowry
can't be so particular.
You want hair, marry a monkey.
Even a poor girl without a dowry
has to look at her husband sometime.
A husband is not to look at.
A husband is to get.
But, Mama, I'm not yet 20 years old.
I don't think I have...
Do you have to boast about your age?
Do you want to tempt the evil eye?
(TUT-TUTTING)
Out, all of you. There's work to be done
before the Sabbath.
Hurry. All of you, hurry.
(HENS CLUCKING)
(COW MOOING)
Golde. Golde.
I have such news for you.
And not "every day in the week" news.
"Once in a lifetime" news.
Such diamonds, such jewels.
I'll find a husband
for every one of them,
but you shouldn't be so picky, right?
Of course "right," because after all,
even the worst husband, God forbid,
is better than no husband,
God forbid.
And who should know better than me?
Ever since my husband died,
I've been a poor widow.
All alone, no one to talk to,
nothing to say to anyone.
All I do at night is think of him.
And even thinking of him
gives me no pleasure.
Is Tzeitel in the house?
Why don't you go in and find out?
Thank you, Bielke.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
YENTE: He never raised his voice.
Good afternoon. Is Tzeitel in the house?
She's busy. Come back later.
But there's something
I'd like to tell her.
Later.
Later?
All right.
What does that poor, skinny tailor
want with Tzeitel?
They have been friends
since they were babies.
They talk, they play.
They play. What do they play?
I don't know. They're children.
From such children come other children.
Motel is nothing.
Yente.
Yente, you said you had news for me.
Children, children.
They are your blessing in your old age.
But my Aaron, may he rest in peace,
couldn't give me children.
To tell you the truth, Golde,
he hardly tried.
But what's the use complaining?
Other women enjoy complaining,
not Yente.
Not every woman in the world is a Yente.
Well, I...
I have to go home now
to prepare my poor Sabbath meal.
So goodbye, Golde,
and it was a pleasure
talking our hearts out to each other.
Yente, you said you had news for me.
Oy, I'm losing my head.
Someday it'll fall off altogether,
and a horse will kick it in the mud,
and "Goodbye, Yente."
Of course, the news.
It's about Lazar Wolf, the butcher.
A good man. A fine man.
And I don't have to tell you
he's well-off, no?
Yes.
But he's lonely, the poor man.
After all,
he's been a widower all these years.
You understand. Of course you do.
So, to make it short.
Out of the whole town,
he's cast his eye on Tzeitel.
My Tzeitel?
No, the Tsar's Tzeitel.
Of course your Tzeitel.
Such a match for my Tzeitel.
But... But Tevye wants a learned man.
He doesn't like Lazar.
Good, so Lazar won't marry him.
He wants the daughter, not the father.
Listen. Listen to me, Golde.
You send Tevye to him.
Don't tell him what it's about.
Let Lazar discuss it himself.
He'll win him over.
He's a good man and a wealthy man.
So, you'll let me know how it went.
And you don't have to thank me, Golde,
because aside from my fee,
which Lazar will pay anyway,
it gives me satisfaction
to make people happy.
True? Of course, "true."
So goodbye, Golde, and you're welcome.
Goodbye, Yente.
Come, come, children,
get changed for the Sabbath.
Hurry. Hurry with your work.
I wonder if Yente
found a husband for you.
I'm not anxious for Yente
to find me a husband.
Not unless it's Motel, the tailor.
I didn't ask you.
Tzeitel, you're the oldest.
They have to make a match for you
before they can make one for me.
And then after her, one for me.
- So if Yente...
- Yente, Yente, Yente.
Well, somebody has to arrange
the matches.
Well, she might
bring someone wonderful.
Someone interesting.
- And well-off.
- And important.
(SINGING MATCHMAKER)
Since when are you interested
in a match, Chava?
I thought you just had
your eye on your books.
And you have your eye
on the rabbi's son.
Well, why not?
We only have one rabbi.
And he only has one son.
Why shouldn't I want the best?
Because you're a girl
from a poor family,
so whatever Yente brings, you'll take.
Right? Of course, "right."
(GROANING)
(QUACKING)
(SIGHING)
Dear God,
was that necessary?
Did you have to make him lame
just before the Sabbath?
That wasn't nice.
It's enough you pick on me,
bless me with five daughters,
a life of poverty. That's all right,
but what have you
got against my horse?
Really,
sometimes I think
when things are too quiet up there,
you say to yourself,
"Let's see. What kind of mischief
"can I play on my friend Tevye?"
So you're finally here, my breadwinner.
I'll talk to you later.
So why are you late today?
His foot went lame.
Well, hurry up. The sun won't wait.
And I have something
important to say to you.
I still have some deliveries
in the village.
You'll be late for the Sabbath.
I won't be late.
You'll be late.
I won't be late!
If you ever stop talking,
You can die from such a man.
As the Good Book says,
"Heal us, O Lord,
and we shall be healed."
In other words,
send us the cure.
We've got the sickness already.
(COW MOOING)
(LAMB BLEATING)
Well, I'm not really complaining.
After all, with your help,
I'm starving to death.
Dear Lord,
you made many, many poor people.
I realize, of course,
it's no shame to be poor,
but it's no great honor, either.
(SIGHS)
So, what would have been so terrible
if I had a small fortune?
(SINGING IF I WERE A RICH MAN)
(SQUAWKING AND CLUCKING)
(NEIGHS)
(SIGHING)
(SCREAMING)
(COW MOOING)
Tevye, Tevye, where's your horse?
Well, he decided to take the day off.
Have a good Sabbath.
Thank you, Your Honor, thank you.
Thank you.
- MAN 1: Tevye, you're late.
- MAN 2: Tevye, hey!
Where's your horse?
It's almost the Sabbath.
MAN 3: Tevye,
you have kept us all waiting.
MAN 4: What happened to your horse?
Look at this!
Look what it says in the paper.
- Look, look, look.
- MAN 5: What's the matter, Avram?
Quiet!
Quiet! Stop braying like a pack of mules
and let a man talk. Talk, Avram.
Well, my paper came
to the post office today
like it does every week.
Though usually it comes on a Thursday,
- but sometimes...
- Avram, that's not talking.
That's babbling.
- Tell us the news.
- What does it say?
Quiet!
Talk, Avram.
Well, I was reading my paper.
It's nothing very important.
A story about the crops in the Ukraine
and this and that.
Avram, talk.
And then, I saw this.
All right.
We all see it.
What does it say?
"In a village called Rajanka,
"all the Jews were evicted,
"forced to leave their homes."
For what reason?
It doesn't say.
Maybe the Tsar wanted their land.
Maybe a plague.
May the Tsar have
his own personal plague!
- Amen!
What's the matter with you?
Why don't you ever bring us
some good news?
It's not my fault.
I only read it.
"An edict from the authorities."
May the authorities grow like onions
with their heads in the ground.
- Amen!
PERCHIK: What good
will your cursing do?
You stand around,
you curse, and you chatter,
and you don't do anything.
You'll all chatter your way
into the grave.
Excuse me.
You're not from this village.
PERCHIK: No.
Where are you from?
Kiev.
I was a student in the university there.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
The university.
Tell me,
is that a place where you learned
how not to respect your elders?
That is where I learned
there is more to life than talk.
You should know
what's going on in the outside world.
Careful, my paper.
Why should I break my head
about the outside world?
Let the outside world
break its own head.
Well put.
He's right. As the Good Book says,
"If you spit in the air,
it lands in your face."
Nonsense.
You can't close your eyes
to what's happening in the world.
He's right.
He's right and he's right?
They can't both be right.
You know, you are also right.
He is right.
He's too young to wipe his own nose.
Good Sabbath, Tevye.
University!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
- Here. Good Sabbath.
- Good Sabbath, Tevye.
Good Sabbath.
Tevye, Tevye.
Oh, yeah. I'm sorry. I apologize.
Here.
- Good Sabbath.
- Tevye, the rabbi's order.
Of course.
So you are from Kiev, Reb...
- Perchik.
So you are a newcomer here?
As Abraham said,
"I'm a stranger in a strange land."
Moses said that.
Forgive me. Forgive me.
As King David said,
"I'm slow of speech and slow of tongue."
That was also Moses.
For a man with a slow tongue,
he talked a lot.
Here, Reb Perchik.
Have a piece.
I have no money, and I'm not a beggar.
Take it. It's a blessing for me to give.
Very well.
For your sake.
Thank you. Thank you.
You know, it's no crime to be poor.
In this world it is the rich
who are the criminals.
Someday their wealth will be ours.
That would be nice.
If they would agree, I would agree.
And who will make this miracle
to come to pass?
People. Ordinary people.
Like you?
Like me.
TEVYE: And until your golden day
comes, Reb Perchik,
how will you live?
By giving lessons to children.
Do you have any children?
I have five daughters.
Five?
Daughters!
PERCHIK: Girls should learn, too.
Girls are people.
- A radical!
- Go away.
I'd be willing to teach them.
Open their minds to great thoughts.
Yeah?
I'd like them to know the Good Book.
Well, the Bible has many lessons
for our times.
Perchik,
I'm a very poor man,
but food for lessons, huh?
Good. Good.
Stay with us for the Sabbath.
Of course, we don't eat like kings,
but we don't starve, either.
As the Good Book says,
"When a poor man eats a chicken,
"one of them is sick."
Where does the book say that?
All right. All right.
It doesn't exactly say that,
but someplace it has something
about a chicken.
- Good Sabbath.
Good Sabbath.
TZEITEL: Do you really
think Yente found someone?
HODEL: I don't know.
TEVYE: Good Sabbath, children.
ALL: Good Sabbath, Papa.
Children, this is Perchik.
Perchik, this is my eldest daughter.
- Good Sabbath.
You have a pleasant daughter.
I have five pleasant daughters.
- This is mine.
- Good Sabbath.
- And this is mine.
- Good Sabbath, Papa.
And this is mine.
And this...
Well, this is not mine.
Perchik, this is Motel Kamzoil.
So, you did us a favor and came home.
Well, this is also mine.
Golde, Golde, this is Perchik from Kiev.
He'll be staying the Sabbath with us.
He is a teacher.
Would you like
to take lessons from him?
- Yes, Papa.
- Good.
I'm a very good teacher.
I heard once that the rabbi
who must praise himself
has a congregation of one.
(LAUGHING)
Your daughter has
a quick and witty tongue.
Yeah, the wit she gets from me.
As the Good Book says...
The Good Book can wait. Get washed.
This tongue she gets from her mother.
Motel, you're also eating with us?
- If...
- Of course. Another blessing.
Tzeitel, Tzeitel, get the small table.
And, Chava, the two chairs from outside.
Children, finish dressing.
You can wash at the well.
- Oh, thank you.
- Hurry, Hodel, help him. Hurry.
Hurry. It's almost the Sabbath. Hurry!
Tevye.
Tevye, I have something to say to you.
Why should today be different?
Tevye, I have something to tell you.
- Tzeitel, I have something to tell you.
- Motel,
- Yente was here.
- I know. I saw her.
If they agree on someone,
there will be a match,
and then it will be too late for us.
But, Tzeitel, I have found someone who
will sell me his used sewing machine.
So maybe in a few weeks
I'll have saved up enough to buy it.
- And then your father...
- A few weeks might be too late.
Lazar Wolf wants to see you.
The butcher? What is it about?
I don't know,
only he says it's important.
What can be important?
I have nothing for him to slaughter.
After the Sabbath,
see him, talk with him.
Talk about what?
If he is thinking about buying
my new milk cow,
he can forget it.
Tevye, I want you to talk...
(PRAYING IN HEBREW)
Tevye.
Tevye, I want you to talk to...
What else can I do?
You could ask my father
for my hand tonight.
Now.
Why should he consider me now?
I'm only a poor tailor.
And I'm only the daughter
of a poor milkman.
Just talk to him.
Tzeitel, if your father says no,
that's it. It's final.
- He'll yell at me.
- Motel.
I'm just a poor tailor.
Motel, even a poor tailor
is entitled to some happiness.
That's true.
(PRAYING)
Amen.
A man sends you an important message,
at least you can talk to him.
- I don't want to talk to...
- Talk to him!
All right!
After the Sabbath, I'll talk to him.
All right. I'll talk to him.
Well, it's getting late.
Where is everybody?
I don't know, Papa.
Children! Come down, children!
We are lighting the candles. Children!
- Reb Tevye.
- Not now, Motel.
Hurry up, children! Hurry up.
- Reb Tevye.
- Not now, Motel.
TEVYE: Golde.
Golde, the sun is almost down.
- Reb Tevye.
- What is it?
Reb Tevye.
- Yes? Yes?
- Reb Tevye.
- I...
Well, Motel, what is it?
Good Sabbath, Reb Tevye.
Good Sabbath. Good Sabbath.
Hurry up.
GOLDE: Hurry, children.
Hurry. It's getting late.
Hurry.
(CUTLERY RATTLING)
(SINGING THE SABBATH PRAYER)
TEVYE: Is Reb...
Is Reb Lazar Wolf at home?
He's in the back.
May I...
Come in.
Thank you. Thank you.
(CLOCK TICKING)
(EXHALING)
And all this from
killing innocent animals.
Don't touch anything.
All right.
(DOOR OPENS)
Well, Tevye.
You're here.
Well, sit down, sit down.
- Thank you, thank you.
- Yeah.
Have a drink.
I won't insult you by saying no.
(LAUGHING)
Well,
how goes it with you, Reb Tevye?
How should it go?
You're right.
And you?
The same.
I'm sorry to hear that.
How is your brother-in-law
in America?
He's doing very well.
- He wrote you?
- No, not lately.
Then how do you know?
If he was doing badly, he would write.
(LAUGHING)
- L'chaim.
- Tevye.
- Yeah?
I suppose you know
why I wanted to see you.
Oh, yes, I do,
but there is no use talking about it.
Tevye, I understand how you feel,
but, after all,
you have a few more without her.
I see.
Today you want one.
Tomorrow you may want two.
Two? What...
What would I do with two?
The same as you do with one.
Tevye.
This is very important to me.
Why is it so important to you?
Frankly,
because
I'm lonely.
Lonely?
Reb Lazar,
what are you talking about?
How can a little cow keep you company?
Little cow?
Is that what you call her?
What else should I call her?
That's what she is.
- Reb Lazar, what are you talking about?
- Don't you know?
Of course I know.
We are talking about my new milk cow,
the one you want to buy from me.
A milk cow?
A milk cow so I won't be lonely?
(LAUGHING)
I'm... I'm talking about
your daughter.
Your daughter, Tzeitel.
My daughter, Tzeitel?
Of course. Your daughter, Tzeitel.
I see her every Thursday
in my butcher shop,
and she's made
a very good impression on me,
a very good impression.
Reb Tevye,
I like her.
Why don't we just shake hands
and call it a match?
And
I'll be good to her.
Tevye.
I...
I like her.
Well?
What do you think?
What do I think?
I never really liked him.
Why should I?
You can have
a fine conversation with him
if you talk about kidneys and livers.
On the other hand,
not everyone has to be a scholar.
And with a butcher,
my daughter
will surely never know hunger.
Maybe I misjudged him.
He's a good man.
He likes her.
And he'll try to make her happy.
What do I think?
It's a match.
- You agree?
- I agree.
Tevye, you've made me a happy man.
- Good.
- Let's drink on it.
Why not?
To you.
No, my friend. To you.
To the both of us.
- To our agreement.
To our prosperity.
To our good health and happiness.
And most important of all...
(GRUNTING)
Well...
(SINGING TO LIFE)
LAZAR: Bartend!
Yes? What is it?
Drinks for everyone!
What's the big occasion?
I'm taking myself a bride!
Who's the lucky one?
Tevye's eldest, Tzeitel!
(ALL CHEERING)
Thank you.
(MEN WHISTLING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
I like it!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
Drinks for everybody!
Mazel tov!
To life!
(MEN CHATTERING)
Tevye.
Tevye,
after
the marriage
we will be
- related.
- Yeah?
You
will be my
papa.
Your papa?
Lazar Wolf,
I always wanted a son.
But I wanted one
a little younger than myself.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- LAZAR: Good night.
- TEVYE: Good night.
I hear that congratulations
are in order, Tevye.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Thank you.
Tevye.
(TEVYE LAUGHING)
Yes, Your Honor.
I have this piece of news
I think I should tell you as a friend.
Yes, Your Honor.
I'm giving you this news
because I like you.
You're an honest, decent person,
even though you are a Jew.
Thank you, Your Honor.
How often does a man get
a compliment like that?
And the news?
We have received orders
that sometime soon
this district is to have
a little unofficial demonstration.
What?
A pogrom?
- Here?
- No, no, no, no.
Just a little unofficial demonstration.
Little?
How little?
Not too serious.
Just some mischief,
so that if an inspector comes through,
he can see that we did our duty.
Personally, I don't know why
there has to be this trouble
between people,
but I thought I should tell you.
Thank you, Your Honor.
You are a good man.
If I may say so,
it's too bad you are not a Jew.
That's what I like about you, Tevye.
You're always joking.
Congratulations again for your daughter.
Thank you, Your Honor.
About the other matter,
it won't be too bad.
I wouldn't worry.
TEVYE: Yeah, of course not.
Dear God,
did you have to send me news like that
today of all days?
I know, I know.
We are the chosen people.
But once in a while,
can't you choose someone else?
Anyway,
thank you for sending a husband
for my Tzeitel.
L'chaim.
(FIDDLE PLAYING)
PERCHIK: Now,
after Jacob had worked
for Laban for seven years,
do you know what happened?
Laban fooled him
and gave him his ugly daughter Leah.
So to marry Rachel,
Jacob was forced to work
another seven years.
So you see, children,
the Bible clearly teaches us
you can never trust an employer.
GIRL: And that is what
the Bible teaches us?
That is the lesson
of the story of Jacob,
if you interpret it correctly.
Is your papa up yet?
No, Mama.
Enough lessons!
Back to the house.
There's work to be done.
Go on, children.
Another story tomorrow.
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
That was a very
interesting lesson, Perchik.
Do you think so?
Although I don't know
if the rabbi would agree
with your interpretation.
Neither, I suppose,
would the rabbi's son.
My little sisters talk too much.
And what do you know about him
except that he is the rabbi's son?
At least I know this,
he doesn't have any strange ideas
about turning the world upside down.
Good day, Perchik.
You have wit,
even a little intelligence.
- Thank you.
- Perhaps.
But what good is your brain?
Without curiosity, it is a rusty tool.
Good day, Hodel.
We have an old custom here.
A boy talks respectfully to a girl.
But, of course, that is too traditional
for an advanced thinker like you.
"Our traditions."
"Nothing must change."
"Everything is perfect
exactly the way it is."
We like our ways.
Our ways are changing all over but here.
Do you know that in the city
boys and girls can be affectionate
without the permission
of a matchmaker?
They hold hands together.
They even dance together.
New dances. Like this.
I learned it in Kiev.
You like it?
It's... It's very nice.
There.
We've just changed an old custom.
Yes.
I mean, thank you.
I mean,
good day!
(GROANING)
(GROANS)
- So, my prince is finally out of bed.
- Oh, God! Not now. Not now.
- Open your eyes. The day's half gone.
- Go away!
Well?
Well, what happened last night
besides your drinking like a peasant?
Did you see Lazar Wolf?
Well?
Well, what did he say?
What did you say?
Where...
- Where... Where is Tzeitel?
- She's in the barn.
- In the barn.
- Do you have news for me?
- Did you talk with Lazar Wolf?
- Oh, the other way.
Well, what happened?
Patience, woman, patience.
As the Good Book says,
"Good news will stay,
"and bad news will refuse to leave."
And there is another saying that goes...
You can die from such a man.
Did you see Lazar?
- Was it friendly?
- Shah, woman, shah!
Are you still drunk, or what?
Here she is.
Tzeitel, my lamb, come here.
You are to be congratulated.
You are going to be married.
GOLDE: Married?
What do you mean, Papa?
(TEVYE CHUCKLING)
Lazar Wolf has asked for your hand.
I knew it!
The butcher?
GOLDE: Oh, dear God, I thank thee.
I thank thee!
Why do you have to...
What do you have to say, Tzeitel?
What can she say?
Let her say one word.
My firstborn, a bride.
May you grow old with him,
in fortune and honor.
Not like Fruma Sarah,
that first wife of Lazar's.
She was a bitter woman.
May she rest in peace.
Not like my Tzeitel.
And now, I must thank Yente.
My Tzeitel, a bride.
A bride, I thank thee.
I thank thee!
- A bride! A bride!
- Well, Chava?
Mazel tov, Tzeitel.
"Mazel tov, Tzeitel"?
What kind of a mazel tov is that?
And you, Reb Perchik,
aren't you going to congratulate her?
Congratulations, Tzeitel.
For getting a rich man.
Ah!
Again with the rich.
What's wrong with being rich?
It's no reason to marry.
Money's the world's curse.
May the lord smite me with it,
and may I never recover!
World's curse.
My Tzeitel knows
I mean only her welfare.
Am I right, Tzeitel?
- Yes, Papa.
- There, you see?
I see.
I see very well.
Well, my child,
why are you so silent?
Aren't you happy with this blessing?
Papa.
- Papa.
- What is it? Tell me.
Papa, I don't want to marry him.
I can't marry him. I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
If I say you will,
you will.
Papa, if it's a matter of money,
I'll do anything.
I'll hire myself out as a servant.
- Just, I don't...
- But we made an agreement!
And with us,
an agreement is an agreement.
Is that
more important than I am, Papa?
Papa, don't force me, please!
I'll be unhappy all my days!
(SOBBING)
- I don't want to marry him.
- All right.
All right.
I won't force you.
Thank you, Papa, thank you.
"Thank you, Papa."
It seems
it was not ordained
that you should have
all the comforts of life.
(HENS SQUAWKING)
(PANTING)
Reb Tevye, may I speak to you?
Later, Motel, later.
But I would like to speak to you.
Not now, not now. I have problems.
That's what I want
to speak to you about.
I think I can help.
Certainly,
like a bandage can help a corpse.
Goodbye, Motel, goodbye.
At least listen to him, Papa.
All right. You have a tongue, talk.
Reb Tevye, I hear you are arranging
a match for Tzeitel.
He also has ears.
Well,
I have a match for Tzeitel.
What kind of a match?
A perfect fit.
- Like a glove.
- A glove.
This match was made
exactly to measure.
"Perfect fit, made to measure."
Motel, stop talking like a tailor
and tell me who is it?
Please don't shout at me, Reb Tevye.
All right, all right, I won't shout.
I shall not shout.
Who is it?
It's me.
Myself.
(LAUGHING)
It's him.
Himself.
Either you're out of your mind
or you're crazy.
He must be crazy!
Arranging a match for yourself?
Tell me what are you, everything?
The bridegroom, the matchmaker,
the guests, all rolled into one?
I suppose you'll even
perform the sermon yourself.
Please don't shout at me, Reb Tevye.
Now, as for being my own matchmaker,
I know it's a little unusual.
Unusual? It's crazy!
Times are changing, Reb Tevye.
The thing is, over a year ago,
your daughter Tzeitel
and I gave each other
our pledge that we would marry.
You gave each other a pledge?
Yes, Papa.
We gave each other our pledge.
They gave each other a pledge.
Unheard of, absurd.
(SINGING TEVYE'S MONOLOGUE)
Where does it stop?
Do I still have something
to say about my daughter?
Or doesn't anyone
have to ask a father anymore?
I've wanted to ask you
for some time, Reb Tevye,
but first I wanted to save up enough
for my own sewing machine.
- So we'd have...
- You stop talking nonsense.
You are just a poor tailor!
That's true, Reb Tevye.
But even a poor tailor
is entitled to some happiness.
I promise you, Reb Tevye,
your daughter will not starve.
He is beginning to talk like a man.
On the other hand,
what kind of a match would that be,
with a poor tailor?
On the other hand,
he is an honest, hard worker.
But on the other hand,
he has absolutely nothing.
On the other hand,
things could never get worse for him.
They could only get better.
They gave each other a pledge.
Unheard of, absurd.
Well, children,
when shall we make the wedding?
Thank you, Papa!
Reb Tevye,
you won't be sorry.
You won't be sorry.
- I won't be sorry?
- No.
I'm sorry already!
Thank you, Papa.
All right. All right.
Papa.
(LAUGHING)
They gave each other a pledge.
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
Golde.
What shall I tell Golde?
(TZEITEL LAUGHING)
TZEITEL: Motel, you were wonderful!
It was a miracle!
(SINGING MIRACLE OF MIRACLES)
(LAUGHING)
WOMAN: Good day.
Hello, Sarah.
Mazel tov, Chava. Mazel tov!
- Thank you.
- Soon it will be you.
- I hope so.
- Give my best wishes to Tzeitel.
- I will.
- Mazel tov! Mazel tov!
MAN: Mazel tov, Chava.
ALL: Mazel tov.
(ALL CHATTERING)
CHAVA: Please, no, don't, I...
Please, I just want to get by.
FYEDKA: All right, stop it.
What's wrong with you, Fyedka?
- Just stop it.
- We're just having
a little fun, Fyedka.
Goodbye, Sasha.
I said, goodbye.
(WHISTLING)
(ALL CHATTERING)
I'm sorry about that.
They mean no harm.
Don't they?
Is there something you want?
Yes. I'd like to talk to you.
I'd rather not.
I've often noticed you
at the bookseller's.
Not many girls in this village
like to read.
Would you like to borrow this book?
It's very good.
No.
Thank you.
Why?
Because I'm not Jewish?
Do you feel about me
the way they feel about you?
I didn't think you would.
And what do you know about me?
Let me tell you about myself.
I'm a pleasant fellow.
Charming,
honest,
ambitious,
quite bright,
and very modest.
Go ahead.
Take the book,
and after you return it,
I'll ask you how you like it,
and we can talk about it for a while.
Then we can talk about life,
how we feel about things.
Here.
Thank you.
Good day, Chava.
Good day.
Fyedka.
- Help!
- Tevye.
Help! Help! Help!
Tevye, what's the matter with you?
Motel... Tzeitel... Help!
Wake up! What is the matter with you?
Wake up!
Where is she?
- Where? Where? Who?
- Where is she?
Where is who?
What are you talking about?
Fruma Sarah, Fruma Sarah,
Lazar Wolf's first wife.
She was standing here a minute ago.
What are you talking about?
Fruma Sarah has been dead for years.
- You must have been dreaming.
- Yes. Yes.
- Shah. Shah.
- Yes.
Now,
tell me what you dreamt,
and I'll tell you what it meant.
It was terrible.
- Tell me.
- All right.
Only don't be frightened!
In the beginning,
I dreamt that
we were having
a celebration of some kind.
Everybody we knew,
all of our beloved departed,
were there.
All of them.
Even your great uncle Mordechai
was there,
and your cousin Rachel was there.
And in the middle of the dream,
in walks your grandmother Tzeitel,
may she rest in peace.
GOLDE: Grandmother Tzeitel!
How did she look?
TEVYE: Well, for a woman
who's dead 30 years,
she looked very good.
Naturally, I went up to greet her.
(SINGING TEVYE'S DREAM)
Motel?
Tailor? She must've heard wrong.
She meant the butcher.
I'll tell her.
- Stop it!
- We announced it already.
We made a bargain with the butcher.
Stop it.
Listen to me!
But he is a butcher!
Tell them!
His name is Lazar Wolf!
(EXCLAIMING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
Here she comes.
(SCREAMING)
Tevye!
(BELL TOLLING)
Shah!
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
(HOWLING)
Jump!
GOLDE: Evil spirit, away!
Such an evil spirit.
May it sink back into the earth.
(TUT-TUTTING)
Such a dark and horrible dream.
And to think it was brought on
because you went to see that butcher.
Tevye, Tevye,
my grandmother Tzeitel,
may she rest in peace,
took the trouble to come
all the way from the other world
to tell us about the tailor.
All I can say is that it's for the best
and couldn't possibly be any better.
- But, Golde...
- Amen.
Amen.
Do you like these troublemakers,
these Christ killers?
Of course not.
I just meant
that things have been peaceful here.
I have other villages to visit.
If you don't want to follow orders,
we shall get someone else who will.
No, no, no, no, sir.
I'll take care of it, of course.
(LAUGHING)
(DRUMS BEATING)
(BAND PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MAN: Quiet down!
Quiet down!
(SINGING SUNRISE, SUNSET)
MAN: Quiet down!
Quiet down!
(EXCLAIMING)
MAN: Quiet down!
(CROWD CHEERING)
It was beautiful. Really beautiful.
Take your places, everybody.
Quiet!
- Quiet!
- Quiet down!
Quiet down!
The newlyweds,
friends.
We are gathered here
to share in the joys
of the newlyweds, Motel and Tzeitel.
May they live together
to a ripe old age.
Amen.
- Amen.
And now I want to say...
(MUMBLING)
Reb Nachum!
Please! Not here!
Now I'd like to announce
that the bride's parents
are giving the newlyweds the following.
A new feather bed,
two pillows...
Goose pillows.
Goose pillows,
a Sabbath tablecloth,
and a pair of candlesticks.
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL APPLAUDING)
MAN: Quiet!
Now.
We are just here on earth
for a short visit.
Even the great and wealthy must die.
In fact,
if the rich could hire others
to die for them,
we, the poor,
would all make a nice living.
Well put.
Lazar Wolf.
Talking about the rich.
There sits our good friend Lazar Wolf.
Lazar has everything in the world
except a bride.
(ALL LAUGHING)
But
Lazar has no ill feelings.
In fact, he told me
that he has a gift for the newlyweds
that he himself wants to announce.
Come on, Lazar. Come on.
Just like he said,
I have no ill feelings.
What's done
is done.
I am giving the newlyweds
five chickens,
one for each of the first five Sabbaths
of their wedded life.
Reb Lazar Wolf,
you are a decent man,
and on behalf of my daughter
and her new husband...
Sit down.
I accept your gift.
There is a famous saying that...
Reb Tevye,
I am not marrying your daughter.
I don't have to listen to your sayings.
Why, if you would only listen
for one moment.
Why should I listen to you?
A man who breaks an agreement!
I have a right to talk!
What right? It's not your wedding.
It should have been!
But it's not, thank goodness.
Don't shame Reb Tevye
at his daughter's wedding.
He shamed me
in front of the whole village.
- He shamed me!
- Praise God, he did.
(SHOUTING)
Rabbi, say something.
I say...
Yeah.
I say, let's sit down.
Yes, yes. Well,
we all heard the words of the rabbi.
Let's sit down.
Now I'm going to sing a little song.
(SINGING)
I don't want that. Leave me alone.
You can keep your diseased chickens!
You leave my chickens out of this!
We made a bargain!
But the terms weren't settled.
We drank on it!
You just sit down, all right?
Once a butcher, always a butcher.
Once a liar, always a liar.
You just sit down, all right?
Those happen to be my chickens.
That man...
I had a sign!
Quiet, I'm singing.
Quiet! Quiet!
What's all the screaming about?
"They drank on it."
"An agreement."
"A sign."
It's all nonsense.
Tzeitel wanted to marry Motel
and not Lazar.
A young girl decides for herself?
Why not? They love each other.
MAN 1: Love? Terrible.
MAN 2: He's a radical.
MAN 3: Musicians, play.
It's a dance. Everybody dance.
It's a wedding.
WOMAN: Some wedding.
- What is he doing?
- Perchik!
Who will dance with me?
Obscene.
- That's a sin!
- It's no sin to dance at a wedding.
- But with a girl?
- Yes, with a girl.
That's what comes
of taking a wild man into your house.
He is not a wild man.
His ideas are
a little bit different, but...
Perchik, come over here.
- Come over here.
- It's a sin.
It's no sin. Ask the rabbi.
- Go on, ask him.
- Ask the rabbi!
(CROWD MURMURING)
TEVYE: Well, Rabbi?
- Dancing?
- Yeah.
Well, it's not exactly forbidden, but...
Well, there you see!
It's not forbidden.
And it's no sin.
Now, who will dance with me?
MAN: He's asking her to dance.
Hodel!
It's only a dance, Mama.
Play!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Say something.
(CROWD GASPING)
- GOLDE: Tevye?
- She's dancing with a man!
I can see that
she is dancing with a man!
And I'm going to dance with my wife!
Tevye!
Mama, no.
Golde! Golde!
Golde!
Motel!
- No. I will not.
- Tzeitel!
Motel!
See that?
You are responsible for that,
and I can't stand it!
I tried my best.
Everybody, dance!
Look.
It's all right. Dance, Rabbi, dance.
(NEIGHING)
(SHOUTING)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
TEVYE: Perchik!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
MAN: All right! Enough!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
I said, enough!
Come!
Orders are orders, understand?
Well,
why are you all standing around?
Clean up!
(CRASHING)
(MEN LAUGHING)
(TRADITION PLAYING)
TEVYE: Troubles, troubles.
That's all you hear from me, right?
But who else can we simple people
take our troubles to?
You know, sometimes I wonder,
who do you take your troubles to?
(GRUNTING)
Go away.
Anyway,
Motel and Tzeitel have been married
for some time now.
They work very hard.
And
they are as poor as squirrels in winter.
But they're so happy
they don't know how miserable they are.
(SIGHING)
Motel keeps talking about
a sewing machine.
I know.
You are very busy now.
Wars, revolutions, floods, plagues.
All those little things
that bring people back to you.
But couldn't you take a second
and get him his sewing machine?
Yeah, and while you are
in the neighborhood,
as you can see, my horse's leg is...
Am I bothering you too much?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
As the Good Book says...
(LAUGHING)
Why should I tell you
what the Good Book says?
So you must go away?
Yes.
But so soon?
Tomorrow morning.
Alone?
No. With a few friends,
and, of course, we'll be joining others.
- Where?
- In the city. Kiev.
Hodel,
there are some things
I cannot tell even you.
I see.
Please don't be upset.
Why should I be upset?
If you must leave, you must.
I do have to.
Couldn't you have told me?
Great changes are about to take place
in this country.
Tremendous changes.
But they can't happen by themselves.
So, naturally,
you feel that you personally have to...
Not only me, many people, Jews,
Gentiles.
Many people hate what's going on.
Don't you understand?
I understand. Of course.
You want to leave.
Then, goodbye.
Hodel, listen to me.
I have work to do.
The greatest work a man can do.
Don't you understand?
Yes, Perchik.
Hodel.
Hodel!
Hodel, wait!
Hodel, there's a question,
a certain question
I wish to discuss with you.
Yes?
It's a political question.
What is it?
The question of marriage.
Is this a political question?
Well, yes.
Yes, everything's political.
Well, like everything else,
the relationship between
a man and a woman has
a socioeconomic base.
Marriage must be founded on
mutual beliefs,
a common attitude
and philosophy towards society.
And affection.
Well, yes, of course.
That is also necessary.
Such a relationship
can have positive social values.
When two people face the world with
unity and solidarity.
And affection.
Yes, that is an important element.
At any rate, I...
I personally am in favor of such a
socioeconomic relationship.
I think
you are asking me to marry you.
Well,
in a theoretical sense,
yes, I am.
I was hoping you were.
(LAUGHING)
I'm very happy, Hodel.
I'm very, very happy.
(CART RATTLING)
(LAUGHING)
- Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon, Reb Tevye.
I have some bad news.
What?
I must leave here.
When?
Tomorrow morning.
I'm sorry to hear that, Perchik.
We'll all miss you.
But I also have some good news.
Good.
You can congratulate me.
Congratulations. What for?
We are engaged.
Engaged?
Yes, Papa. We're engaged.
No, you're not.
I know you like him, and he likes you,
but you're going away,
and you're staying here.
So have a nice trip, Perchik.
And I hope you'll be very happy,
and my answer is no.
Please, Papa. You don't understand.
I understand, I understand.
I gave my permission
to Motel and Tzeitel,
so you feel you also have a right.
I'm sorry, Perchik. I like you.
But you're going away,
so go in good health.
And my answer is still no.
You don't understand, Papa.
And you are not listening. I said no.
Reb Tevye,
we are not asking for your permission,
only for your blessing.
We are going to get married.
You are not asking for my permission?
But we would like your blessing, Papa.
I can't believe my own ears.
My blessing? For what?
(SINGING)
Where has it led? To this!
A man tells me he is getting married.
He doesn't ask me. He tells me!
But, first, he abandons you.
He is not abandoning me, Papa.
As soon as I can,
I will send for her and marry her.
I love her.
He loves her.
Love!
It's a new style.
On the other hand,
our old ways were once new,
weren't they?
On the other hand,
they decided without parents,
without a matchmaker.
On the other hand,
did Adam and Eve have a matchmaker?
Yes.
They did.
And it seems these two
have the same matchmaker.
They're going over my head.
Unheard of, absurd.
Tradition!
Well, children, I have decided
to give you
my blessing and my permission.
Thank you, Papa.
What else could I do?
"Thank you, Papa"?
What am I going to tell your mother?
Another dream?
Perhaps if you tell her
that I'm going to visit a rich uncle.
Perchik.
Please. I can handle my own wife.
TEVYE: Golde.
Golde!
Golde...
Hmm?
Hello, Golde.
Have some soup.
Golde,
I have something very important
to tell you.
Have the soup.
It's warm.
Golde,
I've just met
Perchik and Hodel.
Well?
Well...
Well, they seem to be
very fond of each other.
So? What do you mean?
So...
So I've decided
to give them my permission
to become engaged.
- I'll eat later.
- What?
Just like that? Without even asking me?
Who asks you?
I am the father.
Who is he?
A pauper!
He has nothing, absolutely nothing.
(LAUGHING)
I wouldn't say that.
I hear he has a rich uncle.
A rich uncle!
Golde.
Golde, he is a good man.
I like him.
He's a little crazy, but I like him.
And
what's more important,
Hodel likes him.
Hodel loves him.
So, what can we do?
It's a new world, Golde.
A new world.
Love.
Golde?
Do you love me?
Do I what?
(SINGING DO YOU LOVE ME?)
Maybe it's indigestion.
No, Golde,
I'm asking you a question.
You're a fool.
I know.
Well?
Golde.
And now I'm asking, Golde.
I'm your wife.
I know.
Well?
I suppose I do.
(HORSE CARRIAGE RATTLING)
(MAN SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
Halt.
(MAN SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
PERCHIK: There is no authority
above the will of the people,
and we are the people.
We are Russia!
(CROWD CHEERING)
The time has come, and the time is now.
Now we stand here before you, not one,
but many.
Many like you.
Students, workers,
striving for a better life.
And I urge you, fellow workers,
to band together with us.
Join our movement.
In the factories!
(CROWD CHEERING)
In the schools!
In the army!
(CROWD CHEERING)
The winds of freedom
are beginning to blow all over Russia.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Halt.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
PERCHIK: Wait! Wait! Stand!
Come back!
Wait! Wait, fellow workers.
Don't let them break up our meeting.
We have our rights!
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
YENTE: So I found a girl...
Good day to you, Esther.
She didn't like her. Just a minute.
Tzeitel. Tzeitel.
Good day, Yente.
Tzeitel, I happened to stop
in the post office today
to say hello, see what's what.
It doesn't cost anything to be friendly.
So few people are like that.
Yeah, yeah.
People.
I tell you, Tzeitel,
if God lived on Earth,
people would break his windows.
So you went to the post office?
Yes, and the postman told me
there was a letter there
for your sister, Hodel.
Thanks. I'll go get it.
I got it.
It's from her intended, Perchik.
Hodel will be so happy.
She's been waiting
to hear from him for...
But it's open.
So it happened to be open.
You don't have
to wait for the train, Papa.
You'll be late for your customers.
That's all right.
They will just have to wait for a while.
Is he in bad trouble,
that hero of yours?
Arrested?
Convicted?
Yes, but he did nothing wrong.
He cares nothing for himself.
Everything he does is for other people.
Yes, but if he did nothing wrong,
he wouldn't be in trouble.
Oh, Papa. How can you say that?
What wrongs did Joseph do?
And Abraham and Moses?
And they had troubles.
Yes, but...
But why won't you tell me
where he is now,
this Joseph of yours?
It is far, Papa.
Terribly far.
He is in a settlement in Siberia.
Siberia?
And he asks you
to leave your father and mother
and join him in that frozen wasteland
and marry him there?
No, Papa.
He did not ask me to go.
I want to go.
I don't want him to be alone.
I want to help him in his work.
Hodel.
Papa.
(SINGING FAR FROM THE HOME I LOVE)
(TRAIN WHISTLING)
And who, my child,
will there be to perform a marriage
there in the wilderness?
Papa, I promise you,
we will be married under a canopy.
Yes, yes.
Yes.
(COUGHING)
No doubt a rabbi or two
were also arrested.
(CONDUCTOR BLOWING WHISTLE)
Papa!
God alone knows
when we shall see each other again.
Then,
we will leave it in his hands.
(TRAIN WHISTLING)
Take care of her.
See that she dresses warm.
(RABBI SPEAKING HEBREW)
Even though
she only burned his cooking,
he is permitted to divorce her.
MAN: Just for supper?
Yes, yes, yes.
(ALL CHATTERING)
I'm sorry, Rabbi.
Yes, of course.
What news of the outside world, Avram?
It's terrible, Rabbi. Terrible.
Then don't tell me.
If I want bad news,
I'll read about Noah and the flood.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Tell me, Avram,
surely somewhere
there are good things happening?
Can't you buy a paper
that prints those things?
It's not my fault, Rabbi.
I only read it.
Rabbi, Rabbi, did you hear the news?
More bad news?
No, good news!
At Motel's and Tzeitel's,
a new arrival.
A new arrival at Motel's and Tzeitel's?
I'm so excited!
I must congratulate them!
- It's wonderful.
- So cute!
We just heard the good news. Mazel tov!
MOTEL: Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much.
- It's a nice thing.
- MOTEL: Yes, it is.
- Very nice.
- MOTEL: Thank you.
What is it?
MOTEL: It's a sewing machine.
WOMAN: It's a sewing machine.
- MOTEL: It can work twice as fast.
- Hey.
TZEITEL: You got it!
I got it!
- It's beautiful.
- MOTEL: I know.
Have you tried it yet?
Look.
- Beautiful.
- I know.
And in less than a minute.
See how close and even
the stitches are?
- It's beautiful.
- I know.
From now on,
my clothes will be perfect.
Made by machine.
No more handmade clothes.
(BELL RINGING)
Look, Mama. Look!
Oh!
It's wonderful.
Mazel tov, Motel!
The rabbi!
The rabbi! The rabbi!
Rabbi, is there a blessing
for a sewing machine?
There is a blessing for everything.
(PRAYING IN HEBREW)
- Amen.
That's your new arrival?
What is it, a boy or a girl?
(ALL CHATTERING)
Yankeleh.
(LAUGHING)
Why isn't he asleep?
Oh, Mama, but he's wonderful.
He never cries or...
Shah! Do you want to invite bad luck?
Well...
Well, Motel,
I never thought
you'd amount to anything.
But look at you,
a baby and a sewing machine.
You're a person.
Look, I'll show you how it works.
Go, children.
Come here.
- Go, children.
- First you put the cloth in like this.
It's an amazing thing.
You work it
with your foot and your hand.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Your father is coming.
Chava, let me talk to him.
Let me tell him about us.
No, Fyedka. That would be
the worst thing. I'm sure of it.
- But let me try.
- No.
I'll talk to him.
I promise.
Good afternoon, sir.
Good afternoon.
It's... It's a cold day, isn't it?
Mmm.
Well,
good day, sir.
Good day, Chava.
Good day.
What were you and he talking about?
Nothing. We were just talking.
Good.
Papa.
Fyedka and I,
we've known each other
for a long time now and...
Chaveleh,
I would be much happier
if you would remain friends
from a distance.
You must not forget who you are
and who that man is.
He has a name, Papa.
Of course.
All creatures on earth have a name.
Fyedka is not a creature, Papa.
Fyedka is a man.
Who says he isn't?
It's just that he
is a different kind of man.
As the Good Book says,
"Each shall seek his own kind."
In other words, a bird may love a fish,
but where would they build
a home together?
The world is changing, Papa.
No, Chaveleh.
No.
Some things do not change for us.
Some things will never change.
We don't feel that way.
We?
Fyedka and I.
We want to be married.
What, are you out of your mind?
What?
Don't you understand what that means,
marrying outside of the faith?
- But, Papa...
- No!
I said, no!
Never talk about it again.
Never mention his name again.
Never see him again.
Never.
Do you understand me?
Yes, Papa.
I understand you.
You're finally here.
Let's go home. It's late for supper.
I want to see Motel's new machine.
You'll see it another time.
It's getting late.
Quiet, woman, before I get angry!
Because when I get angry,
even flies don't dare to fly!
I'm very frightened of you.
After we finish supper, I'll faint.
Golde!
I am the man in the house!
I am the head of the family!
And I want to see
Motel's new machine now!
(BELL RINGING)
Now, let's go home.
What are you doing here?
What do you want?
May I see his honor, the priest?
The reverend father?
Yes.
Why do you want to see him?
It's a family matter.
A personal matter.
My daughter.
Yes. What about your daughter?
Please, if I could speak with the...
If I could speak
with the reverend father.
Please.
Wait here.
GOLDE: Tevye!
Tevye!
What is it?
It's Chava.
She left home this morning
with Fyedka.
What?
I've looked everywhere for her.
I even went to the priest.
He told me they were married.
Married?
Yes.
Well.
Go home, Golde.
We have other children at home.
You have work to do.
I have work to do. Go home.
But Chaveleh?
Chava is dead to us.
We'll forget her.
Go home.
Go home, Golde.
Home.
(SINGING CHAVELEH)
Papa?
Papa!
Papa, I've been looking
everywhere for you.
Papa, stop!
At least listen to me.
Papa.
I beg you to accept us.
Accept them?
How can I accept them?
Can I deny everything I believe in?
On the other hand,
can I deny my own daughter?
how can I turn my back on my faith,
my people?
If I try and bend
that far,
I'll break.
On the other hand...
No.
There is no other hand.
No, Chava!
No!
- But, Papa...
- No! No!
Papa!
No!
(SOBBING)
YENTE: Golde,
here they are.
The boys I told you about.
Wonderful boys, Golde.
From good families.
Each of them a prize, a jewel.
You couldn't do better for your girls.
I don't know, Yente.
My girls are still so young.
So, what do they look like,
grandfathers?
True. The marriage can wait,
but, meanwhile, their future
will be all signed and sealed.
GOLDE: Which one for which one?
YENTE: What's the difference?
Take your pick.
They're both wonderful boys.
Yankel, the little, fat one
is apprenticed to a carpenter.
- I'm Yankel.
- Did I ask you?
Yankel, the skinny one,
is apprenticed...
Mama, is Reb Tevye in the house?
He's in the barn.
Is there trouble?
Stay inside, children.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
GOLDE: What is it? What's the matter?
Tevye. Tevye,
have you seen the constable lately?
TEVYE: No. Why?
There are some rumors in town.
We thought since you knew him so well,
maybe he told you
what is true and what is not.
Rumors?
What rumors?
Quiet!
Talk, Avram.
Someone from Zolodin told me
there was an edict issued
in St. Petersburg that all...
TEVYE: Welcome, Your Honor.
What's the good news in the world?
I see that you have company.
They are my friends.
It's just as well.
What I have to say
is for their ears also.
Tevye, how much time
do you need to sell your house
and all your household goods?
Why should I sell my house?
Is it in anybody's way?
I came here to tell you that you
are going to have to leave Anatevka.
And how did I come
to deserve such an honor?
Not just you, of course,
but all of you.
MAN 1: What?
What do you mean?
MAN 2: Why?
Listen to me!
At first, I thought
you might be spared, Tevye,
because of the marriage
of your daughter.
My daughter is dead.
I understand.
At any rate, it affects all of you.
You have to leave.
But...
But this corner of the world
has always been our home.
- Yes.
- MAN: Yes.
Why should we leave?
I don't know why.
There's trouble in the world.
Troublemakers.
Like us?
You aren't the only ones.
Your people must leave all the villages.
Zolodin, Rabalevka.
The entire district must be emptied!
(ALL CHATTERING)
I have an order here!
It says that you must sell your homes
and be out of here in three days.
MAN 1: How? Three days!
That's impossible!
- MAN 2: What about the children?
- Three days?
And you,
you who have known us all your life,
you'd carry out this order?
I've nothing to do with it!
Don't you understand?
I wish you wouldn't say me!
I understand.
And suppose we refuse to go?
You will be forced out!
We will defend ourselves.
- We'll stay in our homes!
- Refuse to leave!
- We won't fall.
- We will keep our land!
- Yes.
- Fight!
Against our militia, our army?
I wouldn't advise that.
I have some advice for you.
Get off my land.
This is still my home,
my land.
Get off my land.
You have three days!
After a lifetime,
a piece of paper and get thee out.
We should get together
with the people of Zolodin.
Maybe they have a plan.
We should defend ourselves!
An eye for an eye
and a tooth for a tooth!
Very good.
That way the whole world
will be blind and toothless.
Rabbi,
we've been waiting
for the Messiah all our lives.
Wouldn't this be
a good time for him to come?
We'll have to wait
for him someplace else.
Meanwhile,
let's start packing.
Well, Anatevka hasn't exactly been
the Garden of Eden.
That's true.
After all, what have we got here?
(SINGING ANATEVKA)
(SIGHING)
It's just a place.
And our forefathers
have been forced out
of many, many places
at a moment's notice.
Maybe that's why
we always wear our hats.
(PRAYING IN HEBREW)
Golde!
Golde, darling!
I had to see you before I left.
Because I have such news for you.
You remember, Golde,
yesterday I told you
I didn't know where to go,
what to do with these old bones?
Now I know.
You want to hear? I'll tell you.
All my life, I've dreamed
of going to one place.
Guess where?
No, you'll never guess.
Every year at Passover, what do we say?
Next year in Jerusalem.
Next year in the Holy Land.
You're going to the Holy Land.
You guessed.
Goodbye, Yente.
Be well,
- and go in peace.
- Yeah.
And so goodbye, Golde.
And sometime maybe we'll meet
on a happier occasion.
Meanwhile, we suffer.
We suffer.
We suffer in silence.
Right? Of course, right.
Where are you going?
You don't know where you're going?
Come, Golde, we have to leave.
Leave. It sounds so easy.
Golde, we'll all be together soon.
Motel, Tzeitel, and the baby,
they'll come, too.
You'll see.
This Motel is a person.
And Hodel and Perchik?
When will we ever see them again?
Do they come visiting us
from Siberia every Sabbath?
You know what she writes.
He sits in prison,
she works.
But soon,
he will be set free,
and together they'll
turn the world upside down.
She couldn't be happier.
And the other children
will be with us.
Not all.
All!
Come, Golde.
I have to clean up.
Sweep the floor.
TEVYE: Sweep the floor?
I don't want to leave a dirty house.
Tevye!
Tevye.
I'm
on my way.
Where are you going?
Chicago.
In America.
Chicago, America?
We are going to New York, America.
We'll be neighbors.
My wife Fruma Sarah,
may she rest in peace,
- has a brother there.
- That's nice.
I hate him!
But
- a relative is a relative.
- Yes.
- Goodbye, Tevye.
- Goodbye, Lazar Wolf.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(COW MOOING)
(LAMB BLEATING)
Well, my old friends,
it's time to say goodbye.
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(WHISTLING)
The farmer Bushenko
will be coming for you later.
He is not a bad sort.
If you are good to him,
he'll be good to you.
Take care of your leg.
Thanks for everything.
Chava.
- Papa will see you.
- I want him to.
I want to say goodbye to him.
He won't listen to you.
But at least he will hear.
Maybe it would be better if I told Mama.
Chaveleh!
CHAVA: Papa.
Papa.
We came to say goodbye.
We are also leaving this place.
We are going to Krakow.
FYEDKA: We cannot stay among people
who can do such things to others.
We wanted you to know that.
FYEDKA: Some
are driven away by edicts,
others by silence.
Goodbye, Papa.
Mama.
FYEDKA: Come, Chava.
Goodbye, Chava.
Fyedka.
And God be with you.
We will write to you in America,
if you like.
GOLDE: We will be staying
with Uncle Avram.
Yes, Mama.
We'll be staying with Uncle Avram.
The whole world has
to know our business.
Stop yelling and finish packing!
We have a long way to go.
Golde,
I don't need your advice.
Tzeitel, don't forget the baby.
TZEITEL: Goodbye, Papa.
(BABY CRYING)
Work hard, Motel.
And come to us soon.
I will, Papa.
I'll work hard.
All right, children.
Let's go.
(WIND HOWLING)
(RABBI PRAYING IN HEBREW)
(FIDDLE PLAYING)