Whoa, lordy!
Wooo, wow!
Lemme outa here! Oh feet, do yo' stuff.
Wu-huh! Wu-huh! Woooow!
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Panting]
[Upbeat instrumental music]
[Rock music]
Going down down down
How far can you go?
You might fall into the Forbidden Zone
Going round round round
Driving me insane
Everything looks different
but nothing has changed
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
Living in the Sixth Dimension
Things get rough
can be tough
It's so hard when you're on your own
When you're on your own
Going down down down
How far can you go?
You might fall into the Forbidden Zone
Going down down down
Cross the border line
The guards look scary
But the girls are pretty fine
Okay! I'm a-going down, I'm a-going down,
I'm a-going down
I know
Turnin' me around, turnin' me around,
turnin' me around,
I know
Thank you very much
for that delicious breakfast.
It was absolument superbe!
[Groans in disgust]
I'd like to chat with you longer...
however, I regret that
Flash and I have to hurry along to school.
As I am a new student,
I don't want to make a bad impression.
Yeah. The principal, Mr. Yodlebein,
sent out bulletins to all the classrooms...
and he said that if anybody's gonna be late,
they're gonna be punished.
Oh, children, don't be late for school.
And, Flash, be sure you tie
your grandfather up...
and check the knots real good.
While he was sniffing around
for food yesterday...
he nearly wandered into the Forbidden Zone.
The Forbidden Zone?
Qu'est-ce que c'est que ça, alors?
What are you ever talking about?
Squeezit Henderson's got a brother
that dresses like a broad.
And he took us down into the basement...
and showed us those funny games,
you know, like the adults play...
and he went through a door,
and he never came out.
A door leading to the Sixth Dimension?
How strange, yet intriguing.
Just imagine the adventurous world
beyond that door.
You don't ever...
You don't ever,
you don't ever....
[Comical instrumental music]
[Singing]
Behind them doors
You don't go through
That is one thing
You do not do
Sin and evil
That's what you'll find
You'll meet two baldheaded devils
there with wild sex on their minds
The King and Queen
of that terrible underworld
They capture and torment
all the little sweet young girls
You can't be serious, Pa,
It sounds like heaven! Ha! Ha! Ha!
I think I'll move there,
you stupid, silly father
[Jazzy instrumental music]
Stay away from that door,
my little daughter
You'll miss yer daddy
You'll miss yer mama
One of these days
You'll be sad and lonely
Some of these days, Laday la hey
You're gonna be so lonely
Some of these days
You're gonna want me only
You'll miss my lovin', miss my kissin'
You're gonna miss your little daddy
When you goes away
You'll be so lonely
For me only, you know, baby
Why I went away
Oh, when I'm leavin'
You don't know
About how your heart be grievin'
You'll miss your little daddy, mama
Some of these days
[Jazzy music continues]
[Singing nonsensically]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Women screaming]
[Women screaming continues]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
Holy cow. It's ten to 9:00.
Come on, Gramps, we gotta tie you up now.
FRENCHY: Oh, la, la, we'll be late for school.
[Singing]
Beautiful dreamer
Come unto me
[speaking Pig Latin]
Ewww! Squeezit Henderson.
Will you get a load of that jerk, will you?
Ewww!
Hey, Frenchy, you got a Kleenex?
I got something stuck in my throat.
No, sorry.
[Slow instrumental music]
SQUEEZIT: Hi, Flash. Hi, Frenchy.
FLASH: How you doing, man?
Flash told me that you have a twin brother
that disappeared behind the door...
in our basement.
It's not my brother, it's my sister.
FLASH: It's your brother, he only acts
like a broad. He's a faggot.
You're the faggot.
Do you think
you'll ever see your sister again?
You know, I think I've accomplished
astral projection with my sister.
FLASH: Ah, banana oil.
Formidable, alors! How fascinating.
You'll have to tell me everything about it.
Well, last night,
my mother was punishing me again...
and I begged her to stop hurting me,
but she wouldn't.
And finally the pain got so intense
and unbearable that I felt like I was dying...
and leaving my body,
and then I had this vision of my sister...
that was so real, I could see her as clearly
as I'm looking at both of you right now.
[Humming]
[Humming continues]
[Singing]
I kept rubbin',
rubbin' on the darned old thing
Ow! Ow! Ow!
FAUSTO: Don't push your luck, Henderson.
Chérie.
Fausto, 1,000 years...
and for some reason,
I just can't get enough of you.
[Soft instrumental music]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Everything got black. I must've fainted.
How amazing.
FRENCHY: And she disappeared
in our own basement.
In your own basement.
Well, so long, Squeezit.
Come on, Sis,
Miss Feldman will mark us tardy.
Come on, Squeezit,
we're going to be late for class.
[Bell ringing]
[Students shouting]
JOHNNY: You fucking kid!
You motherfucking kid!
JOHNNY: I told you not to do that,
you motherfucker.
JOHNNY: I'll kill you, you son of a bitch.
JOHNNY: You fucking bitch.
You motherfucker.
I'll kill you, you fucking bitch.
[Gun shots firing]
Squeezit Henderson, please come forward,
and lead us in the Pledge of Allegiance.
[Grunting]
[All laughing]
[Mimicking cock crowing]
Class, we have a new student.
Flash's sister Susan will come and tell us
of her studies in France.
[Upbeat instrumental music]
[Singing in French]
Le soir on cause d'un tas de choses
Avant de se mettre au pieu
J'apprends la géographie
De la Chine et de la Mandchourie
Les frontières, les rivières
Le Fleuve Jaune et le Fleuve Bleu
Y a meme l'amour c'est curieux
Qu'arrose l'Empire du Milieu
C'est moi qui suis sa petite
Son Anana, son Anana, son Anammite
Je suis vive, je suis charmante
Comme le petit oiseau qui chante
II m'appelle sa petit bourgeoise
Sa Tonkiki, sa Tonkiki, sa Tonkinoise
D'autre lui font les doux yeux
Mais, c'est moi qu'il aime le mieux
Man, I think I'll put up 400 on this one.
[Singing continues]
C'est moi qui suis sa petite
Son Anana, son Anana, son Anammite
Je suis vive, je suis charmante
Comme le petit oiseau qui chante
Check that out, man.
Hey, man, put that motherfucking chip
back on the table.
Put the chip back on the table, man.
D'autre lui font les doux yeux
Mais, c'est moi qu'il aime le mieux
[All applauding]
-I'll blow your brains out.
-Hold me back, blood.
Hold you back nothing, I'll hold you back--
[Gun shot firing]
-Squeezit?
-Johnny just shot Billy.
-Johnny?
-Well, the man was cheating.
So I just had to do away with him,
and that's all there was to it.
That does it, Johnny,
you're going to Mr. Yodlebein's office.
You ain't taking me nowhere,
you honky bitch!
I didn't want to come to school, no way!
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Gun shots firing]
Frenchy, come back, they'll mark you truant!
FRENCHY: Is anybody home?
[Mama grunting]
Mama, are you okay?
I guess I'm all right.
I'll be okay in just a minute.
-Just go out and play.
-Oh, okay.
I think I'm going to take a little peek
behind that Forbidden Door.
I'm so curious, I can't resist.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Screaming]
[Screaming continues]
[Groaning]
Merde, alors!
Hot damn! The Sixth Dimension!
Do I detect a rhumba?
[Singing nonsensically]
[Singing in Spanish]
Bim Bam Boom, Bim Bam Boom
Es el nuevo campás
Que los negros van bailando
en la comparsa
Bim Bam Boom, Bim Bam Boom
La mulatona Mercedes
arrollando va detrás
de la comparsa
Ya no quieren cumbanchear
las negritas del solar
Si no tocan al compás
de este ritmo así
Suénalo, báilalo, gózalo
Bim Bam Boom, Bim Bam Boom
iQué sabrosito está
Este paso arrollador
de la comparsa!
[Singing nonsensically]
PRINCESS: Stop the music! Stop the music!
Seize the intruder.
She must be taken before my parents.
BOTH: Go along with the Princess now,
and don't be cheeky.
[Upbeat instrumental music]
Be sure and call me
if they decide to snuff her.
[Drum roll]
[Trumpets playing]
Who is this that cometh
out of the wilderness...
like pillar of smoke...
perfumed with myrrh and frankincense?
Just another slab of meat for my dungeon.
Quel bordel de merde.
FAUSTO: Thy speech is comely.
FRENCHY: Enculé.
Thy lips are like threads of scarlet.
This isn't very amusing, darling.
Why do you waste your words
on this piece of petit-fois?
Oh, it's nothing, nothing, nothing...
a mere outburst of the poet within me.
Take her to Cell 63.
You're Squeezit Henderson's sister, René.
Cheese it, it's the Princess!
My pet needs a mate.
Oh, he can do it to me. Honest!
Why don't you go down on your knees,
and give him what he wants?
Oooo! You're really gonna get it.
You make a lovely couple.
[Upbeat instrumental music]
[Squeezit laughing]
Lucky, lucky, lucky
the boss really noticed you.
-Oh, yeah?
-Uh-huh!
But how can he bear
the touch of that loathsome Queen?
She's nothing but an old, fat whore.
The Queen is a very important person.
She hurts me a lot, but I respect her.
When I turned 12, Papa said:
''Little woman, better get yourself a wife''
[Singing]
'''Cause you're too mean for a man
She'll clean up your life''
''And if she's the Devil,
you'll know she'll be your friend''
When I turned 13, I spat in my poppa's eye
Took off to find my man
'cause I couldn't find a wife
I spread-eagled in a lot of towns
I couldn't find no man to lay me down
They were so busy a-cock-a-doodle-doin'
But they still couldn't nail me down
So I grew up lonesome
knowing there'd be no man
or woman to get me goin' through this life
'Cause I was hatched out of a witch's egg
Been doomed to fly high
[Upbeat pop music]
like a crane with no legs
I laid down with the Devil
and his sidekick, mankind
But somethin' called lovin'
made me hungry inside
So I went to the Lord
and I asked him for more
than what this world could offer
I laid down with him and I had to grin
'cause he was shyer than a flower
Now thanks to the Lord I've been set free
My lover is the trade winds
that take me out to sea
My life is like nobody else's
There's only one of me
'Cause I was hatched
out of a witch's egg
Been doomed to fly high
Like a crane with no legs
[Frenchy singing in French]
Pleures, pleures, oh pleures
Pleures, pleures sur ton malheur
Pleures, pleures triste coeur
Pleures, pleures, oh pleures, pleures
Pleures, mouillés les fleurs
Pleures, pleures, pleures, pleures
Pleures sur ton bonheur
-Doris, you surprised me.
-Just what do you think you're pulling here?
-I was just only looking at her.
-Oh, yeah?
Listen, buster, looking's dangerous.
Next thing you know,
you'll be sucking on her mangoes.
My, my, aren't you a jealous one?
Well, why shouldn't I be?
It gets on my nerves, you know.
You know, I must have my army.
I'm not about to compromise my position
in life, my ancestry...
my tradition, for your silly little suspicions.
Your army!
Where is your precious army?
I will have a whole army of Zombie.
A Zombie Marine Corps...
a Zombie Navy Corps,
a Zombie Space Cadets--
You're really out to lunch.
Look at this world you've cooked up.
And you expect
to take over another universe?
You dumb fuck.
Just wait until these dead babies
start marching...
and you'll be eating your words.
I am waiting, Your Majesty,
waiting for you to tell me...
why that French slit is so special to you,
and why you carry her photograph...
around in your pocket.
FAUSTO: All right, I'll tell you.
She's French, and that's simple.
And therefore, she's of the master race...
a direct descendant of God, just like me.
Direct descendant of God?
You just want to slip her the pork.
That does it.
I'm hopping the next bus out of here.
FAUSTO: You cannot mean that.
What will you do?
Just go on living, I guess.
Oh, chérie, ma petite coquette,
ma petite princesse.
Mon petit chou, c'est rien.
[Queen Doris sobbing]
[Queen Doris moaning]
[Soft instrumental music]
Harder.
Frenchy! Harder!
I hope you were not treated badly.
I gave strict instructions for you
to be put in our most cheery dungeon.
Why am I prisoner here?
It's for your own safety, chérie.
The Queen may have had you tortured...
or executed, had it not been
for my quick and decisive action.
-Vous-êtes artiste?
-Oh, no, no, no, no.
I am a soldier by profession.
This is only doodling, you know, to relax.
La couleur, la form, l'image!
C'est vraiment magnifique.
Vous êtes tres gentille.
It's nothing, nothing at all.
A is A, A-A-A
A E icky U, U-U-U
Icky A-E-I-O-U, Icky I-O-U
B is Bay, Bay-Bay-Bay
Bay-Be-Ba-Bi-Bo-Bo-Bu-Bu-Bu
Bay-Be-Bay-Be-Bi-Bo-Bu
Bay-B-Bi-Bo
C is say, say say say
say see sicky so soo woo woo
Sicky say see si so so, sicky si so su
Golly, what a groovy tune
The alphabet is fun
Consonants and vowels to learn
The pen is mightier than the gun
F is fay, fi fo foo
-F-U-C-K
-You! You! You!
Ficky Fa Fe Fi Fo Foo
Ficky Fi Fuck you!
G is gay, gay gay gay
gay guy gicky go goo goo goo
Gicky gay, guy, gee--
Shut up, you punk.
[Disco music]
Z! Z!
Z!
[Miss Feldman clearing throat]
FLASH: Squeezit, if you're too scared
to help me rescue René and Frenchy...
FLASH: I'm gonna have to get that
kosher fart grandfather of mine to help me.
SQUEEZIT: Yeah, but Miss Feldman
will never let you out of class this early.
FLASH: Oh, yeah?
[Window pane shattering]
Gramps, come on, lean back.
Let me untie you.
We got to go save Sis.
[Upbeat pop music]
[Shouting]
[Both screaming]
[Both grunting]
Shit.
Come on, Gramps, let's go.
Change your foreign money to local currency.
Okay, Mr. Bernstein,
give me a quarter's worth.
Two craps. How do you like that?
Killer Rosenblatt, the famous Jewish wrestler.
I've read all about you in the paper.
Well, you see, Gramps, he can't hear you...
'cause he's so used to hollering
at the opposition...
he's deaf and dumb.
So what's a nice Jewish boy like you
doing in the Sixth Dimension?
You see Gramps, we're here
to find my sister Frenchy. She disappeared.
The French girl in 63?
Oy vey, oy vey, oy vey!
If the Queen should find out
what the King is doing to that girl...
-She'd murder the poor girl.
-No kidding?
Tell me, Gramps, you got a way,
maybe I can get my sister back?
Get his sister back, he says. Let me think.
I have a strategy that could get her back.
I could even bring Jesus Christ himself
back again.
-For how much?
-For three shekels.
-Okay, three shekels. You got a deal, okay?
-Okay.
Here's three shekels.
Now I'll tell you....
[Speaking Yiddish]
[Adventurous instrumental music]
Wait a minute, Gramps. Hold it.
Let me get rid of this guy.
Hey, Bust Rod, here's a quarter.
Go get me a pack of cigarettes.
Camels, like a good fellow, that's the idea.
Come on, Gramps, let's go find Sis.
[Hollering]
I'll give you one last chance to live...
you sniveling little weasel!
Tell me why you and the Fat One
came into our Kingdom here.
If I tell you, will you let me and Gramps go
and take one of the prisoners with us?
QUEEN DORIS: Of course, dear.
FLASH: See, we really came here...
to rescue my sister,
you understand? Frenchy.
Because Mr. Bernstein said that
she's in great danger.
The King fell in love with her,
and the Queen is jealous.
Oh. You're the Queen.
Lower the rope!
FLASH: Gramps!
But, Your Majesty, you promised.
Gramps, let go of what you're holding.
[Adventurous instrumental music]
Gramps, let go, I might fall!
Assemble all prisoners from Cell 63
into the Interrogation Cell.
But, Mommy, can't I watch some more?
They're still wiggling.
You heard me!
[Eerie instrumental music]
There she is, eyes so sweet
What a shame that soon they'll be
glowing like some burning coal
when I turn on the heat
Impudent, surly bitch
Soon you'll sing a different song
You'll plead for mercy, beg forgiveness
When I throw the switch
You don't scare me now
You don't scare me ever
Asking you for mercy
or forgiveness now, never
Gonna throw the switch
Give it to the bitch
And give her plenty, make her scream
Ti yum titti tum titti tim titti tim hi-hay
[Upbeat music]
Give her all the juice, give her all the juice
Twenty thousand volts in her caboose
Will make her see the error of her ways
Frenchy is going to pay
Look at her acting tough
Well, that's fine for now, honey
I've got plenty time to play
and, sweetheart, I play rough
Getting late, say goodbye
Time to meet your fate
And I do hope that you're thinking of me
When you start to fry
Don't you worry, Mom, I will oversee now
Really, though, don't go to any trouble
over me now
Give her all the juice
Twenty thousand volts in her caboose
Will make her see the error of her ways
Frenchy is going to pay
The Queen will have her way
This poor girl so fair
-Can this be her fate?
-Going to pay
Can there still be time?
Or is it too late?
Frenchy is going to pay
Oh, why must it be
that life is so cruel?
The Queen will have her way
Frenchy is going to pay
Unfair and unjust
Must this be the rule?
Oh, darn. The fuse blew.
-Flash Hercules at your service, ma'am.
-Ma'am? I am the Ex-Queen!
I was once happily married to King Fausto...
until that fat loathsome cow, Queen Doris...
that silicone uddered pig
stole the throne by seducing me...
even though she's not my type.
She thinks I'm dead...
because he, the King,
couldn't stand to see me die...
because he's such a coward,
so he threw me a mile down in this cell...
where I've been for 1,000 years,
and to maintain my sanity...
I've been writing a screenplay,
and it's so difficult...
because there's no hot water,
there's no fresh orange juice.
There's bats falling in my hair at night
and roaches climbing through the pages...
and so much dust on the keys...
that I just can't stand it another minute!
Okay, Queenie, don't worry about nothing.
I'll get you out of this place.
Here, watch my magic propeller,
and off we go.
Come on, Gramps, let's go find Sis.
I've got to change a Tampax,
I'll see you later.
You fuzzy bastard. Come on, Gramps.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Singing]
Pico and Sepulveda
Doheny
[Rhythmic music]
Cahuenga
La Brea
-Tar pits
La Jolla
Sequoia
La Brea
-Tar pits
You can keep Alvarado, Santa Monica
Even Beverly Drive
Vine may be fine,
but for mine I want to feel alive
And settle down in my
-La Brea
-Pico and Sepulveda
Tar pits
Where nobody's dreams come true
Pico and Sepulveda
[Comical instrumental music]
By the way, honey, when is that mentally
retarded Swedish husband of yours...
coming home, anyhow?
[Exploding]
[Man shouting]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
Mmmm, hello there.
Hello there.
[Moaning]
[Exclaiming]
Hi, Pa. Gee, I'm glad to see you.
I'll get you out of here, Pa, don't worry,
and then I'll go save Frenchy.
You leave me be.
In the real world up there,
I was just another rat...
and down here, I also live like a rat.
So what's the difference? Go avay.
I vant to be alone.
Ah, banana oil.
You're gonna see your son in a minute.
He just turned 11.
What the frig are you talking about?
Me, a kid? Ruthy, come on.
You're the one, okay, you big gorilla.
You wanna see him, eh?
You wanna see Chicken Boy?
Oh, Chicken Boy?
You wanna see him? You wanna see
Chicken Boy? Oh, Chicken Boy?
[Laughing]
That's really rich.
-Mom, mom.
-Squeezit, meet your pop.
-Dad?
-I ain't your dad.
Unless we got chickens in the family.
Come here, baby.
Oh, yes.
What are you doing, you big lug?
Squeezit, help your mom!
Let go of my mother.
Hey!
Come here.
SQUEEZIT: I love you.
MOM: Shut up!
You're too much, baby.
Come on, sugar,
I got a hard-on that won't wait...
-And the ship leaves in a couple of hours.
-What do you mean, a couple of hours?
That's a sailor's life, baby.
SQUEEZIT: I love you, Mom.
I love you. I love you.
SQUEEZIT: I don't know where to begin.
CHICKEN: At the beginning.
-I have no self-respect.
-Why, Squeezit.
I have no courage. René and Frenchy
are prisoners in the Sixth Dimension...
and I didn't go
when my help was asked to save them.
-Nobody ever helped you.
-But I don't need any help.
You know the chickens are always ready
to help you any way we can...
-But as you know....
-What can chickens do?
-Precisely.
-I wish I could be brave, like Flash.
Gee whiz!
[Slurping]
[Upbeat instrumental music]
[Telephone ringing]
-Henderson here.
-Hey, Squeezit, man.
Yeah, you got to come down here
right away. We're lost.
-Maybe I'll gain some self-respect.
-Frenchy and René are in great danger.
I've got nothing else to live for. I'll help.
I'll help!
[Adventurous instrumental music]
Where are you taking me? Where's René?
Where's Frenchy?
I demand an answer.
Ow! Ow!
Yoo-hoo!
Well, if it ain't the little Princess!
DEMON: Come on there, boy.
-Gee, that girl was beautiful.
-You said it, brother.
My boss is just dying to stick his fork
in that there tomato.
Is your boss
the leader of the Sixth Dimension?
No, that be the little Midget King.
[Eerie instrumental music]
[Eerie instrumental music intensifies]
Well, son, let me tell you
I'm so pleased to meet you
The boys and I've been expecting
to greet you
As guest of honor in the house of the dead
Just relax, lay yourself down,
say goodbye to your head
-Hi de hi de hi
-Ho de ho de ho
-Wa de wa de way de
-Hi de hi de ho
Please, Mr, Devil, it's not for me I'm pleading
If you help René and Frenchy
I'll give you what you're needing
If you want to bargain,
then produce something real
Deliver me the Princess, boy,
and you've got a deal
Deliver him the Princess, boy,
Okay.
-Oh Sheep dop doop dap daydee doo
-Sheep dop doop dap daydee doo
-Skeeba de deeba de debop dee do
-Oh dop dop dop daddy-o
-Hi de hi de ho
Congratulations, son, you really deliver
This little gal makes me shake and a-shiver
Don't think I've forgotten all the things
that I've said
Don't worry about your friends, relax
Now off with his head
-Hi di hi di hi di hi di hi di
-Ho di ho di ho di ho di ho di ho hi ho
-Ho hi ho hi ho hi he bob de dop o de
-Hi de hi de ho
Be nice to me, babe, or you'll regret it
You are my hostage, and don't you forget it
The night is early
and there's lots to be done
Lets boogie now
Come on, we're gonna have some fun
-Oh ho de ho de ho
Keep an eye on the King.
And keep me posted.
He doesn't know
where I've hid that French slit.
[Singing nonsensically]
He may be a little man...
but he carries a big stick!
And whatever you do, Froggy...
keep him away from that interrogation cell.
Oy vey, the Yiddishe Charleston
Vey's mir
The Yiddishe Charleston
Vatch those Heebie-Jeebies
at the Yiddishe Cabaret
Lo do ti do
The Yiddishe Charleston
Do Ta Ti Do, the Yiddishe Charleston
Little Yiddles on their fiddles
Play it on East Broadway
Alley oop, you must wear a derby hat
When you do that dance
Alley oop, you twist like an acrobat
then you clap your hands
Oy Vey, the Yiddishe Charleston
Vey's mir
Oy, yoy, yoy, yoy, yoy
I knew you'd come to save me!
Bust Rod told me
that the Queen took you here.
I had no idea that she would resort
to such a thing.
Please, I beg your forgiveness.
It's all forgiven, my Fausto.
The Queen said she was gonna ream us
with 20-inch cattle prods...
-And I'm still waiting.
-We must hurry now.
Bust Rod, undo her chains quickly.
I must command you
to leave the Forbidden Zone at once.
This is for your own safety.
Henderson will show you the way out.
Aren't you gonna hump us
one last time, Fausto?
Shut up!
When will I ever see you again, mon amour?
I cannot answer to you that right now...
but somehow I feel
that our destinies are intertwined.
RENÉ: Come on, Frenchy.
FAUSTO: Goodbye.
You let the French girl go?
Don't you think you'd better go get her?
-Goddamn it.
-René, René stop it!
René, help!
Somebody help me! Shit!
Let me go!
Guess what?
The Mystic Knights took the Princess
as hostage...
and if anything happens
to René and Frenchy...
she's really gonna get it.
But I helped them escape.
Yeah, but I heard a rumor
that the Queen captured them all again.
Attention, all soldiers!
[Laughing loudly]
So you thought you'd get away?
Well, your little King
won't be able to help you now!
-Nobody'll find you down here.
-He'll find me, I know he will.
-And he won't let you get away with this shit.
-Oh, yeah?
Well, we'll see about that.
No one can survive
what this child will go through.
So take a good look, you French slit,
'cause you're next.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
ALL: Throw her in the pit!
Khomeini.
ALL: Khomeini.
Throw the French girl in.
That's not fair. It's my turn next.
My frog, you killed my frog, goddamn it!
-You killed my Froggy.
-So get another one, bitch.
You're supposed to be dead.
Uh-uh, Baby. You're dead.
I know that voice. You're the one
the King keeps locked up in the pit.
This is going up your asshole
as soon as I've finished with Queenie here.
Faggot.
Your buns smell like lox, honey,
I can smell them from here.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Queen Doris screaming]
Attention, all soldiers!
We have to save the French girl.
-Hurry up.
-That's what we're trying to do.
Come on, shut up. Let's go.
Hurry up. Come on.
[Upbeat instrumental music]
[Ex-queen screaming]
[Laughing]
[Rhythmic instrumental music]
Nothing can stop me now.
What are you doing?
I'm going to open her up
like a can of worms.
No, our daughter is their hostage.
If you kill the girl, they will kill the Princess.
-Out of my way, or you'll be first.
-Come to your senses, darling.
You'll be killing your own daughter.
[Sobbing]
Oh, God.
Oh, beat me! Oh, kill me!
Oh, fuck that asshole!
[Prisoners grunting]
Please don't die.
Life was so beautiful.
Oh, why does it feel so good to be so bad?
You...you were
the only decent thing in my life.
Smile at me one last time.
Tell me how you love to...
I love to feel your nipples stiffen
when I caress them with my finger tips.
Oh, Fausto. Faust-
[Queen Doris moaning]
[Solemn instrumental music]
[Upbeat instrumental music]
You are my Kingie
My heart's desire turned to fire
with your caress
This must be heaven
I've got my Fausto
I've no doubts our lives are blessed
With all our powers
No one can stop us now
We'll conquer the planets
Then all our dreams come--
-Adenoidal doy voy
-Yes, we can hump them
-Pain is a thrill
-Yeah, sure
-I coronate the New Queen.
-La Chaim.
A toast to him as we salute the true Queen.
She really is a sight.
In death, too, there is pleasure
As dead rats, we're free to bleed
To rot, and at our leisure
be eaten up by worms
La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la,
la, la, la, la
-There's humping here forever
-Forever
And if you think you're really very clever
Just eat more cakes and pies
[Nonsensical singing]
La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la,
la, la, la, la
So really, what's the hurry? Don't worry
So maybe you got couple little troubles?
Just tell them all to me
-We're happy now together
-Forever
-The Hercules are in for stormy weather.
-No, it's really just a breeze!
And so, my friends, sit tight
and some advice to you I'll lend
This drama may be over
But it's really not the end
Come with us in the land of sin and pleasure
You'll be surprised
by the things that you will see
Come with us while we conquer other planets
Through time and space
The Forbidden Galaxy
The Forbidden Zone
Living in the Sixth Dimension
things get rough
can be tough
It's so hard when you're on your own
When you're on your own
Moving in the wrong direction
brings bad luck
Living without protection really sucks
It's so hard when you're on your own
You might fall into The Forbidden Zone
Going down down down
how far can you go
You might fall into The Forbidden Zone
Going down down down
cross the borderline
The guards look scary
but the girls are pretty fine
Okay! I'm a-going down, I'm a-going down
I'm a-going down, I know
Turnin' me around, turnin' me around
turnin' me around, I know ho ho
Living in the Sixth Dimension
Moving in the wrong direction
It's so hard when you're on your own
When you're on you own
The Forbidden Zone
Going down down down
How far can you go?
You might fall into The Forbidden Zone
Hey!
Okay!
Going down down down
cross the borderline
The guards look scary
but the girls are pretty fine
Going round round round
driving me insane
Everything looks different
but nothing has changed
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh