Subtitles modified by Edogaru
# Oh, oh, oh #
# Woke up today #
# Feeling the way #
# I always do #
# Oh, oh, oh #
# Hungry for something
that I can't eat #
# Then I hear that beat #
# That rhythm of town
starts calling me down #
# It's like a message
from high above #
# Oh, oh, oh #
# Pulling me out to the smiles
and the streets that I love #
- Good morning, Baltimore!
- # Good morning, Baltimore #
# Every day's like an open door #
# Every night is a fantasy #
# Every sound's like a symphony #
# Good morning, Baltimore #
# And someday when
I take to the floor #
# The world's gonna
wake up and see #
# Baltimore and me #
# Oh, oh, oh #
# Look at my hair #
# What 'do can compare
with mine today? #
# Oh, oh, oh #
# I've got my hairspray and radio #
# I'm ready to go #
# The rats on the street #
# All dance around my feet #
# They seem to say:
"Tracy, it's up to you" #
# So oh, oh, don't hold me back #
# 'Cause today all
my dreams will come true #
# Good morning, Baltimore #
# There's the flasher
who lives next door #
# There's the bum on
his barroom stool #
# They wish me luck
on my way to school #
# Good morning, Baltimore #
# And someday when
I take to the floor #
# The world's gonna
wake up and see #
# Baltimore and me #
# I know every step #
# I know every song #
# I know there's a place where I belong #
# I see all those party lights
shining ahead #
# So someone invite me
before I drop dead #
# Before she drops dead #
# So oh, oh, give me a chance #
# 'Cause when I start
to dance I'm a movie star #
# Oh, oh, oh #
# Something inside
of me makes me move #
# When I hear that groove #
# My ma tells me no #
# But my feet tell me "go" #
# It's like a drummer inside my heart #
# So oh, oh, don't make me wait #
# One more moment for my life to start #
# I love you, Baltimore #
# Every day's like an open door #
# Every night is a fantasy #
# Every sound's like a symphony #
# And I promise, Baltimore #
# That someday when I take to the floor #
# The world's gonna wake up and see #
# Gonna wake up and see #
# Baltimore and me #
# Yes, more or less, we all agree #
# Someday the world is gonna see #
# Baltimore and me #
Mount Everest is the most
famous, but not the highest...
geographical point on this earth.
Now, who can tell me what that is?
Um, excuse me, Miss Whimsy?
I can't see the board again.
Tracy Turnblad.
If I have to write you up...
for inappropriate hair height
one more time...
you will be removed to detention.
Miss Wimsey, what am I supposed to do?
Hair can't just hang there like a dead thing
on your cheeks.
I mean, well... Uh-you know what I mean.
I... Ahh.
As I said, it is not Mount Everest.
Now, next week we will be talking...
about earthquakes and volcanoes.
And as exciting as that might sound...
we have to look back approximately
60 million years.
Now, if you turn your pages...
we are going to start
with the Ring of Fire.
I want you to contemplate what causes...
the separation of the two components.
Penny, come on, hurry!
Outta my way!
Push! We're late.
Ahh!
- One minute to air.
- OK.
40 to go!
Don't change that channel.
Coming up next: The Corny Collins Show.
30 seconds.
- Hiya, Dad!
- Goodbye!
Hi.
It's my daughter.
10 seconds. Places, everyone.
Hurry up, Penny, we're missing it!
My mom says I'm not
allowed to perspire!
Hey there, teenage Baltimore!
Don't change that
channel 'cause it's time...
for The Corny Collins Show...
Brought to you by Ultra Clutch hairspray.
# Oh, every afternoon when
the clock strikes four #
# Bop bee ba ba ba ba ba ba bee ba #
# Well, a crazy bunch of kids crash
through that door, yeah #
# Bop bee ba ba ba ba ba ba bee ba #
# Well, they throw off their coats #
# And leave the squares behind #
# And then they shake it,
shake it, shake it #
# Like they're losin' their mind #
# You'll never see them frown #
# 'Cause they're the
nicest kids in town #
# Ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh #
# Oh, every afternoon
you turn your Tv on, huh #
# Naa na na na na na na na #
# Yeah, we know you
turn the sound up #
# When your parents
are gone, yeah #
# Naa na na na na na na na #
# Then you twist and shout
for your favorite star #
# And when you've
practiced every step #
# That's in your repertoire #
# You better come on down #
# And meet the nicest kids in town #
Whoo!
# Nice white kids
who like to lead the way #
# And once a month
we have our Negro Day #
# And I'm the man who
keeps it spinnin' round #
# Mr. Corny Collins
with the latest greatest #
# Baltimore sound #
# So, every afternoon drop everything #
Whoo!
# Bop bee ba ba ba ba ba ba bee ba #
# Who needs to read and write #
# When you can dance and sing, yeah! #
# Bop bee ba ba ba ba ba ba bee ba #
# Forget about your
algebra and calculus #
# You can always do your homework
on the mornin' bus #
# Can't tell a verb from a noun #
# They're the nicest kids in town #
# Ooh ooh ooh ooh ooh #
R- r-r-role call!
I'm Amber.
Brad.
Tammy.
Fender.
- Brenda.
- Sketch.
- Shelley.
- IQ.
Lou Ann.
- Joey.
- Mikey.
- vicki.
- Becky.
- Bix.
- Jesse.
- Darla.
- Paulie.
- Noreen.
- Doreen.
And I'm... Link.
Aah!
# So, if every night you're shakin' #
# As you lie in bed #
# Mony, mony #
# Shake it, baby #
# And the bass and drums
are poundin' in your head #
# Mony, mony, ooh, mony, mony #
# Who cares about sleep when
you can snooze in school #
# You'll never get to college
but you'll sure look cool #
# Don't need a cap or a gown #
# When you're the nicest kids in town #
They must think my ears
are garbage cans.
Would you turn that racket down?
I'm tryin' to iron here.
# Nicest kids in #
# Kids in town, whoo! #
Ma, it's not racket.
It's The Corny Collins Show.
Well, it's turning your brains into mud.
Mrs. Turnblad, it's a new dance!
The Stricken Chicken.
Well, I can't hear myself think.
How am I supposed to negotiate pleats?
Edna?
I'm in here, Prudy.
What's that racket?
Ohh, Tracy.
Edna, is my laundry ready?
Yep.
That'll be $3.00, hon.
That's pretty pricey
for a pair of petty pants.
Well, I'm sorry, Prudy...
but some-a your personal stains...
required poundin' with a rock.
I'm sure I don't know what you mean.
You're letting her listen
to that race music again?
My daughter spends every afternoon
at the Stamp and Coin Club.
Oh, really? Well, your daughter hap-
Ohh, ohh.
Oh, what is that? The Wavin' Raven?
It's a little twitchy.
Oh, you wanna play Charades now.
All right.
OK, go ahead.
You.
Penny.
No. Ahh!
Tracy Turnblad, are you tryin' to tell me...
that-that Penny didn't get permission...
from her mother to be here?
What?
Penny.
You are banned from this house.
You will never watch that show again!
- Without that show I have nothing!
- Having nothing builds character!
Toodle-oo, Edna!
Give 'em a hand, folks.
All right, all right.
And, once again,
that's the Stricken Chicken.
We will be right back
for some more of that hot Detroit sound.
And we're off!
Corny.
"Detroit sound"?
What's that, the cries
of people being mugged?
Aw, velma, the kids dig
the rhythm and blues.
Yeah, they're kids, Corny.
That's why we have to steer
them in the white direction.
Right direction?
Didn't I say that?
I'll do it.
You try that again and there'll be stumps
where your feet should be.
You got that? You little whor-
Amber.
...holy moly. Baby.
Good job dancing today.
- It's time.
- Ah!
Link.
Amber.
Ah!
- Amber.
- Amber, Amber, Amber.
Save your personal life
for the cameras, sweetie.
Oh! Shiny.
Tammy, Lou Ann,
you're gonna die.
Speaking of cameras,
did you have a nice nap?
If you'd do your job, my daughter wouldn't
have to fight to be visible.
I gotta show some of the
other kids once in a while.
You know, this is a small city.
There aren't that many stations.
This time next year
you could be wearing...
an ill-fitting tux,
snapping bar mitzvah photos.
I don't know.
# It takes two, baby... #
Show Link.
This is nuts. She can't even dance.
Plastic little spastic.
Oh, Link. I can dance
so much better than her.
Why don't you notice me at school?
Mm-hmm.
# Ooh #
Hey, that was our very own Link Larkin
singin' It Takes Two.
And I'm Motormouth Maybelle remindin'...
the last Tuesday of this month's
your rhythm and blues day.
That's right! Negro Day
will be comin' your way.
So don't-uh... Uh... Over here.
Thank you.
So, catch all the croonin'
when y'all set and tune in.
Thank you, Motormouth.
And now it's time to...
Owner's coming. He'll call
my mother again, let's go.
...very own fun-lovin'...
Hey!
Come on up here, Brenda.
What?
Brenda will be taking a leave of absence
from the show.
How long you gonna be gone, Brenda?
Just nine months.
Seems like we'll have an opening
here on the show for a girl...
just as fun-lovin' but maybe
not quite as freewheelin'.
Wanna be one-a
the nicest kids in town?
Cut school tomorrow and come down
to station WYZT to audition.
- No.
- But, Ma.
Don't test me, Tracy Turnblad.
My diet pill's wearin' off.
But come on.
No one is auditioning for
anything in this household.
But why not? Why not?!
Because dancing is not your future.
One day you're gonna own
Edna's Occidental Laundry.
I don't wanna be a laundress.
I wanna be famous!
Look, if you wanna be famous...
learn how to take blood
outta car upholstery.
That's a skill you can take right to the bank.
- Hey, hey. What's all this ruckus in here?
- Not a word.
Daddy, tomorrow I'm auditioning
to dance on a Tv show.
- No, she is not.
- You are?
First the hair, now this?
But all the kids are battin' up
their hair now, hon.
You're no help.
It's "ratting," Daddy.
And our first lady,
Jacqueline Kennedy, does it.
I don't believe that.
What do you mean,
you don't believe that?!
- I don't.
- How else would it look that way?
I believe that it is naturally stiff.
She doesn't understand anything.
- Dancing on that show is my dream.
- I know.
Just because she wouldn't know
a dream if it bit her on the nose.
Well, I have information for you, missy.
I once had a dream that I owned
a coin-operated laundromat...
and I came down from that cloud
real quickly, I'll tell you that.
No!
- Oh, Wilbur.
- Fine! I'm going to my room!
She thinks I'm bein' mean
but I'm not. Those Tv people...
they don't pick people like Tracy,
or girls like us.
They're gonna hurt her, Wilbur.
I'll talk to her.
Ooh.
'K. Talk to her.
I'll talk to her.
Don't you worry.
OK.
What?
Tracy, this Tv thing.
You really want it?
With all my heart.
Then you go for it!
This is America, babe.
You gotta think big to be big.
Big ain't the problem
in this family, Wilbur.
You follow your dream.
Mine came true, and now I have the most
precious thing in the world.
The Taj Mahal of joke shops.
Heh heh heh heh!
Back step, cha-cha-cha.
Side step, front step.
Back and turn.
Front step, cha-cha-cha.
Tammy, sharper.
Side step, front step.
Back, again.
Oh, my God, Penny, there's Link.
Link!
Penny, pinch me!
Ow!
You told me to.
I can't believe I'm really here auditioning.
Side step, front step.
I can't believe I'm really
here watching you audition.
Front step, cha-cha-cha.
Back step, cha-cha-cha.
Side step, front step.
Back and t-oh, Amber.
Look at this motley crew.
Oh! This town sure has gone downhill...
since I was crowned
Miss Baltimore Crabs.
Ugh.
# Oh, my God,
how times have changed #
# These girls must be blind
or completely deranged #
# But time seemed to halt #
# When I was Miss Baltimore Crabs #
Amber, that move is far too dirty.
Mother, wake up from
that dream of yours.
- This isn't 1930.
- Ha ha ha.
# You can laugh but life's a test #
# Don't do this, don't do that #
# Remember, Mother knows best #
# For the crown's in the vault #
# From when I won Miss Baltimore Crabs #
# These steps are perfect ammunition #
# Let me show you how your mommy
dear took out the competition #
Girls, go get 'em.
Boys, let's rumba.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
# Those poor runner-ups might
still hold some grudges #
# They padded their cups
but I screwed the judges #
# Those broads thought
they'd win if a plate #
# They would spin in their dance #
Aah!
# Not a chance
Boys, put me down #
Oh, good morning, ladies.
Let's see what you got.
# Twist, twist, twist, twist
mashed potato, mambo #
# Ready, begin #
# On my show you'll never find #
# A thrusting hip or bump and grind #
# What's that?
A dance for fleas and ticks? #
# Oh, you should-a seen my bag of tricks #
# Oh, I hit the stage batons ablaze #
# While belting Aida
and preparing soufflés #
# But that triple somersault #
# Is how I clinched
Miss Baltimore Crabs #
Proceed.
# Are you scared we're on live? #
# No, I'm sure I can cope #
# Well, this show isn't broadcast in #
# Cinemascope #
# I never drank one chocolate malt #
# No desserts for Miss Baltimore Crabs #
# This one will never get a date #
# In those hand-me-down clothes #
# Ha! Kid, she'll never get a date
till Daddy buys her a new nose #
# I would say "Oy, gevalt" #
# If I wasn't Miss Baltimore Crabs #
# Do you dance like you dress? #
# Amber, there's no need to be cruel #
# Would you swim
in an integrated pool? #
I sure would.
I'm all for integration.
It's the new frontier!
Not in Baltimore, it isn't.
And may I be frank?
# First impressions can be tough #
# And when I saw you, I knew it #
# If your size weren't enough #
# Your last answer just blew it #
# And so, my dear,
so short and stout #
# You'll never be in #
# So we're kicking you out #
# With your form and your face #
# Aw, well, it isn't your fault #
# You're just down with a case #
# Of Miss Baltimore Crabs #
Uh, you may go.
Um... Thank you?
I think they secretly liked you.
Cutting my class, Tracy Turnblad?
I trust it was something really important.
It should've been.
# Gimme a break, yeah.
Right now! #
# Got a brand-new sound,
so scream and shout #
Hey! Hey!
# With a funky rhythm #
# It's a brand-new look that you can... #
Whoo!
# There's a party groovin'
let's get down #
What you lookin' at?
Nothing. Not you.
Can I help you?
That move's swish.
Ya got that right.
The man can dine me
on a diet of detention...
so long as he don't starve
me of my tunes, baby.
- Does that dance have a name?
- Oh, this?
Call it the "Peyton Place After Midnight. "
I use it to attract, uh, the opposite sex.
Wow.
That is so groovy.
You're really good.
Why, thank you.
So would it be kinda like this?
You can't do that dance.
Hello, now.
Not bad for a white chick.
- Hey, I know where I've seen you before.
- Where?
On Corny's show on Negro Day.
Negro Day's the best.
I wish every day were Negro Day.
At our house, it is.
Hey. Show me another one?
You wanna see another one.
Well-well, here's a little
something signified to say...
Hello, my name is Seaweed...
Oh, oh, oh!
J...
Stubbs.
What's yours, baby?
I'm Tra-cy Turn-blad!
You're gonna get it, white girl!
Well, Tracy, you got it goin' on, girl.
You one of us.
You're joinin' this program already
in progress!
Well, let's go.
# Whoo! #
# Yeah! #
# Got a brand-new sound,
so scream and shout #
# Hey, a funky beat,
now let's be hurrying #
Whoa!
# We can't wait now #
# Have some fun #
# This party now has just begun #
No, I get who Caesar is.
But what's the "Ideas of March"?
I mean, how can
a month have an idea?
Hold on.
Come on.
# Come on and watch me strut my stuff #
# Watch me #
# Come on and watch me #
How you likin' detention now?
I'm a bad, bad girl who
needs to be punished.
# Ohh #
Hey.
You know, Corny's hosting
the hop tomorrow.
If he saw you dancin' like that...
he'd put you on the show.
Mmm...
- See ya.
- Mm.
Ah, whoa. Sorry, little darlin'.
Hope I didn't dent your 'do.
See y'all later.
Hey, Trace. I was looking for you.
What?
# I can hear the bells #
What? What are you talking about?
# Well, don't-cha hear 'em chime? #
Chime's not exactly how I'd put it.
# Can't you feel my heartbeat
keeping perfect time? #
# And all because he #
# Touched me #
# He looked at me and stared #
# Yes, he bumped me #
# My heart was unprepared #
# When he tapped me #
# And knocked me off my feet #
# One little touch now my life's complete #
- # 'Cause when he nudged me #
- Oh!
# Love put me in a fix #
# Yes, it hit me #
# Just like a ton-a bricks #
# Yes, my heart burst #
# Now I know what life's about #
# One little touch and
love's knocked me out #
# And I can hear the bells #
# My head is spinning #
# I can hear the bells #
# Something's beginning #
# Everybody says that
a girl who looks like me #
# Can't win his love #
# Well, just wait and see #
# 'Cause I can hear the bells #
# Just hear them chiming #
# I can hear the bells #
# My temperature's climbing #
# I can't contain my joy #
# 'Cause I finally found the boy #
# I've been missin' #
# Listen, I can hear the bells #
# Round one #
# He'll ask me on a date and then #
# Round two #
# I'll primp but won't be late because #
# Round three #
# Is when we kiss inside his car #
# Won't go all the way
but I'll go pretty fa-ar #
# Round four #
# He'll ask me for my hand and then #
# Round five #
# We'll book the wedding band so by #
# Round six #
# Amber, much to your surprise #
# This heavyweight
champion takes the prize #
# And I can hear the bells #
# My ears are ringing #
# I can hear the bells #
# The bridesmaids are singing #
# Everybody says that
a guy who's such a gem #
# Won't look my way #
# Well, the laugh's on them #
# 'Cause I can hear the bells #
# My father will smile #
# I can hear the bells #
# As he walks me down the aisle #
# My mother starts to cry #
# But I can't see 'cause Link
and I are French kissin' #
# Listen, I can hear the bells #
# Ahh ahh ahh ahh ahh #
# I can hear the bells #
# My head is reeling #
# I can't stop the pealing #
# Everybody warns
that he won't like what he'll see #
# But I know that he'll
look inside of me #
# Yeah, I can hear the bells #
# Today's just the start 'cause #
# I can hear the bells #
# Until death do us part and #
# Even when we die
we'll look down from up above #
# Remembering the night
that we two fell in love #
# We both will shed a tear #
# And he'll whisper as we're reminiscin' #
# Listen, I can hear the bells #
# She can hear the bells #
# I can hear the bells #
# Bum, bum, bum #
# Whoa! #
# Hey, little girl with the cash to burn #
# Well, I'm sellin' somethin'
you won't return #
# Hey, little girl, take me off the shelf #
# 'Cause it's hard havin'
fun playin' with yourself #
# Once you bounce through
the whole selection #
# Shake those hips in my direction #
# Bringing back gifts
she never did see #
# Take me home and then unwrap me #
# Shop around but, little darlin',
I've got to be #
# The ladies' choice #
# Ladies' choice #
Go on. Get out there and show 'em.
It's packed pretty tight.
OK. I'll go in front of you and I'll push.
# Test drive this American male #
Wait.
# It's gonna take cash to fill my tank #
# So let's crack open your piggy bank #
Hey, Seaweed!
Wanna do Peyton Place for Corny?
Are you crazy? You gotta
dance with your crowd...
and I gotta dance with mine.
Why?
It's just the way it is, Tracy.
But it's your dance.
Well, how 'bout you go
borrow it for a second.
- Really?
- Go get it, girl.
# I'm the ladies' choice #
# Ladies' choice #
Whoo!
All right! Yeah!
Whoa!
# Hey, little girl on a spendin' spree #
# I don't come cheap
but the kisses come free #
# On closer inspection
I'm sure that you'll agree #
# Oh, hey, little girl, listen to my plea #
# I come with a lifetime guarantee #
# One day maybe we'll find
that baby makes three #
Link!
# It's the ladies' choice #
# I'm the ladies' choice #
# I'm the ladies' choice-choice-choice #
Mr. And Mrs. Turnblad!
Hey, look out!
Ah!
Mrs. Turnblad!
Mr. Turnblad, come quick!
- Me?
- Come on.
Mrs. Turnblad! Come quick!
You gotta see this!
Oh, I read all about it.
It's a big fake Hollywood set.
No, Mrs. -
You think I'm gonna think
that he's really up there?
It's not John Glenn, Mrs. Turnblad!
Well, why are we watchin' this?
Just watch.
- Lou Ann!
- Joey!
Mikey! vicki! Becky!
Bix! Jesse! Darla!
- Paulie!
- Noreen!
- Doreen!
- Link!
And I'm Tracy!
Aah!
Oh! Oh, my!
# Oh, yeah! #
# And the bass and drums
are poundin' in your head #
Go, Tracy!
- Go, go, Tracy!
# Who cares about sleep when
you can snooze in school? #
# You'll never get to college
but you sure look cool #
# Don't need a cap and a gown #
# When you're the nicest kids in town #
# Woo-oo-oo-oo-oo-oo-oo #
# Kids in town, woo! #
Yeah! That was the dance of the week...
I don't know what happened, Mr. Spritzer.
Corny had some sort
of aneurysm or something...
and... picked her.
...by our brand-new Council Member,
Miss Tracy Turnblad.
So, Trace, come on, cozy up to old Corny
and tell us about yourself.
Well, I watch The Corny Collins Show...
and I do absolutely nothing else!
Ooh! I sure like the way you talk.
Oh, Wilbur, to think that
I almost stopped her...
from reaching for the stars.
And now here she
is on local daytime TV.
She's gonna be a regular.
Imagine, my little girl, regular at last.
I also hope to be the first woman president
or a Rockette.
And if you were president, Tracy...
what would your first official act be?
Hmm.
I'd make every day Negro Day.
I read you like tomorrow's
headlines, Tracy.
What do you think, kids?
You think we might
have a hot new candidate...
for Miss Teenage Hairspray?
That's only the dream of my life.
But Miss Hairspray is mine.
Uh, we're on the air.
And your dream will be
comin' to you, sweetheart...
Saturday, June 2nd,
right here on WYZT.
You have to vote for a person, Corny,
not one of the Himalayas.
Hi, Penny.
Always the charmer, Amber.
I want that chubby communist
girl off the show.
Well, let me be the first
to toss the harpoon.
She's a corrupting influence!
I agree. We don't want our dancers
thrusting like savages!
Hey, speak for yourself.
Don't get flip with me.
I'm not.
Look, now I got some
new ideas for the show.
First, we get rid-a Negro Day.
Finally, some sense outta you.
And we mix those kids in
with the rest-a the Council.
Mix those kids?
That's right, I said it.
This is not a black-and-tan cocktail!
Well, why couldn't it be?
velma, isn't this where
it's all headin' anyway?
Now, you can fight it
or you can rock out to it.
Maybe it is time for some fresh ideas...
like-like a nice, fresh new host!
Heh.
Gee, velma,
how do you fire Corny Collins...
from The Corny Collins Show?
They do it all the time on Lassie!
velma, you've let this go too far!
Me?
- Fix it!
- What?
Fix it!
Ohh!
# Hey, look out for that movin' van #
# Drivin' down our streets #
# You better lock up your man #
# Before he meets the new girl in town #
# Who just came on the scene... #
Tracyface whoopee cushion.
Good choice.
We got your Tracy souvenirs for days.
Here, your signed photos.
Tracy wigs.
# Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa #
# We don't know what to do
'bout the new girl in town #
# The new girl in town #
# Seems to dance on air #
# She's got the coolest hair #
# You better tell the homecoming queen
to hold onto her crown #
# Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa #
# Or she's gonna lose it to #
# The new girl in town #
That big little girl is sending
my sales through the roof.
More people are breathing
aerosol than oxygen!
Do you think you could show us
some of those new dance moves?
Yeah, sure.
Ooh, pretty flowers.
Tracy, wait up!
# She's hip #
# So cool #
# I'm gonna get her after school #
# And yet we'd like to be like her #
# 'Cause she's the kitten
that the cats prefer #
# The new girl in town #
# Has my guy on a string #
# Hey, look, she's wearin' his ring #
# I can't stop cryin' and
so in my own tears #
# I'm gonna drown #
# Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa #
# 'Cause he wants to rendezvous #
# With the new girl #
# We're kinda sad and blue #
# Yes, it's true, girl #
# We'd like to say #
# To the new girl in town #
# The new girl in town #
Hi, I'm here to see Tracy Turnblad.
Where's her write-up?
She doesn't need a detention slip,
she's with me.
Penny, this is Seaweed.
Seaweed, this is Penny.
# Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa #
Huh.
# To the new girl in town #
# The new girl in town #
# Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa #
# From out of the blue, girl #
# Hey, this town's in a stew, girl #
# Ohh, what a hullabaloo, girl #
# She ain't just passing through, girl #
# Ohh, she's sticking like glue, girl #
# Woo, to the man
I thought I knew, girl #
# Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa #
# Hey, look out for that movin' van #
# Look out, look out,
look out, look out #
# She was the new girl in #
# Town #
That's the way you do it.
And I'm your fabled
Miss Motormouth Maybelle...
your DJ du jour,
pitchin' rhythm your way.
So, hey, better stay
and shimmy and sway.
We'll be right back with more Negro Day.
Brought to you by...
Nap-a-Way, for stubborn hair.
Every kink will be gone in a blink.
We're off.
Girls, that was great.
How dare you pick the same song?
They wrote it.
You watch yourself.
You are one inch from being canceled.
You know what your demographic is?
Cleaning ladies and lawn jockeys.
A foot in the door, that's all it is.
One toe at a time.
Eh.
Hello?
Is this the Turnblad residence?
Yes.
Mr. Pinky speakin'.
Mr. Pinky from-from the dress shop?
Uh-huh.
I'd like Tracy
for our spokesgirl.
You want Tracy to do what?
Be our spokesgirl.
Be a spokesgirl?
I think she'd be perfect.
I'd like to meet her...
and discuss the details.
As soon as possible.
OK, um, well, we'll have send
someone down to meet you.
Tonight, if you can.
So, um, oh, OK.
Bye-bye, Mr. Pinky.
Bye-bye.
The Mr. Pinky?
From Mr. Pinky's hefty hideaway!
A spokesgirl?!
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh, tell me I get a free caftan, tell me!
Oh, Tracy, I think perks like
caftans have to be negotiated.
Maybe we should get you an agent.
OK. You be my agent.
What? Tracy Turnblad...
has fame gone to your head
and made you wacky?
Well, why not?
Who's goin' to look out for me...
better than my mom?
Me, an agent?
You see me hobnobbin'
and drinkin' rum and cokes...
with all those hoi pollois?
And out-negotiating them.
Oh, you're crazy.
Oh, Tracy, I haven't left
this house in-in years.
Then isn't it time you did?
Oh, no, Tracy.
We'll have your father meet with him.
L- I don't wanna be seen like this.
Why not?
I'll do it after my next diet.
That's when I'll do it.
Ya see, the neighbors haven't
seen me since I was a size 10.
Don't make me do it, Tracy.
Ma, it's changing out there.
You'll like it.
People who are different.
Their time is coming.
# Hey, Mama, hey, Mama, look around #
# Everybody's groovin'
to a brand-new sound #
# Hey, Mama, hey, Mama follow me #
# I know somethin's in ya
that you wanna set free #
# So let go, go, go of the past now #
# Say hello to the love in your heart #
# Yes, I know that
the world's spinning fast now #
# You gotta get yourself
a brand-new start #
# Hey, Mama, welcome to the sixties #
# Oh-o-o-o-o #
# Oh, Mama, welcome to the sixties #
# Go, Mama, go, go, go #
# Welcome to the sixties #
# Oh-o-o-o-o oh #
# Hey, Mama, yeah, yeah, yeah #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah #
# Hey, Mama, hey, Mama, have some fun #
# I haven't left this house since 1951 #
# Hey, Mama, hey, Mama, take a chance #
# Oh, Tracy, it's been years
since someone asked me to dance #
# So let go, go, go of the past now #
# Say hello to the light in your eyes #
# Yes, I know that the world's
spinning fast now #
# But you gotta run
the race to win the prize #
# Hey, Mama, welcome to the sixties #
# Oh-o-o-o-o #
# Oh, Mama, welcome to the sixties #
# Go, Mama, go, go, go #
# Welcome to the sixties #
Ma, you did it!
Oh, Tracy, I'm a little lightheaded.
There's so much air out here.
Can't we go someplace that's stuffy?
No, Ma, you're on your way.
# Hey, Mama, welcome to the sixties #
# Oh-o-o-o-o #
# Oh, Mama, welcome to the sixties #
# Oh-o-o-o-o-o #
# Go, Mama, go, go, go #
Oh. They're so glamorous.
Wow.
It kicked.
Let's toast to that.
To a boy!
# Yeah, yeah, yeah #
# Welcome to the rhythm
of a brand-new day #
# Take your old-fashioned fears #
# And just throw them away #
# You should add some color
and a fresh new 'do #
# 'Cause it's time for a star #
# Who looks just like you #
Ohh.
Ah!
Oh!
I thought we marked these down.
What?
Ohh.
Thank you, Nadine.
There's my shining star!
Fantastic to meet you!
I'm Mr. Pinky.
It's so nice to meet you.
Ha ha! Tracy, is this your older sister?
Oh, my.
Perhaps she'd like some
complimentary couture.
Couture?
Now, if you'll just sign here.
Flattery will not distract
Miss Turnblad's agent...
from reading the fine print.
Her agent?
Tracy, eat your donuts.
Let's talk.
Mm-hmm.
All right, let's see here.
All right. Now...
Mmm.
Uh-uh. Uh-uh. No!
I want a non-exclusive contract.
Extensions by mutual option.
And I want you to absorb
my 15 percent commission.
Not a dime over 10!
Throw in a bustier?
Hmm.
54 double D?
Triple E.
I hit the mother lode!
# Yeah, yeah, yeah #
Care for a Baby Ruth?
I got one right here.
# Oh-o-o-o-o #
# Oh, Mama, welcome to the sixties #
# Go, Mama, go, go, go #
# Don't-cha let nobody
try to steal your fun #
# 'Cause a little touch of
lipstick never hurt no one #
# The future's got a million
roads for you to choose #
# But you'll walk a little taller
in some high-heeled shoes #
# And once you find the style
that makes you feel like you #
# Something fresh,
something new #
# Step on out, hear us shout #
# Mama, that's your cue #
# Ba da ba da-ba-da #
# Step on out, hear us shout #
# Mama, that's your cue #
# Hey, Tracy, hey, baby, look at me #
# I'm the cutest chickie
that you ever did see #
# Hey, Tracy, hey, baby, look at us #
# Where is there a team
that's half as fabulous #
# I let go, go, go of the past now #
# Said hello to this red carpet ride #
# Yes, I know that the world's
spinning fast now #
# Tell Lollobrigida to step aside #
# Your Mama's welcoming the sixties #
# Oh-o-o-o-o #
# Ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-baby #
# Go, Mama, go, go, go #
# Welcome to the sixties #
# Open the door to the girl who has more #
# She's a star, Tracy, go, go, go #
# Hey, Mama, welcome to the sixties #
# Your mama's hip, your mama's in #
# Hey, Mama #
# Your mama's lookin' at herself
and wonderin' "Where you been?" #
# Where you been? #
# Your mama's lit, she's all aglow #
# Your mama, what she's holdin' back #
# Your mama's gotta let go, go, go #
# Welcome to the "six", to the "O" #
# To the apostrophe "s"
hey-yay, baby, yeah #
# Oh-o-o-o-o #
# Oh, yeah #
# Go, Mama, go, go, go #
# Oh-o-o-o-o-o,
oh-o-o-o-o-o #
# Oh-o-o-o-o go,
go, Mama, go, go, go! #
Mmm. Mmm.
Wait till Dad sees you.
Sees me?
He never notices what I wear.
In 20 years, he's never even said to me,
"nice muumuu" or nothin'.
Now he will.
Well, maybe, if he leaves
that shop for 5 minutes.
I swear, I don't know
what goes on down there.
Well.
Mrs. Turnblad.
I'd know whose mother
you were anywhere.
Really?
Hello, Amber.
Hello, Tracy.
Ma, this is Amber and Mrs. von Tussle.
Mrs. von Tussle is the station's manager.
Oh, the station manager.
Oh! Oh, it was so nice-a
you let her on that show.
Well, Tracy certainly has...
redefined our standards. Ha ha!
That's for sure.
Let me guess...
brand-new dress?
Oh, yes.
Well, you'll stop traffic.
Ha ha ha.
It was nice meeting you. Tracy.
Bye, Tracy.
Ugh.
Ma, don't listen to a word she says!
I'm takin' this back.
Don't you dare.
- I am.
- Don't you dare.
Don't you know why she hates us?
She's afraid I'll beat Amber
for Miss Teenage Hairspray.
Really?
They can't put Tracy in special ed.
I won't have it.
I mean, even if I have to tutor her myself...
they cannot hold my friend back.
- You're a saint.
- Mm.
Oh, and it's totally not true about her
and the entire football team.
I mean, please.
Anybody can get grass stains
all over their back.
Amber, stop it.
I'm sick-a you doin' that.
Just because she's a good dancer.
Uh! I'm sorry.
You think that she can dance?
Well, maybe you'd rather
have her as your partner.
You could get sponsored by Goodyear.
Excuse me. What is
going on back there?
Tracy, that's horrible.
Mr. Flak does not have breasts.
What? No. I would-I would never.
What... Oh.
Oh, and Mr. Larkin,
perhaps you'd like to share...
with the rest of the class Patrick Henry's
immortal last words.
"Kiss my ass"?
You didn't have to do that, Link.
Hey, no prob.
Besides, looks like
a cool scene down here.
Right.
Hey, cool.
Hey, Tracy!
Not quite, huh?
Ah, damn. Just when I was gettin' it.
Listen, man,
you ain't gotta stop now.
My mom's havin' a platter party tonight.
Y'all wanna come check it out?
Now?!
Would you mind if I, too, checked it out?
I've never been to North Avenue before.
Uh, well, would it be safe?
You know, for us?
Calm down, cracker boy.
It's cool.
Wow.
Being invited places by colored people!
It feels so hip!
I'm glad y'all feel that way
'cause, uh, not many people do.
- Y'all know what I'm sayin'?
- Yeah, that's right.
# Hey! #
# I can't see why people look at me #
# And only see the color of my face #
# Ah, yeah, then there's those that try
to help, God knows #
# But always have to put me in my place #
# But I won't ask you to be color-blind #
# 'Cause if you pick the fruit then, girl,
you're sure to find #
# The blacker the berry,
the sweeter the juice #
# I could say it ain't so but, darlin',
what's the use? #
# The darker the chocolate,
the richer the taste #
# And that's where it's at #
# Now, baby, run and tell that #
# Now run and tell that #
# Run and tell that #
# Hey, yeah! #
# I can't see why people disagree #
# Each time I tell 'em what
I know is true, oh, no #
# And if you come #
# And see the world I'm from #
# I bet your heart is
gonna feel it, too, yeah #
# I could lie but, baby, let's be bold #
# vanilla can be nice #
# But if the truth be told #
# Blacker the berry,
the sweeter the juice #
# I could say it ain't so but, darlin',
what's the use? #
# The darker the chocolate,
the richer the taste #
# And that's where it's at #
# Oh, baby, baby, run and tell that #
# Run and tell that #
# Go run and tell that #
# Come on and run and tell that #
# Run and tell that #
# Hey, run and tell #
# Go tell #
# Run and tell that #
Link!
Link Larkin!
# Hey, yeah! #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah #
- Whoo!
- Hey!
Whoo!
# Whoo! #
Come here, girl.
This is my sister, Little Inez.
Oh, I know Tracy Turnblad.
Good for you, girl.
You got on the show.
- Well, you better be next.
- Ya got that right.
Oh, you know she is.
You better show 'em, girl.
Yeah!
# I'm tired of coverin' up all my pride #
# So give me five on the black hand side #
# I got a new way of movin'
and I got my own voice #
# So how can I help but
to shout and rejoice #
# Oh, the people 'round here
can barely pay their rent #
# They try to make a dollar
outta fifteen cent #
# But we got a spirit
money just can't buy #
# It's deep as a river
and soars to the sky, to the sky! #
# Hey, I can't see the reason it can't be #
# The kinda world where
we all get our chance #
# Aw, yeah #
# The time is now #
# So we can show 'em how
just turn the music up #
# And let's all dance, yeah, yeah #
# 'Cause all things are equal
when it comes to love #
# Well, that ain't quite true
'cause when push comes to shove #
# The blacker the berry,
the sweeter the juice #
# They say it ain't so but, darlin',
what's the use? #
# The darker the chocolate,
the richer the taste #
# And that's where it's at #
# Now, baby, baby, baby,
run and tell that #
# Run and tell that #
# Ah yeah, baby#
# Go run and tell that #
# G-g-g-g-go home
and run and tell that #
# Yeah, yeah #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah #
# Whoo! #
- Go, baby!
- Whoo!
It was horrible.
Mom, he just danced on that bus...
with that great white whale
and those negroes.
No, honey.
Reeling him back in is
the easiest thing in the world.
Remember, I control his career.
Ohh.
Now, don't worry.
Mommy will take care of everything.
Are you all hungry
for some good fun?
# Yeah #
# Bring on that pecan pie #
# Pour some sugar on it,
sugar, don't be shy #
# Scoop me up a mess
of that chocolate swirl #
# Don't be stingy,
I'm a growin' girl #
# I offer big love with no apology #
# How can I deny
the world the most of me? #
# I am not afraid
to throw my weight around #
# Pound by pound by pound #
# Because I'm big,
blonde and beautiful #
# Face the fact,
it's simply irrefutable #
# No one wants a meal
that only offers the least #
# When, girl, we're servin'
up the whole damn feast #
Well, looks like y'all
took a step outta bounds.
Now, who we got here?
Mom, I want you to meet my new friends.
This here is Link. Tracy Turnblad.
This is just so afro-tastic!
And this young lady right here...
is Penny Pingleton.
I'm very pleased
and scared to be here.
Oh, now, honey. We got more reason
to be scared on your street.
Latoya, put that record down.
You gonna scratch it.
Can't you keep your little girl...
Shall we dance?
Come on.
My name is Mike.
Mike?
Yes, Mike.
Mike who?
It's Mike.
Anyway, ahem...
I'm calling because
I have some information...
about your daughter's whereabouts.
- What?
- Right now, as we speak...
your daughter has entered
a hotbed of moral...
turpentine.
# Baby don't sleep #
# Baby don't eat #
# Baby just like another boink-boink #
Link, aren't you gonna get
in awful trouble for this?
I'm not plannin' on tellin' my dad.
No, I mean in trouble
with someone else.
Hmm. Maybe.
Maybe it's worth it.
I think knowin' you's the start
of a pretty big adventure.
Ahh!
Tracy Edna Turnblad!
Ooh, we get any more
white people in here...
this gonna be a suburb.
Do you know what I had to pay a cab...
just to consider comin' down here?
Oh, uh, Mom-
No call. You just disappear.
And all mashed up against a crooner?
Um, Edna Turnblad, this is Link.
Come on, we're goin'.
And, Penny, go home before
your mother shoots you.
Miss Edna, is it?
Hi, I mean, you don't
have to rush off, you know.
Well, I do. I left my iron on.
Oh, your iron.
Well, before you go...
you sure you
wouldn't like to have...
a little somethin' to eat?
Mmm-mmm.
Is that braised?
# Whoa oh oh oh oh oh #
# Slice me off a piece
of that hogshead cheese #
# Whoo! #
# And take a look inside #
# My book of recipes #
# Now, don't-cha sniff around
for somethin' fluffy and light #
# We need a man who brings
a man-size appetite #
# We'll use a pinch-a sugar
and a dash-a spice #
# I'll let you lick the spoon
because it tastes so nice #
# We keep it in the oven
till it's good and hot #
# Keep on stirrin' till it hits the spot #
# Because I'm big,
blonde and beautiful #
# There is nothin' 'bout us
that's unsuitable #
# Why sit in the bleachers
timid and afraid #
# When, Edna, you look
like the whole parade? #
# They say that white
has might and thin is in #
# Well, that's just bull #
# 'Cause, ladies, big is back #
# And as for black, it's beautiful #
# All shapes and sizes follow me #
# Who wants a twig when
you can climb a whole tree #
# Yeah, yeah #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah #
Groovy, baby. Groovy.
Hello?
Hello?!
- Graah!
- Oh, my God!
Ha ha ha! Ha ha ha!
Ah! You got me.
Ha ha ha!
Welcome, mmm,
to the Hardy-Har Hut.
If we can't put a smile on your face,
your skin's too tight.
- Oh!
- Bop, bop.
- Oh.
- I got somethin' for ya. Yeah.
It's just in.
You're gonna love it.
Huh?
Oh.
Cigarette?
Ha ha ha.
Tempting but, uh... no, thanks.
- Ha ha ha!
- Oh.
Well, eh.
What can I do you for?
Something for the mister?
Sadly, there is no mister at the moment.
Beautiful woman like yourself?
My husband...
...accidentally suffocated.
You need a fella.
I do. I do need a fella.
And the way to a man's heart
is through his funny bone.
Now here's an icebreaker for ya.
Oh, Miss Maybelle,
you do throw a lovely party.
But what are you celebratin'?
Well, it's kind of an ending.
But it deserved to go out with a bang.
What ended?
Negro Day.
What?
All right. Time y'all knew.
velma von Tussle just told me
we have had our last show.
No.
Yeah, it seems our little show
was a nice little placeholder...
- but it was time to get some ratings.
- Aww!
I didn't wanna tell y'all up front.
I just wanted to have a little fun tonight.
But I practiced so hard.
Now I'll never get a chance
to be on the show.
Oh, you will be seen, baby.
I promise.
You can't have your own show?
Fine, you'll come dance with us.
Hmm. Honey.
You been dozin' off durin' history?
Yes, always.
Trace, black and whites ain't never danced
on Tv together.
Well, if we can't dance...
maybe we should just march.
Ooh, that'd get some big ol' ratin's.
Better time slot, too.
Mm-hmm.
Like on the 11:00 news.
Ahh!
What y'all say?
Should we give this fine woman...
all the ratings she deserves?
- Yeah!
Hey, hey!
Well, it is a school night...
and I think we oughta call it a night.
Tell you what.
We meet up at the church Friday, 4:00...
and we will march on WYZT.
- Yeah!
Yeah!
Tracy, you can't protest, hon.
I mean, these are lovely people...
but if you protest, you'll be on lists.
You'll be on files.
J. Edgar Hoover'll be still wiretappin'...
your cold, dead body in the grave.
Oh, Mother.
Link, we're going with them, right?
Walk with me.
You want your Belgian chocolate
animal droppings.
Dot dot. This store's for you.
- Oh! What a treasure trove.
- Huh?
Come here, baby.
Don't be sad.
We gonna make it happen, OK?
Can I go?
Now, come on, now.
I can't be worried about you out there.
Trace...
I been smilin' and dancin'
on this show for 3 years.
Mrs. von Tussle just promised...
I could sing at the Miss Hairspray pageant.
She's-she invited agents.
That's my shot, Trace.
I can't jeopardize that.
But it's what's right.
I'm sorry, Trace.
I just think this adventure's...
a little...
too big for me.
Oh, God. No, no, no.
That's not what I-
I get it, Link. It's your shot.
No, Trace, that's not what I-
It's fine.
Oh, hon.
I should go.
Give him time.
He'll figure out he's crazy 'bout you.
You have to say that,
you're my mother.
Well, I know a little
somethin' about men.
And, my personal favorite,
x- ray specs.
You can see through anything.
Skin, clothes, you name it.
Now, take your father.
And he's always downstairs
in that shop workin' late.
Do I take it personal? No.
Men always put their career first.
Remember that.
OK.
I'm really tired, I'm gonna go to bed.
All right, hon.
Night.
- I love you.
- I love you, too.
I think I'm gonna go to bed, too.
Oh, I'm so tired.
You don't need those...
to see what's under these clothes.
There's a product that really works...
'cause these are phony
as a three dollar bill.
Incredible!
I could do a fan dance with a lettuce leaf...
and you would remain completely obtuse.
Obtuse.
Yes, obtuse.
I flunked geometry.
Yeah, well-and biology too, no doubt!
Yeah.
Wait! How 'bout this?
OK.
# Those lips, those eyes #
# That food #
# Well, there ain't nothin' like a spread #
# To get ya in the mood #
# Wilbur, can't ya feel the
burnin' flame of hot desire #
# You're gonna need
more than some seltzer #
# To put out this fire #
# I'm wailin': "look out, old Balti- #
# "- more" I'm sellin' somethin' #
# You can't purchase
at a ten-cent store #
# Oh, Wilbur, I feel like a princess #
# Come on and take me to the ball #
# I bet you're tired of heavy lifting #
# Get your hands on somethin' small #
# Because I'm a-big- #
# -blonde- #
# -and beautiful #
# It's time to face the facts #
# It's irrefutable #
# Why waste one more minute #
# Now I feel brand spankin' new #
# Hey, Wilbur, take a look #
# It's all for #
You!
You?!
Ohh!
Edna.
Your wife! You said she was out! Oh!
Wait a minute!
Hi, hon.
Ma, you don't really believe
that he would do that.
You are never setting foot
on that show again.
You hear me?
I heard you the first 400 times, Ma.
- Hey.
- Huh.
Oh.
Daddy.
It wasn't me.
I had to improvise
a bed out of something.
Whoopee cushions?
That will play heck with my sciatica.
Oop. That one was me.
Oh. Oh.
Daddy, are you OK?
Ohh.
Tracy, you know...
these peepers have never
looked at another woman.
This heart only beats for size 60.
Daddy, you know what velma wanted.
She wanted me off the show.
And I knew that,
but how could she go that far?
Come here. Come here, little girl.
Little girl.
And then to just cancel
Negro Day like that.
Just to make sure that
nobody who's different...
or who's black or Chinese...
or maybe who needs to lose a few pounds.
What are you talking? Stop it.
What are you talking?
I think I've been in a bubble or something.
Thinking that fairness
was just going to happen.
It's not.
I think people like me
are gonna have to get up...
off their father's laps and go
out there and fight for it.
Ahh. Your mother and I...
We don't see too far
past our front door.
But you... see all the way to Schenectady.
So, if there's something
you need to stand up for...
don't ya listen to old dogs like us.
We need to learn some new tricks...
from you.
You don't need new tricks, Dad.
You need Mom.
She changed the locks.
Oh.
Good night, Daddy.
Aw, wow.
Come on, baby.
Honey, took me 5 years...
to figure out you were flirting.
How could I ever?
Well, she is very glamorous.
Edna.
She just makes me feel old.
Nonsense.
Doll!
You're spry as a Slinky.
I'm not talkin' to you.
# Styles keep a-changin',
the world's rearrangin' #
# But, Edna,
you're timeless to me #
# Hemlines are shorter,
a beer costs a quarter #
# But time cannot take what comes free #
# You're like a stinky old cheese, babe #
# Just gettin' riper with age #
# You're like a fatal disease, babe #
What?
# But there's no cure,
so let this fever rage #
# Some folks can't stand it,
say time is a bandit #
# But I take the opposite view #
# 'Cause when I need a lift #
# Time brings a gift #
# Another day with you #
# A twist or a waltz #
# It's all the same schmaltz #
# With just a change in the scenery #
# You'll never be old hat #
# That's that #
# You're timeless to me #
# Fads keep a-fadin' #
# Castro's invadin' #
# But, Wilbur,
you're timeless to me #
# Hairdos are higher #
# Mine feels like barbed wire #
# But you say I'm chic as can be #
# You're like a rare vintage ripple #
Thank you.
# A vintage they'll never forget #
# So pour me a teeny-weeny triple #
Any time!
# And we can toast the fact
we ain't dead yet #
What?
# I can't stop eating #
# Your hairline's receding #
Hey.
# And soon
you'll have nothing at all #
Never.
# So you'll wear a wig #
# While I roast a pig #
# Hey! Pass that Geritol #
I love pig.
# Glenn Miller had brass #
# That Chubby Checker's a gas #
# But they all pass eventually #
# You'll never be passé, hip-hooray #
# You're timeless to me #
Heh heh heh!
Grrr!
# You're like a broken-down Chevy #
# All I need is a fresh coat of paint #
# And, Edna, ya got me
goin' hot and heavy #
# You're fat and old #
- What?
- # But, baby, boring you ain't #
# Some folks don't get it #
# But we never fret it #
# 'Cause we know
that time is our friend #
# Yeah, it's plain to see #
# That you're stuck with me #
# Until the bitter end #
# And we got a kid who's blowin' the lid #
# Off the Turnblad family tree #
# You'll always hit the spot #
# Big shot #
# You're timeless to me #
# You'll always be du jour, mon amour #
# You'll always be first string #
# Ring-a-ding-ding #
# You're timeless to me #
# You're timeless #
# To me #
Oh, Wilbur.
Tracy.
Wake up, hon.
Wake up. Everything's good again.
Wilbur! Wilbur!
Uhh!
Seaweed, help pass
those signs out.
Give her one.
Hey, Jackie, we're over here.
Aw, you
lookin' good, Gertrude.
C'mon, y'all.
Here we go now.
Tracy!
You're gonna pay a heavy price.
I know.
You'll never dance on Tv again.
If I can't dance
with Seaweed and Little Inez...
then I don't wanna dance on Tv at all.
I just want tomorrow to be better.
# There's a light #
# In the darkness #
# Though the night
is black as my skin #
# There's a light burnin' bright #
# Showing me the way #
# But I know where I've been #
# There's a cry #
# In the distance #
# It's a voice that comes
from deep within #
# Hey, yeah #
# There's a cry askin' why #
# I pray the answer's up ahead #
# 'Cause I know where I've been #
# There's a road #
# We been travelin' #
# Lost so many #
# On the way #
# But the riches will be plenty #
# Worth the price #
# The price we had to pay #
# There's a dream #
- # In the future #
- # Ooh-ooh #
# There's a struggle #
# That we have yet to win #
# And there's pride in my heart #
# 'Cause I know where I'm goin' #
# Yes, I do #
# And I know where I've been #
# Yeah #
# There's a road #
# We must travel #
# There's a promise #
# There is a promise #
# We must make #
# That we must make #
# But the riches #
# Oh, but the riches #
# Will be plenty #
# The riches will be plenty, yeah #
# Worth the risk #
# And the chances that we take #
# And the chances we take #
# There's a dream #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, in the future #
# There's a struggle #
# Struggle #
# That we have yet to win #
# We have yet to win #
# Use that pride #
# Pride #
# In our hearts #
# To lift us up #
# Lift us up #
# Until tomorrow #
# Oooh #
# 'Cause just to sit
still would be a sin #
# I know it, I know it,
I know where I'm goin' #
# Lord knows I know #
# Where I've been #
# Oh, when we win #
# Yeah, I'll give thanks to my God #
# 'Cause I know where I've been #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah #
Oh, yeah, amen!
Amen, amen!
That's right.
Tracy, hon, you don't
know what you're doing.
Yes, I do, Ma.
Hello, Miss Maybelle.
Well, good evening, Miss Edna.
Nice-a you to join us.
She's got a lovely turnout.
Now I really think they
don't need you anymore.
You come home with me.
Oh.
No, we are not sending a camera crew.
They're protesting
our own station, dimwit.
Why is Channel Five there?
Well, of course they're all Negroes.
And why would-?
Ahh! Ohh.
I know who would.
Oh, I know exactly who would.
2, 4, 6, 8!
Tv's got to integrate!
2, 4, 6, 8! Tv's got to integrate!
2, 4, 6, 8!
Oh, my God, no!
Tv's got to integrate!
- No!
- Ma, come on.
The sound's not working.
You knew there'd be police.
- But I didn't know there'd be cameras.
- So?
Oh, I cannot be seen on television
at this present weight.
2, 4, 6, 8!
Tv's got to integrate!
Excuse me.
Is there some reason
we can't pass by peacefully?
I strongly suggest you
and your little friends...
head back to where you come from.
Hey, you don't have to be so rude.
Tracy!
It's all right, Tracy.
I can handle this.
'Scuse me. She was talking to you.
- Oh, Tracy!
- Oh!
Tracy, no.
You just assaulted a police officer, miss.
- No!
- I what?!
Assaulted?!
Enough! Hey!
All right, boys.
Let's take the whole lot in.
- No!
- Run, Tracy! Run!
2, 4, 6, 8! Tv's got to integrate!
2, 4, 6, 8!
Tv's got to integrate!
2, 4, 6, 8! Tv's got to integrate!
2, 4, 6, 8!
Tv's got to integrate!
And our cameras also
caught Tracy Turnblad...
the teenage Tv personality
and rabble-rouser.
Miss Turnblad brutally
attacked a sergeant...
with a blunt instrument
before fleeing the scene...
You see? You see?
If I let you leave the house...
right now you'd be in prison
fighting whores for cigarettes.
That Tracy Turnblad always
was a bad influence.
Well, you are never, ever gonna see that
beehived harlot again.
OK, Mother. Excuse me.
Penny?
Pray for her.
She's gonna need it.
Tracy! Tracy!
She's not here, I told you.
Hon, she knows...
if the cops are lookin' for her...
this is the first place they'll come.
What this must-a put you through, Wilbur.
I'm so sorry.
I'm not.
You're not?
I'm proud-a you.
You are?
Baby, somebody had to do somethin'.
'Course, we may be eating beans
for the next 10 years.
Bail for 20's kind of pricey.
You bailed all those people out?
Ya upset with me?
I'm sorry.
Hon, it just seemed like the right thing.
Oh, Wilbur, it was the right thing.
Knights in armor
don't come any shinier than you.
But where's our little girl?
Are you OK, Trace?
Oh, you have no idea.
Come on.
Thank you so much.
You're such a great friend.
Thanks.
Penny, the cops are looking for me
everywhere.
You could go to jail for helping me.
Tracy, I'm already in jail. Come on.
Oh, no.
- What?
- Your hair deflated.
Oh, let it.
It was just a symbol
of my conformity to the man.
You are so tough.
So, what do ya think?
Maybe you could live down here.
I don't even know why we
have this room down here...
but there's food, water...
first aid kit, gas mask,
Russian-language books.
It's very well-insulated.
It won't be where you're going.
The police are on their way.
Mom, please don't send my best friend
to the big house.
Penny, hush.
You haven't heard the last
of me, Mrs. Pingleton.
Things need to change...
and I won't stop tryin' to change them.
I don't care how long it takes.
Good, you'll be waiting 20 to life.
Get the jump rope, Penny.
Mom, not the jump rope!
Don't you touch my canned tuna.
You wait till your father
gets out of prison.
You'll see more than a jump rope, missy!
A massive manhunt is
underway for Miss Turnblad...
who bludgeoned sergeant and
decorated Korean war veteran...
Mike Morris with a crowbar,
shattering his jaw...
That is a lie.
They're talkin' about our baby, Wilbur.
They're tellin' lies.
Sergeant Morris is in critical condition.
This is such a Midol moment.
Wilbur, that-Oh! Maybe that's her.
Oh, that's her.
Is that you, Tracy?
Oh, Link. I thought you'd be Tracy.
Uh, no. L-I was just at home, uh...
practicing my new twist on the twist...
and I overheard it on the news.
I can't believe Tracy savagely bludgeoned
an Eagle Scout.
That's just not like her.
Well, it's not true, I was there.
He didn't even bleed.
I shoulda been there...
beside her.
I can't sleep, I can't eat.
You can't eat?
Well, come on in and worry with us.
I'll make you some pork.
Penny Lou Pingleton, you are absolutely...
positively, permanently punished.
You will live on a diet
of saltines and Tang...
and you will never leave
this room again.
Devil child! Devil child!
Seaweed. Shh, don't let her hear you.
Penny, what happened to you?
She's punishing me
for harboring a fugitive...
without her permission.
What are you doing?
I'm here to rescue the fair maiden, baby.
Oh, Seaweed, you do care.
I was afraid the colors of
our skin would keep us apart.
No. These knots might.
W- Was your mom in the navy?
# Once I was a selfish fool
who never understood #
# Never looked inside myself #
# Though on the outside, I looked good #
# Then we met and you made me
the man I am today #
# Tracy, I'm in love with you,
no matter what you weigh #
# 'Cause without love #
# Life is like the seasons
with no summer #
# Without love #
# Life is rock 'n' roll without a drummer #
# Tracy, I'll be yours forever #
# 'Cause I never wanna be #
# Without love #
# Tracy, never set me free #
# No, I ain't lyin' #
# Never set me free #
# Tracy, no, no, no #
# Livin' in the ghetto,
black is everywhere ya go #
# Who'd've thought I'd love a girl #
# Whose skin was white
as winter snow? #
# In my ivory tower #
# Life was just a hostess snack #
# But now I've tasted chocolate #
# And I'm never going back #
# 'Cause without love #
# Life is like a beat
that you can't follow #
# Without love #
# Life is Doris Day at the Apollo #
# Darling, I'll be yours forever #
# 'Cause I never wanna be #
# Without love #
# So, darling, never set me free, no #
# I'm yours forever,
never set me free #
# No, no, no #
# If I'm left without my baby doll #
# I don't know what I'll do #
# Link, I've got to break out #
# So that I can get my hands on you #
# Girl, if I can't touch you,
then I'm gonna lose control #
# Seaweed, you're
my black white knight #
# I've found my blue-eyed soul #
# Sweet freedom is our goal #
# Trace, I wanna kiss ya! #
# Let me out at the next toll! #
# Without love #
# Life is like a prom that won't invite us #
# It's like getting my big break
and laryngitis #
# Without love #
# Life's a 45 when you can't buy it #
# Life is like my mother on a diet #
# Like a week that's only Mondays #
# Only ice cream, never sundaes #
# Like a circle with no center #
# Like a door marked "do not enter" #
# Darling, I'll be yours forever #
# 'Cause I never wanna be #
# Without love #
# Yes, now you've captured me #
# I surrender happily #
# Without love #
# Oh, Seaweed, never set me free #
# No, no, no #
# I ain't lyin' #
# Never set me free #
# No, no, no #
# No, I don't wanna live without #
# Love, love, love #
# Pretty Penny little #
# Darling, you had best believe me #
# Never leave me without love #
Link.
Your pork is ready.
Uh, Mama, I-
You tryin' to hide her here?
Uh.
Why you ain't think-a that before?
Everything she done for us.
Where your manners at, boy?
Ow! Well, I don't know.
And what about this one?
Seaweed's got a girlfriend.
Inez, shut up.
- You.
- Oh.
So this is love.
Well, love is a gift.
Lotta people don't remember that.
So you two better brace yourselves...
for a whole lotta ugly comin' at you...
from a never-ending parade of stupid.
So you met my mom?
Hello?
- Mom?
- Tracy, are you OK?
- Yes, I'm safe.
- Oh, my God.
- Mom, listen.
- Where are you?
- I need your help.
- What?
Tomorrow's the Miss
Teenage Hairspray pageant.
Tracy, you-
I need you to come down to the station.
Well-well, Tracy-
- Dress nice.
- What?
Penny will meet you out front.
Now let me talk to Dad.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Turn your face this way.
The other way. Go.
Everybody,
please take your seats.
The Miss Teenage Hairspray
pageant is about to begin.
Oh, you've come on a very exciting day.
It's our first live show.
Oh! Bye Bye, Birdie.
Oh, my Amber is perfect for that.
She's the pretty little blonde. Ha ha!
And we're live in 5, 4, 3...
And now, broadcast live
in front of a live studio audience...
for the first time from the certified...
up-to-code WYZT studio...
it's the Corny Collins Miss Hairspray
spectacular.
- He's Corny.
Brought to you by Ultra Clutch hairspray.
# What gives a girl power and punch #
# Is it charm, is it poise #
# No, it's hairspray #
# What gets a gal asked out to lunch #
# Is it brains, is it dough
No, it's hairspray #
# If you take a ride with
no can at your side... #
"and preserve our family
through our father. " Hmm.
"Let us make our father drink
wine, and let us lie with him. "
# You can take off in a rocket #
# And in outer space each
hair will be in place... #
Link, the agents are here. Look.
# Why take a chance when
you get up and dance? #
# If you twist, I insist #
# You use hairspray
and tell your mother... #
Maybe they'll sign us together.
# Her head she should smother #
# With Ultra Clutch faithfully #
Well?
There's no sign of her.
We're on every door. She's not inside.
Doesn't mean she won't try.
velma, I seriously doubt
this girl's gonna risk...
incarceration to win a pageant.
# That's me! #
I risked communicable diseases.
She'll certainly risk jail.
# Better than hairspray #
# That's me #
# Ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh,
ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh #
# Ahh, ahh, ahh, ahh #
# What makes a man
reach out and touch? #
# Ultra Clutch #
# So if you're a redhead,
a blonde, or brunette #
Whoo!
# Just take my advice
and you might just get #
# The only thing better
than hairspray #
# That's me #
Ah!
# He's Corny Collins #
# The only thing better
than hairspray #
- # Hairspray #
- Wow!
# That's me #
Hey, baby, you look like
you could use a stiff one.
# Whoo-ooo #
And we are out.
Link, you sprayed it right in my face!
What'd I tell you about that?
Stop! You guys.
Uh, powder.
And we're back.
5, 4.
Here?
3.
And now for the talent
portion of our competition...
our Councilettes...
in their Miss Teenage Hairspray
official dance-off.
Uh!
First off, we have the sunny
pride of Highlandtown, Darla.
Hello, Darla.
Miss Teenage Hairspray.
Your vote is for?
This little girl could power...
all of greater downtown Baltimore...
with her energy-Lou Ann.
Who are you voting for?
Lou Ann?
very good, thank you.
All right.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the almost too happy Tammy.
And thank you, Tammy.
Confirmed sighting.
What?
You three: Outside, now.
We can't go out th-
No, no. No buts. Out, out!
Out! Out, out, out, out!
Whatever you say, Mrs. von Tussle.
Whoo!
Aw, she's too cute, isn't she?
Hold it right there, Tracy.
Looking for someone?
All right, ladies and gentlemen.
- Ha.
- A what?
It was a diversion.
Oh, please, these people are
not capable of a diversion.
It's beyond their mental capacity.
I wouldn't be so sure, velma.
Oh, my God.
What if she's already in the building?
What if she's been here for hours...
and you've locked yourselves out?
What?
- Check the doors!
- Let's go!
It's locked!
They're all locked!
And now a fast girl
who loves to slow dance...
our own smooth-as-silk Shelley.
Ohh!
Keep goin'. Keep goin'. That's it.
Come on.
Put your backs into it, men.
Put your backs into it this time.
Come on, one more time.
One more time.
Come on, come on, come on.
Here's our little dynamic
duo from Conkling Street.
Double your fun
with Noreen and Doreen.
What is with you people?
I mean, how hard is it
to beat down a door?
That hairspray battering ram was heavy.
Heavy?
How could they be heavy, they're...
hollow.
Move it.
Let's get 'em. Let's go.
And, of course...
our three-time
Miss Hairspray champion...
the ever-charming, Amber.
Oh, my God.
You carried her in!
Go!
Ow!
It's locked.
Open it!
Let's give
a final round of applause...
to our Miss Teenage
Hairspray contestants.
Hey.
All right, all right.
We are so close to announcing...
the new Miss Teenage Hairspray.
Look at that board.
What a nail-biter this one is turning into.
Ladies and gentlemen, the final tally.
It is my...
obligation...
to announce that Amber von Tussle...
Is about to get out-danced.
Tracy Turnblad!
What!?
# You can't stop an avalanche #
# As it races down the hill #
# You can try to stop the seasons, girl #
# But 'cha know you never will #
# And you can try
to stop my dancin' feet #
# But I just cannot stand still #
# 'Cause the world keeps
spinnin' round and round #
# And my heart's keepin' time
to the speed of sound #
# I was lost till I heard the drums #
- # Then I found my way #
- No.
- # 'Cause you can't stop the beat #
- Link!
# Ever since this old world began #
# A woman found out if she shook it #
# She could shake up a man #
# And so I'm gonna
shake and shimmy it #
This throne is mine!
# The best that I can today #
# 'Cause you can't stop #
Aah! Let me down!
# The motion of the ocean
or the sun in the sky #
# You can wonder if you wanna
but I never ask why #
# And if you try to hold me down #
# I'm gonna spit in your eye #
# And say #
# That you can't stop the beat #
They love you, Link.
Yeah?
Not for long.
Inez, come on!
Let's dance.
Little Miss Inez Stubbs!
Ladies and gentlemen.
Look at my baby go.
- Inez.
- Inez?
- Mm.
- Come on.
Oh! There you go!
Give her a hand, folks!
Little Miss Inez Stubbs!
Ladies and gentlemen.
# You can't stop a river
as it rushes to the sea #
# You can try to stop
the hands of time #
# But 'cha know it just can't be #
# And if they try to stop us, Seaweed #
# We'll call the N-double-A-C-P #
# 'Cause the world keeps
spinnin' round and round #
# And my heart's keepin' time
to the speed of sound #
# I was lost till I heard the drums #
# Then I found my way #
# 'Cause you can't stop the beat #
# Ever since we first saw the light #
# A man and woman liked to shake it #
# On a Saturday night #
# And so I'm gonna
shake and shimmy it #
- # With all of my might #
- Mother!
# Today #
# 'Cause you can't stop
the motion of the ocean #
# Or the rain from above #
# They can try to stop the paradise #
Hello?! Hello?!
# We're dreamin' of
but you cannot stop #
# The rhythm of two hearts in love #
# To stay #
# 'Cause you can't stop the beat #
Aah! Aah!
Ahh!
Amen.
I am now a checkerboard chick.
Penny!
No!
Aah!
Mommy.
Ow.
Live television: There's nothin' like it.
Penny!
And now, it's the moment
you've all been craving for.
We have to wait till
they go to commercial.
As you know, we've kept the lines open up
to the last minute.
And those lines have been
burnin' up our switchboard.
Never in the history of this pageant...
has there been such a surge of late voting.
Baltimore, you've picked a winner.
And the new Miss Hairspray is...
- Inez Stubbs!
- What?!
Inez, you done it! You did it!
How about that?
Yes!
Come on over here, Little Inez.
Go, babe!
Oh! Inez!
Oh, my God!
Ohh!
That's my baby!
That's my baby girl!
But... She's...
she's not even a candidate.
She just got a tidal wave
of calls, velma.
But this is invalid.
This is impossible.
Well, anyone who dances
for it is eligible.
Rule 30, paragraph 5, asterisk,
down at the bottom. OK.
Well, this also makes you the lead dancer
on The Corny Collins Show.
Ladies and gentlemen,
The Corny Collins Show...
is now and forever officially integrated!
Oh, oh! Oh!
All right. Yeah.
Interracial dancing has broken out
at the WYZT stage.
Just look at the crowd's reaction.
Back to you, Steve.
# I was lost till I heard the drums #
# Then I found my way #
# 'Cause you can't stop the beat #
Amber, stop it!
I lost, Mom.
Let's just deal with it.
No, you did not lose.
You cannot have lost...
because I switched the damn tallies.
Smile, Miss Crabmeat.
You're on Candid Camera.
That was a good shot, don't you think?
Not bad.
Ha ha ha! What are you doing?
Get that away from me!
Go to commercial!
Go!
velma!
Pack your desk.
You've tainted the name of Ultra Clutch.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
How can you taint a cancerous
can-a chemicals?
You're fired!
I ca-I can't be fired.
Oh, yeah?
Last chance
to join the dance, folks.
Everyone is welcome!
Wilbur.
Do it now, or forever wish you had.
Really?
Show 'em, baby.
Nobody can dance like you.
# You can't stop my happiness #
# 'Cause I like the way I am #
# And ya just can't stop
my knife and fork #
# When I see a Christmas ham #
# So if you don't like the way I look #
# Well, I just don't give a damn #
# 'Cause the world keeps spinnin'
round and round #
# And my heart's keepin' time
to the speed of sound #
# I was lost till I heard the drums #
# Then I found my way #
# 'Cause you can't stop the beat #
# Ever since this old world began #
# A woman found out if she shook it #
# She could shake up a man #
# And so I'm gonna shake and shimmy it #
# The best that I can today #
# 'Cause you can't stop #
# The motion of the ocean
or the sun in the sky #
# You can wonder if you wanna
but I'll never ask why #
# And if you try to hold me down #
# I'm gonna spit in your eye #
# And say #
# That you can't stop the beat #
Whoa!
Oh! I love you!
You did great!
Corny, do something.
The show is turning to gumbo.
Not a chance, velma.
This is the future.
Maybelle, let's go.
This is your time.
Yeah.
All right, Miss buttercup.
It's time to wrap this mutha up.
# Oh, oh, oh #
- # You can't stop today #
- No!
# As it comes speedin' down the tracks #
# Ooh, child, yes #
# Child, yesterday is history #
Be gone!
# And it's never comin' back #
# Look ahead! #
# 'Cause tomorrow is a brand-new day #
# And it don't know white from black #
Yeah!
# 'Cause the world keeps
spinnin' round and round #
# And my heart's keepin'
time to the speed of sound #
# I was lost till I heard the drums #
# Then I found my way #
# 'Cause you can't stop the beat #
# Ever since we first saw the light #
# A man and woman
liked to shake it #
# On a Saturday night #
# And so I'm gonna
shake and shimmy it #
# With all of my might #
# Today #
# 'Cause you can't stop
the motion of the ocean #
# Or the rain from above #
# They can try to stop the paradise #
# We're dreamin' of #
# But you cannot stop #
# The rhythm of two hearts in love #
# To stay #
# 'Cause you can't stop the beat #
# Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa #
# Ever since we first saw the sun #
# A man and woman liked to shake it
when the day is done #
# And so we're gonna shake
and shimmy it #
# And have some fun today #
# 'Cause you can't stop #
# The motion of the ocean
or the rain from above #
# They can try to stop the
paradise we're dreamin' of #
# But you'll never stop the rhythm #
# Of two hearts in love to stay #
# 'Cause you can't stop the beat #
# You can't stop the beat #
# Ooh, ooh #
# Hey, old friend, let's look back #
# On the crazy clothes we wore #
# Ain't it fun to look back #
# To see it's all been done before #
# All those nights together #
# Are a special memory #
# And I can't wait for tomorrow #
# Just as long as you're
dancin' next to me #
# 'Cause it's so clear, every year #
# We get stronger #
# Stronger #
# 'Cause what's gone is gone,
the past is the past #
# Turn the radio up #
# And then hit the gas #
# 'Cause I know we've come so far #
# But we've got so far to go #
# I know the road seems long #
# But it won't be long
till it's time to go #
# So, most days, we'll take it fast #
# And some nights, we'll take it slow #
# I know we've come so far #
# But, baby, baby,
we've got so far to go #
# Oh, yeah #
# Baby #
# Hey, old friend, together #
# Side by side and year by year #
# The road was filled
with twists and turns #
# Oh, but that's the road
that got us here #
# Let's move past the bad times #
# But before those memories fade #
# Let's forgive but not forget #
# And learn from all
the mistakes we made #
# 'Cause it's so clear, every year #
# We get stronger #
# Stronger #
# So don't give up and don't say when #
# And just get back
on the road again #
# 'Cause I know we've come so far #
# But we've got so far to go #
# I know the road seems long #
# But it won't be long
till it's time to go #
# So, most days, we'll take it fast #
# And some nights, we'll take it slow #
# I know we've come so far #
# But, baby, baby,
we've got so far to go #
# Oh, yeah #
# Baby #
# Uh, uh, uh, uh #
# Hey, old friend, come
along for the ride #
# There's plenty of room so jump inside #
# The highway's bumpy
every now and then #
# But it's so much better
than where I've been #
# Just keep moving at your own speed #
# Your heart is all the compass
you'll ever need #
# Let's keep cruisin' the road we're on #
# 'Cause the rearview mirror
only shows what's #
# Gone, gone, gone #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah #
# Got so far to go #
# Ohh #
# Yeah #
# 'Cause it's so clear, every year #
# We get stronger #
# Stronger #
# So shine that light #
# Take my hand #
# And let's dance
into the promised land #
# 'Cause I know we've come so far #
# But we've got so far to go #
# I know the road seems long #
# But it won't be long
till it's time to go #
# So, most days, we'll take it fast #
# But some nights, we'll take it slow #
# I know we've come so far #
# But, baby, baby,
we've got so far to go #
# Oh, oh, oh, oh #
# Yeah, yeah #
# Welcome to the sixties #
Stop!
# Stop telling me what to do #
Don't!
# Don't treat me like a child of two #
No!
# I know that you want what's best #
Please!
# But, Mother, please #
# Give it a rest! #
# Stop! Don't! No! Please! #
# Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# Once upon a time
when I was just a kid #
# You never let me do
just what the older kids did #
# But lose that laundry list
of what you won't allow #
# 'Cause, Mama,
I'm a big girl now #
# Once upon a time
I played with childhood toys #
# But now I'd rather play around
with older boys #
# So, if I get a hickey,
please don't have a cow #
# 'Cause, Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# Ma, I gotta tell you
that without a doubt #
# I get my best dancing lessons
from you #
# You're the one who taught me
how to twist and shout #
# Because you shout non-stop
and you're so twisted, too! #
# Wo-oh-oh-oh-oh #
# Once I used to fidget
'cause I just sat home #
# But now I'm just like Gidget
and I gotta get to Rome! #
# So say, arrivederci! #
# Toodle-loo! #
# And ciao! #
# 'Cause, Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# Ohh, stop! Don't! No! Please! #
# Stop! Don't! No! Please! #
# Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# Hey, Mama, say, Mama #
# Once upon a time
I was a shy young thing #
# Could barely walk and talk
so much as dance and sing #
# But let me hit that stage,
I wanna take my bow #
# 'Cause, Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# Wo-oh-oh-oh-oh #
# Once upon a time
I used to dress up Ken #
# But now that I'm a woman,
I like bigger men #
# And I don't need a Barbie doll
to show me how #
# 'Cause, Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# Ooh, ooh, ah #
# Ma, you always taught me
what was right from wrong #
# And now I just wanna give it a try #
# Mama, I've been in the nest
for far too long #
# So please give a push
and, Mama, watch me fly #
# Watch me fly #
Show off.
# Someday I will meet
a man you won't condemn #
# And we will have some kids
and you can torture them #
# But let me be a star
before I take that vow #
# 'Cause, Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# Whoa-oh-oh #
# Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey! #
# Mama, I'm a big girl #
Ooh, such a big, big girl!
# I'm a big girl now #
# Whoa-oh-oh, whoaaaa! #
# Please, Mama, I'm a big girl now #
# They came from way
far out in outer space #
# She's hard to miss
and so they landed on her face #
# She's got cooties! #
# They've found a place to nest #
# She's got cooties #
# Cooties #
# If I were her, I'd be depressed #
# Long tailed, sharp nailed #
# Fuzzy legs, laying eggs #
# Oh, no, ew! #
# In science class she's like
a walking show-and-tell #
# Her pet skunk ran away
'cause it couldn't take the smell #
# She's got cooties #
# Nobody wants to sit by her #
# No, don't need a coat
'cause she's got fur! #
# Circle, circle, dot, dot, dot #
# Glad I got my cootie shot! #
# Come on, boys,
let's stamp 'em out! #
# Uh-uh-uh-uh,
uh-uh-uh-uh #
# Cootie, cootie #
# Come on, boys #
# Uh-uh-uh-uh,
uh-uh-uh-uh #
# Cootie, cootie #
# Come on, boys #
# Whoa, no, no, no #
# She's got cooties #
# She's just as friendly as can be #
# She shows them cootie hospitality #
# She's got cooties #
# She's like a living Twilight Zone #
# Can you get Rod Serling on the phone? #
# Black, white, red, green #
# Every color in between #
# Dresses like a circus clown #
# Somebody oughta hose her down #
# Grew up in a cootie zoo #
# I bet her two-ton
Mama's got 'em, too! #
# She-she-she's coming! #
# She's got cooties #
# Somebody oughta hose her down #
# Oh, yeah #
# She's got cooties #
# Somebody oughta hose her down #
# Yeah, yeah #
# She's got cooties #
# She's just as friendly as can be #
# She shows them cootie hospitality #
# She's got cooties #
# This girly surely catch your eye #
# She surely likes to
let her freak flag fly #
# Come on, boys #
# Let's jam #
# Let's hear it for Mama #
# Come on, boys, let's jam #
# Black, white, red, green #
# Every color in between #
# Dresses like a circus clown #
# Somebody oughta hose her down #
# Grew up in a cootie zoo #
# I bet her two-ton Mama's got 'em, too! #