SubRip by divx.NeKryXe.com
[Woman Singing]
** Heman dubh hirioro **
** Heman dubh hirio **
** Leaving the Lews **
** To leeward **
** Blithely **
** A-sailing seaward **
** White the keel **
** The curling wavelet **
** Tosses high **
** Spraying 'round **
* Tawny *
* The shelving shore *
* The seals that rise *
* Plunging *
* Beneath the water *
* In sharp surprise *
** With eyes of fear **
** And wild alarm **
**** [Fades Out]
** [Rock]
[Woman Continues]
** Leaving the Lews to leeward **
- ** Blithely **
- **** [Rock Fades]
** A-sailing seaward **
** White the keel **
** The curling wavelet **
* Tosses high *
* Spraying 'round *
**** [Rock Continues, Loudly]
- **** [Rock Stops]
- [Woman Continues]
** White the keel **
** The curling wavelet **
** Tosses high **
* Spraying 'round **
[Man] I can't see how
you can say that Roy Orbison...
had anything to do
with Pete Townshend whatsoever.
Now, that's just where
you're wrong, see?
Roy's use of feedback on the guitar solo
on "Ooby Dooby"...
- preceded Pete's stuff
by a good six or seven years.
- [Bell Dinging]
I'm sayin' that the use of feedback
in the rock guitar solo...
was further back than The Who.
Further than Orbison even,
back to the early electric blues
players in the '20s and '30s.
Well, they couldn't avoid feedback in
them days. The amps were rubbish, see?
That's my point.
Rock 'n' roll is not separate
from other music.
It's part of one big picture.
Like life. We're all connected.
If you're so smart, how come
you work as a housekeeper?
I'm an eccentric millionaire.
Why do you work as a gardener?
I am a gardener.
You've not had your coffee yet,
have you?
**** [Rock 'N'Roll]
** Your magic hands **
** Your loving eyes
Your kissable lips **
** Make my heart realize **
** I'm in love
I'm in love **
- **** [Continues, Indistinct]
- [Man] Cheeky Chops.
Can you hold, please?
Irene, 3.00. Yes, that'll be good.
Bye. Cheeky Chops.
** And I don't know what you got **
** But it's got me
and, baby, I'm hooked **
** Like a fish in the sea
You make angels call **
What exactly don't you like
about it, Mrs Williams?
It's a bit... African.
Ah, there she is,
my teenage biker princess.
Hi, Mum.
Hi, Gordo.
Oh, my God. Look at you. You look
like you slept in a tumble dryer.
Come here.
- Can I have 20 pounds, please, Mum?
- Why?
Well, I need currency to have a viable
existence in a capitalistic society.
- Ask a silly question...
- Why are you always
asking me for money?
I'm a teenager.
It's our thing.
Ta.
[Chorus On Radio]
** There will always be an England **
** And England shall be free **
** If England means as much to you **
** As England **
** Means **
** To me ****
- [Changing Station]
- **** [Rock]
- **** [Pop Punk]
[Groans]
Bloody poofy pop music.
- [Changing Station]
- ** [Rap]
- Bloody hell.
- [Changing Station]
[Woman] George, I love you.
I've always loved you.
You never loved me, did you, George?
Did you? Oh, George,
you're not listening to me.
- I don't blame him.
- [Changing Station]
[Man] Tragedy in the world of music.
Rock star Paul Kerr...
was rushed from his mansion
to Bristol Royal Infirmary.
The hospital has made
no statements yet...
but unconfirmed reports are suggesting
that the musician attempted suicide.
Let's go. In the bus.
We're moving out.
- I thought we were staying here tonight.
- Change of plan.
[Woman]
How are you feeling, Mr Kerr?
Um... Well, um...
I'll probably be all right
if you set me up with some drugs.
I'm in a lot of pain.
I think, uh,
morphine would be good.
I'm a psychiatrist, not a dealer.
I don't want a psychiatrist.
I want a proper doctor.
- And morphine.
- Your injuries are superficial.
You don't need morphine.
Then how about some Valium? I'm a wee
bit nervous about it happenin' again.
Yeah. Me too.
You often suicidal, Paul?
Come on. I was drunk.
I did something stupid.
It was a one-off.
I'm not suicidal.
You drove your motorcycle through
a second-floor window in your house.
Would you call that
the act of a sane man?
Hey, I'm a rock star.
I've driven cars into swimmin' pools
and thrown televisions out of windows.
It's part of the job.
Look, be reasonable.
Why would I try and kill myself?
I'm a happy guy.
I'm rich and I'm Scottish.
Doesn't get better than that.
You don't like me, do you?
I think you bring
a lot of hostility to your job.
What's the matter?
Did you have a bad childhood?
Do you still hear the lambs, Clarice?
Hey, you bloody kid,
get away from that bus.
That's rock 'n' roll history, that is.
Grandpa!
Still riding in that
little hair dryer, are you?
- I thought you'd have a Harley by now.
- Try telling Mum that.
Poor mother.
White sheep of the family.
- Where's the band?
- In the pub.
Of course. I thought you were
supposed to be going on tour.
Change of plan.
You know something? I'm really
jonesing for a nice cup of tea.
Come on, then.
[Man Over Radio] Margaret, I love you.
I've always loved you.
But you never loved me,
did you, Margaret?
- Margaret, you're not listening to me.
- Hmph. I don't blame her.
Margaret?
Margaret, where are you?
[Engine Shuts Off]
Oh, bloody hell.
** [Man Rapping, Indistinct]
Oh, Lord. Put some bloody clothes on.
You look like prostitutes.
[TVShuts Off]
What do you want?
How did you get in?
Nice to see you too.
Olivia let me in.
Made me fish fingers.
Delicious, they are.
Right. Good.
You're not surprised to see me?
I saw your bus in the driveway.
You want to get rid of that thing
before it falls apart.
Never. You were conceived in that bus,
girl. That's history, that is.
Your reprobate band
are not sleeping tonight in my house.
I'm still trying to get
the smell out from the last time.
They'll sleep in the bus.
- Where's Olivia?
- In her room...
listening to music like
any other normal teenager.
You're back late.
I'm busy. We're opening
a new salon in Bristol.
Don't you want to know
why I'm here?
Not really.
You've heard, then.
Well, if you don't say anything, I will.
This has gone on long enough.
Don't you start, Dad. I'm warning you.
You've no bloody right, you hear?
Just eat your fish fingers
and keep your nose out of it.
I'm off to bed.
Night, sweetheart.
Mum?
Yeah?
Why is Grandpa here?
He's sleeping on the couch,
and he hasn't done that since Nan died.
But he's, uh...
[Clears Throat] he's Grandpa.
Who knows what he's up to.
Night, then.
Come here.
I want to talk to you.
When I was your age, l...
I was a bit wild.
Yeah, Grandpa said.
What happened?
You can't be wild when you're a parent.
It's pathetic.
- Grandpa's wild.
- I rest my case.
You're too tough on him.
You didn't grow up with him.
Listen. This is important.
I wasn't much older
than you are now.
* I always flirt with death
I will kill *
* But I don't care about it *
* I can face your threats *
* And stand up straight and tall
and shout about it *
** I think I'm on
another world with you **
* With you *
* I'm on another planet with you *
[No Audible Dialogue]
**** [Continues, Indistinct]
Oh, my God.
You had sex with Paul Kerr?
Paul Kerr of the Love Rats,
the '80s pop star?
That's great!
Why didn't you ever tell me?
Oh, no.
You're kidding.
No. No, you're kiddin'.
[Woman]
I'm absolutely serious, Mr Kerr.
I'm very worried about you.
- You can't do this. It's illegal.
- No, no.
It's called a section.
It only needs two doctors
to sign an order saying...
that they think you are a danger
to yourself or to others.
And we can keep you under psychiatric
observation for as long as we see fit.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Please don't blaspheme.
Dr Nahar is a born-again Christian.
You're worried about me?
I think, and Dr Nahar agrees...
that you are a danger to yourself
at this point in time.
Now, this may be
a temporary condition brought on...
by some disappointment or upset...
or it may be
something more serious.
Like what?
I don't know.
That's why I want to observe you.
What if you have a bipolar disorder,
and I let you go and you commit suicide?
I would never forgive myself.
Dr Nahar can forgive you.
He's a born-again Christian.
Give me drugs then.
At least give me a beer
to take the edge off!
I'm not mad.
I'm just creative.
I don't understand why
you had to make up all that rubbish...
about my father being a Russian sailor
and dying in the Cold War.
I mean, where did you get that from?
[Chuckles] It was my idea.
I got it from a film I saw.
Letter to Brezhnev.
Very good it was too.
We had to make up the bit about
him drowning after the Soviet collapse.
- I mean, who could foresee
that coming, eh?
- But why?
It seemed like
the right thing to do.
Why would you tell me that?
I didn't want you
to be part of that world...
all those drugs
and groupies and stuff.
- It's no place for a child.
- Well, you'd know all about the groupies.
- Now don't you be
cheeky to your mother.
- Put a sock in it, Granddad.
- It wasn't what you think.
- It was.
It was Paul Kerr, my father.
- He didn't want his kid around
cramping his style.
- No.
My father didn't want me.
He doesn't know.
- What?
Well, what if he'd taken you away
with all his fancy lawyers...
and given you one of those stupid
pop star kids' names, like Flowerbell...
or-or Moonbeam
or Kipper or something?
You would've grown up the child
of someone famous.
Would that be a good idea?
Julian Lennon,
Victoria Sellers...
uh, Mickey Humperdinck...
Shut up, Dad!
I swear to you, darling...
I did this because
I love you so much.
And I wanted to protect you.
I'm sorry.
And why are you
telling me this now?
Um...
Because your father's sick.
- [Man] Horsie goes down.
- ** [Tapping Single Piano Note]
Horsie goes up.
- Horsie goes down.
- **** [Piano Note Continues]
[Man] 500 of those
deerskin toilet seat covers.
You know, the little fuzzy kind.
And if you can ship those out to me
right away, I'd really appreciate it.
Because, you know,
we need 'em really bad in here.
All right? What'd you say?
You only have the leopard?
** [Piano Note Continues]
Hey, Liberace, could you
play something else, please?
**** [Tapping Higher Note]
**** [Piano Note Continues]
** That's what girls do **
** They keep you guessin'
the whole day through **
** That's what girls **
** That's what girls do **
** They keep you guessin'
the whole day through **
* Play your emotions *
* Push all your buttons
It's true... **
I wish they'd settle down a bit.
Let one of them sing.
Sounds like a competition.
Shut up. Doesn't matter
what it sounds like. Look at them.
Sam, Paul Kerr's on line three.
Oh, tell him I'm in Japan.
Take a message.
Paul Kerr? Jesus, that's a rave from
the grave. I wonder what he wants.
- [Beeping]
- What do they always want?
I can't make a living
out of acts that...
only make one album
every five years.
- He's an artist.
- He's a lousy drunk.
Hi, Paul.
He says he's in Japan.
This is bullshit, Janice. Now you
put him on the phone right now!
- Oh, I'm sorry, Paul.
He won't take the call.
- You tell that bastard...
I will kill him if he doesn't
take that call right now!
Hi. I'm fine.
Yeah.
Of course you are.
[Woman]
Don't you think it's time...
you grew up and thought about
someone else other than yourself?
Don't you think it's about time
you realize there's
other people involved here?
It's not just...
Listen to me!
You have absolutely
no understanding of the situation.
I understand the situation perfectly.
I understand...
you're a selfish, self-centred,
useless Australian bastard!
Cheers, love.
Knew you'd understand.
- I'll call you in a couple of days, okay?
- [Grunting]
Bloody Scots.
The women are worse than the men.
[Snoring]
[Olivia] So don't you get
fed up running around the country...
- in this smelly old bus
with four other men?
- [Chuckles]
When you put it like that,
doesn't sound so great, does it?
- So why do you do it then?
- Music.
I play the music I love
every night of the week...
with friends I've known
for a long, long time.
Now, how many men of my age
do you know that can say that?
I don't know any men your age
except you and the band.
Now you listen to me,
young 'un.
No matter what your mother
may tell you, there is an alternative...
to living in
a nice little house...
and running
a nice little business.
There's nothing wrong
with what your mother does...
but there is nothing wrong
with what I do either.
I know.
Mum just worries.
She worries too much.
You okay?
About the father thing and all that?
Yeah. Mum and I have
arranged an appointment...
to go and see him
at the hospital.
Quite excited about it in a way.
Good. Good.
Olivia tells me you're going
to the hospital to see Paul Kerr.
She wanted to. I didn't feel
I could stand in the way of it.
Why did you tell her
that he didn't know about her?
It's kinder if she thinks he didn't know,
rather than he didn't want to know.
Don't you think
there's been enough lying?
you'd better be going?
I'll call you
from Wolverhampton.
Whatever.
** [Tapping Single Note]
Why have you got
toilet paper in your ears?
I can't hear you.
I've got toilet paper in my ears.
- You have a visitor.
- Finally.
Please, sit down.
Hello. Who are you?
You don't recognize
your father-in-law?
My God. Dad.
- I didn't recognize you
in the leather trousers.
- [Knock At Door]
Dr Bridget, Drew has
his finger stuck in the piano again.
Oh. Excuse me.
I'll be right back.
Okay, Gramps, who are you?
Did Gervasi send you?
And did you bring drugs?
Don't you call me Gramps,
you degenerate Scottish bastard.
No one sent me.
Okay. Who are you?
I am who I said I am.
I'm your father-in-law.
Well, sort of.
Great. Another loony.
You know, there's a guy out there
playing the piano.
I think you'd really enjoy it.
Now you listen to me,
you bloody shit!
My granddaughter is coming
to see you.
Now you be nice to her,
or I'll break your bloody neck.
Do you understand me?
Okay, okay, I'll be nice to her.
You know, 16 years ago
I could've killed you.
Really? Why?
- Oh, you know why.
- [Dr Bridget] Sorry about that.
So, how are we doing?
Well, I think we should rally around him,
you know? Cheer him up. Look after him.
No offence, but why?
None of us really know him.
He never comes out of the house.
I asked if he wanted to play guitar on
the music night here in the pub.
He just laughed at me.
Well, what if he dies? Or they
keep him in the loony bin forever...
and the house is sold,
and some bloody yuppie buys it...
and turns it into a crafts shop
or a bed and breakfast?
The whole village will be crawling
with bored stockbrokers...
in green Wellies practising
their comedy Welsh accents.
"Hello, boyo."
Come on, now, Graham.
That couldn't happen.
It's happening all over Wales.
I say we're better off with
our reclusive Scottish musician.
We hardly see him.
And we're all left alone.
Yeah, I don't want any bloody kids
coming here stealing cars and such.
Well, that's exactly what might happen.
Or worse.
What could be worse?
What if the place were bought...
by an American?
[Gasps]
It's our duty as a community...
to gather 'round
one of our number...
who has hit a dark patch
on life's long and winding road.
Yeah. What do we do?
I have an idea.
**** [Single Piano Notes]
That's quite a story.
So the, um, the old man
wearing the leather trousers...
- he was...
- My father.
My grandpa.
- And Paul doesn't know him?
- [Rebecca] No.
Well, that... that would
explain his reaction.
Sorry about that.
We didn't know he was coming.
I gave him a flea in his ear and sent him
back to his geriatric rockabilly band.
He'll keep out of it now.
He's got a gig
in Uttoxeter tonight.
I'm-I'm sorry. How...
How are you involved here?
Oh, I'm a longtime family friend.
I was there the night she fu...
first met him.
Um, the night Olivia was conceived.
I mean, I wasn't actually in the room.
I got off with the bass player
in the support band. Spike.
We still keep in touch.
Just Christmas cards and stuff.
He lives in Lisbon.
Okay, that's better,
but it's still crap.
See, the piano is capable
of producing music...
of atmospheric
and incandescent beauty.
You, my friend, are turning it into
an instrument of unspeakable torture.
- Now, look. Major chords are
good for upbeat, cheery tunes.
- **** [Major Chords]
- Minor chords give you
a sad, moody feel.
- **** [Minor Chords]
It's all about how
you look at it.
- And dis-chords...
- **** [Striking Off-Chords]
Give you an unsettled, strange feel.
Not that anybody around here
needs that, eh? Eh?
All right, look,
I'll play you somethin'.
But I have to warn you,
guitar is really my thing.
Piano is for girlies.
** [Rock 'N' Roll]
A lot of people get very uncomfortable
around psychiatric patients.
- Perhaps you'd like to wait.
- No, no, I'm fine. Really.
I want to see him.
We've had a long talk about it.
It's what she wants.
Well, maybe it's a good idea,
a shock to the system.
Better it happens in here
than on the outside...
where he can hurt himself
or run into a bar.
But I'm warning you,
he's very depressed.
Don't expect much.
**** [Continues]
- Yeah!
- **** [Ends]
Okay, what?
What is it?
Who are you, some kind of born-again
Christian, talk-you-out-of-suicide squad?
Because, I tell you,
I am not suicidal.
It was a simple accident involving
a bottle of whisky and a motorbike.
It could have happened to anyone.
See? I wouldn't want you growing up
around that kind of behaviour.
Growing up around what kind
of behaviour? What are you talkin' about?
What's goin' on?
Harpoon Louie's, Cardiff, 1987.
Oh, my God. Rebecca.
Oh. He remembered your name.
'Course I remembered her name.
I dedicated a whole album to you.
Lost Woman.
It's got a picture...
of a tiny, wee lost woman
on the front cover.
I didn't buy that one.
- Why not?
- I went off him.
I was never into him.
I liked the Pet Shop Boys.
This is fantastic!
- And-And you've got family!
- Yes and no.
No. This is about me.
Could we have a moment, please?
Yes.
What?
That man, Gordano...
he's not my dad.
You are.
- What?
- You're my father.
That night you spent
with my mum in 1987...
I'm the result.
Oh, uh... No.
Yes.
No, no... No way.
- Yes way.
- Oh, Jesus.
No, his mother
had a better excuse.
What...
Oh, wow.
That's roughly what I said.
Must be alike then.
[Chuckles]
Look, I'm sorry.
L-I don't really know what to say.
Do you, um, got any other kids?
Uh, no.
- You?
- I'm 16.
Oh, God, I can't take this.
I should be inside.
- I'm going in.
- Hey, you promised not to interfere.
- She's my kid.
- Yeah, she's his too.
Oh, God, this is so Greek.
So, uh, what are you up to? School?
Yeah. I'm gettin' ready to leave.
What about a dad?
Do you... I mean, that guy...
is he like your dad?
No. He's Mum's business partner.
He's gay.
I was gonna say...
[Chuckles]
Where's Paul Kerr?
Who are you, his sister?
His long-lost cousin?
I'm Dorise LeFanu.
His wife.
Forget Greek.
This is Jerry Springer.
Mum wants me to go
into the family business.
What's the family business?
Hairdressing.
Why did you try to kill yourself?
I didn't.
It was an accident.
Just nobody in here believes me.
They've sectioned me.
Darling! Ohh!
Oh, I'm sorry I took so long.
Did they hurt you?
Are you all right?
Don't worry, Mr Kerr.
We'll have you out of here in a jiffy.
- Mary?
- Oh!
It's his pet name for me.
Don't speak, my love. Wifey is here now.
I will look after you.
It'll be okay.
I'm having a very strange day.
Impersonating a loony's wife
to help spring him from hospital.
- Yes, I suspect that's highly illegal.
- Oh!
So we could have you arrested
for not arresting us.
- Don't start.
- Nobody will ever know.
- Why did you do this?
- [Mary] What's that, then?
You know.
Dress up with the...
and everything to get me
out of the hospital.
You are valued as
part of our community.
- Yeah, right.
- So don't go killing yourself again.
- Mmm! Apart from anything else,
it's against the law.
- It's illegal, see?
No, I won't.
Too many interesting
things happenin'.
Maybe later.
Give me another whisky.
What the hell is going on?
Shush, shush, shush, shush, shush, shush.
You'll wake Vince.
[Snoring]
If he doesn't get his nap,
he goes mental.
Never mind about that.
You can't light a fire in my driveway!
Well, you can't eat raw chicken.
It's only a little fire.
I'll make sure they clean it up.
I thought you were off playing
a gig in Uttoxeter tonight.
It was cancelled.
They put in a new karaoke machine.
Humph.
How did it feel...
meeting your dad
for the first time?
I didn't really feel anything.
No real connection.
I don't suppose we've got
a lot in common.
- Music.
- We didn't talk about music.
I was in there for five minutes.
You don't have to talk.
If you want to know what
a musician's about, listen to him play.
If you want to know
about your dad...
listen to his music.
What if I want him
to know about me?
** Waiting for the right one
to find me **
** [Humming]
[Olivia]
** Now, if you feel
that you can't go on **
** Because all of your hope is gone **
* And your life is filled
with much confusion *
* And still happiness
is just an illusion *
* And your world around
is crumbling down *
* Darling, reach out *
* Reach out
Reach out for me *
** I'll be there **
** With a love
that will shelter you **
[Doorbell Ringing]
** And I'll be there **
** With a love
that will see you through **
** When you feel lost
and about to give up **
** 'Cause your life
just ain't good enough **
- [Snoring]
- [Doorbell Ringing]
**** [Fades]
- [Doorbell Continues]
- Piss off!
Morning.
Oh, fuck!
[Doorbell Continues]
I'm warnin' you,
if you're a Jehovah's Witness...
He's about to witness
your ass gettin' kicked.
G'day, mate.
Well, you look great.
Bloody hell!
Digger McQuade!
I thought you were dead.
[Both Laughing]
Can I ask you a question?
All right.
What was it like,
that night with my father?
We met after the show.
We were both so young.
It was before he got
really, really famous...
and got into drugs
and everything.
What'd you talk about?
Music mostly.
I remember he was impressed
when I said I liked The Four Tops.
Most people my age back then
were into Kajagoogoo.
[Olivia]
So you just went back to his hotel and...
[Rebecca]
No, I'm telling you, it wasn't like that.
I wasn't like that.
We snuck out away from all
the other band members and roadies.
Went to Jack Williams'
fish and chip shop.
God, it's not
even there any more.
Eventually, after we watched
the sun coming up...
we went back to his hotel
and had breakfast.
And that's when it happened?
Yes.
- It was just a one-night stand?
- Well...
No, um, he had a few days off.
So we holed up in his hotel
and ordered room service for 48 hours.
I told your gran I'd gone to London
to apply for college.
Mum, you tramp!
Don't get any ideas.
It was a stupid thing to do.
Do you still love him?
Don't be ridiculous. Can't love someone
unless you know them.
We were just kids.
It seems like a million years ago...
- like it happened
to someone else, not me.
- That sounds like a cop-out.
Hey, I didn't cop out.
He did.
That's the type of person he is.
I didn't say
you weren't angry at him.
I said you still loved him.
You're a romantic, Olivia.
You'll have to lose that
if you want to survive.
Well, after the band split up, I did
some session work, but it got boring.
And it wasn't like I needed the money
after the Lost Woman album.
Come on. Have some more.
Go on.
Are you done?
Funny looking what's-it.
Friendly, though.
- It's a llama.
- What's his name?
Dolly.
Dolly Llama.
It's a prestige item.
Michael Jackson's got loads of'em.
Looks like a gay sheep.
[Trilling]
Why Loch Ness?
I like it. It's quiet.
You don't like quiet.
You're a drummer.
You like big, noisy stages,
shrill women and loud pubs.
You're Australian, for God's sake.
All of that is true, mate, but I got
a bit tired of it. You know what I mean?
Being a rock star is all right
for a man in his 20s and 30s...
but I'm 43 years old.
I'd feel faintly ridiculous
being part of that world now.
Never thought I'd see the day.
Well, all right,
then why'd you move down here?
What's the best gig
we ever played?
Giants Stadium,
New York, 1989.
No, no.
Apart from that.
Ooh.
- Harpoon Louie's.
- Harpoon Louie's. Yeah, in Cardiff.
- 1987. It's a 20-minute
bike ride from here.
- Yeah.
So what? You're not gonna
play there again, are you?
Yeah. I don't even think
it's there any more.
I've always liked this place. I like this
part of the world, and I like it here.
I get peace to write music.
Peace to isolate, more like.
Nobody to bug you...
as you slowly
drink yourself to death.
Absolutely right, my good
Australian friend. Cheers.
I don't touch it any more, mate.
Been sober eight years.
Oh, no.
You're not one of them, are you?
- What, a poof?
- You know what.
A.A., 12 steps,
and banging a tambourine for Jesus.
Yeah. I'm A.A. All right, mate.
Don't have much to do
with Jesus, as a rule.
You haven't come here to convert me
to some born-again cult, have you?
You believe what you like, mate.
I'm here to help you get off the booze.
- I don't wanna get off the booze.
- 'Course you do.
That's why you drove your bike
through a window.
Oh, and by the way...
I oughta kick your ass for
killing an innocent motorcycle.
All right, look.
I'm not stoppin'.
I'm havin' one later, okay?
That's the ticket.
One day at a time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kum-ba-ya to you too.
** I was walkin'through thejungle
just the other night **
* When I heard a big rumble
and I thought it was a fight *
** We were lost and we listened
and began to move our feet **
** It was a jungle drum a-doin'
a knock-out beat **
* It was a jungle, jungle
jungle, jungle rock *
Those who do not recover
are people who cannot...
or will not completely give themselves
to this simple programme...
usually men and women
who are...
- [Continues, Indistinct]
- ** [Continues, Indistinct]
* It was a jungle, jungle
jungle, jungle rock *
* Well, I moved a little closer
just to get a better view *
** I saw a chimp and a monkey
doin'the Suzie "Q"**
* Well, a gator and a hippo
was doin' the bop *
** While a great big falcon
was makin'me hop **
* It was a jungle, jungle
jungle, jungle rock *
* Ajungle, jungle
* A knock-out beat
and I had to move my feet *
* It was a jungle, jungle
jungle, jungle rock *
* Well, the fox grabbed the rabbit
and did the bunny hop *
* And all the fish stepped by
and was a-cuttin' the rug *
* Well, a camel was a-jitterbuggin'
with a kangaroo *
** And the elephant was movin'
with a ring-dang-doo **
** It was a jungle, jungle
jungle, jungle rock **
** Ajungle, jungle
** A knock-out beat
and I had to move my feet **
** It was a jungle, jungle
jungle, jungle rock **
** Ajungle, jungle
* Ajungle, jungle
jungle, jungle rock *
jungle, jungle rock **
- ** [Ends]
- [Applause]
Does anyone want to accept
a chip for 30 days sober?
You're showin' your age, mate.
Maybe it's time you started knittin'.
Yeah? Well, maybe it's time
you started the amends process, mate.
Hey, I got her pregnant and left her
to raise the kid on her own.
How do you make amends
for that, eh?
I don't know. A nice bunch of flowers,
box of chocolates.
A nice bunch of flowers and a box
of chocolates. What a fantastic idea!
Why didn't I think of that, eh?
Problem solved.