[ Chattering ]
[ Rope Lashing ]
%% [ "Superstar" lnstrumental ]
%% [ Discordant Note ]
% My mind is clearer now %
% At last, all too well %
% I can see %
% Where we all
soon will be %
% lf you strip away %
% The myth from the man %
% You will see %
% Where we all
soon will be %
% Jesus %
% You've started to believe
the things they say of you %
% You really do believe
this talk of God is true %
% And all the good you've done
will soon get swept away %
% You've begun
to matter more %
% Than the things you say %
% Listen, Jesus
I don't like what I see %
% All I ask is that
you listen to me %
% And remember %
% I've been your right-hand man
all along %
% You have set them all
on fire %
% They think they've found
the new messiah %
% And they'll hurt you
when they find they're wrong %
% I remember when
this whole thing began %
% No talk of God then
We called you a man %
% And believe me %
% My admiration for you
hasn't died %
% But every word
you say today %
% Gets twisted 'round
some other way %
% And they'll hurt you
if they think you've lied %
% Nazareth, your famous son
should have stayed a great unknown %
% Like his father carving wood
he'd have made good %
% Tables, chairs and oaken chests
would have suited Jesus best %
% He'd have caused nobody harm
No one alarm %
% Listen, Jesus
Do you care for your race %
% Don't you see
we must keep in our place %
% We are occupied %
% Have you forgotten
how put down we are %
% I am frightened
by the crowd %
% For we are getting
much too loud %
% And they'll crush us
if we go too far %
% lf we go %
% Too far %
% Listen, Jesus
to the warning I give %
% Please remember
that I want us to live %
% But it's sad
to see our chances %
% Weakening with every hour %
% Your followers are blind %
% Too much heaven
on their minds %
% It was beautiful
but now it's sour %
% Yes, it's all %
% Gone sour %
% Oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh
Oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh %
% Listen, Jesus
to the warning I give %
% Please remember
that I want us to live %
% So come on, come on
He won't listen to me %
% Ah, Ah-ah-ah
Oh-oh-oh %
% Come on, listen
Listen to me %
% Come on
and listen to me %
% Ah, Ahh
Oh-oh-oh-oh %
% Come on
Listen to me %
% Come on, listen
% Ah-ah-ahh
Ohh, oh-oh-ohh %
% Come on
Listen to me %
% Listen to me %%
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's happening
What's the buzz %
% Tell me what's a-happening
What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happening %
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
% What's the buzz
% Why should you
want to know %
% Don't you mind
about the future %
% Don't you try
to think ahead %
% Save tomorrow
for tomorrow %
- % Think about today instead %
- % What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
Tell me what's a-happening %
- % I could give you %
- % Facts and figures %
- % What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
- % Even give you plans and forecasts %
- % When do we ride to Jerusalem %
- % Even tell you where I'm goin' %
% When do we ride to Jerusalem
When do we ride to Jerusalem %
% Why should you
want to know %
% Why are you obsessed
with fighting %
% Times and fates
you can't defy %
% lf you knew
the path we're riding %
% You'd understand it
less than I %
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
% Let me try to cool down
your face a bit, Let me try
to cool down your face a bit %
% Let me try to cool down
your face a bit
Let me try to cool down your face %
% Oh, let me try
Let me try %
% To cool down your face %
% Let me try to cool down
your face a bit %
% Mary, mmm, that is good %
% While you prattle
through your supper %
% Where and when
and who and how %
% She alone
is trying to give me %
% What I need
right here and now %
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
Tell me what's a-happening %
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
Tell me what's a-happening %
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
Tell me what's a-happening %
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
% It seems to me
a strange thing %
% Mystifying %
% That a man like you
can waste his time %
% On women of her kind %
Hey, cool it, man.
[ Chuckling ]
% Yes, I can understand that %
% She amuses %
% But to let her kiss you
and stroke your hair %
% That's hardly
in your line %
% It's not that I object
to her profession %
% But she doesn't fit in well
with what you teach and say %
% It doesn't help us
if you're inconsistent %
% They only need
a small excuse %
% To put us all away %
% Who are you
to criticize her %
to despise her %
% Leave her, Leave her
Let her be now %
She's with me now %
% lf your slate is clean
then you can throw stones %
% lf your slate is not
then leave her alone %%
- Hey, Jesus, what do we say ?
- [ Disciples Chattering ]
[ Chattering, lndistinct ]
% I'm amazed
that men like you %
% Can be so shallow
thick and slow %
% There is not a man among you
who knows or cares if I come or go %
% No, you're wrong
You're very wrong %
% How can you say that
How can you say that %
How can you say that %%
Not one.
Not one of you !
% We've been sitting on the fence
for far too long %
% Why let him
upset us %
% Caiaphas, let him be %
% All those imbeciles
will see %
% He really
doesn't matter %
% Jesus is important %
% We've let him
go his way before %
% And while he starts
a major war %
% We theorize
and chatter %
% He's just another
Scripture-thumping hack from Galilee %
% The difference is
they call him King %
% The difference
frightens me %
What about the Romans ?
% When they see
King Jesus crowned %
% Do you think
they'll stand around %
% Cheering and applauding %
% What about our people %
% lf they see
we've lost our nerve %
% Don't you think
that they deserve %
% Something more rewarding %
% They've got
what they want %
% They think so anyway %
% lf he's what they want %
% Why take
their toy away %
% He's a craze %
% Put yourself in my place
I can hardly step aside %
% Cannot let my hands
be tied %
% I am law and order %
% What about our priesthood %
% Don't you see
that we could fall %
% lf we are to last
at all %
% We cannot be divided %
% Then say so
to the Council %
% But don't rely
on subtlety %
% Frighten them
or they won't see %
% Then we are decided %%
Then we are decided.
% Try not to get worried
Try not to turn onto %
% Problems that upset you %
% Don't you know
everything's all right %
% Yes, everything's fine %
% And we want you
to sleep well tonight %
% Let the world turn
without you tonight %
% lf we try, we'll get by
so forget all about us %
- % Tonight %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
% Everything's
all right, yes %
% Sleep and I shall soothe you
calm you and anoint you %
- % Myrrh for your hot forehead %
- % Ah %
% Then you'll feel
everything's all right
Yes, everything's fine %
% And it's cool and
the ointment's sweet %
% For the fire
in your head and feet %
% Close your eyes
Close your eyes %
% And relax
Think of nothing %
- % Tonight %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Hey, hey, woman %
% Your fine ointment
brand-new and expensive %
% Should have been saved
for the poor %
% Why has it been wasted
We could have raised maybe %
% Three hundred
silver pieces or more %
% People who are hungry
People who are starving %
% They matter more
than your %
% Feet and hair %
% Try not to get worried
Try not to turn onto %
- % Problems that upset you %
- % Oh %
- % Don't you know
everything's all right %
- % All right, yes %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Surely you're not saying %
% We have the resources %
% To save the poor
from their lot %
% There will be poor always
pathetically struggling %
% Look at the good things
you've got %
% Think while
you still have me %
% Move while
you still see me %
% You'll be lost
and you'll be sorry %
% When I'm gone %
[ Mary Magdalene ]
% Sleep and I shall soothe you
calm you and anoint you %
- % Myrrh for your hot forehead %
- % Oh %
% Then you'll feel
everything's all right, yes %
% Everything's fine and it's cool
and the ointment's sweet %
% For the fire
in your head and feet %
% Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Think of nothing tonight %
- % Tonight close your eyes and relax %
- % Think of nothing %
- % Close your eyes, Close your eyes %
- % And relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
- % Close your eyes
Close your eyes and relax %
- % Everything's all right, yes %
% Everything's all right, yes
Everything's all right %%
% Good Caiaphas %
% The Council
waits for you %
% The Pharisees %
% And priests
are here for you %
% Ah, gentlemen %
% You know
why we are here %
% We've not much time %
% And quite
a problem here %
[ Men ]
% Hosanna, Superstar %
% Hosanna
Superstar %
[ Women ]
% Hosanna, Superstar %
% Hosanna
Superstar %
% Listen to
that howling mob %
% Of blockheads
in the street %
% A trick or two
with lepers %
% And the whole town's
on its feet %
[ All ]
% He is dangerous %
% Jesus Christ
Superstar %
% He is dangerous %
% Tell us that you're
who they say you are %
% That man is in town right now
to whip up some support %
% A rabble-rousing mission
that I think we must abort %
% He is dangerous %
% Jesus Christ %
% Superstar %
% He is dangerous %
[ Chattering ]
% Look, Caiaphas
They're right outside our yard %
% Quick, Caiaphas
Go call the Roman guard %
% No, wait %
% We need a more permanent solution
to our problem %
% What then to do
about Jesus of Nazareth %
% Miracle wonderman
hero of fools %
% No riots, no army
no fighting, no slogans %
% One thing I'll say for him
Jesus is cool %
% We cannot leave him
to his own devices %
% His half-witted fans
will get out of control %
- % How can we stop him %
- % His glamour increases %
- % By leaps every minute %
- % He's top of the pole %
% I see
bad things arising %
% The crowd crowned him king
which the Romans would ban %
% I see
blood and destruction %
% Our elimination
because of one man %
% Blood and destruction
[ All ]
% Because, because, because of one man %
% Our elimination
because of one man %
% Because, because
because of one %
% Cause of one
cause of one man %
[ Priest ] % What then to do
about this Jesus mania %
[ Annas ] % Oh, how do we deal
with the carpenter-king %
[ Priest ] % Where do we start
with a man who is bigger %
% Than John was when John did
his baptism thing %
% Fools, you have
no perception %
% The stakes we are gambling
are frighteningly high %
% We must crush him
completely %
% So like John before him
this Jesus must die %
% For the sake of the nation
[ All ] % Must die, Must die
This Jesus must die %
% So like John before him
this Jesus must die %
% Must die, Must die
This Jesus must, Jesus must %
% Jesus must die %%
%% [ Trumpets ]
% Hosanna, Heysanna
Sanna, sanna, ho %
% Sanna, heysanna
hosanna %
% Hey, J.C., J.C. %
% Won't you smile at me %
% Sanna, hosanna
Hey, superstar %
% Tell the rabble
to be quiet %
% We anticipate a riot %
% This common crowd %
% ls much too loud %
% Tell the mob
who sing your song %
% That they are fools
and they are wrong %
% They are a curse %
% They should disperse %
% Hosanna, heysanna
Sanna, sanna, ho %
% Sanna, heysanna
hosanna %
% Hey, J.C., J.C.
You're all right by me %
% Sanna, hosanna
Hey, superstar %
% Why waste your breath
moaning at the crowd %
% Nothing can be done
to stop the shouting %
% lf every tongue
were still %
% The noise
would still continue %
% The rocks and stones
themselves %
% Would start to sing %
% Hosanna, heysanna
sanna, sanna, ho %
% Sanna, heysanna
hosanna %
% Hey, J.C., J.C.
won't you fight for me %
% Sanna, hosanna
Hey, superstar %
% Sing me your songs
but not for me alone %
Sing out for yourselves...
% For you are blessed %
% There is not one of you
who cannot win the Kingdom %
% The slow, the suffering %
% The quick, the dead %
% Hosanna, heysanna
sanna, sanna, ho %
% Sanna, heysanna
hosanna %
% Hey, J.C., J.C.
would you die for me %
% Sanna, hosanna
Hey, superstar %%
[ Cheering ]
Jesus ! Jesus !
% Christ, you know I love you
Did you see I waved %
% I believe in you and God
so tell me that I'm saved %
% Christ, you know I love you
Did you see I waved %
% I believe in you and God
so tell me that I'm saved %
% Jesus, I am with you
Touch me, Touch me, Jesus %
% Jesus, I am on your side
Kiss me, Kiss me, Jesus %
% Christ, what more do you need
to convince you %
% That you've made it
and you're easily as strong %
% As the filth from Rome
who rape our country %
% And who've terrorized
our people for so long %
%% [ Vocalizing ]
% Jesus, I am with you
Touch me, Touch me, Jesus %
% Jesus, I am on your side
Kiss me, Kiss me, Jesus %
% Christ, you know I love you
Did you see I waved %
% I believe in you and God
so tell me that I'm saved %
% Christ, you know I love you
Did you see I waved %
% I believe in you and God
so tell me that I'm saved %
% Christ, you know I love you
Did you see I waved %
% I believe in you and God
so tell me that I'm saved %
% Christ, you know I love you
Did you see I waved %
% I believe in you and God
so tell me that I'm saved %
% Jesus, I am with you
Touch me, Touch me, Jesus %
% Jesus, I am on your side
Kiss me, Kiss me, Jesus %
- % There must be over 50,000 %
- % 50,000 %
- % Screamin' love and more for you %
- % Love, love, love %
% And every one
of 50,000 %
- % Would do whatever ya asked them to %
- % Messiah %
% Keep them yellin'
their devotion %
% But add a touch
of hate at Rome %
% You will rise
to greater power %
% We will win ourselves
a home %
- % You'll get the power and the glory %
- % You'll get the glory %
- % Forever and ever and ever %
- % Ever and ever %
- % You'll get the power and the glory %
- % You'll get the power %
- % Forever and ever and ever %
- % Ever and ever %
- % You'll get the power
and the glory, Lord %
- % You'll get the power %
- % Forever and ever and ever %
- % You'll get the glory %
% You'll get the power
You'll get the glory %
- % Hey, hey, hey, hey %
- % You'll get the glory %
- % You %
- % You'll get the power %
% You'll get the power
You'll get the glory %
- % Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey %
- % You'll get the power %
- % You %
% Oh %
% Forever
Amen %
% A... ha-ah-ah
ah-ah-ah %
% ...men %%
% Neither you, Simon %
% Nor the 50,000 %
% Nor the Romans
nor the Jews %
% Nor Judas
nor the twelve %
% Nor the priests
nor the scribes %
% Nor doomed Jerusalem
itself %
% Understand
what power is %
what glory is %
% Understand at all %
% Understand
at all %
% lf you knew %
% All that I knew %
% My poor Jerusalem %
% You'd see the truth %
% But you'd close your eyes %
% But you'd close
your eyes %
% While you live %
% Your troubles are many %
% Poor Jerusalem %
% To conquer death %
% You only have to die %
% You only have
to die %%
% I dreamed
I met a Galilean %
% A most amazing man %
% He had that look
you very rarely find %
% The haunting, hunted kind %
% I asked him to say
what had happened %
% How it all began %
% I asked again
He never said a word %
% As if he hadn't heard %
% And next
the room was full %
% Of wild and angry men %
% They seemed
to hate this man %
% They fell on him and then %
% Disappeared again %
% Then I saw
thousands of millions %
% Crying for this man %
% And then I heard them
mentioning my name %
% And leaving me
the blame %
[ Chorus ]
% Pilate %%
[ Bleating ]
% Roll on up, Jerusalem
Come on in, Jerusalem %
% Sunday, here we go again
Live in me, Jerusalem %
% Here you live, Jerusalem
Here you breathe, Jerusalem %
% While your temple still survives
you at least are still alive %
% I got things you won't believe
Name your pleasure, I will sell %
% I can fix your wildest needs
I got heaven, I got hell %
% Roll on up for my price is down
Come on in for the best in town %
% Take your pick of the finest wine
Lay your bets on this bird of mine %
% What you see
is what you get %
% No one's been
disappointed yet %
% Don't be scared
Give me a try %
% There is nothing
you can't buy %
% Name your price, I got everything
Hurry, It's all going fast %
% Borrow cash
on the finest terms %
% Hurry now
while stocks still last %
[ Crowd Chattering ]
% Roll on up, Jerusalem
Come on in, Jerusalem %
% Sunday, here we go again
Live in me, Jerusalem %
% Here you live, Jerusalem
Here you breathe, Jerusalem %
% While your temple still survives
you at least are still alive %
% I got things you won't believe
Name your pleasure, I will sell %%
[ Screaming ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
% My temple
should be %
% A house of prayer %
% But you have made it %
% A den of thieves %%
Get out !
[ Crowd Screaming,
Yelling ]
% My time %
% ls almost through %
% Little left to do %
% After all, I've tried
for three years %
% Seems like 30 %
% Feels like 30 %
% See my eyes
I can hardly see %
% See me stand
I can hardly walk %
% I believe
you can make me whole %
% See my tongue
I can hardly talk %
% See my skin
I'm a mass of blood %
% See my legs
I can hardly stand %
% I believe
you can make me well %
% See my purse
I'm a poor, poor man %
[ All ] % Will you touch
Will you mend me, Christ %
% Won't you touch
Won't you heal me, Christ %
% Will you kiss
You can cure me, Christ %
% Won't you kiss
Won't you pay me, Christ %
% See my eyes
I can hardly see %
% See me stand
I can hardly walk %
% I believe
you can make me whole %
% See my tongue
I can hardly talk %
% See my skin
I'm a mass of blood %
% See my legs
I can hardly stand %
% I believe
you can make me well %
% See my purse
I'm a poor, poor man %
% Will you touch
Will you mend me, Christ %
% Won't you touch
Will you heal me, Christ %
% Will you kiss
You can cure me, Christ %
% Won't you kiss
Won't you pay me, Christ %
% See my eyes
I can hardly see %
% See me stand
I can hardly walk %
% I believe
you can make me whole %
% See my tongue
I can hardly talk %
% See my skin
I'm a mass of blood %
% See my legs
I can hardly stand %
% I believe
you can make me well %
% See my purse
I'm a poor, poor man %
% Will you touch
Will you mend me, Christ %
% Won't you touch
Will you heal me, Christ %
% Will you kiss
You can cure me, Christ %
% Won't you kiss
Won't you pay me, Christ %
% See my eyes
I can hardly see %
% See me stand
I can hardly walk %
% I believe you can make me whole
See my tongue I can hardly talk %
- % See my skin, I'm a mass of blood %
- [ Jesus Moaning ]
- There's too many of you !
- % I believe you can make me well %
- Don't push me !
- % See my purse, I'm a poor, poor man %
- % Will you touch
Will you mend me, Christ %
- There's too little of me.
- % Will you kiss
You can cure me, Christ %
- Don't crowd me !
% See my eyes
I can hardly see %
- Leave me alone !
- % I believe you can make me whole %
% See my tongue
I can hardly talk %%
Jesus !
Touch me, Jesus !
% Close your eyes
Close your eyes %
% And forget
all about us %
% Tonight %%
% I don't know
how to love him %
% What to do
How to move him %
% I've been changed %
% Yes, really changed %
% ln these past few days
when I've seen myself %
% I seem like someone else %
% I don't know how
to take this %
% I don't see
why he moves me %
% He's a man %
% He's just a man %
% And I've had
so many men before %
% ln very many ways %
% He's just one more %
% Should I bring him down
Should I scream and shout %
% Should I speak of love
Let my feelings out %
% I never thought
I'd come to this %
% What's it all about %
% Don't ya think
it's rather funny %
% I should be
in this position %
% I'm the one
who's always been %
% So calm, so cool
No lover's fool %
% Running every show %
% He scares me so %
% I never thought
I'd come to this %
% What's it all about %
% Yet if he said
he loved me %
% I'd be lost
I'd be frightened %
% I couldn't cope %
% Just couldn't cope %
% I'd turn my head
I'd back away %
% I wouldn't want to know %
% He scares me so %
% I want him so %
% I love him %
% So %%
[ Engines Roaring ]
% Now if I help you
it matters that you see %
% These sordid kind of things
are coming hard to me %
% It's taken me some time
to work out what to do %
% I weighed the whole thing out
before I came to you %
% I have no thought at all
about my own reward %
% I really didn't come here
of my own accord %
% Just don't say I'm %
% Damned for all time %
% I came because I had to
I'm the one who saw %
% Jesus can't control it
like he did before %
% Furthermore, I know
that Jesus thinks so too %
% Jesus wouldn't mind
that I was here with you %
% I have no thought at all
about my own reward %
% I really didn't come here
of my own accord %
% Just don't say I'm %
% Damned for all time %
% Annas, you're a friend
a worldly man and wise %
% Caiaphas, my friend
I know you sympathize %
% Why are we the prophets
Why are we the ones %
% We see the sad solution
Know what must be done %
% I have no thought at all
about my own reward %
% I really didn't come here
of my own accord %
% Just don't say I'm %
% Damned %
% For all time %
% Cut the protesting
Forget the excuses %
% We want information
Get up off the floor %
% We have the papers
we need to arrest him %
% You know his movements
We know the law %
% Your help in this matter
won't go unrewarded %
% We'll pay you in silver
cash on the nail %
% We just need to know
where the soldiers can find him %
- % With no crowd 'round him %
- % Then we can't fail %
% I don't want
your blood money %
% Oh, that doesn't matter
Our expenses are good %
% I don't need
your blood money %
% But you might as well take it
We think that you should %
% Think of the things
you can do with that money %
% Choose any charity
Give to the poor %
% We've noted your motives
We've noted your feelings %
% This isn't blood money
It's a-- %
- A fee.
- % A fee, nothing more %%
% On Thursday night %
% You'll find him
where you want him %
% Far from the crowds %
% ln the Garden %
% Of Gethsemane %%
[ Chorus ]
% So long, Judas %
% So long, Judas %%
[ Jets Roaring ]
% Look at all my trials
and tribulations %
% Sinking in a gentle pool
of wine %
% Don't disturb me now %
% I can see the answers %
% Till this evening
is this morning %
% Life is fine %
% Always hoped that
I'd be an apostle %
% Knew that I would
make it if I tried %
% Then when we retire %
% We can write
the Gospels %
% So they'll still talk about us
when we've died %
% The end %
% ls just a little harder %
% When brought about %
% By friends %
% For all you care %
% This wine
could be my blood %
% For all you care %
% This bread %
% Could be my body %
The end.
% This is my blood
you drink %
% This is my body you eat %
% lf you would, remember me %
% When you eat and drink %%
% I must be mad
thinking I'll be remembered %
% Yes, I must be
out of my head %
% Look at your blank faces
My name will mean nothing %
% Ten minutes
after I'm dead %
% One of you denies me
One of you betrays me %
[ Apostles Shouting ]
No ! No !
[ Indistinct Shouting ]
% Peter will deny me %
- No, not me !
- % ln just a few hours %
% Three times will deny me
And that's not all I see %
% One of you here dining
One of my 12 chosen %
% Will leave to betray me %
% Cut out the dramatics
You know very well who %
- % Why don't you go do it ? %
- % You want me to do it ? %
- % Hurry, they are waiting %
- % lf you knew why I do it %
% I don't care
why you do it %
% To think I admired you
Well, now I despise you %
- % You liar, you Judas %
- % You wanted me to do it %
% What if I just stayed here
and ruined your ambition
Christ, you deserve it %
% Hurry, you fool
Hurry and go %
% Save me your speeches
I don't want to know %
% Go, Go %%
% Look at all my trials
and tribulations %
% Sinking in a gentle pool
of wine %
% What's that in the bread
It's gone to my head
% Till this morning
is this evening %
% Life is fine %
% Always hoped that
I'd be an apostle %
% Knew that I would make it
if I tried %
% Then when we retire
we can write the Gospels %
% So they'll all talk about us
when we've died %%
% You sad
pathetic man %
% See where you
brought us to %
% Our ideals die around us
and all because of you %
% But the saddest cut of all
Someone had to turn you in %
% Like a common criminal
Like a wounded animal %
% A jaded mandarin
A jaded mandarin %
% Like a jaded, faded
faded, jaded, jaded mandarin %
% Get out
They're waiting %
% Get out %
% They're waiting
Oh, they're waiting for you %
% Every time I look at you
I don't understand %
% Why you let the things you did
get so out of hand %
% You'd have managed better
if you'd had it planned %
% A-a-a-ah %%
[ Bleating ]
% Always hoped that
I'd be an apostle %
% Knew that I would make it
if I tried %
% lf I tried %
% Then when we retire
we can write the Gospels %
% So they'll still
talk about us %
% When we've died %%
% Will no one stay awake
with me %
% Peter, John, James %
% Will none of you wait
with me %
% Peter %
% John %
% James %
% I only want to say %
% lf there is a way %
% Take this cup
away from me %
% For I don't want
to taste its poison %
% Feel it burn me %
% I have changed %
% I'm not as sure
as when we started %
% Then, I was inspired %
% Now %
% I'm sad and tired %
% Listen %
% Surely I've exceeded
expectations %
% Tried for three years %
% Seems like 30 %
% Could You ask as much %
% From any other man %
% But if I die %
% See the saga through %
% And do the things
You ask of me %
% Let them hate me
hit me, hurt me %
% Nail me
to their tree %
% I'd want to know
I'd want to know, my God %
% I'd want to see
I'd want to see, my God %
% Why I %
% Should die %
% Would I be more noticed
than I ever was before %
% Would the things
I've said and done %
% Matter any more %
% I'd have to know
I'd have to know, my Lord %
% I'd have to see
I'd have to see, my Lord %
% lf I die
what will be my reward %
% Have to know
I'd have to know, my Lord %
% Why %
% Why should I die %
% Oh, why should I die %
% Can You show me now %
% That I would not be
killed in vain %
% Show me just a little %
% Of Your omnipresent brain %
% Show me there's a reason
for Your wanting me to die %
% You're far too keen
on where and how %
% But not so hot on why %
% All right %
% I'll die %
% Oh, Oh
Just watch me die %
% See how %
% See how I'll die %
% Oh-h-h %
% Just watch me die %
% Then %
% I was inspired %
% Now %
I'm sad and tired.
% After all %
I've tried for three years.
Seems like 90.
% Why then am I scared
to finish %
% What I started %
% What You started %
I didn't start it.
% God %
% Thy will is hard %
% But You hold every card %
% I will drink %
% Your cup of poison %
% Nail me to Your cross %
% And break me %
% Bleed me %
% Beat me, Kill me %
% Take me now %
% Before I change my mind %%
Judas,
must you betray me...
% With a kiss %
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's happening %
Tell me what's happenin' %
% What's happenin' %
% What's the buzz
Tell me what's a-happenin' %
% Hang on, Lord
We're gonna fight for you %
- % Hang on, Lord
- % Hang on, Lord %
% Hang on, Lord
We're gonna fight for you %
- % Hang on, Lord
- % We're gonna fight for you %
% Put away your sword %
% Don't you know
that it's all over %
% It was nice, but %
% Now it's gone %
% Why are you obsessed
with fighting %
% Stick to fishing
from now on %%
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
[ Man Laughing ]
% Tell me, Christ
how you feel tonight %
% Do you plan
to put up a fight %
% Do you feel that
you've had the breaks %
% What would you say
were your big mistakes %
% Do you think that
you may retire %
% Did you think
you would get much higher %
% How do you view
your coming trial %
% Have your men proved
it's all worthwhile %
% Come with us
to see Caiaphas %
% You'll just love
the high priest's house %
seeing Caiaphas %
% You'll just die
in the high priest's house %
% Come on, God
This is not like you %
% Let us know
what you're gonna do %
% You know what
your supporters feel %
% You'll escape
in the final reel %
% Tell me, Christ
how you feel tonight %
% Do you plan
to put up a fight %
% Do you feel that
you had the breaks %
% What would you say
were your big mistakes %
% Come with us
to see Caiaphas %
% You'll just love
the high priest's house %
seeing Caiaphas %
% You'll just die
in the high priest's house %
% Now we have him
Now we've got him %
% Now we have him now
We have got him now %
% Jesus, you must realize %
% The serious charges
facing you %
% You say you're the Son of God
in all your handouts
Well, is it true %
% That's what you say
You say that I am %
% There you have it, gentlemen
What more evidence do we need %
% Judas, thank you
for the victim %
% Stay a while
You'll see it bleed %
% Now we have him
Now we've got him %
% Take him to Pilate
Take him to Pilate %
Take him to Pilate %%
% I think I've
seen you somewhere %
I remember.
% You were with that man
they took away %
% I recognize
your face %
% You've got
the wrong man, lady %
% I don't know him %
% And I wasn't where
he was tonight %
% Never near the place %
% That's strange for I am sure
I saw you with him %
% You were right by his side
and yet you denied %
% I tell you
I was never, ever with him %
But I saw you too.
He looked just like you.
I don't know him !
% Peter, don't you know
what you have said %
% You've gone
and cut him dead %
% I had to do it
Don't you see %
% Or else
they'd go for me %
% It's what he told us
you would do %
% I wonder
how he knew %%
[ Crowd Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
- Come on. Come on.
- There he is, see? Hurry. Come on.
% Who is %
% This broken man %
% Cluttering up %
% My hallway %
% Who is this unfortunate %
% Someone Christ
King of the Jews %
Oh. So this is
Jesus Christ.
% I am really
quite surprised %
You look so small.
Not a king at all.
% We all know
that you are news %
But are you King ?
% King of the Jews %
Your words, not mine.
% What do %
% You mean by that %
% That is not an answer %
% You're deep %
% ln trouble, friend %
% Someone Christ
King of the Jews %
% How can someone
in your state %
% Be so cool
about his fate %
An amazing thing,
this silent king.
% Since you come
from Galilee %
% Then you need not
come to me %
You're Herod's race.
[ Chuckles ]
You're Herod's case.
% Hey, hosanna
Heysanna %
% Sanna
sanna ho %
% Sanna, heysanna, ho
and how %
% Hey, J.C., J.C. %
% Please explain to me %
% You had everything
Where is it now %%
Jesus, I am overjoyed...
% To meet you face to face %
You've been getting
quite a name...
% All around the place %
% Healing cripples %
- Ooh.
- % Raising from the dead %
[ All Gasping ]
% Now I understand
you're God %
[ Gasping ]
Hmm ? Huh ?
Mmm.
% At least that's
what you've said %
% So %
% You are the Christ
You're the great Jesus Christ %
% Prove to me
that you're divine %
% Change my water
into wine %
% That's all you need do
Then I'll know it's all true %
% Come on
King of the Jews %
% Jesus, you just won't believe the hit
you've made around here %
% You are all we talk about
You're the wonder of the year %
% Oh, what a pity
if it's all a lie %
% Still I'm sure that you can rock
the cynics if you try %
% So if you are the Christ
Yes, the great Jesus Christ %
% Prove to me that
you're no fool %
% Walk across
my swimming pool %
- % lf you do that for me %
- Whoo !
- % Then I'll let you go free %
% Come on
King of the Jews %
% I only ask what I'd ask
any superstar %
% What is it that you have got
that puts you where you are %
% Oh-ho-ho
I am waiting %
% Yes, I'm a captive fan %
% I'm dying to be shown that
you are not just any man %
% So if you are the Christ
Yes, the great Jesus Christ %
% Feed my household
with this bread %
% You can do it
on your head %
Uh, or has something gone wrong ?
Jesus, why do you take so long ?
Aw, come on,
King of the Jews !
% Hey, aren't you %
% Scared of me, Christ %
% Mister wonderful Christ %
Aaah !
You're a joke !
You're not the Lord.
You're nothing but a fraud.
% Take him away
He's got nothing to say %%
Get out,
you King of the--
Get out, King of the-- Oh !
Get out, you King of the Jews !
Get out of here !
You-- You--
Get out of here, you !
Get out of my life !
% I've been living
to see you %
% Dying to see you
but it shouldn't be like this %
% This was unexpected
What do I do now %
% Could we start again
please %
% I've been very hopeful
so far %
% Now for the first time %
% I think we're going wrong %
% Hurry up and tell me
This is just a dream %
% Or could we start again
please %
% I think you've made
your point now %
% You've even gone a bit too far to get
the message home %
% Before it gets
too frightening %
% We ought to call
a halt %
% So could we start again
please %
% I've been living
to see you %
% Dying to see you
but it shouldn't be like this %
% This was unexpected
What do I do now %
% Could we start again
please %
% I think you've made
your point now %
% You've even gone a bit too far to get
the message home %
% Before it gets
too frightening %
% We ought to call a halt
So could we start again please %
% Could we start again
please %
% Could we start again %
% Could we start again %%
% My God
I saw him %
% He looked three-quarters dead and
he was so bad I had to turn my head %
% You beat him so hard
that he was bent and lame %
% And I know who
everybody's gonna blame %
% I don't believe he knows
I acted for our good %
% I'd save him all this suffering
if I could %
% Don't believe
Our good %
% And I'd save him
if I could %
% Cut the confessions
Forget the excuses %
% I don't understand why
you're filled with remorse %
% All that you've said has
come true with a vengeance %
% The mob turned against him
You backed the right horse %
% What you have done will be
the saving of everyone %
% You'll be remembered
forever for this %
% And not only that
You've been paid for your efforts %
% Pretty good wages
for one little kiss %
% Christ, I know
you can't hear me %
% But I only did
what you wanted me to %
% Christ, I'd sell out
the nation %
% For I have been saddled
with the murder of you %
% I have been spattered
with innocent blood %
% I shall be dragged through
the slime and the mud %
% I have been spattered
with innocent blood %
% I shall be dragged through the slime
and the slime and the %
% Slime and the mud %%
% I %
% Don't know how
to love him %
% I don't know
why he moves me %
% He's a man %
% He's just a man %
% He is not a king %
% He's just the same %
% As anyone I know %
% He scares me so %
% When he's cold and dead %
% Will he let me be
Does he love %
% Does he love me too %
% Does he care for me %%
My mind is--
It's in darkness.
God. God, I'm sick !
I've been used !
And You knew
all the time !
God-- God, I will never know
why You chose me...
for Your crime !
For Your bloody crime !
You have murdered me !
Mur-- Murdered me !
Murdered me ! Murdered me !
Murdered me ! Murdered-- !
% So long, Judas %
% And so, the king
is once again my guest %
% And why is this %
% Was Herod unimpressed %
[ Caiaphas ]
% We turn to Rome %
% To sentence Nazareth %
% We have no law %
% To put a man to death %
% We need him crucified %
% It's all
you have to do %
% We need him crucified
It's all you have to do %
% Talk to me, Jesus Christ
You have been brought here %
Manacled, beaten,
by your own people.
Do you have the first idea
why you deserve it ?
% Listen, King of the Jews
Where is your kingdom %
% Look at me
Am I a Jew %
I have no kingdom.
In this world,
I'm through.
- % Talk to me, Jesus Christ %
- There may be a kingdom...
for me somewhere.
If you only knew.
- Then you are a king.
- % It's you that say I am %
% I look for truth
and find that I get damned %
% And what is truth
ls truth unchanging law %
% We both have truths
Are mine the same as yours %
[ Crowd ]
Crucify him ! Crucify him !
What do you mean ?
You'd crucify your king ?
[ Crowd ]
% We have no king but Caesar %
He's done no wrong.
No, not the slightest thing.
% We have no king but Caesar
Crucify him %
Well, this is new.
Respect for Caesar !
Until now, this has been
noticeably lacking.
Who is this Jesus ?
Why is he different ?
You Jews produce messiahs
by the sackful.
% We need him crucified
It's all you have to do %
% Talk to me
Jesus Christ %
% Look at
your Jesus Christ %
% I'll agree
he's mad %
% Ought to be locked up %
% But that is not a reason
to destroy him %
% He's a sad little man
not a king or god %
% Not a thief
I need a crime %
[ Shouting ]
Crucify him ! Crucify him !
Crucify him !
% Behold the man
Behold your shattered king %
% We have no king
but Caesar %
% You hypocrites
You hate us more than him %
% We have no king but Caesar
Crucify him %
% I see no reason
I find no evil %
% This man is harmless
so why does he upset you %
% He's just misguided
Thinks he's important %
But to keep you vultures happy,
I shall flog him !
Crucify him ! Crucify him !
Crucify him !
Crucify !
Crucify ! Crucify !
Crucify him ! Crucify him !
Crucify ! Crucify ! Crucify !
Crucify ! Crucify him !
Crucify him !
Crucify ! Crucify !
- [ Pilate ] One,
- [ Mary Screaming ]
two,
three, four,
five, six,
seven,
eight, nine,
ten,
eleven,
twelve,
thirteen,
fourteen,
fifteen,
sixteen,
seventeen,
eighteen,
nineteen,
twenty,
twenty-one,
twenty-two,
twenty-three,
twenty-four,
twenty-five,
twenty-six,
twenty-seven,
twenty-eight,
twenty-nine,
thirty,
thirty-one,
thirty-two,
thirty-three,
thirty-four,
thirty-five,
thirty-six,
thirty-seven,
thirty-eight,
thirty-nine !
[ Pilate ]
% Where are you from Jesus %
% What do you want
Jesus %
% Tell me %
% You've got to be careful %
% You could be dead soon %
% Could well be %
% Why do you not speak %
% When I hold your life
in my hands %
% How can you
stay quiet %
% I don't believe
you understand %
% You have nothing
in your hands %
Any power you have...
comes to you
from far beyond.
Everything is fixed,
and you can't change it.
You're a fool,
Jesus Christ !
- % How can I help you %
- [ Crowd ] % Pilate, crucify him %
% Crucify
Remember Caesar %
% You have a duty
to keep the peace %
% So crucify him %
% Remember Caesar
You'll be demoted %
% You'll be deported
Crucify him %
% Remember Caesar
You have a duty %
% To keep the peace
so crucify him %
% Remember Caesar
You'll be demoted %
% You'll be deported
Crucify him %
% Remember Caesar
You have a duty %
% To keep the peace
so crucify him %
% Remember Caesar
You'll be demoted %
% You'll be deported
Crucify him %
% Don't let me stop %
% Your great
self-destruction %
% Die if you want to %
% You misguided martyr %
% I wash my hands %
% Of your demolition %
% Die if you want to %
% You innocent puppet %%
[ Crowd Cheering,
Shouting ]
%% [ "Superstar" lnstrumental ]
% Mmm, every time I look at you
I don't understand %
% Why you let the things you did
get so out of hand %
% You'd have managed better
if you'd had it planned %
% Now why'd you choose such a backward
time and such a strange land %
% lf you'd come today you could
have reached the whole nation %
% lsrael in 4 B.C. had
no mass communication %
- % Don't you get me wrong %
- % Don't you get me wrong now %
- % Don't you get me wrong now
Only wanna know %
- % Don't you get me wrong %
- % Only wanna know %
- % Only wanna know now %
- % Only wanna know, Only wanna know %
- % Only wanna know %
% Oh-Ohh
I only wanna know %
% Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ %
% Who are you
What have you sacrificed %
% Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ %
% Who are you
What have you sacrificed %
% Jesus Christ Superstar %
% Do you think you're
what they say you are %
% Jesus Christ Superstar %
% Do you think you're
what they say you are %
% Tell me %
% What you think about
your friends at the top %
% Now who'd you think besides yourself
was the pick of the crop %
% Buddha, was he where it's at
ls he where you are %
% Could Mohammed move a mountain
or was that just P.R. %
% Did you mean to die like that
Was that a mistake or %
% Did you know your messy death
would be a record breaker %
- % Don't you get me wrong
Don't you get me wrong %
- % Don't you get me wrong %
- % Don't you get me wrong now %
- % Don't you get me wrong
Don't you get me wrong %
- % Don't you get me wrong now %
% Only wanna know
Only wanna know now %
- % Only wanna know %
- % Only wanna know, Only wanna know %
- % Only wanna know now %
- % I only wanna know %
% Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ %
% Who are you
What have you sacrificed %
% Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ %
% Who are you
What have you sacrificed %
- % Jesus Christ Superstar %
- % Jesus %
- % I only wanna know %
- % Do you think you're
what they say you are %
- % Tell me, tell me, tell me %
- % Jesus Christ Superstar %
% Tell me
Don't you get me wrong %
% I only wanna know %
- % Jesus Christ, Jesus Christ %
- % Jesus %
% I only wanna know %
- % Tell me, Tell me, Tell me %
- % Tell me, Tell me %
% Tell me
Don't you get me wrong %
% I only wanna know
Come on %
- % Jesus %
- % Only wanna know %
- % Jesus, only wanna know %
- % I only wanna know %
- % Tell me, Tell me, Tell me, Tell me %
- % Jesus Christ Superstar %
% Don't you get me wrong
I only wanna know %
- % Come on, Jesus %
- % Jesus Christ %
% Jesus %
% I only wanna know
Tell me %
- % Tell me, Tell me, Tell me %
- % Tell me %%
[ Laughter ]
[ Laughter Continues ]
Father, forgive them.
They don't know
what they're doing.
My God. My God,
why have You
forgotten me ?
Father,
into Your hands...
I commend...
my spirit.