Hey, everybody.
It's me, Mickey Mouse.
Say, you wanna come
inside my clubhouse?
Well, all right! Let's go.
Oops! [chuckles]
Gee, I forget this every time.
Now, to make the clubhouse appear,
we need to say
the magic words exactly right.
'Cause if we don't, well,
something funny might happen.
The magic words are...
Meeska, mooska, Mickey Mouse.
Say it with me.
Meeska, mooska, Mickey Mouse!
[# They Might Be Giants:
Mickey Mouse Clubhouse Theme]
# M-I-C-K-E-Y M-O-U-S-E
That's me!
# It's the Mickey Mouse Clubhouse
# Come inside
It's fun inside
- # It's the Mickey Mouse Clubhouse
- [man] Roll call.
- Donald.
- Present.
- Daisy.
- Here.
- Goofy.
- Pluto.
- [Barks]
- Minnie.
- Here.
- Mickey.
- Right here.
# It's the Mickey Mouse Clubhouse
# Come inside
It's fun inside
# M-I-C-K-E-Y M-O-U-S-E #
[Mickey] It's the Mickey Mouse
Clubhouse.
Mickey's Great Clubhouse Hunt.
Welcome to our clubhouse.
Say, you know what this is a picture of?
An egg. Right!
Ooh, a decorated egg.
'Cause today we're having
an Easter egg hunt.
And you know what?
Everybody's invited, including you.
- Hi, Mickey.
- We're here for the Easter party.
Uh-huh. Thanks for the invitation.
[Barks]
I got an invitation too.
Hmm. Now where did I put it?
Oh yeah, in my hat.
[Chuckles]
[Squeaks]
Hmm. Ducky.
[Rattling]
I'm Goofy Bunny.
[Chuckles]
Here it is.
Oh, Mickey, decorating for the party
is gonna be so much fun.
We've got streamers and banners
and party hats and...
Hey, where's Donald?
He was supposed to bring everything.
Here I am.
[Grunting]
[Donald] Look out!
Aw, phooey.
[Barks]
Whoa!
Come on, everybody.
Let's get ready.
# We're getting ready for
the best Easter party ever
# The best part is we'll be together
# And we'll be friends forever
# It's springtime
A shing-a-ling-a-ling time
# Springtime
A make you wanna sing time
# La la la la
La la la la la
# Hanging the streamers
I'm the tallest one
# Finding eggs is so much fun
# I made a banner with glitter and glue
# Decorated eggs of yellow and blue
# I'm making the music
I can't wait
# Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy
This is gonna be great!
# So much to do
No time to stop
# I wanna do the bunny hop
# Hop, hop, hop, hop
# We're getting ready for
the best Easter party ever
# The best part is we'll be together
# And we'll be friends forever
# It's springtime
A shing-a-ling-a-ling time
# Springtime
A make you wanna sing time
# La la la la
La la la la la
[Daisy] # In summer we
swim and have a ball
# Autumn has pumpkins
and leaves that fall
[Minnie] # In winter
Santa Claus comes to call
# But I love spring best of all
# Yeah
# We're getting ready for
the best Easter party ever
# The best part is we'll be together
# And we'll be friends forever
# It's springtime
A shing-a-ling-a-ling time
# Springtime
A make you wanna sing time
# La la la la
La la la la la #
[all laughing]
Oh, it's not fair.
Mickey's having an Easter party
and everybody got an invitation but me.
And, and I like eggs and
chocolate bunnies and jelly beans.
[Sighs] If the clubhouse were mine,
I'd invite me.
Hmm...
# Pete's Clubhouse
Pete's Clubhouse
Pete's Clubhouse #
That's it.
If I become the leader of the clubhouse,
I can invite myself to the party.
[Sighs]
But how can I get Mickey
to leave the clubhouse?
[Humming]
Oh, yes. The party cake.
This gives me a sneaky idea.
[Humming]
Whoa!
Oh. Oh. Ooh.
Hello there, Clarabelle.
Oh. Why, hello... Pete.
Say, why don't you let me
be a polite gentlemanlike person,
and carry Mickey's cake
to the clubhouse for you?
Oh, my! How courteous of you.
But... you sure you're
not up to something sneaky?
[Gasps] Me? Sneaky?
Oh, why, I'm just being
a polite gentlemanlike person...
...beautiful Clarabelle.
[Giggles]
Why, thank you.
Here, Pete. You take the cake.
I certainly do.
I mean, my pleasure.
[Giggles]
Now I can go make myself
even more beautiful for the party.
Bye-bye.
- # M-I-C-K-E-Y
- [beeping]
[Ringing]
- Hello.
- Hello, Mickety Mouse.
- Yes?
- This is Clarabelle Cow.
Are you sure?
This sounds like Pete.
Oh, I mean...
[mimicking] This is Clarabelle Cow,
and you need to go to the bakery
right away to pick up your cake.
- [Chuckles] I mean... [high chuckle]
- Oh, well, sure thing, Clarabelle.
I'll head right over.
[Chuckles]
When Mickey leaves, then
I'll become leader of the clubhouse.
[Laughing]
Hmm. That's funny.
Come on, fella.
Let's go pick up the cake.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- See ya later, Minnie.
- Bye-bye, Mickey.
Everybody say ''upslide.''
- Whee!
- [Barking]
- [Doorbell rings]
- Oh, I wonder who that could be.
[Mimicking] Um, uh... Hiya, Minnie.
I'm back with the cake.
Oh, and uh, I'm Mickey Mouse.
[Giggles] Is that Mickey?
I am so... I am so Mickey,
leader of the clubhouse.
Well, if you're Mickey, then you'd
know everything Mickey knows, right?
- Yeah, sure.
- OK, then.
To open up the clubhouse,
what are the right magic words?
And remember what happens
if you use the wrong words.
Um... Let me see.
Mickey said them before,
but now I don't remember.
Oh, I know.
Um, uh, It's...
Piska, pooska, pick-a-Mouse.
I mean, uh, Mickey Mouse. Ha ha.
- Are those the right magic words?
- Yeah, yeah.
Oh, no. Those are not
the right magic words.
- Whoa.
- Oh.
- Oh, no.
- Oh!
- [Both scream]
- [Grunts]
- [Gasps] Pete.
- What?
[Donald] Hey, what's the big idea?
[Daisy] Whoa. Up, up and away.
Gosh.
Where's the ground going?
This can't be right.
Now what?
Uh, hopsy-popsy, shooba-dee-doo.
Uh, handsy-glovesy...
Please come down.
Oopsie.
I said the wrong magic words, didn't I?
Drat. I'm in big trouble now.
[Humming]
Oh, ding dong it, it's Mickey.
I'd better get out of here
before he sees me.
Strange that Clarabelle
wasn't at the bakery.
[Barking]
Huh?! What happened
to the clubhouse?
The clubhouse floated away?
Who made that happen?
Pete did it? He said the wrong
magic words? Uh-oh!
We've gotta get the clubhouse back and
rescue Minnie, Goofy, Daisy and Donald,
or we won't be able
to have our Easter party.
Will you help us find all the pieces of
the clubhouse and get our friends back?
Hot dog!
[Sniffing]
Hey, look. Pluto's already on the trail.
Attaboy, Pluto.
Come on, let's follow Pluto
and look for the clubhouse.
Aw, Pluto, how will we ever find
all the pieces of the clubhouse?
Whoa! Whoo-hoo!
Ta-da!
Oh, boy! It's Professor Von Drake.
- [Chuckles] Hello there, Mickey.
- Professor, we need your help.
The clubhouse floated away.
You're telling me. I almost rocketed
right into the clubhouse pants.
Fortunately, the professor
went under the pants.
I said ''underpants.''
Did you hear that?
You saw the clubhouse pants?
That's right.
They landed right over there.
Oh, Minnie.
- Oh, you found me.
- We rescued Minnie.
[Sniffing]
[Growls and barks]
Hey, wait a minute. That's Pete.
No, it's not.
Oh, that Pete is running away.
Aw, Pete must think I'm upset with him
for making the clubhouse float away.
But I'm not.
Gee, we could really use his help.
Don't worry about that, Mickey.
Now that we've found the pants,
we've got the Mousekedoer to help us.
Say, that's right, Professor.
Oh, that means we can
use our Mouseketools.
Hot dog!
Come on, everybody.
Let's go get our Mouseketools
from the Mousekedoer.
[Hydraulic hissing]
# Mouseker-hey, Mouseker-hi
Mouseker-ho
# Mouseker-ready, Mouseker-set
Here we go
# You're a thinkin' and a solvin'
Work it through-er
# Mouseker-me, Mouseker-you
Mousekedoer
# Meeska, mooska, Mousekedoer
# Mouseketools Mouseketools
Mouseketools
# Here are your Mouseketools #
[Mickey] A pacifier?
My toolbox.
A crane. Wow!
Ooh, and the mystery Mouseketool.
That's a surprise tool
that can help us later.
Look, it's Toodles.
Hiya, Toodles.
- Hi there, Mr. Toodles.
- Hi, Toodles.
[Mickey] Toodles is gonna bring us our
Mouseketools when we need them.
Oh, boy!
We got our Mouseketools.
Now let's go find the
other pieces of the clubhouse.
And rescue Donald, Daisy and Goofy.
[Barking]
Hold on, Mickey. We've got to get this
pants piece back where it belongs.
Oops. You're right.
Hmm. How are we going
to do that, Professor?
Every time you
find a piece of the clubhouse,
you have to touch it. Like so...
Then, you're gonna say
the right magic words.
Well, we know those.
Meeska, mooska, Mickey Mouse.
That's right. And after you're
saying the magic words,
the piece will fly back home with you.
Alright. Let's send the pants back home.
Everybody say the right magic words.
[All] Meeska, mooska, Mickey Mouse!
[Von Drake] Whoop-de-do. Here we go.
Oh, boy. We did it!
We did it!
Well, ain't that something?
The pants are back.
They sure are. Thanks, everybody.
But, Mickey, before we can
have our Easter party,
we need to find four more pieces.
Four more. You betcha!
Professor, what's the
next piece we need to find?
Well, why don't we
check with Toodles, let's?
Good idea.
Everybody say, ''Oh, Toodles!''
[All] Oh, Toodles!
Alright. Toodles, do your doodles.
[Von Drake] Oh, look at that.
It's like a puzzle.
Now, already we've found
the first piece, the pants.
Where does the first piece go?
In number one.
[Mickey] So what's the next
number we need to find?
[Von Drake] Number two.
Right, the shoe.
Just remember...
# The pieces of the clubhouse
look a lot like Mickey Mouse
- # Number one
- # The pants
- # Number two
- # The shoe
- # Number three
- # The head
- # Number four
- # The ears
- # And number five
- # The hand
# Let's do that again
Oh, boy!
# The pieces of the clubhouse
look a lot like Mickey Mouse
- # Number one
- # The pants
- # Number two
- # The shoe
- # Number three
- # The head
- # Number four
- # The ears
- # And number five
- # The hand
- # The hand?
- # The hand #
OK, we gotta find number two.
- The shoe.
- That's the shoe garage, is what.
Come on.
Let's go find the shoe garage.
- [Clicking]
- [Cow mooing]
[Engine sputtering, coughing]
- Goodbye, Mickey. Happy landings.
- Good luck, Mickey.
[Chuckles] Bunny ears.
Are you ready to be my copilot?
Swell! Pilot to copilot,
if you see the shoe garage, say ''shoe.''
Yeah, there it is. And there's Goofy.
Hey there, Mickey.
Goofy, you're heading for a waterfall.
Wow! Heading for a waterfall?!
Why would I want to do that?!
Whoa!
Gee, we gotta rescue Goofy.
Quick!
[Tires screeching]
- [Gasps]
- [Goofy] Oh, Mickey.
Hold on, Goof.
We're coming to the rescue.
Hey, Mickey,
you gotta unstick the shoe.
I mean, get the shoe unstuck.
And get me out of here!
Let's check our Mouseketools
for something to help us.
Everybody say, ''Oh, Toodles!''
Oh, Toodles!
[Mickey] We've got a pacifier,
my toolbox,
a crane, and the mystery Mouseketool.
Which Mouseketool will help us
lift the shoe out of the river?
The crane. Right!
We got ears, say ''cheers!''
OK, now we're controlling the crane.
Which way should we move
the handy helper to grab the shoe?
Should we move it up or down?
[Chuckles] Down. Right!
[Chuckles] You got it!
Which way should we move
the handy helper
to pull the shoe out of the river?
Up. Right!
- [Hydraulic hissing]
- [Beeping]
Good job.
We got the shoe garage out of the river.
Yippee!
Thanks for saving Goofy Bunny.
Now let's bring the shoe back home.
Everybody say the right magic words.
[Both] Meeska, mooska, Mickey Mouse.
[Goofy shrieks]
- [Von Drake] How do you like that?
- [Minnie] It's back.
Whoo-hoo! You found the shoe!
And Goofy Bunny is back too.
Alright. Now let's see what piece
we gotta find next.
# The pieces of the clubhouse
look a lot like Mickey Mouse
- # Number one
- # The pants
- # Number two
- # The shoe
- # Number three
- # The head
- # Number four
- # The ears
- # And number five
- # The hand
- # The hand?
- # The hand #
[Von Drake] We found the second piece,
the shoe garage.
Where does it go?
- Right, in number two.
- [Mickey] What number's next?
Number three.
[Von Drake] That's the clubhouse head,
is what that is.
Come on. Let's go find
the clubhouse head.
[Engine rewing]
Happy head-hunting.
- [Chuckling]
- [Barking]
Let's look for the clubhouse head.
Yikes!
That was close.
Let's keep looking.
Well, lookie there.
- [Daisy] Whoa.
- [Mickey] Is that the clubhouse head?
It sure is. Come on.
Mickey!
Please get me down.
- I'm getting dizzy.
- Gee.
We gotta get the head down
and rescue Daisy.
What's holding the head way up there?
The water. Right!
We're gonna have to turn the water off
to bring the head back down.
Yes. Just turn...
...the valve.
Hmm. Turn the valve.
[Straining]
[Panting]
[Straining] Wow!
- [Crash]
- [Cat screeching]
Well, that didn't work.
[Chuckles] Gee, this is
really hard to turn.
Say, do you see anyone
who could help us turn the valve?
Yeah, there's Pete.
He's strong. Hiya, Pete.
Oopsie! Gotta go.
- Pete, wait!
- [Chicken clucks]
Aw gee, we could've
really used his help.
[Daisy] Hurry, Mickey.
Hey, I'll betcha a Mouseketool
can help us turn the valve.
Everybody say, ''Oh, Toodles!''
Oh, Toodles!
[Mickey] Which Mouseketool has
something to help us tighten the valve?
My toolbox. Right!
We got ears, say ''cheers!''
Oh, boy!
Which wrench matches
the shape on the valve?
This one, the flower shape.
Right. Now we can tighten
the valve and stop the water.
Will you help me tighten the valve?
Great! Turn the wrench with me.
Turn, turn, turn.
Now, one more great big turn.
[Straining] Turn!
Wow! You're really strong.
Whew! Thanks for
getting me down, Mickey.
And thank you too.
Aw, anytime.
Come on. Let's get the
clubhouse head back home.
Everybody say the right magic words.
Meeska, mooska, Mickey Mouse.
[Daisy] Whee!
- [Goofy] You're back! Yipee!
- [Von Drake] There they are.
- Oh, terrific.
- You did it.
With the head back in place,
we're really getting ahead.
- And Daisy's back home.
- We did it!
Alright, let's see what piece
we need to find next.
# The pieces of the clubhouse
look a lot like Mickey Mouse
- # Number one
- # The pants
- # Number two
- # The shoe
- # Number three
- # The head
- # Number four
- # The ears
- # And number five
- # The hand
- # The hand?
- # The hand #
[Von Drake] We found the third piece.
That's the head, you know.
Now then, where does
the third piece go?
Right! In number three.
[Mickey] So what number piece
should we look for next?
Number four, the ears.
[Von Drake] Two round ears,
just like Mickey's ears.
You know, I have
a suspicion where they went.
Good thing I have a giant telescope.
- [Cow mooing]
- [Hydraulic hissing]
- Gosh.
- Oh, my!
That is a big telescope.
[Barking]
How about a peek there, Mickey.
Gee, sure thing, Professor.
Come on, look with me.
Let's find the clubhouse ears.
Now, if you see the ears, say ''ears!''
Ooh. [snickers]
- Hello.
- Hi, there.
[Both laughing]
[Mickey] Aw, that's Chip 'n Dale.
What? You saw the ears?
Yeah, there they are.
Gosh, but how are we
gonna get to them?
Well, to get them,
we can take the clubhouse rocket.
Great idea, Minnie.
[Chuckles] Come on, copilots.
[Minnie] Blasting off in ten seconds.
Count down from ten to one with us.
Ten, nine, eight,
seven, six, five,
four, three, two, one...
Blastoff!
[All cheering]
Oh, boy!
Let's look at the screen
and figure out how to get to the ears.
Do you see the ears?
Yep. There they are, on that planet.
Hmm. Now which path
should we take to get there?
The path of pink space rocks?
The path of yellow stars?
Or the path of purple satellites?
The path of stars! Right.
Oh, and look, Mickey.
The stars are making a pattern.
Big star, little star, little star.
# Big star, little star, little star
Sing the pattern with us.
# Big star, little star, little star #
[Minnie giggles] Hooray! We made it.
Let's go get those ears.
Good luck, Mickey.
See you at the clubhouse.
Help me rocket to the ears.
Put your hands up in the air
and fly with me.
Here we go!
Donald!
Are you in there?
Oh, boy, oh, boy!
You found me.
[Marching music plays]
[Chuckles]
OK, Donald.
Let's send these ears back home.
Everybody say the right magic words.
Meeska, mooska, Mickey Mouse.
[Mickey chuckles] Wahoo!
[Chip 'n Dale chuckling]
- [All cheering]
- The ears are back!
- You found the ears.
- And Donald's back.
I was in outer space.
Oh, boy! We got all our friends back.
But we still have
one last piece to find.
# The pieces of the clubhouse
look a lot like Mickey Mouse
- # Number one
- # The pants
- # Number two
- # The shoe
- # Number three
- # The head
- # Number four
- # The ears
- # And number five
- # The hand
- # The hand?
- # The hand #
[Von Drake] Let's see.
We found the fourth piece, the ears.
Where do they go?
Right, in number four.
[Mickey] So what number
do we still need to find?
Number five, the hand.
[Von Drake] That's the glove balloon,
you know.
[Chuckles] Ooh.
We don't need the glove balloon, Mickey.
I'm ready for the Easter party
right now.
Yeah, me too.
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
Uh-oh.
Mickey, what's the matter?
I, uh... We don't have any Easter eggs.
What?! No Easter eggs?
I put all our eggs in one basket.
The glove balloon basket.
Oh, boy. This is one bad pickle.
Where could the glove balloon
have gone?
Yeah, we've looked
almost everywhere.
- Even in outer space.
- Oh, this is terrible.
Exasperating.
[Whimpering]
Aw, Pluto. [sniffles]
Well, the clubhouse just won't
be the same without the glove balloon.
And I ruined the party.
Gosh, I wish somebody saw
where the glove balloon went.
Hmm. Oh, I know. Pete did.
He saw all the pieces
of the clubhouse float away.
That's right. Maybe Pete knows
where the glove balloon went.
You at home out there,
do you see Pete anywhere?
Huh?
Uh-uh, uh-uh... Shh.
- You see Pete?
- Yes, there he is.
No, there he ain't.
Help us call for Pete.
Say, ''Oh, Pete.''
[All] Oh, Pete.
Gosh, maybe Pete didn't hear us.
Let's call him again, louder.
[Iouder] Oh, Pete!
[Chuckles] One more time everybody.
The loudest of all.
[Yelling] Oh, Pete!
Oh.
Hello, everybody.
You know, I...
I wasn't hiding or anything.
- I just...
- Pete! Oh, boy!
- I sure am glad to see ya.
- You are?
It's OK, Pete. We know
you said the wrong magic words
and made the clubhouse go to pieces.
But I didn't mean to.
I was just playing, you see. And...
- Don't worry. You can make up for it.
- I can?
I need you to think really hard.
Now, did you happen to see
where the glove balloon went?
The glove balloon, you say?
Let me think now.
Glove? Kinda like this one, bigger?
- Uh-huh.
- Yeah, yeah.
The glove balloon. Right.
I remember. I saw it
float all the way up there.
[Mickey] Wow! All the way
up into the clouds.
Gosh, that's where the giant lives.
- Giant?
- Oh, boy.
You don't want to be disturbing him.
But we need to get
the glove balloon back.
Why, it's the last piece
of the clubhouse.
Don't forget about the Easter eggs.
We can't have an
Easter egg hunt without eggs.
Hmm. We're gonna need something
to help us float quietly
up into the clouds.
Well, maybe one of those
Mousekedoodles...
I mean, Mouseketools can help us.
Good idea, Goofy Bunny.
Everybody say, ''Oh, Toodles.''
[All] Oh, Toodles!
[Mickey] We've got two
Mouseketools left.
The pacifier and
the mystery Mouseketool.
Can we use the pacifier
to float up into the clouds?
[Giggles] Nah, that's silly.
[Von Drake] Yipee! That means it's time
for the mystery Mouseketool.
[Mickey] Everybody say,
''Mystery Mouseketool.''
What's today's mystery Mouseketool?
- [Goofy] A bunch of balloons.
- [Mickey] You betcha.
Hmm. Will the balloons help us
float quietly up into the clouds?
They sure will.
We got ears, say ''cheers!''
Oh... I'm floating away.
Don't worry, Pete.
I'm coming with ya.
- Whoa!
- Be careful!
- Happy landings!
Whoa. It's cloudy in these clouds.
Do you see the glove balloon?
You do? Where?
How about that? There it is.
Imagine that.
Inside the giant's barn.
[Gulps]
Come on.
Let's go get that glove balloon.
I'm not scared at all.
I'm not scared at...
Well, maybe just a little.
- [Door creaking]
- [Snoring]
- The giant.
- Shh.
- We don't want to wake him up.
- Oh, we sure don't.
You know what, I got a good idea.
I'll wait outside safe and sound,
I mean, uh, standing guard,
things like that,
while you do everything and...
Pete, you said you weren't scared.
Are we brave?
- We sure are.
- We are?
Oh, yeah. We are brave.
Come on. Let's tiptoe
up to the glove balloon.
You f... first.
Help us tiptoe up to the balloon.
You need to stand up first.
Up on your feet.
Now, tiptoe with us.
[Snoring]
The giant's snoring is keeping
the balloon really high.
We're gonna need something
to stop the giant from snoring.
How can we make a giant stop snoring?
It can't be done, I tell ya.
That's why we got our Mouseketools.
Everybody whisper, ''Oh, Toodles.''
[Whispering] Oh, Toodles.
[Mickey] Will the pacifier stop
the giant from snoring?
It sure will.
We picked all our Mouseketools.
Everybody whisper, ''Super cheers!''
[Sucking]
We did it. Now let's take
the glove balloon home.
Good idea. I'll go first.
[Grunting]
Chicken feathers.
[Pete] Oh... Whoa.
[Grunts] Oopsie.
- Oh, excuse me.
- Pete, look out.
Oh... [grunts]
Hmm?
[Sniffing]
Fee-fi-fo-fum.
I smell something yummy, yum, yum.
Yikes! We better get out of here.
Ooh! A little birdie with round ears.
Mickey!
D'uh... I always wanted
a birdie for a pet.
Oh, tweet-tweet.
I'll keep you in my birdie cage.
Ooh, I'm gonna go
get you some birdie food.
I'll be right back.
D'uh, bye-bye birdie.
Uh-oh. What should I do?
Oh, it's mean Pete.
[Chuckles] This is your
big chance, Pete, buddy.
Now that you've got the glove balloon,
you can have the
clubhouse all to yourself.
- Just like you were thinking.
- Yeah. Pete's clubhouse.
- Uh-oh. It's nice Pete.
- Now, now, Petey.
You know it's not nice to leave
poor Mickey in the giant's birdcage.
- He's your friend.
- Mickey's not your friend.
He didn't even give you an invitation
to the Easter party, remember?
- He's got you there, nice Pete.
- Oh. But Mickey did invite you.
The invitation's right there,
inside your back pocket.
- It's been there all this time.
- It is?
Do you see the invitation?
Well, paint me
a polka-dotted bunny rabbit
and sit me in the plastic green grass.
I got an invitation to the Easter party.
Oh... Mickey didn't forget me.
Maybe I shouldn't have been so sneaky.
Oh, weasels.
Well, what are we waiting for?
We gotta save our friend, Mickey.
Hold on there, pal.
Pete!
[Grunting]
Say, will you kids help me
fly the glove balloon
all the way up to the birdcage
and save Mickey?
Great!
Now, reach your hand in the air
and grab the rope.
Now pull.
It's working. OK, keep pulling there.
Great! Now, one more big pull!
Way to go! We made it.
Hurry up, Pete.
We gotta open the birdcage
before the giant comes back.
Will you help me and Pete
lift the latch?
Great!
Now put your hands out in front of you,
grab the latch and lift.
- Lift, lift, lift.
[Both straining]
We almost got it.
[Giant] # Fee-fi-fo-fum
Fee-fi-fo-fum
Oh, pomegranates,
the giant's coming back.
Now, one more great big lift.
[Both straining]
Hooray! Good work.
Now let's get out of here.
Huh? [grunting]
Come back, birdie.
Hurry there, Mickey.
The giant's coming.
We have to say
the magic words super fast.
What are the right magic words?
Meeska, mooska, Mickey Mouse.
Say them again, only faster.
Bye-bye.
I taught him how to fly.
- [Pete laughing]
- [Mickey] Hooray!
- Oh, boy.
- [Pete] That was a close one.
Whew! Gee, thanks for helping us
get away from the giant.
[Chuckling] Ooh!
Lookie here.
Easter eggs and jelly beans.
Aw, those are for the Easter party.
You got your invitation,
didn't you, Pete?
I sure did, Mickey.
I thought you forgot about me,
but you didn't.
'Cause you're my pal.
[Chuckles] You betcha, pal.
You know, I'm glad you're leader
of the clubhouse, Mickey.
[Sighs] It's too much work for me.
[Chuckles] Oh, look. We're almost home.
[All cheering]
They're home.
- That's fantastic!
- This is great!
Yahoo! You found
all five pieces, you did.
# The pieces of the clubhouse
look a lot like Mickey Mouse
- # Number one
- # The pants
- # Number two
- # The shoe
- # Number three
- # The head
- # Number four
- # The ears
- # And number five
- # The hand
- # The hand?
- # The hand #
[Von Drake] Now that we
got the fifth piece,
the handy glove balloon,
where does it go?
In number five. Right you are.
[Mickey] We put the
clubhouse back together.
[All cheering]
- [Mickey] Oh, boy!
- Yipee!
It sure is the best clubhouse.
Now we can have our Easter party.
- Yeah!
- [All cheering]
Oh, Pete, you brought the cake.
My hero.
Oh, look what I found everybody.
Look.
- I found one too.
- Me three.
They don't call me
Goofy Bunny for nothing.
[Chuckling]
# This really, really is
the best Easter party ever
# The best part is we're all together
# And we'll be friends forever
# It's springtime
A shing-a-ling-a-ling time
# Springtime
A make you wanna sing time
# La la la la
La la la la la
# Hanging the streamers
I'm the tallest one
# Finding eggs is so much fun
# I made a banner
with glitter and glue
# Decorated eggs of yellow and blue
# I'm making the music
I can't wait
# Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy
This is gonna be great!
# So much to do
No time to stop
# I wanna do the bunny hop
# Hop, hop, hop, hop
# This really, really is
the best Easter party ever
# The best part is we're all together
# And we'll be friends forever
# It's springtime
A shing-a-ling-a-ling time
# Springtime
A make you wanna sing time
# La la la la
La la la la la
[Daisy] # In summer we
swim and have a ball
# Autumn has pumpkins
and leaves that fall
[Minnie] # In winter
Santa Claus comes to call
# But I love spring best of all
# Yeah!
# This really, really is
the best Easter party ever
# The best part is we're all together
# And we'll be friends forever
# It's springtime
A shing-a-ling-a-ling time
# Springtime
A make you wanna sing time
# La la la la
La la la la la #
[all laughing]
[Chuckling] Aw.
Come on, everybody.
Up on your feet.
Let's do the hot dog dance.
[# They Might Be Giants: Hot Dog!]
# Hot dog!
[Barking in tune]
# Hot dog, hot dog
Hot diggity dog
# Now we got ears
It's time for cheers
# Hot dog, hot dog
The problem's solved
Hot diggity dog
Wow! We had quite a day
hunting for the parts of the clubhouse.
We found the clubhouse pants first.
[Minnie] That's where I was.
[Mickey] Then we used the crane
to get the shoe garage.
[Goofy] I nearly fell
down the waterfall.
[Mickey] Next we used the toolbox
to get Daisy down.
[Daisy] I was dizzy Daisy.
[Mickey] We found Donald in space.
[Donald] Outer space.
[Mickey] And, finally, we used the
balloons to fly up to the clouds,
and the pacifier to get the glove
balloon away from the giant.
What a hot dog day!
# Hot dog, hot dog
Hot diggity dog
# It's a brand new day
What you waiting for?
# Get up, stretch out
Stomp on the floor
# Hot dog, hot dog
Hot diggity dog
# We're splitting the scene
We're full of beans
# So long for now
From Mickey Mouse
That's me.
# And the Mickey Mouse
# Clubhouse #
See ya real soon.
Subtitles by ARAVIND B
[by_agentsmith@yahoo.com]