NARRATOR:
In 1899, the streets of New York City
echoed with the voices of newsies,
peddling the newspapers
of Joseph Pulitzer,
William Randolph Hearst
and other giants of the newspaper world.
On every corner,
you saw them carrying the banner,
bringing you the news
for a penny a pape.
Poor orphans and runaways,
the newsies were a ragged army
without a leader.
Until one day, all that changed.
[FINGERS SNAPPING]
Boots!
[BOYS YAWNING]
Skittery. Skittery.
- Skittery!
- I didn't do it. Ow!
What do you mean, you didn't do it?
Get up. Get up!
When you get up,
you have to get up. Snitch!
Get up, get up, get up.
Come on, everybody's sleeping here.
They sleep, they sleep.
They sleep their life away, these kids.
The ink is wet. The presses are rolling!
Sell the papes! Sell the papes!
BOY 1:
Hey.
Hey, Cowboy. Hey, Cowboy. Come on.
You're dreaming about selling papers?
Hey, hey, hey.
Don't want to.
What's the matter with you?
- What's the matter with me?
- What's the matter with you?
I ain't selling any of your--
Get off my back.
- Hey, go away from me. You're mad.
- Come on. Hey.
Kid. Ha-ha-ha!
Get up. Get up, boy.
Come on, come on.
All right, carry your banner!
Sell the papers! Sell the papers!
What are you doing? Sell the papers!
Everybody, everybody.
What are you doing?
You too. You too. Get on over there.
All right, don't go.
[SINGING]
That's my cigar
You'll steal another
Hey, hey, bummers, we got work to do
Since when did you become
Me mother?
Ah, stop your bawling
ALL:
Who asked you?
[YAWNS]
- So how'd you sleep, Jack?
- On me back, Mush.
Ha-ha-ha! Hear that, fellas?
Hear what Jack said?
I asked Jack how he slept and he said,
"On me back, Mush."
Hey, Jack, when I walk,
does it look like I'm faking it?
- No. Who says you're faking it?
- I don't know.
It's just-- There's so many fake crips
on the street today,
a real crip ain't got a chance.
I gotta find me a new selling spot
where they ain't used to seeing me.
Try Bottle Alley or the harbor
Try Central Park, it's guaranteed
Try any banker, bum or barber
They almost all knows how to read
I smell money
You smell foul
Met this girl last night
Ah, move your elbow
Pass the towel
For a buck, I might
ALL:
Ain't it a fine life?
Carrying the banner through it all
A mighty fine life
Carrying the banner tough and tall
Every morning
We goes where we wishes
We's as free as fishes
Sure beats washing dishes
What a fine life
Carrying the banner, home free all
BOY 1:
Whoo!
BOY 2: Yeah.
BOY 3: Yeah.
BOY 4: Move it. Go, go, go.
Come on, come on, come on.
Hurry up. Come on, come on, come on.
Hurry up. Get the lead out of your pants.
Come on, come on. Move it, move it.
Go, go, go. Hurry. Go, go, go!
ALL:
Summer stinks and winter's waiting
Welcome to New York
Boy, ain't nature fascinating
When youse gotta walk?
Still it's a fine life
- Carrying the banner with me chums
- It's a fine life
- A mighty fine life
- Blowing every nickel as it comes
- It's a fine life
- I'm no snoozer
Sitting makes me antsy
I likes living chancy
ALL:
Harlem to Delancey
What a fine life
Carrying the banner through the slums
Blessed children
Though you wander lost and depraved
Jesus loves you
You shall be saved
- Patrick
- Just give me half a cup
- Darling
- Something to wake me up
- Since you left me
- I gotta find an angle
- I am undone
- I gotta sell more papes
- Mother
ALL: Papers is all I got
Wish I could catch a breeze
- Loves you
- Sure hope the headline's hot
All I can catch is fleas
- God help me if it's not
- God save
- Somebody help me please
- My
- Son
- If I hate the headline
I'll make up the headline
And I'll say anything I have to
Because it's two for a penny
If I take too many
Weasel just makes me eat them after
Look, they're putting up a headline
You call that a headline?
I get better stories
From the copper on the beat
I was gonna start with 20
But a dozen will be plenty
Will you tell me
How am I gonna make ends meet?
We need a good assassination
We need an earthquake or a war
How about a crooked politician?
Hey, stupid, that ain't news no more
Uptown to Grand Central Station
Down to city hall
We improves our circulation
Walking till we fall
So we'll be out there
Carrying the banner man to man
The idiot what wrote it
Must be working for The Sun
We'll be out there
Soaking every sucker that we can
Heard the toll was even higher
Why do I miss all the fun?
See the headlines
Newsies on a mission
Kill the competition
Sell the next edition
While we're out there
Carrying the banner is the--
BOY 1:
Hey.
BOY 2:
Come here. Hey.
Dear me.
What is that unpleasant aroma?
I fear the sewer may have backed up
during the night.
BOOTS:
Ah, too rotten to be the sewer.
Yeah, yeah.
It must be the Delancey brothers.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Hi, boys.
In the back, you lousy little shrimp.
BOY 3: Hey.
BOY 4: See that?
That's not good to do that, not healthy.
You shouldn't be calling people
lousy little shrimps, Oscar,
unless you're referring to the family
resemblance in your brother here.
ALL:
Ooh.
Hey, hey, 5-to-1, the Cowboy
skunks them, huh? Who's betting?
ALL: Bum odds.
- That's right, it's an insult.
So is this.
[ALL CHEERING]
RACETRACK:
Come on.
BOY 1:
Yeah, take him.
BOY 2:
Cowboy, look out.
Where'd Cowboy go?
BOY 3:
Hey, look, there he goes.
BOY 4:
Where is he?
[BOTH GRUNT]
[ALL LAUGHING]
- What do you think you're doing?
KID BLINK: Go, Jack.
OSCAR: Get him.
- Running.
It's a fine life
Carrying the banner through it all
Thank you. Thank you.
A mighty fine life
- Thank you. Thank you. You're too kind.
- Carrying the banner tough and tall
Thank you.
See the headline
Newsies on a mission
Kill the competition
- Sell the next edition
- Come on.
What a fine life
Carrying the banner
- It's a fine life
- Go get 'em, Cowboy
Carrying the banner
- It's a fine life
- You've got 'em, Cowboy
Carrying the banner
- It's a fine life
- Go get 'em, Cowboy
Carrying the banner
- It's a fine life
- You've got 'em, Cowboy
Carrying the banner
It's a-- Go!
This is for the newsies.
[ALL CHEERING]
Brilliant performance, Jackie, brilliant.
Better than yesterday's.
You're too kind to me, Race.
You're too kind.
- We'll play again tomorrow, Cowboy.
- That'll be nice.
RACETRACK: You're late, boys.
MORRIS: You're as good as dead, Cowboy.
Mr. Weasel?
WEASEL: All right, all right.
Hold your horses, hold your horses.
I'm coming.
So did you miss me, Weasel?
- Did you? Did you miss me?
RACETRACK: Brilliant, Jack.
I told you a million times,
the name is Weisel.
Mr. Weisel to you.
How many?
Don't rush me. I'm perusing
the merchandise, Mr. Weasel.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
BOY 1: Nice.
RACETRACK: He's perusing.
The usual.
A hundred papes to the wise guy.
- Next.
- Morning, Your Honor.
Listen. Do me a favor, Weas?
Spot me 50 papes, huh?
I got a hot tip.
You won't waste your money.
- It's a sure thing?
- Oh, yeah. Not like last time.
Uh-huh. Fifty papes. Next.
Hey, Mr. Weisel.
Hey, how about 30 papes, please?
WEASEL:
Thirty papes for Crutchy.
- Anything good this morning?
CRUTCHY: Thanks.
JACK: You wanna sit down?
WEASEL: Next.
Uh, twenty papes, please.
- Twenty papes.
- Thanks.
Look at this.
"Baby born with two heads."
It must be from Brooklyn.
Hey, hey, come on, come on.
You got your papes. Now beat it.
I paid for 20, I only got 19.
WEASEL:
Are you accusing me of lying, kid?
DAVID:
No, I just want my paper.
He said beat it.
No, it's 19, Weasel.
It's 19. But don't worry about it,
it's an honest mistake.
I mean, Morris,
he can't count to 20 with his shoes on.
[ALL LAUGHING]
WEASEL:
All right, get out of here.
- Hold it. Race, will you spot me two bits?
- Here.
Thanks. Another 50 for my friend here.
- I don't want another 50.
- Sure you do.
- Every newsie wants more papes.
- I don't.
RACETRACK: What, are you stupid?
DAVID: I don't want your papes.
I don't take charity from anybody.
I don't even know you. I don't care to.
So here are your papes.
- Cowboy. They call him Cowboy.
- Yeah.
Well, that and a lot of other things,
including Jack Kelly,
which is what my mother called me.
- And what do they call you, kid?
- Les. And this is my brother, David.
- He's older.
- Oh, no kidding.
- So how old are you, Les?
- Near 10.
Near 10. Well, that's no good.
If anyone asks, you should say you're 7.
See, younger sells more papes. If we're
gonna be partners, we wanna be the best.
Wait, wait, wait.
Who said anything about partners?
Well, you owe me two bits, right?
Well, so I'll consider that an investment.
We sell together,
we split seventy-thirty.
Plus you get the benefit
of observing me, no charge.
[SCOFFS]
Hey, you're getting the chance
of a lifetime here, Davey.
You learn from Jack,
you learn from the best.
- The best.
BOY 1: That's right.
Well, if he's the best,
then how come he needs me?
ALL:
Ooh.
Listen, I don't need you, pal.
But I ain't got a cute little brother
like Les here to front for me.
You know, with this kid's puss
and my God-given talent,
we could move 1000 papes a week.
So, what do you say, Les?
- You wanna sell papes for me?
- Yeah.
JACK: So it's a deal?
DAVID: Wait, wait. Hold it.
It's gotta be at least fifty-fifty.
Sixty-forty or I forget the whole thing.
- That's fair.
BOY 2: A golden opportunity.
BOY 3: That's fair.
BOY 4: That's fair.
BOY 2:
A golden opportunity here.
What do you say?
- It's very fair.
BOY 5: Twenty papes, Mr. Weasel.
- What's the matter?
- That's disgusting.
[ALL LAUGHING]
The name of the game
is volume, Dave.
You only took 20 papes.
- Why?
- Bad headline.
That's the first thing you gotta learn.
Headlines don't sell papes.
Newsies sell papes.
ALL:
Newsies.
We're what holds this town together.
Without newsies, nobody knows nothing.
KID BLINK:
That's right. Hey, fellas.
BOY 1:
Look at that angel.
MUSH:
I'm in heaven.
Baby born with three heads!
ALL:
Get your papes here!
[ALL CLAMORING]
PULITZER:
"Trolley Strike Drags on for Third Week."
And this so-called headline
drags on for infinity.
BUNSEN:
The news is slow, Mr. Pulitzer.
The trolley strike's all we got.
Well, that's all
Mr. William Randolph Hearst has too,
but look how he covers the strike.
Look!
We'll get a new headline writer, sir.
We'll steal Hearst's man.
Offer him double.
SEITZ:
That's how he stole him from us.
It's not the headlines, chief.
These circulation wars
are cutting into our profits
because you spend as much as you make
trying to beat Hearst.
Then we need to make more profits.
You do not penny-pinch
when you're in a war, Seitz.
Victory means everything.
Now, when I created The World...
[BOYS CLAMORING IN DISTANCE]
What is that deafening noise?
Just the newsies, sir.
I'll go and have them quieted.
Never mind the newsies.
[PULITZER CHUCKLES]
- Where was I?
- Creating The World, chief.
SPECS:
Baby born with three heads!
PULITZER: There's lots of money
down there in those streets, gentlemen.
I wanna know how I can get more of it.
By tonight.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[GRUNTS]
[CHEERING AND SHOUTING]
Extra, extra. Trolley strike drags on.
Extra, extra. Ellis Island in flames.
Big conflagration.
Hey, what? Wait. Where's that story?
Thank you, sir. Page 9.
Thousands flee in panic!
MAN 1: Hey, here you go.
- Thank you. Much obliged to you. Ladies.
"Trash fire next to immigration building
terrifies sea gulls"?
JACK:
Terrified flight from inferno!
Thousands of lives at stake.
Thank you.
MAN 2: Up here. Up here.
JACK: At the top.
Extra, extra!
Thank you, sir.
Extra, extra.
Hey, you start in the back like I told you?
Okay, show me again.
[COUGHS]
[IN BRITISH ACCENT]
Buy me last pape, mister?
Ha. It's heartbreaking. Go get them.
My father taught us not to lie.
Yeah, well, mine told me not to starve,
so we both got an education.
You're just making up things,
all these headlines.
I don't do nothing
the guys who write it don't do.
Anyway, it ain't lying.
It's just improving the truth a little.
[CROWD BOOING]
[BELL DINGS]
[BOXERS PUNCHING]
MAN 3:
Right hook.
MAN 4:
Hey, come on.
- Look at that.
MAN 5: Let's go!
Sock him!
Come on!
The guy gave me a quarter.
- Quick, give me more of those papers.
DAVID: Wait, wait, hold on.
[SNIFFS]
- You smell like beer.
- Oh, that's how I made the quarter.
The guy bet me I wouldn't drink some.
Hey, no drinking on the job.
It's bad for business.
I mean, what if somebody called a cop
on you?
Is he a friend of yours?
Beat it. It's the bulls.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
LES:
All this for one sip of beer?
DAVID:
Come on, Les. Come on.
SNYDER:
Stop, I say!
DAVID: Hurry up, come on.
Come on, hurry up. Hurry up.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
SNYDER:
Sullivan!
JACK:
Up this way.
DAVID: All right. I got you, I got you.
Come on, let's go.
JACK:
Sleeper! Okay, jump.
DAVID:
Hurry up. Hurry up.
- He's right behind us. He's right behind us.
SNYDER: Move.
JACK:
Whoa!
DAVID: That's where--
JACK: Beat it.
DAVID:
Sit down.
Sullivan!
Wait till I get you back to the Refuge!
I'm not running any further.
- I want some answers.
- Shut up.
Who is he and why was he chasing you,
and what is this Refuge?
Refuge is this jail for kids.
The guy chasing me is Snyder.
He's the warden.
- You were in jail?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- Well, I was starving so I stole some food.
- Right, food.
- Yeah, food.
He called you Sullivan.
Yeah, well, my name's Kelly. Jack Kelly.
You think I'm lying?
- You have a way of improving the truth.
- Yeah?
- Why was he chasing you?
- Because I escaped.
Oh, boy. How?
Well, this big shot gave me a ride out
in his carriage.
I bet it was the mayor, right?
No, Teddy Roosevelt.
You ever heard of him?
MEDDA:
What is going on there?
Out, out, out. Out.
You wouldn't kick me out without
a kiss goodbye, would you, Medda?
Oh, Kelly. Ha-ha-ha.
Where you been, kid?
Oh, I miss seeing you
up in the balcony.
Hanging on your every word.
- So, Medda, this is David and Les.
- Yes. Hello.
And this is the greatest star
of the vaudeville stage today,
Aww.
Miss Medda Larkson,
the Swedish meadowlark.
[IN SWEDISH ACCENT]
Welcome, gentlemen.
Medda also owns the joint.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Well, what have we here?
Oh, aren't you the cutest little fellow
that ever was?
Oh, yes, you are.
[COUGHING]
Are you all right?
[IN BRITISH ACCENT]
Buy me last pape, lady?
Oh, you are good.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, yeah. Oh, this kid is really good.
Speaking as one professional to another,
I'd say you've got a great future.
So is it all right if we stay here for a while?
Just till the problem outside goes away.
Oh, sure. Sure, stay as long as you like.
Toby, just give my guests
whatever they want.
- Toby.
TOBY: Right!
Hey, lads, whatever you'd like.
Gumdrops, gumdrops.
Licorice whips.
ANNOUNCER:
Miss Medda Larkson.
[SINGING]
My lovey-dovey baby
I boo-hoo-hoo for you
I used to be your tootsie-wootsie
Then you said toodley-doo
I miss the hanky-panky
Each nighty-night till 3
Come back, my lovey-dovey baby
And coochie-coo with me
[CROWD SHOUTING
AND WHISTLING]
So you liked that?
Oh, I loved that. I loved it.
It was great. She is beautiful.
How do you know her?
She's a friend of my father's.
Come on, Les.
You wanna shine my shoes for me?
Oh, it's getting late.
My parents are gonna be worried.
What about yours?
No, they're out west
looking for a place to live.
Like this.
See? That's Santa Fe, New Mexico.
As soon as they find the right ranch,
they're gonna send for me.
- Then you'll be a real cowboy.
- Yep.
[CRASHING]
[CROWD SHOUTING]
LES:
Come on, fellas. Wait up!
MAN 1:
Hyah! Hyah!
Jack, why don't we go back to my place
and divvy up?
You can meet my folks.
MAN 2:
You stop that. Stop that! Hey!
It's the trolley strike, Dave.
These couple of dumb-asses
must not have joined or something.
Jack, let's get out of here.
[BELL RINGING]
So maybe we get a good headline
tomorrow, Dave.
Look at this.
He slept the whole way through it.
- My God, what happened?
- Nothing, Mama. He's just sleeping.
We've been waiting dinner for you.
Where have you been?
ESTHER:
It's been a good day.
You made all of this
selling newspapers?
DAVID:
Well, half of it's Jack's.
This is our selling partner, uh,
and our friend.
- Jack Kelly, my parents.
- Hello.
Uh, that's my sister, Sarah.
Esther, maybe David's partner
would like to join us for dinner.
Why don't you add a little more water
to the soup?
Mayer.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
So I gotta say that from what I saw today,
your boys are a couple of born newsies.
- Can I have a little more? Thanks.
- Yes.
So with my experience
and their hard work,
I figure we can peddle 1000 a week,
not even break a sweat.
- That many?
- More when the headlines are good.
So, what makes a headline good?
Well, you know, catchy words
like "maniac" or "corpse" or, um...
Let's see, "love nest" or "nude."
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Excuse me.
Maybe I'm talking too much.
Sarah,
go get the cake your mother's hiding
in the cabinet.
- That's for your birthday tomorrow.
- Well, I've had enough birthdays.
This is a celebration, huh?
DAVID: I'll get the knife.
SARAH: I got the plates.
It's only the beginning, Papa.
The longer I work,
the more money I'll make.
You only work
until I go back to the factory.
And then you are going back to school
like you promised.
Happy birthday, Papa.
Thank you.
Here's your knife.
This is going to heal.
They'll give me back my job.
I'll make them.
Our visitor.
Here, a piece for David.
Thanks.
[SINGING]
Come back, my lovey-dovey baby
And coochie-coo with me
[BOTH LAUGH]
ESTHER:
And what is this, David, hmm?
So how did your pop get hurt?
The factory. It was an accident.
He's no good to them anymore
so they just fired him.
He's got no union to protect him.
MAYER:
David,
it's time to come in now.
All right.
JACK:
Jack, why don't you stay here tonight?
No, thanks.
I got my own place.
But your family's real nice, Dave,
like mine.
- See you tomorrow.
- All right.
- Carrying the banner.
[ESTHER SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
[ESTHER HUMMING]
[SINGING]
So that's what they call a family
Mother, daughter, father, son
Guess that everything you heard about
Is true
So you ain't got any family
Well, who said you needed one?
Ain't you glad nobody's waiting up
For you
When I dream on my own
I'm alone but I ain't lonely
For a dreamer
Night's the only time of day
When the city's finally sleeping
When my thoughts begin to stray
And I'm on the train
That's bound for Santa Fe
And I'm free like the wind
Like I'm gonna live forever
It's a feeling time can never take away
All I need's a few more dollars
And I'm out of here to stay
Dreams come true
Yes, they do, in Santa Fe
Where does it say
You gotta live and die here?
A guy can't catch a break?
Why should you only take
What you're given?
Why should you spend
Your whole life living
Trapped where there ain't no future
Even at 17?
Breaking your back
For someone else's sake
If the light don't seem to suit you
How about a change of scene?
Far from the lousy headlines
And the deadlines in between
[GRUNTING]
COWBOY:
Yee-ha! Whoo!
Hey, boy, come on back here!
Hey, that's my horse.
Santa Fe, are you there?
Do you swear you won't forget me?
If I found you
Would you let me come and stay?
I ain't getting any younger
And before my dying day
I want space, not just air
Let them laugh in my face, I don't care
Save a place
I'll be there
So that's what they call a family
Ain't you glad you ain't that way?
Ain't you glad
You got a dream called Santa Fe?
- Hey, Race.
- Hey, Jack.
JACK:
How was your day at the track?
RACETRACK:
Remember that hot tip I told you about?
JACK: Yeah.
- Nobody told the horse.
I know we need to make more money.
That's why we're here,
to find out how to make more money.
JONATHAN:
I have several proposals. First,
to increase the paper's price.
Oh. Ohh. Then Hearst undersells me
and I'm in the poorhouse.
Brilliant, Jonathan, brilliant.
Brilliant.
Not the customer price.
The price to the distribution apparatus.
Charge the newsies more
for their papers?
- Bad idea, chief.
JONATHAN: Very well.
My next proposal,
salary cuts.
Particularly those at the top.
- Very bad idea.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Now, what do the newsies pay now,
50 cents per 100 papers?
If you raised it to, uh...
What? Uh, 60 cents?
A mere 10th of a cent per paper.
That multiplied by 40,000 papers a day.
[IMITATING ADDING MACHINE]
Seven days a week.
It definitely adds up, sir.
If you do this, every newsie we've got
will head straight for Hearst.
You don't know Hearst like I do, Seitz.
As newspapermen, he and I would cut
each other's throats to get an advantage.
But as gentlemen and as businessmen,
we often see eye to eye
on certain things.
Now, if we do it, Hearst and I--
If we do it,
then the other papers will do it.
It's gonna be awfully rough
on those children.
Nonsense, nonsense.
It'll be good for them.
Incentive, make them work harder,
sell more papers.
They'll look on it--
They'll look on it as a challenge.
A challenge.
KID BLINK:
They jacked up the price.
Did you hear that, Jack?
Ten cents a hundred.
You know what, it's bad enough
that we gotta eat what we don't sell.
Now they jacked up the price.
Can you believe that?
This will bust me.
I'm barely making a living right now.
I'll be back sleeping on the streets.
It don't make no sense.
I mean, all the money Pulitzer's making...
-Why would he gouge us?
- Because he's a tightwad, that's why.
KID BLINK: That's right.
- Hey, come on. Pipe down, it's just a gag.
- So why the jack-up, Weasel?
WEASEL: Why not?
It's a nice day.
Why don't you ask Mr. Pulitzer?
They can't do this to me, Jack.
RACETRACK: They can do whatever
they want. It's their stinking paper.
It ain't fair. We got no rights at all.
Come on, it's a rigged deck.
They got all the marbles, okay?
Jack, we got no choice.
Let's get our lousy papes
while they still got some.
No, nobody's going anywhere.
MUSH: We gotta eat, Jack.
- They can't get away with this.
Clear out, clear out.
Give him some room.
Let him think.
Jack, you done thinking yet?
WEASEL:
Hey, hey, hey.
World employees only
on this side of the gate.
[BOYS SHOUTING]
BOY 1:
Put a lid on it.
Well, listen, one thing for sure.
If we don't sell papes,
then nobody sells papes.
Nobody comes through those gates
till they put the price back where it was.
- What do you mean, like a strike?
- Yeah, like a strike.
BOY 2:
Oh, Jack.
- What, are you out of your mind?
- It's a good idea.
Jack, I was just joking.
We can't strike. We don't have a union.
Yeah, but if we go on strike,
then we are a union, right?
No, we're just a bunch of angry kids
with no money.
Maybe if we got every newsie
in New York, but...
Yeah, well, we organize.
- Crutchy, you take up a collection.
- Swell.
JACK: We'll get all the newsies
in New York together.
Jack, this isn't a joke.
You saw what happened
to those trolley workers.
Yeah, well, that's another good idea.
Any newsie don't join with us,
then we bust their heads
like the trolley workers.
DAVID: Stop and think about this, Jack.
JACK: What?
You can't just rush everybody into this.
All right, let me think about it.
Oh, listen, Dave's right.
I mean, Pulitzer and Hearst
and all them other rich fellas,
- I mean, they own this city.
ALL: Yeah.
So do we really think a bunch of street rats
like us can make any difference?
The choice has gotta be yours.
Are we just gonna take what they give us
or are we gonna strike?
- Strike!
BOY 3: Let's do it. Let's do it.
Keep talking, Jack. Tell us what to do.
BOY 4:
Yeah, tell us what to do, Jack.
Will you tell us what to do, Dave?
BOY 5: Yeah, come on, Dave,
tell us what to do.
BOY 6: As long as we stick together.
BOY 7: We gotta stick together.
Pulitzer and Hearst
have to respect our rights.
All right.
Hey, listen.
Pulitzer and Hearst
have to respect the rights
of the working boys of New York!
[ALL CHEERING]
That's right!
Well, that worked pretty good.
So, what else?
Tell them that they can't treat us
like we don't exist.
Pulitzer and Hearst,
they think we're nothing.
- Are we nothing?
ALL: No!
If we stick together like the trolley workers,
then they can't break us up.
[SINGING] Pulitzer and Hearst
They think they got us
- Do they got us?
ALL: No!
We're a union now, the newsboys union.
We have to start acting like a union.
Even though we ain't got hats or badges
We're a union, just by saying so
And The World will know
What's to stop someone
from selling our papes?
- We'll talk with them.
- Some don't hear so good.
Well, then we'll soak them!
No, we can't beat up kids in the street,
it'll give us a bad name.
CRUTCHY: Can't get any worse.
BOY 8: Jack.
What's it gonna take
to stop the wagons?
- Are we ready?
ALL: Yeah!
No.
[CHEERING]
What's it gonna take
To stop the scabbers?
Can we do it?
ALL:
Yeah!
We'll do what we gotta do
Until we break the will
Of mighty Bill and Joe
ALL:
And The World will know
And The Journal too
Mr. Hearst and Pulitzer
Have we got news for you
Now The World will hear
What we've got to say
We've been hawking headlines
But we're making them today
And our ranks will grow
And we'll kick their rear
And The World will know
That we've been here
BOY 9: That's right.
Who does he think he is, anyway?
Nobody's gonna mess with the newsies.
When the circulation bell starts ringing,
will we hear it?
ALL:
No!
What if the Delanceys come out swinging
Will we hear it?
No!
When you've got 100 voices singing
Who can hear a lousy whistle blow?
And The World will know
That this ain't no game
That we got a ton of rotten fruit
And perfect aim
So they gave their word
But it ain't worth beans
Now they're gonna see
What "stop the presses" really means
And the day has come
And the time is now
And the fear is gone
- And their name is mud
ALL: And the strike is on
- And I can't stand blood
ALL: And The World will
Pulitzer may own The World
But he don't own us
ALL: Pulitzer may own The World
Pulitzer may crack the whip
But he won't whip us
ALL: Pulitzer may crack the whip
And The World will know
And The World will learn
And The World will wonder
How we made the tables turn
And The World will see
That we had to choose
That the things we do today
Will be tomorrow's news
And the old will fall
And the young stand tall
And the time is now
And our ranks will grow
- And our ranks will grow
- And grow
- And so The World will feel the fire
And finally know
[ALL CHEERING]
BOYS [CHANTING]:
Strike! Strike! Strike!
[CHANTING CONTINUES]
[BOYS CHEERING]
We gotta get word out
to all the newsies in New York.
I need some of those...
- What do you call them?
BOY 1: Whatever you want.
- Ambassadors?
- Yeah.
Right, you guys,
you gotta be ambassadors
and go tell the others
that we're on strike.
Say, Jack, I'll take Harlem.
- Yeah, I got midtown.
- I got the Bowery, Jack.
Hey, I'll take the Bronx. Come on.
All right, and Bumlets, and Specs
and Skittery, you take Queens.
- All right, all right.
JACK: And Pie Eater, Snoddy, eastside.
Snipeshooter, you go with them.
So, what about Brooklyn?
Who wants Brooklyn?
Come on, Spot Conlon's territory.
What's the matter,
you scared of Brooklyn?
Hey, we ain't scared of Brooklyn.
- Spot Conlon makes us a little nervous.
BOY 2: Yeah.
Well, he don't make me nervous.
So you and me, Boots,
we'll go to Brooklyn.
- All right.
- And Dave can keep us company.
Right, Dave?
Sure, just as soon as you take
our demands to Pulitzer.
- Me to Pulitzer?
- Well, you're the leader, Jack.
BOY 3:
Go tell him, Jack. We're behind you.
JACK: Well, maybe the kid
will soften him up a little.
[ALL CHEERING]
ALL [CHANTING]:
Strike! Strike! Strike!
[CHANTING CONTINUES]
DENTON: Hey, what is this strike?
What's going on?
DAVID: Uh, we're bringing
our demands to Pulitzer.
What demands?
The newsies' demands.
We're on strike.
Huh. I'm with The New York Sun.
I'm Bryan Denton.
You seem like the kid in charge.
What's your name?
David.
David. David as in David and Goliath?
[DENTON CHUCKLES]
You really think old man Pulitzer's
gonna listen to your demands?
He has to.
MAN: Out, hooligan!
- So's your old lady!
You tell Pulitzer
he needs an appointment with me.
Yeah!
So this real snooty mug says to me,
"You can't see Mr. Pulitzer.
No one sees Mr. Pulitzer."
Real hoity-toity, you know the type?
- Real hoity-toity.
- So that's when I says to him:
"Listen, I ain't in the habit of
transacting no business with office boys.
Just tell him Jack Kelly's here
to see him now."
- That's when he threw us out.
DAVID: Ha, ha!
DENTON:
Does it scare you?
You're going up against
the most powerful man in New York City.
Oh, yeah, look at me, I'm trembling.
All right, keep me informed.
I wanna know everything
that's going on.
- All right?
- Are we really an important story?
DENTON:
Well, what's important?
Last year, I covered the war in Cuba.
Charged up San Juan Hill
with Colonel Teddy Roosevelt.
That was a very important story.
So is the newsies' strike important?
It all depends on you.
So my name's really gonna be
in the papers?
- Any objections?
JACK: Not as long as you get it right.
Kelly. Jack Kelly.
Oh, and Denton?
No pictures.
Sure.
DAVID: I've never been to Brooklyn, you?
BOOTS: Really?
I spent a month there one night.
JACK:
Watch this.
[JACK YELLS]
DAVID: So is this Spot Conlon
really dangerous?
[JACK & BOOTS LAUGH]
MAN:
Hang on to that, mate.
BOY 1:
Going somewhere, Kelly?
MAN: Move closer.
BOY 2: Aye-aye, captain.
MAN:
Right, Kelly.
Well, if it ain't
Jack Be Nimble, Jack Be Quick.
So you moved up in the world, Spot.
Got a river view and everything.
Hey, Boots, how's it rolling?
Here, I got a couple
of real good shooters here.
SPOT:
Yeah.
So, Jackie boy,
- I've been hearing things from little birds.
- Yeah?
SPOT:
Things from Harlem,
Queens.
All over.
They're chirping in my ear.
Jackie boy's newsies is playing
like they're going on strike.
Yeah, well, we are.
But we're not playing.
We are going on strike.
Oh, yeah? Yeah?
What is this, Jackie boy?
Some kind of walking mouth?
JACK: Yeah, it's a mouth.
But a mouth with a brain.
And if you got half of one,
you'll listen to what he's gotta say.
Go on, tell him.
Well, we started the strike,
but we can't do it alone.
So we've been talking
to other newsies all around.
Yeah.
So they told me.
But what did they tell you?
They're waiting to see what
Spot Conlon does. That you're the key.
That Spot Conlon is the most respected
and famous newsie in all of New York.
And probably everywhere else.
And if Spot Conlon joins the strike,
then they'll join,
and we'll be unstoppable.
So you gotta join us beca--
Well, you gotta.
Well, you're right, Jack.
Brains.
But I got brains too.
And more than just half of one.
How do I know you punks won't run
the first time some goon comes at you
with a club?
How do I know
you got what it takes to win?
Because I'm telling you, Spot.
SPOT:
That ain't good enough, Jackie boy.
You gotta show me.
BOY 1: Here, two.
BOY 2: I'll make you a side bet for 50 bits.
- Double down, boys. Double down.
BOY 3: Tag, you're it.
BOY 4: Pick it up, pick it up.
BOY 5: Hey, Jack.
RACETRACK: How you doing, Jack?
BOY 6: We'll go again.
BOY 7: Jack.
RACETRACK: So where's Spot, huh?
He was concerned about us
being serious. Can you imagine that?
Well, you know, Jack, maybe we ought
to ease off a little, you know?
Without Spot and the others,
there's not enough of us, Jack, you know?
Jack, maybe we're moving too soon.
- Maybe we ain't ready.
- Think so?
I think we should forget about it
for a little while.
JACK: Oh, do you?
- Yeah. I mean, we're not Brooklyn.
Hey, who are we kidding here?
Spot was right.
Is it just a game to you guys?
RACETRACK: Not a game.
BOY 8: It's just that--
- Hey, Crutchy.
CRUTCHY: Hey, Jack.
[SINGING]
Open the gates and seize the day
Don't be afraid and don't delay
Nothing can break us
No one can make us
Give our rights away
Arise and seize the day
BOY 1:
Yeah!
ALL:
Now is the time to seize the day
Send out the call and join the fray
Wrongs will be righted if we're united
Let us seize the day
[ALL CHEERING]
DAVID:
Friends of the friendless seize the day
ALL:
Raise up the torch and light the way
Proud and defiant, we'll slay the giant
Let us seize the day
Neighbor to neighbor
Father to son
One for all and all for one
Open the gates and seize the day
Don't be afraid and don't delay
Nothing can break us
No one can make us
Give our rights away
Neighbor to neighbor
Father to son
One for all and all for one
- Yeah!
[BELL RINGS]
- Anybody hear that?
ALL: No!
- So, what are we gonna do about it?
ALL: Soak them!
[BOYS CLAMORING]
WEASEL: Hurry up. Come on, come on.
It's a beautiful day.
Let's go. Let's go.
Come on, buy your papes.
Next. What's going on here?
Move it, move it! Move it!
- Next.
BOY 1: All right.
KID BLINK: Thattaboy.
JACK: All right. You did good.
BOY 2: That's right.
- It's about time. Where you been?
BOY 3: We got a big one, fellas.
BOY 4: Well, what do we have here?
BOY 5:
Drop the papes.
RACETRACK: Is he a newsie or what?
BOY 6: Hey, hey, hey.
DAVID:
Fellas, fellas.
BOY 7:
No.
DAVID:
Blink.
Now, Jack, just don't--
ALL:
Hey!
[ALL SHOUTING]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
WEASEL:
Hey, hey, hey!
MORRIS:
I'm gonna crack your dome!
WEASEL:
What's he doing?
What are you staring at?
What are you looking at?
OSCAR:
Look out.
MORRIS:
Come on, come on, come on.
BOY 8:
Come on!
[BOYS WHOOPING]
Jack!
Jack.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
Hey, it's the bulls. Hey, cheese it.
Cheese it, it's the bulls.
[LAUGHING]
RACETRACK:
Whoa! Crutchy! Scram! Scram!
[WHISTLES BLOWING]
- Hey.
CRUTCHY: Hey, fellas, how you doing?
Huh? Huh?
Hey, guys, don't. Hey, what you doing?
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
JACK:
So here it is, the Refuge.
My home sweet home.
DAVID: How can you be sure
they sent Crutchy here?
How can I be sure the Delanceys stink?
It's just the way things work, you know?
An orphan gets arrested, Snyder
makes sure he gets sent straight here
so he can rehabilitate him, you know?
The more kids in the Refuge,
the more money the city sends
to take care of them,
the more Snyder sticks in his pocket.
He's here.
DAVID:
So how come you brought the rope?
[FOOTSTEPS]
[GRUNTING]
JACK:
All right.
All right. Gently, Dave, gently.
That's good. That's good.
Cowboy, you miss the joint?
What do you say, Ten-Pin?
Listen, you got a new guy in here, Crutchy.
- The gimp? I'll get him for you.
- Yeah, the gimp.
Crutchy, Jack.
Hey, Crutchy.
[BOYS SNEEZING AND COUGHING]
I don't believe it.
Hey, thanks.
JACK:
Hey, Crutchy.
Hey, what are you hanging
around here for, huh?
What do you mean,
what am I hanging around here for?
- You know who's up on the roof? Dave.
CRUTCHY: Who?
Is that Dave?
- Hey, Dave, how you doing?
- Shh!
Listen, Crutchy, go get your stuff.
We're gonna get you out of here.
Well, uh...
Actually,
I ain't walking so good.
Oscar and Morris kind of worked me over
a little, you know?
They hurt you?
Listen, don't worry about it. Me and Dave,
we can carry you out of here.
Hey, I don't want nobody carrying me.
Never, do you hear?
Hey. Hey, Davey, you know,
they still talk
about how Jack rode out of here
on that coach.
Oh, yeah, Teddy Roosevelt's, right?
You already heard the story.
- You mean it's true?
- Of course.
[FOOTSTEPS]
Hey, cheese it.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Uh, Mr. Warden Snyder, sir,
you know, I was thinking.
I'd just like you to know that when
you were taking a nap this afternoon...
[CRUTCHY SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
I don't think they're
just going to go away, chief.
Mr. Pulitzer, sir.
Just give me the means
and I'll take care of them for you.
Give him whatever means he requires.
I want this nonsense done with,
once and for all.
- Chief--
- Shut your mouth, Seitz!
ALL [SINGING]:
Open the gates and seize the day
Don't be afraid and don't delay
Nothing can break us
No one can make us
Give our rights away
Arise and seize the day
[GRUNTING]
ALL:
Whoa!
BOY 1: Yeah!
ALL: Oh!
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[BOYS SHOUTING]
BOY 2: What are you doing?
All right, I'm running out.
RACETRACK:
Come on, you grafters, cross the line.
All right, everyone remain calm.
- Let's soak them for Crutchy.
BOY 3: Soak them for Crutchy!
Oh, Jack. Jack, it's a trick!
[BOYS SHOUTING]
DENTON:
Wait!
Hey, Jackie boy.
DAVID:
Les, get out of here, go.
Hey, hey.
- Aren't you gonna stop them, sir?
POLICEMAN: Just move along, mister.
Never fear, Brooklyn is here.
MUSH: It's Brooklyn.
BOY 4: Brooklyn.
[BOYS CHEERING]
MAN 1:
Aah!
MAN 2:
Ow!
[MEN GRUNTING]
Hey, I give up, all right?
All right, I give up.
[GROANS]
Hey, Spot.
RACETRACK:
Hi, Weas.
DAVID:
Are you all right?
[BOYS SHOUTING]
[ALL CHEERING]
Hey, David.
Jack. Boys, freeze.
- Freeze.
- All right, guys.
BOY: Extra, extra! Children's crusade.
Newsies stop The World. Yeah!
DENTON: Hey, fellas.
BOY 1: Hey.
This is it.
You're in this too, yeah.
[ALL CHATTERING]
Hey, hey. Bigtime.
KID BLINK:
Hey, what you got there, Jack?
SPOT:
Where's my picture?
Hey, where's me picture?
Where's me picture?
BOOTS: Hey, all of them words there,
they all about us?
MUSH: Look, Jack. You look like a general.
JACK: Get your fingers off my face.
- Where does it say my name?
- Quit thinking about yourself.
Well, you got us on the front page.
You got yourselves on the front page.
I just gotta make sure you stay there.
So what, you get your picture in
the papes? So, what's that get you, huh?
- Hey, what are you talking about, huh?
JACK: Hey, shut up.
- You've been in a bad mood all day.
- I'm not in a bad mood.
You've been glum and dumb.
What's the matter with you?
You're in the papes, you're famous.
You're famous, you get anything you want.
And that's what's so great
about New York.
ALL:
Yeah.
[SINGING] A pair of new shoes
With matching laces
A permanent box
At the Sheepshead races
A porcelain tub with boiling water
A Saturday night
With the mayor's daughter
Look at me, I'm the king of New York
Suddenly I'm respectable
Staring right at you, lousy with stature
Nobbing with all the muckety-mucks
I'm blowing my dough and going deluxe
Then there I be, ain't I pretty?
- It's my city, I'm the king of New York
BOY 2:
Don't rip the paper.
I said, don't rip it.
A corduroy suit with fitted knickers
A mezzanine seat to see the flickers
Havana cigars that cost a quarter
An editor's desk for the star reporter
Tip your hat, he's the king of New York
How about that?
I'm the king of New York
In nothing flat, he'll be covering
Brooklyn to Trenton, our man Denton
Making the headline out of a hunch
- Protecting the weak
- And paying for lunch
- When I'm at bat, strong men crumble
- Proud yet humble
- I'm the king of New York
- He's the king of New York
Gotta be either dead or dreaming
Because look at that pape
With my face beaming
Tomorrow they may wrap fishes in it
But I was a star for one whole minute
BOY 3:
That's right.
[BOYS WHOOPING]
Starting now, I'm the king of New York
Ain't you heard?
I'm the king of New York
Holy cow, it's a miracle
Pulitzer's crying, Weasel, he's dying
Flashpots are shooting bright as the sun
I'm one highfalutin son of a gun
Don't ask me how fortune found me
Fate just crowned me
Now I'm king of New York
Look and see, once a piker
Now a striker, I'm the king of New York
Victory, front-page story
Guts and glory
I'm the king of New York
[ALL CHEERING]
So let's have some ideas.
Well, we gotta show people
where we stand.
Yeah, so we gotta stay in the papes.
My paper's the only one
printing any strike news so far.
So we should do something
that's so big,
the other papers are gonna feel stupid
if they try and ignore us.
- Right.
- Like a rally.
A newsie rally with all the kids
from all over New York.
We'll make it the biggest, loudest,
noisiest blowout this town's ever seen.
- We'll send a message to the big boys.
RACETRACK: I'll give them a message.
Yeah. There's a lot of us
and we ain't going away.
We'll fight until damn doomsday
if it means we get a fair shake.
SPOT: I'll fight to that.
BOY 4: Yeah.
- Hey, you guys, to our man Denton.
- Oh...
ALL:
To our man Denton!
Hey, Mr. Snyder, how was your supper?
Hey, that's Jack.
He looks just like hisself.
You know this boy?
No, no.
You have a famous friend, this Jack.
Do you know where he lives?
I never heard of him, honest.
It's this brain of mine.
It's always making mistakes.
It's got a mind of its own.
Can I get you anything else,
Mr. Snyder?
Goodbye, Mr. Snyder.
So did I spell it right, Kloppman?
Very good. That's very good.
- I like it. Yeah.
- Strike.
Excuse-- Excuse me.
Can I help you?
You have a boy
who calls himself Jack Kelly?
- I wish to see him.
- Jack Kelly? Jack--
Never heard of him.
Any of you boys ever heard
of Jack Kelly?
That's an unusual name for these parts.
RACETRACK:
Oh, you mean Jack Kelly.
Yeah, he was here,
but he put an egg in his shoe and beat it.
[BOYS LAUGHING]
I have reason to believe that he is
an escaped prisoner, possibly dangerous.
Oh. Is he dangerous?
I better look in my files.
Come, this way, please.
Give to the newsie strike fund, mister?
Huh?
Did you sleep out there all night?
Yeah.
Why didn't you wake us up?
Well, I didn't wanna disturb nobody.
Anyway, it's like the Waldorf out here.
Great view and cool air.
Go up on the roof.
[JACK GRUNTING]
- Are you hungry?
- Yeah.
Good, because I made you breakfast.
Papa's so proud of you and David.
You should hear him
talking about Jack Kelly,
the strike leader
who occasionally takes his meals with us.
Well, this is one strike leader who's gonna
be very happy when it's all over.
I can get out of here, go to Santa Fe.
I mean, there's nothing for me to stay for,
is there?
You know, you should see Santa Fe.
Everything's different there. It's all bigger.
You know, the desert, and the sky
and the sun.
It's the same sun as here.
Yeah, it just looks different.
I should get ready for work.
Sarah?
I'm just not used to having whether I stay
or whether I go matter to anybody.
Yeah, I'm not saying
it should matter to you.
I'm just saying... Um...
But does it matter?
MAYOR:
Of course, the city is very concerned
that this event
doesn't get out of hand, but--
Chief?
We can't just charge in and break it up,
Mr. Pulitzer.
- We've got no legal cause.
- Legal cause.
Would the fact that this rally
is organized by an escaped criminal
be cause enough, mayor?
- Escaped criminal?
PULITZER: Mm-hm.
A fugitive from one of your prisons,
mayor.
A convicted thief.
He's been living at large for some time
under the alias of Jack Kelly.
- What's his real name?
SNYDER: Sullivan.
Francis Sullivan, Your Honor.
I would've caught him before now, but...
You know Warden Snyder, don't you?
I believe you know him
because you appointed him.
Yes.
Well, if this boy is a fugitive,
then the chief can quietly arrest him.
No, no, no. Not quietly. Not quietly.
I want an example made.
I want this rabble he's roused
to see what happens
to those who would dare to...
[GROWLS]
They should see justice in action, chief.
Arrest him at the rally.
By the way, mayor,
I'm having a few friends for cards tonight,
newspaper friends,
Willie Hearst, Gordon Bennett.
Perhaps you'll join us.
Talk about the coming election.
I'd be honored.
[UPBEAT CABARET MUSIC PLAYING]
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[BOYS CHEERING]
Carrying the banner!
You know the boys, mayor.
This is Mr. Bennett of The Tribune.
- Mr. Taylor of The Times.
- Nice to see you.
- Of course you know Mr. Hearst.
- Of course.
This is a new member of our little group,
Mr. Gammon.
- He just came back from Europe.
- Welcome home.
PULITZER: Mr. Gammon owns the, what?
The New York Sun.
Cigar, sir?
So we've come a long way,
but we ain't there yet.
Maybe it's only gonna get tougher
from now on.
But that's fine,
we'll just get tougher with it.
But also...
Also we gotta get smart
and start listening to my pal, David.
BOY 1: Yeah!
ALL: Yeah!
Who says, "Stop soaking the scabs."
What are we supposed to do to the bums,
kiss them?
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Hey, look, any scab I see,
I soak them, period.
[ALL CHEERING]
No, no, no,
that's what they want us to do.
If we get violent,
it's just playing into their hands.
Hey, look, they're gonna be playing
with my hands, all right?
Because it ain't what they say,
it's what we say.
And nobody ain't gonna listen to us
unless we make them.
[ALL SHOUTING]
You got no brains.
We're starting to fight each other.
It's just what the big shots wanna see.
That we're street trash.
Street rats with no brains,
no respect for nothing
including ourselves.
So here's how it is.
If we don't act together, we're nothing.
If we don't stick together, we're nothing.
And if we can't even trust each other,
then we're nothing.
- Tell them, Jack!
- So, what's it gonna be?
Listen to Jack.
We're with you, Jack.
So, what do you say, Spot?
I say that what you say
is what I say.
[ALL CHEERING]
- Yeah. Yeah.
- All right.
[UPBEAT CABARET MUSIC PLAYING]
BOY 2:
I love you, Medda!
ALL [SINGING]:
High times, hard times
Sometimes the living is sweet
And sometimes there's nothing to eat
But I always lands on my feet
So when there's dry times
I wait for high times and then
I put on my best and I stick out my chest
And I'm off to the races again
Whoo! Go, Medda! Medda!
Hello, newsies, what's new?
[ALL CHEERING]
MEDDA [SINGING]:
So your old lady don't love you no more
So you're afraid
There's a wolf at your door
So you got street rats
That scream in your ear
BOY 3:
Gorgeous.
BOY 4:
Someone pinch me. I'm dreaming.
ALL:
You win some, you lose some, my dear
Oh, high times, hard times
Sometimes the living is sweet
And sometimes there's nothing to eat
But I always lands on my feet
So when there's dry times
I wait for high times and then
I put on my best and I stick out my chest
And I'm off to the races again
I put on my best
- I put on my best
MEDDA: Oh, yes
- And I stick out my chest
- And I'm off
And I'm off
To the races again
[ALL CHEERING]
Excuse me, aren't you Warden Snyder?
Bryan Denton of The Sun.
How do you do, sir?
I heard about your wonderful work
with the children
and I wondered
if I might get an interview with you.
- Jack.
- Hey, David.
- Jack, it's Snyder.
- What? What?
It's Sny-- It's Snyder!
Right there.
Let me get that correct.
That's Snider as in "snide"?
Smile, sir.
Medda, thanks. I gotta run.
BOY 5:
Yeah.
[WHISTLES BLOWING]
DAVID:
Pardon me.
No, no. no. Stay with me.
[RACETRACK GRUNTS]
No! No, for God's sake! Don't!
He's just a child! Can't you see that?
Why don't you pick on
someone your own size?
Racetrack!
DAVID:
Get out of here. Now. Let's go!
POLICEMAN 1:
Hey, come here, Sullivan. I got you.
BOY 6:
Run!
Go up there. All right, no, go here.
Come on.
POLICEMAN 2:
Over here. Over here.
Push me.
Get out of here. Go.
POLICEMAN 3: Stop, boys, where you are.
POLICEMAN 4: Hey, you, come back here.
POLICEMAN 5: Hey, I said stop them.
WEASEL: Show's over, Cowboy.
Jack, you all right? Come on.
KID BLINK:
Beat it!
BOY 7:
Hey!
POLICEMAN 6:
You, hey, stop right there.
Steady!
POLICEMAN 7:
Come here, you.
[GRUNTS]
DAVID:
Jack!
BAILIFF: All rise, all rise.
Court is now in session.
Judge E.A. Monahan presiding.
Are any of you represented by counsel?
BOY 1: What's a counsel?
BOY 2: That's what I said.
No. Good, good.
That'll move things along considerably.
Your Honor, I object.
On what grounds?
On the grounds of Brooklyn,
Your Honor.
[BOYS LAUGHING]
[GAVEL BANGS]
I fine each of you $5
or two weeks' confinement
in the House of Refuge.
Whoa, whoa.
Hey. Hey, we ain't got 5 bucks.
We don't even got 5 cents.
Hey, Your Honor, how about
I roll you for it? Double or nothing.
All right, move along, move along.
Your Honor, I'll pay the fines.
All of them.
- Come on.
- Hey, fellas, you all right?
BOY 3: It's David.
- Where's Jack?
Look, we gotta meet at the restaurant.
Everybody. We have to talk.
Pay the clerk. Move it along.
Hey, fellas.
- Hey, Cowboy, nice shiner.
BOY 4: Cowboy.
[GAVEL BANGS]
JUDGE: Pay the clerk. Move it along.
- Jack's fine.
Hey, Denton,
I guess we made all the papes this time.
So how did my picture look?
None of the papers covered the rally,
not even The Sun.
Case of Jack Kelly.
Inciting to riot, assault, resisting arrest.
Judge Monahan,
I'll speak for this young man.
You two know each other.
Ain't that nice?
Just move it along, Warden Snyder.
This boy's real name
is Francis Sullivan.
His mother's deceased.
His father's a convict
in the state penitentiary.
He's an escapee
from the House of Refuge
where his original sentence for three
months was extended to six months
for disruptive behavior.
Like demanding we eat the food
you steal from us.
Followed by an additional six months
for an attempted escape.
Attempted?
Last time wasn't an attempted escape.
Remember, Snyder?
Remember me and Teddy Roosevelt
and the carriage?
Remember Roosevelt
Therefore, I ask that he be returned
to the House of Refuge.
Away for my own good, right,
Movealong?
For my own good
and for what he kicks back to you.
And that the court order
his incarceration until the age of 21
in the hope that we may yet guide him
to a useful and productive life.
So ordered.
No!
JUDGE:
Next.
BOY 1: Hey, Mr. Denton.
BOY 2: Denton.
BOY 3:
Shh!
- Thanks for bailing us out.
- My pleasure.
Why didn't The Sun print the story?
Because it never happened.
What do you mean, it never happened?
You were there.
I tell you, if it's not in the papers,
it never happened.
The owners decreed
that it not be in the papers, therefore...
Anyway, I came
to tell you fellas goodbye.
- I...
- What happened? Did you get fired?
No, I got reassigned back to my old job
as The Sun's ace war correspondent.
They want me to leave right away.
The owner thinks that I should only cover
the really important stories, so...
Yep. Well, wish me luck, fellas.
At least half of what I wish for you.
They don't always fire you, David.
I would be blackballed
from every paper in the country.
Hey.
I'm a newspaperman.
I have to have a paper to write for.
This is the story I wrote about the rally.
And...
I want you to read it at least.
Bill?
- No, no.
- This should cover it.
Thanks.
We get Jack out of the Refuge tonight.
And from now on,
we trust no one but the newsies.
BOY 4: Yeah.
BOY 5: That's right.
RACETRACK:
Come on, get the lead out your pants.
BOY 6:
Let's go.
BOY 7:
We're gonna be okay.
DRIVER:
Move along, boy.
That's where we saw Crutchy.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
- It's Jack. It's Jack.
- Shh, shh, shh!
DRIVER:
Whoa, boy.
Where they taking him, Dave?
There's one way to find out.
I'll meet you guys at the square.
Racetrack, watch him.
DRIVER:
Whoa. Whoa.
Get him inside.
MAN 1: Oh, well, about ready to wrap up
for the night.
MAN 2: It's gonna be another late one.
MAN 1: Yes. Yes, I know.
[MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Sit.
You know what I was doing
when I was your age, boy?
I was in a war.
The Civil War.
Yeah, I heard of it.
So did you win?
People think that the wars
are about right or wrong. They're not.
- They're about power.
- Yeah, I heard of that too.
You know,
I don't just sell your papes, Joe.
Sometimes I read them.
Power of the press
is the greatest power of them all.
I tell this city how to think.
I tell this city how to vote.
I shape its future.
Yeah? Well,
right now I'm just thinking
about one future, and that's mine.
Well, so am I, boy.
I have the power to see that
you stay locked in the Refuge.
And I have the power
to break out again.
Or I could see you released tomorrow
free and clear
with more money in your pockets
than you could earn
in, well, three lifetimes.
Are you bribing me, Joe?
Mm. Well, no.
Well, it's been nice chatting with you, Joe,
but I gotta be going now.
Wait. You listen to me, boy.
Now, you just shut your mouth
and listen to me.
You shut up and listen to me for once.
It's no game I'm playing.
You work for me until the strike is over.
And it will end, boy, make no mistake,
without you.
Then you go
wherever you want to buy a ticket for,
away from the Refuge,
these foul streets. Free.
With money to spend
and nobody chasing you.
I must have you scared pretty bad,
old man.
I offer you freedom and money
just to work for me again.
To your friends, I won't be so kind.
Now, your partner,
what's his name, David?
I understand he has a family.
What do you think the Refuge
would do to him?
And it would be you who put him there.
And all the others.
After all, you're their leader.
Go back to the Refuge tonight.
Think about it.
Give me your answer in the morning.
Jack, come on. Come on.
Run.
SNYDER: After him!
DAVID: Hurry up.
Beat it. Beat it.
Don't worry.
He's got no place to go.
DAVID:
Come on, keep running.
JACK: You shouldn't have done this,
Dave. They could put you in jail.
- I don't care.
- Come here.
What about your family?
What happens to them if you go in jail?
You don't know nothing about jail.
Now, thanks for what you've done,
but you get out of here.
I don't understand.
I don't understand either,
but just get out of here!
- No!
- Go!
[SINGING]
Santa Fe
My old friend
I can't spend my whole life hiding
You're the only light
That's guiding me today
Psst! Jack. Look.
I snitched it off of Snyder's plate
when I was serving him.
It's the biggest one.
Oh, Mr. Snyder was eating good tonight.
The stuff that we don't never get.
He got potatoes, olives,
even bacon, sauerkraut.
Hey, guess what I done
to his sauerkraut, huh?
So, what's it get you?
Another three months probably.
But you can't let them beat you, right,
Jack? That's what you always say.
We was beat when we was born.
Will you keep a candle burning?
Will you help me find my way?
You're my chance to break free
And who knows
When my next one will be
Santa Fe
Wait for me
GROUP 1: Stop The World!
GROUP 2: No more papes!
- Stop The World!
- No more papes!
[ALL SHOUTING]
Cheese it! Race, please, help me.
I need some help.
All right, I ain't deaf.
POLICEMAN 1:
Useless street rats.
- Hey, hey, hey. Break it up. Break it up.
POLICEMAN 2: Hold it. Hold it right there.
RACETRACK:
Don't let that happen again.
- Hey. Hey, Race. Race, come here.
- What?
Tell me I'm just seeing things.
Just tell me I'm seeing things.
RACETRACK:
No, you ain't seeing things. That's Jack.
- What's he doing?
SPOT: He's dressed like a scabber.
Jack?
Jack, look at me, will you?
Come on, it's me, Mush.
Look at me. What are you doing, Jack?
This ain't happening. This can't
be happening. What are you doing, Jack?
- Come on, what are you doing?
- Hey, what is this?
Where'd he get them clothes?
Mr. Pulitzer picked them out himself.
BOY 1: I don't believe this.
- A special gift to a special employee.
SPOT:
What? He sold us out.
Look at him in his little suit. You bum.
I'll soak you.
- You fink!
SPOT: Enough! Let me get my hands dirty.
Come here, you dirty, rotten scabber.
[ALL CLAMORING]
SPOT:
I'll murder you!
- Ah. You wanna talk to him?
SPOT: Traitor!
Come on. Come on, sure.
Go right ahead.
DAVID: This is why
you didn't escape last night.
Yeah.
You're a liar.
You lied about everything.
You lied about your father being out west
because he's not out west.
You didn't even tell me your real name.
So? What you wanna do about it,
Dave?
I don't understand you.
Oh, so let me spell it out for you.
You see, I ain't got nobody
tucking me in at night like you.
It's just me. I gotta look out for myself,
all right?
You had the newsies.
Oh, what did being a newsie ever give me,
but a dime a day and a few black eyes.
You know, I can't afford
to be a kid no more, Dave.
For the first time in my life,
I got money in my pockets.
Real money.
Money. You understand?
I got more on the way and as soon
as I collect, I'm gone, I'm away, all right?
Well, that's good.
That's good because we don't need you.
We don't need you!
Because all those words you said,
those were mine.
Yeah, but you never had the guts
to put them across yourself, did you?
I do now.
[SIGHS]
Come on. What's the matter?
Got a problem?
[BOYS SHOUTING]
Maybe you'd like a new suit
of your own, huh?
- Never!
- Get out of here! Get out of here!
POLICEMAN 3: Out of the way.
Out of the way. Out of the way.
Back! Back, I said!
POLICEMAN 4:
Hey! Hey!
KID BLINK:
You make me sick!
BOY 2: Look at yourself.
- I trusted you!
Seize the day, huh, Jack?
He's fooling them
so he can spy on them or something.
- Yeah, that's it. He's fooling them.
BOY 3: No.
- Yeah, he's spying on them, kid.
LES: He's spying on them.
Les.
What is this?
I'm saving it.
David.
It's Denton's article.
"The Dark Truth: Why Our City
Really Fears the Newsies' Strike.
By Bryan Denton.
Last night I saw naked force
exercised against mere boys,
the newsies, who were the--"
One trick, Cowboy,
and it's right back to the Refuge. Please.
Uh, are you gonna be requiring
anything else this evening, huh?
No? Aww. Tsk, tsk.
Well, then,
I ought to be saying good night.
Remember, one trick
and I go straight to Mr. Pulitzer.
WEASEL: Move it along, please,
gentlemen, move it along.
Twenty papes. Next.
BOY 1: Twenty papes, please.
WEASEL: Uh-huh.
BOY 2: Thirty papes, please.
WEASEL: Yes, sir. Thirty papes. Next.
BOY 3: I'll take 50 papes.
WEASEL: Yes, sir. Fifty papes.
Fifty papes. Next.
Sleep well, Cowboy?
Come with us, Cowboy.
We're gonna go fix your pal Davey.
- Fix him so he can't walk.
- Shut up.
WEASEL:
Uh-uh.
Lift one finger,
it's right back to the Refuge.
Next.
BOY 4:
Fifty.
- Good morning.
WOMAN: Good morning to you.
Excuse me, sweet face.
How's your little brother, tootsie, huh?
Where's the little Davey?
[OSCAR CHUCKLING]
Leave my sister alone.
Stop it!
Leave him alone!
You stupid ape.
No!
- What happened? Are you hurt?
- No, I'm all right. I'm all right.
- Help Sarah.
SARAH: Run, Davey!
OSCAR:
Oh, yeah, run, Davey.
We got the best part of your family
right here.
SARAH:
Let go of me!
MORRIS: Oh, I'm gonna enjoy this.
- Stop it!
OSCAR: Get up.
SARAH: Les!
- Stop, you're hurting him. No!
OSCAR: Davey.
Leave him alone!
[DAVID GRUNTING]
SARAH:
Stop it!
Leave him alone!
[MORRIS CHUCKLING]
JACK:
Get over here.
Get up.
Remember Crutchy?
- You all right?
- Yeah.
David?
You better run, Cowboy.
We're gonna tell Uncle Weas.
You'll be in the Refuge by suppertime.
OSCAR: Run, you lousy cow. Run!
SARAH: Hey!
LES:
Run, get out of here. Don't come back.
You hear me?
What, you couldn't stay away?
Well, I guess
I can't be something I ain't.
A scab?
No, smart.
Did you mean what you wrote here?
About all these sweatshop kids
listening to me?
I don't write anything I don't mean.
Well, come on in.
I was just packing a few things.
So, yes, I meant it.
This city thrives on child labor.
A lot of people make money that way.
They're terrified
that the newsies' strike will spread.
Well, there's really not much chance
of that as long as they got the power.
Sometimes all it takes is a voice.
One voice that becomes a hundred
and then a thousand,
unless it's silenced.
Why can't we spread the strike?
Have another big rally
and get the word out
to all the sweatshop kids? Why not?
What are we gonna do?
Put an ad in the newspaper?
No, we'll do better than that.
We'll make our own paper.
We tell them they gotta join us.
Isn't that a good idea?
Yeah, it is.
But what do we know
about printing a newspaper?
Nothing, but our man, Denton...
Yeah, but I think our man, Denton,
has something more important to do.
I mean, he's going
to be an ace war correspondent.
Right, Denton?
[DENTON CHUCKLES]
All right.
Where do we start?
All right, we gotta move fast.
Now, we're gonna need
the newsies to circulate.
DENTON: There's something else
we need. We need a printing press.
So it happens
I know a guy with a printing press.
[WHISPERING]
You've been living here?
Shh! They're right above us.
If Weasel catches us,
we're all in the slam.
[WHISPERING]
Oh, right. A platen press.
Looks like old man Pulitzer
never threw anything away.
DAVID:
Will this thing work?
It better. We have a deadline.
DENTON [SINGS]:
This is the story you wanted to write
Well, tonight is a night that you can
JACK: Just get this done
And by dawn's early light
You can finish the fight you began
DAVID:
This time we're in it to stay
SARAH:
Think about seizing the day
JACK: Think of that train
As she rolls into old Santa Fe
Tell them I'm on my way
ALL:
See old man Pulitzer snug in his bed
He don't care if we're dead or alive
Three satin pillows are under his head
While we're begging for bread
To survive
Joe, if you're still counting sheep
Wake up and read them and weep
You got your thugs
With their sticks and their slugs
Yeah, but we got a promise to keep
Once and for all, something tells me
The tide will be turning
Once and for all, there's a fire inside me
That won't stop burning
Now that the choices are clear
Now that tomorrow is here
Watch how the mighty can fall
For once and for all
It's awfully nice of Mr. Pulitzer
to let us use his press.
Yeah, I just hope
I get to thank him for it someday.
ALL: This is for kids
Shining shoes in the street
With no shoes on their feet every day
Hey, kid, can you read?
Read that.
SARAH:
Take this. Read these.
Know how to read? Read that, all right?
BOOTS:
Carrying The Banner!
ALL: Once and for all
We'll be there to defend one another
Once and for all, every kid is our friend
- Good morning, miss.
- Support the newsies.
Hey, meet you at the square.
BOY: Pass the word.
ALL: Five thousand reasons to try
Going over the wall
DAVID:
Let's go.
ALL:
Either we stand or we fall
For once
Once and for all
ROOSEVELT:
Disgraceful, Denty.
Those poor boys.
I thought you'd feel this way, governor.
ROOSEVELT:
And I did nothing.
Until now.
Good. Very good, sir.
[BOYS CHATTERING]
So when's the others coming, kid?
They ain't coming.
Ain't gonna be nobody but us.
- Come on, Jack.
SPECS: Have hope, Jack.
[SINGING]
When the circulation bell starts ringing
Will we hear it?
No.
What if the Delanceys
Come out swinging?
Will we hear it?
No.
- Attaboy.
- It's gonna be all right.
It's all right.
CROWD [SINGING]:
When you got a million voices singing
Who can hear
- A lousy whistle blow?
- Look!
And The World will know
[ALL CHEERING]
Brooklyn!
The World will feel the fire
And finally know
[ALL CHEERING]
BOY 1:
We're gonna strike!
- We're back.
BOY 1 : Strike!
ALL [CHANTING]:
Jack! Jack! Jack!
Strike! Strike! Strike!
[CHANTING CONTINUES]
BOY 2: We got you.
BOY 3: Yes!
Dear me.
What have we here?
[FOOTSTEPS]
It's awful. Everyone's calling.
Mr. Hearst, Mr. Bennett and the mayor,
and such awful language.
The city is at a standstill
and they blame the chief.
It's like the end of the world.
Oh, dear, I didn't say that.
Extra, extra, Joe.
Read all about it.
I promised that if you defied me
that I would break you.
I'll keep that promise, boy.
Now, I gave you the chance to be free.
I don't understand.
Anyone who doesn't act
in his own self-interest is a fool.
- And what does that make you?
- What?
- Oh, this is my pal, David.
PULITZER: Yeah, David.
The walking mouth.
You talk about self-interest,
but since the strike,
your circulation's been down 70 percent.
Every day you're losing
thousands of dollars just to beat us out
of one lousy tenth of a cent. Why?
JACK:
You see, it ain't about the money, Dave.
If Joe gives in to nobodies like us,
that means we got the power.
And he can't do that
no matter what it costs. Am I right, Joe?
I sent for the police.
They must be here by now.
Send them in, Seitz. Send them in.
And I'm not going back to jail, Joe.
Look out here. Right out here
is right where your power ends.
PULITZER:
Close the windows. Close the windows.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
Stop that infernal noise! Go home!
- Go home! Go home! Go home!
- I don't hear you, Joe!
PULITZER:
Go home to your mothers and fathers!
- Go home! Now, you listen to me.
- I can't hear you.
- You should listen to me for a change.
- No, you listen to me.
- No, you should listen!
- Shut the window and shut up!
There's a lot of people out there
and they ain't just gonna go away.
They got voices now
and they're gonna be listened to.
Putting me in jail
is not gonna stop them.
That's the power of the press, Joe.
[WINDOWS CLOSE]
So thanks for teaching me about it.
Those kids put out
a pretty good paper there, chief.
I ordered a printing ban
on all strike matters. Now, who defied it?
Whose press did you use to print this?
Whose?
Well, we only used the best, Joe.
So I just wanna say,
thanks again.
Hey, fellas, they're over here.
They're over here.
[CLAMORING]
- What'd they say, huh?
BOY 1: Jack, tell us.
BOY 2:
Did they give in? They give in?
Well, the strike's over. We beat them.
We beat them!
[ALL CHEERING]
WEASEL:
Out of my way. Out of my way.
BOY 3:
All right!
RACETRACK: Hey, don't feel bad, Weas.
BOY 3: All right!
WEASEL:
Excuse me. Excuse me. Excuse me.
Jack. Jack, it's the bulls.
It's the bulls, let me down.
BOY 4: Go.
RACETRACK: Jack, get down.
JACK:
Go.
- Jack, it's over.
- Let him go!
No, no, no. You don't have to run.
Not anymore.
Not from the likes of him anyway.
Come on, come on.
BOY 5:
Hey, Crutchy, come on out of there.
Uh, remember what I told you,
Mr. Snyder.
The first thing you do in jail,
make friends with the rats.
Share what you got in common.
- Uh, officer, may I, please?
POLICEMAN: Sure, kid.
[ALL CHEERING]
- Hey, Crutchy.
CRUTCHY: Hey, guys.
You won't be seeing much of him
anymore.
Say goodbye, Warden.
Jack, you ought to have seen it.
He come storming into the Refuge
waving his walking stick like a sword,
and he's leading this army of lawyers
and cops--
Who comes walking in?
You know, your friend. Him.
Teddy Roosevelt.
The governor's very grateful
you brought this problem to his attention.
- Roosevelt?
- I said you might need a lift somewhere.
He's glad to oblige. Anywhere you want.
And this time you ride inside.
BOY 6: Get to ride with Teddy Roosevelt.
- So could he drop me at the train yards?
BOY 7: The train yards?
- Yeah, if that's what you want.
[BELL RINGING]
[SINGING]
Try Bottle Alley or the harbor
BOY 1:
I'll go down to the harbor.
Try Central Park, it's guaranteed
BOY 2: I'm not going to Central Park.
BOY 3: I'm going.
Try any banker, bum or barber
They almost all knows how to read
BOOTS: Summer stinks
SKITTERY: And winter's waiting
ALL:
Welcome to New York
Boy, ain't nature fascinating
When youse gotta walk?
BOY 4:
Come on, come on, come on.
Hurry up, get the lead out of your pants!
Hundred papes.
- All right, Davey.
RACETRACK: Attaboy, Davey.
Thanks.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Jack!
- There's Jack.
- He's back.
CRUTCHY:
Fantastic.
Thanks for the advice, governor.
Like you said, I still got things to do.
Besides, I got family here.
CRUTCHY: Jack, this is wonderful.
Hey, Jack, how you doing?
- I told you. I told you.
JACK: Yes.
Hey, you, Skittery.
So how's the headline today?
Headlines don't sell papes.
Newsies sell papes.
[ALL CHEERING]
Come here, Davey.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Thanks, Davey.
All right, Jack!
RACETRACK:
Whoo! Jackie boy!
JACK: Spot!
DAVID: Spot!
SARAH: Goodbye, Spot!
JACK: Go back to Brooklyn.
ALL [SINGING]:
It's a fine life carrying the banner
We got 'em, Cowboy
- It's a fine life carrying the banner
- We showed 'em how, boy
- We got 'em, Cowboy
- It's a fine life carrying the banner
- We showed 'em how, boy
BOY 5:
Extra! Extra!
BOY 6:
Hey!
BOY 7:
Come on. Get your paper here!
["KING OF NEW YORK" PLAYING]
Look at me
I'm the king of New York
Suddenly I'm respectable
Staring right at you
Lousy with stature
Nobbing with all the muckety mucks
I'm blowing my dough and going deluxe
Then there I be, ain't I pretty?
It's my city
I'm the king of New York
Starting now
Ain't you heard?
I'm the king of New York
Holy cow, it's a miracle
Pulitzer's crying
Weasel, he's dying
Flashpots are shooting
Bright as the sun
I'm one highfalutin son of a gun
Don't ask me how fortune found me
Fate just crowned me
I'm the king of New York
Victory, front page story
Guts and glory
I'm the king of New York
["THE WORLD WILL KNOW" PLAYING]
And The World will know
And The World will learn
And The World will wonder
How we made the tables turn
And The World will see
That we had to choose
That the things we do today
Will be tomorrow's news
And the old will fall
And the young stand tall
And the time is now
And the winds will blow
And our ranks will grow
And grow and grow and so
The World will feel the fire
And finally know