##["Oklahoma"]
##["The Surrey With
the Fringe on Top"]
#There's a bright, golden haze
on the meadow #
#The corn is as high
as a elephant's eye #
#An' it looks like it's climb in'
clear up to the sky #
# Oh, what a beautiful mornin' #
# Oh, what a beautiful day #
# I got a beautiful feelin' #
# Ev'rythin's goin' my way #
[Birds Chirping]
#All the sounds of the earth
are like music #
#The breeze is so busy
it don't miss a tree #
#And an ol' weepin' willer
is laughin' at me #
# Oh, what a beautiful mornin' #
# Oh, what a beautiful day #
# I got a beautiful feelin' #
# Ev'rythin's goin' my way #
# Oh, what a beautiful day #
[Rooster Crows]
[Chickens Clucking]
- Hi, Aunt Eller!
- Don't scare me to death.
- What you doin' around here?
- I come a-singin' to you.
# Oh, what a beautiful mornin' #
# Oh, what a beautiful day #
# I got a beautiful feelin' #
# Ev'rythin's goin' my way #
If I wasn't an old woman, and if you wasn't
so young and smart-alecky...
why, I'd marry you and get you
to sit around at night and sing to me.
No, you wouldn't neither, 'cause I wouldn't
marry you nor none of your kinfolk.
- If I could help it.
- Oh, none of my kinfolks, huh?
And you can tell 'em that too.
All of 'em.
Including that niece of your'n,
Miss Laurey Williams.
Who you takin'
to the box social tonight?
I ain't thought much about it yet.
- Bet you come over to ask Laurey.
- What if I did?
You askin' me too?
I'll wear my fascinator.
- Yeah, you too.
- Yeah, yeah.
# Oh, what a beautiful mornin'#
# Oh, what a beautiful day #
I thought you were somebody.
#I got a beautiful feelin'#
# Ev'rythin's goin' my way ##
Is this all that's come a-callin'
at already 8:00 this Saturday morning?
You knowed it was me
before you opened the door.
- No such of a thing.
- Well, you did too.
You heared my voice.
You knowed it was me.
I heared someone singing
like a bullfrog in a pond.
You knowed it was me, so you set in there,
thinkin' up something mean to say.
I'm a good mind not to ask you
to the box social.
- Oh, you two.
- If you asked me, I wouldn't go with you.
Besides, how'd you take me?
You ain't bought a new buggy
with red wheels onto it, have you?
- No, I ain't.
- A spankin' team with their bridles all a-jinglin'?
- No.
- Expect me to ride on behind ol' Blue I guess.
You better ask that old Cummings girl
you took such a shine to.
If I was to ask you, Miss Laurey smarty,
there'd be a way to take ya.
Oh, there would?
How'd we get there?
#When I take you out
tonight with me #
# Honey, here's the way
it's goin' to be #
#You will set behind a team
of snowwhite horses #
# In the slickest gig you ever see #
# Chicks and ducks
and geese better scurry #
#When I take you out
in the surrey #
#When I take you out in the surrey
with the fringe on top #
#Watch that fringe
and see how it flutters #
#When I drive them
high steppin' strutters #
# Nosey pokes'll peek
thru their shutters #
#And their eyes will pop #
#The wheels are yeller
the upholstery's brown #
#The dashboard's genuine leather #
#With isinglass curtains
y'can roll right down #
# In case there's
a change in the weather #
#Two bright side lights
winkin' and blinkin' #
#Ain't no finer rig
I'm a thinkin' #
#You c'n keep yer rig
if you're thinkin' #
# 'At I'd keer to swop #
# Fer that shiny little surrey
with the fringe on the top #
#Would y' say the fringe
was made of silk #
[Laughs]
#Wouldn't have
no other kind but silk #
# Has it really got a team
of snow-white horses #
# One's like snow
The other's more like milk #
#All the world'll fly in a flurry #
# When I take you
out in the surrey #
# When I take you out in the surrey
with the fringe on top #
# When we hit that road
hell fer leather #
# Cats and dogs'll dance
in the heather #
#Birds and frogs'll
sing all together #
#And the toads will hop #
# The wind'll whistle
as we rattle along #
# The cows'll moo in the clover #
# The river will ripple out
a whispered song #
#And whisper it over and over #
[Softly]
#Don't you wisht y'd go on forever #
#Don't you wisht
y'd go on forever #
# Don't you wisht
#And ud never stop #
# In that shiny little surrey
with the fringe on the top #
You'd sure feel like a queen
settin' up in that carriage.
Only she talked to me
so mean a while back...
- I'm a good mind not to take her.
- I ain't said I was goin'.
- Well, I ain't asked ya.
- Where'd you get such a rig at?
I'll bet he's went and hired a rig over
at Claremore, thinkin' I'd go with him.
I did not hire it.
I made the whole thing up out of my head.
- What? Made it up?
- Dashboard and all.
[Laughing]
Get off the place, you!
Aunt Eller, make him get hisself out of here!
Tellin' me lies.
Now hold on. Makin' up a few "purties"
ain't agin no law I know of.
Besides, don't you wish
there was such a rig though?
You could go to the play party and do a hoedown
till morning if you was a mind to.
Then when you was all wore out,
why, I'd just lift you onto the surrey...
jump up alongside you,
and we'd just point the horses home.
I can just picture the whole thing.
# I can see the stars
gittin' blurry #
#When we ride back home
in the surrey' #
# Ridin' slowly home
in the surrey #
#With the fringe on top #
# I can feel the day gittin' older #
# Feel a sleepy head
near my shoulder #
# Noddin', droopin'
close to my shoulder #
#Till it falls, kerplop #
#The sun is swimmin'
on the rim of a hill #
#The moon is takin' a header #
#And jist as I'm thinkin'
all the earth is still #
#A lark'll wake up
in the medder #
# Hush! You'll bird
my baby's a sleepin' #
# May be got a dream
worth a keepin' #
#Whoa! You team
and just keep a creepin' #
#At a slow clip clop #
# Don't you hurry with the surrey #
#With the fringe #
# On the #
#Top ##
- Only- Only there ain't no such rig.
- Well, uh-
Why'd you come around here with your stories
and your lies, gettin' me all worked up?
Who'd wanna ride
alongside of you anyway?
Why don't you grab her and kiss her
when she acts that a-way, Curly?
- She's just aching for you to, I bet.
- I won't even speak to him...
let alone allow him to kiss me...
the braggin', bowlegged,
wished-he'd-had-a-sweetheart bum!
She likes you quite a lot.
She liked me any more,
she'd sic the dogs onto me.
- Hello, Jud.
- Hello, yourself.
Listen, who's the low filthy sneak Laurey's
got her cap set for?
- You.
- Never mind that.
There must be plenty of men
a-tryin' to spark her.
- Plenty.
- What about him?
Oh, she wouldn't take up
with a fella like that...
that bullet-colored,
growly hired hand.
Now, don't you go say
nothin' agin Jud.
Best hired hand I ever had.
Just about runs
the farm by hisself.
Well, two women couldn't do it.
You oughta know 'at.
He's around
all the time, ain't he?
Takes his meals with you
and sleeps down in the smokehouse.
I changed my mind
about cleaning the henhouse today.
I gotta quit early 'cause I'm driving
Laurey to the party tonight.
- You're driving Laurey?
- I asked her.
Well, wouldn't that
just make you bawl?
Don't forget, Aunt Eller.
You and me still got a date together.
How we going, Curly,
in that rig you made up?
That there ain't
no made-up rig, you hear?
I done hired it over to Claremore.
- Why don't you go with him?
- I can't. I promised Jud.
- Why ever did you?
- 'Cause Curly's too fresh and too bigheaded...
waitin' till
the last minute to ask me.
Aunt Eller, are you really going
with Curly tonight?
I sure am.
You didn't want him.
But you could go with me and Jud.
You picked your feller,
I picked mine.
That's the way
you want it, ain't it?
You're sure a pair.
Crazy young'uns.
Time I started for the station.
Hey, Curly.
Tell all the folks to stop by here...
on their way to the Skidmore party
to freshen up.
I will, Aunt Eller. You see you got
your beauty spots fastened on proper...
so as you won't lose
them off, you hear?
That's a right smart turnout.
#Ain't no finer rig
I'm a thinkin' #
#That I'd keer to swop #
#Fer that shiny little surrey #
# With the fringe on the top ##
[Wheels Rattling]
Aunt Eller!
Lookin' for me?
Gonna be a nice evenin'
for the party.
- Jud.
- What?
I don't think I can-
You ain't figurin' on goin'
with someone else, are you?
Well, l-
Laurey!
I'll come by for you
along around about sundown.
[Train Chugging]
- [Dog Barking]
- [Bell Ringing]
[Chattering]
What'd you do up at the fair, Will?
Bust any bones?
Aw, too smart for that.
Just made sure I landed on my head.
- Will Parker.
- Hi, Aunt Eller.
If you ain't got them fancy lanterns
for the Skidmore party...
- get back on that train.
- [Laughs]
- Here you are.
- You do any good in the steer ropin', Will?
Oh, I did pretty good.
I won prize money.
- That's my boy.
- I've got to get over to Ado Annie's.
Her pa said I could have her
if'n I was ever worth $50.
And I got that $50.
If Annie's pa keeps his promise...
we'll be dancin' at your wedding.
If'n he don't, I'll take her right
from under his nose.
Besides which, I won't give him the present
I brung for him.
Lookee here, fellas,
what I got for Ado Annie's pa.
Excuse us, Aunt Eller.
You hold it up to your eye like this, see.
Then when you get a good look, you turn it
around at the top and the picture changes.
- Well, I'll be "sidegated."
- They call it the Little Wonder.
Silly goats!
The hussy!
Ought to be ashamed of herself.
You too. How do you turn the thing
to see the other picture?
- Right at the top, Aunt Eller.
- Wait, I'm gettin' it.
[Gasps]
[Laughs]
I'm a good mind
to tell Annie on you.
Bet you carried on
plenty in Kansas City.
Well, I sure did see a lot of things
I never did see before.
# I got to Kansas City on a Frid'y #
# By Sattiday I larned
a thing or two #
# For up to then
I didn't have an idy #
# Of whut the modren world
was comin' to #
# I counted twenty gas buggies
goin' by their sel's #
#Almost ev'ry time I tuck a walk #
# 'Nen I put my ear
to a Bell Telephone #
#And a strange womern
started in to talk #
- #To you #
- #Whut next #
- #Yeah, whut #
# Ev'rythin's up to date in Kansas City #
#They've gone about
as fur as they c'n go #
#They went an build a skyscraper
seven stories high #
#About as high as
a buildin' orta grow #
# Ev'rythin's like a dream
in Kansas City #
# It's better
than a magic lantern show #
#Y' c'n turn the radiator on
when ever you want some heat #
#With ev'ry kind o' comfort
ev'ry house is all complete #
#You c'n walk to privies in the rain
and never wet your feet #
#They've gone about as fur
as they c'n go #
#Yes, sir
They've gone about as fur as they c'n go #
# Evry thin's up to date
in Kansas City #
#They've gone about as fur
as they c'n go #
#They got a big theayter
they call a burleequee #
- # Fer fifty cents you c'n see a dandy show #
- # Gals #
- # One of the gals was fat and pink and pretty #
- Aha!
#As round above
as she was round below #
# I could swear that she was padded
from her shoulder to her heel #
#And then she started dancin'
and her dancin' made me feel #
#That every single thing
she had was absolutely real #
# She went about as fur
as she could go #
#Yes, sir
She went about as fur as she could go #
- What you doin', Will?
- Well, this is called a two-step.
That's all they're dancing nowadays.
Why, the waltz is through.
Of course, they don't do it alone.
Come on, Aunt Eller!
- # Oh, that's about as fur as I can go #
- #Yes, sir #
#And that's about as fur
as she can go ##
- What you doing now, Will?
- Well, this here's called ragtime.
I seen a couple actors doin' it.
- Don't like it.
- Oh, Will, I do!
[Horse Nickers]
Still don't like it.
Come on, Aunt Eller, do-si-do!
Hey, ha, pick it up!
[Chattering]
Hey! Ha ha!
- Hyah!
- Ho!
[Chattering]
- Ha!
- Yahoo!
Hey there, Will Parker!
Come back here!
- [Bell Ringing]
- [Train Whistle Blowing]
- [Girls] Oh!
- [Bell Ringing]
[Train Whistle Blows]
[Bell Clanging]
Ado Annie, I could ride with you like this
to the end of the world.
Please, Mr. Hakim,
don't start talkin' purty.
Laurey!
Yoo-hoo! Laurey!
Whoa!
Laurey!
- Hello, Laurey.
- What you doing with that peddler-man?
- Will Parker gets back today.
- Will Parker. Oh, foot.
- I didn't count on today being Saturday.
- I can see that.
My, oh, my, Miss Laurey!
"Jippity" crickets.
Last time I come through here,
you was teeny like a shrimp with freckles.
Now look on you.
Quit a-bitin' me! If you ain't had
no breakfast, go eat yourself a green apple.
Are you coming in or going out?
Standing still while you're here.
Go up to the house and wait.
It'll be no trouble
at all to wait right here.
So much water.
Why don't we all
take a swim together?
In Persia, where I come from,
bathing is a social event.
- Well, this ain't Persia!
- I can already see you two young ladies...
in those beautiful
Persian bathing suits.
What do they wear
when they bathe socially in Persia?
- Nothing.
- Nothing. Ooh!
The peddler-man's gonna drive me
to the box social.
I got up sort of a tasty lunch.
But you're promised
to Will Parker, ain't ya?
Oh, ain't what you might say, promised.
I just told him maybe.
Don't you like Will no more?
Of course I do.
There won't never be nobody like Will.
Then what about this peddler-man?
Oh, there won't never be
nobody like him neither.
Well, you gotta make up your mind.
Which one do you like the best?
- Well, whatever one I'm with.
- Well, you are a silly.
Well, now, Laurey, you know that nobody
paid me no mind up till this year...
on account I was scrawny
and flat as a beanpole.
But then I kinda
rounded up a little...
- and now the boys act different to me.
- What's wrong with that?
Nothing's wrong.
I like it!
I like it so much
when a fella talks pretty to me...
I get all shaky
from horn to hoof.
- Don't you?
- Can't think what you're talking about.
Don't you feel kinda sorry for a fella
when he looks like he wants to kiss ya?
Well, you can't just go around kissing every man
that asks ya. Didn't anyone tell you that?
Yeah, they told me.
# It ain't so much a question #
# Of not knowin' whut to do #
# I knowed whut's right
and wrong since I been ten #
# I heared a lot of stories #
#And I reckon they are true #
#A'bout how girls
're put upon by men #
# I know I mustn't
fall into the pit #
# But when I'm with a feller #
# I fer git #
# I'm jist a girl who cain't say no #
# I'm in a turrible fix #
# I always say
"come on, le's go" #
#Jist when I orta
say "nix" #
#When a person tries
to kiss a girl #
# I know she orta
give his face a smack #
# But as soon as
someone kisses me #
# I somehow sorta
wanta kiss him back #
# I'm jist a fool
when lights are low #
# I cain't be prissy and quaint #
# I ain't the type that c'n faint #
# How c'n I be whut I ain't #
# I cain't #
# Say no #
#Whut you goin' to do
when a feller gits flirty #
#And starts to talk purty #
#Whut you goin' to do #
# S'posin' at he says 'at
yer lips 're like cherries #
# Er roses er berries #
#Whut you goin' to do #
# S'posin' 'at he says 'at
yer sweeter 'n cream #
#And he's gotta
have cream or die #
#Whut you goin' to do
when he talks thet way #
# Spit in his eye #
# I'm jist a girl who cain't say no #
# Kissin's my favorite food #
#Wither with out the mistle toe #
# I'm in a holiday mood #
# Other girls are coy
and hard to catch #
# But other girls
ain't havin' any fun #
# Ev'ry time I lose
a wrestlin' match #
# I have a funny feelin' that I won #
#Though I can feel the undertow #
# I never make a complaint #
#Till it's too late fer restraint #
#Then when I want to
I cain't #
# I cain't #
# Say #
# No ##
It's like I told you, Laurey,
I get sorry for 'em.
And now that old Will
has to come home.
First thing you know, he'll start talking
pretty to me and changing my mind back.
- But Will wants to marry you.
- So does Ali Hakim.
- Did he ask you about marryin'?
- Not directly.
But how I know this,
he said this morning...
that he wanted for me to ride with him
to the end of the world.
Well, if we drove only as far as "Catoosy,"
he couldn't bring me home till morning...
and that means
a wedding, don't it?
Not to a peddler, it don't.
## [Whistling]
[Bells Clanging]
I've been waiting for you
to show your face again, old peddler-man.
Remember what you told me? You said
that eggbeater you sold me would beat up eggs...
wring out dishrags, turn the ice cream freezer
and I don't know what all.
- Now, Aunt Eller, just listen.
- Don't you Aunt Eller me, you little wart. I'm mad.
If the eggbeater don't work,
I give you something just as good. A present.
I wouldn't have it.
- What is it?
- Real silk. Made in Persia.
What would I do with
an old Persian garter?
It looks pretty.
Now gimme the other one.
Which one? Oh, you want to buy
this one to match that one?
What do you mean
do I wanna buy it?
I can let you have it for 50 cents.
Do you want me to get that eggbeater
and ram it down your windpipe?
- Gimme that.
- Howdy, Aunt Eller.
- Hi, yourself.
- Now that all the ladies are here...
let me show you
some pretty "doodaddles."
Lace around the bottom
and there are bows running in and out.
Well, I never wear 'em myself,
but I sure do like to look at 'em.
- How about these?
- Yeah, they's all right if you ain't goin' no place.
Don't nobody want to buy something?
How about you, Miss Laurey?
You must be wanting something...
a pretty young girl like you.
Me? Of course
I want something.
I want a buckle made out of
shiny silver to fasten onto my shoes.
I want a dress with lace.
I want perfume. I want to be purty.
- I wanna smell like a honeysuckle vine.
- Give her a cake of soap.
I want things
I can't tell you about.
Not only things to look at
and hold in your hand...
but things
to happen to you...
things so nice that if they ever did
happen to you, your heart would quit beating.
I got a-just the thing.
The elixir of Egypt.
A secret formula,
belong to pharaoh's daughter.
- Smellin' salts.
- But a special kind of smelling salts.
Here, read what it says
on the label.
You take a deep breath,
and you see everything clear.
That's what pharaoh's daughter used to do
when she had to decide what dress to wear...
or which prince
she ought to marry.
She would take a whiff of this.
- I'll take a bottle of that, Mr. Peddler.
- Oh, precious stuff.
- How much?
- Two bits.
- Throwin' away your money.
- Helps you decide what to do.
Put your trappings away
and come inside.
Come along, Laurey. Maybe we can
find him something to eat and drink.
Ali, Laurey and me
been having an argument.
- About what, baby?
- About what you meant...
when you said that about drivin' with me
to the end of the world.
Well, I didn't really mean
Well, then how far
did you wanna go?
About as far as say... Claremore.
- What's at Claremore?
- The hotel.
In front is a veranda,
inside is the lobby...
and upstairs, baby,
might be paradise.
I thought they's just bedrooms.
For you and me, baby, paradise.
You see, I knowsed I was right.
You do wanna marry me.
- Don'tcha?
- Oh, Ado Annie-What did you say?
I said you do wanna marry me, don'tcha?
What'd you say?
I didn't say nothing.
[Man]
Ya-hoo!
Oh, foot, just when-
That's Will Parker.
Promise me you won't fight him!
[Whinnies]
Ado Annie!
How's my honey bunch?
How's the sweetest little 120 pounds of sugar
in the territory?
Will, this is Ali Hakim.
Hiya, Hak!
Don't mind the way I talk.
It's all right.
I'm gonna marry her.
- Marry her? On purpose?
- No such other thing!
Uh, it's a wonderful thing
to be married.
- I got a brother in Persia got six wife.
- Six wives all at once?
Why sure. That's the way
they do it in them countries.
Not always. I got another brother in Persia
only got one wife.
He's a bachelor.
You know what I got
for first prize at the fair?
- Fifty dollars.
- Oh, well, that was good.
- You catch on?
Your pa promised I could marry you if'n
I could ever get $50 together all at one time.
That's right. He did.
Your pa's like
all the rest of them farmers.
Don't think us cowboys
got much sense.
Well, this'll show him.
You know what I done with the $50?
- I spent it all on presents for you.
- Oh!
But if you spent it,
you ain't got no cash.
What I got's worth more than cash.
The fella that sold me
the stuff told me.
- But, Will-
- Stop saying "But, Will."
When do I get a little kiss?
Oh, Ado Annie, honey, you ain't been
off my mind since I left...
all the time at the fairgrounds
even when I was chasing them steers.
I'd rope one under the hoofs,
and I'd pull him up real sharp...
and he'd land on his little old rump
and then I'd think of you.
Don't start talkin' purty.
See'd a lot of pretty girls in Kansas City.
I didn't give one a look.
How could you see 'em
if you didn't give 'em a look?
I mean, I didn't look
lovin' at them...
the way I look at you.
The way I look at you.
Oh, Will, please don't look like that.
I cain't bear it.
I won't stop looking like this
till you give me a little ol' kiss.
Oh, well, what's a little old kiss?
Nothin', less'n it comes from you.
Oh, you-you do talk purty.
No! I won't!
# Sposin' 'at I say 'at
your lip's 're like cherries #
# Er roses er berries #
#Whut you gonna do #
# Cain't you feel my heart
palpitain' an' bumpin' #
#Awaitin' fer sump'n
Sump'n nice from you #
# I gotta git a kiss
an' it's gotta be quick #
# Er I'll jump in a crick an' die #
#Whut's a girl to do
when you talk that a-way ##
[Yipping]
Must be the folks stopping
on their way to Skidmore's. Oh!
Oh, you're all welcome!
Glad you could all come.
Everybody come in
and have a good time.
Curly!
[Giggling]
I've been 'bout behind you
the whole way.
I know. I heared you.
Oh, welcome.
Everybody's welcome.
# Oh, what a beautiful mornin' #
# Oh, what a beautiful day #
#I got a beautiful feelin'#
# Ev'rythin's goin' my way #
# Oh, what a beautiful day ##
Girls, come on in the house
and freshen up.
You boys, better drive your wagons
down to the trough...
and give your horses some water.
Hi, Laurey.
Hey, Curly, don't you reckon
you better take care of your horses too?
Thanks, Aunt Eller.
I reckon I better.
Oh, can't I come too, Curly?
I just love to watch the way you handle horses.
It's about all
I can handle, I guess.
[Woman Cackles]
Another mile in that buggy with that Perkins boy,
and I'd have lost my mind.
I'll take Wilbur
if you don't want him.
Looks like Curly's took up
with that Cummings girl.
[Gasps]
What do I care about that?
#Why should a woman
who is healthy and strong #
# Blubbering like a baby
if her man goes away #
#A weepin' and a wailin'
how he's done her wrong #
#That's one thing
you'll never hear me say #
# Never gonna think
that the man I lose #
# Is the only man among men #
# I'll snap my fingers
to show I don't care #
# I'll buy me
a brand new dress to wear #
# I'll scrub my neck #
#And I'll brush my hair #
#And start all over again #
# Many a new face
will please my eye #
# Many a new love will find me #
# Never've I once
looked back to sigh #
# Over the romance behind me #
# Many a new day
will dawn before I do #
# Many a light lad
may kiss and fly #
#A kiss gone by is by gone #
# Never've I asked an August sky #
# "Where has last July gone" #
# Never've I wandered
through the rye #
#Wonderin' where has
some guy gone #
# Many a new day
will dawn before I do #
# Many a new face
will please my eye #
# Many a new love will find me #
# Never've I once
looked back to sigh #
# Over the romance behind me #
#Many a new day
will dawn before I do #
# Never've I chased the honey bee #
#Who carelessly cajoled me #
# Somebody else just as sweet as he #
# Cheered me and consoled me #
# Never've I wept in to my tea #
# Over the deal someone doled me #
# Many a new day will dawn #
# Many a red sun will set #
# Many a blue moon will shine #
# Before I do #
# Many a new face
will please my eye #
# Many a new love will find me #
# Never've I once
looked back to sigh #
# Over the romance behind me #
# Many a new day will dawn #
# Many a red sun will set #
# Many a blue moon will shine #
- # Before-#
- [Woman Cackles]
# Many a blue moon will shine #
# Before I #
# Do ##
Maurice, time we got out of here.
Back to the open road.
#The open road #
Ali. Ali, I'm sure sorry
to see you lookin' so happy...
'cause what I got to say
will make you miserable.
- I gotta marry Will.
- Oh, well, that sure is sad news for me.
Well, he's a fine fellow.
Don't hide your feelings, Ali!
I can't bear it.
I'd rather have you come right out and say
your heart's busted in two.
- Are you positive you got to marry Will?
- Sure as shootin'!
- There's no chance for you to change your mind?
- No chance.
- All right then. My heart is busted in two.
- [Gunshot]
- Hello, Pa. What you been shootin'?
- Rabbits.
That true what I hear
about Will Parker getting $50?
That's right, Pa.
He wants to hold you to your promise.
Too bad. Still in all,
I can't go back on my word.
Listen to me, Annie I advise you
to get that money before he loses it all.
Put it in your stocking
or inside your corset...
where he can't get at it-
Or can he?
But, Pa, he ain't exactly kept it.
He spent it all on presents.
See, what did I tell ya?
Well, now he can't have you.
- I said it had to be $50 cash!
- Is that fair, Mr. Carnes?
- Who the devil are you?
- Oh, Pa, that's Ali Hakim.
Well, shut your face,
or I'll fill your behind so full of buckshot...
you'll be walking around like a duck
the rest of your life.
Ali, if I don't
have to marry Will...
maybe your heart don't have to be busted
in two like you said.
- I did not say that.
- Oh, yes, you did.
- No, no, I did not.
- Are you trying to make
my daughter out to be a liar?
No, I'm only trying to make clear to you
what a liar I am, if she is telling the truth.
- What else you been sayin' to my daughter?
- Oh! An awful lot.
- When?
- Last night in the moonlight.
- Where?
- Alongside a haystack.
- Oh, listen, Mr. Carnes.
- I'm listenin'. What else did you say?
- He called me his Persian kitten.
- What'd you call her that fer?
- I don't remember.
- I do. He said I's like a Persian kitten...
'cause they is the cats
with the soft, round tails.
That's enough. In this country,
that better be a proposal of marriage.
- That's what I thought.
- That what you think?
- Look, Mr. Carnes-
- I'm lookin'. I'm lookin'.
I'm no good.
I'm a peddler!
A peddler has to travel
up and down and all around.
You'd hardly ever
see your daughter no more.
That'd be all right.
Just take care of her, son.
- Just take care of my little rosebud.
- Oh, Pa, 'at's purty.
Uh, you sure for certain
you can bear to let me go?
- Are you sure, Mr. Carnes?
- You just try to change my mind.
Aw, Ali, ain't it wonderful, Pa making up
our minds for us? And he won't change neither.
Once he gives his word
that you can have me, you've got me!
I know I got you.
Mrs. Ali Hakim,
the peddler's bride!
- [Women Giggling]
- Oh, wait till I tell those girls!
Laurey! Laurey!
The peddler-man and me's
gonna get married!
[Woman Cackling]
Congratulations.
I hope we'll be very happy.
Hi, Laurey.
What you doin'?
Gonna pick peaches.
[Giggles]
I peeked in your basket up at the house.
I see you got gooseberry tarts too.
I wonder if they's
as light as mine.
Mine would like to float away
if you blew on them.
I just did blow on one of mine,
and it broke into a million pieces.
Ain't she funny?
[Laughs]
Oh!
- Stop that!
- [Indistinct Arguing]
- Stop it!
- Gertie!
Go on up the house
and cool off!
Get along! Mind!
Don't forget tonight at the auction,
Curly, mine's the biggest hamper!
[Laughs]
So that's that old Cummings gal
I heared so much talk of.
- You seen her before, ain't ya?
- But not since she got so old.
Never did see anybody get
so peaked-lookin' in such a short time.
Yeah. Says she's 18.
Ha! Bet she's 19.
Are you really gonna drive
to the box social with that Jud fella?
- I reckon so. Why?
- Oh, nothing.
It's just that everybody seems
to expect me to take you.
Then maybe it's just
as well you ain't!
We don't want people
talkin' about us, do we?
Do you think people
really do talk about us?
Well, you know how they are,
like a swarm of mud wasps...
always gotta be buzzing
about something.
What are they saying,
that you're stuck on me?
Uh-uh. Most of the talk
is that you're stuck on me.
Can't imagine how these
ugly rumors start.
Me, neither.
#Why do they think up stories that link
my name with yours #
#Why do the neighbors gossip all day
behind their doors #
# I know a way to prove
what they say is quite untrue #
# Here is the gist
a practical list #
# Of "don'ts" #
# For you #
# Don't throw #
# Bouquets at me #
# Don't please #
# My folks too much #
# Don't laugh #
#At my jokes too much #
# People will say we're in love #
- Who laughs at your jokes?
- # Don't sigh #
#And gaze at me #
#Your sighs #
#Are so like mine #
#Your eyes #
# Mustn't glow like mine #
# People will say we're in love #
# Don't start #
- # Collecting things #
- # Like what #
# Give me my rose and my glove #
# Sweetheart #
#They're suspecting things #
# People will say #
#We're in #
# Love #
# Some people claim
that you are to blame #
#As much as I #
#Why do you take
the trouble to bake #
# My fav'rite pie #
# Grant in' you wish
I carved our initials #
# On that tree #
#Just keep a slice
of all the advice #
#You give so free #
# Don't praise #
# My charm too much #
# Don't look #
# So vain with me #
# Don't stand #
# In the rain with me #
# People will say we're in love #
# Don't take #
# My arm too much #
# Don't keep #
#Your hand in mine #
#Your hand #
# Feels so grand in mine #
# People will say we're in love #
# Don't dance #
#All night with me #
#Till the stars fade from above #
#They'll see #
# It's alright with me #
# People will say #
#We're in #
# Love ##
Don't you think you could tell that Jud fella
you'd rather go with me tonight?
Curly-
No, I couldn't.
Oh, you couldn't.
Think I'll go down to the smokehouse
where Jud's at.
See what's so elegant about him, makes
all the girls want to go to parties with him.
- Curly!
- What?
Nothin'.
[Quacking]
[Knock At Door]
Well, open it, can't you?
Well, what do you want?
Oh, l- I done got through with my business
up there at the house.
I just thought I'd pay a call.
- You got a gun, I see.
- That's right.
It's a Colt.45.
Oh.
Say, now.
That there pink picture-
That's a naked woman, ain't it?
Plumb stark naked as a jaybird.
Shucks, that ain't a thing
to what I could show you.
Well, that's
a good-lookin' rope.
Feels good too.
[Grunts]
That's a good, strong hook
you got there, Jud.
You know what?
You could hang yourself on that.
- I could what?
- You could hang yourself.
Yes, sir.
Easy as rollin' off a log.
Why, in five minutes
or less, with good luck...
- you could be dead as a doornail.
- What do you mean by that?
Oh, then folks would
come to your funeral.
- And they'd sing sad songs.
- [Scoffs]
Why, they would.
You never know how many people like you
till you're dead.
You'd be laid out in a parlor.
All decked out in your best suit.
Your hair combed down slick,
high starched collar.
Lots of pretty flowers
all around you.
Would there be flowers,
you think?
And palms too-
all around your coffin.
Folks would gather round,
and men would bare their heads.
Women would sniffle softly.
Some probably even faint-
ones that took a shine to you
whilst you was alive.
Now, what women
ever took a shine to me?
Why, lots of women.
Only they never come right out
and tell you how they feel...
unless you die first.
I guess maybe you're right.
They'd sure sing loud,
though, when the singin' would start.
Sing like their hearts would break.
# Pore Jud is daid #
# Pore Jud Fry is daid #
#All gather' round
his cawfin now and cry #
# He had a heart of gold #
#And he wasn't very old #
# Oh, why did sich a feller
have to die #
# Pore Jud is daid #
# Pore Jud Fry is daid #
# He's lookin' oh, so peaceful
and serene #
#And serene #
# He's all laid out to rest #
#With his hands
a crost his chest #
# His fingernails
have never been so clean #
And then the preacher'd
get up, and he'd say-
Folks, we are gathered here to moan
and groan over our brother Jud Fry...
who hung hisself up
by a rope in a smokehouse.
And then there'd be weepin' and wailin'
from some of those women.
And then he'd say-
Jud was the most misunderstood man
in this territory.
People used to think
he was a mean, ugly fella.
And call him a dirty skunk
and ornery pig stealer.
# But the folks
'at really knowed him #
Knowed that beneath
them two dirty shirts he always wore-
#There beat a heart
as big as all out-doors #
#As big as all outdoors #
#Jud Fry loved his fellow man #
# He loved his fellow man #
He loved the birds
of the forests...
and the beasts of the field.
He loved the mice
and the vermin in the barn.
And he treated the rats
like equals.
Which was right.
He loved all the little children.
He loved everything
and everybody in the world.
Only-
Only he never let on.
So nobody ever knowed it.
# Pore Jud is daid #
# Pore Jud Fry is daid #
# His friends'll weep and wail
for miles around #
# Miles around #
#The daisies in the dell #
#Will give out a diff'rent smell #
# Becuz pore Jud
is underneath the ground #
# Pore Jud is daid #
#A candle lights his haid #
# He's layin' in a cawfin
made of wood #
#Wood #
#And folks are feelin' sad #
# Cuz they useter treat him bad #
#And now they know their friend
has gone fer good #
# Good #
[Together]
# Pore Jud is daid #
#A candle lights his haid #
# He's lookin' oh so purty
and so nice #
# He looks like he's asleep #
# It's a shame
that he won't keep #
# But it's summer #
#And we're runnin' out of ice #
[Together]
# Pore #
#Jud #
#Jud ##
[Chuckles]
Yes, sir.
That sure will be
an interesting funeral.
I wouldn't like to miss it.
Well, maybe you will.
Maybe you'll go first.
Well...
let's see now.
Where'd you work at
before you come up here?
Was up by, uh,
Quapaw, wasn't it?
That's right.
Lousy they was to me too.
Always makin' out
they were better than I was.
Always treating me
like I was dirt.
So, uh, what'd you do?
Get even?
Who said anything
about getting even?
No one I recollect.
Just come into my head.
If it come to gettin' even with somebody,
I'd know how to do it.
You remember the fire
in the Bartlett farm over by Sweetwater?
I sure do.
It was about five years ago.
Burned up the father
and the mother and the daughter.
It was a terrible accident.
That weren't no accident.
Fella told me.
Said that the hired hand
was stuck on the Bartlett girl...
and one day he found her
in the hayloft with another fella.
And 'twas him
that burned the place?
Took him weeks to get the kerosene,
buying it at different times.
Fella that told me...
he made out like
it happened in Missouri...
but I knew all the time
it was the Bartlett farm.
What a liar he was.
Get a little air in here.
You ain't told me yet
what business you had here.
We got no cattle to sell
and no cow ponies.
Could be only one other thing
on this farm you could want...
and it better not be that.
- That's just what it is.
- You keep away from her, you hear?
You know, somebody
ought to tell Laurey...
just what kind of a man you are.
And for that matter, somebody
ought to tell you once about yourself.
Curly, you better get out of here.
In this country, there's just two things
you can do if you're a man.
You can live outdoors is one...
and you can live in a hole
is the other.
I set by my horse
in the brush somewheres...
and I heared a rattlesnake
many a time.
[Imitates Rattlesnake]
He'd go-
Scared to death
somebody gonna step on him.
- Got his old fangs all ready.
- Curly, you better get out of here!
How did you get to be
the way you are anyhow?
Sittin' in here in this filthy hole.
Why don't you do something healthy
once in a while...
'stead of stayin' shut up here,
a-crawlin' and festerin'?
[Shouts]
[Gun Clatters On Table]
[Dog Barking,
Chickens Clucking]
Well.
You ought to feel better now.
I wish you'd let me
show you something.
There's a knothole
over there...
Ripped by:
SkyFury