Some say that as we grow up,
we become different people...
at different ages,
but l don't believe this.
l thinkwe remain the same
throughout,
merely passing in these years
from one room to another...
but always in the same house.
lfwe unlockthe rooms
ofthe far past,
we can look in and see ourselves
beginning to become you and me.
[Singing]
One,two,three
SMALL BOY:.
l won't go to bed, Nana.
l won't go to bed.
-Liza, is it 6:.OO yet?
-Yes.
Please, Nana, do l have to
go to bed?
[Nana barks]
Liza,we're pretending
we're Mother and Father
and we're going to the ball
tonight. Come play.
Always playing games.
l have much more important
things to do...
than play at make-believe
and dancing.
[Singing]
One,two,three, one,two,three
MOTHER:. Wendy,John.
WENDY:. Oh, Mother!
JOHN:. You look lovely.
MOTHER:. Oh,thankyou.
What are you doing
in my hat?
We're doing an act.
Yes. We're playing at being
you and Father.
l'm Father.
A little less noise there
a little less noise.
Mother,they never let me play
Father. They never let me dance.
Well,we'll soon fix that.
There. May l have the honor
ofthis dance, Mr. Darling?
One,two,three
One,two,three, one
You dance beautifully,
Mr. Darling.
FATHER:. Mother! Mother!
WENDY:. Oh, it's Father.
Oh,there you are, Mother.
MOTHER:. What's the matter
Father dear?
The matter? This tie. It will
not tie, not round my neck.
Round the bedpost, oh,yes,
but round my neck, no.
Oh, dear no.
Begs to be excused.
Say it again, Father.
Say it again.
A little less noise there.
l warn you ofthis,
that unless this goes round...
my neck properly,we don't go
out to dinnertonight.
lfwe don't go out to dinner,
l'll never go
to the office again,
and if l never go to the office
again,we will starve...
and our children will be flung
into the streets.
CHILDREN:. Oh, no, Father!
Wait a minute, Father dear.
l think l've got it.
Oh! One more day
when all is right.
Oh, Nana, Nana.
Mother, look here.
Hairs all over my trousers.
Clumsy, clumsy.
-l'll brush them off, Father.
-Thankyou.
There's times l think
it's a mistake...
to have a dog for a nurse.
Oh, George. Nana's a treasure.
No doubt. But l sometimes have
a sorrt offeeling...
that she looks upon the children
as her puppies.
George,we must keep Nana.
l'll tell you why.
Get ready for bed, children.
Nana will take you.
That's right.
Now, run along.
George.
Tonight l saw a face
at the window.
Face at the window
two floors up?
lt was a face of a little boy.
He was tying to get in.
Oh, it's impossible.
That's not the first time
l've seen that boy.
-Oh?
-The first time was a week ago.
l remember because it was
Nana's night off.
l was sitting there by the fire,
and suddenly l felt a draft...
as though the windowwere open.
l looked...
and l sawthat boy in the room.
l screamed.
Just then, Nana came back
and sprang at him at once.
The boy leapt at the window.
Nana closed it quickly.
-lt was too late to catch him.
-l thought so.
But wait! He escaped, but his
shadow hadn't time to get out.
l hid it.
l rolled it up.
-And here it is.
-Aha!
Well, l don't think
it's anyone we know,
though he does look a scoundrel.
You know, l think he comes back
tying to get his shadow.
-l daresay.
-But wait!
l haven't told you all.
The boy was not quite alone.
He was accompanied by...
l don't know
howto describe it.
A ball of light
no biggerthan my fist...
that darrted around the room
like a living thing.
This is most unusual.
-George,what can it mean?
-What indeed?
What indeed?
Oh, Nana! Oh, my knee! My knee!
WENDY:. Father, she's cying.
She's cying? What about me?
Go and coddle her.
Nobody ever coddles me.
l'm only the breadwinner.
Why should l be coddled?
Why,why,why?
Not so loud.
Liza will hear.
l refuse to allowthat dog
to lord over me in my nursey...
one hour longer.
WENDY:. Oh, Father!
ln vain, in vain. Your place
is downstairs. Come on, Nana.
MOTHER:. George.
Rememberwhat l told you
about that boy?
Am l master in this house
or is she? Come on, Nana.
[Nana barks]
FATHER:. Ow!
Come, Nana.
Good Nana.
Nice Nana.
Dear Nana.
Pretty Nana.
Gotcha! Come out! This way!
[Family protesting]
Oh, he's chaining Nana up!
FATHER:. Out the dooryou go.
JOHN:. She's unhappy.
FATHER:. No, no. There,there.
That's not her unhappy bark.
That's her bark
when she smells danger.
Wendy, are you sure?
Yes, Mother.
[Nana barking]
WENDY:. Is eveything all right?
lt's all quiet and still.
l wish l weren't going out
to dinnertonight.
MICHAEL:. Can anything
harm us, Mommy,
afterthe night-lights are lit?
No, precious. They're the eyes
a mother leaves behind...
to guard her children.
Now sing your good-night song...
and into your beds.
[Singing]
Tender shepherd,tender shepherd
Let me help you count your sheep
One in the meadow
Two in the garden
Three in the nursey,
fast asleep
MICHAEL:. Tender shepherd,
tender shepherd
JOHN:. Tender shepherd,
WENDY:. Tender shepherd,
tender shepherd
Watches over all his sheep
One, say your prayers
And two, close your eyes
And three, safe and happily,
fall asleep
Fall asleep
Fall asleep.
Dear night-lights that protecct
my sleeping children,
burn clear and steadfast
tonight.
[Nana barking]
[Bell tinkling]
Tinker Bell.
[Nana barking]
Tinker Bell!
Tink! Where are you?
[Tinkling]
There you are.
Tink, do come out ofthat jug.
Do you knowwhere it is?
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
Overthere?
My shadow!
l'll stickyou on with soap.
My shadow,what's the matter
with you?
Boy,why are you cying?
What's your name?
Wendy Myra Angela Darling.
Peter Pan.
Where do you live?
Second to the right
and straight on till morning.
ls that what they put
on your letters?
Don't get any letters.
But your mother gets letters.
Don't have a mother.
-Oh, Peter!
-You mustn't touch me!
But why?
No one must evertouch me.
Why not?
l don't know.
No wonderyou were cying.
l wasn't cying about that.
l can't get my shadow
to stick on.
lt's come off? How awful!
Oh, ha ha ha! Peter!
You've been tying
to stick it on with soap.
-Well,then?
-l'll have to sew it on foryou,
my little man.
-Thankyou.
-Now,you sit there.
l daresay this will hurrt
a little.
l never cy.
[Peterwhistling]
There!
Thankyou.
PETER:. Wouldn't you know it!
My shadow!
My vey own shadow!
WENDY:. But it's only a shadow.
Yes, but it's all mine.
Oh, l'm clever!
Oh,the cleverness of me!
WENDY:. Of course, l did nothing.
You're conceited!
Conceited?
[Singing]
Not me
lt's just that l am what l am
And l'm me
When l look at myself
and l see in myself
All the wonderful things
that l see
lf l'm pleased with myself
l have evey good reason to be
l gotta crow
l'm just the cleverest fella
'Twas ever my forrtune to know
l taught a trickto my shadow
To stickto the tip of my toe
l gotta crow
l gotta brag
l think it's sweet
l have fingers and feet
l can wiggle and wag
l can climb trees and play tag
with the breeze
ln the meadows below
l gotta crow
lf l were a vey ordinay
Eveyday thing
l'd never be heard
Cock-a-doodlin' round
like a bird
So naturally
When l discoverthe cleverness
of a remarkable me
How can l hide it
When deep down inside,
it just tickles me so?
That l gotta let go
And crow
[Crows]
Ha ha ha!
l'm really a rare thing
Such a fairthing
l can't keep still
l'm bursting with pride
And l just couldn't
keep it inside
lf l tried
So naturally
When l discoverthe cleverness
of a remarkable me
How can l hide it
When deep down inside,
it just tickles me so?
That l gotta let go
And crow
[Crowing]
Oh, Peter,you are so clever.
Peter, how old are you?
l don't know.
l ran away from home
the day l was born.
Ran away? Why?
Because l heard Father
and Mother discussing...
what l was to be
when l became a man.
l want to always be a little boy
and have fun.
So l ran away, and l've lived
a long time among the fairies.
Oh, Peter!
Do you really knowfairies?
Yes.
But they're nearly all dead now.
You see,Wendy,when the first
baby laughed forthe first time,
the laugh broke into
a thousand pieces,
and they all went
skipping about.
And that was the beginning
offairies.
So now evey time
a new baby is born,
its first laugh becomes a faiy.
There ought to be a faiy
for evey girl and boy.
WENDY:. Ought to be? Isn't there?
Oh, no.
Children know such a lot now.
Soon,they don't believe.
And evey time a child says
''l don't believe in fairies,''
there's a faiy someplace
that falls down dead.
WENDY:. Poorthings!
l can't think
where she's gone to.
-Tink!
-Peter!
You don't mean to tell me
there's a faiy in this room?!
She came here with me.
[Rattling]
Wendy, l believe l've shut her
up in that drawer.
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
Well,you needn't say that.
Well, l'm vey sory.
Well, how did l know
you were in the drawer?
Tink,this lady wishes
you were herfaiy.
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
What did she say?
She's not vey polite.
She says you're a great
ugly girl, and she's mine.
Tink,you knowyou can't be my
faiy because l'm a gentleman,
and you're a lady.
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
What did she say?
She said, ''You silly ass.''
She's quite a common girl,
you know.
[Nana barks]
Oh, it's all right.
She's chained up.
Peter,where do you live?
PETER:. Way out there!
WENDY:. Well, how do you find
yourway home?
You just follow
all the golden arrows.
Where do they lead you?
lt's a secret place.
Oh, please tell me.
Would you believe me
if l told you?
l promise.
PETER:. For sure?
WENDY:. For sure.
Then l'll tell you.
[Singing] l have a place
where dreams are born
And time is never planned
lt's not on any charrt
You must find it with your hearrt
Never Never Land
lt might be miles
beyond the moon
Or right there where you stand
Just keep an open mind
And then suddenly you'll find
Never Never Land
You'll have a treasure
ifyou stay there
More precious farthan gold
For once you have found
yourway there
You can never, never grow old
And that's my home
where dreams are born
And time is never planned
Just think of lovely things
And your hearrt will fly on wings
Forever
ln Never Never Land
Peter,what does it look like?
lt's an island,Wendy.
A large one?
No. Quite small...
and nicely crammed...
with hardly any space between
one adventure and another.
Oh, it sounds lovely.
Who else lives there, Peter?
The Lost Boys.
Who are they?
They're the children who fall
out oftheir carriages...
when the nurse is looking
the otherway.
lfthey're not claimed
in 7 days,
they're sent far away
to Never Land.
l'm captain!
What fun it must be!
Yes...
But we're rather lonely.
Peter,why did you come
to our nursey window?
To hearthe stories.
None of us know any stories.
How perrfecctly awwful.
Wendy...
Your motherwas telling you
such a lovely stoy.
Oh? Which stoy is it?
lt was about the prince.
And he couldn't find the lady
who wore the glass slipper.
Oh. That's ''Cinderella.''
He found her.
And they lived
happily ever after.
l'm glad!
Where are you going?
-To tell the other boys!
-Oh, please don't go!
l know lots of stories.
Do you?
WENDY:. Oh,the stories
l could tell the other boys.
Come on. We'll fly.
Fly? You can fly?
Wendy, come with me.
Oh, howwe should
all respecct you.
And you could tuck us in at
night and make pockets for us.
None of us has any pockets.
Would you teach John and Michael
howto fly?
lfyou like.
John! Michael! Wake up!
There's a boy here who's going
to teach us to fly.
MICHAEL:. There is?
JOHN:. l'll get up at once.
[Nana barking]
Someone's coming. Quick! Hide!
There. You see?
They are perrfecctly safe
and sound asleep in bed.
[WoofWoof]
Now, no more.
Go along,you naughty dog.
[Nana barking]
All clear!
MICHAEL:. Fly!
JOHN:. Can you really fly?
-l'll teach you.
-How lovely to fly.
l'll teach you to jum,p
on the wind's back
and away we'll go!
-Ooh!
-Wendy,when you're sleeping...
in your silly bed,you might be
flying about with me,
saying funny things
to the stars.
MICHAEL:. How do you do it?
You just think lovely,
wonderrful thoughts,
and up you go!
l'm flying!
[Peter singing]
l'm flying
CHILDREN:. Flying!
Flying! Flying!
Look at me,way up high
Suddenly, here am l, l'm flying
l'm flying
CHILDREN:. Flying!
Flying! Flying!
l can soar, l can weave
And what's more
l'm not even tying'
High up
and as light as l can be
l must be a sight lovely to see
l'm flying
CHILDREN:. Flying!
Flying! Flying!
Nothing will stop me now
Higher still, look at how
l can zoom around
Way up offthe ground
l'm flying
l fly, and l'm all
overthe place
You ty, and you'll fall
flat on yourface
PETER:. Ha ha ha!
l'm flying
CHILDREN:. Flying!
Flying! Flying!
Over bed, over chair
Duckyour head, clearthe air
Oh,what lovely fun
Watch me, eveyone
Take a look at me
and see how easily it's done
l'm flying
PETER:. You like it?
WENDY:. Oh,yes, Peter!
Want to learn how?
JOHN:. Yes. Please teach us.
First l must blow
the faiy dust on you.
JOHN:. Oh, me first! Me!
PETER:. Ha ha ha!
Now,think lovely thoughts.
CHILDREN:. Think lovely thoughts.
Fishing!
Hopscotch!
Candy!
Picnics!
Summer!
-Candy!
-Sailing!
Flowers!
Candy!
Lovelierthoughts, Michael.
Christmas!
That's it!
WENDY:. Michael
did you see that?
[Michael screaming]
PETER:. Come on! l'll take you
to Never Never Land!
WENDY:. Never Land? How lovely
to go to Never Land!
PETER:. There are pirates
and Indians.
JOHN:. Pirates?!
Let's go at once!
PETER:. Get ready!
PETER:. Ah.
[Peter singing]
You're ready
CHILDREN:. Ready! Ready! Ready!
Don't forget, don't be slow
Ready, set, here we go
Wendy, Michael,John
Tinker Bell, come on!
Hury up and follow me,
for l will soon be gone
l'm flying!
MICHAEL:. Wait for me!
Wait for me!
LIZA:. Where are you going?
MICHAEL:. l'm flying!
Oh, l'm flying!
l'm going to Never Land!
PETER:. Whee!
Come on!
Let's go to Never Never Land!
PETER:. l'm flying!
PETER:. Come on!
Come on, let's fly!
Come on! l'll take you
to Never Land!
l'm flying!
NARRATOR:. Second to the right
and straight on till morning.
That is the way to Never Land.
lfyou close your eyes,
you will see a pool
of lovely pale colors.
lfyou squeeze them tighter,
the pool will take on
different shapes,
and the colors
will become brighter,
so bright that in a moment,
they'll go on fire.
And in that moment
just before they do,
you will see Never Land,
a magic island on whose shores
children are forever at play.
[Squawking]
BOY:. Now!
-Did you catch her?
-No, but look!
Tootles, has Peter
come backyet?
-No, he hasn't.
-Maybe he's waiting to hear...
the end of ''Cinderella.''
l'm always afraid
of pirates and Indians.
Yes,when Peter's not here
to protecct us.
Oh, l'm not afraid of anything.
BOYS:. Oh!
[Boys yelling]
[Men singing]
BOY:. What's that?
[Men singing] We massacre
Indians, kill little boys
And caterto Captain Hook
BOYS:. Pirates!
PIRRATES:. Yo-ho!
PIRRATES:. Ha!
PIRRATES:. Yo-ho! Yo-ho!
Yo-ho!
Ah! Ah!
[Singing]
We're bloody buccaneers, ha
And each a murderous crook, ha
We massacre Indians
kill little boys
And caterto Captain Hook
PIRRATES:. Yo-ho!
HOOK:. Yo-ho!
The terrible Captain Hook
-Clumsy!
-Aah!
-Butterrfingers!
-l'll get him, Captain!
-Aha!
Aah! No, Captain! No!
Drop that pistol first!
lt was one ofthose boys
you hate.
-l could have shot him dead.
-Aye.
And with the first crack
it will bring Tiger Lily
and her Indians.
PIRRATES:. Indians!
-Do you want to lose your scalp?
-That is true.
Shall l after him, Captain,
and tickle him
with Johnny Corkscrew?
Johnny's a silent fellow.
No, Smee.
That's only one,
and l want to mischief
all ofthem.
They must be around here
somewhere.
Scatter and lookforthem!
But most of all, l want
their captain, Peter Pan.
'Twas he cut off me arm.
l've waited long to shake hands
with him with this.
Ooh, l'll tear him.
Yet l've oft heard you say...
your hookwas worrth
a score of hands...
for combing the hair
and other homely uses.
Aye. If l were a mother,
l should pray that me children
be born with this...
instead ofthat.
But Peterthrew me hand
to a crocodile...
who happened to be passing by,
and that croc liked
the taste of me hand so much
he's followed me ever since
from land to land,
from sea to sea
he follows the ship licking
his lips forthe rest of me.
Well, in a way,
it is a sorrt of compliment.
Well, l want
no such compliments.
l want Peter Pan,who first
gave the brute his taste for me.
Smee,that crocwould have
got me long ere this...
if it could have
crept upon me unawares.
But by some lucky chance,
it swallowed a clock.
A clock!
And it goes tick-to,ck-tick
within him
and so before he can reach me
l hearthe tick and bolt!
Ha ha ha ha! Oh!
-What's the matter, Captain?
-This seat's hot. It's vey hot.
Odds, bods, hammer, and tongs,
l'm burning! Smee, help me!
SMEE:. Yes,yes.
That's enough, Smee.
Ooh! Help me.
A chimney! Smee,these boys
must be living...
[Boys' voices]
Underground! Call backthe band!
l must think!
lnspire me! Play,you dogs!
SMEE:. What tempo, Captain?
Tempo,tempo,tempo...
A tango.
SMEE:. A tango!
[Band playing tango]
SMEE:. Ungrip your plan, Captain.
[Captain Hook singing]
To cook a cake quite large
And fill each layer in between
With icing mixed with poison
Till it turns a tempting green
We'll place it nearthe house
Just where the boys
are sure to come
And being greedy
They won't care
to question such a plum
The boys who have
no mother sweet
No one to showthem
their mistake
Won't know it's dangerous to eat
So damp and rich a cake
And so before
The blinking of an eye
Those boys will eat
that poison cake
And one by one
They'll die
HOOK:. Olé!
PIRRATES:. Bravo! Bravo!
Oh, no. Stop it!
[Tick-tock]
-Smee! Smee!
-What's the matter, Captain?
-Smee!
HOOK:. The croc!
SMEE:. How do you know?
l can hear it ticking!
Save me, Smee! Save me!
Save me! Oh, save me, Smee!
Aah!
SMEE:. Don't leave me, Captain!
Don't leave me, Captain!
They're gone.
BOYS:. Indians!
Shh!
ALL:. Aah!
-Hee hee hee!
-Shh!
Make-um too much noise!
Listen to Tiger Lily.
When on warpath, shh!
ALL:. Shh!
TIGER LILY:. Aga waga wigwam.
ALL:. Aga waga wigwam.
ALL:. Wah!
-Ah-choo!
-Shh!
ltty-bitty tepee.
-Tee hee hee hee hee.
-Aah! Ha ha ha ha ha! Ah!
Oh! Wah! Hee!
Ah! Oh! Wah! Hee!
Oh-oh-oh!
Ha! Ha! Wah! Wah! Ya!
Hee-haw! Hee-haw!
Ha!
Oh!
Wah! Hee!
-Ah!
-Wah!
-Aga waga meatball
Aah! Aah! Aah! Aah!
Shh! Shh! Shh! Shh!
Aah!
They're gone.
Tootles:. Help! Help! Help!
[Boys yelling]
Help! Help! Help! Help!
Look! A bird!
ALL:. A bird!
PETER:. PoorWendy.
WENDY:. PoorWendy.
BOY:. It's a Wendy bird.
-Bird must be omen.
-Good or bad omen?
Famous Indian proverb--
when in doubt, run!
Hey, boys,
Iet's shoot the Wendy.
Aye. Shoot it quick.
Bows and arrows.
Out ofthe way!
l shot the Wendy.
Peterwill be so pleased
with me.
[Fanfare plays]
BOYS:. It's Peter!
TOOTLES:. He's back! He's back!
Let's surprise him
with the Wendy.
Hide it, quick!
[Peter crowing]
Greetings, boys. l'm back,
and l have a great surprise.
-So do we.
-We killed a great big bird.
BOYS:. Look!
Wendy!
With an arrow in her hearrt.
This is no bird.
It's a lady.
BOYS:. A lady?
l was bringing her here
to be our mother.
And nowyou've killed her.
Whose arrow?
Mine, Peter.
Oh, dastard hand!
l cannot strike.
Something stops me.
BOY:. Look at her arm!
PETER:. She lives!
BOYS:. She lives!
See,the arrow struck
against this button.
Are you asleep,Wendy?
Thankyou.
Don't you want to get up
and play?
Howwill we get Wendy
into the house?
l know.
We'll build a house around her.
BOYS:. Ah!
PETER:. Come.
l have a plan.
[Peter singing]
We'll need lots ofwood
Need lots of leaves
Need lots of paint
But hush, hush, hush, hush
Hush
Let's be quiet as a mouse
And build a lovely little house
ForWendy
All forWendy
She's come to stay
And be our mother
At last we have a mother
''Home sweet home'' upon the wall
A welcome mat down in the hall
ForWendy
So that Wendy
Won't go away
BOYS:. We have a mother
at last we have a mother
Oh,what pleasure
she'll bring to us
Make us pockets
And sing to us
Tell us stories
we've been longing to hear
Over and over
She'll be waiting at the door
We won't be lonely anymore
Since Wendy
Lovely Wendy's here to stay
We have a mother
at last we have a mot'her
Hury up and get ready.
Bring eveything forthe house.
Quick! Quick!
[Whistling]
Oh,thanks.
ALL:. We have a mother
at last we have a mothe'r
Help, Peter! How do we get out?
Now! Oh!
Oh,what pleasure
she'll bring to us
Make us pockets
And sing to us
Tell us stories
We've been longing to hear
Over and over
She'll be waiting at the door
We won't be lonely anymore
Since Wendy
Lovely Wendy's here to stay
BOYS:. We have a mother
at last we have a mother
She'll be our mother
lt's nice to have a mother
Wendy's here to stay
BOYS:. Wendy lady, be our mother.
Oh, l'd love to be your mother,
provided Peter
will be the father.
Ha! All right.
As long as
it's only make-believe.
[All singing]
La la la la
La la la la la la la la
La la la
La la la la
We have a mother
at last we have a mot'her
-Look! A cake!
-Oh, boy!
BOYS:. A cake!
WENDY:. Now, children
l'm sure this cake is much
too damp and rich foryou.
BOYS:. Oh! l want a piece.
Now, let's go inside,
and before l put you to sleep,
l'll have just enough time
to finish the stoy
of ''Cinderella.''
BOYS:. Ah! ''Cinderella!''
The game is up.
Those boys have found a mother.
What's a mother?
-l must think.
-What tempo, Captain?
Tempo,tempo,tempo,tempo...
-A tarantella!
[Playing tarantella]
[Singing] Methinks
l see a spark, a gleam
A glimmer of a plan
With which perhaps l may redeem
me honor as a man
Kidnap Wendy, seize the boys,
and you'll have Hookto thank
Forwhen the time is ripe,
you see
The children walkthe plank
Oh,when was such a princely
plot concoccted by another?
To murder all the boys and keep
the Wendy for our mother
Tra la la la
Oh, and keep the Wendy
For our mother
Yo-ho,yo-ho
To the ship,to the ship
To the ship,to the ship,
to the ship,to the ship
To the ship,to the ship
To the ship.
Good night, Peter.
Good night,Wendy.
Guard the house well.
l will.
How do you do?
Oh,thankyou.
NARRRATOR:. Exciting adventures
hapt evey day on the island...
because it was so small.
[Squawking]
One,two,three,four.
[Wildy]
[Squawking]
Bah! Ugga Wuggal Ostrich.
ALL:. Ugga Wuggal Ostrich.
[Pirates singing]
We're bloody buccaneers, ha
And each a murderous crook
SMEE:. Aha!
HOOK:. Feather.
Indians! Pursue them!
A little respecct there
foryourfather.
Repeat after me...
[Peter singing]
l won't grow up
[Boys singing]
PETER:. l don't wanna
go to school
BOYS:. l don't wanna go to school
PETER:. Just to learn
to be a parrot
BOYS:. Just to learn
PETER:. And recite a silly rule
BOYS:. And recite a silly rule
PETER:. If growing up
means it would be
Beneath my dignity
to climb a tree
l'll never grow up
Never grow up, never grow up
Not me.
Not l.
BOYS:. Not me.
PETER:. l won't grow up
BOYS:. l won't grow up
PETER:. l don't wanna wear a tie
BOYS:. l don't wanna wear a tie
PETER:. Or a serious expression
BOYS:. Or a serious expression
PETER:. In the middle ofJuly
BOYS:. In the middle ofJuly
PETER:. And if it means
l must prepare
To shoulder burdens
with a worried air
ALL:. l'll never grow up
Never grow up, never grow up
Not me.
Not l.
BOYS:. Not me.
PETER:. So there.
PETER:. Never gonna be a man
ALL:. l won't
PETER:. Like to see somebody ty
ALL:. And make me
PETER:. Anyone who wants to ty
PETER:. Turn into a man
Catch me ifyou can
l won't grow up
BOYS:. l won't grow up
PETER:. Not a penny will l pinch
BOYS:. Not a penny will l pinch
PETER:. l will never grow
a mustache
BOYS:. l will never grow
PETER:. Or a fracction of an inch
BOYS:. Or a fracction of an inch
ALL:. 'Cause growing up
is awwfuller
Than all the awwful things
that everwere
l'll never grow up
Never grow up, never grow up
No, sir
[Laughing]
-l won't grow up
-l will never even ty
-l will do what Petertells me
PETER:. And l'll never
ask him why
BOYS:. And l'll never ask him why
-We won't grow up
-We will never grow a day
-And if someone tries to make us
-We will simply run away
-l won't grow up
-No, l promise that l won't
-l will stay a boy forever
PETER:. And be banished
if l don't
BOYS:. And be banished if l don't
'Cause Never Land will always be
The home ofyouth and joy
and liberrty
l'll never grow up
Never grow up, never grow up
-Not me
No, sir
Not me!
[Laughing]
[Pirates singing]
Bloody buccaneers
And each a murderous crook
Move,you spalpeen, move.
The Captain ordered us to tie
Tiger Lily to the tree...
and leave herthere
forthe wolves.
PoorTiger Lily
PIRRATE:. What was that?
Ahoy there,you lubbers!
lt is the Captain.
He must be close by.
We have tied the Indian
to the tree, Captain.
Set herfree.
SMEE:. Oh, but, Captain--
Cut her bonds
or l'll plunge me hook' in you.
Better do
what the Captain orders.
SMEE:. Aye, aye.
-Woo woo woo woo!
HOOK:. Ahoy there.
lt is the Captain.
Captain, is all well?
All is vey well.
Where's the redskin?
lt is all right, Captain.
We let her go.
Let her go?!
Ah! 'Twas your own orders,
Captain.
You called to us
to let her go.
Brimstone and gall!
What cozeny is here?
Ha ha ha ha!
Spirit that haunts this dark
forest tonight, dost hear me?
Odds, bobs, hammer, and tongs,
l hearyou.
Tell me, Spirit,
who are you?
PETER:. l am Hook.
HOOK:. Hook?
PETER:. Captain
ofthe Jolly Roger.
Then ifyou are Hook,
who am l?
A codfish.
A codfish?
Have we been captained
all this time by a codfish?
lt's lowering to our pride.
PIRRATES:. Yeah. Come on.
Don't leave me forthis!
Spirit ofthe forest,
have you another name?
PETER:. Yes.
ls it, uh,vegetable?
PETER:. No.
Um...Mineral?
Animal?
PETER:. Yes.
HOOK:. Ah!
Have you anothervoice?
PETER:. Yes.
[Singing operatically]
La la, la la, la la la
La la la, la la
lt's a lady.
[Peter singing operatic scales]
[Singing in Italian]
lt's a beautiful lady!
[Singing]
Oh, my mysterious lady
What is your name?
PETER:. La
Oh, my mysterious lady,
from whence have you came?
PETER:. La
La la la la la la
Answer my plea
Whom may ye be?
La la la laaa la la la
La la, la la, la la, la la
La la, la la
PETER:. Aah!
Oh, my mysterious lady
What is your name?
Take offthat veil
And let me see yourface
Why hide your beauty
beneath that ton of lace?
Take offyourveil
And let me see yourface
Why hide your beauty
beneath that ton of lace?
Take offthe veil
and let me see yourface
Why hide your beauty
beneath that ton of lace?
Oh!
[Singing]
What's your secret?
PETER:. La la la la la la
HOOK:. Tell your secret
Speak, oh, speak,
oh, speak, l pray
Oh,tell me
oh,tell me your'name
HOOK:. Ow!
[Peter singing operatic scales]
La la la
HOOK:. Perfavore.
[Peter singing in Italian]
HOOK:. Misericordia.
[Hook playing accompaniment]
[Peter singing with flute]
PIRRATES:. Aah!
PETER:. Aah!
PETER:. Hey!
PIRRATES:. Hey!
PETER:. Aah!
PETER:. Yoo-hoo!
PIRRATES:. Aah!
lNDIANS:. Woo woo woo woo!
TIGER LILY:. Yah!
PETER:. Don't shoot!
We're friends now.
BOYS:. Friends?
l saved Tiger Lily,'s life
in the forest
and she saved my life.
PETER:. No hands.
PETER:. Ha ha ha.
PETER:. Come on. Shake hands
with your new brothers.
Oh, don't be afraid.
Tiger Lily, let's smoke-um
peace pipe.
[Peter singing] Uggawa, uggawa,
uggawa, uggawa,wah
[Tiger Lily singing] Uggawa,
uggawa, uggawa, uggawa,wah
Guggabug, guggabug,
guggabug, guggabug,wah,who
Uggabug, uggabug,
uggabug, uggabug
Ah bawabah
when we get in tro' uble
Ugga woo,
there's just one thing to do
PETER:. l'll just send
forTiger Lily
TIGER LILY:. l'll just send
for Peter Pan
We'll be coming
willy-nilly, Lily
Beat on the drum
And l will come
PETER:. And l will come and save
the brave, noble redskin
ALL:. Boom boom
INDIANS:. Uggawa, uggawa
Uggawa, uggawa,wah
BOYS AND WENDY:. Uggawa, uggawa,
uggawa, uggawa,wah
-Ug! Wah!
lbbity bibbity,
ibbity bibbity zab
Pufawop, pufawop, pufawop,
pufawop, bah wah
lbbity bibbity, ibbity bibbity
Zabil, zevil
ifwe come to'evil
Zabil, zoo
there's just one th'ing to do
We'll just send forTiger Lily
We'll just send for Peter Pan
We'll be coming
willy-nilly, Lily
Send up a flare
And l'll be there
You knowyou really got a friend
A friend
We'll be true blood brothers
to the end
Ugga ugga wah!
Ugga ugga wah! Ugga ugga wah!
Ugga ugga wah,wah,wah!
PETERAND TIGER LILY:. Uggawug,
uggawug, ugga wugga wah, hoo
ALL:. Uggawug, uggawug, uggawug,
ugga wugga wah, hoo
Boopadoop, boopadoop, boopadoop,
boopadoop,wah, hoo
PETERAND TIGER LILY:. Uggawug,
uggawug, uggawug, ugga wugga
PETER:. Ah,they'll wetcha
ifthe pirates getcha
And you're took
away by Captain Hook
ALL:. Hook!
TIGER LILY:. What will we do?
l'll just send forTiger Lily
l'll just send for Peter Pan
We'll be coming
willy-nilly, Lily
Send up a flare
And l'll be there
You knowyou really got a friend
ALL:. A friend!
We'll be true blood brothers
to the end
PETER:. Ah!
[All laughing]
WENDY:. Oh,Tiger Lily,
l'm sory, but l'll never get
my children to sleep...
after all this excitement.
TIGER LILY:. Oh,we go up
and keep guard.
We'll watch for pirates!
WENDY:. Now, children
make yourfather comforrta'ble.
Here's your chair, Father.
TWlNS:. Here are your slippers,
Father.
JOHN:. Here's your pipe, Father.
PETER:. Thankyou.
MICHAEL:. Here's your paper,
Daddy.
WENDY:. Now, let's go inside
and get washed up.
They are sweet,
aren't they, Peter?
There's nothing better
than sitting by the fireside...
with the little ones close by...
Mother.
MICHAEL:. Peter?
Don't you think
l'm too big for a cradle?
[Peter imitating Father]
A little less noise there.
What is it, Peter?
lt's only pretend, isn't it,
that l'm theirfather?
Oh,yes, Peter.
But they are ours,
yours and mine.
But not really.
Well, no
not ifyou don't'wish it.
l don't.
Peter.
What are your exacct feelings
for me?
Those of a devoted son,Wendy.
l thought so.
You're so strange.
Tinker Bell's just the same.
There's something
she wants to be to me
but she says it's not my mother.
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
l almost agree with her.
BOY:. We're all ready
for bed now, Mother.
TOOTLES:. l brushed
my teeth.
WENDY:. Well,then
into your beds you g'o.
WENDY:. Peter?
Do you know a lullaby
to sing to our children?
Lullaby?
Lullaby.
l think so.
Sometimes, late at night...
l seem to remember...
[Singing]
Once upon a time and long ago
l heard someone singing
soft and low
Nowwhen day is done
and night is near
l recall this song
l used to hear
My child, my vey own
Don't be afraid
you're not alone'
Sleep until the dawn,
for all is well
Long ago,this song
was sung to me
Now it's just a distant melody
Somewhere from the past
l used to know
Once upon a time and long ago
Wendy?
WENDY:. Yes, Michael?
l'm homesick. l want to go home.
JOHN:. So do l.
Yes. We must go home.
Perhaps Motherwill be
in half mourning by this time.
TTWIN:. Oh,Wendy,
you're not leaving us?
l must. At once.
Peter, l appeal to you to make
the necessay arrangements.
All right. Tink,you are
to get up at once...
and take Wendy on a journey
across the sea.
[Tinker Bell tinkles]
WENDY:. Oh, dear ones...
lfyou come with me,
l feel almost sure my mother
and fatherwould adopt you.
BOYS:. Hooray!
Can we go, Peter?
PETER:. All right.
BOYS:. Oh, boy!
Then put your beds away
quickly...
and be sure to bring the baby
clothes you were lost in.
Peter, l'm going to give you
your medicine...
before yourjourney.
Get yourthings, Peter.
l'm not going with you,Wendy.
Oh,yes, Peter.
-No.
-But why not?
l don't want to grow up
and learn about solemn things.
l want to always be
a little boy and have fun.
No one's gonna catch me
and make me a man.
-We're ready to go now.
-We've got our clothes.
WENDY:. Peter isn't
coming with us.
BOYS:. Oh...Peterwon't come?
Then, Peter,we won't leave you.
lt's all right.
lfyou find your mothers,
l hope you'll like them.
BOYS:. We're not gonna go
without you.
PETER:. Now, no fuss, no
blubbering. Just say good-bye.
[lndians shouting]
PETER:. Shh! It's over.
WENDY:. But who won?
PETER:. Ifthe Indians have won
they'll beat the tom-tom.
Listen.
[Steady beat]
PETER:. The Indians have won!
An Indian vicctoy!
ALL:. Yay!
PETER:. You'll be
perrfecctly safe now,Wendy.
Tiger Lily will escorrt you
through the forest.
And, um...here's some faiy dust
to help you fly.
Good-bye, boys.
JOHN:. Good-bye, Peter.
MICHAEL:. And thankyou.
Bye, Peter.
-Bye, Peter.
Good-bye, Peter.
Bye, Peter.
WENDY:. Peter.
That's your medicine,you know.
Hmm. l won't forget it.
Peter...lfyou come for me
once a year,
l'll do your spring-cleaning.
Will you come?
lfyou like.
You won't forget?
Peter...
lf another little girl,
one youngerthan l...
[Sobbing]
Oh, Peter
how l wish l could take you up
and squinch you.
Yes, l know.
Well, good-bye.
Wendy?
[Pirates laughing]
HOOK:. Take them all to the ship.
The boys we'll make
walkthe plank.
And Wendy will be our mother.
[Pirates laughing]
SMEE:. But what about Peter?
HOOK:. This...for Peter.
[Smee gasps]
-Poison!
-Aye.
Ha ha! He's doomed.
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
What?
ls anyone there?
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
What? The Indians
have been defeated?
And Wendy and the boys have been
captured by the pirates?
l'll rescue her!
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
What? Oh,that's just
my medicine.
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
Poison?
Nonsense.
Who could have poisoned it?
l promised Wendy to take it,
and l'm going to,
aS SOOn aS
l've sharpened my dagger.
Tink!
You've drunk my medicine.
[Tinker Bell tinkling weakly]
What's the matterwith you?
lt was poisoned!
You drank it to save my life!
Tink!
DearTink!
You're dying.
[Tinker Bell tinkling weakly]
Your light is growing faint,
and if it goes out,
that means you're dead.
Yourvoice is so low
l can scarcely hear
what you're saying.
You think...
You thinkthat...
That what,Tink?
[Tinker Bell tinkling weakly]
That you could get well again...
if children believed in fairies.
Do you believe?
Oh, please, please believe!
lfyou believe,
whereveryou are,
clap your hands,
and she'll hearyou.
Clap!
Clap! Don't let Tink die! Clap!
[Tinker Bell tinkling]
She's getting better.
Clap! Clap!
She's getting stronger!
Oh! She's all well now!
Oh,thankyou!
Thankyou. Thankyou.
And nowto rescue Wendy!
NARRRATOR:. It is night
in Never Land.
Not farfrom
the Mermaids' Lagoon,
one green light
squinting over Kidd's Creek,
which is nearthe mo,uth
ofthe Pirate River
marks where the ship
The Jolly Roger lies at anchor.
A rakish-looking craft,
fore to the hull
she lies low in the darkwater
wrapped in the blanket
ofthe night,
a cannibal ofthe seas.
How still the night is.
Nothing sounds alive.
Now is the hourwhen child,ren
in their homes are abed
their lips bright-browned
with a good-night chocolate...
and theirtongues drowsily
searching for belated crumbs...
housed insecurely
on their shining cheeks.
Compare with them,the captive
children on this boat!
Split me infinitives,
but 'tis me hour oftriumph--
Peter killed at last...
and all the boys
about to walkthe plank.
At last, l've reached me peak!
l'm the greatest villain
of all time!
HOOK:. Who was Bluebeard?
PIRRATES:. Nobody!
HOOK:. Who was Nero?
HOOK:. Who was Jackthe Ripper?
PIRRATES:. Nobody!
HOOK:. Ha ha ha!
[Singing] Who's the swiniest
swine in the world?
[Pirates singing]
Captain Hook, Captain Hook
HOOK:. Who's the dirrtiest dog
in this wonderrful world?
PIRRATES:. Captain Hook,
Captain Hook
Captain ofvillainy,
murder, and loot
Eagerto kill any who
says that his hook isn't cute
SMEE:. It's cute!
HOOK:. Ha ha ha!
[Singing] Who's the slimiest
rat in the pack?
[Pirates singing]
Captain Hook, Captain Hook
HOOK:. Who's unlovable?
PIRRATES:. You
HOOK:. Who's unlivable?
HOOK:. Whose behavior
is quite unforgivable?
PIRRATES:. You
HOOK:. Who would stoop
To the lowest and meanest
oftricks in the book?
PIRRATES:. Tricks in the book
Blimey, slimy Captain Hook
Captain Hook, Captain Hook
Captain Hook
Aah!
PIRRATES:. Yay!
-Captain.
-Oh,well.
PIRRATES:. Yay!
All morrtals envy me,
yet betterfor Hookto have had
Iess ambition.
Oh,fame,fame
thou glittering bau'ble.
ln searching forthee,
what fame have l not lost?
[Cloth ripping]
No little children love me.
l'm told that they,play
at Peter Pan
and the strongest always chooses
to be Peter.
They force the baby to be Hook.
[Sniffs]
The baby.
That's where the canker gnaws.
l'm told they find Smee lovable.
How can l break it to him
that they find him lovable?
No!
Bicarbonate of soda, No!
Not even--
[Cloth ripping]
Smee.
HOOK:. All in one piece?
PIRRATES:. Yay!
HOOK:. Who's the swiniest?
PIRRATES:. Swiniest!
HOOK:. The doggiest?
The slimiest?
[Singing] Who's the creepiest
creep in the world?
[Pirates singing]
Captain Hook, Captain Hook
HOOK:. Who's dispensable?
PIRRATES:. You
HOOK:. Reprehensible?
HOOK:. Whose behavior is quite
indefensible?
PIRRATES:. You
HOOK:. Who's the crawlingest
Cruelest, crummiest
crookedest crook?
PIRRATES:. Crookedest crook
What a prize,what a joy
Mrs. Hook's little baby boy
The scourge ofthe sea
Just little old me.
Captain
Hook, Hook, Hook
ALL:. Yo-ho!
HOOK:. Wah!
Fetch in the prisoners...
and bring up their mother!
[Pirates laughing and shouting]
[Tootles screaming]
Ha ha ha ha!
Well, me proud beauty,
you're about to see
your children walkthe plank!
BOYS:. No!
WENDY:. Are they to die?
HOOK:. Ha ha ha ha! They are.
[Pirates laughing]
Silence, all,for a mother's
Iast words to her sons.
These are my last words--
HOOK:. Thankyou. Take them in
and fetch in the plank!
[Pirates shouting]
[Tick-tock]
HOOK:. Smee! Smee! Smee!
SMEE:. What's the matter?
HOOK:. The croc! The croc!
Hide me, Smee! Hide me!
-l'll hide you!
-Smee.
[Ticking]
Shh!
PIRRATE:. Aah!
[Peter crows]
HOOK:. What was that?
What was that?
Black Bill's dead! Stabbed!
PIRRATES:. Dead? Stabbed?
The cabin's black as a pit.
There's somethin,g terrible
in there
the thing you heard a-crowin'!
Cecco, go back and fetch me out
that doodle-doo.
No, Captain! No! No!
Cecco.
No, Captain! Don't make me
go back in there! Ooh!
l'll go! l'll go!
CECCO:. Aah!
[Peter crowing]
'Sdeath!
Will no one fetch me out
that doodle-doo?
Wait till Cecco comes out.
PIRRATES:. Yeah!
Did l hearyou volunteer,
Starkey?
STARKEY:. No, by thunder!
HOOK:. Well, me hook
thinks you did.
l think it would be advisable
Starkey,to humorthe hook.
STARKEY:. l'll swing
before l go in there!
PIRRATES:. Yeah!
HOOK:. Mutiny?
HOOK:. Then Starkey is the
ringleader! Come on, Starkey.
[Starkey screaming]
[Splash]
Any other gentlemen
suggest mutiny?
l'll go in and fetch out
the doodle-doo meself.
Someone put out the light!
-Someone?
-Where's Cecco?
HOOK:. He's as dead as Bill.
-Poor Cecco.
-lt's Hook's fault!
[Eveyone yelling]
l have a notion.
Why not send them inside?
Let them find
the doodle-doo.
They kill him,
so much the better.
lf he kills them
we're none the wo'rse.
[Pirates yelling in agreement]
Oh! The doodle-doo's
killed them all!
PIRRATE:. The ship's bewitched!
ALL:. The ship's bewitched!
-The ship's bewitched!
HOOK:. There's a Jonah aboard.
PETER:. Aye, aye!
There's a Jonah aboard!
PETER:. It's a man with a hook!
PIRRATES:. Yeah!
HOOK:. No, no, lads!
It's a girl!
[Pirates yelling]
HOOK:. Take herto the plank!
SMEE:. Aye,to the plank.
PETER:. To the plank!
[Pirates yelling]
[Wendy screaming]
There's none can save you now,
missy!
PETER:. There is one!
HOOK:. Who's that?
Peter Pan,the avenger!
HOOK:. Have at him!
ALL:. No!
PETER:. Wait, boys!
This man is mine!
BOYS:. Yay!
So, Pan,this is all your doing.
Aye, Hook. This is all my doing.
Proud and impudent youth,
prepare to meet thy doom!
Dark and sinister man
have at thee!
lt isn't fair.
l say as though it were
my last breath, it isn't fair.
'Tis a fiend
that's fighting me.
Pan,who and what arrt thou?
l am youth!
l am joy!
l am freedom!
[Boys cheering]
l'll blow up the ship!
[Eveyone yelling]
[All screaming]
HOOK:. In two minutes,the ship
will be blown to pieces.
Get back,you purelings born.
l'll showyou the road
to dusty death.
There will be a holocaust
of children.
There's something great
to the idea.
Aah!
The croc! The croc! The croc!
Pan, no words of mine...
can express
me utter contempt foryou.
[Splash]
[Explosion]
[All singing]
Yo-ho,yo-ho
The wonderrful Peter Pan
TIGER LILY:. Peter Pan is the sun
and the moon and the stars!
[All cheering]
TIGER LILY:. Peter Pan
is the lamp and the light!
[All cheering]
TIGER LILY:. Peter Pan is
the bravest and strongest...
of all boys!
[All cheering]
PETER:. Yes, l know.
l don't say it to boast.
lt's because
l cannot tell a lie.
[Peter singing]
l gotta crow
[All crowing]
l'm just the cleverest fella
'twas ever my forrtune to know
[All crowing]
l give the sign,
and the sunlight will shine
And the forest will grow
ALL:. Ooh!
PETER:. And the rivers
will flow
l gotta crow
[Crowing]
Away with them!
LIZA:. Oh, Peter.
You are the most wonderrful boy
in the whole world.
ls there anything
that you couldn't do?
Nothing.
Peter,will you teach me
howto crow?
Sure.
[Peter singing]
You do it,too
-Me?
-Yes.
And ifyou choose
You will find such unusual
things you can do
[Liza crows weakly]
You're getting warm
But your mouth should be forming
a happier ''Err''
LIZA:. Err!
PETER:. Err!
PETER:. Ha ha!
[Peter singing]
Don't be such a sissy
Prim and prissy
Let out a crow
You've nothing to fear
Come and whisper it
close to my ear
Err err.
[Louder]
Err Err!
[Crows loudly]
PETER:. Good!
[Singing]
And nowwe can crow
[Liza crows]
Just like a rooster
we'll be our own boos'ter
And let out a crow
[Crowing]
We'll give the proudest
and gayest and loudest
Of crows that we know
[Liza crowing]
Eveybody let go
And crow
[Crowing]
[Nana whimpering]
Oh, Nana, dear
it breaks my hearrt'...
to see you turn down their beds
night after night.
But they'll never come back.
Never.
No, Nana! Don't disturb
the master.
He uses your house as his home
out of remorse.
l'll wake him
when it's time for his dinner.
[Children singing]
Tender shepherd,tender shepherd
Let me help you count your sheep
One in the meadow,two--
[All talking excitedly]
A little less noise there
please. A little less noise'.
Father, Father,the children
have come home!
-Michael!
-Oh, Papa!
FATHER:. John! Wendy!
MOTHER:. Liza!
MOTHER:. Who are they?
WENDY:. They're a few more of us.
Won't you adopt them, Father?
FATHER:. Adopt them?
What, all six ofthem?
WENDY:. Please, Father?
MOTHER:. Oh, George, don't you
thinkwe could manage?
FATHER:. Well,what's another
six or seven?
[Children cheering]
[Boys singing]
We will grow up
[Family singing]
They will grow up
BOYS:. We will mind
our p's and q's
FAMILY:. They will mind
their p's and q's
BOYS:. We will never be a bother
FAMILY:. They will never
be a bother
BOYS:. And we'll always
shine our shoes
FATHER:. To think
of all those shoes.
FAMILY:. We have no room
to spare, it's true
BOYS:. But, oh,what of it?
We'll pretend we do
We're gonna grow up
Gonna grow up,
gonna grow up
FATHER:. Like me
BOYS:. Like l
BOYS:. Like me
FATHER:. Now, good cleanup.
To the tub!
[Boys cheering]
FATHER:. To the tub. Come on.
MOTHER:. It's time
for Michael's bath.
MOTHER:. Come,John.
You won't forget
to come for me, Peter?
Please. Please, don't forget.
NARRRATOR:. That was
the last time...
the girl Wendy
ever saw Peter.
Years came and went without
bringing the careless boy.
Wendy tried,for Peter's sake,
not to have growing pains,
but,you see, all children
except Peter grow up.
Then...
One night, a long time after,
when it was once more
spring-cleaning time...
the stars blew open
the nursey windows.
Hello,Wendy.
Peter!
Where's John?
WENDY:. Ha! He's not here now.
ls Michael asleep?
WENDY:. Yes. No!
That's not Michael.
-ls it a new one?
-Yes.
-Boy or girl?
-lt's a girl.
-What's her name?
-Jane.
Jane.
WENDY:. Peter.
Are you expeccting me
to fly away with you?
Of course.
That's why l came.
Have you forgotten
it's spring-cleaning time?
l can't come.
l've forgotten howto fly.
-l'll teach you again.
-No, Peter!
Don't waste
yourfaiy dust on me.
What's the matter?
l'm old, Peter.
l'm ever so much more than 20.
l grew up a long time ago.
You promised not to.
l couldn't help it.
l'm a married woman now.
No,you're not. No,you're not!
Yes, and the little girl
in the bed is my child.
[Sobbing]
No, she's not! No, she's not!
MAN:. Mother! Mother!
[Peter sobbing]
Boy,why are you cying?
l'm Peter Pan.
JANE:. Yes. l know.
l came to take my--
mother...backto Never Land.
Yes, l know.
l've been waiting foryou.
-For me?
-Oh,yes, Peter.
Would you teach me howto fly?
Do you know any stories?
JANE:. Oh, l know
Iots of stories.
And--and would you
tuck me in at night...
and mend my pockets for me?
JANE:. Oh,yes, Peter!
Take me with you!
[Peter crowing]
First l must throw
the faiy dust on you!
Nowthink lovely,
wonderrful thoughts...
and up you go!
JANE:. How sweet!
PETER:. Ah, she's sweet!
She's sweet!
JANE:. Look at me! l'm flying!
PETER:. She's my mother.
Come on,Jane.
WENDY:. No! No!
JANE:. Please!
lt's just for spring-cleaning.
He wants me always
to do his spring-cleaning.
Oh, if only l could go with you.
You can't.
You see,Wendy...
You're too grown-up.
-Ready,Jane?
-Ready!
[Singing]
Then come with me
Where dreams are born
And time is never planned
Just think of lovely things
And your hearrt will fly on wings
Forever
ln Never Never Land
PETER:. Whee!
Come on!
Let's go to Never Never Land!
l'm flying!