[Man]
Petey.
[Man #2]
Where'd he go?
[Man]
He must have went that-a-way.
- [Man] Oh, Petey...
- [Owl Hooting]
I'll wring his neck!
[Man #2]
Petey!
- Petey.
- [Hooting Continues]
- [Whispering] Elliott, put me down.
- [Men Chattering, Indistinct]
- [Man] Look around.
- [Woman] Spread out!
They're getting closer.
We'd better hide.
- [Knocking]
- Stop swingin' your tail.
You almost knocked me down.
Here they come.
- Squish down!
- [Grass Rustling]
Petey.
- [Whispering] No, don't!
- [Rustling]
- [Thudding]
- [Screaming]
Somethin' hit me!
[Laughing Continues]
- What somethin'?
- If I knowed what somethin',
I wouldn't call it "somethin',"
I'd call it by its name.
I told you not
to swing your tail.
No, no, don't!
- [Thudding]
- [Screaming]
- [Squishing]
- [Laughing]
[Popping]
You done it!
[Laughing]
Dumb polecats!
Fightin' it out while that little snake
of a kid gets further away!
- [Screaming]
- Now why are y'all playing in the mud...
when you know we gotta
find that boy?
He's gotta be around
here somewhere. Find him!
Aw, Ma!
Why don't we...
just go on back home
and do some eatin'?
I'll tell ya... 'cause you
ain't gonna do no eatin'...
until you find
that little brat!
- [Rustling, Smacking]
- [Screaming] Who done that?
[Laughing]
Hey, Ma, why don't we just
get ourselves another orphan, huh?
Because I done paid
our last $50 for Pete,
plus 50 cents legal fees.
And we ain't got another
$50 plus legal, that's why!
Do ya understand? Well, here's
somethin' you will understand.
You're gonna have to start workin'
the farm with your own two hands...
less'n you spot
that little twerp.
- [Muttering]
- And get me out of
this here mud hole, Merle.
Come on. I'm stuck.
Don't just sit around in it.
Come on.
Get me out of here.
[Muttering]
[Together]
Petey! Petey!
[Ma]
Petey! Petey, Petey, Petey!
We better stay here.
I'm tired, aren't you?
[Speaking Gibberish]
- Good night, Elliott.
- [Gibberish]
[Munching,
Gulping]
[Swallowing]
[Gulping, Swallowing
Continue]
Hi, Elliott.
Oh, boy.
Those look good.
[Humming]
[Clicking Tongue]
I'm starved.
You sure changed my life.
- I didn't think I'd ever
be happy until I met you.
- Ooh. [Clicks Tongue]
Mm.
Whoops. One left.
You can have it.
- Thanks!
- [Gibberish]
Mm. You're
a good cook, Elliott.
- [Gibberish]
- [Laughing]
I look in your eyes
and you whisper sweetly
[Dragon "Singing"]
We don't match in size
but we fit so neatly
[Dragon "Scatting"]
It's nice waking up
when you're close beside me
Humming in my ear
- [Humming]
- You're joking!
- I can't believe it. You do?
- [Humming]
- I love you too
[Pete] Remember the night
when you first confided
[Elliott Humming]
And things went so right
that we both decided
[Elliott Humming]
Now we're together
and life is perfect
Don't ever disappear
- [Humming]
- Oh, really?
- Oh, you're just saying that.
- [Humming]
- Is it true?
- I love you too
We're walking down
a road of our own
Where rain can never fall
[Giggling]
I'm glad I don't
have to be alone
[Humming, Snorting]
You know what to say
when I want direction
[Elliott Humming]
You don't turn away
when I need protection
[Roaring]
[Sneezing]
Your voice is the sound
of an angel singing
Music I wait to hear
- [Humming, Crooning]
- Say it again!
- And again!
- [Crooning Continues]
- Everything seems so new!
[Crooning]
- I love you too
- [Crooning]
I love you too
[Crooning]
[Bass Crooning]
- I love you too
- [Crooning]
- [Chuckling]
- "Paz-a-muh-quoddy."
Passamaquoddy.
Sounds like a nice place.
[Mumbling Gibberish]
Now, Elliott, we want the people
of Passamaquoddy to like us.
- Don't we?
- [Gibberish]
I mean, you're kind of big,
and we don't want to scare anyone.
- Do we?
- [Growling, Clicking Tongue]
So you better not
show yourself, understand?
[Gasps, Sighs]
I know how ya feel, but you'll
have to make yourself invisible.
[Humming]
Nope.
- [Panting]
- Uh-uh.
- Nope. [Giggling]
- [Gibberish]
- Nope.
- [Moaning]
- [Panting]
- I'm sorry, but
the whole thing has to go.
Behave yourself, Elliott.
[Elliott Muttering]
[Muttering Continues]
[Meowing]
[Sighs]
- Hi!
- [Clattering]
- [Whinnying]
- [Shouting]
I told ya
not to fool around.
Get on the sidewalk
and stay next to me.
[Banging]
[Squishing]
Look out, Elliott!
- Oops. Clumsy, clumsy, clumsy.
- [All Laughing]
I'm sorry, real sorry.
I was telling my dragon
not to bump his head on the sign.
All right, smarties.
Into your classroom.
March, march, march
march, march!
[Teacher]
March! March!
How dare you?
I mean, how dare you lie and try
to embarrass me in front of my students.
- I wasn't lying.
- That's a lie on top of a lie.
Ugh! You're not
one of my pupils.
What school are you
playing hooky from?
- I-I don't go to school.
- Ah! I knew it.
That's just
what this town needs.
- [Elliott Giggling]
- [Teacher] Another ignoramus.
- No, Elliott.
- [Ripping]
[All Laughing]
You disgusting
little street urchin!
You could be locked up for this.
Where's the sheriff?
Gentlemen,
I propose to say...
Passamaquoddy's
a beautiful community...
where the sun always rises
and the sun always sets.
- That's very deep.
- Elliott...
It's a place of serenity
and security,
where the unexpected
never happens.
- Ow!
- [Elliott Grumbles, Growls]
- It's okay, Elliott.
- [Astonished Mumbling]
It seems to say,
"Welcome!"
You-You absolute oaf.
You-You idiot!
- No, come, come.
- Look, it was that kid that pushed me.
He pulled off
Miss Taylor's petticoat.
- He walked through my cement
with his big feet.
- He scared my horse, Victoria.
Let's get out
of here, Elliott.
- We-Well, where is this person?
- Th-There he goes!
- Well, detain him. Detain him.
- [Crowd Shouting]
[Chuckling]
- Elliott...
- Uh-oh.
- You spoiled everything.
- [Gibberish]
Darn you, Elliott.
I told you to behave.
[Sorrowful Gibberish]
[Sighs]
Scallops.
And some oysters.
And...
Oh, hello there,
little boy.
- Hi.
- [Sniffing]
- [Puzzled Gibberish]
- Hey! Hey, you look terrible.
- Whoopee!
Hey, your friend's...
turned green.
- [Gibberish]
- If I didn't know any better,
I'd say he was a dragon.
- A drag-drag...
- [Growls]
Dragon!
- Elliott, didn't I tell you that...
- [Frantic Gibberish]
- [Loud Chattering]
- [Screaming, Indistinct]
[Gibberish]
Oh! Gentlemen...
A dragon, a dragon
I swear I saw a dragon
A green and seething
fire-breathing monster is in sight
With eyes of red a lion's head
and wings as dark as night
Oh, he has a jaw of gleaming teeth
He's 50 feet in height
It's true, it's true
Oh, what are we to do
He'll break us all in two
Oh, he's comin' in
His great big fin
is right against the door
So board up all the windows
And get down on the floor
Has anybody seen my dad?
Nora, please,
my child, come in.
- Get off that street.
- What's the matter?
- Worst thing I ever saw
in my life out on the street.
- What was it?
- I don't want to tell you for
fear it'll scare you to death!
- Scare me.
A dragon, a dragon
I swear I saw a dragon
His tail lashing, he'll be
smashing every shop in town
With scaly feet he'll crack the street
and tear the steeple down
It's not some loony dream
I heard a scream from Sheriff Brown
It's true, it's true
Oh, what are we to do
- It's true, it's true
- Old Lampie's in a stew
A dragon, a dragon
I swear there was a dragon
You're off your hinges
All those binges put you in a haze
You crazy fools
It's all your doggone fault
he's in a daze
Let go of me, let go of me
and mend your wicked ways
- [Braying]
- Aah!
What makes you think there
ever was, there never was
There never, never, ever was
a dragon, dragon, dragon
Dragon, dragon
dragon, dragon, dragon
[Grumbling,
Indistinct]
- Now, why don't you just calm down?
- I seen his face.
If you wanna
call it a face.
It was this close to me.
Why don't you
lie down, Dad? Come on.
You know what else?
It started to smile at me.
- Well, did you smile back?
- I didn't have time to smile.
I was too busy running.
And you know...
And you know what else?
There was this boy with it.
And he wasn't afraid.
- This boy...
- Lie down.
[Clicking, Mumbling]
[Gibberish]
[Humming]
We're in a lot of trouble,
and it's all your fault.
[Sighing]
[Inhaling]
[Exhaling]
[Inhaling, Exhaling]
I don't wanna play.
You did everything wrong
is Passamaquoddy.
Now everybody hates us.
I don't know whether
you're good for me...
or bad.
[Sniffles]
I'm sorry, Elliott.
I didn't really mean that.
It's just
I don't know what to do,
and I'm scared.
[Sniffles]
[Groans]
Hello in there!
[Whispering]
Get back!
[Grumbling, Grunting]
Hi.
- What are you doing here?
- Oh, just playing tic-tac-toe.
[Chuckling] Well, this isn't exactly
the best place for tic-tac-toe.
The tide's coming in.
High water reaches this cave sometimes.
You better
head for home.
You're not from
Passamaquoddy, are you?
Nope.
Just sort of... traveling.
Where are your parents?
Where are you staying?
- What's your name?
- Pete.
I'm Nora, and I have to get back
on watch, up in the lighthouse.
There's chowder on the stove,
if you'd like some.
Wh-What's the matter?
It's a hand, not a shark.
You can finish that chowder...
if you'd like.
[Exhales, Sniffles]
Oh, I forgot something.
Be right back.
I forgive you, Elliott.
- [Giggles]
- [Sighs, Chuckles]
Stay here till I see what
it's like up in the lighthouse.
Woo-woo-woo-woo!
The Gogans own me,
I guess.
They said it was against the law
for me to ever leave them.
Where did you get
that bruise?
Mr. Gogan. I was milking the cow,
and I missed the bucket.
- Had he done that before?
- All the time.
The first time I ran away,
the orphan home sent me back.
This time,
I'll just keep running.
Well, you'll be safe here.
Nora, no one's ever been this nice
to me. I'll always remember it.
Pete, why don't you
sleep here tonight?
We'll figure out
what to do tomorrow.
Okay?
Wonderful.
I've got work to do. Come on.
Are you anybody's mother?
I'm not even anybody's wife.
But you're gonna get
married now, aren't you?
[Scoffs] I'm already married
to this lighthouse.
- Who's that?
- Paul.
- Is he part of your family?
- He almost was.
- How can someone almost
be part of a family?
- We were going to be married.
How come you weren't?
Well, as far as we know,
his ship was headed for a storm.
They were never heard from again.
That was a year ago.
He'll come back.
I tell myself
the same thing every day,
standing up there
watching for ships on the horizon.
[Sighs] Time I should be thinking of
other things, so they tell me.
I'll have to ask
Elliott about Paul.
He has a way
of knowing things.
Who's Elliott?
- My dragon.
- Dragon?
[Gasps]
So you're the boy with the dragon.
- Yup.
- Where is he?
- Down in the cave.
- That's interesting.
I've never known anyone with a dragon.
What does he look like?
Just a plain,
ordinary dragon.
How plain?
How ordinary?
He has the head of a camel
The neck
of a crocodile
It sounds rather strange.
He's both
a fish and a mammal
And I hope
he'll never change
'Cause it's not easy
to find someone who cares
It's not easy
to find magic in pairs
I'm glad I found him
I love him
I won't let him
get away
'Cause it's not easy
You say
the head of a camel
- The neck of a crocodile
- And the ears of a cow!
It's clear that friends
can be different
Yes, I understand you now
[Together] It's not easy
to find someone who cares
It's not easy
to find magic in pairs
Now that you have him
Hold him
Treasure him
from day to day
It's so easy
Life is lollipops
and raindrops
With the one
you love
Someone you can
always be with
Argue and agree with
Climb the highest tree with
[Together]
It's not easy
To share somebody's dream
It gets easy
when you work as a team
You've got to tend it
Fan it
That's what
I plan to do
Oh, I had one friend
by my side
Now I have two
Him and you
Him and me
[Together]
And it's so easy
[Humming]
- Good morning, sir.
- Good morning, son.
- Nice to see you again.
- Ah. Thank you.
Aah!
- It's you!
- What's the matter?
It's you.
The boy with the dragon.
Yes, sir.
[Screaming]
Dad! Dad, what is it?
- The boy with the dragon.
- I know, I know. Now, just take it easy.
You saw it.
You saw it?
I didn't actually see it,
but I know what it looks like.
- But wha...
- We'll talk about it later.
O-One thing I must know:
It isn't in the lighthouse, is it?
- No, Elliott's down in the cave.
- Oh, Ellio...
Elliott? Lt... It even has a name.
There's nothing
to get upset about.
You're right. Right, there's
nothing to get upset about.
Nothing. No, why should I get upset?
I should be happy.
L... I should be happy! I'll go down
to the saloon and I'll tell the boys.
I'll say, "Boys, here it is."
And then hear the apologies. [Laughs]
Elliott'll be happy
to do it for you, sir.
Good boy. Good lad.
Just you and me and Elliott.
We'll go into the saloon.
Oh. Elliott...
He won't... won't start
to scratch or...
or fight, or set anything
on fire, will he?
- Well, he's sort of...
- Sort of what?
- Unpredictable.
- Now, don't do anything with Elliott.
Wh-Why don't you
leave him where he is?
- It's too dangerous
to take him into town.
- It's dangerous.
Now, I don't want either one of you
to say a word about Elliott...
- to anyone, do you understand,
- No. No. Yes!
Until we've
talked this over.
Now, let's all have breakfast. The lamp
has to be polished, the lens cleaned,
and I want to take Pete
to buy new clothes.
Yes, well, clean Elliott
and eat the lamp.
I mean, we'll...
clea-clean the lamp.
[Muttering] Elliott!
The name's Elliott. Did you hear that?
Doc Terminus is comin'!
Are they still after us?
We lost 'em.
Good.
- Passamaquoddy ahead, ahoy!
- What?
Pass-a-ma-quoddy ahead, ahoy!
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes.
[Dog Barking]
- [Screams] Slow down!
- My fence!
Throw out the anchor!
Since we all concur, gentlemen,
I suggest that we adjourn.
[Screams]
[Townspeople Screaming]
- Watch Bones.
- Get him off of me! Get him off!
I think they remember us.
Uh-oh. I think
I remember them.
- Just act normal.
- I am acting normal. I'm ready to run.
- Quick, what's the name
of this town again?
- Passamaquoddy.
- "Quassama" what?
- Passamaquoddy!
Got it. How wonderful to see
your smiling faces again.
All of you.
I-I've never known
such warmth,
such welcome,
such loving hospitality.
Get out, ya quack!
And don't bring those
phony remedies here again.
Go on back where
you belong: Jail.
- [Booing]
- Thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
I sense enthusiasm,
I sense loving response,
and that's why I feel
that this is my home...
away from home.
I've been bringing cures
from Pilgrim Heights to Provincetown
Treated rabid fever
down on Queen Anne Road
Gout or gastritis
Mumps or bronchitis
Bites and burns and blue abrasions
Got a pill for all occasions
Little Sipowissot
was so nice to visit
And Scraggy Neck
is lovely to recall
I took your drug for losing weight
and now I'm a blob
But now there's so much
more of you to love
I wiped out impetigo
on the banks of Buttermilk
Flu is under firm control
in Powder Hole
Terminus potions
tablets and lotions
Major news in modern science
Step up now and join my clients
Spent a day in Buzzard's Bay
They couldn't keep me there
Even turned away
from Kingdom Hall
They probably
threw you out
[Laughing]
They probably threw...
My hair was gray and thanks to you
it turned into pink
But that color.
It's so becoming.
- Aah!
- We're gonna wash your phony
tonics right down the sink
Wait. Listen.
My specialties are
audiology, mycology,
serology, teratology,
embryology, psychology, zoology...
and any other "ology"
you can think of!
My friends, you're not
giving me a chance!
[Sobs] I brought all these
medicines back from Paris.
- France.
- [Crowd] Ohh!
Honi soit qui mal y pense:
Shamed be he who thinks evil of it.
And that's what the medical
business is all about, folks:
People helping people.
You should all have help.
Gadzooks!
What have we here?
Oh, Doctor, Doctor, Doctor.
[Panting]
All I'm askin' for
is a miracle.
All he wants
is a miracle, folks.
How can I deny him? If he's willing
to pay for it, he's gonna get it.
- Any price.
- One dollar, sir.
[Drumroll]
[Drumroll Ends]
- I trust him.
- I believe in the Doc.
I'd put my life
in his hands.
My friends you've seen a miracle
and you'll see many more
People will come pourin' in
from land and sea
We'll have centers for testing
Let's start investing
- Keep those dimes
and dollars mounting
- I'll collect
I'll do the counting
Everyone who lives here
will be strong and healthy
You'll be getting richer
by the day
- Hurray!
- Hear them acclaim us
This town will be famous
The whole wide world
will look at us and say
It's
Pardonmaquassy
No.
Paquamassady, no, no
Passamamassy
Quadamapoddy
Passamadaddy
Quadampassy
Quadamaddy, Deppadaddy
Depamassy, Quadapassy
Passapassapassaquassa
- [Bawling]
- "Quoddy."
[Crowd]
Passamaquoddy
I know.
Pete, if you bring up the oil can,
we'll be ready for the night.
Sure. Before that, I'd like
to show Elliott my new suit.
No! No, no.
You can't bring Elliott up here.
Government regulation 302
states that...
no dragons
shall be allowed...
on the premises of
the United States' lighthouses.
Now, go on down and get
the oil so I can mark it up
in the log that you did that.
Okay. Nora, first can
I bring Paul's picture down to Elliott?
Then he can start
looking for Paul.
All right.
[Door Opens,
Closes]
- Thanks, Dad.
- For what?
- For making believe about
the dragon and going along with it.
- Making...
It means a lot to Pete.
Sort of a family he made up.
I'm not making believe.
I actually saw it.
And I haven't been
the same since!
Go to the cave; you'd see
it too, and your eyes would...
- [Popping] pop right out!
- [Scoffs]
I was there.
I saw nothing!
Dad, be realistic.
Oh, you wanna be realistic.
Let's talk about how realistic you are.
Here you are, waiting for
someone to come back that just
ain't gonna come back, Nora.
And if waitin' for over
a year hasn't told ya nothin',
then you're not the one to talk
about being realistic, are you?
Honey, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean that.
I'm going down
to the hardware store.
[Humming, Panting]
Hi, Elliott!
How do you like my new suit?
Wow!
[Panting]
[Gibberish]
And new shoes too.
Look at the way they shine!
[Laughing]
Nora's so nice to me,
I want us to do something for her.
I want you to concentrate
on finding Paul for Nora.
This is what he looks like.
[Gibberish]
Remember his face.
Try real hard.
Hmm.
[Gibberish]
Better go now.
- [Kissing]
- Aww.
- See ya tomorrow.
- [Whistling]
[Giggling]
I've had nothing,
nothing but bad luck in this burg.
Hey! Ooh...
- I'm sorry, Doc.
- You see what I mean, hmm?
Doc, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it, Hoagy.
- I di... Can I buy everybody a round?
- Yeah.
Huh? Well... Hey, 'cause,
Doc, I gotta talk to you. Okay?
- Sit down.
- May I? Thank you.
Hey, you're a ma...
You're a man of science, ain't you?
A man of science, yes.
Yes, I am.
With degrees from
the Royal Medical College, London.
- Huh?
- The Gleinen Einen Peitzen in Vienna.
- Oh!
- And the Moulin Rouge in Paris.
Oh. You know
anything about dragons?
Of course I do. I see them in all
the big cities going down the streets,
with that funny little walk, wearing
bright colors, fluttering around...
No, no, no. I'm talkin'
about a real dragon.
Real dragon. With fire...
fire coming out of his mouth.
And he's got real wings.
Uh, you need
a veterinarian. Hmm?
- Why do you ask?
- I saw one.
Is it sitting at the next table?
Hmm? [Chuckling]
I tell ya, I saw a real dragon
yesterday afternoon.
He's owned... owned
by a young boy...
by the name of Pete.
You are trying to tell me
that there is a dragon here...
- In Passamacracka? Yeah.
- "Quoddy."
- Yes.
- I told you this was a rotten town.
Well, in my educated
opinion, sir,
- I think you've been up
in your lighthouse too long.
- Huh?
Wait. Wait, listen. What if what
I just told you was true?
In my scientific opinion,
the existence of a dragon...
would have an impact
of gigantic proportions.
Mythology and legend would
become history and science.
- One could really make
a quick buck with it.
- Well, I can prove it.
I can prove it!
H-His name is Elliott.
[Stammering] H-He's downstairs.
You could go and see him right now.
Unfortunately,
I cannot make it right now.
I have an appointment with a young lady
who's interested in a nursing career.
- Oh. Oh.
- I wanna see it.
- You wanna see it?
Well, see it you shall!
- Okay.
I tell you
that he's in there.
[Deep Sighing]
[Lips Smacking]
- Are you convinced?
- Absolutely.
- Well, let's get outta here.
- Wait a minute.
- Wait a minute. Wait a mi...
- I-I want to pet him.
Huh? You wa...
You want to pet him?
Are you crazy?
I know you ain't drunk.
No matter what
you see in here,
don't get scared.
[Footsteps]
Hey, I might as well
tell you straight off,
you're gonna see
a hideous monster.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes.
And it's big.
Fifty feet of terror!
Claws! Claws so sharp
they could tear a man to shreds.
- [Gulps]
- Eyes, evil eyes...
that can see
right through ya.
And a tail that's
so big and powerful,
it could destroy
the hull of a frigate!
It can wipe out
an entire crew...
with one swish
of his tail.
Face... Face so terrible,
it could turn
a man to stone,
a hero into a coward.
A flame so hot,
it could roast
a turkey!
And a mouth
so terrible,
it could devour a man and...
[Spits] spit him 20 leagues.
Stay close.
[Sputtering]
It's g-g-g-got m-me.
[Screams]
[Stammering]
Look at it!
[Screams]
[Both Screaming]
[Shuddering]
Them eyes are lookin'
right through us.
Look, don't ever let a dragon
know you're... you're afraid of him.
- [Whimpering]
- [Mumbling]
Stop-Stop shaking,
and-and smile.
Can't stop shaking,
and I am smiling.
[Stammering]
Hello. Hello. Hello, Elliott.
[Gibberish]
Aah! Hey,
see how smart he is?
- [Whimpering]
- He said hello to me.
Yeah! He likes me!
- Y-You do somethin' so he'll like you.
- L-Like me?
Yeah. Do somethin'
to make him like you.
- Huh?
- You think?
Elliott, would you...
would you like
a little b-belt, huh?
[Sniffing]
[Murmuring]
[Gulping]
Hmm?
[Rumbling]
[Hissing,
Roaring]
[Both Screaming]
[Screaming]
[Wheezing,
Panting]
[Humming]
[Panting]
Is it... Is it two parts fish oil
and three parts seawater...
and six parts
potato squeezings,
or is it only
two parts seawater, hmm?
Ten parts seawater, hmm? That much.
[Chuckles] No wonder they love it.
S-s-s-s-s-s...
- Saw it.
- Saw what?
El-El-El...
Dra-Dra-Dra...
What is an "el-el-el
dra-dra-dra," hmm?
Dr-Dr-Dragon.
[Panting]
I-I saw the dragon.
L-Lampie wasn't lying.
It's real. It belched flame at me.
Belched?
You saw a belching dragon?
You sure you weren't belching yourself
in front of the mirror?
N-Never saw anything
so horrible in my life.
Th-Thought
I was a goner.
There was no need
for him to do that.
I only offered him
a sociable drink.
Hoagy, I can't stand you
when you're drunk.
Doc, look at me.
I'm not drunk.
What I saw tonight
sobered me in a second.
I swear... I swear to you,
there's a big, horrible dragon...
up in that cave, I swear.
I just realized,
I can't stand you when you're sober!
Now, get out of here. Get yourself
a good, stiff drink. Out!
I swear.
A vicious dragon.
Out!
Dragon.
[Humming]
I ain't got hardly
nothin' to sell.
So? I pulled my nets in,
and there weren't a fish in 'em.
I just docked. There ain't nothin' out
in that ocean but water.
It's real strange,
I'm tellin' ya.
It's like every fish
sorta disappeared.
Just suddenly
up and disappeared.
There's the cause of it.
That kid Pete.
From the day he come to town,
the fishing turned sour.
- Don't be ridiculous.
- It's that crazy dragon talk of his.
That kid's been nothin'
but bad luck wherever he goes.
You're a bunch of
superstitious ding-dongs.
You know that fishing grounds shift
from time to time.
Elliott'll make
the fish come back.
There he goes,
talkin' dragons again.
Hey, kid! There ain't no room
in this town for a dragon,
and there ain't no room in this town
for jinxes like you, neither!
Well, if there's enough room
for a chowderhead like you,
then there's more than
enough room for a dragon.
There's room for everyone
in this world
If everyone makes
some room
Won't you move over
and share this world
Everyone make
some room
Even a dragon deserves a place
a wide-open space
With no reins
No chains
He wants to play games
Dance with you
Give him a chance
To sing his song
He only wants
to belong
There's room for everyone
in this world
Will everyone
make some room
Spread out while Elliott
gets uncurled
Fly on his back
and zoom
Rock him and ride him
and line up beside him
You'll see how
quickly you blend
A dragon is just
one more stranger
In search of a friend
There's room for everyone
in this world
Back up
and make some room
Let's all move over
and share this world
Everyone make some room
Just think how far out
the ocean goes
The whirling wind blows
shore to shore, door to door
Think of the valleys and mountaintops
The Earth never stops
- So deep, so high
- With miles of sky
We all have
part of the pie
Welcome the dragon
while you have a chance
Give him his moment
To rise up and dance
[Square Dance Music]
There's room for everyone
in this world
Will everyone make some room
- Elliott!
- Love given freely
Can spare this world
Let friendly feelings bloom
[Together] Just give an inch
Give a yard, never flinch
When the time comes
to offer a hand
So let's all make sure
we give everyone somewhere to stand
Let's all make sure
[Nora]
Just the way God planned it
Just the way God planned
[Bell Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
You're late. You're late.
Late. Late. Late.
[Bell Ringing]
Why is the bell ringing?
There's no one out there.
I'll stop it.
- Elliott, stop it!
- [Elliott Chattering]
The bell isn't supposed
to ring till recess!
- Stop that!
- I'm not doing it.
Liar. Liar, liar.
It's the knuckle cracker
for you.
Three for lying and three...
for whom the bell tolls. Come.
Put your hands out.
Palms down, knuckles up.
One. Two.
- Three! Four!
- It doesn't hurt much, Elliott.
- Whom are you talking to? Five, six!
- Elliott!
- Whom?
- My dragon.
- [Laughing]
- Your dragon, wagon.
Nothing but a network of lies!
Three more
for your imagination!
Seven! Eight!
And a great big nine!
Go stand in the corner.
[Huffs]
Work, work, work, everyone.
All this nonsense
about a dragon.
[Elliott Humming]
- No, Elliott!
- You did it! You pulled
the chair out from under me.
- It was Elliott.
- [Gasps] That does it.
You've had a taste
of the knuckle cracker.
Now you'll have a dose
of the behind breaker.
- Bend over.
- [Elliott Growling, Thumping]
[Screaming]
No, no, Elliott.
Get out!
[Elliott Grunting]
- [Crowd Chattering]
- [Elliott Growling]
No, Elliott, you're going
about this the wrong way.
- Go back to the cave. Go on!
- [Elliott Grumbling]
[Man]
Jehoshaphat! Would you look at that!
- Why do I hear a bell ringing?
- School must be out.
It's too early, stupid.
See, I told you.
School is out.
- Wait! What's happening?
- Pete's dragon wrecked the school!
I told you.
I told you!
[Man]
What's happened over there? Something
crashed right through the school.
Look at it, I'm telling you.
It's a big hole in the side of the wall.
And a dragon
came in through one wall...
and went out the other wall.
Now do you believe me?
[Chuckling]
- You think this kid Pete
would sell it?
- Money talks.
First there's a dragon.
Now he tells me money talks.
Will miracles never cease?
Dragons, dragons, dragons.
Dragons.
[Coughing]
"List of useful parts:
Claws, ears, tongue."
Hey, this could be
a very profitable business.
There are so many cures
from bits of dragon.
[Chuckling]
Dragon whiskers
Dragon toes
A dragon tooth
And a dragon nose
Every little piece
We could make a million
by slicing him, dicing him
Hoagy, we could sell
every little shell
There's enough of him
to go around
Money, money, money
by the pound
Every little piece
I can take a scissor
and clip him up, rip him up
Every little part
is a work of art
Think of what
a dragon heart would bring
Wrapped up in a ribbon
and a string
Dragon liver
can cure a cold
Dragon powder grows hair
[Gasping]
With dragon blood
you'll never grow old
Every item
is covered with gold
Every little piece
Dragon, you're my wagon to destiny
you're the key
Every little shred
moving me ahead
Every dream of mine
will be fulfilled
Oh, what a dragon business
we can build
Dragon cartilage
keeps you thin
Dragon fat is for burns
[Gasping]
A dragon tear will
clear up your skin
Watch the profits
come rolling in
Every little piece
Every little crease
Oh, lead me to the dragon
I'll buy him up, tie him up
Drag him from the cave
Show him that I'm brave
I'll bind him up
Grind him up
Lop him up
Chop him up
Can't you hear
that jingle-jangle sound
Oh yeah
[Together]
It's money money, money by the pound
Good morning, Miss Nora.
So, this is where you live, eh?
At last we've seen the light.
[Chuckling]
I tell you, you've got to have
a sense of humor these days.
- And you must be Pete.
- Yes, sir!
I'm Dr. Terminus,
and this is Hoagy,
who's doing
his internship with me.
I heard about the incident
at school yesterday.
- I'd rather not discuss it.
- I realize you must be
disturbed about it, and, uh,
up to here in dragons.
You know, Pete, I have
always loved dragons.
They're such
wonderful creatures.
When they're not busy
destroying things, of course.
I've had a dream since
I was your age that one day...
I would have
my very own dragon.
I would consider my life
to be fulfilled...
and would be most grateful
if you would sell me your dragon.
You wanna buy Elliott?
Sight unseen. As is.
We'll give him
a good home. Bless him.
I couldn't sell him.
Sure you could! That's what life
is all about: Buying and selling.
- I'll give ya three dollars.
- [Whispering] Offer him four!
I'll offer him five.
It'll make his head swim.
Five... dollars.
I can't sell him.
I don't own him.
- Well, what did ya do, rent him?
- Well, who owns him?
Well, nobody, I guess.
He just came to me.
He only goes to those who need him.
I need him.
Listen, Doc, I don't know what you're
up to, but you better forget about this.
- He's not for sale.
- Nora, go paint your lighthouse.
Pete, my boy,
you're conversant with Elliott.
Now, talk to him.
Tell him how much I need him.
Deliver Elliott to me
and the fiver is yours,
plus a bottle of my medicine
that's guaranteed to bring on
puberty two years ahead of time,
and that's better than a dragon, hmm?
[Chuckling]
- Doc, maybe you should
talk to Elliott yourself.
- Mm-hmm.
Wh-Where is he?
Does he speak English?
Down the beach.
- Where?
- Right there, by the water.
- Right. I still don't see...
- That's because he's invisible today.
[Laughing]
They know they're sitting
on a gold mine.
Well, they've had their chance
to make a few dollars.
That dragon doesn't belong to anybody.
He's fair game, and he's gonna be ours!
We'll bind him up, grind him up
Lock him up, chop him up
Can't you hear
that jingle-jangle sound
- Oh yeah
- [Cackling]
It's money, money, money
by the pound
- [Horn Blowing]
- Ahh!
[Laughing]
Uh! Ah-ah-ah!
Fog! Fog!
- Where's the fog?
- There's not much fog.
We were just using the horn
to chase off a few buzzards.
Few buzzards. Nora,
how many times must l...
Oh, started already, huh?
Look, if you're
gonna whitewash, son,
let your brush
go up and down, up...
that's a boy...
and down.
- Up and down. Up and down.
- That's right.
- [Chuckling]
- This is fun.
If it's so much fun, I'm gonna leave
it to you and Nora to finish up...
while I go in and take
a nice little nap.
This is the best time
I've ever had in my whole life.
- It is?
- Yeah.
Tell him, Nora.
Pete, Lampie and I
have talked it over.
- We feel the time has come
for you to stop running.
- Yes, it's true.
If it's all right with you,
we'd like you to live here with us.
Oh, Nora, Lampie, do you mean this
could be my real home?
- It certainly does.
- And Elliott too?
- Well, l...
- Sure, and Elliott too.
But Elliott has to live
in the cave.
All right, he will.
- Oh.
- [Lampie Chuckling]
No, no, no!
Not on me! Not on me!
On the side of the building,
please, huh?
- Now up... Up and down.
- And down. Up and down.
You know what?
It's a brazzle
dazzle day
So throw off the past
and everything in it
That's the brazzle
dazzle way
Enjoying your time
from minute to minute
- Running through the sand
without your shoes on
- Shoes on
Making sure that you
don't keep your blues on
- Finding a boat we can cruise on
- [Whistling]
It's a brazzle
dazzle day
When you think of love
and never of sorrow
That's the brazzle
dazzle way
- To do your work now
- And take off tomorrow
Flying through the air
You don't need wings on
- Wings on
Climb right up and feel the thrill
it brings on
[All]
Rock with the wind as it sings on
Ride higher and higher
And glide above the clouds
Free
No one to catch us
or slow us
Even the birds
are below us
It's a brazzle dazzle day
A lifetime of joy
in just a few hours
All our brazzle dazzle years
have just begun
We'll follow the sun
and replay
This brazzle dazzle day
[Breathing On Glass]
When your job becomes a frolic
you'll become a "brazz-a-holic"
[All]
Ride higher and higher
And glide above the clouds
Free
No one to catch us
or slow us
Even the birds
are below us
It's a brazzle
dazzle day
A lifetime of joy
in just a few hours
All our brazzle dazzle years
Have just begun
We'll follow the sun and replay
This brazzle dazzle day
Come on. Come on.
Whoa, boy. Say, have you seen
anything of a mean, fresh kid...
'bout yea big?
Answers to the name of Pete.
Half of the kids in this town
answer to the name of Pete.
Other half don't answer.
- Let me break his bones, Pa!
- Just a minute!
This particular Pete,
he's always talkin'...
to his big, hokey-pokey,
uh, whatchamacallit, uh...
- Dragon.
- Dragon?
Merle, this here's
the place.
Come on, Willie.
It would be unethical of me
to leave my patient at a time like this.
It's important.
About the dragon.
Put your foot on there.
Now, don't move, stay tense,
or that weight will fall,
that clamp will break your jaw,
tear your gums apart
and go through your cheek.
- Tense. Tense!
- [Whimpering]
[Whimpering]
See that wagonload of worms? They're
lookin' for the kid and the dragon.
I knew there'd be competition.
Come on.
[Lampie]
Careful as you bring 'em aside.
I got one!
Ugh! It's ugly!
Well! If it ain't
our own little Petey!
- [Cackling]
- The Gogans!
Well, you look so nice and clean,
and those new clothes.
I guess all those good manners
I taught you done paid off.
Who's that pretty lady
you're with, little Pete?
- Yeah. Introduce us.
I'm Nora, and Pete
is staying with me.
Why, boys, I believe she's tryin'
to break up our happy little family.
Elliott went to look for Paul.
I wish he were here.
Don't worry. They won't get you.
Come on, Dad.
I guess we're gonna
take him back now, miss,
to his own home, sweet home.
- Come on, Pete.
- You won't be taking him anywhere!
Okay, lady. We're gonna take him
whether you like it or not.
- Right, boys?
- Right, Pa.
Willie, you grab onto Pete,
while I hold onto her.
You grab Pete.
I wanna hold her.
- I wanna hold her!
- Well, I'm gonna hold her!
[Squabbling]
All right!
I'll settle this.
You two grab the brat.
I'll hold her.
Lf'n you think you're gonna hold her
like my boys wanna hold her,
you're gonna be holdin' your head,
ya understand?
Lady, that boy is ours!
We got a bill of sale
right here
That says
he belongs to us
We bought him
fair and square last year
And we own
the little cuss
Look here
Read the writin'
That gives us
a legal claim
[Gogans] Oh, we got a bill
of sale right here
With dear
little Petey's name
- You can't have him
- He's gotta clean and sweep
- You don't love him
- Feed the hens
and call in the sheep
- All you've done up to now
- Plant seeds, pull weeds
- Is break his heart
- Bow to all our needs
- You'll abuse him
- Carry water from the well
- And just use him
- Answer every time we yell
Watch out or I'll
take you apart
We'd like to see you try it
We got a bill of sale right here
that says he belongs to us
Fight all you want
Won't do no good
to holler and fume and fuss
Leave town, keep on goin'
before I can count to five
- Come on! Row!
- [Explosion]
It's Elliott!
We got a bill of sale
right here
Right here
[Sighing]
It's downright dangerous,
getting all wet like this.
We done had
our bath in May!
Ahh-ahh-ahh...
- [Sneezing]
- [Men] Bless you, Ma.
- [Coughing]
- Excuse me, folks.
I witnessed what happened today,
and I'm completely sympathetic with you.
- What's sympathetic mean?
- I'm Doc Terminus. Like to talk to you.
Oh, Doc, I got
this here "poomonia."
- Sit down.
- Ahh-ahh-ahh...
[Sneezing]
- Bless you, Ma.
[Groaning, Panting]
I got this terrible ache in my back!
Good. What's rightfully yours
is rightfully yours.
Now, you want Pete, right?
- Right!
I want... the dragon.
- The dragon?
- [Laughing]
W-W-Wait a minute.
Now I got
a stitch in my side.
You really want
the dragon?
Very much. Mm-hmm.
Well, then, what are you willing
to give for it?
The help you need
getting Pete.
I'll need the same kind
of help getting the dragon.
[Cackling]
[Laughing]
N-Now I think the pain's
in my head!
- Have we got a deal?
- Sure.
We scratch your back,
you scratch ours.
The boathouse,
sunset, hmm?
Uh, Doc.
What you gonna do
with a dragon?
Oh, maybe put him on a ranch,
breed him. Hmm?
Big stud fees.
Ahoy. Ahoy. Here.
How would you like to make
the fishing good again?
- How do we do that?
- Catch that dragon!
Set a trap for him, throw a net
over him, drag him away.
Good-bye, Elliott.
Hello, fish. Hmm?
Sunset, the boathouse.
Spread the word, hmm?
[Fishermen Murmuring
In Agreement]
Get back!
Dr. Terminus! Here's that
there harpoon you wanted!
Good! Put it
right over there!
[Ma]
Now you just remember our bargain!
Okay, I want separate trip lines
on the primary tarp,
the secondary net
and on the tertiary.
- T-Tertiary?
- What's that?
Dragon medicine.
[Cackling]
- Okay, fix it.
- We've done it!
Don't signal
till you're re...
- [Men Shouting]
- Get this net up off of me!
Will you get this... Will you
get this net up! Up! Up!
Now, I've gotta go
and get that kid.
You rehearse this and make it run
like clockwork or else.
Elliott!
Oh, Elliott, you were terrific
the way you saved us from the Gogans.
- [Laughing]
- What?
[Gibberish]
Do you mean it?
[Clicking Tongue]
Wow! That's great.
You're the most wonderful dragon
in the whole world.
[Soft Growling,
Clicking Tongue]
Wait till I tell Nora!
[Humming]
Nora! Nora! Good news!
Elliott found Paul,
and he's on his way home!
- Pete...
- I wouldn't say anything
like that if I were you.
But it's true.
Elliott said.
Please.
There's been enough talk
about Paul,
and Elliott too.
[Sighing]
Both of us have to be...
realistic.
Paul's ship went down.
He's not coming back.
And I have to adjust
my life to it.
You have to make
a big adjustment too.
You have us now.
You don't have to make believe
your only friend is a dragon.
But I'm not making believe.
That's what I mean
by "realistic."
There are no dragons.
Except for Elliott.
He's real.
Lampie, you've seen him,
haven't you?
Well, l...
I thought I saw him.
Wait till Paul gets here. Then you'll
know how realistic Elliott is.
Okay.
Until that time, let's try
not to talk about it.
How about filling
the reserve oil can?
Sure.
Well, at least one of us
is entitled to have illusions.
[Thunderclap]
[Wind Howling]
Pete! Pete, it's Elliott!
- What's the matter?
- Elliott's in Passapaka... Pakadaka...
He's in town, and he's
tearing the place apart.
- You've gotta do something.
- Oh, no!
[Laughing]
We should be
in the channel.
We should've made
Passamaquoddy Light by now.
I know the light keepers
personally.
- He's in there! Come on!
- Elliott! Elliott!
Did I say the primary
was really the tertiary?
[Men Shouting]
Never!
- Where's Elliott?
- Nowhere!
Your hokey-pokey dragon's
out helping Santa Claus pull his sled!
- Boys!
- Let me go!
Now you're never
gonna get away again!
We're gonna put chains
on you when you're workin'!
- And when you're not workin'.
- And when you're sleepin'!
Okay, okay. Tear him to pieces
in your own time.
Right now he is
the bait for the trap.
Take him in there where that thing can
see him when he comes through the door.
He'll head straight for Pete.
We spring the trap.
After the tertiary net drops on him,
I'll give you the signal,
and you fire the harpoon
right into the middle.
- No! No!
- Yes! Yes! Got it?
Got it!
But what I don't got is,
h-h-how you gonna get that monster,
that hideous beast, that nightmare
sent by the devil, to come here?
Easy. We get someone he knows
to bring him here.
Well, who'd be crazy enough
to do that?
No! No!
He knows you.
He trusts you.
He scares me!
He hates me!
Hoagy.
We are all on this earth
for a purpose,
and the time
for your purpose is now.
I know that inside this pale, frail,
pathetic shell of a man...
there is a Vesuvius
ready to erupt.
Now, I've known you,
man and beast,
since, since you
were nothing.
But now, Hoagy, now,
you're still nothing,
but you could be
something!
You can be a somebody.
A legend, Hoagy. A legend in
your own lifetime, not a joke!
The moment's here, Hoagy.
Grab it. Grab it!
Today the jester.
Tomorrow the king!
- No!
- Get out!
[Whimpering]
[Elliott Snoring]
E-Elliott.
C-Can you come out here
for a second? Please?
[Snoring]
[Gasping]
Wake up.
W-W-Wake up!
[Snarling]
D-D-Don't get n-n-nervous!
I'm a friend.
[Groaning, Snorting]
Don't roast me!
[Snarling]
Boo!
- Ahh!
- [Laughing]
H-Hon... Honest.
L-l-I-I-I got a m-mess...
m-m-m-message about P-P-Pete!
- T-The G-G-Gogans...
- [Snarling]
Got P-P-P-Pete!
- [Bellowing]
- Ahh!
[Snarling, Roaring]
Aaah!
Follow me!
[Thunderclap]
There's a reef between us
and the channel.
Dad, I can't find Pete.
- Can you get it lit?
- I have to put in a dry wick.
Battle stations!
[Hoagy] I told you!
I told you, Elliott! There he is!
Look out, Elliott!
It's a trap!
Aaah! Get him!
He's right here!
Drop everything!
[Men Shouting]
[Elliott Bellowing]
Elliott, over here!
[Hoagy] Get me out of here!
Elliott, don't step on me!
- Am I seeing what I think I'm seeing?
- It's beginnin' to look like a...
- Dragon!
- Don't say that!
I've got it!
We've done it! Out!
We've got it!
- Hoagy!
- [Elliott Growling]
Please!
Please, let me out!
- Doc, please!
- Get out of there! Get out of there!
- Doc, get me out!
Get me out! Get me out!
- Okay. Okay!
[Growling]
- [Growling]
- [Men Shouting]
Help, Elliott, help!
Man this harpoon. Take this.
[Chuckling]
Light the fuse.
No, no!
Don't shoot Elliott!
[Ma Screaming,
Shouting]
[Pa]
Get him back! Get him back!
The other.
- [Pa] Pick him up!
- [Ma] Take him outside!
[Hoagy]
Get out of the way!
- [Whimpering]
- [Screaming]
He's going!
Let me get a bead on him!
- Elliott, save me!
- [Ma] Don't let him get away again!
Get him outta here!
- Hands...
- Elliott, don't let 'em take me!
[Growling]
[Roaring]
[Stammering]
Wait! Wait!
[Ma Shouting]
- [Muttering]
- [Gogans Whimpering]
Huh? Pete!
- Thanks, Elliott.
- [Muttering]
You just listen to me!
That there boy belongs to me!
I paid fifty dollars for him,
plus legals, and I got a bill
of sale right here to prove it.
[Snarling]
- Boo.
- [Screaming]
[Ma]
Merle, help! Don't just stand there!
Come on! Get me outta here!
Get me outta here!
[Ma]
You clucks!
[Elliott Laughing]
- [Grunting, Groaning]
- [Ma] Let him keep the brat!
[Roaring]
[Ma]
Come on! Get in the wagon!
[Shouting]
[Ma]
Wait! Wait for us!
[Elliott Howling]
Daaah-ah-ah!
Aaah-hoo-hoo-hoo!
[Screaming]
Aaah! Doh!
Hoagy, get me down!
We've gotta do something!
That dragon's gonna get away!
[Snarling]
[Screaming]
He's gonna eat us up!
[Growling]
Oh!
[Whimpering]
[Wagon Crashing]
...in the street.
Quite a storm here.
Wait a minute.
Watch those stairs.
- [Gasping]
- [Electricity Crackling]
Oh, look!
Th-Th-There really
is a dragon!
Yes, and he saved us!
- Dragon!
- A dragon! A real dragon!
- Attaboy, Elliott.
- [Muttering]
[Clicking Tongue]
That ship's headed
for the reef!
Go down and sound
the foghorn!
[Foghorn Blowing]
Elliott, quick! Quick!
[Ship Creaking]
Nora, let me have the light
so I can see what I'm doing.
[Foghorn Blowing]
Come on, Elliott.
You can do it.
- [Foghorn Blowing]
- I got it!
Come on, Elliott.
- [Foghorn Blowing]
- Come on, Elliott!
[Panting]
[Pete]
Hurry!
What's the matter?
Everything is wet in here,
that's what's the matter!
- Don't worry, Lampie. Elliott came.
- Elliott?
That's all I need is
a dragon in here. Ah!
Get him outta here!
[Muttering]
Start your burner, Elliott.
Light the wick.
[Gibberish]
- [Clicking Tongue]
- All right, Elliott. Go ahead. Light it.
[Pete]
Now, Elliott! Now!
All right.
Where's the fire?
- [Groaning]
- What's the matter?
[Gibberish, Sputtering]
- He's all squished up in the stairs.
- [Foghorn Blowing]
- [Elliott Blowing]
- El-Elliott?
- [Gibberish]
He's real.
He's really real.
[Muttering,
Clicking Tongue]
- Of course he is.
He's gonna light the wick.
- Can he do it?
Can he? He can throw a flame clear
across to Bar Harbor...
if he can get
his own burner goin'!
[Gasping]
- Come on, Elliott!
- [Whining]
- Go on!
[Lampie]
Blow, Elliott!
[Drawing A Deep Breath]
- Wow! [Panting]
- [Pete] Elliott, you did it!
[Gibberish,
Clicking Tongue]
Look there!
That means the harbor
is dead ahead, Captain!
Hard right rudder!
Elliott, I could give you
a great big kiss.
[Shuddering]
A dragon, a dragon
You bet we saw a dragon
So big and brave, he came to
save a village in distress
He kept the ship from crashing
when he heard the S.O.S.
He faced a group of villains
and he fought them with success
He's great
- A chum
- A pal
- A mate
A dragon, a dragon
We're proud to love a dragon
Before he came to fight the storm
the night was dark and dim
Now everyone in town is safe again
because of him
He filled the ocean full of fish
He packed it to the brim
We want it known
that he's our very own
Nora! Nora!
Paul!
Gather around, everyone. I'm going
to have a few appropriate words to say.
Gather around. Come on.
Closer, closer.
There you are, yes.
It's nice to see you.
Ladies...
Ladies and gentlemen,
Pete, I want you to thank
Elliott the dragon...
for the council here
and all the townspeople.
- You do that?
- Well, he's right here.
He'd appreciate it
if you'd thank him yourself.
- [Laughter]
- You mean I can talk right to him, huh?
Go right to the main source.
That was my campaign...
- No, he's over here.
- Oh! Oh, over that side.
So, uh, on behalf of...
[Laughter]
[Muttering]
Thank you.
It's a brazzle dazzle day
- So throw off the past
and everything in it
- [Elliott Clicking Tongue]
That's the brazzle
dazzle way
Enjoying your time
from minute to minute
Hi!
Oh, Elliott,
you're the greatest.
You've made everybody happy,
especially me.
I'm very proud of you.
[Muttering]
We've got a real family now
and a place to live.
[Clearing Throat]
[Gibberish]
You've gotta go?
When will you be back?
[Gulping, Muttering,
Sniffling]
You... You won't be back?
[Muttering]
But why?
Did I do something wrong?
[Muttering]
[Snarling]
There's another kid
in trouble?
[Muttering,
Growling]
[Soft Roar]
Well, if anyone can get him
out of it, you can.
- Ohh...
- [Giggling]
[Muttering]
I won't see you again,
will I?
Ever.
[Sniffling, Whimpering]
[Sniffling]
What are you sniffing for?
[Gasping, Sneezing]
[Laughing]
[Chuckling]
Now, remember,
don't scare people.
[Gibberish]
Good-bye, Elliott.
Good-bye.
[Gibberish]
- It is a dragon!
- [Pete, Lampie, Nora] It's Elliott!
[Pete] And remember,
you're supposed to be invisible!