We have with us today a man who
is so much a part of the culture...
That he scarcely needs
an introduction.
Pootie tang.
Good to have you here with us.
- Sepatown.
- Pootie tang, you've had incredible success,
And you've had it
in a variety of fields--
Music, films,
martial arts, pottery.
- How do you do it? What makes you tick?
- Well, bob, i'm a pone toni.
Got my dillies on a peppatain.
I hear that.
Now, pootie, a lot of young artists, really,
say that you are their inspiration.
Well, i can't say the nay-No,
my brother. Wa-Da-Tah.
I understand, though,
you got a new movie coming out, is that right?
Yeah.
Yes, it's called sine your pitty on the runny kine.
- Wow. And who's in it besides yourself?
- Oh, well, there's trucky,
Uh, bad bitty, dirty dee,
Lacey, j.B., Uh,
Biggie shorty
and robert vaughn.
You have a clip you'd like to show us?
Yeah, baby.
All right,
let's take a look then at this clip...
From pootie tang's new movie,
sine your pitty on the runny kine.
[Man narrating]
it was the year 2001.
It was the best of times.
It was the worst of times.
The big city was thriving,
but the inner city was dying.
Who was killing it?
This man. Dick lecter.
The head
of corporate america.
But the people had hope...
Because they knew that there was
one man who could fight the power.
One man who could stop
the madness.
One man who could beat
dick lecter like the l.A.P.D.
And that man-- That man
was pootie tang.
See that guy?
That's bad bitty.
The baddest drug dealer
in town.
Hey, bad bitty,
here comes dirty dee.
* Low-Down and dirty boy,
you know what i'm 'bout *
Dirty bastard!
* Stay out my way
* and keep my name
out your mouth *
[Narrator] that's dirty dee,
the dirtiest dude around.
He handles all of corporate america's dirty work.
* Believe me you receivin'
some bodily harm **
Next to dirty dee,
that's froggy, the enforcer.
Yo, bad bitty!
How you be?
I'm bad, dirty dee.
You're still dirty, i can see.
Let's deal, baby.
- You got yours?
- Froggy.
It's dirty money.
You got yours?
Right!
But how do i know
if they any good?
Let's test 'em out.
Hey, kid!
Come over here!
[Narrator] that's kid,
the dumbest kid in town.
What you want, mister?
Here. Have some of this.
Is it candy?
Told you.
Yeah.
It's the kind of candy that you smoke out of a pipe.
[All laughing]
Pipe candy.
Pootie tang!
* Come on
* yeah, yeah, yeah
* pootie tang, baby
* motown, baby
* yeah, yeah, yeah
* little j, y'all *
- Capachow.
- Yea! Pootie tang.
Dirty dee, you a baddy
daddy lamatai tebby chai.
Get that pootie!
* Make 'em say ugh
* na-Na, na-Na
say ugh, ugh, ugh *
* ugh, ugh, ugh
* make 'em say ugh
na-Na, na-Na *
* na-Na, na-Na
make 'em say ugh, ugh *
* make 'em go ugh, ugh
* na-Na, na-Na
** [continues]
That's a canapan,
all the way down.
You mother--
- [Groans]
- Shut up, bitch!
Ow! Ow! Okay, i quit.
[Sobbing]
My face!
[Laughing]
run, pootie! Run!
[Dirty dee]
aw, hell!
Come on!
Get out! Get out!
Get out! Out!
Hiya, pootie tang.
[Laughs]
yeah.
No car wash.
No soap!
No soap! No! No!
Sa da tay.
* Hey, hey
* hey
* hey, hey, hey
* hey, hey-Hey
* he's got it all
he's on the money *
* and he's maintained
he knows what he wants *
* he's got it all
he'll sine your pitty *
* and it's no thang
he's that pootie tang *
* somebody's on the floor
* it's another
smooth-Talkin' brother *
* everybody's lookin' at him
* as he puts his tie down the ladies on the dance floor *
* he's got the whole world
wrapped around his finger *
* a one-Woman man
and you know he understands *
* casanova with a fancy car
* you can tell
he's gonna go all night *
* he's got it all
he's on the money *
* and he's maintained
he knows what he wants *
* he's got it all
he'll sine your pitty *
* and it's no thang
he's that pootie tang *
* he's hip to the core
* got a belt buckle locket
you know where he got it *
* he's a player by trade
* and you can see him on the corner
doing business on his tippi tai *
* [continues, indistinct]
* he's the c.E.O.
Of his own world *
* he commands r-E-S-P-E-C-T
* and you know he's
good to go all night *
* he's got it all
he's on the money *
* and he's maintained
* he knows what he wants
he's got it all *
* he'll sine your pitty
and it's no thang *
* he's that pootie tang
* [continues, indistinct]
* turnin' heads
can't let 'em take ya *
* pootie be packin' crys
and ladies be payin' paper *
* let me see you
do your thing *
** [continues, indistinct]
* turnin' heads
can't let 'em take ya *
* pootie be packin' crys
and ladies be payin' paper *
* yeah, yeah, yeah
* he's got it all
he's on the money *
* and he's maintained
he knows what he wants *
* he's got it all
he'll sine your pitty *
* and it's no thang
he's that pootie tang **
[Narrator] pootie tang was born in a
small town outside of gary, indiana.
And that town
was called chicago.
As he grew,
Everyone noticed something different
about the way pootie would talk.
It baffled everyone--
Doctors, scientists.
Let me break it down
to you like this.
Pootie tang is, was
and will always be...
Too cool for words.
[Kid] hi, pootie!
Pootie tang was the most popular kid in town.
We didn't always know
what he was saying,
But we always knew
what he meant.
Like i knew i was his best friend.
That's me. Trust me.
Yeah, he had
a special effect on people,
Especially on the ladies.
Not girls.
Grown-Ass women.
Hiya, pootie tang. I'm a tine cappy,
my damie. Wa-Da-Tah.
All right, pootie tang.
But for some of the ladies,
Pootie was just
too hot to handle.
Damn you, pootie tang!
I can't take
no more of this!
Who do you think you are,
treatin' me this way?
Oh, i've had it with you!
You hear me talkin' to you with your nappy head!
This is it!
I'm finished with you!
Get out of my life,
pootie tang!
You think i'm jokin'?
Take your shit!
Take your shit and get out,
pootie tang! I'm sick of you!
Pootie--
Pootie, don't go.
* Just because you bought her
a brand-New car *
* and you got to live
and eat in a mansion *
* like a movie star *
Pootie tang
was an only child.
His father, daddy tang,
worked hard to raise pootie right.
He had this belt.
He was so fast with that belt...
That before pootie could do wrong,
daddy tang would set him right.
Don't you grab them peas
without askin' your mama, boy.
May i dane on the cherries,
mama di?
Yes, you may, pootie tang.
Now, that's better.
You got to have respect
to get respect, pootie tang.
So, do you have any girlfriends at school, pootie?
Aw, mama di. There's a sine
tippi in a classi-Ti.
She's a cole toni.
Don't you talk dirty
to your mama, boy.
Always got your head
in them girls.
You need to have
your head in the books.
Leave the ladies alone.
[Narrator]
and that's the way it was.
Daddy tang and his belt
was always there,
Teaching pootie the difference
between good and bad.
Now, when i say he was always there,
i mean he was always there.
Hey, pootie, let's
steal some apples.
When pootie was only six,
his mother died,
Leaving him
and his father alone.
- Pootie was very sad.
- I know, son.
But his father was a comfort to him.
[Slurping]
Don't slurp your soup
in here, boy.
Two weeks later,
another terrible tragedy.
His father was fatally injured at the steel mill.
What the fu--
Gorilla!
It was incredible.
Only the third time a man had been
mauled by a gorilla at that steel mill.
Gorilla! Oh!
On his deathbed,
daddy tang had pootie make a solemn promise.
Pootie,
I know
i brought you up tough,
But that's
'cause i love you.
It's tough
out there, pootie.
You got drugs,
crime, gorillas.
Yeah.
I ain't gonna
be here much longer,
So i'm gonna
give you this.
Pootie,
that's my belt.
As long as you got it
right on your side,
You could whoop anyone's ass with just that belt.
I know
you love the ladies,
And lord knows
the ladies love you.
Don't let the ladies come between you and the belt.
[Weak coughing]
[Narrator] those were daddy tang's last words:
"Don't let the ladies come between you and the belt."
But there was something
else about the ladies...
That daddy tang forgot
to tell little pootie.
- Pootie tang turned out just fine.
- [Crowd] pootie tang!
Daddy tang
would have been proud.
Yeah, pootie had it all--
Hit records, movies,
Magazine covers,
fancy cars,
Famous friends, beautiful
custom-Made clothes...
And ladies, ladies, ladies.
Through it all, i was right there by his side.
That's me. Trucky.
And that's my man,
pootie tang.
Pootie tang.
Pootie tang!
Big-Time celebrity,
ass-Kickin' crime fighter...
And role model
to the children.
[Announcer] pootie tang has a
message for the children of america,
So you better
wapatah to the bammies 'cause:
Pootie says cigarettes and fast-Food
burgers are bad like netatai.
And don't drink malt liquor 'cause
you don't need to 'cause you're okay.
Sa da tay. Also, eat
all your vegetables...
And don't bang the dillies.
[Trucky] that's frank,
dick lecter's right-Hand man.
So what do we care?
We care because
he's making these.
People have been making p.S.A.'S for years.
Hasn't made a difference.
Eddie, uh, hit me
with those figures.
Uh, since the inception of
pootie tang's p.S.A. Campaign,
Sales of lecter burgers
are down 30 percent,
Lecter cigarettes
down 20 percent...
And lecter whiskey,
Almost out of business.
For the first time,
somebody's getting to these kids, and it's killing us.
It's killing us.
[Rings]
Hello, mr. Lecter.
Frank, i have a job for you.
Yes, sir.
I tell you, man,
pootie tang is one bad brother, man.
[Trucky] that's j.B. And lacey.
We make up pootie's crew.
Pootie tang will draw you a picture
of how he's gonna kick your ass...
Then mail it to you
ten days in advance.
The picture
gets there, right?
You go,
"what the hell is this?"
Then pootie tang knocks on your door,
promptly kicks your ass,
And you still won't know
what happened to you.
You got that right.
He is a kick-Ass artiste. Yes.
Know what i'm sayin'?
He like the da vinci of ass-Kicking.
That sounds kind of good. Pootie tang,
the da vinci of ass-Kicking.
Aw, man, pootie tang
whoop your ass so bad...
That you could
write it off on your taxes.
That's right. You got right here,
ass-Whooping number one,
Ass-Whooping number two.
This right here, you can't write that off.
That's just gettin' beat up.
I like to also add that pootie
tang can kick some ass too, boy.
Oh, here come pootie tang now.
Hey! Pootie tang! All right!
We was just talkin' about you.
All right, pootie tang!
Pootie tang, hey, man,
you going to biggie shorty's party tomorrow, man?
[Trucky] i guess you're wonderin' who is biggie shorty.
* Biggie shorty
I'm biggie shorty.
* Biggie, baby
Let me tell you
about me and pootie tang.
* Sepatai
Since the very day we met,
i knew pootie was to be my man.
* Yeah, baby
I knew all i had
to do was wait...
* wa-Da-Tah *
And one day all that bullshit
would catch up with pootie...
And he would be mine.
Hey, man,
you going to biggie shorty's party tomorrow, man?
Ranacan.
Whoo! Ha-Ha!
We gonna party tomorrow, man.
There's gonna be some bitches in there.
You right. You right. Respect the women.
Respect the women.
Whoo! Look at that car!
[Trucky] damn that car big!
And long
like an old snake.
Man, that car's so big,
it's got its own sky.
It's big too.
Whoo!
Keep it running.
Yes, sir.
Hiya, fellas. Whoo!
Kinda hot for a hootenanny, huh?
You hear that?
A hootenanny?
What the hell is a damn hootenanny?
I'm a-- I'm looking
for, uh, pootie tang.
Pootie tang?
What you want with pootie tang?
Um, i-I need
to talk to him.
[Clears throat] all right, uh, look, pootie.
I'm a representative of lecter corp.
Do you know what that is?
Great.
Well, uh, dick lecter,
The c.E.O., Mind you,
of lecter corp., He likes you.
He likes you, pootie,
and he wants to make you a very rich, rich man.
I have a contract here
for pootie to endorse.
Tasty heavy
pork chunk cereal.
It's delicious.
It's a wonderful product. Kids love it.
And kids love you.
We just wanna put that together.
Nah, di.
That's a canapan
to the semachai.
I didn't even tell you
how much it pays, pootie.
Twenty million dollars to sign with us for just one year.
Oh, what do you say,
pootie?
I got to say the nay-No,
my brother. Wa-Da-Tah.
Wa-Da-Tah?
How do you say the nay-No to 20 million? Why?
Maybe pootie don't wanna sign
because he knows you're full of it.
Yeah. First of all,
he knows that cereal's full of sugar.
And number two,
that's not all that you guys sell.
You sell cigarettes, whiskey,
bad time burgers, switchblades.
And it also says right here that you will
no longer have pootie doing p.S.A.'S...
Telling the kids to eat
healthy and to be smart.
Well, sure, exclusivity
goes without saying.
I'm sure your ugly intentions go without saying.
Take a walk,
money man.
See, my damie,
pootie tang don't wa-Da-Tah to the shama cow...
'Cause that's a cama
cama leepa-Chaiii, dig?
Hey, tang, to you, they're children.
To me, they're dollar signs.
Doh!
- Ooh!
- Cover your grill.
Sa da tay!
Pootie!
Pootie tang!
Aw, man!
You funny, man.
You are a funny man.
You's a wild boy.
[Trucky] pootie smacked the taste out of frank's mouth.
Oh, man, that
was funny to us. Ha-Ha!
But there was one man
who was not laughing at all.
Pootie tang goes out there
and makes everybody love him.
He tells them
not to buy my products.
He steals from me.
And what do i do?
I say take my money. Here.
Take it. Fine. Huh?
And he says no.
[Trucky] i guess you're wondering,
who is this bitch here?
That's ireenie,
dick lecter's main squeeze...
And the most dangerous
woman on the planet.
Now, she don't look it,
but she can bring any man down.
I know what makes
pootie tang...
Tick, tock, tick.
** [R&b instrumental]
That's cool.
All right.
Cut the drums too.
** [Stops]
[Man] it's all gone now, pootie.
What do you wanna do?
Lepatime.
What's he got
on his mind?
We're starting
from scratch, i guess.
Pootie knows
what pootie do.
This is gonna be good.
Okay, pootie,
i'll play back the levels the way you set them.
No instruments, no vocals,
no levels, everything silent.
Set it on me. Bleed.
Pootie don't need no words.
Don't even need no music.
Whoa!
We have got a hit, baby.
I like it.
Everybody seems to like it.
But right now i got somethin' i know you all gonna like.
We got the world premiere
from pootie tang,
And you know it's gonna
be out of this world.
That's right. 'Cause you
all loved his last record,
"Sine your pitty
on the runny kine."
Well, you all gonna
love this new one.
The new one is called--
So let's listen up to the new
record by pootie tang called--
From pootie tang.
[No sound]
Oh, yeah.
Ah.
* Uh, uh, uh-Uh *
Damn, this is good!
This is good!
Man, pootie done
did it again!
Pootie too good!
Turn that noise down,
damn it!
Legendary pootie tang has done it
once again with his new song entitled--
Already considered one of the greatest hits of all time.
[Woman] this was the scene earlier today... oh,
you are so fine.
As fans mobbed pootie tang
in the streets,
Many saying they hadn't heard an
artist this profound since al b. Sure.
I love you!
[Speaking gibberish]
** [hip-Hop] ooh,
pootie was blowin' up now.
We talkin' big. I mean,
we talkin' "macarena" big.
We talkin'
electric slide big.
We're talkin' bentleys
and drinkin' crys big,
Girls in bikini thongs big.
Everybody want a piece of pootie.
You think i'm playin'?
[Crowd shouting]
Here we go, baby.
Come on. Get up here.
Aiight!
[Laughing]
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
We got pootie tang
in the house tonight.
Come on up, pootie.
Come on.
I need you to sing
a song with me.
Beloved.
I love you,
pootie tang. Damn.
That's a batu shane,
my tellie. Wa-Da-Tah.
* I'm
* falling in love
with you *
* because you are
my man so right *
* tippi tai on my capa-Town
* and i'm
* oh, yeah
* thinking
of only you *
* because you move me
so right *
* manatine bitty
* all around my damie
* shimmy
na na na, na-Na-Na *
[Scattered screams]
* i feel you
* all on me, baby
* i want you
i want you, baby *
* shimmy
na na na, na-Na-Na *
* shimmy na na
* whoa, yeah, yeah
[Pootie]
* lepatime
* on my clammy dees
* penatiine
* on my damie kings
* i'ma cry the pooster
* i'ma cry
the pooster **
Pootie tang
up in this joint tonight.
Pootie tang!
Oh, pootie!
[Screams]
[Screaming continues]
I love you.
I want you.
Oh, take me with you.
Please, pootie.
Pootie, please.
Please. Oh!
Wait! Oh! Pootie!
Wait! Oh! Oh!
Oh, pootie, i love you.
I want you.
I love you, pootie.
Please!
[Screams]
Uh--
Pootie?
Don't leave me out here
in my lonesome.
Give a girl something!
It's not right.
[Trucky] whoo! She's fine!
Why did pootie pass that up?
'Cause she's crazy. Look at her,
licking milk out of a bowl.
* Oh,
pootie tang you gonna sine that pitty pootie tang **
Biggie shorty.
Pootie tang!
- All right!
- Bata shane, my dillie?
Same as always, baby.
You come by tomorrow.
We gonna have a party!
Talk about
all the sisters and me.
You gonna be there?
Wa-Da-Tah.
All right, pootie!
Pootie tang!
Hola, guapo.
Hey, young boys.
Hey, look at her, man.
Pink lady. Mmm!
Pull up, man. Pull up.
Shh.
Pull up!
[Excited laughter]
[Laughing continues]
Huh? What you want?
- You want somethin'?
- Yes, baby, i want it.
What you want?
I want you to do
the two of us.
How much?
Hey, baby,
what's your problem?
Just 'cause a girl
like to dress fancy...
And stand on a street corner
near some whores,
You automatically
think she's hooking?
Wouldn't you?
No, i wouldn't.
I'm a lady,
you-- You greasy bastard.
** [Hip-Hop]
Presidential campaign. Yeah.
Y.A. D.P.G. Nate dogg.
Oh, yeah! Pootie tang
and his boys are here!
Dog pound!
* Better know that i'm workin' tonight *
* better know i'll be hittin' them drawers
* * i'll be hitting them drawers *
* ain't no mystery
i do it right *
* i got her screamin'
coming back for more *
Yo, man,
a biggie shorty party is exclusive, man.
They don't let nobody
in a biggie shorty party.
They got a line around the block.
Ain't nobody in, man.
You know what?
Nobody we know can get in this party, man.
They don't let no light in.
They don't let no electricity in.
They don't let no water in.
They don't let no air in.
Air is right now going, "hey, man,
i'm air. I'm on the list. Let me in."
And they won't let air in.
And you know air gets in everywhere.
That's how exclusive
a biggie shorty party is.
You know what else?
It's hard to get in too.
I hate you!
[Girl]
go, trucky! Go, trucky!
Go, trucky! Go, trucky!
Go, trucky!
Pretty girl. Pretty girl.
Where you go, girl?
Pootie, you are the sexiest
bastard on god's green earth.
Yeah.
I tell you, though.
Someday i'm gonna get me
a piece of you myself.
Sepatown.
Sepatown, my ass.
You gonna be inside
of a bed with me someday.
You mark my words,
you skinny, wonderful man.
Pretty girl!
Sexy!
Pretty girl?
Pretty girl!
How does a woman
get to you anyway?
It's like a state secret.
How to bed pootie tang.
All right,
get off him already.
He don't want none of your mess.
Puta.
I tell you what, pootie.
Someday you gonna meet
your match in a woman.
the darth vadar of t and a.
Some woman's gonna kick your
ass and love you to death...
And then you gonna be
lying in the dumpster...
Done banged to death
by the dark side of love.
And on that day, pootie,
I'm gonna be there.
And i'm gonna make
sweet love to you.
Sexy girl!
Damn, man.
Oh, i'm sorry.
I thought she was somebody else, man.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, man.
Damn. I didn't get
your name, did i?
Damn. Do i know you?
Do you want me
to pull your legs off?
Pardon me?
You wanna make out?
Uh, i might enjoy that.
I just might enjoy that.
I might enjoy that. You know,
i just might enjoy that.
Ooh, ooh! Oh!
[Screams]
Oh! Okay, wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait a minute!
Look here. Call me a sissy,
but you need to stop, baby.
You are tearing me apart.
You're killing me.
You want me to stop?
Well, yes, i do.
Okay, then,
you tell me something.
What do you wanna know?
What's pootie's secret?
Oh. Oh.
I can't tell you that.
[Trucky] now,
i would never do anything to hurt pootie tang.
But like i said,
ireenie knew how to break a brother down.
I can't tell you that.
You can't? All right.
[Screams]
Whoo! Whoo!
Okay, wait.
I'll tell you.
I'll tell you. I'll tell you.
It's the belt.
It's-It's-It's magical.
He can kick anybody's ass with that damn belt.
Freeze, sucker!
Yeah. Give me your money,
you fancy pants bastard,
Or i'll stick this
in you deep.
Wa-Da-Tah,
my damie.
Hey, i'm not your damie.
Now, give me your cash. I know you got it.
Hey, i told you
to back off!
Pootie. Hey, pootie.
Trucky.
Pootie, the craziest thing just happened to me.
I'm in the club, man.
I'm-- Pootie, look out.
Bang! Bang! Bang! Bang!
Bang! Bang! Bang! Bang! Bang!
Bang! Bang! Bang!
[Groans]
Pootie?
Everything under control?
[Sobbing]
Kayed a brother, di.
Kayed a brother, di!
I'm a shamey day!
Oh, it hurts pootie
to kill a man,
But he knows
he's got to do it.
But it hurts him
so bad...
To right those wrongs.
My man pootie tang!
[Siren wailing]
[Sobbing continues]
Come back
on the bettie tai!
Come back on
the bettie tai!
Come back
on the bettie tai!
Huh? Huh?
Pootie tang?
Hey, all right,
my damie.
Now, why didn't trucky tell pootie
that he told ireenie all his business?
Just runnin' his mouth.
I guess when you see a man
being brought back from the dead,
You forget shit.
Or maybe you just
a dumb-Ass.
[Trucky] stop the movie.
Remember when daddy tang told little pootie--
Don't let the ladies come between you and the belt.
Well, what daddy tang forgot to tell
pootie was about his only weakness:
Ho's.
Even pootie tang's belt
was no match for ireenie.
You can't beat a ho' with a belt.
They like that shit.
* That girl is poison
* that girl is poison
* poison *
I'm sorry.
Did my cart hit your cart?
Oh. I'm so sorry
about that.
Did i hurt you?
Oh, what a drag.
Again, i am...
Very sorry!
* If i were you
i'd take precaution *
* before i step to meet
a fly girl *
** [continues]
[Ireenie] pootie,
will you do something for me?
Will you do something
for me?
Sign your pretty name.
Sign it.
Sign it. Sign it.
He signed it.
Oh, god.
Signed it?
Nice job, ireenie.
You're a damn genius, baby.
Uh-Huh.
"I, pootie tang, do surrender
to lecter corp...
All the rights to
my image and likeness."
No.
Oh, yes, yes.
"I will wholeheartedly endorse all lecter corp.
Products...
"And will do my best to convince
the children of the world...
"That the above mentioned
are all clean, safe...
And should be bought
and used by all of them."
No, not
the tippi tais, no.
No, no. You are part of the corporation,
just like us.
Thought you could stay
out of it, huh?
Welcome aboard,
pootie tang.
Are you looking
for something, my friend?
Are you?
I've got it all now.
Shocking news today as beloved
pootie tang has agreed to endorse...
Several controversial
products for lecter corp.,
The infamous
giant corporation.
Yo, fellas,
somethin' on the tv about pootie tang.
Even my kids, man, looked up to him.
You know what i mean?
They don't even look at dad
like they look at him.
But now since he crossed,
man, my little--
My little man came up to me the other day and was like,
"Man, how could he do
that bullshit, man?
[Beep] that [beep]" i'm lookin' at him like, "whoa."
[Speaking spanish]
[Continues in spanish]
Pootie tang has made my children cry.
I'll not support him anymore.
Lecter corp.
Effectively owns the name pootie tang,
His image and all copyrights
that go along with it.
Mr. Lecter!
Mr. Tang has agreed to do several
commercials endorsing our sneakers,
Food products and cigarettes, whiskey,
mace, switchblades, rat poison.
[Woman] mr. Lecter,
can we have a statement--
* why you sell out,
pootie **
Pootie?
Oh, no!
You know, biggie shorty,
i got to say,
I always had a high opinion of pootie tang.
But the way things are going now,
not only has he sold out,
He's scraping
the bottom of the barrel.
Pootie tang was drugged
by that crazy-Ass ireenie.
- Haven't you been watchin' the movie?
- And that's what disturbs me.
He's out there telling kids not to go to school,
To eat fast food,
to do drugs.
This is not the pootie tang i thought
i knew and i used to admire.
- Pootie tang-- He would never tell kids like that.
- You're in denial.
He's out there doing dirt to his own reputation.
Look.
- You don't know pootie tang.
- I don't know pootie tang?
Believe me,
i know pootie tang,
And this is not the pootie tang i thought i knew.
You know what? I thought a man of
your stature would have better sense...
Than to fall
for no mess like that.
[Sighs] look,
this thing has all fallen apart.
The man used to be admired
by people of all walks of life.
And you know what?
If the world is gonna fall for this
mess about my pootie tang,
Then maybe the world
don't deserve pootie tang.
What do you think pootie tang
needs at this point in his life?
He just needs some
of my good lovin'...
And he will be all right.
- You watch.
- I hope you're right.
- I know i'm right.
- Yeah, we'll see.
Yeah, we'll see.
That's right.
Watch.
I will.
* You used to be a hero
* now you're just
a big, fat zero **
[Trucky]
pootie tang was messed up.
Punk bitch.
Sellout.
[Trucky] look at him.
Damn, pootie! Get a job, you bum.
Get it together, man.
Pootie looked like who did it and ran.
Pootie turned to the only woman who could help him.
Biggie shorty.
* Biggie shorty
* biggie, baby *
Pootie!
Aw, pootie.
Poor pootie tang.
Tippi tai.
That's all right.
Mama's got you.
Biggie shorty's
gonna take care of you.
Don't you worry.
Gonna have sex
with you too, you know.
Finally.
Are you sure you
gotta go, pootie?
Yeah.
[Sucks teeth]
that's a damn shame.
You were the best piece
of man i ever had.
You know,
you could just stay here and live between my bosoms...
For the rest
of your life.
Pootie gotta flittie tai,
biggie shorty.
Man's gotta do, i suppose.
I guess as long as you gone they can't
make you do no more commercials.
But where you gonna go?
I tell you what.
I got a little farmhouse outside of greenville.
It was my mama's. It ain't much,
but nobody's livin' there.
You go out there,
find yourself, blah, blah, blah.
But then you come
back to me, okay?
That's a fine tine, baby.
Now, give me some of that bony ass
one more time before you hit the road.
Man, i hates prison.
Prison sucks.
I reckon
it's supposed to.
You got somethin'
for me?
Oh! Oh!
Uh-Huh. Uh-Huh.
Mm-Hmm.
Oh!
Oh, this some fine dirt.
This is some good dirt.
Oh!
You know i'm gonna hook you up.
Man, i hate
these bastards.
They make me shower
every day.
They never let me get dirty.
I need to be dirty. I'm dirty dee, damn it!
Dirty dee.
Huh?
You gonna be dirty
again soon. I promise.
It's that pootie tang.
He got to be stopped.
I'm the one that's got to stop him.
Pootie goddamn tang!
* You gonna, you gotta
you gonna, you gotta **
Thank you.
[Trucky] pootie! Pootie!
Pootie! Pootie!
[Trucky] pootie was headed to the farm.
I wanted to go with him.
I wanna go with you, brother.
'Cause everything that happened was all my fault.
Pootie, everything that happened, man,
it's all my fault.
I told that bitch all about him.
I told this bitch all these things about you, man.
She just used it against him.
And she just used it against you.
I was sorry. I'm sorry, man.
I'm so sorry.
It was killing me.
Only did it for the ass.
Only did it for her ass, you understand.
That deri-Teri was
all the dinie, huh?
I felt like he saved my life.
Pootie, man, i just feel like...
You saved my life.
And i messed his all up.
Now i messed yours all up.
I wanted him to forgive me.
Can you ever forgive me, man?
Aw, trucky.
You my main damie, man.
Ain't no bad tammie
between us.
I wondered if he meant it.
You mean it?
I'm a baino denny.
I wanted to go to the farm with him.
Can i go to the farm
with you, brother?
Wa-Da-Tah!
All right!
Me and pootie going to the farm!
Whoo! You know,
i'm lookin' forward to this farm life.
Enough of the city
for me. Whoo!
Yeah, this is just
what we need, pootie.
Live off the fat
of the land, work hard.
Farming, farming, farming.
I can't wait, man.
I cannot wait.
We're gonna milk that cow.
Ooh-Whoo!
Get all that milk.
Two percent fat free.
Skim milk. All that, man.
Chocolate milk.
I don't need
no television, cappuccino,
Partying all night long.
I'm want some blisters on my hands,
some sweat on my back.
That's what i want, pootie.
[Grunts]
Shit!
Oh, man. My pants.
Oh, man! My damn pants.
All right.
Farming, farming, farming.
[Grunting]
This is not the thing, man.
This ain't cool, man.
Dirty shoes,
dirty pants,
Dirty shirt,
musty, stinky.
It's hotter than
a camel's hump out here, man.
And mosquitos all over my shirt.
I can't do it, man.
[Dog barking] whose dog is
this dog following me around?
Whose dog is that?
You don't know who dog that is.
That could be anybody's dog.
It's too hot.
You know you're hot.
* Rip
* sho' you right
* come on
* shing-A-Ling shing
shing-A-Ling shong *
shing-A-Ling shong **
[Trucky] i didn't wanna leave pootie,
but i wasn't trying to hear all that survival shit.
Outback, my ass.
I need conveniences, man.
On the other hand,
pootie was lovin' every minute of it.
He was rejuvenated.
You hear that? Rejuvenated.
He was "juvenated" before,
lost it...
And got "juvenated" again.
* That lasts
* all night long
* home of the omino
* home of the domino
* home of the two-Piece
and the pepper *
And when pootie planted
his first cornstalk,
- Damie.
- He was happy.
Too damn happy, if you ask me.
It was just corn.
* I'm a southern girl
* southern girl
* country-Fied but that was just what he needed...
To take his mind
off his troubles.
Rown on the crowny town.
* You so country, yo *
Mornin'.
Hi, daddy.
Not now, stacy, honey.
Listen. There's a new fella here in town.
He's coming in here in a minute.
So?
So? So maybe you can
marry him, that's what so.
Aw, daddy!
Oh, come on.
Cut that shit out, stacy.
Here he comes.
[Chuckles] [sobbing]
Yeah. Hey there.
You got your can
filled all right?
Oh. This here
is, uh, my daughter.
Stacy.
Dillie on,
My damie.
[Shrieks]
Oh!
And she's a looker,
ain't she? Huh?
* Oh, ah, ooh, baby *
Ah, dirty dee.
God, you stink.
Thank you.
I wanna talk to you
about pootie tang.
You mean public enemy number one in my world.
[All laughing]
Huh? Right?
We learned that anything
can be addictive.
We took our burgers and
pumped them so full of m.S.D...
That people can't even
taste real food anymore.
Today american kids don't eat
'cause they're hungry.
They eat 'cause they just gotta
have another lecter burger.
You see,
i own pootie's name.
He's mine.
I don't need him to sell my products anymore...
Because i've got thousands of them all over the country.
I'm just gonna give them the
clothes and this training tape.
And remember, when making
a public appearance,
Pootie tang always
struts like this.
Next week we're opening a brand-New
nationwide chain of burger stands.
Pootie's
bad time burgers.
As a matter of fact,
the only thing that could mess up our little party...
Is if the real pootie
showed up.
But that ain't
good enough.
I want him dead.
[Dirty dee] yeah.
I'd like to put that bitch in the ground myself,
but i ain't magical.
I been tryin' to get
that pootie for years.
He done jailed or offed all my boys.
All i got left is froggy.
Nobody know
where pootie's at.
I know where he's at.
I got people
everywhere, baby.
Nobody can hide
from corporate america.
And as far
as how to beat him,
Maybe this will help.
[Stacy]
hello?
Hello? [Trucky] uh-Oh.
Look at this.
Remember her? That's stacy,
the sheriff's daughter.
He's been trying to get her ass
married since she was 12 years old.
Hello?
Is anybody here?
Why, um--
I-I'm sorry. I, uh--
Well, i-I made you
a pie... cake. Um--
D-D-Do you want
the pie?
Ohh.
I-I-I know
i'm not pretty or--
Or sexy.
Y-Y-You--
You probably like a...
sexy girl, right?
Baby,
I'm gonna sine your pitty
on the runny kine.
[Screaming]
[Moaning, grunting]
Now, see, that's what makes
pootie tang a real hero.
He can't stand by and see
a woman not lovin' herself.
He's gonna put
the love in her.
Now, me, i say just
give her a compliment.
Hey, i like your shoes.
Have you been workin' out?
Girl, what you doin'
with your hair?
But i tell you what,
I'm only gonna buy this hero shit but so many times.
[Trucky] back in the big city,
all hell was breaking loose.
I'm talking about
drug dealin', drug usin',
Booty shakin',
too much damn tv,
Drinkin', people eating too much,
gettin' all fat and sloppy,
Fightin', kids out of school,
ain't nobody readin',
People actin'
a straight damn fool.
And corporate america
was just loving it.
Look at them.
It's a party now.
Since he left, it just changed.
Everything just went bonkers.
Everybody lost their mind
and what not.
Pootie tang,
you shouldn't do this.
You should come back to the city,
where you belong.
[Trucky] back on the farm,
the worst happened.
Pootie tang's cornstalk died.
And for the third time
in his life,
Pootie lost the only thing
that was important to him.
First his family, then his belt,
and now his corn died.
Farm life was
driving pootie crazy.
He must have lost his damn mind.
Look at him.
Down on his knees,
crying over a piece of corn.
Not even popcorn.
Regular damn corn.
Pootie tang had lost all hope,
And it was gonna take
a miracle to bring him back.
[Daddy tang]
pootie.
Pootie tang!
Up here, pootie.
Hey, watch the leaves.
Daddy?
You damn right i'm your daddy.
Pootie, what you doin' runnin' away from your problems?
- Did i teach you like that?
- [Mumbling]
Hey, don't you
mumble, boy!
[Cowbells ringing]
pootie, my boy.
Mama di.
Pootie, you're a good man.
I'm proud of you.
You have so much love in you,
and you can give it like a gift.
Your father was wrong to tell
you to guard it like a secret.
- W-W-What was that?
- Shut your mouth!
- Woman!
- You corn-Ass fool!
Pootie, teach the world
right from wrong,
But love the world
at the same time.
That's the key.
Where's your belt, boy?
You let some girl
get your belt.
You let the ladies
I knew that would happen.
Now you done lost all your confidence.
I'll tell you something, pootie,
ain't nothing special about that belt.
I bought it at piggly wiggly for 95 cents.
You don't never need
that belt, boy,
'Cause you got
the goodness in your heart.
Now you need to go out there
and take that and kick some ass.
[Mumbling] hey,
don't you mumble, boy!
Now, go out there,
take that goodness...
And teach the world
right from wrong.
Now git!
I, uh--
I think maybe you and me
got something to talk about.
I, uh--
I understand you and stacy there...
[clears throat]
Got to know
each other, huh?
[Bell dings]
Had yourself
a little time there, eh?
Huh? Huh?
Yeah.
[Laughing]
Oh, that's terrific!
Well, partner,
When's the wedding, huh?
Huh?
[Clicks]
Like i say, i sure would
be mighty proud...
To have you
for a son-In-Law.
**
* low-Down and dirty boy,
you know what i'm 'bout * [horn honking]
* stay out my way and
keep my name out your mouth *
** [continues]
What the hell?
Pootie tang!
Uh-Huh!
What you doin' way out here?
You know these guys?
I come to call you out,
maggot-Eatin' bitch!
You ain't come one,
but many tine tanies.
Well, i gets by with a little help from my friends.
Now, listen here, fellas,
we don't want no trouble here.
Why don't you just
move on through, huh?
What up, hopalong?
You just back off there, young man.
I'm sheriff of this here county.
[Trucky] damn! Hold up, hold up!
Rewind that. Go back. Go back.
Let me see that one more time!
I'm sheriff
of this here county.
Oh! That had to hurt his ass!
I know he's embarrassed.
Slap him like a bitch!
Pow-Ya! Ooh!
He shouldn't have done that.
He done messed around and got pootie tang mad, baby.
Come on, pootie!
Question:
where do you think you--
Wait! Hold up!
Hold up, pootie.
Yeah! Hah hah hah!
Capa-Town, my ass!
Oh, you not so bad
now, are you?
Huh?
Yeah.
[Belt hissing]
* make 'em say ugh, ugh
* na-Na na-Na
na-Na na-Na *
* make 'em say ugh
ugh, ugh, ugh *
* ugh, ugh, ugh
* make 'em say ugh *
Ugh, ugh.
Guess you, um,
Slapped him like
a bitch, huh?
[Chuckling]
yeah.
Now,
[Clicks]
like i was sayin'--
* i wanna be your man
* yes, i do
[Horn honking]
* i wanna be your man *
[Trucky] i was searching for pootie high and low,
Then i finally remembered
he was at the farm.
All this time i had been talking about the farm.
[Horn honks]
How the hell did i forget
he was at the damn farm?
Anyway, i got there
just in the nick of time.
Oh, pootie, you got
to come back to the city...
Right now.
What's the dabble, di?
Hey, there's a wedding
going on here.
Man, they are using
your face, man.
They're making you sell these products, man,
even when you're not there.
I'm talkin' about
cigarettes, man.
And look. Malt liquor?
Pootie tang malt liquor?
They got all these
pootie-Alikes, man.
You know what i'm saying?
Hawkin' all this shit.
And everybody thinks
it's you, man, really.
Come back to the city and let
everybody know the truth, man.
Come on!
All right, pootie tang!
Whoo!
Oh, ho ho ho!
I ain't the marrying type.
I don't make my bed.
I leave the toilet seat up all the time.
I'm a single--
Oh, but she is
a lovely lady though.
Pootie tang and i are thrilled
to be opening this,
The first pootie tang
bad time burger restaurant.
Right, pootie?
Sa da tay.
Sa da tay. Got that?
That ain't pootie tang.
That's doodie tang.
You know, that ain't
pootie tang neither.
I know it ain't
pootie tang!
I just said
it ain't pootie tang!
It's doodie tang!
Shut up!
Sepatown, tipi tais.
There you go.
[Tires screeching]
Oh, christ.
[Woman]
hey, that's pootie tang.
Wa-Da-Tah.
Don't pay attention to him.
That's nobody.
This is pootie tang here.
Yes. I'm pootie.
Now, clap it up, my hammies.
Rinatine, my america.
Coola may, my ca--
[Feedback]
You think you've
solved the problem?
Well, guess again.
[Whistles]
See, i got more pooties
than you, pootie.
You're not only late,
but you're outnumbered.
And by this time tomorrow,
there'll be so many pooties out there,
You won't matter.
Ha!
He ain't alone,
mr. Rich man. I'm here too.
Wa-Da-Tah!
Yeah, baby. Come on.
Come on.
Bitch!
[Cheering]
pootie! Pootie!
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
You lookin' at my ass?
Uh-Huh. You bastards
ain't going anyplace!
Bye-Bye, bad time!
All right!
I got 'em, pootie!
Capachow.
Yea! Yeah!
Pootie!
Pootie tang is back!
Pootie tang!
[Belt cracking] no, no!
No, pootie, no!
I got to say the nay-No,
my brother.
[Groaning]
What will you do now,
pootie?
We're gonna get married.
Yeah.
[Crowd cheering] [trucky] and
that's the way it went down.
Pootie tang got his man,
and biggie shorty got her man.
But not before she handled
one little piece of business.
[Doorbell rings]
Oh, hi.
Man, it is hot today!
Ooh, it's hot out here, man.
It is hot today!
You know, it's hot out.
Yeah, i just said that.
I said it's hot out here, man.
Yeah, you know,
it's hot too.
Yeah, that's why i said it, man!
It is hot out here!
I know. I'm just
saying it's hot too.
And as for me, trucky--
Oh, shit! My lasagna!
What?
Oh, goddamn it, trucky!
I can't believe you burned
that lasagna again!
Who i look like?
I'm not chef boyardee!
You've been burning things
since the day--
You know, that is the longest
damn movie clip i've ever seen.
But then again,
you're pootie tang.
Well, sa da tay.
Exactly. Pootie tang,
it's been biddie having you by.
Ah, bob, i dabe ba samie,
my brother.
Cole me on the panny sty.
I'm sorry.
What was that?
Cole-- Cole me
on the panny sty.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Cole me down
on the panny sty?
Oh, cole me down
on the panny sty!
All right! Thank you, pootie tang,
thank you! Yeah, baby, yeah!
Hey, pootie tang, pootie tang,
pootie tang, pootie tang!
Oh, i love him!
I love pootie tang!
Oh! Oh!
Pootie! Pootie!
Oh, he's so sexy!
He's so sexy!
I love pootie!
Aah! Pootie!
Oh, pootie!
Oh, pootie tang!
Aah! Aah!
Oh, i love you, pootie!
Aah!
[Man] cut!
** [Instrumental] pootie tang got three gold records.
Pootie get all the grammies because he's pootie tang.
Yes, he's terrific.
I don't think he's so great.
[Music stops]
Uh-Oh. Uh-Oh, girl.
Uh-Oh, now.
Pootie's got you now.
Ha ha! Pootie about to make
reservations on you now, girl!
Oh, girl,
the red phone is blinkin'!
It's over for you now, baby.
It's over now for you. You know it's over, girl!
He done got you in the radar, baby.
Pootie got you now, girl!
Whoo!
Red phone ringin', baby!
Red phone ringin'.
Red phone-- Ow!
Man's gotta do, i suppose.
I guess as long as you gone,
they can't make you do no more movies.
Oh! No more movies.
[Man] let's do that line again.
I'm gonna sine your pitty
on the runny kine.
[Screaming]
**
* i'm gonna sine your pitty
on the runny kine *
We don't like no trouble
around here, you know.
It's a quiet town.
You look all right though.
A little weird though,
ain't ya?
That's my panny, di.
Well,
I suppose so.
Yeah, baby,
it's time to get dirty!
Yeah!
* Low-Down and dirty
* boy, you know
what i'm 'bout *
* stay our my way and
keep my name out your mouth *
* 'cause i'm low-Down, dirty
out-Fist ya early *
* stay up early
to catch the worm *
* now, you can slip if you wann
let me get you on the corner *
* believe me, you receivin'
some bodily harm **
Yeah.
I can't hear a word you're saying
'cause i got earplugs in, my man.
But i'm gonna try somethin'.
Yeah!
[Man] boom! That's it.
And everybody run away!
Run, run, run, run, run!
No, pootie stays!
[Crew laughing]
[Crew cheering]
**
* see, right about now
it's going down like this *
* little j, baby
* yeah, yeah, yeah
* pootie tang, baby
* motown, baby * whoa, whoa,
whoa whoa, whoa, whoa *
* hey, you know what
* i'm gonna get things my way
* 'cause i know how to play it
in the right way *
* 0-7-365 days
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa *
* and y'all sing his name
* little j
* girl, sing his name
* whoa, whoa, whoa
whoa, whoa, whoa *
* little j *
I'm gonna sine your kitty
on the sepatime.
**
[Belt cracks]
* whoa, pootie tang
* you gonna sine that pitty
pootie tang *
* you gotta sine that pitty
* you gonna, you gotta
you gonna, you gotta *
[Pootie tang] i'm gonna sine
your pitty on the runny kine.
* Pootie tang gonna
love the ladies *
* pootie tang gonna
sabe his damies *
* pootie tang, be careful
the children *
* pootie tang gonna
dai on the dildren *
he gonna, he gotta *
* he gotta
* whoa, if you're
sellin' drugs *
Baby, i'm gonna sine
your pitty...
On the runny...
Kine.
Man! Pootie
done did it again!
* Ohh
7-0-2.
* Oh, oh, oh
* oh, oh, oh
whoa, oh, oh, oh *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* pootie is a shot-Callin' player
stackin' nothin' but papers *
* he gets his mack on with flavor * * always playin'
* when he goes out kickin' and clubbin'
or when he's with b.B bumpin' *
* he knows the ladies they love him * * pootie tangin'
* and he's got this look in his eyes
like i'm his number one prize *
* and yet still he
maintains composure *
* so when you're doin' your thing do it like pootie tang *
* he hangs for some time
we get to know ya *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* pootie, you know
you're one in a million *
* you speakin'
what you be feelin' *
* and now you got me
i'm willin' *
* wanna breathe the air
that you're breathin' *
* shall we tell you the reason i
think i'm what you be needin' *
* come on,
baby let's take a ride just wanna be by your side *
* got a feeling like
it's my duty *
* to let you share my world
just wanna be your girl *
* 'cause i like the way
you're tangin', pootie *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* hey
* ooh ohh
* ooh
* boy, you kill me
* ooh, he's pootie tangin'
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
* if you think
you're pootie tangin' *
* on the dance floor shake your thing it's all right,
all right *
Capachow.
Sepatime.
Wa-Da-Tah.
Yeah, baby.
Sa da tay.