TULIE [SINGING]:
♪ Gather 'round, you'll hear a sound
♪ Ancient and mysterious
♪ Where banshees cry and goblins sigh
♪ In manners dark and curious
♪ In the swamp where gators swim
♪ There's much to fear, you'll see
♪ But the spirits float adrift
♪ On the bayou breeze
♪ Mission bells and voodoo spells
♪ The sounds of witches shrieking
♪ Listen close, you'll hear a ghost
♪ Or a zombie choir weeping
♪ In the swamp, the spiders bile
♪ It's wild, I guarantee
♪ How the spirits float adrift
♪ On the bayou breeze
♪ In the swamp, them spiders bile
♪ It's wild, I guarantee
♪ How the spirits float adrift
♪ On the bayou breeze
♪ On the bayou breeze. ♪
Well, hello there. Come on.
Come, come, come. Have you a seat.
Kick them shoes off you.
Shh. But not too loud, now.
You see, me, I'm fixing to have me
some gumbo tonight.
And them catfish
can get mighty skittish, yeah.
Whoa. Whoa.
What...? Oh, no, you don't.
You get back, you!
Get back, y'all loony lizards!
I'm going to have y'all for my gumbo.
Oh, what...?
[LAUGHS]
Oh, that's a leech.
Oh, you cute little critter.
Yeah, yeah, that's right.
[GULPS]
[ANIMAL SCREECHING NEARBY]
You know what that was?
Me neither. Hoo-hoo!
But it could be one of them vampires.
They all around these parts, yeah.
Look here.
That's the jewels
of a vampire bride, y'all.
I found them down the bayou.
They're some kind of pretty, eh?
But let me tell y'all, she didn't
wanna get married to no vampire, no.
And who can blame her? Who would?
But she was forced to.
And then came a talking dog...
Whoop. I done almost spoiled the ending.
Heh.
We got to start at the beginning, cher.
And that,
that happened along way from here.
VELMA [OVER RADIO]: Scooby, Shaggy,
you guys spot anything yet?
- Uh-uh.
- Call me crazy, Scooby...
- ...but don't these pipes look familiar?
- Kind of.
SHAGGY: Didn't we run into
that big rat creature down here?
That was two weeks ago, Shaggy,
in the New York sewers.
How could you forget?
Wasn't that the glop monster?
The glop monster was on Saturday.
Remember?
Rat creature, then glop monster,
then snake-osaurus.
They're all starting to merge.
Better get ready for this one, Shaggy,
because it's coming.
I know. It's coming our way.
That was on Saturday too.
[WHIMPERS]
[HOWLING]
SCOOBY:
Huh?
[WHIMPERS]
[YELLS THEN GRUNTS]
[SCREECHES]
[WHIMPERS]
[SHAGGY & SCOOBY SCREAM]
- Hang on.
SHAGGY: It's huge!
We're coming.
Whatever you do, don't let it eat you
before we get there.
[SHAGGY & SCOOBY WHIMPERING]
[SQUEAKING]
Oh, it's just a common cockroach.
There is nothing common
about a cockroach.
Is it singing?
Not singing. Signaling.
Signaling to what?
To that cockroach.
[SCREECHING]
[BOTH SCREAM]
DAPHNE:
Gross!
Glad I brought a giant roll of flypaper.
Oh... Unh!
[FRED MUMBLING]
There, that's better.
Or not.
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
VELMA:
Mr. Clapper.
Of course.
He was using the cockroach monster...
...to drum up customers
for his exterminator company.
Just as I thought, guys. Guys?
[SCOOBY WHIMPERS]
[FRED GRUNTING]
[SQUEAKING]
Ew! Get it away!
I think we could all use a nice vacation.
Vacation?
FRED: No, Daphne.
SHAGGY: Don't do it. We're begging you.
DAPHNE:
I'm sorry, guys, but I have to do this.
SHAGGY: No!
SCOOBY: No!
Show tunes make road trips
so much better.
[UPBEAT SHOW TUNE
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
The songs do get stuck in your head.
Tell us about it.
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Well, I don't hear Velma complaining.
Did you say something?
Oh, are we still listening to show tunes?
You all complain now, but I bet
you'll be singing along in no time.
SHAGGY: Ha, ha. You hear that, Scoob?
SCOOBY: Yeah.
[SCOOBY LAUGHS]
So, Velma, you ever gonna reveal
our secret vacation destination?
Not till we get there.
You guys are gonna love it.
Just as long as
they've got plenty of sunshine.
There is only one thing Scooby-Doo
and I are hoping for this vacation.
[SINGING] ♪ I don't want no more ghouls
♪ Or nothing scary
♪ No apparitions giving me a fright
♪ Don't want nothing
that I need to bury
♪ Or creatures that go
bumping in the night
[BOTH LAUGH]
DAPHNE: ♪ No poltergeists
and nothing supernatural
♪ No giant beast
♪ That sneaks up from behind
[BOTH LAUGH]
♪ No ghosts that rattle chains
♪ Or things that eat your brains
♪ No banshee witch
♪ That scares me out of my mind
♪ We're finally on vacation
♪ And going someplace new
SCOOBY:
♪ Rest and relaxation
ALL:
♪ Is all we're gonna do
FRED:
♪ I don't want no zombies or kooks
♪ My friends, we're finally done
♪ With all them goblins and spooks
♪ That kept us on the run
♪ We're gonna be cool as cukes
♪ Our monster days are through
♪ - No demonic beast and nothing
deceased SCOOBY:♪ It's time to relax
SHAGGY:
♪ And that's what we're gonna do
[ALL SCATTING]
VELMA: ♪ No more frown
♪ We're moving down the road now
♪ Keep that metal pedal to the floor
♪ We haven't got a clue
♪ Where we're headed to
ALL: ♪ But it's somewhere
♪ That we've never been before
DAPHNE & VELMA:
♪ Cruising down the highway
♪ Free without a care
♪ It feels bizarre because
♪ There are no werewolves anywhere
♪ Don't want no dragons or freaks
♪ And no crazy evil sprites
♪ I don't want no
phantom that shrieks
♪ Haunting us every night
♪ I don't want no Comic-Con geeks
♪ Walking up out of the blue
DAPHNE & VELMA:
♪ Dressed like bats and 7-fool rats
♪ Chasing me down and saying
♪ "How do you do?"
[ALL SCATTING]
♪ Lift your hand up high
♪ Let it wave goodbye
♪ To them gremlins
and monsters galore
♪ Tell them all we're gone
♪ 'Cause we're moving on
♪ And we ain't coming
back any more. ♪
[ALL SCATTING]
Hey, look, our destination.
See? Show tunes really do
help pass the time.
DAPHNE:
"Petit Chauve Sourie Ville"? Ooh.
[DAPHNE SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
Like, it sounds monster-free to me.
Hoo-hon!
Yeah, up top.
What does the French translate to?
Oh, it means "Little Bat Town."
- Uh-oh.
- Not to worry, Scoob.
Velma promised us this place would be
ghost-, ghoul-, and goblin-free.
What? Whoa!
[BOTH SCREAM]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[MAN GRUNTS]
[VELMA & FRED GASP]
[BOTH YELL]
Hey, I'm stalking here! I'm stalking here!
She didn't say anything about vampires.
Didn't I?
[DAPHNE CHUCKLES]
Mm, must've slipped my mind.
[BOTH WHIMPER]
Shaggy, Scooby, you can come out.
It was just a kid in a costume.
Like, you sure?
Absolutely. He's probably just here
for the vampire festival.
BOTH:
Oh.
Vampire festival?
VELMA:
Yup, Vampire Palooza.
You brought us to a vampire convention?
To relax?
Not a vampire convention.
It's a celebration of all things vampiric.
Cool. And what better place
to experience it than Little Bat Town.
Ooh! Vampires are so romantic.
Have you read Silverlight?
Twelve times. I'm hoping
the author will be here to sign it.
Are we missing something here?
Like, what's so romantic about
undead creatures who sleep in coffins...
...prowl the night in search of victims,
steal their blood...
...and turn them
into their zombie servants?
Oh, those are old-school vampires.
Modern vampires are fun and super-cool.
Vampires don't sleep in coffins any more.
They sleep in Seattle.
[VELMA CHUCKLES]
- You're not making us feel better.
- Uh-uh.
Says here this place was founded
in the 19th century...
...by Abraham Van Helsing, the famous
vampire hunter of Dracula fame.
And it's still owned by
one of the Van Helsings' descendants.
So it's like a ghost town.
No, a vampire ghost town.
[BOTH WHIMPER]
This is the last time
we let you pick the vacation spot.
- Yeah.
- Relax, guys.
There's absolutely nothing to fear.
Hey, Scoob,
when have we heard that before?
Every day of our lives.
You guys worry too much.
Well, we're not the only ones.
This fair is an abomination,
an affront to all that is good and decent.
[CARNIVAL MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Sign the petition to ban vampires?
- Like, that's a cause we can support.
- Mm-hm, mm-hm.
Here there be demons.
Here there also be corn dogs.
Fools. Fools, I say.
Will you allow temptation to lure you
into the fangy den of the bloodsucker?
Pretty much. Corn dogs!
Corn dogs, yum.
[SHAGGY CHUCKLES]
Hey, Scoob, if the food's this good
outside the festival...
...I can't wait to see
what they've got inside.
Guys, there's no such thing
as real vampires.
SCOOBY:
Mm.
No such thing
as paying customers either.
[SIGHS]
Five more complimentary passes.
I'll be lucky to break even this year.
Like, not exactly the kind of bite
I'm looking for.
[LAUGHS]
We're guests of Vincent Van Helsing.
- He owns...
- Yes, yes.
I'm Lita Rutland, owner of the festival.
I know who Van Helsing is.
Unfortunately no one else does.
[GRUNTING]
[SNORING]
[GRUNTS]
Imagine a vampire author
in these vampire-crazed times...
...who doesn't sell any books.
Maybe he's just having an off day.
Yeah, maybe.
He's still one of the foremost authorities
on vampire history.
Perhaps, but the world's moved on
from his old-school vampire tales.
Well, I've read all his books.
I think.
Well, you kids enjoy your free lunch. I
mean, your time here at Vampire Palooza.
She's friendly.
Velma.
It's good to see a familiar face.
And this must be the rest
of the famous mystery-hunting crew.
Guys, I'd like you to meet our host...
...the world's foremost expert
on vampires...
...Vincent Van Helsing.
A pleasure.
You know, I'm also an author.
Perhaps you've read my books?
My vampire tales are fact-based.
And not that lusty teen tripe
that's all the rage these days.
Yeah, that modern stuff is way lame.
Hey, did you guys know
Mr. Van Helsing...
...is the great-great-great-grandson
of Abraham Van Helsing?
FRED:
Wow, a direct descendant...
- ...of the famous vampire hunter for real?
- It's true.
My family has been in the vampire
business for a long time.
That's why I became a vampirologist.
A vampire-what-igist?
Uh, vampirology is the academic study
of the vampire from A to Z.
Come, I'll show you.
VAN HELSING:
My collection of vampire artifacts...
...go back to the very dawn
of the vampire.
FRED:
This stuff is fang-tastic.
Heh. Get it?
I used the word "fang" instead of "fan."
[CHUCKLES]
We get it.
Wow, the ancient book of vampire.
I thought only one copy
of this existed in the world.
You're looking at it.
Check out these awesome stakes.
- Steaks? Where?
- Yummy.
[FRED CLEARS THROAT]
- Oh, those kinds of stakes.
- Aw.
Look at these vampire jewels. Gorgeous.
VAN HELSING: Those belonged
to an actual Vampire's bride...
...in ancient Walachia.
Looks like she scored
a wealthy vampire husband.
VAN HELSING:
They're quite priceless.
But those stones don't compare
to the real jewel of my collection.
A face to launch 100 million fears.
I bring you the dreaded vampire
Lord Valdronya.
Entombed in glass
for nigh a thousand years.
- Oh, my gosh.
- Wow!
Awesome.
- Looks fake to me.
- Me too.
[BOTH SCREAM]
The vampire lives!
Guys, don't be ridiculous.
- His eyes were glowing!
SCOOBY: Mm-hm.
You'll have to excuse them.
They tend to be slightly excitable.
Perfectly understandable.
Lord Valdronya was quite
the fearsome fellow in his day.
We're lucky he's sealed under glass now.
This glass is so murky.
- Ah, Velma, always the skeptic.
- Eh, it's my thing.
Even if the vampire were alive,
he wouldn't get anywhere.
This glass is 6 inches thick.
If only Valdronya would wake...
...I'd have tourists filling this place
like back in the day.
And I wouldn't have
to rent my property...
...to Lita Rutland's
traveling vampire festival just to get by.
Sounds rough.
Lita's threatened to pull out next year
if things don't pick up.
I'm afraid I may not be able
to save my family's legacy.
Then again,
you never know what will happen.
Maybe my latest book
will become a best seller.
You write books? That's fu... Ow.
- Don't we have a show to see?
- Ah, yes. We'd better get going.
The vampires await.
[BOTH YELL]
Wait for us!
VAN HELSING: Our tickets are
being held in the box office. Wait here.
I'll be right back.
VELMA:
"Fangenschanz."
Fangenschanz?
I've heard of them.
They're supposed to be the most amazing
vampire-themed theater troupe ever.
Here, Scoob.
Wear this garlic for protection.
- Vampires hate it.
- Yeah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
you can't bring garlic in here.
SHAGGY: "No wooden stakes, garlic
or flash photography."
Huh. Well, I hate to let
perfectly good food go to waste.
No garlic on us.
Ugh. Gross. Just go inside.
Weirdos.
Hello.
[WOMAN GRUNTING]
Ew, someone's wearing
some stanky perfume.
[SCOOBY & SHAGGY SNIFFING]
- I don't smell it. Do you, Scoob?
- Nope.
VELMA:
According to the program...
...the members of Fangenschanz are so
dedicated to the vampire lifestyle...
...they perform only at night.
Method actors.
[DRAMATIC ORCHESTRAL MUSIC
PLAYS OVER SPEAKERS]
Ladies and gentle mortals,
it's feeding time.
[UPBEAT JAZZ MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[SINGING]
♪ What's that you hear?
♪ The sound of fear
♪ Because they're here
♪ Vampires roaming the night
♪ What's that you say?
[SNARLING]
♪ Can't be, no way
[GIRL SHRIEKS]
♪ They're fake?
♪ Okay
♪ Believe whatever you might
♪ But when the moon is full
♪ On a starlit night
♪ You best all lock
your doors up light
♪ Because, my friend
♪ The vampires start to dance
ACTORS:
♪ And they're all around you
♪ Everybody's coming to play
♪ Oh, yes, they found you
♪ And now they're
gonna lake you away
♪ So watch out, lake care
♪ Be smart, beware
♪ Because out there
♪ Something's waiting for you
♪ When midnight comes,
it's time to hide
♪ Say good night and run inside
♪ Because that, my friend, is when
♪ They all come out again
♪ Oh, yes, right now is when
♪ The vampires dance
♪ The vampires dance. ♪
Boo!
Yeah!
[WHISTLES]
What? I'm just showing my appreciation.
[WHISTLING AND CHEERING]
We welcome you,
friends and potential blood donors.
And while we are mere performers,
be warned.
If you fear the sight of a real living
vampire, please, leave now.
That's our cue.
[BOTH WHIMPERING]
[BRAM LAUGHS]
Too late.
And now for the first time on any stage,
we shall attempt the unheard of:
The Vampire's return from the grave.
[LAUGHS]
Wow, he's very good.
Don't you guys think he's good?
Like, good?
FRED:
Meh.
Behold the ancient talisman
of the immortal blood-drinkers.
Take heed, for the mortal world
shall soon be invaded.
[ALL CHANTING IN ANCIENT TONGUE]
Blackest rose, wolf and bane
Bats and crows.
That spell is from
the ancient book of vampire.
These jokers are playing
with supernatural fire.
[CHANTING CONTINUES]
[GASPS]
What the...?
[GUARD YELLS]
[ACTORS SHOUT INDISTINCTLY]
It's working?
[ALL snum]
Uh... Uh...
[GRUNTS]
This is bad. This is very bad.
[GRUNTING]
That's not Henry.
Oh, no.
[ROARS THEN SCREECHES]
[LAUGHS]
WOMAN:
Whoa.
[WOMAN CHUCKLES]
[CHATTERING]
[SCOOBY WHIMPERING]
- Next year, we're going to Miami.
- Yeah.
I was getting ready before the show
when I was attacked by that vampire.
Are you sure?
Unless you know someone else with
massive fangs and glowing green eyes.
I guess he put me under some sort of spell
and I passed out.
That resurrection chant
was from the ancient book of vampire.
Where on earth did you learn it?
Um, the Internet.
Well, I am afraid you may have unleashed
an unholy terror upon us all.
Maybe we shouldn't
jump to conclusions just yet.
Yeah, I'm sure this nice young man...
Uh, I didn't get your name. Oh.
Bram. And you are?
[CHUCKLES]
Bram. I mean, Daphne.
I'm not Bram, you are. Ha-ha-ha.
Oh. What were we talking about?
We were saying we don't know for sure
that Valdronya escaped from his tomb.
Oh. Uh, we should check that out.
You kids go ahead.
I'll stick around here to have a word
with the actors.
You guys can't hide forever.
SHAGGY: Care to try us?
- No. Let's go.
SHAGGY: Careful.
GUARD: Unh.
- He's been bitten.
- Hmm. Maybe. Or...
VELMA:
We've got bigger problems.
Unh. This lid is still sealed tight.
Well, that vampire couldn't have
just walked through the glass.
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[MAN LAUGHING]
The vampire queen's jewels are gone.
Jinkies.
[BOTH GASP]
[VAMPIRE LAUGHS THEN SCREECHES]
DAPHNE:
Duck!
No, bat!
Such beauty and innocence...
...with the countenance of a queen.
My queen.
Your queen?
FRED:
I don't think so.
[VALDRONYA GRUNTS]
[SHAGGY GRUNTS]
[SNARLS]
Yeah, there's no such thing
as real vampires, until now.
There's a beast on the loose,
a spawn of the netherworld.
I say it's time we shut this foul fair down
for the good of the community.
Uh, set it up over there
by that rabble rouser.
Hello, Kelly Smith
from KDTV Action 10 News.
Looks like someone spilled the beans
about our escaped vampire.
The audience thought
it was all part of the show.
- Hope you're not implying my performers-
- I leaked it.
You? But..
This could be just the thing we need
to boost attendance.
Ah. They do say there's no such thing
as bad publicity.
That's the spirit. Now,
which would you say is my good side?
VAN HELSING: I am so relieved
that none of you kids were hurt last night.
Not physically,
but the mental wounds run deep.
Yeah, run deep.
Those foolish actors have no idea
the monster they've set loose.
We can't be certain this is their doing.
Or that we've got a real vampire
on our hands.
Did you check the museum's
security system?
Yep, the cameras recorded nothing.
System's on the fritz, but I just
can't afford to fix it right now.
Let's say it is a real vampire.
How did he escape that sealed tomb?
A living vampire can transform into mist.
All it would need
is a tiny gap in the glass.
This could all be a diversion
to steal those jewels. Just saying.
GUARD:
Oh, what a night.
Thanks for letting me sleep here, boss.
No problem, Daniel.
I hope you're feeling better.
Neck's a little sore,
but other than that...
[BOTH SCREAM]
The bite of the beast.
He could turn batty any second.
Doubtful. If he had been bitten
by a vampire, could he survive this?
Sunlight makes a vampire explode.
Wow, gorgeous day outside.
- Huh?
- He didn't crumble to dust.
He could be one of the rare few with
an antibody resistant to vampire venom.
Or he wasn't bitten at all.
Those look more like blisters than bites.
When you were attacked, did it feel like...
...oh, I don't know,
a thousand volts of electricity?
Uh, actually, yeah. How'd you know?
I volunteer at the police academy
on weekends.
If there's one thing I know,
it's Taser burns.
[GRUNTING AND YELLING]
That tickles.
- Pretty good detective work, pal.
- Thanks.
Well, we also found your Taser
lying on the ground next to you.
I must've tripped and zapped myself.
Huh.
Weird.
I'd better go put that in my report.
That explains the bite marks,
but how do you explain the vampire?
So many questions.
It's quite the conundrum.
A real whodunit.
We'll need to put our heads together
on this one.
Uh-oh.
I know where this is going.
Yep, I'd say we've got a real live
boney fide mystery on our hands.
Eyewitness accounts aside...
...we've had no confirmation
of the supposed vampires' existence...
...from anyone associated with the fair.
LITA:
You want confirmation?
No one is safe.
I'm here to tell you
from firsthand experience...
...that vampires bite.
So much for keeping this
on the down-low.
[SINGING] ♪ Gather 'round, hear me now
♪ Listen up, 'cause I vow
♪ There's a vampire
roaming the night
♪ He had wings and a snout
♪ With these fangs hanging out
♪ That can rip and can
tear when they bite
♪ He flew down from the skies
♪ With those red glowing eyes
♪ And he smiled and I knew in a sec
♪ He had come there for me
♪ 'Cause he leaped up in glee
♪ Then he pounced
♪ And he bit me on the neck
[CROWD GASPS]
♪ Yes, I screamed and cried out
♪ "It's a vampire!"
♪ I escaped and ran into the light
♪ I held up one of these
♪ And we all saw him freeze
♪ Then he shrieked in the night
♪ And flew off out of sight
♪ Be advised and be scared
♪ Be alert, be prepared
♪ Buy this garlic we
have here on sale
♪ Gel a charm for your neck
♪ We lake cash, we lake check
♪ And ship free, COD
through the mail
♪ How 'bout this vampire spray?
♪ It keeps dandruff away
♪ Sold in tonic and lotion or mist
♪ Here, these potions we make
♪ And this big wooden stake
♪ At a price that you
just can't resist
♪ We lake MasterCard, Visa and Chase
♪ Not Discover
♪ We're open till 9 every night
♪ Not on Sunday
♪ In bulk, any size
♪ Then our discount applies
♪ So invest in the best
♪ Bring ID or a check
♪ And buy one of each
♪ Maybe two, what the heck
♪ You can't be loo safe
♪ When protecting your neck
♪ From the vamp
♪ The vampire's bile ♪
[LITA LAUGHING]
DAPHNE: Looks like Lita's little
press conference was good for business.
BOYS [IN UNISON]:
Aah! Vampire!
Where? Where?
[GROWLING]
[RATTLING]
[LAUGHS]
Fred, don't tell me
you're buying into the hype.
[CHUCKLES]
Of course not.
Want a bite of this garlic pizza?
It has magical protective powers.
[LAUGHING]
Having a vampire on the loose is the best
thing that's ever happened to this festival.
Hasn't boosted my book sales.
- It just did.
- Why, thank you, Lita.
You want it signed?
Sure, make it out to "receptacle."
Trash receptacle.
- Huh?
- Ha-ha-ha!
SHAGGY:
Hey!
It's getting so you can't find a safe place
to hide anywhere.
Vampires are all around us, people.
Now, keep alert.
You hear that, Scoob?
Let's move, move, move.
Hey, Poubelle,
I told you to get off the property.
You're scaring away the customers.
I'm here with Jesper Poubelle from the
Society for Moral and Wholesome Living.
Jesper, how can people slay safe
from vampire attacks?
They can join in our crusade of moral
righteousness against supernatural evil.
Together we can stamp out
the vampire scourge.
VELMA:
I've heard enough.
That guy is becoming
quite the media star.
More like milking the situation
for everything it's worth.
I think it's time
we pay Mr. Poubelle a visit.
POUBELLE: That's right. This is
a certifiable, undeniable crisis, people.
It is high time we institute
a dusk-to-dawn curfew.
I'll keep Poubelle occupied.
You guys see what you can dig up.
POUBELLE:
...Overreacting.
But ignore this warning
and you'll be knocking on the doors to...
Shaggy, you and Scooby stand watch.
If anyone comes, tap on the door.
We're in.
[SQUEAK]
Wow, what a wreck.
They may be moral and wholesome,
but they're not very clean.
We've got hundreds of reports
of vampire sightings.
Couldn't people be imagining these things
because you're causing them to panic?
I didn't create the evil.
Maybe not, but you sure seem to be eager
to take advantage of it.
Young lady, your questions
were not cleared with my staff.
Someone check her credentials.
Uh, I think I left them in the car.
Fred, I found something.
Ew, I hope it's not more spiders.
"Poubelle for mayor"?
What are you two doing back here?
SHAGGY: Um, uh...
SCOOBY: Uh... Uh...
- We're, uh...
- We're door inspectors.
Stand back. This one might explode.
[SHAGGY & SCOOBY GRUNT]
Doors don't explo...
Why'd you signal?
Stay right where you are.
Run away!
[SHAGGY YELLS]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Get in!
GUARD:
Hey, stop that thing! Stop!
[ALL SIGH]
DAPHNE:
Poubelle is running for office.
That explains a lot.
He's using the vampire to get attention
for his movement...
...and boost his upcoming campaign.
Still, it isn't proof
he's behind the vampire attacks.
He's just using them to his advantage.
This fog is like soup.
Maybe you should let me drive.
I'm good. Sort of enjoying it.
[SNARLS]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[VALDRONYA GRUNTING]
[DAPHNE SHRIEKING]
[THUD]
[VALDRONYA LAUGHS THEN SNARLS]
Daphne, look out!
Brace yourselves!
[ALL SCREAMING]
That opening is too tight.
We won't make it.
[DAPHNE GASPS]
[SHRIEKS]
I'm telling you, Poubelle,
you can't come in here.
You're scaring off my customers.
And I'm telling you, I've got a special
dispensation from the sheriff himself.
That's right, Ms. Rutland.
By order of the court,
I have recruited these gentlemen.
We are hereby deputized
vampire hunters.
[SIGHS]
Vampire hunters, ho!
MAN: All right.
WOMAN: Let's go.
[CHATTERING]
Who would actually fall
for that scaremonger's rantings?
They say there's a fraidycat
born every minute.
Ah, there you are. I got us all
neck protectors, just to be safe.
I see your point, Velma.
Hey, where are Scooby and Shaggy?
They went to the food court
to calm their nerves.
Heh. Those guys are so jumpy.
[NOISEMAKER RATTLING]
FRED:
Yaah! A vampire!
The food court should be right here
behind the theater.
Unless the map is upside down.
[SCOOBY CHUCKLES]
Careful. Damage anything
and we're as good as dead.
What are you doing back here?
This is a restricted area.
We're just looking for the food court.
Uh-oh.
- We can't let them go.
- What if they tell someone...
- ...what they've seen?
- You're right.
Uh, what have we seen?
Scooby, I think we're in...
Hey, look, a Hollywood talent scout.
[BOTH WHIMPERING]
I think we lost them.
[GROWLING]
BOTH:
Huh?
We better find that food court, Scoob
Your tummy's grumbling.
Not mine.
Well, it isn't mine.
[SNARLING]
[ROARS]
Stay back or I'll be forced to use this.
Maybe later!
[SHAGGY YELLING]
I've been bitten by a vampire!
[GIRL GASPS]
Look, Mama, a real vampire.
[SNARLING]
[ROARS]
[HUMMING]
SHAGGY:
Incoming!
[YELLING]
Phew. He's gone, Scoob.
And I'm a goner.
I've been bitten by a vampire.
I'll probably sprout fangs any second
and...
Is this ketchup?
Bloodsuckers!
BOTH:
Where?
That one shape-shifted into a dog.
Uh-oh.
- I think they mean us.
- Get them!
[CROWD SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Appears we lost
them crafty shape-shifters.
I guess we best head back
before our torches burn out.
MAN 1: Yeah.
WOMAN: All right.
MAN 2:
Oh, well. Maybe next time.
Ah. Phew. We're safe, Scoob.
Except for the fact we're lost in a swamp.
And I could turn into a vampire
at any moment.
[GRUNTS THEN WHIMPERING]
Check out my bite. Is it bad?
Don't sugarcoat it. I know I'm done for.
You should get out of here
before I turn all bat-ified.
Uh-uh. I'm not going.
Once the vampire venom
takes hold of my system...
...there's no guarantee
I won't sink my fangs into you.
We have to split up, Scoob.
No, Shaggy. No.
It's the only way to save yourself.
Just turn away from me
and don't look back.
[SCOOBY WHIMPERING]
I can't.
I guess I'll have to do this myself.
Huh?
SHAGGY:
Goodbye, old friend.
I hope one day you'll see that
this is best for both of us.
Shaggy?
[WHIMPERING]
One foot in front of the other.
Don't look back. Don't ever look--
[WHIMPERING]
I looked back.
[LAUGHS]
[SCOOBY LAUGHS]
- Shaggy.
- Promise you'll never leave me, Scoob.
Never.
[CHUCKLES]
Wha--? What are you doing?
Checking for vampire symptoms.
Say "ah."
Ah.
Scoob, you're the best pal
a guy could have.
A real friend to the end.
[SINGING]♪ Whenever I'm down
♪ Right there on the ground
♪ Lying out flat on my face
♪Who is the pup
♪ Picking me up
♪ And gelling me back in the race?
♪ Who'll be around and watching my back
♪ Guide me along and keep me on track?
♪ Forever he's there
♪ We're a pair
♪ Scooby and me
♪ When the going gels tough
♪ - And things can gel
♪ - Rough
♪ - You're the one on whom I depend
♪ - Who, me?
♪ - I'll give you the proof, I'll' climb up on the--
♪ - Roof
♪ And shout to the world
♪ "You're my friend!"
[HOWLS]
♪ And when I'm a vampire
♪ Roaming the night
♪ Because you're my pal
♪ I'll just lake a small bile
♪ You're one of the greats
♪ And we're males
♪ Scooby and me
[SCOOBY CHUCKLES]
♪ Oh, Scooby and me
♪ We're gonna be together for good
♪ That buddy of mine
♪ If you're ever in doubt
♪ Need me helping you out
♪ You know that would if I got time
♪ If you're ever in jail
♪ And you're needing some bail
♪ Or a friend to set you free
[SCOOBY YELLS]
♪ You can always count on me
♪ 'Cause tell me where would I be
♪ Without you by my side
♪ My friend and my guide
♪ Helping to carry me through
♪ People go by
♪ If I live or I die
♪ They wouldn't care, but not you
♪ You are the one who keeps me at ease
♪ - Giving me love and occasional fleas
♪ - Sorry
♪ No matter what comes
♪ We are chums
♪ Scooby and me ♪
Yep.
[LAUGHS]
In the interest of public safety, I am
hereby issuing a dusk-to-dawn curfew.
- No one is to be out past dark.
POUBELLE: Yes!
[CROWD CHEERING]
Now that is more like it.
This extreme measure is seen as a victory
for local anti-vampire crusader...
...and now mayoral candidate,
Jesper Poubelle.
[SINGING] ♪Closing us down
♪But that isn't fair
♪ I'm warning you all
♪ You belle! Beware
♪ You're messing with me
♪ And you'll see
♪ You're all gonna pay
♪ Oh, I'm broke, I'm ruined
♪ What will I do?
♪ Oh, what happens
♪ When the rent is due?
♪Oh, watch out, my friends
♪ There's vampires on the loose
♪ And that's why I brought the noose
♪ You just kif fed
the golden goose ♪
ACTORS: Oh, got a show to do
CROWD: Vampires here.
ACTORS: Curtain up
CROWD: Run them out of town.
Hey, Scooby-Doo.
ACTORS: Opening night revue
CROWD: Bad show.
ACTORS: Don't give up
CROWD: It's time to shut them down.
What would! do?
They're to blame, it's true.
Poubelle, shame on you.
We're not the same as you.
Where would I be without you?
[HOWLS]
Scooby and me We always will be.
- Together forever as friends.
- Gel out, don't want vampires.
- You are the one, second to none.
- Leave us because.
- The pal on which a buddy depends.
- We know the show goes on.
They are the ones
They're evil and bad.
Watch out for them
They're crazy and mad.
What do you do when there's vampires
Where there shouldn't be?
- Listen to me.
- You can't do this to me.
Doesn't anyone see?
Why'd this happen to me?
It's always going to be
Scooby and me
[BIRD SQUAWKING]
Scooby, I think we've got company.
[ANIMAL TRILLING]
[SNAKE HISSING]
[SHAGGY & SCOOBY WHIMPERING]
But critics call the move shortsighted and
a slinging blow to the local economy.
[VAN HELSING SIGHS]
It's an assault on capitalism.
Disgusting.
This is the last time I bring my fair
to this Podunk town.
Without the income from Lita's festival,
there's no way I can keep this place afloat.
I'm ruined.
We'll try to solve this mystery
before Lita packs up for good.
Thank you, Velma.
I'm really lucky to have you kids here.
FRED:
Hey, guys.
I'm worried about Shaggy and Scooby.
I haven't seen them since last night.
They probably got spooked by
their own shadows and hid out all night.
I just hope the vampire didn't get them.
I highly doubt we're dealing
with a real vampire.
Show him, Daphne.
I found this in the Mystery Machine.
It's a piece of the Vampire's cloak.
I must've torn it loose
when he attacked us.
What's an old piece of fabric
gonna prove?
It's not old.
It's clearly poly-krillion, a synthetic
material first produced in 1997.
Girlfriend knows her fabrics.
[CHUCKLES]
So the vampire, or whatever it was,
probably isn't a thousand years old.
Oh, what a relief.
I mean, not that I thought
we were dealing with a real vampire.
That would be dumb to think that.
Actually I must confess...
...the outfit Valdronya was wearing
in his tomb was new.
How? You said he was sealed in his tomb
for a thousand years.
Yes, but his clothing
had disintegrated overtime.
We unsealed him briefly for authentication
and in the name of modesty.
Valdronya's clothing had disintegrated,
but he didn't. That's odd.
A vampire is a living being,
even in a state of slumber.
This is what's left
of his original garments.
Antique Asian silk.
Spun gold markings.
The thick hand weave.
Fabric like this hasn't been made
for 500 years.
Valdronya is still out there.
Think I'll just grab these things.
[WHISTLES]
I'm afraid those actors unleashed
an unholy terror upon us all.
Yes, the actors.
Ooh. I'll go check them out.
I bet you will.
Freddy, do I detect a little
twinge of jealousy?
Me, jealous of some vitamin D-deprived,
historical vampire reenactment nuts?
[CHUCKLES]
Maybe I should go with you.
No, thanks.
I'm well prepared to handle Bram.
Uh... I mean, the actors. Bye.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
Hmm.
Hello? Anyone in here?
[CLANGING]
Strange place for a laser projector.
[DAPHNE SHRIEKS]
Bram. Don't sneak up on a girl like that.
I wasn't the one sneaking.
You looking for something or someone?
Actually, I... Do you sleep up there?
To know the vampire,
you must become the vampire.
Hm. You're really committed.
It's the role I was meant for.
So do you lurk around
darkened theaters often?
More than you know.
Well, there's something
we have in common...
- ...right off the bat.
- Cute.
Grab on. I'll teach you to fly.
I don't know. Promise not to drop me?
Only a fool would drop a girl like you.
Smooth.
Wow, this is amazing.
It's fate that brought you here.
Destiny. A cosmic occurrence.
A vision foretold.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Bram, I think you're very interesting,
but you're one cliché from my limit.
Daphne.
[SINGING]
♪ From the moment you'd first seen us
♪ Did you ever in your life think
♪ You'd be standing here with me?
♪ With this thing we have between us
♪ I could tell that it was fate
♪ And it was always meant to be
♪ Yes, you and! were meant for glory
♪ And something greater
♪ Than this drab little world that we see
♪ And who'd have thought that later
♪ You and! would have this dale
♪ A dale with destiny
♪ I can't believe you think I'd buy that
♪ Come on, I've heard this all before
♪ It's just a line, I'm not naive
♪ I really can't believe you'd try that
♪ I've gotta say you must be nuts
♪ To think that's something I'd believe
♪ You lay it on there kind of heavy
♪ With all this talk of something special
♪ So, what could it be?
♪ What if I say I know a way
♪ To immortality? ♪
Really?
[SINGING]
♪ You and! could live forever
♪ You mean our lives would never end?
♪ That's right
♪ And we won't be aging ever?
♪ You'd be Bram's immortal friend
♪ - For real?
♪ - That's the deal
♪ - Can't you feel, it's so exciting?
♪ - Everlasting life eternal
♪ You've been chosen for this honor
♪ You'll have wealth and you'll have fame
♪ I gotta write this in my journal
♪ Just wail and see
♪ Everyone will know your name
♪ - Will I slay cute?
♪ - Absolute
BOTH:
♪ We'll be going down in history
♪ We'll be known throughout the world
♪ Eternity for you and me
♪ Let's live forever and ever
♪ Yes, never to sever
♪ Together forever, we'll be
♪ You and me ♪
I'm gonna have to say thanks, but no.
Points for trying though.
This makes us very unhappy.
Well, I'm sorry, but... Us?
[ALL SNARLING]
Seize the Vampire's bride.
The what?
[GRUNTS]
[YAWNS]
Where are we?
No clue, Scoob. Not that it matters.
This swamp is as good a home as any
for a vampire and his canine pal.
- Except for the leeches.
- Leeches?
[BOTH YELLING]
[BOTH SIGH]
But, hey, we won't let a few little leeches
spoil things, will we, Scoob?
No way.
[CHUCKLES]
[BOTH YELL]
SHAGGY:
Snake!
Gators!
Crawdads!
Snakes and gators and crawdads.
Oh, my.
I think we need a new life plan,
Scooby-Don.
Shaggy, look.
A tin shack. It's a dream come true.
Remember, Scoob, don't say anything
about me being a vampire.
Okay.
- Company? Come on in, cher. Hoo-hon!
SHAGGY: Whoa!
Sit you down a spell
while I put on that gumbo.
Gumbo?
Like, man, our luck has changed, Scoob.
My name's Tulie.
That's not my real name, no.
But that's what it say on the shack,
so I go with that. Hoo-hon!
Hon! Look at that right there.
Now we cooking some kind of yeah.
How come you live way out here
in the middle of nowhere?
Well, if you must know, I'm on the run.
- From what?
- Vampires!
Ooh, I hate them, me.
And if I ever catch me one,
I'm going to grind his bones for stew.
Maybe we should be going.
Stay right there.
It's gumbo time.
SCOOBY:
Ah.
Well, I wasn't always a crazy old hermit.
I used to be a handsome inventor
of fantastical devices.
Oh, yeah? What'd you invent?
Gadgets, whatchamacallits, thingamajigs.
Stuff that go:
Buzz, buzz, hoppity-hoppity, hoop!
I had me a little shop over there
at Petit Chauve Sourie Ville...
...where I sold things...
...the most popular item being a hat
with two cup holders and along straw...
...so you could have two soda pops
while you're watching that ball game.
Like, wow, ha, ha,
you invented the drinky hat?
[LAUGHS]
No, but I sold them in the store.
Ain't nobody ever bought my inventions
because, like I said, they mostly just went.
Bleep, bleep, bloop, bloop,
hoop, hoop.
But then I created
the greatest invention ever:
Flying shoes.
They're based on the same principle
as a hover boat.
But the fans be pointed down
to lift you off the ground.
Whoo-whoo-whoo! There you go.
And I was all set to show them
to a big shoe company...
...when a vampire attacked me
and stole the prototypes.
Well, I filed me an insurance claim.
But it turns out
they don't cover vampire attacks.
Hoo-hon.
That's awful.
More, please.
Me too.
I was ruined, y'all.
I've been living out here
in the swamp ever since.
And that is why
I hates me them vampires.
Like, how long ago did this happen?
I don't know, long as
I've been growing these here whiskers.
Maybe two, three weeks now.
Oh, well, that's life.
You know, sometime you lose everything
on account of vampires...
...sometime you don't. Ha, ha.
How y'all like the gumbo?
Amazing.
Amazing. Mm-mm-mm.
Yeah.
That's because of my special ingredient.
Heh.
Leeches.
I likes to put them leech in the gumbo.
Leech gumbo. Yum. That's good, yeah.
[SHAGGY YELLS]
BOTH:
Thanks for everything.
Y'all come back anytime!
[GRUNTING]
[GUN COCKS]
Look at this. The stolen jewels are part of
some sort of vampire wedding ceremony.
VAN HELSING:
The vampire bonding ritual.
According to legend, if the vampire
takes the soul of his mortal bride...
...he'll gain unbridled power.
VELMA: The ceremony must take place
upon the third moon...
...following the Vampire's release
from captivity.
That's tonight.
If Valdronya succeeds,
he'll be unstoppable.
Unstoppable? Not if I can help it.
Maybe vampires were tough to catch
back in the day, but times have changed.
There's a new breed of vampire hunter
on the scene: me.
Vampire hunting
is serious business, Fred.
You must be prepared for anything.
Oh, I'm prepared, all right.
[VELMA & VAN HELSING YELL]
Gotta watch that hair trigger.
Not so fast.
The vampire has the jewels...
...but he still needs one thing
for the wedding: a bride.
Not just any bride.
A mortal beauty, pure of heart.
That could take a while to find.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hey, it's a text from Daphne.
"Been kidnapped by vampire actors.
Help!."
A mortal beauty, pure of heart.
- Daphne.
- Jinkies.
I knew those actors
were involved somehow.
According to the book...
...those who offer up the Vampire's bride
will be rewarded with immortality.
That's a heck of a finder's fee.
Any idea where they'll take her?
I saw a star chart in here pointing out
the precise coordinates of the ceremony.
We could make a copy.
- Or that.
- Let's move.
If the wedding takes place, Daphne
will become the bride of the vampire.
You know, I'm pure of heart.
Does anyone ever think
of kidnapping me? No.
Uh, Velma, focus.
Sorry.
Tonight we give Valdronya the king
his queen.
And we shall be rewarded
with eternal life as real vampires.
All hail Valdronya!
[GRUNTING]
Relax, Daphne.
It's just your soul you're giving up.
Easy for you to say.
You obviously never had one.
We're close.
Stop. Did you hear that? In the trees.
[RUSTLING AND SQUAWKING]
[BOTH GASP]
Must have been my imagination.
[YELLS]
- Hang on.
- Save yourselves.
[YELLS]
SHAGGY:
Zoinks!
I got something. Come on.
- Shaggy?
- Nice shooting, Fred.
Scooby, what are you guys doing
in the swamp?
Yeah, don't you know
it's dangerous out here?
- Clearly.
- Yeah.
The calibration is still off.
Let's get you down from there.
Don't get too close, Velma.
I've been bitten by a vampire.
I could turn bloodsucker any second.
That's no bite. It's a splinter.
[SHAGGY YELLS THEN THUDS]
So I'm not gonna turn
into a bloodsucking weirdo?
Bloodsucker? No.
Weirdo? We're too late for that.
Fire in the hole.
[ALL YELL]
Still off.
Maybe it's best if you set that thing
to net mode from now on.
The appointed hour is near, my friends.
And soon our efforts will be repaid
with immortality.
A jewel for a jewel.
[DAPHNE GRUNTS]
You're such the charmer.
You are so lucky to be chosen.
I'm sure you'll find an evil vampire king
of your own one day.
Let the wedding ceremony begin!
[DRAMATIC ORCHESTRAL MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
ACTORS [SINGING]:
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah
♪ Dearly beloved
We're gathered today
♪ To praise the one called Daphne
And give her away
♪ Linked and joined forever
She'll be by your side
♪ Valdronya, we present you
Your vampire bride ♪
- Looks like we're in time for the wedding.
- Wedding?
I wish someone had told us.
We don't even have a gift.
I've got a gift right here.
- Huh?
- I don't get it.
He means we're gonna stop the wedding
from happening.
My way sounded cooler.
ACTORS [SINGING]:
♪ Hear us now, Valdronya
♪ And come to our side
♪ The time has come for claiming
Your vampire bride
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah
♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah ♪
Behold, the king has heard our call.
This is it. Here he comes.
[SNARLS]
Bow down before your king.
[GASPS]
Excellent work, my little vampire-lings.
[SINGING] ♪ Close your eyes
♪ And come to me
♪ When you wake
♪ Then you shall be
♪ Alive for all eternity
♪ With me
[ALL SINGING IN ANCIENT TONGUE]
♪ Dark of the moon and
beauty so bright
♪ Spirits arise and
call to the night
♪ From Earth to the stars
And all that's between
♪ Beware and behold
the vampire queen ♪
[GRUNTING]
A mortal beauty.
Your queen.
SHAGGY:
Hold it.
Hi. Uh, mind if I get a picture
of the happy couple?
[ROARS]
That one's for the memory book.
Ha, ha. Yikes!
[SNARLING]
[SHAGGY YELLS]
[GRUNTS THEN PANTING]
[YELLING]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTS]
[SNARLING]
[GASPS]
[BOTH YELLING]
Daphne, you okay?
Ha, ha. Velma, you came to my wedding.
Oh, don't cry, Velma.
You won't always be a bridesmaid.
I'm not crying.
Valdronya's using gas
to hypnotize everyone.
[SCOFFS]
Whatever you've gotta tell yourself.
Ha, ha.
SHAGGY:
Like, that is one unhappy groom.
[SNARLS]
[STAKE GUN BEEPING]
Come on. I must have gotten water
in the compressor.
Keep him busy while I fix this thing.
- Aah!
- Dead end!
Whoa!
In more ways than one!
[SNARLS]
[LAUGHING]
Yipe!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
Ha-ha-ha. Hm?
DAPHNE:
Ahem. Here's your stupid amulet.
[SNARLS]
Nice shot.
- He-yah!
- Unh!
Actually, Velma,
I kind of wanted to keep that.
Sorry.
I'll make you all my vampire servants.
[VALDRONYA YELLS]
[ALL COUGHING]
[GRUNTS]
I'd say you're looking at a net loss.
I think I'll raise the stakes.
[GROANS]
Let's see who's under that mask.
Like I've been saying all along,
there's no such thing as real vampires.
Right, Mr. Van Helsing?
ALL:
Van Helsing?
But why?
He was trying to save
Petit Chauve Souris Ville...
...by staging a series
of real live vampire events.
Events tied to his latest book,
The Bride of the Vampire...
...which I actually read. It's not bad.
You really liked it?
I said it's not bad. Don't push it.
So by creating a real vampire legend,
he'd get tourists year-round.
And sell books.
[SIGHS]
It's true.
I wanted to put the Van Helsing name
back on the map.
I thought once word spread
of the ceremony...
...tourists would flock here
to see the place...
...where a real live vampire
wedding ritual had happened.
Then I would no longer need
Lita Rutland...
...and her schlocky Vampire Palooza
to make ends meet.
And what about the actors?
VELMA:
Merely pawns in his game.
They were so devoted to the vampire
way of life, they were easily duped.
When Valdronya first appeared, they really
thought their ritual had conjured him up.
Van Helsing used their intense belief
in vampires against them.
But Van Helsing was in the audience when
Valdronya materialized in the theater.
DAPHNE:
He used a laser projector for that.
VELMA: I'd wager he planted
similar projectors in the museum...
...to give the illusion of the vampire
in the glass coffin.
Security cameras rewired for
special effects would explain a lot...
...including why there was no surveillance
footage of Valdronya's supposed escape.
When Daphne tore off a piece of modern
fabric from Valdronya's cloak...
...Mr. Van Helsing must've feared the
threads of his plot were unraveling...
...so to speak.
Looking at it now...
...I suspect he passed off ancient
fabric from his museum as a cover-up.
He staged his own demise in the swamp
using this.
BOTH:
Aah! Vampires!
No, a simple mechanical device
he planted in the marsh.
Probably a prop from the theater.
So when he was kicking and flailing...
He was actually triggering it.
But, like,
how did he hypnotize everyone?
Knockout gas.
No one knew what hit them.
But when they awoke,
they remembered seeing Valdronya...
...and thought he'd mesmerized them.
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
By gassing everyone at the wedding,
he'd slip away...
...but leave eyewitnesses to tell the
tale of Valdronya and his bride.
The actors already lived like vampires,
so they could just go on like that...
...thinking they were actually immortal.
You've really thought of everything.
Eh, it's what we do.
Daphne, I... I'm sorry
for putting you through all this.
Well, it's not every day a girl is kidnapped
to be an ancient Vampire's bride.
In a strange way, I'm flattered.
Really? Maybe after I get out of prison,
we could grab a coffee and...
Heh. Not on your life, bat boy.
I don't date actors.
Move along, fella.
Like, there's one thing
about this whole plan I don't get.
Why'd Van Helsing need us?
You were my credible witnesses.
It's one thing to have a bunch of
weirdo vampire-reenactment nuts...
...spreading my tale.
Quite another
when the story is recounted...
...by respected monster hunters
such as yourselves.
We're respected?
My family's legacy
would have been restored.
Not to mention,
you would have sold loads of books.
That too.
[SIGHS]
Wow, like, that is one elaborate plan.
And I would have gotten away with it,
if not for you meddling...
Let's go, Van Helsing.
Well, gang,
it looks like another mystery is solved.
[SINGING] ♪ I don't want no more ghouls
♪ Or nothing scary
♪ No vampire creatures
giving me a fright
♪ No ghosts that rattle chains
♪ Or things that eat your brains
♪ Or monsters that go flying
♪ Through the night
♪ We're going on vacation
♪ And heading somewhere new
♪ Rest and relaxation
♪ Is all we're gonna do
♪ Want no more actors or kooks
♪ Van Helsing's scheme is done
♪ With all his vampire spooks
♪ And now it's time to run
♪ We're gonna be cool as cukes
♪ Our monster days are through
♪ No demonic beast
♪ And nothing deceased
♪ It's time to relax
♪ And that's what we're gonna do ♪
[ALL SCATTING]
[English - US - SDH]
TULIE [SINGING]:
♪ There is only one thing Scooby-Doo
and I are hoping for this vacation.
[SINGING]
[BOTH LAUGH]
DAPHNE:
SCOOBY:
ALL:
FRED:
SCOOBY:
SHAGGY:
ALL:
VELMA:
DAPHNE & VELMA:
ALL:
[DRAMATIC ORCHESTRAL MUSIC
PLAYS OVER SPEAKERS]
Ladies and gentle mortals,
it's feeding time.
[UPBEAT JAZZ MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[SINGING]
[SNARLING]
[GIRL SHRIEKS]
ACTORS:
[WHIMPERING]
Boo!
[SINGING]
[CROWD GASPS]
[LITA LAUGHING]
[SINGING]
[SCOOBY CHUCKLES]
[SCOOBY YELLS]
Sorry.
Yep.
[LAUGHS]
[SINGING]
CROWD:
Gel out, don't want vampires.
ACTORS:
Leave us because.
We know the show goes on.
[SINGING]
BOTH: