[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[DRUM CADENCE]
[BAND PLAYS76 TROMBONES]
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
ALL ABOARD!
LET HIM GO, ORVILLE.
I GUESS WE MADE IT PLAIN
WE DON'T WANT
NO MORE TRAVELING SALESMEN
IN BRIGHTON.
CREDIT'S NO GOOD
FOR A NOTION SALESMAN.
HOW FAR YOU GOING,
FRIEND?
WHEREVER THE PEOPLE ARE AS GREEN
AS THE MONEY, FRIEND.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH CREDIT?
IT'S OLD-FASHIONED.
YOU'RE AN ANVIL SALESMAN.
YOUR FIRM GIVE CREDIT?
NO, SIR!
NOR ANYBODY ELSE.
NEXT STATION STOP,
RIVER CITY, IOWA.
♪♪ CASH
FOR THE MERCHANDISE ♪♪
♪♪ CASH FOR
THE BUTTONHOOKS ♪♪
♪♪ CASH
FOR THE COTTON GOODS ♪♪
♪♪ CASH FOR
THE HARD GOODS ♪♪
♪♪ CASH
FOR THE FANCY GOODS ♪♪
♪
♪♪ CASH FOR THE SOFT GOODS ♪
♪♪ CASH FOR THE NOGGINS ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE PIGGINS
AND THE FIRKINS ♪♪
♪♪ CASH
FOR THE HOGSHEAD ♪♪
♪♪ CASK, AND DEMIJOHN ♪♪
♪♪ CASH
FOR THE CRACKERS ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE PICKLES
AND THE FLYPAPER ♪♪
♪♪ LOOK, WHADDYA TALK? ♪♪
♪♪ WHADDYA TALK?
WHADDYA TALK? ♪♪
♪
♪♪ WHERE
DO YOU GET IT? ♪
♪♪ YOU CAN TALK,
YOU CAN TALK ♪♪
♪♪ YOU CAN BICKER,
BICKER, BICKER ♪♪
♪♪ YOU CAN TALK ♪♪
♪
♪♪ TALK, TALK, TALK,
BICKER, BICKER, BICKER ♪
♪♪ YOU CAN TALK
ALL YOU WANT TO ♪♪
♪♪ BUT IT'S DIFFEREN
T THAN IT WAS ♪♪
♪♪ NO, IT AIN'T,
NO, IT AIN'T ♪♪
♪♪ BUT YOU GOT TO KNOW
THE TERRITORY ♪♪
♪♪ SHH SHH SHH
SHH SHH SHH ♪♪
♪♪ IT'S THE MODEL "T"
FORD MADE THE TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ MADE THE PEOPLE
WANT TO GO ♪♪
♪♪ WANT TO GIT,
WANT TO GIT ♪♪
♪♪ WANT TO GIT UP
AND GO ♪♪
♪
♪♪ 7, 8, 9, 1O, 12 ♪
♪♪ 14, 22, 23 MILES
TO THE COUNTY SEAT ♪
♪♪ YES, SIR,
YES, SIR ♪♪
♪♪ WHO'S GONNA
PATRONIZE ♪♪
♪♪ A LITTLE, BITTY
2-BY-4 ♪♪
♪♪ KIND OF STORE
ANYMORE? ♪♪
♪♪ WHADDYA TALK?
WHADDYA TALK? ♪♪
♪♪ GONE WITH THE HOGSHEAD,
CASK, AND DEMIJOHN ♪♪
♪♪ GONE WITH THE SUGAR BARREL,
PICKLE BARREL, MILK PAN ♪♪
♪♪ GONE WITH THE TUB
AND THE PAIL AND THE TIERCE ♪♪
♪♪ EVER MEET A FELLOW
BY THE NAME OF HILL? ♪♪
HILL?
HILL? HILL?
NO!
♪♪ JUST A MINUTE,
JUST A MINUTE ♪♪
♪♪ NEVER HEARD OF ANY
SALESMAN HILL ♪♪
♪♪ HE DOESN'T KNOW
THE TERRITORY ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT'S
THE FELLA'S LINE? ♪♪
♪♪ NEVER WORRIES
ABOUT HIS LINE ♪♪
♪♪ OR A DOGGONE THING ♪♪
♪♪ HE'S JUST A BANG-BEAT
, BELL-RINGIN' ♪♪
♪♪ BIG-HAUL, GREAT-GO,
NECK-OR-NOTHING ♪♪
♪♪ RIP-ROARIN' ♪♪
♪♪ EVERY-TIME
A-BULL'S-EYE SALESMAN ♪♪
♪♪ THAT'S PROFESSOR
HAROLD HILL ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT'S THE FELLA'S LINE?
WHAT'S HIS LINE? ♪♪
♪♪ HE'S A FAKE AND DOESN'T
KNOW THE TERRITORY ♪♪
♪♪ WHADDYA TALK? WHADDYA TALK?
WHADDYA TALK? WHADDYA TALK? ♪♪
♪♪ HE'S A MUSIC MAN ♪♪
♪♪ HE'S A WHAT?
HE'S A WHAT? ♪♪
♪♪ HE'S A MUSIC MAN ♪♪
♪♪ HE SELLS CLARINETS
TO THE KIDS IN TOWN ♪♪
♪♪ WITH THE BIG TROMBONES
AND THE RAT-A-TAT DRUMS ♪♪
♪♪ BIG BRASS BASS,
BIG BRASS BASS ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE PICCOLO,
THE UNIFORMS, TOO ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A SHINY GOLD BRAID
ON THE COAT ♪♪
♪♪ AND A BIG RED STRIPE
RUNNING-- ♪♪
♪♪ WELL, I DON'T KNO
W MUCH ABOUT BANDS ♪♪
♪♪ BUT I DO KNOW YOU
CAN'T MAKE A LIVING ♪♪
♪♪ SELLING
BIG TROMBONES ♪♪
♪♪ NO, SIR ♪♪
♪♪ MANDOLIN PICKS,
PERHAPS ♪♪
♪♪ AND HERE AND THER
E A JEW'S-HARP ♪♪
♪♪ NO, THE FELLOW
SELLS BANDS ♪♪
♪♪ BOYS' BANDS ♪♪
♪♪ I DON'T KNOW HOW
HE DOES IT ♪♪
♪♪ BUT HE LIVES
LIKE A KING ♪♪
♪♪ AND HE DALLIES
AND HE GATHERS ♪♪
♪♪ AND HE PLUCKS
AND HE SHINES ♪♪
♪♪ AND WHEN
THE MAN DANCES ♪♪
♪♪ CERTAINLY, BOYS,
WHAT ELSE? ♪♪
♪♪ THE PIPER PAYS HIM ♪♪
♪♪ YES, SIR ♪♪
♪
♪♪ WHEN THE MAN DANCES ♪
♪♪ CERTAINLY, BOYS ♪
♪♪ WHAT ELSE? ♪♪
♪♪ THE PIPER PAYS HIM ♪♪
♪♪ YESSSSSSSSIR ♪♪
BUT HE DOESN'T KNOW
THE TERRITORY!
RIVER CITY!
STATION STOP RIVER CITY!
JUST CROSSED THE STATE LINE
INTO IOWA.
POPULATION RIVER CITY,
2,212.
CIGARETTES ILLEGAL
IN THIS STATE.
ALL ABOARD!
IF YOU'RE ALL THROUGH,
I'LL TELL YOU
ABOUT HAROLD HILL.
SAY, YOU KNOW HILL?
I NEVER SAW HIM
IN MY LIFE,
BUT I'VE JUST BEEN RUN OUT
OF TOWN BECAUSE OF HILL.
HE'S GIVEN EVERY ONE
OF US A BLACK EYE.
YOU GO INTO TOWN
TO CALL ON THE TRADE,
AND THEY'RE WAITING FOR YOU
WITH TAR AND FEATHERS
TO RIDE YOU OUT THE CITY
LIMITS ON A RAIL.
HOW DO YOU ACCOUNT
FOR A THING LIKE THAT?
THIS HILL GOES AROUND
SELLING BAND INSTRUMENTS
AND UNIFORMS
AND INSTRUCTION BOOKS
BY GUARANTEEING
TO TEACH THE KIDS TO PLAY.
STANDS TO REASON.
ORGANIZES THEM KIDS
INTO A BAND
WITH HIMSELF
AS THE LEADER.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THAT?
HE DON'T KNOW
ONE NOTE FROM ANOTHER!
A BASS DRUM
FROM A PIPE ORGAN!
HE'S A BARE-FACED,
DOUBLE-SHUFFLE,
TWO-BIT THIMBLERIGGER,
AND I'LL CATCH UP
WITH HIM ONE OF THESE DAYS.
I'LL HAVE THE LAW
ON HIM SO QUICK!
TERRITORY'S TOUGH ENOUGH
WITHOUT HIM FOULING UP THE NEST.
I'D LIKE TO BE AROUND
WHEN YOU CATCH UP WITH HIM.
I WON'T CATCH UP
WITH HIM IN IOWA.
HE'S TOO SMART TO PULL
THAT FLIMFLAM OUT HERE.
NOT ON THESE
NECK-BOWED HAWKEYES.
GENTLEMEN,
YOU INTRIGUE ME.
I'LL HAVE TO
GIVE IOWA A TRY.
DON'T BELIEVE
I CAUGHT YOUR NAME.
DON'T BELIEVE I DROPPED IT.
UH, SIR...
THAT'S
A FINE-LOOKING ANIMAL.
FOR A HORSE, YEAH.
GOOD MORNING,
NEIGHBOR.
COULD YOU KINDLY
DIRECT ME
WHICH WAY IS
THE CENTER OF TOWN?
RUNS RIGHT DOWN
THE MIDDLE OF THE STREET.
EXCUSE ME, FRIEND,
WHERE WOULD I FIND
A GOOD HOTEL?
TRY THE PALMER HOUSE
IN CHICAGO.
I'M A STRANGER
IN YOUR TOWN.
WHAT DO YOU FOLKS
DO AROUND HERE
FOR EXCITEMENT?
MIND OUR BUSINESS.
♪♪
♪♪ YOU ARE IN IOWAY
IOWAY?
I ALWAYS THOUGHT
YOU FOLKS PREFERRED IOWUH.
WE DO.
HE JUST SAID IOWAY.
WESAY IT
NOW AND THEN,
BUT WE DON'T LIKE
ANYBODY ELSE TO.
♪♪ WE ARE FROM IOWAY ♪♪
YOU FOLKS CERTAINLY
DO KNOW HOW
TO MAKE A BODY
FEEL AT HOME.
♪♪ OH, THERE'S NOTHING
HALFWAY ♪♪
♪♪ ABOUT THE IOWA WAY
TO TREAT YOU ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN WE GREET YOU ♪♪
♪♪ WHICH WE
MAY NOT DO AT ALL ♪♪
♪♪ THERE'S
AN IOWA KIND ♪♪
♪♪ A SPECIAL CHIP-ON-THE
- SHOULDER ATTITUDE ♪♪
♪♪ WE'VE NEVER BEEN
WITHOUT ♪♪
♪♪ THAT WE RECALL ♪♪
♪♪ WE CAN BE COLD AS A FALLING
THERMOMETER IN DECEMBER ♪♪
♪♪ IF YOU ASK ABOUT
OUR WEATHER IN JULY ♪♪
♪♪ AND WE'RE SO
BY-GOD STUBBORN ♪♪
♪♪ WE CAN STAND
TOUCHING NOSES ♪♪
♪♪ FOR A WEEK
AT A TIME ♪♪
♪♪ AND NEVER SEE
EYE-TO-EYE ♪♪
♪♪ BUT WHAT THE HECK? ♪♪
♪♪ YOU'RE WELCOME ♪♪
♪♪ JOIN US AT THE PICNIC ♪♪
♪♪ YOU CAN
EAT YOUR FILL ♪♪
♪
♪♪ OF ALL THE FOOD
YOU BRING YOURSELF ♪
♪♪ YOU REALLY OUGHT TO GIVE
IOWA A TRY ♪♪
♪♪ PROVIDED YOU ARE
CONTRARY ♪♪
GOOD MORNING,
MAYOR SHINN!
IT IS IF YOU WANT TO
GO AROUND IN YOUR
DRAWERS ALL DAY.
♪♪ WE CAN BE COLD AS A FALLING
THERMOMETER IN DECEMBER ♪♪
♪♪ IF YOU ASK ABOUT
OUR WEATHER IN JULY ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ AND WE'RE SO BY-GOD STUBBORN
♪
♪♪ WE CAN STAND TOUCHING NOSES ♪
♪♪ FOR A WEEK AT A TIME
AND NEVER SEE EYE-TO-EYE ♪♪
♪♪ BUT WE'LL GIVE YOU
OUR SHIRT ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE BACK
TO GO WITH IT ♪♪
♪♪ IF YOUR CROP
SHOULD HAPPEN TO DIE ♪♪
♪♪ SO
WHAT THE HECK? ♪♪
♪♪ YOU'RE WELCOME ♪♪
♪♪ GLAD TO HAVE YOU
WITH US ♪♪
♪♪ EVEN THOUGH WE MAY NOT
EVER MENTION IT AGAIN ♪♪
♪♪ YOU REALLY OUGHT TO GIVE
IOWA ♪♪
♪♪ HAWKEYE, IOWA ♪♪
♪♪ DUBUQUE, DES MOINES,
DAVENPORT ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ MARSHALLTOWN, MASON CITY
♪♪ KEOKUK, AMES, CLEAR LAKE
♪♪ OUGHT TO GIVE
IOWA A TRY ♪♪
MR., UH, SQUIRES.
I'M INTERESTED
IN A RIG FOR SUNDAY
IF YOU CAN ACCOMMODATE ME.
THEN YOU OUGHT
TO SEE THE MAN
IN CHARGE
OF HIRING RIGS.
RIGS?
RIGGS?
AIN'T NOBODY HERE
BY THAT NAME.
MARCELLUS!
MARCELLUS WASHBURN!
GREGORY!
OF ALL THE PEOPLE
TO RUN INTO IN IOWA!
GREGORY!
SHH! PROFESSOR HAROLD HILL'S
THE NAME THIS TRIP.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
YOU WERE COMING?
I DIDN'T KNOW I WAS, MYSELF.
I NEVER THOUGHT I'D FIND
A SLICKER LIKE YOU
OUT HERE IN THE HAILSTONE
AND SARSAPARILLA BELT.
THIS IS
WHERE I WORK.
YOU MEAN
YOU LIVE IN THIS TOWN?
YEAH!
I LIKE IT, TOO.
IT'S NOT BROOKLYN,
NEW YORK, BUT...
BROOKLYN?
THIS ISN'T EVEN DUBUQUE.
HEY, ARE YOU
HIDING OUT OR WHAT?
NO. JUST NOT
AS LIGHT ON MY FEET
AS I WAS WHEN I WAS
SHILLING FOR YOU.
YOU'RE IN A BUSINESS,
GOT A LOT OF CLOSE SHAVES.
I GOT A NICE JOB NOW
AND A NICE GIRL,
ETHEL TOFFELMIER,
THE BOSS' NIECE.
SO YOU'VE GONE
LEGITIMATE, HUH?
I KNEW
YOU'D COME TO NO GOOD.
WHAT ARE YOU SELLING?
LAST I HEARD,
YOU WERE SELLING
STEAM AUTOMOBILES.
I WAS.
WHAT HAPPENED?
SOMEBODY ACTUALLY
INVENTED ONE. NO.
SO NOW I'M BACK
AT THE OLD STAND.
NOT BOYS' BANDS.
THEY GOT NO CALL
FOR BOYS' BANDS HERE.
ANYTHING THEY DON'T
ALREADY HAVE,
THEY DO WITHOUT.
THEY GOT MUSIC?
THEY GOT A GRAMOPHONE
DOWN TO THE BARBERSHOP.
A STUCK-UP LIBRARIAN
GIVES PIANO.
MAIDEN LADY.
SHE'LL EXPOSE YOU
BEFORE YOU GET
THIS BAG UNPACKED.
YOU KNOW MAIDEN LADY
LIBRARIANS WHO GIVE PIANO
ARE A SPECIALTY OF MINE.
YOU JUST POINT HER OUT TO ME
THE MINUTE YOU SEE HER.
I'LL BACK HER
INTO A CORNER
AND BREATHE
ON HER GLASSES.
THAR SHE BLOWS.
I'LL DO IT,
BUT I WON'T LIKE IT.
THAT'S NOT
THE LIBRARIAN.
THAT'S MRS. SHINN,
THE MAYOR'S WIFE.
GOOD AFTERNOON,
MRS. SHINN.
DON'T CHANGE
THE SUBJECT.
IS SOMETHING
THE MATTER?
THE SAME THING THAT'S
ALWAYS THE MATTER HERE.
LOOK. IS THIS
THE SORT OF BOOK
YOU GIVE
MY DAUGHTER TO READ,
THISRUBY HAT
OF OMAR KAYAYAY?
I AM APPALLED!
I DID RECOMMEND IT.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL
PERSIAN POETRY.
IT'SDIRTY
PEOPLE LYING OUT
IN THE WOODS
EATING SANDWICHES,
GETTING DRUNK
WITH PITFALL
AND WITH GIN.
DRINKING DIRECTLY
OUT OF JUGS
WITH INNOCENT
YOUNG GIRLS.
NO DAUGHTER OF MINE
EVER--
MRS. SHINN!
THE RUBAIYAT OF OMAR
KHAYYAMIS A CLASSIC.
IT'S A SMUTTY BOOK,
LIKE MOST OF THE OTHERS
YOU KEEP HERE.
WOULDN'T YOU RATHER YOUR
DAUGHTER READ A CLASSIC
THAN ELINOR GLYN?
WHAT ELINOR GLYN READS
ISHERMOTHER'S PROBLEM.
JUST KEEP YOUR DIRTY BOOKS
AWAY FROMMYDAUGHTER.
MARCE, YOU SURE
PICKED YOURSELF A TOWN.
LET ME TAKE YOU
TO THE HOTEL.
I'M NOT SURE
I'M STAYING YET.
FIRST I'VE GOT TO
FIND A WAY
TO GET INTO SOME OF
THESE IOWA BOODLEBAGS.
GREG, IT AIN'T EASY.
I NEED AN OPENING.
YOU REMEMBER THE PITCH.
WHAT CAN I USE?
WHAT'S NEW AROUND HERE?
A FARMER BROUGHT IN
AN EGG HAD THREE YOLKS.
IT WAS IN THE PAPER.
OH, THAT'S EXCITING,
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU
TALK ABOUT?
THERE'S THE WEATHER,
WHEN IT'S IN SEASON.
I NEED SOME IDEAS.
I'M GOING TO
GET YOUR TOWN
OUT OF THE SERIOUS
TROUBLE IT'S IN.
RIVER CITY
AIN'T IN ANY TROUBLE.
THEN I'LL HAVE
TO CREATE SOME.
MUST CREATE
A DESPERATE NEED
IN YOUR TOWN
FOR A BOYS' BAND.
WHY DOES EVERYBODY
KEEP RUBBERING
INTO THE BILLIARD
PARLOR?
THEY JUST GOT IN
A NEW POOL TABLE.
SURELY THEY'VE SEEN
A POOL TABLE BEFORE.
NO, JUST BILLIARDS.
THAT'LL DO IT.
JUST SIT WHERE YOU ARE.
REMEMBER, IF YOU SEE
THAT MUSIC TEACHER...
ARE YOU MR. DUNLOP?
YEAH.
WELL, EITHER YOU'RE
CLOSING YOUR EYES
TO A SITUATION YOU DO
NOT WISH TO ACKNOWLEDGE,
OR YOU ARE NOT AWARE
OF THE CALIBER
OF DISASTER
INDICATED
BY THE PRESENCE
OF A POOL TABLE
IN YOUR COMMUNITY.
♪♪ WELL, YOU GOT TROUBLE,
MY FRIEND ♪♪
♪♪ RIGHT HERE, I SAY, TROUBL
E RIGHT HERE IN RIVER CITY ♪♪
♪♪ WHY, SURE,
I'M A BILLIARD PLAYER ♪♪
♪
♪♪ MIGHTY PROUD TO SAY
I'M MIGHTY PROUD TO SAY IT ♪
♪♪ I CONSIDER THAT
THE HOURS I SPEND ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A CUE IN MY HAND
ARE GOLDEN ♪♪
♪♪ HELP YOU CULTIVATE
HORSE SENSE ♪♪
♪♪ AND A COOL HEAD
AND A KEEN EYE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ EVER TAKE AND TRY TO GIVE
AN IRON-CLAD LEAVE TO YOURSELF ♪
♪♪ FROM A THREE-RAIL
BILLIARD SHOT? ♪♪
♪
♪♪ BUT JUST AS I SAY IT TAKES
JUDGMENT, BRAINS, AND MATURITY ♪
♪♪ TO SCORE
IN A BALKLINE GAME ♪♪
♪♪ I SAY THAT ANY BOOB CAN TAKE
AND SHOVE A BALL IN A POCKET ♪♪
♪♪ AND I CALL THAT SLOTH ♪♪
♪♪ THE FIRST BIG STEP ON THE ROA
TO THE DEPTHS OF DEGRADA-- ♪♪
♪♪ I SAY, FIRST MEDICINAL
WINE FROM A TEASPOON ♪♪
♪
♪♪ THEN BEER FROM A BOTTLE ♪
♪♪ AND THE NEXT THING YOU KNOW ♪
♪♪ YOUR SON IS PLAYIN' ♪♪
♪♪ FOR MONEY
IN A PINCH-BACK SUIT ♪♪
♪♪ AND LISTENIN' TO SOME BIG
OUT-OF-TOWN JASPER ♪♪
♪♪ TELL HIM ABOUT
HORSERACE GAMBLIN' ♪♪
♪♪ NOT A WHOLESOME
TROTTIN' RACE, NO! ♪♪
♪♪ BUT A RACE
WHERE THEY SET DOWN ♪♪
♪♪ RIGHT ON THE HORSE! ♪♪
♪♪ LIKE TO SEE
SOME STUCK-UP JOCKEY BOY ♪♪
♪♪ SETTIN' ON DAN PATCH? ♪♪
♪♪ MAKE YOUR BLOOD BOIL? ♪♪
♪♪ WELL, I SHOULD SAY! ♪♪
♪♪ LET ME TELL YOU
WHAT I MEAN ♪♪
♪♪ YOU GOT 1, 2, 3, 4 ♪♪
♪
♪♪ 5, 6 POCKETS IN A TABLE ♪
♪♪ POCKETS THAT MARK
THE DIFFERENCE BETWEEN ♪♪
♪♪ A GENTLEMAN AND A BUM ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A CAPITAL "B"
AND THAT RHYMES WITH "P" ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ AND THAT STANDS FOR POOL
♪♪ AND ALL WEEK LONG
YOUR RIVER CITY YOUTH ♪♪
♪
♪♪ WILL BE FRITTERIN' AWAY ♪
♪♪ I SAY, YOUR YOUNG MEN
WILL BE FRITTERIN' ♪♪
♪♪ FRITTERIN' AWAY
THEIR NOONTIME ♪♪
♪♪ SUPPERTIME,
CHORETIME, TOO ♪♪
♪♪ GET THE BALL
IN THE POCKET! ♪♪
♪♪ NEVER MIND
GETTIN' DANDELIONS PULLED ♪♪
♪♪ OR THE SCREEN DOOR PATCHE
D OR THE BEEFSTEAK POUNDED ♪♪
♪♪ NEVER MIND PUMPIN' ANY WATER
TILL YOUR PARENTS ARE CAUGHT ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A CISTERN EMPTY
ON A SATURDAY NIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ AND THAT'S TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ YES, YOU GOT
LOTS AND LOTS OF TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ I'M THINKIN' OF THE KIDS
IN THE KNICKERBOCKERS ♪♪
♪
♪♪ SHIRT-TAILED YOUNG ONES ♪
♪♪ PEEKIN' IN THE POOL HALL
WINDOW AFTER SCHOOL ♪♪
♪♪ YOU GOT TROUBLE, FOLKS ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ RIGHT HERE IN RIVER CITY
♪♪ TROUBLE WITH A CAPITAL "T
" AND THAT RHYMES WITH "P" ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ AND THAT STANDS FOR POOL
♪♪ NOW, I KNOW ALL YOU FOLKS
ARE THE RIGHT KIND OF PARENTS ♪♪
♪♪ I'M GONNA BE
PERFECTLY FRANK ♪♪
♪♪ WOULD YOU LIKE TO KNOW ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT KIND OF CONVERSATION
GOES ON ♪♪
♪♪ WHILE THEY'RE LOAFIN' AROUND
THAT HALL? ♪♪
♪♪ THEY'RE TRYIN' OUT BEVO,
TRYIN' OUT CUBEBS ♪♪
♪♪ TRYIN' OUT TAILOR-MADES
LIKE CIGARETTE FIENDS ♪♪
♪♪ AND BRAGGIN' ♪♪
♪
♪♪ ALL ABOUT
HOW THEY'RE GONNA COVER UP ♪
♪♪ A TELL-TALE BREATH
WITH SEN-SEN ♪♪
♪♪ ONE FINE NIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ THEY LEAVE THE POOL HALL ♪♪
♪♪ HEADIN' FOR THE DANCE
AT THE ARMORY ♪♪
♪♪ LIBERTINE MEN ♪♪
♪♪ AND SCARLET WOMEN ♪♪
♪♪ AND RAGTIME,
SHAMELESS MUSIC ♪♪
♪♪ THAT'LL GRAB YOUR SON,
YOUR DAUGHTER ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE ARMS OF
A JUNGLE ANIMAL INSTINCT ♪♪
♪♪ MASS-TERIA! ♪♪
♪♪ FRIENDS, THE IDLE BRAIN
IS THE DEVIL'S PLAYGROUND ♪♪
♪♪ TROUBLE,
RIGHT HERE IN RIVER CITY ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A CAPITAL "T"
AND THAT RHYMES WITH "P" ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ AND THAT STANDS FOR POOL
♪♪ WE SURELY GOT TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ RIGHT HERE IN RIVER CITY
♪♪ GOTTA FIGURE OUT A WAY ♪♪
♪♪ TO KEEP THE YOUNG ONES
MORAL AFTER SCHOOL ♪♪
♪♪ OUR CHILDREN'S CHILDREN
GONNA HAVE TROUBLE ♪♪
MOTHERS OF RIVER CITY!
HEED THAT WARNING
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
WATCH FOR THE TELLTALE
SIGNS OF CORRUPTION.
THE MINUTE YOUR SON
LEAVES THE HOUSE,
DOES HE REBUCKLE
HIS KNICKERBOCKERS
BELOW THE KNEE?
IS THERE
A NICOTINE STAIN
ON HIS INDEX FINGER?
A DIME NOVEL
HIDDEN IN THE CORN CRIB?
IS HE STARTING TO
MEMORIZE JOKES
FROMCAPTAIN BILLY'S
WHIZ BANG?
ARE CERTAIN WORDS
CREEPING INTO
HIS CONVERSATION?
WORDS LIKE,
LIKE "SWELL"
AND "SO'S YOUR OLD MAN"?
IF SO, MY FRIENDS...
♪♪ YOU GOT TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ RIGHT HERE IN RIVER CITY
♪♪ WITH A CAPITAL "T"
AND THAT RHYMES WITH "P" ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ AND THAT STANDS FOR POOL
♪♪ WE SURELY GOT TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ RIGHT HERE IN RIVER CITY
♪♪ REMEMBER THEMAINE,
PLYMOUTH ROCK ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE GOLDEN RULE ♪♪
♪♪ OUR CHILDREN'S CHILDREN
GONNA HAVE TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ OH HO, WE GOT TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ WE'RE IN TERRIBLE,
TERRIBLE TROUBLE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ THAT GAME
WITH THE 15 NUMBERED BALLS ♪
♪♪ IS THE DEVIL'S TOOL ♪♪
♪♪ OH, YES, WE'VE GOT TROUBL
E TROUBLE TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ WE'VE GOT BIG,
BIG TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A CAPITAL "T" ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ AND THAT RHYMES WITH "P"
♪♪ AND THAT STANDS
FOR POOL ♪♪
♪♪ THAT STANDS FOR POOL ♪♪
♪♪ REMEMBER, MY FRIENDS,
LISTEN TO ME ♪♪
♪♪ BECAUSE I PASS
THIS WAY BUT ONCE ♪♪
♪♪ TROUBLE, TROUBLE,
TROUBLE, TROUBLE... ♪♪
♪♪ OH, WE GOT TROUBL
E TROUBLE, TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ RIGHT HERE
IN RIVER CITY ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A CAPITAL "T" AN
D THAT RHYMES WITH "P" ♪♪
♪♪ AND THAT STANDS
FOR POOL ♪♪
♪
♪♪ STANDS FOR POOL ♪
♪♪ SAY WE GOT
TROUBLE, TROUBLE ♪♪
♪♪ RIGHT HERE
IN RIVER CITY ♪♪
♪♪ GOTTA FIGURE OUT
A WAY ♪♪
♪♪ TO KEEP THE YOUNG ONE
S MORAL AFTER SCHOOL ♪♪
DID YOU DROP YOUR--
NO.
DIDN'T I
MEET YOU IN--
NO.
I'LL ONLY BE IN TOWN
A SHORT WHILE.
GOOD!
[PIANO PLAYING]
♪♪#
♪♪
HELLO, MAMA.
KEEP ON, AMARYLLIS.
I'LL BE THERE
IN A MINUTE.
♪♪#
♪♪
THAT'S FINE.
NOW DO YOUR EXERCISES.
LIBRARY OPEN
LATER THAN USUAL
TONIGHT, DEAR?
IT ALWAYS IS, MAMA.
A MAN WITH A SUITCASE
FOLLOWED ME HOME.
OH? WHO?
I NEVER
SAW HIM BEFORE.
DID HE
SAY ANYTHING?
HE TRIED.
DID YOU
SAY ANYTHING?
OF COURSE NOT, MAMA.
NOW, DON'T DAWDLE,
AMARYLLIS.
♪♪ SOL, DO, LA,
RE, TI, MI ♪♪
♪
♪♪ A LITTLE SLOWER ♪
♪♪ AND PLEASE KEEP
THE FINGERS CURVED ♪
♪♪ AS NICE AND HIGH
AS YOU POSSIBLY CAN ♪♪
DON'T GET FASTER,
DEAR.
IF YOU DON'T MIND MY SAYING SO,
IT WOULDN'T HAVE HURT YOU
TO HAVE FOUND OUT
WHAT THE GENTLEMAN WANTED.
I KNOW WHAT
THE GENTLEMAN WANTED.
WHAT, DEAR?
YOU'LL FIND IT
IN BALZAC.
EXCUSE ME FOR LIVING,
BUT I NEVER READ IT.
♪♪ NEITHER HAS ANYONE
ELSE IN THIS TOWN ♪♪
♪♪ THERE YOU GO AGAIN
WITH THE SAME OLD COMMENT ♪♪
♪♪ ABOUT THE LOW MENTALITY
OF RIVER CITY PEOPLE ♪♪
♪♪ AND TAKIN' IT ALL
TOO MUCH TO HEART ♪♪
NOW, MAMA,
♪♪ AS LONG AS THE MADISO
N PUBLIC LIBRARY ♪♪
♪♪ WAS ENTRUSTED
TO ME ♪♪
♪♪ FOR THE PURPOSE
OF IMPROVING ♪♪
♪♪ RIVER CITY'S
CULTURAL LEVEL ♪♪
♪♪ I CAN'T HELP
MY CONCERN ♪♪
♪♪ THAT THE LADIES
OF RIVER CITY ♪♪
♪♪ KEEP IGNORING ALL MY
COUNSEL AND ADVICE ♪♪
BUT DARLING,
♪♪ WHEN A WOMAN
HAS A HUSBAND ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU'VE GOT NONE ♪♪
♪♪ WHY SHOULD SHE
TAKE ADVICE FROM YOU ♪♪
♪♪ EVEN IF YOU CAN QUOTE
BALZAC AND SHAKESPEARE ♪♪
♪♪ AND ALL THEM OTHER
HIGHFALUTIN' GREEKS? ♪♪
♪♪ IF YOU DON'T MIND
MY SAYIN' SO ♪♪
♪♪ YOU HAVE
A BAD HABIT ♪♪
♪♪ OF CHANGIN'
EVERY SUBJECT ♪♪
♪♪ NO, I HAVEN'T
CHANGED THE SUBJECT ♪♪
♪♪ I WAS TALKIN'
ABOUT THAT STRANGER ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT STRANGER? ♪♪
♪♪ WITH THE SUITCASE ♪♪
♪♪ WHO MAY BE
YOUR VERY LAST CHANCE ♪♪
♪♪ DO YOU THINK
THAT I'D ALLOW ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ A COMMON MASHER?
♪♪ NOW REALLY, MAMA
♪♪ I HAVE
MY STANDARDS ♪♪
♪♪ WHERE MEN
ARE CONCERNED ♪♪
♪♪ AND I HAVE
NO INTENTION-- ♪♪
♪♪ I KNOW ALL ABOUT
YOUR STANDARDS ♪♪
♪♪ AND IF YOU DON'T MIND
MY SAYIN' SO ♪♪
♪♪ THERE'S NOT
A MAN ALIVE ♪♪
♪♪ WHO COULD HOPE TO
MEASURE UP TO THAT BLEND ♪♪
♪♪ OF PAUL BUNYAN,
ST. PAT, AND NOAH WEBSTER ♪♪
♪♪ YOU'VE CONCOCTED
FOR YOURSELF ♪♪
♪♪ OUT OF
YOUR IRISH IMAGINATION ♪♪
♪♪ YOUR IOWA STUBBORNNESS ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOUR LIBRARY
FULL OF BOOKS ♪♪
IF THAT ISN'T
THE BEST I'VE HEARD!
THANK YOU.
CAN I HAVE A DRINK?
MAYI--
MAY I HAVE A DRINK?
YES, YOU MAY.
[DOOR CREAKS]
HELLO, WINTHROP.
WINTHROP,
IT'S AFTER DARK.
I'M HAVING A PARTY
ON SATURDAY.
WILL YOU
PLEASE COME?
IT'S GOING TO BE
A VERY NICE PARTY.
I'D ESPECIALLY
LIKE IT
IF YOU'D COME.
WELL, WINTHROP,
ARE YOU GOING
OR AREN'T YOU?
NO.
NO, WHAT?
NO, THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW THE LITTLE
GIRL'S NAME.
I'LL BET
HE WON'T SAY IT.
NO, THANK YOU,WHO?
NO, THANK YOU,
AMARYLLITH.
AMARYLLITH!
HA HA HA!
HE'S CRYING!
HELLO, WINTHROP.
YOU DIDN'T SAY HELLO
TO YOUR SISTER.
HE HATES TO
SAY AMARYLLIS
BECAUSE OF
THE LISP.
HE'S ASHAMED.
WE KNOW
ALL ABOUT HIS LISP.
WHY SHOULD HE GET
SO MAD AT PEOPLE
JUST BECAUSE
HE LISPS?
THAT'S PART OF IT.
WHAT'S THE REST
OF IT?
NEVER MIND. IT'S JUST THAT
HE NEVER TALKS VERY MUCH.
NOT EVEN TO YOU
AND YOUR MOTHER?
NO. WE HAVE TO
BE VERY PATIENT.
I'M PATIENT.
I EVEN SAY
GOOD NIGHT TO HIM
ON THE EVENING STAR
EVERY NIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT,
MY WINTHROP.
GOOD NIGHT.
SLEEP TIGHT.
AND HE NEVER
SAYS ANYTHING TO ME.
OH, DARLING,
DON'T CRY.
YOU'LL HAVE LOTS OF TIME
FOR SWEETHEARTS.
IF NOT WINTHROP,
THEN SOMEONE ELSE.
NEVER. I'LL END UP
AN OLD MAID LIKE YOU.
I'M SORRY, MISS MARIAN.
CAN I PLAY
MY CROSS-HAND PIECE?
MAYI--
MAY I PLAY
MY CROSS-HAND PIECE?
YES, YOU MAY.
IF A GIRL DOESN'T
HAVE A SWEETHEART,
WHO IS SHE GOING
TO SAY GOOD NIGHT TO
ON THE EVENING STAR?
FOR THE TIME BEING,
YOU CAN JUST SAY,
"GOOD NIGHT,
MY SOMEONE."
THEN YOU CAN
PUT THE NAME IN
WHEN THE RIGHT
SOMEONE COMES ALONG.
ALL RIGHT. IT'S BETTER
THAN NOTHING.
YES, IT IS.
NOW YOU CAN PLAY
YOUR CROSS-HAND PIECE.
♪♪ GOOD NIGHT,
MY SOMEONE ♪♪
♪♪ GOOD NIGHT, MY LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ SLEEP TIGHT,
MY SOMEONE ♪♪
♪♪ SLEEP TIGHT, MY LOVE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ OUR STAR IS SHINING ♪
♪♪ ITS BRIGHTEST LIGHT ♪
♪♪ FOR GOOD NIGHT,
MY LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ FOR GOOD NIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ SWEET DREAMS
BE YOURS, DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ IF DREAMS
THERE BE ♪♪
♪♪ SWEET DREAMS
TO CARRY YOU ♪♪
♪♪ CLOSE TO ME ♪♪
♪♪ I WISH THEY MAY ♪♪
♪♪ AND I WISH
THEY MIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ NOW GOOD NIGHT,
MY SOMEONE ♪♪
♪♪ GOOD NIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ TRUE LOVE
CAN BE WHISPERED ♪♪
♪♪ FROM HEART TO HEART ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN LOVERS ARE PARTED,
THEY SAY ♪♪
♪♪ BUT I MUST DEPEND ON ♪♪
♪♪ A WISH AND A STAR ♪♪
♪♪ AS LONG AS MY HEART ♪♪
♪♪ DOESN'T KNOW
WHO YOU ARE ♪♪
♪♪ SWEET DREAMS
BE YOURS, DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ IF DREAMS THERE BE ♪♪
♪♪ SWEET DREAMS
TO CARRY YOU ♪♪
♪♪ CLOSE TO ME ♪♪
♪♪ I WISH THEY MAY ♪♪
♪♪ AND I WISH THEY MIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ NOW GOOD NIGHT,
MY SOMEONE ♪♪
♪♪ GOOD NIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ OH, COLUMBIA,
THE GEM OF THE OCEAN ♪♪
♪♪ THE HOME OF THE BRAVE
AND THE FREE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ THE SHRINE
OF EACH PATRIOT'S DEVOTION ♪
♪♪ A WORLD OFFERS HOMAGE
TO THEE ♪♪
♪♪ THY MANDATES
MAKE HEROES ASSEMBLE ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN LIBERTY'S FORM
STANDS IN VIEW ♪♪
♪♪ THY BANNERS
MAKE TYRANNY TREMBLE ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN BORNE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ BY THE RED, WHITE, AND BLUE ♪
♪♪ WHEN BORNE BY THE RED,
WHITE, AND BLUE ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN BORNE
BY THE RED, WHITE, AND BLUE ♪♪
♪♪ THY BANNERS
MAKE TYRANNY TREMBLE ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN BORNE
BY THE RED, WHITE, AND BLUE ♪♪
I'M SURE WE'RE ALL
GRATEFUL TO MY WIFE,
EULALIE MACKECKNIE SHINN,
FOR LEADING THE SINGING.
[APPLAUSE]
AND TO ETHEL TOFFELMIER,
OUR FINE
PLAYER-PIANO PLAYER...
PIANO.
[APPLAUSE]
AS MAYOR OF RIVER CITY,
I WELCOME
YOU RIVER CITY-ZEANS
TO THE 4th OF JULY
EXERCISES
SET UP FOR THE INDOORS
HERE IN MADISON GYMNASIUM
ON ACCOUNT OF THE WEATHER
BEING SO CHANCY.
[MURMURING]
"FOURSCORE--"
[CLACK CLACK CLACK]
THE MEMBERS
OF THE SCHOOL BOARD
WILL NOW PRESENT
A PATRIOTIC TABLEAU.
OH. OH.
THE MEMBERS
OF THE SCHOOL BOARD
WILLNOTPRESENT
A PATRIOTIC TABLEAU.
SOME DISAGREEMENT ABOUT
COSTUMES, I SUPPOSE.
INSTEAD,
THE WA TAN YE GIRLS
OF THE LOCAL WIGWAM
OF HIAWATHA
WILL PRESENT A SPECTACLE,
MY WIFE.
HA HA HA!
IN WHICH MY WIFE,
EULALIE MACKECKNIE SHINN,
WILL TAKE
A LEADING PART.
[APPLAUSE]
I WILL COUNT TO 2O
IN THE INDIAN
TONGUE.
EEN, TEEN, TEATHER
FEATHER, FIP.
SAINTY, LAITY,
CORIA PREDIP.
EENDIK, TEENDIK,
TEATHERDIK,
FEATHERDIK--
[BOOM]
AAH! I'M SHOT!
THEY'VE SHOT ME!
WHO SET OFF
THAT FIRECRACKER?
TOMMY DJILAS
DID IT!
YES, TOMMY DJILAS.
I WOULDN'T LEAVE
IF I WERE YOU.
MRS. SHINN...
WILL RECOVER.
NO THANKS TO
A CERTAIN YOUNG RUFFIAN
WHO IS A DISGRACE
TO OUR CITY!
"FOURSCORE...
AND SEVEN YEARS AGO,
OUR--"
THE PAINE'S
FIREWORKS SPECTACLE,
"THE LAST DAYS
OF POMP-EE-II,"
WILL TAKE PLACE
AT 9:3O,
PROVIDING
IT ISN'T RAINING.
IT WILL BE OVER
AT THE MADISON PICNIC PARK
ACROSS THE CRICK
FROM THE PEST HOUSE.
WHAT'S THIS TALK
ABOUT RAIN?
DIDN'TTHE GAZETTE
PREDICT FAIR?
IT DID. THAT'S WHY WE ALL
PREPARED FOR A STORM.
MY PAPER'S ACCURATE
MOST OF THE TIME.
I WOULDN'T LAST
IN BANKING
BEING MOSTLY
ACCURATE!
WILL YOU MEMBERS
OF THE SCHOOL BOARD
STOP BICKERING
IN PUBLIC?
NEVER MIND!
"FOURSCORE--"
WE HEARD THERE'S
A POOL TABLE IN TOWN.
I HEARD THAT!
JUST A MINUTE!
IS IT A POOL TABLE
OR ISN'T IT?
WILL YOU ALLOW ME TO GET ON
WITH THE EXERCISES?
NOT UNTIL WE SETTLE
THIS POOL TABLE
MATTER!
YEAH! YEAH!
LET'S PROTECT
OUR CHILDREN!
WE'VE GOTTA PROTECT
RESIST SIN
AND CORRUPTION!
LET'S SMITE
THAT DEVIL
AND KEEP OUR
YOUNG BOYS PURE!
PURE BOYS!
FOLKS, LISTEN.
♪♪ MAY I HAVE
YOUR ATTENTION, PLEASE? ♪♪
♪♪ ATTENTION, PLEASE ♪♪
♪♪ I CAN DEAL
WITH THE TROUBLE, FRIENDS ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A WAVE
OF MY HAND ♪♪
♪♪ THIS VERY HAND ♪♪
♪♪ PLEASE OBSERVE ME,
IF YOU WILL ♪♪
♪♪ I'M PROFESSOR HAROLD HILL ♪♪
♪♪ AND I'M HERE TO ORGANIZE
A RIVER CITY BOYS' BAND ♪♪
♪♪ BRR-RR-RMP! ♪♪
♪♪ OH, THINK, MY FRIENDS ♪♪
♪♪ HOW CAN ANY POOL TABLE
EVER HOPE TO COMPETE ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A GOLD TROMBONE? ♪♪
♪♪ BRRAA DA RA DA DA
DAT DA RA RA ♪♪
♪♪ REMEMBER, MY FRIENDS ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT A HANDFUL
OF TRUMPET PLAYERS DID ♪♪
♪♪ TO THE FAMOUS,
FABLED WALLS OF JERICHO ♪♪
♪♪ OH, BILLIARD PARLOR WALLS
COME A-TUMBLIN' DOWN ♪♪
♪♪ WELL, A BAND WILL DO IT,
MY FRIENDS ♪♪
♪♪ OH, YES,
I SAID A BOYS' BAND ♪♪
♪♪ DO YOU HEAR ME? ♪♪
♪♪ I SAID RIVER CITY
GOTTA HAVE A BOYS' BAND ♪♪
♪♪ AND I MEAN
SHE NEEDS IT TODAY ♪♪
♪♪ WELL, PROFESSOR
HAROLD HILL'S ON HAND ♪♪
♪♪ RIVER CITY'S GONNA HAVE
HER BOYS' BAND ♪♪
♪♪ AS SURE AS THE LORD MADE
LITTLE GREEN APPLES ♪♪
♪♪ AND THAT BAND'S
GONNA BE IN UNIFORM ♪♪
♪♪ JOHNNY, WILLY,
TEDDY, FRED ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU SEE THE GLITTER
OF CRASHING CYMBALS ♪♪
♪♪ YOU HEAR THE THUNDER
OF ROLLING DRUMS ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE SHIMMER
OF TRUMPETS ♪♪
♪♪ TUM TA DA! ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU'LL FEEL SOMETHING
AKIN TO THE ELECTRIC THRILL ♪♪
♪♪ I ONCE ENJOYED ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN GILMORE,
PAT CONWAY ♪♪
♪♪ THE GREAT CREATOR
W.C. HANDY ♪♪
♪♪ AND JOHN PHILIP SOUSA ♪♪
♪♪ ALL CAME TO TOWN
ON THE VERY SAME HISTORIC DAY ♪♪
♪♪ 76 TROMBONES
LED THE BIG PARADE ♪♪
♪♪ WITH 11O CORNETS
CLOSE AT HAND ♪♪
♪♪ THEY WERE FOLLOWED
BY ROWS AND ROWS ♪♪
♪
♪♪ OF THE FINEST VIRTUOSOS ♪
♪♪ THE CREAM
OF EVERY FAMOUS BAND ♪♪
♪♪ 76 TROMBONES
CAUGHT THE MORNING SUN ♪♪
♪♪ WITH 11O CORNETS
RIGHT BEHIND ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WERE MORE THAN
A THOUSAND REEDS ♪♪
♪
♪♪ SPRINGING UP LIKE WEEDS ♪
♪♪ THERE WERE HORNS
OF EVERY SHAPE AND KIND ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WERE
COPPER-BOTTOM TIMPANI ♪♪
♪♪ IN HORSE PLATOONS ♪♪
♪♪ THUNDERING, THUNDERING
ALL ALONG THE WAY ♪♪
♪♪ DOUBLE-BELL EUPHONIUMS
AND BIG BASSOONS ♪♪
♪♪ EACH BASSOON
HAVING HIS BIG FAT SAY ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WERE 5O MOUNTED CANNON
IN THE BATTERY ♪♪
♪♪ THUNDERING, THUNDERING
LOUDER THAN BEFORE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ CLARINETS OF EVERY SIZE ♪
♪♪ AND TRUMPETERS
WHO'D IMPROVISE ♪♪
♪♪ A FULL OCTAVE HIGHER
THAN THE SCORE ♪♪
OH!
♪♪ 76 TROMBONES
HIT THE COUNTERPOINT ♪♪
♪♪ WHILE 11O CORNETS
BLAZED AWAY ♪♪
♪♪ TO THE RHYTHM
OF HARCH! HARCH! HARCH! ♪♪
♪♪ ALL THE KIDS
BEGAN TO MARCH ♪♪
♪♪ AND THEY'RE MARCHING STILL
RIGHT TODAY ♪♪
AIN'T NOTHIN' LIKE
A BRASS BAND
TO STIR
A FELLOW UP.
WHEN I HEAR
THEM TROMBONES...
IT'S THEM PECK HORNS
THAT REALLY DOES IT.
BET YOU ESTHERVILLE
AIN'T GOT ANYTHING LIKE IT.
OR EVEN DES MOINES.
I'LL STAKE
MY RIVER CITY BAND
AGAINST ANY TOWN
WEST OF CHICAGO.
WHAT BAND?
HONESTLY, A BUNCH
OF GROWN MEN!
ALONG COMES THIS
FLY-BY-NIGHT SALESMAN,
AND YOU'RE ALL TAKEN IN.
SHE'S RIGHT!
THE MAN'S A SPELLBINDER!
I HAVEN'T SEEN
IOWA PEOPLE GET SO EXCITED
SINCE FRANK GOTCH
AND STRANGLER LEWIS
LAY ON THE MAT
FOR 3 1/2 HOURS WITHOUT MOVING.
THAT WAS EXCITING.
NEVER MIND!
MEN, THIS CALLS
FOR EMERGENCY ACTION.
I WANT
THAT MAN'S CREDENTIALS.
GRAB THAT HOODLUM!
HE ALMOST BLEW UP MRS. SHINN.
GREAT HONK!
LET ME GO!
HAVE TO MAKE
AN EXAMPLE OF THIS ONE.
RINGLEADER, YOU KNOW.
EVERYTHING HE DOES,
THE GANG DOES.
YOU WILD KID. HANGING
AROUND MY OLDEST GIRL!
HIS FATHER'S ONE OF THEM
LITHUANIANS SOUTH OF TOWN.
WHAT DID I DO?
TAGGING DOWN MAIN STREET
AFTER MY OLDEST GIRL.
I WASN'T EITHER
TAGGING.
DON'T YOU
COUNTERDICT ME.
WE'S JUST WALKING!
GREAT HONK!
YOU WATCH
YOUR PHRASEOLOGY!
I KNOW WHAT YOU WAS DOING.
MY LITTLE GRACIE SEEN YOU.
STAY AWAY
FROM MY OLDEST GIRL
OR YOU'LL HEAR FROM ME.
HILL, I'LL TALK
TO YOU MONDAY MORNING
ABOUT THIS BAND THING RIGHT HERE
IN CITY HALL. 10:00 SHARP.
CONSTABLE,
I'LL BE RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE BOY.
YOU DON'T KNOW THIS KID.
HE'S TOUGH.
PROBABLY GOT HIS GANG
WAITING AROUND THE CORNER.
OH, I'LL BE CAREFUL.
TOMMY, LET'S TALK
ABOUT THE BAND.
GEE, THAT'S FOR
THE LITTLE KIDS.
YOU WON'T PLAY
IN THE BAND.
LOOK, YOU'RE
MECHANICALLY MINDED.
HAVE YOU DONE ANYTHING
WITH PERPETUAL MOTION?
YEAH, I NEARLY HAD IT
A COUPLE TIMES.
WELL, YOU'RE MY MAN.
DO YOU REALIZE NOBODY
HAS EVER INVENTED
A MUSIC HOLDER
FOR A MARCHING
PICCOLO PLAYER.
THERE'S NO PLACE
TO HANG MUSIC.
WHERE COULD I
GET SOME WIRE?
LOOK IN YOUR CELLAR.
THAT'S WHERE PEOPLE
KEEP WIRE.
TOMMY!
YES, SIR?
CONSTABLE, HERE'S HOW TO
BREAK UP A GANG.
MISS, WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
ZANEETA.
I DIDN'T HAVE
ANY IDEA
YOU WAS
BECKONING TO ME?
YE GODS!
DO YOU KNOW
TOMMY DJILAS?
TOMMY,
THIS IS ZANEETA.
ESCORT THE YOUNG
LADY HOME.
I HAVE TO GO
TO THE LIBRARY.
YE GODS!
ESCORT THE YOUNG LADY HOME
BY WAY OF THE LIBRARY--
BY WAY OF
THE CANDY KITCHEN.
YES, SIR!
DO I HAFTA?
OH, YOU HAFTA.
YES, SIR!
YE GODS!
PROFESSOR,
YOU'RE PRETTY BRIGHT,
ONLY YOU MADE
TWO MISTAKES.
OH?
THE MAYOR OWNS
THAT BILLIARD PARLOR
AND THAT NEW POOL TABLE.
YOU DON'T SAY.
WHAT WAS
MY OTHER MISTAKE?
THAT ZANEETA,
SHE'S THE MAYOR'S
OLDEST GIRL.
[WHISTLES76 TROMBONES]
[WHISTLE]
GOOD EVENING, LADIES.
HA HA HA!
JUST A MINUTE,
PROFESSOR HILL.
SORRY, PROFESSOR,
BUT WE'RE THE SCHOOL BOARD.
WE NEED
YOUR CREDENTIALS.
ACADEMIC
CERTIFICATES.
NOTHING
OF THE KIND.
WE NEED LETTERS
AND PAPERS.
MAKE HIM
PUT UP A BOND.
WHAT AM I HEARING?
YOU, SIR.
♪♪
♪♪ SAY
"ICE CREAM" ♪♪
I DON'T SING.
TALK, THEN.
[DEEP VOICE]
DOWN HERE.
♪♪ ICE CREAM ♪♪
ICE CREAM.
♪♪ TALK SLOW ♪♪
♪♪ ICE CREAM ♪♪
SINGING IS JUST
SUSTAINED TALKING.
NOW YOU, SIR.
♪♪ ICE CREAM ♪♪
♪♪ IIICE CREEEAM ♪♪
LADIES, FROM NOW ON,
YOU'LL NEVER SEE
ONE OF THOSE MEN
WITHOUT
THE OTHER THREE.
PROFESSOR, YOU'RE WRONG.
THEY'VE HATED EACH OTHER
FOR 15 YEARS.
♪♪ ICE CREAM ♪♪
WELL!
YOU GO AHEAD, MOM.
I'LL BE THERE IN A MINUTE.
LET'S TRY IT
AGAIN.
♪♪ HOW CAN THERE BE ♪♪
♪♪ ANY SIN IN SINCERE? ♪♪
♪♪ WHERE IS THE GOOD
IN GOOD-BYE? ♪♪
♪♪ IN GOOD-BYYYE ♪♪
♪♪ YOUR APPREHENSIONS ♪♪
YOUR APPREHENSIONS
CONFUSE ME, DEAR.
♪♪ CONFUSE ME, DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ PUZZLE AND MYSTIFY ♪♪
♪♪ MYSTIFY ♪♪
♪♪ TELL ME ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT CAN BE FAIR ♪♪
♪♪ IN FAREWELL, DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ WHILE ONE SINGLE STAR
SHINES ♪♪
♪♪ ABOOOoooOOOVE? ♪♪
♪♪ HOW CAN THERE BE
ANY SIN ♪♪
♪♪ IN SINCERE? ♪♪
♪♪ AREN'T WE SINCERELY ♪♪
♪♪ IN LOVE? ♪♪
♪♪ OH, WE'RE IN LOVE ♪♪
I DON'T SUPPOSE YOU LIVE
ALONE OR ANYTHING.
NO.
I HAVE SOME WONDERFUL
CARAMELS OVER THE HOTEL--
MR. HILL--
OH, PLEASE, PLEASE!
PROFESSOR HILL!
PROFESSOR?
OF WHAT?
AT WHAT COLLEGE
DO THEY GIVE A DEGREE
FOR ACCOSTING WOMEN
LIKE A SATURDAY NIGHT
ROWDY AT A PUBLIC
DANCE HALL?
I WOULDN'T KNOW ABOUT THAT.
I'M A CONSERVATORY MAN.
GARY, INDIANA.
GOLD MEDAL CLASS OF 'O5.
EVEN IF THAT'S TRUE,
I'M NOT EASILY
MESMERIZED.
I AM NOT IMPRESSED
BY YOUR CREDENTIALS,
WHICH I
HAVE NOT SEEN,
NOR YOUR MANNERS,
WHICH I HAVE!
[WHISTLE]
Hill: IT'S A GOLDEN KEY,
AS IT WERE.
YOUR KEY TO THE MAGIC
WORLD OF MUSIC.
NONE OF OUR FAMILY
HAS EVER BEEN
WHAT YOU'D CALL
MUSICAL.
OH, MADAM,
THAT YOU DO NOT KNOW.
THE MAIN THING IS IMAGINATION
AND PROPER INSTRUCTION. AH.
NOW YOU, YOUNG MAN,
REPEAT AFTER ME.
[WHISTLES]
♪
♪♪ I LOVE MUSIC, MOMMY ♪
[OFF KEY]
♪♪ I LOVE MUSIC, MOMMY ♪♪
NOW YOU, YOUNG MAN.
[WHISTLES]
♪♪ ME, TOO, MOMMY ♪♪
[OFF KEY]
OH, MADAM, IT'S AMAZING.
2 MEMBERS OF THE SAME FAMILY
WITH ABSOLUTELY PERFECT PITCH.
SIGN HERE, MADAM.
YOU SURE CUT A SWATH
DOWN AT THE HIGH SCHOOL
YESTERDAY.
YEAH.
WHEN YOU WERE TALKING
ABOUT ALL THEM TROMBONES,
YOU LOOKED JUST LIKE
YOU USED TO BACK IN JOPLIN.
JOPLIN?
YEAH. WHEN YOU
USED TO IMITATE
THAT ITALIAN BANDLEADER
IN THE PARK.
OH, YEAH.
♪♪ LA TA TA TA ♪♪
♪♪ TA TA TUM TA DA TA DA ♪♪
OH, THAT'S KID STUFF.
I'M IN RARE FORM
THESE DAYS, SON.
JUST YOU KEEP YOUR EYE ON ME
FOR THE NEXT 4 WEEKS.
4 WEEKS?
YOU USED TO GET THE
INSTRUMENTS IN 10 DAYS.
OH, I STILL DO, BUT IT TAKES
4 WEEKS FOR THE UNIFORMS.
UNIFORMS?
YOU'VE ADDED UNIFORMS?
UNIFORMS
AND INSTRUCTION BOOKS.
I FIGURE WHAT'S THE USE
OF WARMING UP
IF YOU'RE NOT GONNA PITCH?
YOU CAN'T
PASS YOURSELF OFF
AS A MUSIC PROFESSOR
FOR 4 WEEKS.
YOU CAN'T READ
A NOTE OF MUSIC.
I NOW HAVE A REVOLUTIONARY NEW
METHOD CALLED THE THINK SYSTEM,
WHERE YOU DON'T BOTHER
WITH NOTES.
MY BOY,
SOMEDAY READING MUSIC
IS GOING TO BE
ABSOLUTELY OBSOLETE.
I HOPE IT'S SOON,
'CAUSE IN 4 WEEKS
THESE PEOPLE ARE GONNA
WANNA HEAR SOME MUSIC.
YEAH, BUT WHEN
THE UNIFORMS ARRIVE,
THEY FORGET
EVERYTHING ELSE.
AT LEAST LONG ENOUGH FOR
ME TO COLLECT AND LEAVE.
OH, THIS IS A REFINED
OPERATION, SON,
AND I'VE GOT IT TIMED
RIGHT DOWN
TO THE LAST WAVE
OF THE BRAKEMAN'S HAND
ON THE LAST TRAIN
OUT OF TOWN.
[ALL TALKING AT ONCE]
GOOD EVENING, LADIES.
OHH.
PROFESSOR HILL,
WE'RE ALL AGOG.
YES.
SIMPLY AGOG.
ON THEQUE VIVE.
EVERYBODY'S SO EXCITED
ABOUT THE BAND.
I'M ETHEL TOFFELMIER,
THE PIANOLA GIRL.
AND THIS IS AVIS GRUBB.
HOW DO YOU DO?
AND MRS. HICKS.
HELLO.
AND MRS. SQUIRES.
AND OF COURSE, YOU'VE MET
EULALIE MACKECKNIE SHINN,
OUR MAYOR'S WIFE.
YES, INDEED.
OH, YES.
ISN'T IT EXCITING,
EULALIE?
I COULDN'T SAY.
OH, NO, I COULD NOT SAY.
I COULD NOT SAY AT THIS TIME.
MY HUSBAND WILL WISH
TO INVESTIGATE, I'M SURE,
AND NATURALLY I'M RETICENT.
OH, YES, I'M RETICENT.
YES, OF COURSE.
I UNDERSTAND,
MRS. SHINN.
BUT YOU SEE,
PART OF MY MUSIC PLANS
INCLUDE A COMMITTEE
ON THE DANCE,
AND I WAS THINKING--
OH, DO THAT AGAIN,
MRS. SHINN.
DO WHAT?
WHAT DID I DO?
YOUR FOOT. THE WAY
YOU RAISED IT JUST NOW.
OH, WELL, I HAVE A BUNION
THERE THAT BOTHERS ME.
OH, WHAT GRACE.
OH, MR. HILL.
WHAT NATURAL FLOW
OF RHYTHM.
OH, OH, MR. HILL.
WHAT EXPRESSION OF LINE
AND MOVEMENT.
MOVEMENT.
OH, YOU MUST ACCEPT
THE CHAIRMANSHIP
OF THE LADIES' AUXILIARY
FOR THE CLASSIC DANCE.
MUSTN'T SHE, LADIES?
YES.
MRS. SHINN, YOUR EVERY MOVE
BESPEAKS DEL SARTRE.
WILL YOU? WILL YOU?
SAY YES, MRS. SHINN.
WELL, I--THAT IS--
DANCING, WELL.
THEN YOU ACCEPT.
YES, INDEED, AND I
WOULD LIKE TO SAY--
OH, THANK YOU,
MRS. SHINN.
OH, HO HO.
[ALL TALKING AT ONCE]
AND NOW THE YOUNG LADY
WHO TEACHES THE PIANO.
MARIAN PAROO, I BELIEVE.
OHH! OHH!
OHH!
WELL, AFTER ALL,
SHE IS THE LIBRARIAN.
SHE MUST HAVE
PICKED HIM OUT.
TALKING UP
TO A MAN LIKE THAT.
HE WOULDN'T
TALK UP ABOUT IT
IF SHE DIDN'T TRY
TURKEY TALKING TO HIM.
DON'T YOU TAKE HER TICKET
AND PUNCH IT FOR HER.
PICKED HER UP FIRST
CRACK LIKE A CHEAP JACK.
NOT MUCH PICK TO HER
IF YOU ASK ME.
PICK A LITTLE,
TALK A LOT.
TALK A LITTLE.
CHEAP, CHEAP, CHEAP.
TALK A LOT,
PICK A LITTLE.
PICK A LITTLE,
TALK A LITTLE,
CHEAP,
CHEAP, CHEAP.
♪♪
♪♪ PICK A LITTLE, TALK A LITTLE
♪♪ CHEAP, CHEAP, CHEAP ♪♪
♪♪ TALK A LOT,
PICK A LITTLE MORE ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ PICK A LITTLE, TALK A LITTLE
♪♪ PICK A LITTLE, TALK,
CHEAP, CHEAP, CHEAP ♪♪
♪♪ TALK A LOT,
PICK A LITTLE MORE ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ PICK A LITTLE, TALK A LITTLE
♪♪ CHEAP, CHEAP, CHEAP ♪♪
PROFESSOR, HER KIND OF WOMAN
DOESN'T BELONG ON ANY COMMITTEE.
OF COURSE,
I SHOULDN'T TELL YOU THIS,
BUT SHE ADVOCATES DIRTY BOOKS.
DIRTY BOOKS?
CHAUCER.
RABELAIS.
BALZAC.
♪♪ CHEAP, CHEAP, CHEAP ♪♪
AND THE WORST THING--
OF COURSE,
I SHOULDN'T TELL YOU THIS.
I'LL TELL.
THE MAN LIVED ON MY STREET.
LET ME TELL.
NO. I'LL TELL.
SHE MADE BRAZEN
OVERTURES TO A MAN
WHO NEVER HAD
A FRIEND IN THIS TOWN
UNTIL SHE CAME HERE.
OLD MISER MADISON.
MISER MADISON?
MISER--
MADISON.
MADISON PICNIC PARK?
MADISON GYMNASIUM?
MADISON HOSPITAL?
THAT MISER MADISON?
EXACTLY.
WHO DID HE THINK
HE WAS, ANYWAY?
I SHOULD SAY.
THE SHOW-OFF.
HE GAVE THE TOWN
THE LIBRARY, DIDN'T HE?
THAT'S JUST IT.
WHEN HE DIED,
HE LEFT THE LIBRARY
BUILDING TO THE CITY.
BUT HE LEFT
ALL THE BOOKS TO HER.
SHE WAS SEEN GOING
AND COMING
FROM HIS PLACE.
♪♪ OH, YES, THAT WOMAN MADE
BRAZEN OVERTURES ♪♪
♪♪ WITH A GUILT
THAT'S GUARANTEED ♪♪
♪♪ SHE HAD A GOLDEN GLINT
IN HER EYE ♪♪
♪♪ AND A SILVER VOICE
WITH A COUNTERFEIT RING ♪♪
♪♪ JUST MELT HER DOWN ♪♪
♪♪ AND YOU'LL REVEAL A LUMP
OF LEAD AS COLD AS STEEL HERE ♪♪
♪♪ WHERE A WOMAN'S HEART
SHOULD BE ♪♪
♪♪ HE LEFT RIVER CITY
THE LIBRARY BUILDING ♪♪
♪♪ BUT HE LEFT
ALL THE BOOKS TO HER ♪♪
♪♪ CHAUCER ♪♪
♪♪ RABELAIS ♪♪
♪♪ BALZAC ♪♪
♪♪ CHEAP, CHEAP, CHEAP ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ PICK A LITTLE, TALK A LITTLE
JUST A MINUTE HERE,
PROFESSOR.
SORRY. WE NEED
YOUR CREDENTIALS.
WHY, CERTAINLY,
GENTLEMEN.
I HAVE JUST WHAT YOU WANT
OVER AT MY HOTEL.
PLEASE COME WITH ME.
GOOD NIGHT, LADIES.
♪♪ GOOD NIGHT, LADIES ♪♪
♪♪ WE'RE GOING
TO LEAVE YOU NOW ♪♪
♪♪ FAREWELL, LADIES ♪♪
♪♪ PICK A LITTLE,
TALK A LITTLE ♪♪
♪♪ FAREWELL, LADIES ♪♪
♪♪ PICK A LITTLE,
TALK A LITTLE ♪♪
♪♪ CHEAP, CHEAP, CHEAP ♪♪
♪♪ WE'RE GOING
TO LEAVE YOU NOW ♪♪
♪♪ CHEAP, CHEAP, CHEAP ♪♪
♪♪ PICK A LITTLE,
TALK A LITTLE, CHEAP ♪♪
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[WHISTLING]
CAN I VISIT THE HORSES?
MAY I?
MAY I VISIT THE HORSES?
WELL, IT'S NOT VISITING
HOURS, BUT ALL RIGHT.
[WHISTLES]
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL
EVENING.
YEAH, NOT BAD.
NOT BAD AT ALL
FOR A LITTLE PLACE
LIKE RIVER CITY, IOWA.
SAY, WHY DON'T YOU COME OVER
TO THE BOARDING HOUSE?
WE GOT CHICKEN
CROQUETS TONIGHT
NO, I'M NOT THINKING
ABOUT FOOD.
GONNA LINE YOURSELF UP
A LITTLE KNOODLING, HUH?
NO. I GOT SOMETHING TO LOOK UP
OVER AT THE LIBRARY.
FROM WHAT I'VE HEARD--
[WHISTLES]
SAY, WHY DON'T YOU
LET ME FIX YOU UP
WITH MYRTLE TOFFELMIER,
ETHEL'S SISTER?
REAL NICE GIRL.
TEACHES SUNDAY SCHOOL.
NO WIDE-EYED, EAGER, INNOCENT
SUNDAY SCHOOL TEACHER FOR ME.
THAT KIND OF GAL
SPINS WEBS--
NOW, LISTEN, BOY.
♪♪ A GAL WHO TRADES
ON ALL THAT PURITY ♪♪
♪♪ MERELY WANTS TO
TRADE MY INDEPENDENCE ♪♪
♪♪ FOR HER SECURITY ♪♪
♪♪ THE ONLY AFFIRMATIVE
SHE WILL FILE ♪♪
♪♪ REFERS TO MARCHING
DOWN THE AISLE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ NO GOLDEN, GLORIOUS,
GLEAMING, PRISTINE GODDESS ♪
♪♪ NO, SIR ♪♪
♪♪ FOR NO DIANA
DO I PLAY FAWN ♪♪
♪♪ I CAN TELL YOU THAT
RIGHT NOW ♪♪
♪♪ I SNARL, I HISS ♪♪
♪♪ HOW CAN IGNORANCE
BE COMPARED TO BLISS? ♪♪
♪♪ I SPARK, I FIZZ ♪♪
♪♪ FOR THE LADY WHO KNOWS
WHAT TIME IT IS ♪♪
♪♪ I CHEER, AND I RAVE ♪♪
♪♪ FOR THE VIRTUE
I'M TOO LATE TO SAVE ♪♪
♪♪ THE SADDER BUT WISER GIRL
FOR ME ♪♪
♪♪ NO BRIGHT-EYED, BLUSHING,
BREATHLESS, BABY-DOLL BABY ♪♪
♪♪ NO, SIR, THAT KIND
OF CHILD TIES KNOTS ♪♪
♪♪ NO SAILOR
EVER KNEW ♪♪
♪♪ I PREFER
TO TAKE A CHANCE ♪♪
♪♪ ON A MORE
ADULT ROMANCE ♪♪
♪♪ NO DEWY YOUNG MISS
WHO KEEPS RESISTING ♪♪
♪♪ ALL THE TIME
SHE KEEPS INSISTING ♪♪
♪♪ NO WIDE-EYED, WHOLESOME,
INNOCENT FEMALE ♪♪
♪♪ NO, SIR ♪♪
♪♪ WHY, SHE'S THE FISHERMAN,
I'M THE FISH, YOU SEE ♪♪
PLOP!
♪♪ I FLINCH, I SHY ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN THE LASS WITH
THE DELICATE AIR GOES BY ♪♪
♪♪ I SMILE, I GRIN ♪♪
♪♪ WHEN THE GAL WITH A TOUCH
OF SIN WALKS IN ♪♪
♪♪ I HOPE, AND I PRAY ♪♪
♪♪ FOR HESTER TO WIN
JUST ONE MORE "A" ♪♪
♪♪ THE SADDER BUT WISER GIRL'S
THE GIRL FOR ME ♪♪
♪♪ THE SADDER BUT WISER GIRL
FOR ME ♪♪
HA HA HA HA!
[NEIGH!]
NO,
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I KNOW EVERYTHING,
AND IT DOESN'T MAKE
ANY DIFFERENCE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
MR. MADISON.
YOU WERE PROBABLY
VERY YOUNG.
ANYONE CAN MAKE
A MISTAKE.
WHAT?
NO APOLOGIES,
NO EXPLANATIONS.
I'LL ONLY BE IN TOWN
A SHORT WHILE,
AND THE SADDER
BUT WISER GIRL FOR ME.
WOULD YOU MAKE YOUR
SELECTION AND LEAVE?
I HAVE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO TAKE OUT?
THE LIBRARIAN.
QUIET,
PLEASE.
THE LIBRARIAN.
YOU'RE NOT
LISTENING, MARIAN.
LOOK.
♪♪ MAR... ♪♪
♪
♪♪ ...RIAN ♪
MARBLES--
SIX STEELIES,
EIGHT AGGIES,
A DOZEN PEEWEES,
AND ONE
GREAT BIG GLASSIE
WITH AN AMERICAN
FLAG IN THE MIDDLE.
I THINK
I'LL DROP THEM.
NO!
SHHH!
♪♪ MADAM LIBRAR...♪♪
♪♪ ...RIAN ♪♪
♪♪ OH, WHAT CAN I DO
, MY DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ TO CATCH
YOUR EAR? ♪♪
♪♪ I LOVE YOU
MADLY, MADLY ♪♪
♪♪ MADAM LIBRARIAN,
MARIAN ♪♪
♪♪ HEAVEN HELP US ♪♪
♪♪ IF THE LIBRARY
CAUGHT ON FIRE ♪♪
♪♪ AND THE VOLUNTEER
HOSE BRIGADE-MEN ♪♪
♪♪ HAD TO WHISPER
THE NEWS TO MAR... ♪♪
♪♪ ...RIAN ♪♪
♪
♪♪ MADAM LIBRAR... ♪
SHHH!
♪
♪♪ ...RIAN ♪
♪♪ OH, WHAT CAN I SAY,
MY DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ TO MAKE IT CLEAR? ♪♪
♪
♪♪ I NEED YOU BADLY, BADLY ♪
♪♪ MADAM LIBRARIAN, MARIAN ♪
♪♪ IF I STUMBLED
AND I BUSTED ♪♪
♪♪ MY WHATCHAMACALLIT ♪♪
♪♪ I COULD LIE ON YOUR
FLOOR UNNOTICED ♪♪
♪♪ TILL MY BODY
HAD TURNED TO CAR... ♪♪
♪♪ ...RION ♪♪
♪♪ MADAM LIBRAR... ♪♪
♪♪ ...RIAN ♪♪
♪♪ NOW, IN THE MOONLIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ A MAN COULD SING IT ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE MOONLIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ AND A FELLOW
WOULD KNOW ♪♪
♪♪ THAT HIS DARLING ♪♪
♪♪ HAD HEARD EVERY WORD
OF HIS SONG ♪♪
♪♪ WITH THE MOONLIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ HELPING ALONG ♪♪
♪♪ BUT WHEN I TRY
IN HERE ♪♪
♪♪ TO TELL YOU, DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ I LOVE YOU
MADLY, MADLY ♪♪
♪♪ MADAM LIBRARIAN,
MARIAN ♪♪
♪♪ IT'S A LONG-LOST CAUSE ♪♪
♪♪ I CAN NEVER WIN ♪♪
♪♪ FOR THE CIVILIZED WORLD
ACCEPTS ♪♪
♪♪ AS UNFORGIVABLE SIN ♪♪
♪♪ ANY TALKING OUT LOUD
WITH ANY LIBRARIAN ♪♪
♪♪ SUCH AS MAR... ♪♪
♪♪ ...RIAN ♪♪
♪♪ MADAM LIBRAR... ♪♪
[COUGH COUGH]
♪♪ ...RIAN ♪♪
SHHH!
AAH! HA HA!
TOMMY!
[TAPPITY-TAPPITY-TAP]
SHHH!
♪♪ BUT WHEN I TR
Y IN HERE ♪♪
♪♪ TO TELL YOU, DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ I LOVE YOU
MADLY, MADLY ♪♪
♪♪ MADAM LIBRARIAN,
MARIAN ♪♪
♪♪ IT'S A LONG-LOST CAUSE ♪♪
♪♪ I CAN NEVER WIN ♪♪
♪♪ FOR THE CIVILIZED WORLD
ACCEPTS ♪♪
♪♪ AS UNFORGIVABLE SIN ♪♪
♪♪ ANY TALKING OUT LOUD
WITH ANY LIBRARIAN ♪♪
♪♪ SUCH AS MAR... ♪♪
LADIES DANCE COMMITTEE
MEETS TUESDAY NIGHTS.
♪♪ ...IAN ♪♪
MARSHMALLOW?
[BANG]
♪♪ MADAM LIBRAR... ♪♪
♪♪ ...RIAN ♪♪
[WHISTLING76 TROMBONES]
HEY, PROFESSOR!
HELLO, TOMMY!
I THINK I'VE GOT IT.
YEAH? MY MUSIC HOLDER
FOR A MARCHING
PICCOLO PLAYER.
I STILL HAVE
A COUPLE OF FLAWS.
EVEN EDISON DOESN'T ALWAYS
GET IT RIGHT THE FIRST TIME.
WHAT'S YOUR
DIFFICULTY?
WHEN YOU HOLD IT
TIGHT ENOUGH
TO KEEP
THE MUSIC STEADY,
YOU CUT OFF
THE CIRCULATION,
AND YOU CAN'T
WIGGLE YOUR FINGERS.
MEANWHILE,
YOU COULD GO BLIND.
I'D SAY IT STILL
NEEDS SOME WORK.
LIKE TO CHECK OUT
A FEW PROSPECTS WITH ME?
YOU MEAN YOU'RE
GOING IN THERE?
I DON'T SEE
ANY QUARANTINE SIGN.
GEE, I GOTTA HAND IT
TO YOU, PROFESSOR.
SEE YOU LATER...
I HOPE.
[RING]
JUST A MINUTE HERE.
ARE YOU SOLICITING?
YOU HAVEN'T GOT
A LICENSE.
WHY, NO, MR. MAYOR.
MR. MAYOR,
I COLLECT DOORBELLS,
AND THIS PARTICULAR
SPECIMEN
HAS AN UNUSUAL
TONE QUALITY--
FLATTERY
WILL NOT AVAIL YOU.
SOLICITING IS STATUTORY
IN THIS COUNTY--
MALFEASANCE
WITHOUT A PERMIT.
WHY HAVEN'T YOU
BEEN OVER TO CITY HALL
WITH YOUR REFERENCES?
I MUST HAVE
JUST MISSED YOU.
NONE OF YOUR ALIBIS!
MR. MAYOR!
YOUR HAND.
ISN'T THAT AMAZING?
WHAT? WHAT?
THAT SPREAD OF
THE LITTLE FINGER--
IT'S HEREDITARY.
IT IS?
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
WHY, IT MEANS THAT
YOUR SON'S LITTLE FINGER
IS PERFECTLY SITUATED
TO OPERATE
THE SPIT VALVE
ON A B-FLAT FLUGELHORN.
IS THAT GOOD?
GOOD?
IT ALSO MEANS AMERICA
HAS PRODUCED AN ARTIST
WHO CAN FLUGEL
THEMINUTE WALTZ
IN 5O SECONDS.
HOW CAN I GET
ONE OF THOSE HORNS?
SIGN HERE,
MR. MAYOR.
YES, SIR.
FINE, FINE.
THAT WILL BE $17
IMPORT FEE.
JUST THINK, I COULD HAVE
MISSED THIS WHOLE THING.
MY SON COULD HAVE...
I HAVEN'T GOT
ANY SON!
OH, GEORGE.
I NEVER HAD A SON!
I NEVER SAID
YOU DID.
WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
I'D CERTAINLY KNOW
IF I GAVE YOU A SON.
I'M NOT
TALKING TO YOU.
WELL, WHO ARE YOU
TALKING TO?
HIM.
WHO?
NEVER MIND.
ZANEETA, CALL DR. PYNE
FOR YOUR FATHER.
AH, YES, MY DEAR MRS. PAROO,
YOU MUST REALIZE
THAT ONLY 1
OUT OF EVERY 78 ADULTS
HAS A GANGLION THAT
REACHES THE LIGATURE
CLEAR DOWN TO THE APEX.
THIS AUTOMATICALLY
TURNS YOUR ENTIRE FACE
INTO AN AMAZING
EMBOUCHURE.
I AIN'T NEVER HAD A SICK DAY
IN ME LIFE, DOCTOR.
PROFESSOR.
PROFESSOR. WHAT
SHALL I DO FOR IT?
NO, YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
I'M TRYING
TO TELL YOU
THAT YOU HAVE ALL OF
THE FACIAL CHARACTERISTICS
OF A CORNET VIRTUOSO.
IF YOUR BOY HAS
THAT SAME FIRM CHIN,
THOSE SPLENDID
CHEEK MUSCLES--
OH, BY GEORGE...
NOT THAT HE COULD EVER REALLY
BE GREAT, YOU UNDERSTAND.
OH, IS THAT SO?
AND IN THE NAME OF
ST. BRIDGET, WHY NOT?
ALL OF THE REALLY GREAT
CORNET PLAYERS WERE IRISH--
O'CLARK,
O'MENDEZ, O'KLEIN.
BUT, PROFESSOR,
WEAREIRISH.
NO. NO, REALLY?
WELL, THAT CLINCHES IT.
SIGN HERE, MADAM.
YOUR BOY WAS BORN
TO PLAY THE CORNET.
OH, FINE, FINE.
THAT WILL BE $7.OO
EARNEST MONEY.
NOTHING MORE DUE UNTIL
THE FIRST INSTALLMENT,
PAYABLE AT THE OPENING
OF BAND PRACTICE.
OH, THANK YOU.
AND OF COURSE, I'LL NEED
YOUR BOY'S MEASUREMENTS
FOR HIS BAND UNIFORM.
HIS UNIFORM?
OH, YES.
WINTHROP!
WELL!
HELLO THERE, SON.
WHY, CERTAINLY,
HIS UNIFORM.
AND THERE WON'T BE A PENNY
DUE UNTIL DELIVERY,
WHICH GIVES HIM 4 WEEKS
TO ENJOY,
TO ANTICPATE, TO IMAGINE
AT NO COST WHATSOEVER.
NEVER ALLOW THE DEMANDS
OF TOMORROW TO INTERFERE
WITH THE PLEASURES
AND EXCITEMENTS OF TODAY.
WILL IT
HAVE A...A...
A...?
A STRIPE!
WHY CERTAINLY,
MY BOY!
A WIDE RED STRIPE
DOWN EACH SIDE.
NOW, WHAT DO YOU
THINK OF THAT?
[BARKS]
YOU'LL HAVE TO EXCUSE
WINTHROP, PROFESSOR.
WE CAN'T GET HIM TO SAY
3 WORDS A DAY--
NOT EVEN TO US.
AND IF YOU CAN GET HIM
TO PLAY IN THAT BAND,
YOU'LL HAVE SAINT MICHAEL'S
OWN WAY WITH YOU.
BUT IF ANYBODY CAN DO IT,
I BET YOU CAN.
THANK YOU.
YOU'VE A GIFT OF
THE BLARNEY ABOUT YOU
AND NO MISTAKING
ABOUT THAT.
WHERE ARE YOU FROM,
MY BOY?
GARY, INDIANA.
I KNEW IT! GAR--
WHAT'D YOU SAY?
GARY, INDIANA.
IN FACT, GARY CONSERVATORY
WAS MY ALMA MATER.
WAS SHE?
OH, YES, INDEED.
GOLD MEDAL CLASS OF 'O5.
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT A WONDERFUL
NAME ♪♪
♪♪ NAMED FOR
ALBERT GARY ♪♪
♪♪ OF JUDICIARY
FAME ♪♪
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ AS A SHAKESPEARE
WOULD SAY ♪♪
♪♪ TRIPS ALONG SOFTLY ON
THE TONGUE THIS WAY ♪♪
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ LET ME SAY IT
ONCE AGAIN ♪♪
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ THAT'S THE TOWN
THAT KNEW ME WHEN ♪♪
♪♪ NOW, IF YOU'D LIKE
TO HAVE A LOGICAL EXPLANATION ♪♪
♪♪ HOW I HAPPENED ON THIS
ELEGANT SYNCOPATION ♪♪
♪♪ I WILL SAY WITHOUT
A MOMENT OF HESITATION ♪♪
♪♪ THERE IS
JUST ONE PLACE ♪♪
♪♪ THAT CAN
LIGHT MY FACE ♪♪
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ NOT LOUISIANA ♪♪
♪♪ PARIS, FRANCE
NEW YORK, OR ROME ♪♪
♪♪ BUT GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ MY HOME SWEET HOME ♪♪
AAH!
MAMA!
HOW DO YOU DO,
MISS PAROO?
MR. HILL?
OF COURSE--PAROO!
I THOUGHT THE NAME
SOUNDED FAMILIAR.
I'VE BEEN TRYING TO SEE YOU
SINCE THE OTHER NIGHT.
HE WANTS TO PUT
WINTHROP IN THE BAND.
WE'RE NOT
INTERESTED, MAMA.
BUT THE BOY MIGHT HAVE
HIS FATHER'S MUSICAL GIFT.
HE DOES HAVE
MY GANGLION, YOU KNOW.
YOUR HUSBAND
IS MUSICAL?
WELL, I'D LIKE
TO TALK TO HIM.
DO YOU ALWAYS BURST
INTO PEOPLE'S HOMES,
PRYING INTO
PERSONAL AFFAIRS?
WE'RE NOT
INTERESTED.
MARIAN!
WELL, THERE'S ONE FOR
AND ONE AGAINST.
WHY NOT LET THE BOY'S
FATHER DECIDE?
THE BOY'S FATHER
IS DEAD.
ANYTHING ELSE?
OH, I AM SORRY.
BUT THAT'S
ALL THE MORE REASON
WHY YOUR BROTHER SHOULD
HAVE SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
MY BROTHER IS
AN UNHAPPY CHILD
WHO CAN'T UNDERSTAND
WHY HIS FATHER
WAS TAKEN AWAY.
WOULD YOU CARE TO
EXPLAIN IT TO HIM?
HE'S BEEN BROODING
ABOUT IT FOR 2 YEARS.
AND AS FOR
YOUR MUSICAL TRICKS,
WHY DON'T YOU
GO INTO BUSINESS
WITH SOME NICE
CARNIVAL MAN
WHO SELLS
GOLD-PAINTED WATCHES
AND GLASS-DIAMOND RINGS?
MUSICAL TRICKS?
NOW, MISS PAROO--
YOU KNOW, I HAVE A FEELING
SHE LIKES THE IDEA.
OH, A LITTLE CAUTIOUS,
PERHAPS,
BUT I ADMIRE THAT
IN A WOMAN.
YOU JUST KEEP ME ALIVE,
AND I'LL BE BACK
LATER IN THE WEEK.
I DO HOPE YOU'LL
EXCUSE MARIAN, PROFESSOR.
SHE'S NOT REALLY--
OH, PLEASE. DON'T YOU
WORRY ABOUT A THING.
I'M SURE THAT AT HEART
SHE'S AS LOVELY
AS YOURSELF.
GOOD DAY TO YOU,
WIDOW PAROO.
AHHHHH.
HAS HE GONE?
HE HAS, AND I HOPE
NOT FOREVER.
DARLING, DON'T YOU EVER
THINK OF YOUR FUTURE?
NOW, MAMA, A GIRL'S FUTURE
DOESN'T DEPEND
ON ENCOURAGING EVERY
FAST-TALKING, SELF-CENTERED,
WOMAN-CHASING TRAVELING MAN
WHO COMES TO TOWN.
ALL RIGHT, DARLING,
ALL RIGHT.
ONLY IT'S A WELL-KNOWN
PRINCIPLE
THAT IF YOU KEEP
THE FLINT IN ONE DRAWER
AND THE STEEL
IN THE OTHER
YOU'LL NEVER STRIKE
MUCH OF A FIRE.
MAMA!
A FINE-LOOKING MAN
AND EDUCATED--
GARY, INDIANA,
CONSERVATION CLASS
OF 'O5.
THE FACT THAT HE CLAIMS
HIS COMMODITY IS MUSIC
DOES NOT IN THIS
PARTICULAR CASE IMPRESS ME,
NOR DOES ANYTHING
ELSE ABOUT HIM.
WELL, I GIVE UP.
AT YOUR AGE--IF YOU
DON'T MIND MY ASKING--
WHAT ARE YOU
WAITING FOR?
WELL, I'M NOT WAITING
FOR ED GRINER,
WHO BACKS ME INTO
THE ANCIENT HISTORY SHELF
EVERY TIME HE COMES
INTO THE LIBRARY.
HE DOES?
OR ED GAMMAGE,
WHO HAS THE BUGGY WITH
THE REMOVABLE BACK SEAT.
WELL, IF YOU'RE WAITING FOR
A KNIGHT IN SHINING ARMOR
TO COME RIDING
UP THE STREET...
WELL, I'M NOT WAITING
FOR THAT, EITHER, MAMA.
WELL, WHAT ARE YOU
WAITING FOR?
MARIAN PAROO, IF YOU
DON'T MIND MY ASKING,
DON'T YOU EVER THINK
ABOUT BEING IN LOVE?
BEING IN LOVE,
MAMA?
♪♪ BEING IN LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ USED TO BE
MY FAVORITE DREAM ♪♪
♪♪ OH, YES ♪♪
♪♪ I'VE BEEN IN LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ MORE THAN
ANYBODY ELSE HAS ♪♪
♪♪ I GUESS ♪♪
♪♪ MY FIRST LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ HEROICALLY RAN
THE STREETCAR ♪♪
♪♪ I TINGLED
AT EVERY CLANG CLANG ♪♪
♪♪ NEXT, I FELL
FOR THE PRINCIPAL ♪♪
♪♪ BUT, OH,
THAT TEACHER WHO SANG ♪♪
♪♪ IN THE GLOAMING ♪♪
♪♪ KNEE-DEEP IN LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT A LOVELY DREAM
AND YET ♪♪
♪♪ SOMEHOW ♪♪
♪♪ KNEE-DEEP IN LOVE'S ♪♪
♪♪ ONLY HALF OF WHAT
I'M LONGING FOR ♪♪
♪♪ NOW ♪♪
♪♪ I STILL LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ MY BEING IN LOVE
WITH SOMEONE ♪♪
♪♪ BUT TELL ME,
WHY COULDN'T THERE BE ♪♪
♪♪ SOMEBODY
BEING IN LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ WITH ♪♪
♪♪ ME? ♪♪
♪♪ ALL I WANT
IS A PLAIN MAN ♪♪
♪♪ ALL I WANT IS A MODEST MAN ♪♪
♪♪ A QUIET MAN ♪♪
♪♪ A GENTLE MAN ♪♪
♪♪ A STRAIGHTFORWARD
AND HONEST MAN ♪♪
♪♪ TO SIT WITH ME ♪♪
♪♪ IN A COTTAGE ♪♪
♪♪ SOMEWHERE
IN THE STATE OF IOWA ♪♪
♪♪ AND I WOULD
LIKE HIM TO BE ♪♪
♪♪ MORE INTERESTED
IN ME ♪♪
♪♪ THAN HE IS
IN HIMSELF ♪♪
♪♪ AND MORE INTERESTED
IN US ♪♪
♪♪ THAN IN ME ♪♪
♪♪ AND IF OCCASIONALLY
HE'D PONDER ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT MAKES SHAKESPEARE
AND BEETHOVEN GREAT ♪♪
♪♪ HIM I COULD LOVE
TILL I DIE ♪♪
♪♪ HIM ♪♪
♪♪ I COULD LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ TILL I DIE ♪♪
♪♪ BEING IN LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ WHAT A LOVELY DREAM
AND YET ♪♪
♪♪ SOMEHOW ♪♪
♪
♪♪ BEING IN LOVE'S ♪
♪♪ ONLY HALF OF WHAT
I'M LONGING FOR ♪♪
♪♪ NOW ♪♪
♪♪ AND SO THEN ♪♪
♪♪ TONIGHT I'LL BE
IN THERE DREAMING ♪♪
♪♪ AND HOPING ♪♪
♪♪ THAT SOMEDAY
THERE'LL BE ♪♪
JUST ONCE!
♪♪ SOMEBODY
BEING IN LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ WITH ♪♪
♪♪ ME ♪♪
PLEASE, ZANEETA.
TOMMY, I CAN'T.
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE DOING
MY READING.
JUST TO THE CANDY
KITCHEN. COME ON.
WITH MAMA AND PAPA
SHOPPING ALL UP AND DOWN
CENTER STREET?
YE GODS!
ALL RIGHT, THEN
MEET ME AFTER SUPPER.
I CAN'T.
IT'S EPWORTH LEAGUE
TONIGHT.
MEET YOU WHERE?
THE FOOTBRIDGE.
YOU SEE? ISN'T THAT
JUST WHAT I SAID?
LAST TIME THE LUMBERYARD
AND NOW THE FOOTBRIDGE.
WHERE WILL YOU
MEET ME AFTER THAT?
IN THE BLACK HOLE
OF CALCUTTA?
YE GODS!
SHH!
IT'S INDECENT
TO MEET BOYS
AT THE FOOTBRIDGE.
FIRST THING
AFTER SUPPER?
ALL RIGHT.
YE GODS!
SHH!
THE WELLS FARGO
WAGON!
WAGON?
♪♪ OH HO,
THE WELLS FARGO WAGON ♪♪
♪♪ IS A-COMIN'
DOWN THE STREET ♪♪
♪♪ OH, PLEASE
LET IT BE FOR ME ♪♪
♪♪ OH HO,
THE WELLS FARGO WAGON ♪♪
♪♪ IS A-COMIN'
DOWN THE STREET ♪♪
♪♪ I WISH, I WISH I KNEW
WHAT IT COULD BE ♪♪
♪♪ I GOT A BOX
OF MAPLE SUGAR ♪♪
♪♪ ON MY BIRTHDAY ♪♪
♪♪ IN MARCH, I GOT
A GRAY MACKINAW ♪♪
♪♪ AND ONCE I GOT
SOME GRAPEFRUIT ♪♪
♪♪ FROM TAMPA ♪♪
♪♪ MONTGOMERY WARD
SENT ME A BATHTUB ♪♪
♪♪ AND
A CROSSCUT SAW ♪♪
IS THAT THE FIRST THING
I SAID OR NOT?
YES, GEORGE.
YES. THE VERY FIRST
THING I SAID,
OR I'LL EAT HAY
WITH A HORSE--
"GET THAT SPELLBINDER'S
CREDENTIALS!" I SAID,
MORNING OF JULY 4, 1912.
NOW MY WIFE
IS OFF DANCING
AT ANY AND ALL HOURS
INSTEAD OF IN THE HOME,
THE SCHOOL BOARD IS SINGING
UP STREET AND DOWN
INSTEAD OF TENDING
TO CITY MATTERS,
MY OLDEST GIRL
IS BOODLING AROUND
WITH SOME WILD KID,
AND MY BUSINESS
HAS FELL OFF SO FAR
I CAN'T FIND
THE BALANCE SHEET.
MAYOR SHINN,
I FOUND SOMETHING
VERY INTERESTING
IN THIS BOOK
ABOUT PROFESSOR
HILL'S ALMA MATER.
I KNOW ALL ABOUT THAT.
IN FACT, THAT'S ALL I CAN
EVER GET OUT OF HIM--
GARY CONSERVATORY,
CLASS OF 'O5.
BUT IF YOU'D JUST
TAKE TIME TO READ
A LITTLE ABOUT
THE CONSERVATORY,
YOU WOULDN'T HAVE
TO LOOK ANY FURTHER.
IT'S ON PAGE--
PAPA, THE WELLS FARGO
WAGON IS COMING THIS WAY!
WELLS FARGO WAGON?
IT COULD BE
THE BAND INSTRUMENTS!
THE BAND
INSTRUMENTS?
BUT,
MAYOR SHINN--
LATER, LATER.
♪♪ OH HO,
THE WELLS FARGO WAGON ♪♪
♪♪ IS A-COMIN' NOW ♪♪
♪♪ IS IT A PREPAID SURPRISE
OR C.O.D.? ♪♪
♪♪ IT COULD
BE CURTAINS ♪♪
♪♪ OR DISHES ♪♪
♪♪ OR A DOUBLE
BOILER ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ OR IT COULD BE--
♪♪ YES, IT COULD BE,
YES, YOU'RE RIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ IT SURELY COULD BE ♪♪
♪♪ SOMETHIN'
SPECIAL ♪♪
♪♪ SOMETHING VERY,
VERY SPECIAL NOW ♪♪
♪♪ JUST FOR ME ♪♪
♪♪ OH HO,
THE WELLS FARGO WAGON ♪♪
♪♪ IS A-COMIN'
DOWN THE STREET ♪♪
♪♪ OH, DON'T LET HIM
PASS MY DOOR ♪♪
♪♪ OH HO,
THE WELLS FARGO WAGON ♪♪
♪♪ IS A-COMIN'
DOWN THE STREET ♪♪
♪♪ I WISH I KNEW
WHAT HE WAS COMIN' FOR ♪♪
♪♪ I GOT SOME SALMON ♪♪
♪♪ FROM SEATTLE
LAST SEPTEMBER ♪♪
♪♪ AND I EXPECT
A NEW ROCKIN' CHAIR ♪♪
♪♪ I HOPE I GET MY RAISINS
FROM FRESNO ♪♪
♪♪ THE DAR HAVE SENT A CANNO
N FOR THE COURTHOUSE SQUARE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ OH HO,
THE WELLTH FARGO WAGON ♪
♪♪
♪♪ ITH A-COMIN' NOW
♪♪ I DON'T KNOW ♪♪
♪♪ HOW I CAN
EVER WAIT TO THEE ♪♪
♪♪ IT COULD BE THOMETHIN
' FOR THOMEONE ♪♪
♪♪ WHO ITH
NO RELATION ♪♪
♪
♪♪ BUT IT COULD BE ♪
♪♪ THOMETHIN'
THPECIAL ♪♪
♪♪ JUTHT FOR ME ♪♪
♪♪ OH HO,
THE WELLS FARGO WAGON ♪♪
♪♪ IS A-COMIN' ♪♪
♪♪ OH HO,
THIS WELLS FARGO WAGON ♪♪
♪♪ IS A-COMIN' ♪♪
♪♪ OH HO,
THIS WELLS FARGO WAGON ♪♪
♪♪ DON'T YOU DARE
TO MAKE A STOP ♪♪
♪♪ UNTIL YOU STOP ♪♪
FOR ME ♪♪
HERE YOU ARE, WINTHROP.
MY CORNET.
GEE THANKTH,
PROFETHOR.
THITHTER, ITHN'T THITH
THE MOTHT THCRUMPTHIOUTH
THOLID-GOLD THING
YOU EVER THAW?
I NEVER THOUGHT
I'D EVER THEE
ANYTHING THO THCRUMPTHIOUTH
AS A THOLID-GOLD THING!
OH, THISTER!
NOW, REMEMBER, MEN,
STAY OFF THE STREETS,
PAY ATTENTION
TO YOUR INSTRUMENTS,
AND THINK ABOUT
THEMINUET IN G.
♪♪ LA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE DA DEE DA ♪♪
♪♪ LA DEE DA ♪♪
THAT'S IT.
♪♪ LA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE DA ♪♪
ROUND ONE FOR YOU,
MR. HILL,
BUT I'D BETTER HEAR
SOME BY GOD TOOTIN'
OUT OF THEM HORNS
IN PRETTY SHORT ORDER,
OR I'LL SEE YOU IN
FRONT OF THE GRAND JURY
OVER AT THE COUNTY THEAT!
YES.
NOW, MISS MARIAN,
ABOUT THAT BOOK--
GEORGE,
COME ALONG.
TEMPUS FUGIT.
YOU WATCH
YOUR PHRASEOLOGY!
GO ALONG
IF YOU WANT TO.
I'VE GOT TO GET SOMETHING
FROM THE LIBRARIAN.
ABOUT THAT BOOK,
UH...
LADIES DANCE COMMITTEE
MEETS TUESDAY NIGHTS
AT THE HIGH SCHOOL.
THEY'LL BE COUNTING
ON YOU.
♪♪ LA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE DA ♪♪
♪♪ LA DEE DA ♪♪
♪♪ LA DA DA DA
DA DA DA DA DUM ♪♪
♪♪ LA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE DA DEE DUM ♪♪
♪♪ BUMM DEE DUM DEE
DUM DEE DUM DEE DUM ♪♪
♪♪ BA DA DA ♪♪
♪♪ BA DEE DA ♪♪
♪♪ BA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE DA DEE DUM ♪♪
♪♪ BA DEE DA ♪♪
♪♪ DA DEE DUM ♪♪
REALLY, GIRLS!
HURRY ALONG, LADIES.
HURRY ALONG!
TEMPUS FUGIT!
LET'S START
WITH OUR POSTURE EXERCISES.
♪♪ ♪♪
♪♪
LOVELY, LADIES,
LOVELY.
NOW TURN.
TAKE THE BODY
WITH YOU.
LOVELY.
LOVELY, LADIES.
NOW FOR
OUR GRECIAN URNS.
ONE GRECIAN URN.
2 GRECIAN URNS.
OH, THAT'S JUST AMAZING.
AND A FOUNTAIN.
TRICKLE, TRICKLE,
TRICKLE, TRICKLE...
OH, SPLENDID,
LADIES!
SPLENDID!
OUR DELSARTE DISPLAY
WILL BE THE HIGHLIGHT
OF THE ICE CREAM
SOCIABLE.
GIRLS!
NOW ONCE AGAIN.
PRACTICE MAKES
PERFECTION,
WHICH IS
WHAT WE WANT.
REMEMBER, MEN.
IF YOU WANT TO PLAY
THEMINUET IN G,
THINKTHEMINUET IN G.
IT'S A SIMPLE MEETING
OF 2 MINDS--
YOURS AND BEETHOVEN'S.
ALL TOGETHER NOW.
PROFESSOR,
I CAN'T EVEN THINK
HOW TO HOLD
THE HORN RIGHT.
THERE'S THESE LITTLE
SPIGOTS ON THE SIDE,
BUT WHICH ONE'S WHICH?
AH HA HA!
EXPERIMENTATION.
TRIAL AND ERROR.
COULD YOU SHOW ME,
PROFESSOR?
SON, I'M GOING TO
TELL YOU SOMETHING
THE GREAT GIUSEPPE CREATORE
SAID TO ME ONCE
UNDER LIKE CIRCUMSTANCES.
"PROFESSOR HILL," HE SAID,
"THAT IS YOUR INSTRUMENT.
"HOLD ONTO IT.
CHERISH IT.
"DON'T LET ANYBODY ELSE
PLAY AROUND WITH IT,
"NOT EVEN ME,
NOT EVEN YOU,
UNTIL YOU FEEL
YOU'RE READY."
BUT--
AH AH AH.
YES, SIR.
ALL TOGETHER, NOW.
OVER AND OVER.
♪♪ LA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE DA DEE DA ♪♪
♪♪ LA DEE DA ♪♪
TOMMY?
♪♪ LA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE... ♪♪
TAKE CHARGE
OF THE GROUP.
ANOTHER HALF HOUR
AT LEAST
ON THEMINUET.
♪♪ LA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE DA DEE DA ♪♪
♪♪ LA DEE DA ♪♪
♪♪ LA DEE DA DEE
DA DEE DA... ♪♪
STRAWBERRY PHOSPHATE,
PLEASE.
BE RIGHT WITH YOU.
YE GODS!
GREAT HONK!
IF THERE'S ANYTHING
YOU DON'T SEE THERE,
YOU BE SURE
AND ASK FOR IT.
AHEM.
OH, PROFESSOR HILL,
I DIDN'T SEE YOU.
MAY I JOIN YOU?
WELL, REALLY, I--
WHERE?
THEY WERE SEEN!
RED-HANDED!
CAUGHT IN THE ACT!
TAKE YOUR HANDS
OFF MY DAUGHTER!
PAPA!
MR. SHINN, YOUR HONOR,
YOUR DAUGHTER AND I
ARE GOING STEADY
BEHIND YOUR BACK.
WHY, YOU--
WE'D RATHER BE DOING IT
IN FRONT OF YOUR BACK.
DO WHAT?
NEVER MIND!
ZANEETA'S
SCARED OF YOU,
BUT I'M NOT!
I SHOULD THINK YOU'D HATE
TO HAVE YOUR OWN DAUGHTER
SCARED OF YOU.
GREAT HONK.
I'M GOING TO WARN YOU
ONCE MORE.
IF I EVER CATCH YOU
TOUCHING MY DAUGHTER,
I'LL HORSEWHIP YOU.
NOW, GEORGE!
NOT ONE POOP
OUT OF YOU, MADAM.
I THINK
HE MEANS PEEP.
YEAH.
NOW GET OUT
OF THIS PUBLIC EMPORIUM!
I GOT AS MUCH RIGHT
IN A PUBLIC EMPORIUM
AS ANYBODY!
RIGHT? HOW DO YOU GET
ANY RIGHT AROUND HERE,
AIDING AND ABETTING
THE SWINDLING ACTIVITIES
OF THIS SPELLBINDING
CYMBAL SALESMAN?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT I SEE
WRITTEN ALL OVER YOU?
REFORM SCHOOL.
NOW GET OUT!
GET OUT,
YOU WILD KID, YOU!
PAPA, PLEASE!
IT'S CAPULETS LIKE YOU
MAKE BLOOD
IN THE MARKETPLACE!
YE GODS!
YOU WATCH YOUR
PHRASEOLOGY,
YOUNG WOMAN!
GO HOME.
TAKING UP
WITH WILD KIDS
FROM THE WRONG SIDE
OF TOWN...
MAYOR SHINN, IF I COULD
JUST MAKE YOU UNDERSTAND.
WELL, YOU CAN'T!
AND, BY THE WAY, THANKS
FOR THE BUGGY RIDE.
I READ THAT BOOK
YOU GAVE ME
FROM COVER TO COVER
FOR A WHOLE WEEK NOW
AND DIDN'T FIND
A THING.
MR. MAYOR,
IF YOU PLEASE--
I'LL SETTLE YOUR HASH
AS SOON AS I GET
THESE PREMISES
OFF MY OLDEST GIRL.
YES?
ALL RIGHT,
BUT IN THE MEANTIME,
I'D LIKE YOU TO KNOW
I'M VOUCHING FOR TOMMY DJILAS.
THAT BOY HAS THE CONFIDENCE
OF EVERY KID IN THIS TOWN.
YOU'LL BE STANDING IN LINE
WAITING TO SHAKE HIS HAND
BY THE TIME OUR BAND PLAYS
ITS FIRST CONCERT.
BY THAT TIME, MY FINE
YOUNG FEATHERED--
MY FEATHERED YOUNG--
MY FEATHERED FINE--
NEVER MIND!
HA HA HA HA!
OLIVER, JACEY,
EWART, OLIN!
I WANT THAT MAN'S
REFERENCES,
AND I WANT THEM
TONIGHT!
HE'S SLIPPERIER THAN
A MISSISSIPPI...
STURGEON.
I THINK MAYOR SHINN
BEHAVED ABOMINABLY,
AND I THINK IT WAS
WONDERFUL OF YOU
STICKING UP FOR TOMMY DJILAS
THE WAY YOU DID.
OH, THAT WAS NOTHING.
OH, YES, IT WAS.
WELL, A MAN CAN'T GO BACK
ON HIS PRINCIPLES
MERELY BECAUSE A LITTLE
PERSONAL RISK IS INVOLVED.
WHAT DOES THE POET SAY?
"A COWARD DIES
A THOUSAND DEATHS,
A BRAVE MAN...
ONLY 500."
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
GET HIS PAPERS
OR GET HIM IN JAIL!
I COULDN'T MAKE
MYSELF ANY CLEARER
IF I WAS A BUTTONHOOK
IN THE WELL WATER!
I'VE BEEN WANTING
TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT WINTHROP'S CORNET.
OH, YES.
A BEAUTIFUL INSTRUMENT--
HAND-HAMMERED BRASS,
MOTHER-OF-PEARL KEYS.
BUT HE NEVER TOUCHES
THE CORNET.
HE SAID YOU TOLD HIM
IT WASN'T NECESSARY.
YOU MUST UNDERSTAND,
MISS MARIAN--
SOMETHING ABOUT
A THINK SYSTEM.
HE SAYS IF HETHINKS
THEMINUET IN G,
HE CAN PLAY IT.
I ADMIT IT'S STILL IN
THE EXPERIMENTAL STAGES,
AND I SUPPOSE TO
A SEASONED PROFESSIONAL
IT MAY SEEM LUDICROUS.
OH, YOU MUSTN'T
SAY THAT.
I MUSTN'T?
NO. WHY,
THROUGHOUT HISTORY,
THE TRUE ORIGINATOR
IS ALWAYS LAUGHED AT.
I HOPE YOU DON'T
CLASS ME
WITH THOSE SMALL MINDS
WHO RIDICULED--
GALILEO.
YES. AND HIS CONCEPTION
OF THE HEAVENS.
OR FULTON.
YES. OR COLUMBUS.
AND HIS CONCEPTION
OF THE EGG. UH, GLOBE.
THE ONE THING
ONE MUST REMEMBER,
NO MATTER WHO ONE IS
OR WHAT ONE IS WORKING FOR,
ONE CAN DO ANYTHING
IF ONE PUTS ONE'S MIND TO IT.
MISS MARIAN, IF ONE
COULD ONLY TELL YOU
HOW MUCH
YOU'VE DONE FOR ONE.
I WOULD DEEM IT
A GREAT PRIVILEGE
TO TALK WITH YOU
AGAIN.
WELL, ALL I SAID--
MAY ONE CALL UPON YOU
SOME EVENING?
ANY NIGHT THIS WEEK.
[WHISTLINGGARY, INDIANA]
GOOD EVENING,
GENTLEMEN.
SORRY, PROFESSOR,
BUT WE GOT OUR ORDERS.
WE ALL
BEEN DEPUTIZED.
YES, YES, YES, YES.
WELL, CONGRATULATIONS.
NOW, LET ME SEE.
EVERY TIME I TRY
TO GIVE YOU FELLOWS
THOSE CREDENTIALS,
YOU ALWAYS TRY TO CHANGE
THE SUBJECT SOMEHOW.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE
A CONSPIRACY.
I'LL JUST GO TO MY ROOM
AND GET THEM RIGHT NOW.
SORRY. AFRAID
I'LL HAVE TO GO WITH YOU.
OH, YES.
WELL, LET'S SEE
IF I HAVE MY KEY.
WHAT'S THIS?
WELL, WHAT DO YOU KNOW?
A TESTIMONIAL FROM THE ONLY
FEMALE BASSOON PLAYER
EVER TO APPEAR
ON THE REDPATH CIRCUIT--
MADAME REENYHOOK.
OH, THAT'S
HER STAGE NAME, OF COURSE.
ACTUALLY, SHE'S FROM MOLINE.
LIDA ROSE QUACKENBUSH.
COULDN'T I
JUST SEE THAT?
YOU NEVER FORGET
THE NAME LIDA ROSE.
JUST LIKE
IN THE OLD SONG.
NONE OF THAT, NOW.
♪♪ LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ I'M HOME AGAIN, ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ TO GET THE ♪♪
♪♪ SUN ♪♪
♪♪ BACK IN THE ♪♪
♪♪ SKY ♪♪
♪♪ LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ I'M HOME AGAIN, ROSE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ ABOUT A THOUSAND KISSES SHY ♪
♪♪ DING ♪♪
♪♪ DONG ♪♪
♪♪ I CAN HEAR ♪♪
♪♪ THE CHAPEL BELL CHIME ♪♪
♪♪ DING ♪♪
♪♪ DONG ♪♪
♪
♪♪ AT THE LEAST SUGGESTION ♪
♪♪ I'LL POP THE QUESTION ♪♪
♪♪ LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ I'M HOME AGAIN, ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ WITHOUT A SWEETHEART
TO MY NAME ♪♪
♪♪ LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ HOW EVERYONE KNOWS ♪♪
♪♪ THAT I AM HOPING
YOU'RE THE SAME ♪♪
♪
♪♪ SO HERE IS MY LOVE SONG ♪
♪♪ NOT FANCY OR FINE ♪♪
♪♪ LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ OH, WON'T YOU BE ♪♪
♪♪ MINE?
LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ LIDA ROSE
OH, LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ OH, LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ DREAM OF NOW
♪♪ DREAM OF THEN ♪♪
♪♪ DREAM OF A LOVE SONG ♪♪
♪♪ THAT MIGHT HAVE BEEN ♪♪
♪♪ DO I LOVE YOU? ♪♪
♪♪ OH, YES, I LOVE YOU ♪♪
♪♪ AND I'LL BRAVELY TELL YOU ♪♪
♪♪ BUT ONLY
WHEN WE DREAM AGAIN ♪♪
♪♪ SWEET ♪♪
♪♪ AND LOW ♪♪
♪♪ HOW SWEET THAT MEMORY ♪♪
♪♪ HOW LONG AGO? ♪♪
♪♪ FOREVER? ♪♪
♪♪ OH, YES, FOREVER ♪♪
♪♪ WILL I EVER TELL? ♪♪
♪♪ LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ OH, LIDA ROSE, OH ♪♪
♪
♪♪ DREAM OF NOW... ♪
♪♪ TO GET THE SUN
BACK IN THE SKY... ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ DREAM OF A LOVE SONG
♪♪ ABOUT A THOUSAND
KISSES SHY ♪♪
♪♪ DO I LOVE YOU? ♪♪
♪♪ I CAN HEAR
THE CHAPEL BELL CHIME ♪♪
♪♪ AND I'LL
BRAVELY TELL YOU ♪♪
♪♪ AT THE LEAST SUGGESTION
I'LL POP THE QUESTION ♪♪
♪♪ SWEET AND LOW ♪♪
♪♪ WITHOUT A SWEETHEART
TO MY NAME ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ HOW SWEET THE MEMORY
♪♪ THAT I AM HOPING
YOU'RE THE SAME ♪♪
♪♪ FOREVER? ♪♪
♪♪ NOT FANCY OR FINE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ WILL I
EVER TELL YOU? ♪
OH, LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ OH, NO ♪♪
[SIGHS]
WILL YOU EVER STOP
ARGUING WITH YOURSELF?
WILL YOU EVER TELL HIM?
WON'T YOU EVER TELL HIM?
AH, YES, AH, NO.
AW, FIDDLESTICKS.
JUST OPEN YOUR MOUTH
AND LET IT COME OUT.
NOW, MAMA...
NOW, NOTHING.
AND IF HE EVER CALLS AGAIN,
YOU SEE HIM ALONE.
AND IF YOU HAVEN'T GOT
THE GUMPTION
TO TELL HIM
HOW YOU FEEL--
TELL HIM?
THERE'S NOTHING WRONG
WITH A LADYLIKE HINT.
WHAT'S THAT THING
YOU GOT?
IT'TH A GENUINE HERCULETH
COMBINATHION POCKETKNIFE
AND TOOL KIT
WITH THICK,
THTURDY THTEEL BLADES.
BLESSED
MARTIN OF TOURS!
ONE THPEAR BLADE,
ONE THMALL PEN BLADE,
A FILE, AND A COMBINATHION
TACK PULLER AND THCREWDRIVER.
WHERE'D YOU PICK UP
THAT HORRIBLE WEAPON?
IT WAS A PRESENT
FROM HAROLD.
PROFESSOR HILL?
UH-HUH.
HE THAYTH IF I'M GOING TO
THTICK AROUND RIVER THITY,
I BETTER LEARN
TO WHITTLE AND THPIT.
I GOT THE THPITTING DOWN
PRETTY GOOD.
WINTHROP, WHAT
DO YOU AND HAROLD
FIND TO TALK ABOUT?
THOMETIMETH
WE TALK BUTHINETH
AND THOMETIMETH
JUTHT PLAIN TALK.
HE TALKS ABOUT HIS HOMETOWN,
GARY, INDIANA,
AND HE THAID MAYBE HE'LL
TAKE ME THERE THOMEDAY.
WELL, ISN'T THAT NICE?
HE TAUGHT ME
A THONG ABOUT IT
WITH HARDLY
ANY ETHETH IN IT.
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ LET ME THAY IT
ONTHE AGAIN ♪♪
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ THAT'TH THE TOWN
THAT KNEW ME WHEN ♪♪
♪♪ IF YOU'D LIKE TO HAVE
A LOGICAL EXPLANATHION ♪♪
♪♪ HOW I HAPPENED ON
THITH ELEGANT THINCOPATHION ♪♪
♪♪ I WILL THAY WITHOUT A MOMENT
OF HETHITATHION ♪♪
♪♪ THERE ITH JUTHT ONE PLATHE ♪♪
♪
♪♪ THAT CAN LIGHT MY FATHE ♪
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ AND NOT LOUITHIANA ♪♪
♪♪ PARITH, FRANTH
NEW YORK, OR ROME ♪♪
♪♪ BUT ♪♪
♪♪ GARY, INDIANA ♪♪
♪♪ MY HOME, SWEET HOME ♪♪
[TAPPITY-TAPPITY-TAP]
HA HA HA HA!
ALL RIGHT,
ENOUGH OF THAT.
COME ALONG, NOW.
YOU STILL HAVE TO CHANGE
FOR THE SOCIABLE.
HEY, DO THE SHINNS
LIVE AROUND HERE SOMEWHERE?
THE SHINN HOME
IS ON EAST ELM.
THIS IS WEST ELM.
OH, CRIMINY!
OH, I SEE YOU'RE
THE PIANO TEACHER
HERE IN TOWN.
YOU MUST KNOW ABOUT
THIS FELLOW HILL
FORMING
A BOYS' BAND HERE.
YES!
WELL, DON'T LET THAT
WORRY YOU NO MORE.
I GOT THE GOODS ON HIM
IN SPADES,
THAT SWINDLING
2-BIT THIMBLERIGGER!
THAT'S WHY I GOT
TO SEE SHINN.
I'M JUST PASSING
THROUGH,
AND NUMBER 8 ONLY MAKES
A 15-MINUTE
WATER STOP, AND--
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
OOH!
I WISH IT WAS 2O.
SURE COULD CONCENTRATE
5 MINUTES ON YOU,
GIRLIE-GIRL.
WHO ARE YOU?
THE NAME'S
CHARLIE COWELL.
ANVIL SALESMAN.
[BANG]
BUT I'VE GOT HEAVIER
THINGS ON MY MIND.
I'VE GOT TO PROTECT
THE GOOD NAME OF
THE TRAVELING FRATERNITY
FROM THAT SWINDLER HILL.
MR. COWELL, YOU'RE
MAKING A BIG MISTAKE.
MISTAKE, MY OLD LADY'S
CORSET COVER.
THAT FELLOW'S BEEN
THE RASPBERRY SEED
IN MY WISDOM TOOTH
JUST LONG ENOUGH.
HE SPOILED ILLINOIS
FOR ME,
BUT HE'S NOT GOING
TO SPOIL IOWA.
WHAT KIND OF MUSIC
TEACHER ARE YOU, ANYWAY?
HE'S NO MORE PROFESSOR--
I KNOW ALL ABOUT THAT.
BAND LEADERS ARE
ALWAYS CALLED PROFESSOR.
IT'S AN ACADEMIC COURTESY.
HE'S A FINE DIRECTOR--
NOW WAIT A MINUTE!
FINE DIRECTOR?
YOU HEARD ONE NOTE
OF MUSIC FROM ANY BAND?
WELL...NO, BUT--
BUT NOTHING,
GIRLIE-GIRL.
HE NEVER FORMED
A BAND IN HIS LIFE,
AND YOU THINK
HE EVER WILL?
NOT ON YOUR PREVIOUS
EXISTENCE.
IF YOU'LL JUST LISTEN
TO ME FOR A MINUTE...
I'D LIKE TO...
DO MORE THAN THAT
IF I HAD THE TIME.
SURE GOT THE INCLINATION.
BUT I'VE GOT TO GET BACK
ON THAT TRAIN,
AND I'VE GOT TO LEAVE
THIS DYNAMITE
WITH SOMEBODY ON THE WAY
TO THE DEPOT.
BYE, GIRLIE-GIRL.
I'LL SEE YOU
NEXT TIME.
YOU'LL NEVER MAKE
THAT TRAIN AT THE DEPOT.
YOU'LL HAVE TO CATCH IT
AT THE CROSSING.
NO, SIR.
GOT TO LEAVE WORD,
AND I CAN SEE YOU AIN'T
THE ONE TO LEAVE IT WITH.
WAIT A MINUTE...
MR. COWELL.
♪♪
♪♪♪♪♪♪
YOU DON'T KNOW ME
VERY WELL YET.
IS THAT AN INVITATION,
GIRLIE-GIRL?
NO!
I MEAN, UH,
I DON'T KNOW YOU.
YEAH, I'D NEED
MORE TIME ANYWAY.
WHAT I MEAN IS, UH,
AS WELL
AS I'D LIKE TO.
♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪
OH, THERE'S NO TROUBLE
THERE, GIRLIE-GIRL.
♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪
I'VE, UH,
NEVER MET A MAN
WHO SELLS ANVILS BEFORE.
IT'S REALLY QUITE...
DIFFERENT.
♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪
IT TAKES A REAL SALESMAN
TO TELL YOU THAT.
ANVILS HAVE A LIMITED
APPEAL, YOU KNOW.
♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪
WHAT AM I DOING?
IF I MISS THAT TRAIN,
I'LL LOSE MY JOB.
I'VE GOT TO LEAVE WORD
ABOUT THAT FELLOW HILL.
LEAVE WORD WITH ME.
NOT ON YOUR TINTYPE,
GIRLIE-GIRL.
HOW DO I KNOW YOU'D
DELIVER THESE LETTERS?
TRY ME.
♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪ ♪♪
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
[TRAIN
RUMBLES]
THERE'S YOUR TRAIN.
NOW RUN FOR IT!
WHY, YOU
DOUBLE-DEALING--
WHO DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE PROTECTING?
THAT GUY HAS A GAL
IN EVERY COUNTY
IN ILLINOIS,
AND THAT'S
1O2 COUNTIES!
NOT COUNTING
THE PIANO TEACHERS
LIKE YOU
HE COZIES UP TO
JUST TO KEEP
YOUR MOUTHS SHUT.
NEITHER ONE OF YOU
HAVE HEARD
THE LAST OF ME,
GIRLIE-GIRL!
♪♪ ...SUGGESTION ♪♪
♪♪ I'LL POP THE QUESTION ♪♪
♪♪ LIDA ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ I'M HOME AGAIN, ROSE ♪♪
♪♪ WITHOUT A SWEETHEART
TO MY NAME ♪♪
♪♪ GOOD EVENING,
MISS MARIANNNN ♪♪
♪♪ LIDA ROSE,
HOW EVERYONE KNOWS ♪♪
♪♪ THAT I AM HOPING
YOU'RE THE SAME ♪♪
MARIAN!
♪♪ SO HERE IS MY LOVE... ♪♪
MARIAN, DEAR,
WHO WAS YOU TALKING--
WHY, PROFESSOR HILL!
MRS. PAROO, THE TOP
OF THE EVENING.
MISS MARIAN.
YOU AND MARIAN
COME UP AND SET.
I'VE GOT SOME JELLY
ON THE STOVE.
THERE'S NO JELLY
ON THE STOVE, MAMA.
WELL, I'LL PUT SOME ON.
SHALL WE SET,
AS YOUR MOTHER SAID?
REALLY, I DON'T--
YOU DID ASK ME
TO CALL, REMEMBER?
DID I?
I DIDN'T MEAN ANYTHING.
OH, NOW, MISS MARIAN,
I'M NOT SUGGESTING
THAT YOUR INVITATION
INFERRED ANYTHING
BUT ACADEMIC
ENLIGHTENMENT,
THE THINK SYSTEM.
I'VE BEEN BY YOUR HOUSE
A TIME OR TWO
TO TRY TO
EXPLAIN IT TO YOU,
BUT THERE ALWAYS SEEM
TO BE PEOPLE AROUND--
LADIES, MOSTLY,
I THOUGHT.
YES. MRS. SQUIRES AND
SEVERAL OF THE OTHER LADIES.
I'M GLAD.
I WOULDN'T WANT ANYONE
BEATING MY TIME.
YOU WOULDN'T?
NO, MA'AM.
WELL, IT'S EVIDENTLY
NOT THE CONVENIENT
EVENING.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER
AT THE SOCIABLE.
PROFESSOR HILL,
IS IT TRUE THAT
YOU'VE HAD A HUNDRED...
WHAT I'M TRYING
TO SAY IS...
YES?
I WAS WONDERING...
HOW YOU DEVELOPED
THE THINK SYSTEM.
THE THINK SYSTEM?
OH! THE THINK
SYSTEM!
WELL, IT'S QUITE
SIMPLE, REALLY.
IT'S AS SIMPLE
AS WHISTLING.
NO ONE HAD TO DEVELOP
ANY ELABORATE TECHNIQUE
FOR WHISTLING.
YOU SIMPLY THINK
THE TUNE UP HERE,
AND IT COMES OUT
CLEARLY HERE.
[WHISTLING]
JUST YOU SUPPOSE
YOU TRY THIS YOURSELF.
I'LL TAKE YOUR WORD FOR IT.
WHY DON'T WE ALL
SIT DOWN?
ARE ALL MUSIC TEACHERS
AS DENSE AS I AM?
ALLMUSIC TEACHERS?
DARESAY
YOU'VE MET DOZENS,
MAYBE
EVEN A HUNDRED.
WELL...
ARE THEY ALL AS
FASCINATED AS I WITH...
THE THINK SYSTEM?
SOME MORE
AND SOME LESS.
ONE YOUNG LADY HAD
THOUGHT UP THE SAME SYSTEM
BEFORE I GOT TO HER TOWN.
SHE SHOWED ME
A FEW REFINEMENTS.
I SEE.
HAVE I SAID
SOMETHING WRONG?
PLEASE DON'T LET ME
KEEP YOU, PROFESSOR HILL.
YOU MUST HAVE MANY MORE
IMPORTANT THINGS TO DO
THAN EXPLAIN
THE THINK SYSTEM TO ME.
NOPE. I CAN'T THINK OF A ONE.
LET'S SIT DOWN.
I MUST BE
VERY DULL COMPANY
FOR A MAN
OF YOUR EXPERIENCE.
WHERE DID YOU EVER GET
AN IDEA LIKE THAT?
ONE HEARS RUMORS ABOUT
TRAVELING SALESMEN.
YOU MUSTN'T BELIEVE
EVERYTHING YOU HEAR.
AFTER ALL,
ONE EVEN HEARS RUMORS
ABOUT LIBRARIANS.
I PRESUME
YOU'RE REFERRING
TO UNCLE MADDY?
UNCLEMADDY?
MR. MADISON,
MY FATHER'S BEST FRIEND.
NO MATTER WHAT THEY SAY,
HE LEFT ME
THAT LIBRARY JOB TO ME
SO MOTHER, WINTHROP, AND I
COULD HAVE SOME SECURITY.
SURELY
YOUDON'T BELIEVE--
NO, NO, NO, BUT THAT'S
JUST WHAT I'M SAYING.
WHY DO YOU SUPPOSE
PEOPLE START THOSE RUMORS?
NARROW-MINDEDNESS,
JEALOUSY.
JEALOUSY,
MOSTLY, I GUESS.
EXACTLY!
JEALOUSY MOSTLY STARTS RUMORS
ABOUT TRAVELING SALESMEN.
WHAT HAVE YOU HEARD?
OH, NOTHING
ABOUT YOU PERSONALLY.
IT'S JUST,
YOU KNOW, GENERALLY.
WELL, WHAT
HAVE YOU HEARD GENERALLY?
JUST THAT...
BUT, OF COURSE!
IT STANDS TO REASON
THAT DISAPPOINTMENT
AND JEALOUSY
CAN LEAD TO--
TAKE YOU,
FOR INSTANCE.
YOUR ATTENTIONS TO
CUSTOMERS AND TEACHERS
MIGHT EASILY
BE MISCONSTRUED,
MIGHTN'T THEY?
I MEAN, NOW, HONESTLY,
AND AS YOU SAY, IF A SALESMAN
OR SOMEBODY WERE JEALOUS,
THEY COULD BE DOWNRIGHT
LIES, NOW, COULDN'T THEY?
WHAT COULD?
RUMORS AND THINGS.
WHY, OF COURSE!
IT JUST GOES TO SHOW YOU
YOU SHOULD NEVER BELIEVE
EVERYTHING YOU HEAR.
I MEAN, IF YOU'D
JUST DISCUSS THINGS!
I WOULD BE DELIGHTED
TO DISCUSS
ANYTHING IN THE WORLD
WITH YOU,
BUT COULDN'T WE DO IT
SITTING DOWN?
YOU DO SIT?
YOUR KNEES BEND?
WE COULD SIT
ON THE STEPS.
WE COULD ALSO
SIT ON A LOG
AT THE FOOTBRIDGE.
NO. I COULDN'T DO THAT.
I'VE NEVER BEEN TO
THE FOOTBRIDGE WITH A MAN
IN MY LIFE.
JUST TO TALK.
I HAVE TO DRESS
FOR THE SOCIABLE.
THEN MEET ME THERE
IN 15 MINUTES.
OH, NO, I--I CAN'T.
PLEASE.
SOME OTHER TIME.
MAYBE TOMORROW.
PLEASE.
OH, MY DEAR
LITTLE LIBRARIAN,
YOU PILE UP
ENOUGH TOMORROWS,
AND YOU'LL FIND YOU'VE
COLLECTED NOTHING
BUT A LOT OF
EMPTY YESTERDAYS.
I DON'T KNOW ABOUT YOU,
BUT I'D LIKE TO MAKE
TODAY WORTH REMEMBERING.
OHH.
SO WOULD I.
THE FOOTBRIDGE.
15 MINUTES.
MAMA!
WHAT?
I JUST TOLD THE PROFESSOR
I'D MEET HIM
AT THE FOOTBRIDGE.
GLORY BE AND
THE SAINTS BE PRAISED.
IT WORKS!
WHAT WORKS?
I'VE BEEN USING
THE THINK SYSTEM ON YOU
FROM THE PARLOR.
HEY, ANY OF YOU PEOPLE
MAYOR SHINN?
HEY!
HEY! PLEASE!
YOU'VE GOT TO
CLEAR THIS AREA.
MRS. SHINN WANTS TO START
THE ENTERTAINMENT.
OH!
WE WANT TO DANCE.
WAIT UNTIL YOU SEE
SOME OF THE NEW STEPS
PROFESSOR HILL
TAUGHT US.
MR. WASHBURN, MY GROUP
IS READY TO PERFORM!
START HER OUT,
MR. WASHBURN.
OK. WHAT WILL IT BE?
THE SHIPOOPI!
YAY!
♪♪ NOW, A WOMAN WHO'LL KISS
ON THE VERY FIRST DATE ♪♪
♪♪ IS USUALLY A HUSSY ♪♪
♪♪ AND A WOMAN WHO'LL KISS
ON THE SECOND TIME OUT ♪♪
♪♪ IS ANYTHING BUT FUSSY ♪♪
♪
♪♪ BUT A WOMAN WHO'LL WAIT
TILL THE THIRD TIME AROUND ♪
♪♪ HEAD IN THE CLOUDS,
FEET ON THE GROUND ♪♪
♪♪ SHE'S THE GIRL
HE'S GLAD HE'S FOUND ♪♪
♪♪ SHE'S HIS SHIPOOPI ♪♪
♪♪ SHIPOOPI ♪♪
♪♪ THE GIRL
WHO'S HARD TO GET ♪♪
♪♪ SHIPOOPI ♪♪
♪♪ BUT YOU CAN
WIN HER YET ♪♪
♪♪ WALK HER ONCE
JUST TO RAISE THE CURTAIN ♪♪
♪♪ WALK AROUND TWICE,
AND YOU MAKE FOR CERTAIN ♪♪
♪♪ ONCE MORE
IN THE FLOWER GARDEN ♪♪
♪♪ SHE WILL NEVER GET SORE
IF YOU BEG HER PARDON ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ DO RE MI FA SOL LA SI DO
♪♪ SI LA SOL FA MI RE DO ♪♪
♪♪ SQUEEZE HER ONCE
WHEN SHE ISN'T LOOKING ♪♪
♪♪ IF YOU GET A SQUEEZE BACK
, THAT'S FANCY COOKIN' ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ ONCE MORE FOR A PEPPER-UPPER
♪♪ SHE WILL NEVER GET SORE
ON HER WAY TO SUPPER ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ DO RE MI FA SOL LA SI DO
♪♪ SI DO ♪♪
♪♪ NOW, LITTLE OL' SAL
WAS A NO-GAL ♪♪
♪♪ AS ANYONE COULD SEE ♪♪
♪♪ LOOK AT HER NOW,
SHE'S A GO-GAL ♪♪
♪♪ WHO ONLY GOES FOR ME ♪♪
♪♪ SQUEEZE HER ONCE
WHEN SHE ISN'T LOOKING ♪♪
♪♪ IF YOU GET A SQUEEZE BACK
, THAT'S FANCY COOKIN' ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ ONCE MORE FOR A PEPPER-UPPER
♪♪ SHE WILL NEVER GET SORE
ON HER WAY TO SUPPER ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ DO RE MI FA SOL LA SI DO
♪♪ SI DO ♪♪
♪♪ SHIPOOPI ♪♪
♪♪ THE GIRL
WHO'S HARD TO GET ♪♪
♪♪ SHIPOOPI ♪♪
♪♪ BUT YOU
CAN WIN HER YET ♪♪
WHOA!
♪♪ SHIPOOPI ♪♪
♪♪ THE GIRL
WHO'S HARD TO GET ♪♪
♪♪
♪♪ SHIPOOPI
♪
♪♪ SHIPOOPI... ♪
HEY, PROFESSOR,
SHOW US SOME NEW STEPS!
WHOA!
♪♪ SHIPOOPI ♪♪
♪♪ THE GIRL WHO'S HARD TO GET ♪♪
♪
♪♪ BUT YOU CAN WIN HER YET ♪
♪♪ YOU CAN WIN HER YET ♪♪
♪♪ SHIPOOPI! ♪♪
YAY!
WHOO!
WHOO! HOO!
YAY!
PROFESSOR HILL, I--
THIS IS NO PLACE
TO TALK.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
BACK DOWN?
NO. I'LL COME, BUT I PROMISED
MOTHER AND WINTHROP
TO HAVE A PLATE OF CREAM
WITH THEM.
YOU GO ALONG.
I'LL MEET YOU THERE.
15 MINUTES.
HA HA HA HA!
AND NOW WE ARRIVE
AT THE HIGH-WATER MARK
OF THE EVENING'S FESTIVITIES.
THE RIVER CITY LADIES'
EURYTHMIC DANCE GROUP,
UNDER THE LEADERSHIP
OF MY WIFE,
WILL GIVE THEIR INTERPRETATION
OF, UH, OF...
PSSST!
GRECIAN URNS.
YES.
PSST! PSST!
ONE GRECIAN URN.
[APPLAUSE]
HA HA HA!
[PLAYING
GOOD NIGHT, MY SOMEONE]
MISS MARIAN,
YOU'RE LATE.
YOU SAID 15 MINUTES.
I DON'T MEAN
THAT KIND OF LATE.
I MEANT...I'D SAY
ABOUT 26 YEARS LATE.
IT TOOK YOU ALL THIS TIME
TO GET TO THE FOOTBRIDGE
WITH A FELLOW.
IF YOU WANT TO KNOW
THE TRUTH,
IT WAS ALMOST LONGER.
HALFWAY HERE,
I NEARLY TURNED BACK.
I SUPPOSE I'M NOT THE FIRST
PERSON TO DISCOVER
A GIRL DOESN'T
THINK TOO CLEARLY
WHEN UNDER THE SPELL
OF YOUR SALESMANSHIP.
OH, NOW, MISS MARIAN,
YOU SURELY DON'T THINK
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO SELLYOUANYTHING?
NO. YOU'VE GIVEN ME
SOMETHING.
THAT'S WHY
I HAD TO COME.
I DON'T RECALL
GIVING YOU--
OH, YES,
SOMETHING BEAUTIFUL.
THAT'S WHY I CAME.
AND I'M SO GLAD.
PLEASE DON'T BE AFRAID THAT
I EXPECT TOO MUCH MORE.
ONE CAN'T EXPECT
A TRAVELING SALESMAN
TO STAY PUT.
I KNOW THERE HAVE BEEN
MANY PORTS OF CALL,
AND THERE'LL BE
MANY MORE.
STILL, I CAN BE GRATEFUL
FOR WHAT YOU'VE
LEFT BEHIND--FOR ME.
WELL, MARIAN--
♪♪ THERE WERE BELLS
ON THE HILL ♪♪
♪
♪♪ BUT I NEVER
HEARD THEM RINGING ♪
♪♪ NO, I NEVER
HEARD THEM AT ALL ♪♪
♪♪ TILL THERE
WAS YOU ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WERE BIRDS
IN THE SKY ♪♪
♪♪ BUT I NEVER
SAW THEM WINGING ♪♪
♪♪ NO, I NEVER
SAW THEM AT ALL ♪♪
♪♪ TILL THERE WAS YOU ♪♪
♪♪ AND THERE WAS MUSIC ♪♪
♪♪ AND THERE WERE
WONDERFUL ROSES ♪♪
♪♪ THEY TELL ME ♪♪
♪♪ IN SWEET,
FRAGRANT MEADOWS ♪♪
♪
♪♪ OF DAWN AND DEW ♪
♪♪ THERE WAS LOVE
ALL AROUND ♪♪
♪♪ BUT I NEVER
HEARD IT SINGING ♪♪
♪♪ NO, I NEVER
HEARD IT AT ALL ♪♪
♪♪ TILL THERE
WAS YOU ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WAS LOVE
ALL AROUND ♪♪
♪♪ BUT I NEVER
HEARD IT SINGING ♪♪
♪♪ NO, I NEVER
HEARD IT AT ALL ♪♪
♪♪ TILL THERE
WAS YOU ♪♪
MARIAN, THERE ARE
A LOT OF THINGS
THAT YOU DON'T KNOW
ABOUT ME.
I'M NOT ASKING.
EXCUSE ME.
I'M EXPECTING A TELEGRAM
FROM RUDI FRIML.
THIS COULD BE IT.
SAY, WHO'S THE SALESMAN
AROUND HERE?
LOOKS LIKE SHE'S SELLING,
AND YOU'RE BUYING.
I TOLD YOU I HAD
TO KEEP HER OFF BALANCE.
YEAH. SHE'S SO
OFF BALANCE NOW
YOU CAN'T TELL HER FROM
A CATBOAT IN A HURRICANE.
I GOT TO KEEP HER
THAT WAY
UNTIL THOSE UNIFORMS
ARRIVE.
THEY'RE HERE,
AND THE KIDS ARE IN THEM.
TOMMY PASSED OUT UNIFORMS AND
COLLECTED MOST OF THE MONEY.
NOW HE'S TRYING TO KEEP
THE KIDS TOGETHER,
PRETENDING THERE'S
A BAND PRACTICE
DOWN AT THE LUMBER YARD.
WHAT TIME DOES
THE FREIGHT TRAIN GO?
9:4O.
IT ISN'T EVEN
8:3O YET.
LISTEN, YOU BETTER
CHEESE IT NOW WHILE YOU CAN.
LISTEN, I CAME UP
THROUGH THE RANKS
ON THIS SKIRMISH,
AND I'M NOT RESIGNING
WITHOUT MY COMMISSION.
NOW GO ON. BEAT IT.
NEVER A PEACEFUL MOMENT
IN THE MUSIC BUSINESS.
NOW, WHERE WERE WE?
YOU WERE GOING TO
TELL ME
WHAT I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT YOU.
YEAH. WE DON'T HAVE TO
GO INTO THAT RIGHT NOW,
DO WE?
OF COURSE NOT.
WE NEVER HAVE TO
GO INTO THAT, HAROLD.
MADAM LIBRARIAN,
YOU ARE A LADY
FROM THE GROUND UP.
THE LIBRARIAN
HASN'T FELT MUCH
LIKE DOING
RESEARCH LATELY.
BUT SHE DID PLENTY OF IT
WHEN YOU FIRST CAME HERE.
OH?
ABOUT WHAT?
OH, ABOUT
PROFESSOR HAROLD HILL,
GARY CONSERVATORY
OF MUSIC,
GOLD MEDAL CLASS
OF 'O5.
HAROLD,
THERE WASN'T ANY
GARY CONSERVATORY
IN 'O5.
WELL, THERE MOST--
BECAUSE THE TOWN
WASN'T BUILT UNTIL 'O6.
COME ON, WALK ME HOME.
I HAVE TO GET SOMETHING
TO DRAW AROUND MY SHOULDERS.
YOU KNEW
ALL THE TIME.
I'VE KNOWN SINCE 3 DAYS
AFTER YOU CAME HERE.
I TORE THIS OUT OF
THE INDIANA JOURNAL.
I MEANT TO USE IT
AGAINST YOU.
NOW I GIVE IT TO YOU
WITH ALL MY HEART.
BUT IF YOU KNEW--
♪♪ IT'S YOUR SWEET
"HELLO, DEAR" ♪♪
♪♪ THAT SETS ME UP ♪♪
♪♪ AND IT'S YOUR
"GOT TO GO, DEAR" ♪♪
♪♪ THAT GETS ME DOWN ♪♪
♪♪ IT'S YOU
ON MY PILLOW ♪♪
♪♪ IN ALL OF MY DREAMS ♪♪
♪♪ TILL ONCE MORE
THE MORNING... ♪♪
STOP! STOP!
STOP, I TELL YOU!
LISTEN TO THIS MAN.
WHY, YOU
BONE-HEADED,
SQUARE-TOED,
TANK-TOWN BOOBS!
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO TELL YOU!
CAN'T YOU GET IT
THROUGH YOUR HEADS
THAT THIS MUSIC FELLOW'S
GIVING YOU
THE DOUBLE SHUFFLE?
HE'S PUTTING THE SHAKE
ON YOU!
HE'S TAKING OUT
YOUR EYE TEETH
WHILE YOU'RE LOOKING
THE OTHER WAY!
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING
TO SAY, MISTER?
I'LL TELL YOU
WHAT I'M SAYING!
THERE'S BURGLARS
IN THE BEDROOM
WHILE YOU'RE FIDDLING
IN THE PARLOR!
WHO'S BEDROOM ARE
THE BURGLARS FIDDLING IN?
QUIET.
I'M TALKING
ABOUT HAROLD HILL--
A SHELL WORKER,
A FLIMFLAMMER,
AN 18-KARAT THIEF!
YOU MEAN
THE MUSIC PROFESSOR?
MUSIC PROFESSOR?
NOT ON YOUR FIRELESS
COOKER, MISTER!
FELLOW THAT
ORGANIZED THE BAND?
THERE AIN'T
ANY BAND.
THERE AIN'T NEVER
BEEN A BAND!
GONNA BE A BAND!
AND UNLESS YOU HUNT
THIS MAN DOWN RIGHT NOW
LIKE A MAD DOG,
THERE AIN'T GONNA BE
A HAROLD HILL, EITHER!
HE'LL BE ON HIS WAY
TO THE STATE LINE!
I SAID ALL ALONG,
GET HIS CREDENTIALS!
I GOT HIS CREDENTIALS
RIGHT HERE!
WELL, WHAT ARE WE
WAITING FOR?
I WANT MY MONEY BACK!
I WANT HIS HIDE!
FIND HIM AND BRING HIM
OVER TO THE HIGH SCHOOL
ROPED AND HOG-TIED
IF YOU HAVE TO
AND DON'T LET HIM
GIVE YOU THE SLIP!
ALL RIGHT, AFTER HIM!
HAVE YOU SEEN
PROFESSOR HILL?
HAVEN'T BEEN LOOKING
FOR HIM.
I'LL ONLY BE A MINUTE.
[WHISTLING76 TROMBONES]
♪♪ WHILE 11O CORNETS
PLAYED THE AIR ♪♪
♪♪ THEN I MODESTLY
TOOK MY PLACE ♪♪
♪♪ AS THE ONE
AND ONLY BASS ♪♪
♪
♪♪ AND I OOMPAHED
UP AND DOWN THE SQUARE ♪
♪♪ GOOD NIGHT,
MY SOMEONE ♪♪
♪♪ GOOD NIGHT, MY LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ WITH 11O CORNETS
RIGHT BEHIND ♪♪
♪♪ OUR STAR IS SHINING ♪♪
♪♪ ITS BRIGHTEST LIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WERE HORNS
OF EVERY SHAPE AND... ♪♪
♪♪ SWEET DREAMS
BE YOURS, DEAR ♪♪
♪♪ IF DREAMS
THERE BE ♪♪
♪♪ WHILE 11O CORNETS
PLAYED THE AIR ♪♪
♪♪ I WISH I MAY ♪♪
♪♪ AND I WISH
I MIGHT ♪♪
♪♪ NOW GOOD NIGHT,
MY SOMEONE... ♪♪
GOOD NIGHT.
HE'S NOT
IN THERE.
TRY THE LIVERY
STABLE!
TRY THE FREIGHT DEPOT!
LET'S GO, GREG.
I GOT THE FLIVVER
ALL CRANKED UP.
THEY'RE ON TO YOU
ALREADY.
THERE'S A CRAZY
ANVIL SALESMAN
RUNNING ALL OVER TOWN
SPILLING EVERYTHING.
COME ON!
YOU BETTER RUN,
PROFESSOR.
THEY'RE TALKING
ABOUT TAR AND FEATHERS.
I'VE BEEN LOOKING
ALL OVER FOR WINTHROP.
HE'S RUN AWAY.
MAYBE HE'S IN HIS ROOM.
IT'S NOT OFTEN
I FIND MYSELF
AT A LOSS FOR WORDS, BUT--
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
DON'T YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU DON'T OWE ME
A WORD--NOT A WORD.
HURRY, PLEASE.
GREG!
HARRY'S NOT
AROUND HERE, FOLKS!
LET'S TRY DOWN
BY THE CREAMERY!
HOLD ON A MINUTE,
SON.
I'M NOT YOUR SON.
LEAVE ME GO!
NO. NOT UNTIL I TALK
TO YOU A MINUTE.
I WON'T LISTEN.
YOU WOULDN'T
TELL THE TRUTH, ANYWAY.
I WOULD, TOO.
WOULD NOT.
WOULD, TOO.
I'LL TELL YOU ANYTHING
YOU WANT TO KNOW.
CAN YOU LEAD A BAND?
NO.
ARE YOU A BIG LIAR?
YES.
ARE YOU A DIRTY,
ROTTEN CROOK?
YES.
LEAVE ME GO,
YOU BIG LIAR.
YOU WANTED THE TRUTH,
DIDN'T YOU?
LOOK, I'M BIGGER
THAN YOU ARE,
AND YOU'RE GOING TO
STAND THERE AND GET IT ALL,
SO JUST STOP WIGGLING.
NOW, THERE ARE
2 THINGS
YOU'RE ENTITLED
TO KNOW.
ONE, YOU'RE
A WONDERFUL KID.
I THOUGHT SO
FROM THE FIRST.
THAT'S WHY I WANTED YOU
IN THE BAND,
SO YOU'D STOP
MOPING AROUND AND
FEELING SORRY FOR YOURSELF.
WHAT BAND?
I ALWAYS THINK
THERE'S A BAND, KID.
WHAT'S THE OTHER THING
I'M ENTITLED TO KNOW?
THE OTHER THING'S
NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS,
COME TO THINK OF IT.
I WITH YOU'D NEVER
COME TO RIVER THITY.
NO, YOU DON'T,
WINTHROP.
THITHTER,
YOU BELIEVE HIM?
I BELIEVE EVERYTHING
HE EVER SAID.
BUT HE PROMITHED UTH.
I KNOW WHAT
HE PROMISED US,
AND IT ALL HAPPENED
JUST LIKE HE SAID--
THE LIGHTS, THE COLORS,
THE CYMBALS,
AND THE FLAGS.
WHERE WATH ALL THAT?
IN THE WAY EVERY KID
IN THIS TOWN WALKED AROUND
AND LOOKED AND ACTED--
ESPECIALLY YOU.
AND THE PARENTS, TOO.
DOES MAMA WISH HE'D
NEVER COME TO RIVER CITY?
WELL, YOU DO,
DON'T YOU?
NO, WINTHROP.
YOU BETTER GO, HAROLD,
PLEASE.
GO ON, PROFETHOR.
HURRY UP.
I CAN'T GO,
WINTHROP.
WHY NOT?
FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN MY LIFE,
I GOT MY FOOT
CAUGHT IN THE DOOR.
♪♪ THERE WAS LOVE ♪♪
♪♪ ALL AROUND ♪♪
♪♪ BUT I NEVER
HEARD IT SINGING ♪♪
♪♪ NO, I NEVER
HEARD IT AT ALL ♪♪
TILL THERE WAS YOU.
GREG!
GREG, THEY'RE HERE!
RUN THIS WAY!
GO, PROFETHOR,
THAT WAY!
REMEMBER,
FELLOW RIVER CITY-ZEANS,
I DID EVERYTHING
IN MY POWER
TO PREVENT
THIS DIRE HAPPENING FROM...
HAPPENING.
"FOURSCORE--"
HOW DO YOU PROPOSE
TO GET OUR MONEY BACK?
HE COLLECTED
ALMOST $3OO ON UNIFORMS.
I HAVEN'T
SEEN A UNIFORM
OR MY BOY,
EITHER.
HE'S A KIDNAPER.
A FINE SITUATION
WE HAVE HERE, ISN'T IT?
"FOURSCORE--"
JUST A MINUTE!
VIRTUE HAS TRIUMPHED!
THE SWORD OF RESTIBUTION
HAS CUT DOWN
PROFESSOR HAROLD HILL!
OH! OH!
AND IF THERE ARE THOSE,
AS I'VE HEARD,
WHO ARE MELTING TAR
AND PLUCKING FEATHERS,
I WILL NOT
SAY THEM NAY.
I SHOULD THINK
SOME OF YOU
COULD FORGET
YOUR IOWA STUBBORNNESS
LONG ENOUGH TO REMEMBER
WHAT THIS TOWN WAS LIKE
BEFORE HAROLD HILL CAME.
WELL, DO YOU?
NOW, HOLD UP
THERE--
AND AFTER HE CAME--
SUDDENLY, THERE WERE
THINGS TO DO,
THINGS TO BE PROUD OF,
AND PEOPLE TO GO
OUT OF YOUR WAY FOR.
SURELY, SOME OF YOU
CAN BE GRATEFUL
FOR WHAT THIS MAN
HAS BROUGHT TO US.
AND I SHOULD THINK
YOU'D WANT TO ADMIT IT!
YOU'RE WASTING
A GREAT DEAL OF TIME HERE!
IF THERE'S A PERSON
IN THIS HALL
WHO DOESN'T WANT THIS MAN HILL
TARRED AND FEATHERED,
LET HIM, BY GOD,
STAND UP!
EULALIE, SIT DOWN!
[WHOMP]
[STAMPS FOOT]
THE REST OF YOU
WHO ARE STANDING THERE
LIKE A COTE
OF SHROPSHIRE SHEEP--
MAYBE YOU CAN REMEMBER
SOME OTHER THINGS,
LIKE WHAT YOU PAID
FOR ALL THOSE UNIFORMS,
TECHNICAL
INSTRUCTION BOOKS,
AND BAND INSTRUMENTS
WITH THE CLEAR
UNDERSTANDING AND WARRANTY
YOUR CHILDREN WOULD BE
TAUGHT TO PLAY IN A BAND!
WELL, WHERE'S THE BAND?
WHERE'S THE BAND?
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
OH! OH!
AWW! AWW!
NO, I COULDN'T.
NOW, THINK, MEN.
THINK!
♪♪#
♪♪#!
♪♪%$
THAT'S MY BARNEY!
THAT TUBA'S
MYBARNEY!
WONDERFUL, BARNEY.
THAT'S EDDIE!
THAT'S EDDIE'S
CLARINET!
♪♪#!
♪♪%$
LINUS,
PLAY TO ME, SON.
PLAY TO ME!
♪♪#!
♪♪%$
DAVEY!
THAT'S MY DAVEY!
♪♪#!
♪♪%$
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[TWEET]
[PLAYING76 TROMBONES]
[BANG]
OH!
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
WARNER BROS.
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
♪♪ 76 TROMBONES
LED THE BIG PARADE ♪♪
♪♪ WITH 11O CORNETS
CLOSE AT HAND ♪♪
♪♪ THEY WERE FOLLOWED
BY ROWS AND ROWS ♪♪
♪♪ OF THE FINEST VIRTUOSOS ♪
♪
♪♪ THE CREAM
OF EVERY FAMOUS BAND ♪♪
♪♪ 76 TROMBONES
CAUGHT THE MORNING SUN ♪♪
♪♪ WITH 11O CORNETS
RIGHT BEHIND ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WERE MORE THAN
A THOUSAND REEDS ♪♪
♪♪ SPRINGING UP LIKE WEEDS ♪
♪
♪♪ THERE WERE HORNS
OF EVERY SHAPE AND KIND ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WERE
COPPER-BOTTOM TIMPANI ♪♪
♪♪ IN HORSE PLATOONS ♪♪
♪♪ THUNDERING, THUNDERING
ALL ALONG THE WAY ♪♪
♪♪ DOUBLE-BELL EUPHONIUMS
AND BIG BASSOONS ♪♪
♪♪ EACH BASSOON
HAVING HIS BIG FAT SAY ♪♪
♪♪ THERE WERE 5O MOUNTED CANNON
IN THE BATTERY ♪♪
♪♪ THUNDERING, THUNDERING
LOUDER THAN BEFORE ♪♪
♪♪ CLARINETS OF EVERY SIZE ♪
♪
♪♪ AND TRUMPETERS
WHO'D IMPROVISE ♪♪
♪♪ A FULL OCTAVE HIGHER ♪♪
♪♪ THAN THE SCORE ♪♪