(WOMAN VOCALISING)
(BABY COOING)
(VOCALISING CONTINUES)
(SINGING) You are my world
My darling
What a wonderful world I see
You are the song I'm singing
You're my beautiful Melody
Darling we'd better be going
Look at her, isn't she glowing
She looks divine
and you look exquisite
- But look at the time
- Couldn't be is it
The crew is awaiting your orders
We're sailing away from our borders
Steady. boy, steady
Ahoy there! They're coming!
Trumpeters ready!
Drummers, start drumming!
(TRUMPETERS PLAY FANFARE)
Down to the sea we go
Down to a world I know
There's never been not ever before
A child born of sea and shore
CREW: Down to the sea we go
Down to the world below
A journey to bless a princess-to-be
Under the sun
And under the sea
Ariel's coming
Ariel's coming?
- Ariel's coming?
- Ariel's coming
- Ariel's coming, Ariel's coming
What's all the big commotion
That's spreading through the ocean
From sea to shining sea
(LAUGHS)
There is no hesitating
Today we celebrating
Ariel's Melody
Today when Triton's daughter
comes back here to the water
We gonna have a spree
Ha!
The boat is nearer now
I think I hear her now
Ariel's Melody
CHORUS: La-da, da-da, di-da-da
- La-da, da-da, di-da-da
- Ohh-oh
- CHORUS: La-da-di-daah
- Yeah
- CHORUS: La, la-da, di-da-da
- La-la-la
- CHORUS: La-da, di-da-da
- La-la-la La-la, la-la
MERPEOPLE: Up from the sea we rise
Up to the world of skies
There's never been not ever before
A child born of sea and shore
Up from the sea we rise
Up to the world of skies
Forever to be together as one
Under the sea
And under the sun
This is your world my darling
One world, the land and sea
My hope for you for always
Is that your heart will hold part of me
Down to the sea we go
- Up from the sea
- Down to the world below
ALL: Together we come forever to be
Under one sun
The land and the sea
- MAN 1: Congratulations!
- (WHISTLING AND CHEERING)
MAN 2: Wonderful!
(COOING)
My precious Melody,
I'm giving you this locket
so that you will never forget
that part of your heart
will always belong to the sea.
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
(COOING CONTINUES)
Melody!
(CACKLING)
A party!
Ursula's crazy sister!
I didn't miss the cake and ice cream,
did I? (LAUGHING)
Morgana!
Surrender the baby, or I'll...
Ah-ah-ah.
Ursula would have simply
loved to have come,
but something came up.
Now, what was it? Oh, yes.
- (GASPS)
- You all shish-kebabbed her!
One minute you're on top,
the next you're sushi.
Now, is that fair, Gramps? I ask you.
But then, whoever said
we had to play fair?
(CACKLES)
Oh, Undertow!
Make way, little mershrimp!
I'm comin' through!
(GASPS)
(MELODY COOING)
Hand over the trident,
or your precious granddaughter
will be shark chow!
You can have anything you want.
Just don't harm little Melody.
Well, well.
I get the trident,
avenge poor, unfortunate Ursula,
and gain all the powers of the ocean,
and it's not even 10:00.
Not a bad morning.
- Hit the deck!
- (GROANS)
Ahh! Ohh!
(BOTH SCREAM)
(COOING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
Melody!
What have you done to me? Look at me!
I'm an anchovy! Ah!
This isn't the end, Triton!
It's just the beginning!
After her!
(MORGANA CACKLING)
You'll never find me!
But I'll find you
and your precious granddaughter!
We shall not rest
until that madwoman is vanquished!
Find her!
TRITON: I'm sorry.
There is no sign of her. She's vanished.
- We'll keep trying.
- ARIEL: Sweetie, no.
Oh, we've got to keep Melody
away from her.
Until Morgana is found,
Melody can't go in the sea.
And neither will I.
- But, Ariel...
- I'm sorry, Flounder.
But if Morgana is anything like Ursula,
she'll never give up.
This is the only way.
Melody can't know about
merpeople or Atlantica
or even you, Daddy.
(SIGHS)
Very well, Ariel.
You're right.
Sebastian, you will watch over her.
Me?
Aww!
ARIEL: Melody?
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Melody?
Oh, Carlotta, have you seen Melody?
Not since this morning, Your Majesty.
(CHEF LOUIS HUMMING)
Louis, Melody's not in here, is she?
No, Your Highness,
but her birthday cake is.
Twelve petite candles.
C'est magnifique!
Whoa-ohh!
(CHUCKLES)
Whoo-eee!
This is gonna be some kind of shindig.
Yes, sir,
a real swanky soiree, as they say.
There's just one thing missing,
the guest of honour!
"Sebastian, you watch over her,"
he said.
(GRUNTS)
I'm too old for this!
A crab my age
should be retired, getting a tan,
playing sea golf,
sipping a tuna colada!
Not baby-sitting another teenager.
Oh. Hmm.
(GASPS) Melody!
(SIGHS)
Hey, Scuttle.
Hey, Sebastian. What's kickin'?
Uh, hat's kickin'? Hmm. Let me see.
Don't rush me.
Ha! You know perfectly well
what's kicking.
Now, come along.
You gonna be late for the...
- (SPLASHING)
- (COUGHING)
(GIGGLING)
Sorry, Sebastian.
Melody, child,
how many times do I have to tell you?
BOTH: It is expressly forbidden
for you to be swimming
beyond the safety of the sea wall.
Beyond the safety of the sea wall.
Any such swimming
is a reckless disregard of the rules,
don't you know?
- Stop that.
- (GIGGLES)
Oh, Sebastian, I can't help it.
I just love the sea!
Hey! (COUGHING) Come back here!
You're just like,
like your mother.
(CHORTLING) Hi, Melody.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(MORGANA LAUGHING)
Trust me!
This time I'm sure I've got it right.
Yeah, that's what you said last time,
and I was sore for a week.
Oh, stop your carping and stand still.
Oh, this is gonna hurt.
Yes. Yes. Yes!
Uh-oh.
(SIGHS)
Hmph!
Aw!
(GROANS)
(SNICKERING)
Oh.
It's just no use.
The power of the trident
is just too strong for me to overcome.
I bet Ursula could've done it.
What was that you said?
Nothin'. I'm just sayin'...
Stop criticising me!
That's all my mother ever did
was criticise me.
It was always Ursula this or Ursula that
or, "Morgana, why can't you be
more like your sister
"Ursula!"
Well, it isn't
Ursula's fault I got miniaturised.
- It's yours!
- Is not!
Your fault that we had to hide out here
for 12 frostbitten years.
- Is not!
- Your fault that we can never
show our faces in polite society again!
You're really pushing it, small fry.
(MORGANA GASPS)
BOTH: It's the locket!
Ooh-ha-ha!
This is just the kind of break
in the ice we've been waiting for.
When Ariel's innocent little daughter
uncovers the secret of that locket,
she's going to have lots of questions.
And who'll be right there
with all the answers?
- (CHUCKLES) We will.
- Exactly!
She'll be the perfect tool
for Triton's undoing.
And I'll get to be big again.
Finally I'll succeed
at the one thing my sister never could.
Really, really big again!
Total domination of the seas!
- (CACKLING)
- (LAUGHING) I'll be huge!
Melody, please.
If your mother ever found out
you'd been swimming out here...
I know, I know. She'd flip.
I had a thought here.
Now, where'd it go? Hmm.
Hey, Sebastian, what's my mom
got against the ocean anyway?
I mean, how could there
be anything wrong with something so
wonderful?
(MELODY GIGGLES)
You know what?
Sometimes I even pretend
I have fins.
(SIGHS)
I wish I could tell my mom how I feel.
But she'd never understand.
I can talk to crabs, but
not to her.
Wait a minute. (GROANS)
It just hit me.
How 'bout you tell Ariel
how you really feel?
Oh, yes, by all means.
Just waltz right in
and tell her you been out here
swimming in the ocean!
We could all just have a big party.
(GASPS) The party!
Say, that reminds me of somethin'.
(MAX BARKING)
- Whoa!
- Oh, Your... Your Highness.
Sorry. My fault.
I gotta go.
Can't go to the party without shoes.
(GIGGLES)
If you ask me, she's a little strange.
- I heard she actually talks to fish.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
BOY 1: You're kidding.
BOY 2: It should make
for an interesting party.
GIRL: Yes! I should say! (LAUGHING)
(MAX BARKING)
(SNIFFING)
(PANTING)
- (SEAGULLS CALLING)
- (SIGHS)
I miss you, Daddy.
I wish you could be here with us.
(SIGHS)
- Mother?
- (GASPS)
- What are you doing?
- Uh, nothing.
(BOTH SIGH)
ARIEL: I'll be right up!
Melody?
(GASPS)
(SPUTTERS)
I'm ready.
(CHUCKLES)
Here. Let me help.
(DOOR OPENS)
So, we're having a bad hair day.
If we were,
you wouldn't be helping, would you?
I'm just here to let you know there are
a lot of people downstairs...
Oh, we'll be right down.
Give us two minutes.
(CHUCKLING) Right, two...
Where have I heard that before?
Mom, put down the brush.
- It's hopeless.
- Oh.
You look beautiful.
Do I have to do this?
Everybody thinks I'm weird.
Oh, honey, everyone has trouble
fitting in at your age.
I know I did.
I was a regular fish out of water.
You? No way.
I'm just so afraid
I'm gonna make a total fool of myself.
Melody, this isn't just
about the party, is it?
Is there something
you want to talk about?
You know you can always
tell me anything.
Well, okay.
I mean, it's kinda crazy and
sort of impossible.
Now, don't freak,
but what I dream about
more than anything in the whole world...
- (TAPPING ON GLASS)
- How's it coming?
Oh, Melody. Is that you?
You look beautiful.
(GIGGLES)
He's right. Now, we'll talk later.
You're going to have
a wonderful time tonight. Trust me.
May I present Her Royal Highness,
Princess Melody.
Oh, yeah. Mom's right. I can do this.
(MUFFLED SHOUTS)
Um, hi. Would you like to dance?
(WHISPERS) Go on.
Sure. Okay.
(MUFFLED SHOUTS CONTINUE)
(WALTZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANS)
(MUFFLED SHOUTS CONTINUE)
(GASPS)
- (CRUNCH)
- Yeow!
(GASPS)
(YELLING)
Huh?
(YELLING CONTINUES)
Ahh!
(HUMMING)
(LOUD SPLAT)
- Hmm
- (LAUGHS)
(GUESTS MURMURING)
- Oh, no!
- That's it.
I'm booking myself on a cruise.
- I'm so sorry.
- Well, I should say!
- Are you okay, Sebastian?
- So.
- Who is she talking to?
- (LAUGHING)
- She's talking to a crab!
- (GUESTS LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
You!
- (SHRIEKS)
- Saboteur!
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
You're going in the bouillabaisse!
Oh, no! No, Louis!
You don't wanna do this, man!
I'm old! I'm not tender any more!
Louis!
(GROWLS)
Ah!
Huh?
Melody!
(GROWLS)
Death to the crab!
(SPUTTERS)
Oh, Louis!
(SOBBING)
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Oh, sweetheart,
I'm so sorry.
What's wrong with me?
Oh, nothing's wrong with you.
Mom, I'm the princess of disaster.
Being a teenager is hard,
and, uh, all kids your age feel awkward.
- And...
- Melody?
What is this? My name's on here.
(GASPS)
- (MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
- That song. Where have I heard it?
It's Atlantica.
With merpeople and everything.
Mother, you always said it
was just an old fish tale.
Where did you get this?
I, I found it.
You went over the wall, didn't you?
Actually, I went under it.
I hate that stupid wall.
Melody, you know you're
not allowed in the sea.
But why?
And why does that necklace
have my name on it?
Melody, listen to me.
You're hiding something from me.
You deliberately disobeyed me!
I never want you going out there again!
It's dangerous in the sea!
How would you know?
You've never even been in it!
(RESUMES SOBBING)
Melody, I...
Uh...
(SIGHS) Oh, no.
Ariel, darling,
we knew this day would come.
Oh, Eric.
You're right.
It's time I trusted her with the truth.
Oh, now, child, it's gonna be okay.
You know, when I was a teenager
you couldn't get me
out of my shell for nothin'.
I had this high, squeaky voice
and these itty-bitty little pincers.
And then one day, boom!
I sound like Caruso
and these whoppers pop out!
Young lady, just where
do you think you're going?
I've gotta figure this out.
(WHIMPERS)
This necklace means something,
and if no one's gonna tell me,
I'm gonna find out myself.
Ahh!
(GASPING)
Melody, please!
You're making a big mistake!
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, this is delicious.
This is divine!
- Let's go, flatsos.
- (MORGANA CHUCKLES)
Hurry, Undertow.
There's a little girl out there
who needs our help.
All right, Sebastian,
you must remain calm.
This is not your fault.
All you have to do
is go in there and calmly explain
that Melody has run away.
No reason to lose your head.
Whatever you do,
you "absitively, " "positutely"
must not panic.
- Melody!
- (GASPS)
- Melody's gone, Melody's gone!
- Sebastian? What are you doing here?
All my fault! I tried to stop her!
(SOBBING) I don't deserve to live!
Gone? Gone where?
Out, out.
To the sea.
(BLOWS NOSE)
What do you mean?
Where could she be going?
To Morgana's.
And she can tell me what this
locket means,
why it has my name on it?
(CHUCKLING) Oh, sure, kid.
Morgana's the best. She'll help ya.
Okay. Then let's go.
(CHUCKLES WICKEDLY)
(SNICKERING)
Angel face, meet the one and only
Morgana.
Oh, welcome, my precious.
Oh, don't be shy.
Come in. Come in out of the cold.
Sit, sit.
Put your feet up.
Hungry? Afraid all I have is a cold plate.
(CHUCKLES)
Smelt-cicle? Kelp chip?
Hush guppy?
Uh, no, thank you.
I was hoping you could
tell me about this pendant,
why it has my name on it.
My mother wouldn't tell me. (SIGHS)
She just doesn't understand.
Oh, you're not the only one with
a mother who doesn't understand you.
Believe me, I know just how you feel.
Dear child, did you ever consider
that it has your name on it
because it has your destiny in it?
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
Oh, deep down you know
you weren't meant to be
a lowly human.
What you are is something
far more enchanting.
A mermaid?
But it's not possible.
(CHUCKLES) Darling,
anything's possible.
You can turn me into a mermaid?
Piece of fish cake, honey.
(MUTTERS) Huh!
Lotsa luck.
(HUMMING)
Ah.
Ursula's magic? Where'd you get that?
I've been saving it
for a special occasion.
(CHUCKLES) One drop of this
and, bada-bing, bada-boom!
You're in fin city! Whee!
- Really?
- Come, my darling.
Your destiny awaits you.
(CACKLING)
(CONTINUES CACKLING)
I don't believe it!
I'm a mermaid.
Say it loud, say it proud! (CACKLING)
(LAUGHING)
I'm a mermaid!
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
You had this all along.
You could've changed me back.
Why, I oughta...
Keep your scales on, small fry.
I'm still reeling her in.
ARIEL: Oh, Daddy, I'm so worried.
Everything's going to be all right, Ariel.
We have search parties
scouring the ocean.
I'm going to join them now myself.
Ariel, maybe you should go with him.
But, Eric...
I need to stay here
and lead the search on land.
But you know these waters,
and you know our daughter.
You have to go.
It may be dangerous.
Eric's right, Daddy.
I should've known
I couldn't keep Melody from the sea.
It's a part of her.
And a part of me.
I have to go.
Bring her home.
What a totally cool feeling!
(GIGGLING) Whee!
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERS)
Oh, excuse me. I'm so sorry, ma'am.
(SINGING) Okay, get a grip
Get the hang of this flipper
It's like slipping two feet
into one big, huge slipper
This way is left
Which way is right
Oh, now I'll be circling
in circles all night
Oh, so this is forward. No problem.
I can't believe I can do this and more
To swim in the sea
like I walk on the shore
Out of my shell
Not closed up like a clam
Look out, sea
This is me
Here I am
For a moment all of me
Is alive and at home in the sea
I'm swirling and twirling
So graceful and grand
Not stubbing my toes
Getting stuck in the sand
For a moment life is cool
I'm a splash in the world's biggest pool
This is more than my thoughts
ever thought it could be
For a moment
Just a moment
Lucky me
(GIGGLING)
If only for one moment
I had shared with you all I know
The sea wouldn't be a mystery
Oh, why did you have to go
Everything's newer
and brighter and bluer
And truer to life than before
Watch me soar
For a moment I can shine
Got a grin and a fin that works fine
My fingers are wrinkly
and I really don't care
If all of my curls
have curled out of my hair
For a moment I can feel
All the dreams
I've been dreaming are real
Wish my mother could hear it
The sea is my song
For a moment
Just a moment
I belong
I will find you, my darling
And the moment that I do
I'll hold you close, my Melody
And sing the song of the sea
With you
- Sing the song of the sea
- For a moment, just a moment
- With you
- I belong
Oh, thank you! Thank you so much!
Oh. (SNIFFLING)
What's the matter?
Oh, I knew this would happen.
One taste, and you're hooked.
Oh, Undertow,
I'm such a failure, such a...
Oh, my precious,
there wasn't enough potion
for this to be a forever spell.
Please, I don't want
to go back to being an ordinary girl.
Isn't there some way
I can stay a mermaid?
No, I'm afraid there's
absolutely no possible way.
Well, there is one way.
No. What am I thinking?
It's far too dangerous.
What? What's too dangerous?
Well, I could make the spell last longer
if I had my magic trident.
Oh, but it was stolen years ago
by a deranged kleptomaniac,
and there's no one to get it back for me.
Maybe I could get it back for you.
You would do that for me?
If I did, would you
make me a mermaid forever?
Even longer, if you like. (CHUCKLES)
Now, here is where the scoundrel lives.
Atlantica?
You mean it's not just an old fish tale?
It really exists?
Of course it exists, dear.
Whoever told you otherwise?
My mother.
Well, I'm sure she didn't mean
to be cruel and deceitful.
Okay, I'll bring back your trident.
You can count on me!
Be careful, dear.
Enjoy those fins!
While you can.
(CHUCKLES WICKEDLY)
Hmm. Let's see.
South to Two Circles Pass,
then, uh, north to...
No, no, um, east to...
Uh... Hmm.
Ah...
- (SNEEZES)
- Whoa!
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
My map. It's ruined.
Now how am I gonna
find my way to Atlantica?
Help! Someone, please!
Help! Oh! Oh, hold on, sweetie!
We'll save you!
Help! Mama! Hurry!
I can't reach her.
- (ALL GRUNTING)
- (ALL MURMURING)
Somebody help us!
(TIP SINGS FANFARE)
Mightier than a hurricane!
Braver than a killer whale!
Faster than a moray eel!
It's the fearless adventurers...
Slash-explorers.
Titanic Tip
and his trusty sidekick Dash!
- Oh, no.
- Not them.
(CHUCKLES)
This is it, Dash. Redemption.
No, not the walrus.
- DASH: Sorry. Excuse me.
- Ow!
Oh, was that your face?
We're finally gonna be heroes for real.
Yeah, they're not gonna
laugh at us any more.
- This is too easy.
- (GRUNTING)
And a-one, and a-two,
and a shark...
- Shark?
- Shark!
DASH: Shark, shark, shark!
TIP: Comin' through!
- Goin' up, goin' up, goin' up!
- Goin' down.
(ALL SCREAM)
(ALL GRUNTING)
Ahh!
Oh! Mmm! Mmm.
- (ALL GRUNTING)
- TIP: Get off me!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Well, that wasn't so bad.
Oh.
- Mama!
- Mmm!
Another plan perfectly executed.
What did you think you were doing?
We were just trying to be heroes.
You call abandoning my baby heroic?
You two boys almost got us all killed.
Oh, yeah, some fearless heroes.
- More like zeroes!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
PENGUIN: That's a good one!
Go ahead.
Laugh your stinkin' tuxedos off.
We'll show you, someday.
- Excuse me.
- Ahh!
Ohh! Ooh!
You don't have to be scared of me.
I won't hurt you.
Scared? Who said anything
about bein' scared?
Don't you know an evasive manoeuvre
when you see one?
(GIGGLES)
Hi. I'm Melody.
This here's Tip, and I'm Dash.
Excuse me, Mr I Spill My Guts
To Total Strangers.
- You just blew our cover.
- I was just trying to be friendly.
Uh, guys, I really need to get going,
so if you could just tell me...
See? Now she's gonna leave,
and it's all your fault.
My fault? (SPUTTERS)
- Guys...
- She's probably allergic to blubber.
Oh, yeah?
Well, maybe she doesn't like
birds that can't fly!
- (GASPS)
- Guys...
Well, you can't fly either.
And you walk funny.
- Guys!
- Oh, yeah?
Well, you can't fly either!
Guys!
Do either of you know how to get
to Atlantica? I don't have much time.
Why do you want to go to Atlantica?
I have to get something
that was stolen from a friend.
If I don't, I'll turn back into...
A what? Turn back into a what?
A human.
(GASPS)
I knew there was something
unfishy about you.
Tough break, sister. Drop us a line.
Let us know how it all turns out.
- We'll take you.
- You will?
- We will?
- She's a damsel in distress.
It's our big chance.
Whew. Hoo-boy.
I can't believe I'm doing this.
Somebody stop me.
All right, then, we're in.
On to Atlantica!
A-ha!
(SINGING) Taming the tides
Swarming the seas
Beware, barracudas
Drop to your knees
Aah!
Defending our friends and anemones
As big as a whale
Hey!
With a much smaller tail
Facing the foe with our fearless flukes
Daring the dastards
to put up their dukes
Great globs of gore
We'll storm the shore
And seek the unknown
Then can we go home?
BOTH: Titanic Tip and Daring Dash
Adventurers-slash-explorers
Titanic Tip and Daring Dash
Our gallant quest to do our best
And smile for our adorers
MELODY: We'll save the day
DASH: And make a splash
Titanic Tip and Daring Dash
We'll clobber those crabs
with their clammy claws
We'll shatter those sharks
with their savage jaws
- The battle is fierce
- And mercifully brief
The conquering heroes return
as kings of the reef
We'll dine with the best
Dressed with a flair
Climb every mountain
Because it's there
Come on, follow me
We'll make history
To courage
To us
- The trident
- Or bust
ALL: Titanic Tip and Daring Dash
Adventurers-slash-explorers
Titanic Tip and Daring Dash
- We'll save the day
- And make a splash
- Melody
- Tip and Daring Dash
ALL: All for three and three for one
Atlantica
Here we come
MELODY: I knew it! It's real!
- Atlantica.
- (MORGANA CHUCKLES)
That's right, Princess.
Just a little further.
Cloak! Dagger!
Go make sure that no one interferes
with her return. Hmm?
Have you heard anything, Daddy?
I've been searching everywhere,
but I'd... Flounder!
Daddy!
FLOUNDER: Now what?
(CHUCKLES)
- Sorry.
- Ariel?
- Flounder?
- Ariel!
Oh, I've missed you! (GIGGLES)
Boy, you're sure not a guppy any more.
(CHUCKLES) You can say that again.
- Over here!
- Throw it to me!
- Yeah!
- I want it!
Ow!
Children, what did I say
about playing Kick the Clam
on the reef?
- Sorry, Dad.
- Kids. (CHUCKLES)
I'm sorry about Melody.
Flounder, I really need your help.
Wild sea horses couldn't stop me.
GUPPY 1: Oh, boy!
GUPPY 2: Follow me!
GUPPY 3: Come on!
(SIGHS) It's so beautiful.
BOTH: Whoa!
- Sorry. My...
- Sorry. My fault.
- ...fault.
- Hi.
Uh...
I don't think I've seen you around here.
What's your name?
I'm Mel... Mel...
Hey, guys! Meet Mel-Mel.
- Hi.
- Hey, you wanna hang out with us?
All right, all right.
Break it up. Break it up!
There's nothing to see here.
Move along.
Come on, Miss Popularity.
We have a previous engagement.
Remember?
Maybe I'll catch you later.
(SIGHS) This is what happens
when you bring a country fish
to the big city.
Was that a penguin?
Wow!
DASH: Nice crib.
Come on. Follow me.
(MELODY GASPS)
That must be him.
He looks sad.
- He doesn't look like a thief.
- They never do.
Look! There it is!
A fork? We're risking our tails for a fork?
We haven't time for this.
I want every available
merman searching!
Find her!
- (RATTLING)
- Hmm.
Dash, if this is the end,
I just want you to know, pal,
I'm sorry I said that thing
about the blubber.
- Well, I'm sorry about the fish breath.
- Yeah...
- You didn't say anything about that.
- But I was thinkin' it.
(BOTH WHIMPERING)
King Triton, your daughter has returned.
- Ooh, that was close.
- Whew!
Oh, sure, that's it.
Take your time. Kick back. Relax.
Let's all just linger here and die!
I'm sure she'll turn up soon.
He's coming back!
(MELODY GASPS)
My necklace!
Ah, don't worry, Ariel. We'll find her.
Daddy! The trident!
But that's not possible.
Nobody can remove the trident
from the stand except you, sire.
You or one of your descendants.
Melody.
Who I was supposed to be watching.
Go ahead, crack me open.
Make a crab cake out of me, sire.
But how could she have gotten here?
Morgana.
If she gets her hands on my trident...
Double the search parties!
I want every creature
in the ocean on patrol!
Yes, sire!
ARIEL: Wait a minute.
I know those two.
It's all my fault.
If I had just paid a little more attention
instead of blabbering
on and on and on...
...and on and on.
From now on, Your Majesty,
nothing gets past
me.
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
We did it!
Uh-huh. Uh...
Hmm?
All this time Atlantica was never
that far away from home.
This is your home?
It used to be.
Whoa, what a pad.
Talk about your kerb appeal.
But what's with the wall?
I know good fences make good
neighbours, but isn't that a bit much?
What you tryin' to keep out?
It wasn't built to keep something out.
It was built to keep me in.
Come on. Let's go.
DASH: Whoa-ho-ho!
TIP: Whoo-hoo!
TIP: You know, kid, the three of us,
we make a pretty good team.
DASH: Once you're a permanent
mermaid, we'll be friends forever.
- We'll be inseparable.
- Nothing will ever come between us.
- Shark! Run! Run!
- Shark!
No, wait!
- It's just...
- (LAUGHS)
Leavin' so soon, boys?
What can I say?
When you got it, you got it.
Hey! You got it!
Sweetheart, you're my new hero.
Let's go. It's time for some magic.
But... But my friends...
Ha! You mean you call those two
yellow-bellied sea slugs your friends?
Come on!
You wanna be a mermaid, or what?
We got the power. We got the power.
(GRUNTING)
We got the power!
(GASPS) So there it is.
Swim back as fast as you can and tell
my father. I'll try to find Melody.
Oh, but if that old sea witch is in there,
and then there's that mean little shark,
and then those manta rays come, and
then she takes those creepy tentacles
so suction cups stick to your face, and...
(SIGHS) Uh-uh.
No way you're going in there alone.
But, Flounder, if we both go,
who's going to tell Daddy
where Morgana's lair is?
What's all the whispering about?
Is Melody around here?
- Did you find her yet? If she's...
- Scuttle!
(WHISPERS) Get down and be quiet.
Wait a minute.
Scuttle can get help.
Scuttle, I need you
to pay very close attention.
We're doomed.
Oh, there you are, darling!
Oh, I was so worried about you.
And look!
You've brought back my trident.
- Clever girl.
- Give it to her! Give it to her!
Hey!
Forgive him, dear.
He's got a little size issue.
Now, if you'll just hand over the...
- Melody, don't! Don't listen to her!
- Mom!
BOTH: You're a mermaid?
Ariel, how nice of you to come.
And you brought Flopper with you.
The name's Flounder.
Grrr!
"Grrr" yourself, pipsqueak.
Get that thing and hit me.
One bite, and he's shrimp toast.
Sweetheart, hand me my trident now.
All this time, and you never told me?
Kept the most important secret in
her whole life from her own daughter.
Please, give it to me, Melody.
No, hand it to me.
- It's for your own good.
- She's lying!
I've given you
what you've always wanted.
She's the one who lied to you
all these years.
- I was trying to protect you.
- By fencing me in?
You knew how much I loved the sea.
Why did you keep the truth from me?
Melody, listen to me. If there was one
thing in my life that I could do over...
Too late, Mom.
Melody, no!
(CACKLING)
All the power of the seven seas
at my command!
Hello! Can we get with the programme?
It's still a small world down here!
Mom!
Your mommy was only trying
to protect you from moi!
What she did, she did out of... (SNIFFS)
...love.
Little Melody's been a very naughty girl,
stealing from her own grandfather.
My grandfather?
King Triton, ruler of Atlantica,
commander in chief of all of the oceans!
Or at least he was,
until a certain little thief came along.
You tricked me.
You've got no one to blame but yourself.
Tell me, Melody.
Is being a mermaid
everything you dreamed?
Was it worth it?
(CACKLING)
(GASPS)
Oh!
- (GROANS)
- Melody!
Oh, and by the way,
your time as a mermaid
has just about expired.
Catch you later.
I've got bigger fish to fry!
Bigger fish! Now, there's an idea!
(GRUNTING)
We gotta keep trying.
It's no use. It's too thick.
(SOBBING) Oh, Flounder.
I've ruined everything.
We're guppies, man. Jellyfish.
The great Tip and Dash.
Cowards-slash-losers.
Well, at least we're alive.
Yeah, if you wanna call this living.
Okay, on the one hand,
we can live a long, healthy life,
albeit as disgusting,
pathetic, cowardly...
- Worms.
- That's good. Good.
Cowardly worms.
On the other hand, we could gather
our courage, if we had any,
and storm the fortress and be heroes.
Yeah, until they hack us up
into fish bait.
You're right.
(THUNDER CRACKING)
(DASH GASPS)
Melody's in there.
She could be in big trouble.
She may really need our help!
So what's it gonna be?
A lifetime as worms,
or two minutes as heroes?
(CRACKING CONTINUES)
All hail Queen Morgana!
I'm hailin'! I'm hailin'!
SCUTTLE: Hold on, sweetie!
The cavalry is comin'!
(GASPS)
Ariel!
Ah! Prince Eric.
Come to join the party?
We're having a blast!
Ahh!
(CREW YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
Oh, how dear Ursula
would have adored this.
Morgana!
King Triton?
Oh, please! Is that the best you can do?
Release my daughter,
surrender my granddaughter
and I shall spare you.
Ooh!
What you gonna do?
Throw the crab at me? (CACKLING)
Hmph!
(LAUGHING)
Face it, Triton. You're all washed up!
Uh-oh!
Ha-ha!
I'm gonna be teachin' you
some manners!
Oh, look at me. I'm bait!
(GASPS)
(SHRIEKS)
Oh, yeah!
Ha-ha!
Look out!
Where's Melody?
What have you done with her?
Oh, you want to join your daughter?
I think that can be arranged.
(YELLS)
(BARKS)
Eric!
(MUFFLED YELLING)
You are a very bad lady!
(SCUTTLE GRUNTING)
Very bad.
(BOTH YELLING)
(CHUCKLES)
Goin' somewhere, boys?
Uh, we're just lookin' for
the little penguin's room.
(BOTH CHUCKLE NERVOUSLY)
Well, it's been nice knowin' ya.
(YELLS)
Now, that is one brave hunk of blubber.
I'll hold him! You go find Melody!
(DASH GROANING)
Hurry!
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
What's... What's happening?
Oh, no! Oh... (GURGLING)
- I thought you were gonna hold him!
- I am holding him!
Nice fishy.
Ooh. Big fishy.
Hold on, Melody! (GRUNTS)
I'm gonna bust us out of here
if it's the last thing I
do.
Tip! Help!
Another plan perfectly executed.
FLOUNDER: Melody!
TIP: Uh-oh.
(SHRIEKS)
Ha!
(GROANING)
Fools! I have the trident now.
And all the creatures
of the sea are in my power!
(CACKLING)
I'm the queen of the sea,
and you will bow down before me!
- This can't be good for the lower back.
- Pathetic fools!
Watch and see how
utterly powerful I can be!
MELODY: Mom!
The end begins
for all of you with fins!
(CACKLING)
That's it, Triton.
Bow down!
Bow down before me!
No, Your Majesty. You mustn't.
I'm sorry, Sebastian. (GRUNTS)
I have no choice.
Oh! Wishes do come true.
See that, Ma?
Who's your favourite now?
(LAUGHING)
It's over, Triton.
I sentence you
to oblivion!
You!
Just what do you think
you're going to do with that?
Stay back!
(LAUGHS)
Wrong end, sweetheart.
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
(SHRIEKS)
MELODY: Grandfather?
I think this belongs to you.
No!
(SCREAMS)
Never again
will you or yours threaten my family.
There will be no escape for you
- ever!
- (GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERS) Mommy.
(MOANS)
- Dad?
- Oh, Melody,
I was so afraid we'd lost you.
I'm sorry, Mother.
Oh, no, sweetie. We're sorry.
We should have told you the truth.
I didn't mean to hurt anyone.
I just hoped I'd
be a better mermaid than a girl.
Oh, Melody, sweetie, it doesn't matter
if you have fins or feet.
We love you for who you are
on the inside.
Our very brave little girl.
Just like your mother.
Oh, Grandfather!
Melody, I don't blame you
for wanting to join us merfolk.
And because you're my granddaughter,
I'm giving you a most precious gift.
A choice, you can come
to Atlantica with me
or you can return to your home on land.
It's up to you.
I have a better idea.
(MELODY GIGGLING)
Now we can all be together!
Ooh!
(SINGING) I feel the music playing
It's swinging and it's swaying
Life is a rhapsody
Whoo!
Today we're so delighted
Today we're all united
Here on the land and sea
I see the sails are sailing
Even the whales are whaling
We're swimming fancy free
(GRUNTS)
We're feeling better now
We sing together now
here on the land and sea
La-dee-da
Pick up the beat
Move your fins and move your feet
Life is sweet, life is grand
Blowing bubbles
with the bass sprats band
- Everybody now!
- Come on in!
There's plenty of water for everyone!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- Look out!
- There's no more stormy weather
- Now we can sing together
In perfect harmony
We're feeling better now
We sing together now
here on the land and sea
- Those on land sing
- La dee dah doh
- Those below sing
- Lo dee doh doh
SEBASTIAN:
Life is sweet as sweet can be
On the land and on the sea
Everybody sing
Come on, Grimsby, join us.
The water's great!
I think not, sir.
The very idea seems rather absur...
SEBASTIAN: We're feeling better now
We sing together now
Here on the land and sea
Whoa!
Sorry.
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.
We're feeling better now
We sing together now
Here on the land
And sea
(MELODY GIGGLES)
WOMAN: (SINGING)
Look at this stuff, isn't it neat
Wouldn't you think
my collection's complete
Wouldn't you think I'm the girl
The girl who has everything
Look at this trove
Treasures untold
How many wonders
can one cavern hold
Looking around here you'd think
Sure, she's got everything
I've got gadgets and gizmos a-plenty
I've got who's-it's and what's-it's galore
You want thingamabobs
I've got twenty
But who cares
No big deal
I want more
I want to be where the people are
I want to see
Want to see 'em dancing
Walking around on those
What do you call 'em
Oh, feet
Flipping your fins
you don't get too far
Legs are required for jumpin', dancin'
Strollin' along down the
What's that word again
Street
Up where they walk
Up where they run
Up where they stay
all day in the sun
Wandering free
Wish I could be part of that world
What would I give if I could live
Out of these waters
What would I pay to spend a day
Warm on the sand
Betcha on land they understand
Bet they don't
reprimand their daughters
Bright young women
Sick of swimmin'
Ready to stand
And ready to know
what the people know
Ask them my questions
and get some answers
What's a fire and why does it
What's the word
Burn
When's it my turn
Wouldn't I love
Love to explore that shore up above
Out of the sea
Wish I could be
Part of that world