[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
* The hills are alive *
* With the sound of music *
* With songs they have sung *
* For a thousand years *
* The hills fill my heart *
* With the sound of music *
* My heart wants to sing *
* Every song it hears *
* My heart wants to beat *
* Like the wings of the birds *
* That rise from the lake *
* To the trees *
* My heart wants to sigh *
* Like a chime that flies *
* From a church on a breeze *
* To laugh like a brook *
* When it trips and falls *
* Over stones on its way *
* To sing through the night *
* Like a lark who is
learning to pray *
* I *
* Go to the hills *
* When my heart is lonely *
* I know I will hear *
* What I've heard before *
* My heart will be blessed *
* With the sound of music *
* And I'll sing *
* Once *
* More *
[ Church Bells Ring ]
Oh!
[ Singing In Latin ]
[ Church Bells Ring ]
* Alleluia *
* Alleluia... *
Reverend Mother.
Sister Bernice.
I simply cannot find her.
Maria?
She's missing from the Abbey again.
Perhaps we should
have put a cowbell...
around her neck.
Have you tried the barn?
You know how much
she adores the animals.
I have looked everywhere,
in all of the usual places.
Sister Bernice,
considering that it's Maria,
I suggest you look
in someplace unusual.
Well, Reverend Mother,
I hope this
new infraction...
ends whatever doubts
you may still have...
about Maria's future here.
I always try to keep faith
in my doubts, Sister Berthe.
After all, the wool
of a black sheep...
is just as warm.
We are not talking about sheep,
black or white, Sister Margaretta.
Of all the candidates
for the novitiate,
I would say Maria is
the least likely--
Children, Children!
We were speculating
about the qualifications...
of some of our postulants.
The Mistress of Novices...
and the Mistress of Postulants...
were trying to help me...
by expressing
opposite points of view.
Tell me, Sister Catherine,
what do you think of Maria?
She's a wonderful girl,
some of the time.
Sister Agatha?
It's very easy to like Maria,
except when it's difficult.
And you, Sister Sophia?
I love her very dearly,
but she always seems to be
in trouble, doesn't she?
Exactly what I say.
* She climbs a tree
and scrapes her knee *
* Her dress
has got a tear *
* She waltzes
on her way to mass *
* And whistles on the stair *
* And underneath her wimple *
* She has curlers in her hair *
* I've even heard her singing *
* In the abbey *
* She's always late for chapel *
* But her penitence is real *
* She's always late for everything *
* Except for every meal *
* I hate to have to say it *
* But I very firmly feel *
* Maria's not an asset
to the Abbey *
* I'd like to say
a word in her behalf *
Then say it, Sister Margaretta.
* Maria *
* Makes me laugh *
* How do you solve
a problem like Maria? *
* How do you catch a cloud
and pin it down? *
* How do you find a word
that means Maria? *
* A flibbertigibbet *
* A will-o'-the-wisp *
* A clown *
* Many a thing you know
you'd like to tell her *
* Many a thing
she ought to understand *
* But how do you
make her stay *
* And listen
to all you say? *
* How do you keep
a wave upon the sand? *
* Oh, how do you solve
a problem like Maria? *
* How do you
hold a moonbeam *
* In your hand? *
* When I'm with her,
I'm confused *
* Out of focus,
and bemused *
* And I never know
exactly where I am *
* Unpredictable as weather *
* She's as flighty as a feather *
* She's a darling *
* She's a demon *
* She's a lamb *
* She'd out-pester any pest *
* Drive a hornet from its nest *
* She can throw a whirling
dervish out of whirl *
* She is gentle she is wild *
* She's a riddle
She's a child *
* She's a headache *
* She's an angel *
* She's a girl *
* How do you solve a problem
like Maria? *
* How do you catch a cloud
and pin it down? *
* How do you find
a word that means Maria? *
* A flibbertigibbet *
* A will-o'-the-wisp *
* A clown *
* Many a thing you know
you'd like to tell her *
* Many a thing
she ought to understand *
* But how do
you make her stay *
* And listen to
all you say? *
* How do you keep
a wave upon the sand? *
* Oh, how do you solve
a problem like Maria? *
[ Door Slams ]
* How do you
hold a moonbeam *
* In *
* Your *
* Hand? *
You may go in now, Maria.
Come here, my child.
Now, sit down.
Oh. Oh, Reverend Mother,
I'm so sorry.
I just couldn't help myself.
The gates were open,
And the hills were beckoning,
and before I--
Dear, I haven't summoned
you here for apologies.
Oh, please, Mother, do let me
ask for forgiveness.
If it would make you
feel better.
Yes. Well, you see,
the sky was so blue today,
And everything was
so green and fragrant.
I just had to be a part of it.
And the bird kept leading me
higher and higher,
as though it wanted me...
to go right through
the clouds with it.
Child, suppose darkness
had come and you were lost?
Oh, Mother, I could never
be lost up there.
That's my mountain.
I was brought up on it.
It was the mountain
that led me to you.
Oh?
When I was a child,
I would come down the mountain...
and climb a tree and look
over into your garden.
I'd see the sisters at work,
And I'd hear them sing
on their way to vespers...
which brings me to another
transgression, Reverend Mother.
I was singing out there today
without permission.
Maria, it is only here
in the abbey...
that we have rules about
postulants singing.
I can't seem to stop
singing wherever I am.
And what's worse, I can't
seem to stop saying things--
everything and anything
I think and feel.
Some people would
call that honesty.
But it's terrible,
Reverend Mother.
You know how Sister Berthe
always makes me kiss the floor...
after we've had a disagreement?
Lately I've taken to kissing
the floor when I see her coming
just to save time.
Maria, when you saw us
over the abbey wall
and longed to be one of us,
that didn't necessarily mean
that you were prepared
for the way we live here, did it?
No, Mother, but I pray, and I try,
and I am learning. I really am.
What is the most important lesson
you have learned here, my child?
To find out what
is the will of God
and to do it
wholeheartedly.
Maria...
it seems to be the will of God
that you leave us.
- Leave you?
- Only for a while, Maria.
Oh, no, please, Don't do that.
Don't send me away.
This is where I belong.
It's my home, my family.
It's my life.
But are you truly ready for it?
Yes, I am.
Perhaps if you go
out into the world
for a time,
knowing what we
expect of you,
You will have
a chance to find out
if you could expect it
of yourself.
I know what you expect,
mother, and I can do it.
I promise I can.
Maria.
Yes, Mother...
If it is God's will.
there is a family near Salzburg
that needs a governess
until September.
September?
To take care of seven children.
Seven children!
Do you like children, Maria?
Well, yes, but seven!
I will tell Captain von Trapp
to expect you tomorrow.
Uh, Captain?
A retired officer of
the Imperial Navy.
a fine man and a brave one.
His wife died several years ago,
leaving him alone
with the children.
I understand he's had
a most difficult time
managing to keep
a governess there.
Uh, why difficult,
Reverend Mother?
The Lord will show you
in his own good time.
When The Lord closes a door,
somewhere he opens a window.
* What will this day be like? *
* I wonder *
* What will my future be? *
* It could be so exciting *
* To be out in the world *
* To be free *
* My heart should
be wildly rejoicing *
* Oh, what's
the matter with me? *
* I have always
longed for adventure *
* To do the things
I've never dared *
* Now here
I'm facing adventure *
* Then why *
* Am I so scared? *
* A Captain
with seven children *
* What's so fearsome
about that? *
* Oh, I must stop these doubts,
all these worries *
* If I don't, I just know
I'll turn back *
* I must dream
of the things I am seeking *
* I am seeking
the courage *
* I lack *
* The courage to
serve them with reliance *
* Face my mistakes
without defiance *
* Show them I'm worthy *
* And while I show them *
* I'll *
* Show *
* Me *
* So *
* Let them bring on
all their problems *
* I'll do better
than my best *
* I have confidence *
* They'll put me
to the test *
* But I'll make them see
I have confidence in me *
* Somehow
I will impress them *
* I will be
firm but kind *
* And all those children *
* Heaven bless them *
* They will look up to me
and mind me *
* With each step,
I am more certain *
* Everything
will turn out fine *
* I have confidence
the world can all be mine *
* They'll have to agree *
* I have
confidence in me *
* I have confidence
in sunshine *
in rain *
* I have confidence that
spring will come again *
* Besides which, you see *
* I have
confidence in me *
* Strength doesn't
lie in numbers *
lie in wealth *
* Strength lies in nights
of peaceful slumbers *
* When you wake up,
wake up *
* It's healthy, all I trust
I leave my heart to *
* All I trust
becomes my own *
* I have confidence
in confidence *
* Alone... *
Oh, help.
* I have confidence *
* In confidence alone *
* Besides which, you see *
* I have confidence *
* In me *
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Oh!
Hello! Here I am.
I'm from
the convent.
I'm the new
governess, Captain.
And I'm the old
butler, fraulein.
Oh. Well,
how do you do?
Hmm...
You'll, uh,
wait here, please.
[ Door Opens ]
In the future,
you'll kindly remember
there are certain rooms
in this house
which are not
to be disturbed.
Yes, Captain, sir.
And why do you stare
at me that way?
You don't look at all
like a sea captain, sir.
I'm afraid you don't look
very much like a governess.
Turn around, please.
What?
Turn.
Hat off.
It's the dress. You'll have
to put on another one
before you meet
the children.
But I don't have
another one.
When we entered
the abbey,
our worldly clothes
were given to the poor.
What about this one?
The poor didn't
want this one.
Hmm.
I would have made
myself a new dress,
but there wasn't time.
I can make
my own clothes.
Well, I'll see that you
get some material.
Today, if possible.
Now, fraulein...
Maria.
Fraulein Maria,
I don't know how much
the Mother Abbess
has told you.
Not much.
You're the 1 2th in
a long line of governesses
who have come to look
after my children
since their mother died.
I trust that you will be an
improvement on the last one.
She stayed only two hours.
What's wrong
with the children, sir?
There's nothing wrong
with the children,
only the governesses.
They were completely unable
to maintain discipline.
Without it, this house
cannot be properly run.
Will you please
remember that, fraulein?
Yes, sir.
Every morning you will drill
the children in their studies.
I will not permit them to dream
away their summer holidays.
Each afternoon they will
march about the grounds,
breathing deeply.
Bedtime is to be strictly
observed, no exceptions.
Excuse me, sir,
when do they play?
You will see to it that
they conduct themselves
at all time with the utmost
orderliness and decorum.
I'm placing you in command.
Yes, sir!
[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Running Footsteps ]
[ Blowing Whistle ]
Now, this is your new
governess, Fraulein Maria.
As I sound your signals,
You will step forward
and give your name.
You, fraulein,
will listen carefully.
Learn those signals so you can
call them when you want them.
[ Blowing Whistle ]
Liesl.
Friedrich.
Louisa.
Kurt.
Brigitta.
Marta.
[ Blows Whistle ]
And Gretl. Ahem.
Now, let's see
how well you listened.
Oh, I won't need to whistle
for them, Reverend Captain.
I mean, I'll use their names.
and such lovely names.
[ von Trapp ]
Fraulein, this is a large house.
The grounds
are very extensive,
and I will not have
anyone shouting.
Take this, please.
learn to use it.
The children
will help you.
Now, when I want you,
this is what you will hear.
[ Whistle Blows ]
No, sir. I'm sorry, sir.
I could never answer
to a whistle.
Whistles are for dogs
and cats and other animals,
but not for children,
and definitely not for me.
It would be
too humiliating.
Fraulein, were you this
much trouble at the abbey?
Oh, much more, sir.
Hmm...
[ Whistle Blows ]
Excuse me, sir.
I don't know your signal?
You may call me
Captain.
At ease.
Well, now that
there's just us,
Would you please tell me
all your names again
And how old you are?
I'm Liesl.
I'm 1 6 years old,
and I don't need
a governess.
I'm glad you told me, Liesl.
We'll just be good friends.
I'm Friedrich.
I'm 1 4. I'm impossible.
Really? Who told you
that, Friedrich?
Fraulein Josephine,
four governesses ago.
I'm Brigitta.
You, um, didn't tell me
how old you are, Louisa.
I'm Brigitta.
She's Louisa.
She's 1 3 years old,
and you're smart.
I'm 1 0, and I think
your dress
is the ugliest one
I ever saw.
Brigitta, you
shouldn't say that.
Why not? Don't you
think it's ugly?
Of course, but Fraulein
Hilda's was ugliest.
I'm Kurt. I'm 1 1 .
I'm incorrigible.
Congratulations.
What's
incorrigible?
I think it means
you want to be
treated like a boy.
Mm-hmm?
I'm Marta,
and I'm gonna be 7
on Tuesday.
And I'd like
a pink parasol.
Well, pink's my
favorite color, too.
[ Stomp, Stomp ]
Yes, you're Gretl,
and you're
five years old?
My, you're
practically a lady.
Now I have
to tell you a secret--
I've never been
a governess before.
You mean you don't
know anything
about being
a governess?
Nothing. I'll need
lots of advice.
Well, the best way
to start is to be sure
to tell father to mind
his own business.
You must never come
to dinner on time.
Never eat
soup quietly.
[ Slurp ]
And during
dessert,
always blow
your nose.
Don't you believe a word
they say, fraulein.
Why not?
- Because I like you!
- [ Clapping ]
All right, children,
outside for your walk.
Father's orders.
Now, hurry up, hurry up.
Quick, quick, quick!
Fraulein Maria,
I'm Frau Schmidt,
the housekeeper.
How do you do?
I'll show you
to your room.
Follow me.
Poor little dears.
Ah! Aah! Aah! Oh!
- Oh--
- You're very lucky.
with Fraulein Helga,
it was a snake.
Good evening.
Good evening,
children.
Fraulein Maria.
Aah!
Enchanting
little ritual.
Something you learned
at the abbey?
No, it's-- um--
um...
rheumatism.
Excuse me. Haven't we
forgotten to thank the Lord?
For what we are
about to receive,
may the Lord make us
truly thankful. Amen.
Amen.
[ Children ]
I'd like to thank each of you
for the precious gift
you left in my pocket
earlier today.
Um... what gift?
It's meant to be a secret
between the children and me.
Then I suggest that you
keep it and let us eat.
Knowing how nervous
I must have been,
a stranger
in a new household,
Knowing how important it was
for me to feel accepted,
it was so kind
and thoughtful of you
to make my first moments here
so warm, happy, and pleasant.
- What is the matter, Marta?
- Nothing.
[ Children Crying ]
Fraulein, is it
to be at every meal
or merely at dinnertime
that you intend leading
us all through this rare
and wonderful new world
of indigestion?
They're all right.
They're just happy.
[ Crying Gets Louder]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Rolfe, good evening.
Good evening, Franz.
I trust everything
is under control?
Yes. Yes.
Good.
- Are there any developments?
- Perhaps.
Is the Captain at home?
He's at dinner.
With the family?
Yes.
Please give him this
telegram at once.
Certainly.
- Telegram for you, sir.
- Mm.
Franz,
who delivered it?
That young lad
Rolfe, of course.
Father,
may I be excused?
Hmm.
Children, in the morning,
I shall be going to Vienna.
[ All ]
Not again, Father !
How long will you be
gone this time, Father?
I'm not sure, Gretl.
To visit Baroness
Schraeder again?
Mind your own business!
As a matter of fact,
yes, Louisa.
Why can't we ever get
to see the baroness?
Why would she
want to see you?
It just so happens, Marta, you
are going to see the baroness.
I'm bringing her back
with me to visit us all.
[ Children ]
Good!
And Uncle Max.
[ Children Shouting ]
Uncle Max!
Rolfe!
Oh, Rolfe.
No, Liesl,
we mustn't.
Why not, silly?
I don't know--
Isn't this why you're
here waiting for me?
Yes, of course.
I've missed you, Liesl.
You have? How much?
So much
that I even thought
of sending you
a telegram
just so I'd be able
to deliver it here.
Oh, that's a lovely thought.
Why don't you, right now?
But I'm here.
Please, Rolfe,
send me a telegram.
I'll start it for you.
Dear Liesl...
I'd like to be able to tell you
how I feel about you. Stop.
Unfortunately, this wire
is already too expensive.
Sincerely, Rolfe.
''Sincerely''?
Cordially.
''Cordially''?
Affectionately?
Mmm!
Will there be any reply?
Dear Rolfe. Stop.
Don't stop.
Your Liesl.
If only we didn't
always have to wait
for someone to send
father a telegram.
How do I know when
I'll see you again?
Well, let's see.
I could come here by mistake...
With a telegram
for Colonel Schneider.
He's here from Berlin,
staying with--
No one's supposed to
know he's here.
Don't tell your father, now.
Why not?
Well, your father's
so... so Austrian.
We're all Austrian.
Well, some people think
we ought to be German,
and they're very mad
at those who don't think so.
They're getting ready to...
Well, let's hope your father
doesn't get into trouble.
Don't worry about father.
He's a big naval hero.
He was even decorated
by the Emperor.
I know. I don't worry about him,
but I do worry
about his daughter.
Me? Why?
Well, you're so...
What?
You're such a baby!
I'm 1 6.
What's such a baby about that?
* You wait, little girl,
on an empty stage *
* For fate to turn the light on *
* Your life, little girl,
is an empty page *
* That men will want to write on *
* To write on *
* You are 1 6 going on 1 7 *
* Baby, it's time to think *
* Better beware,
be canny and careful *
* Baby, you're on the brink *
* You are 1 6 going on 1 7 *
* Fellows will fall in line *
* Eager young lads
and rouès and cads *
* Will offer you food and wine *
* Totally unprepared are you *
* To face a world of men *
* Timid and shy
and scared are you *
* Of things beyond your ken *
* You need someone
older and wiser *
* Telling you what to do *
* I am 1 7 going on 1 8 *
* I'll take care of you *
[ Thunder ]
* I am 1 6 going on 1 7 *
* I know that I'm naive *
* Fellows I meet
may tell me I'm sweet *
* And willingly, I believe *
* I am 1 6, going on 1 7 *
* Innocent as a rose *
* Bachelor dandies *
* Drinkers of brandies *
* What do I know of those? *
* Totally unprepared am I *
* To face a world of men *
* Timid and shy and scared am I *
* Of things beyond my ken *
* I need someone older and wiser *
* Telling me what to do *
* You are 1 7 going on 1 8 *
* I'll depend on you *
Wheee!
- [ Knock On Door ]
- Come in.
Frau Schmidt.
For your new dresses,
Fraulein Maria.
The Captain had these
sent out from town.
Oh, how lovely.
I'm sure these will make
the prettiest clothes
I've ever had.
Tell me,
do you think the Captain
would get me some more
material if I asked him?
How many dresses
does a governess need?
Not for me.
For the children.
I want to make them
some play clothes.
The von Trapp children don't play.
They march.
Surely, you don't approve of that.
Ever since the Captain
lost his poor wife,
he runs this house
as if he were on one
of his ships again.
Whistles, orders,
no more music, no more laughing.
Nothing that reminds him of her.
Even the children.
It's so wrong!
Oh, well... how do
you like your room?
There'll be new drapes
at the windows.
New drapes? But these are fine.
Nevertheless, new ones
have been ordered.
Oh, but I really don't need them.
Good night, now.
Frau Schmidt,
Do you think if I asked
the Captain tomorrow
about the material--
He's leaving for Vienna
in the morning.
Oh, yes, of course. Well,
how long will he be gone?
That all depends.
The last time
he visited the baroness,
- he stayed for a month.
- Oh.
I shouldn't be saying this--
Not to you, I mean,
I don't know you that well--
But if you ask me,
the Captain's thinking
very seriously
of marrying the woman
before the summer's over.
Oh, that would be wonderful!
The children will have
a mother again!
Yes. well, good night.
Good night.
Dear Father,
now I know why you've sent me here.
To help these children prepare
themselves for a new mother.
And I pray that this will become
a happy family in thy sight.
God bless the Captain.
God bless Liesl and Friedrich.
God bless Louisa, Brigitta,
Marta, and little Gretl.
And, oh, I forgot the other boy.
What's his name?
Well, God bless
what's-his-name.
God bless
the Reverend Mother
and Sister Margaretta
and everybody
at Nonnberg Abbey.
And now, dear God, about Liesl--
Help her to know
that I'm her friend.
And help her to tell me
what she's been up to.
Are you going to tell on me?
Shh. Help me to be understanding
so that I may
guide her footsteps.
In the name
of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Ghost, Amen.
I was out taking a walk,
and somebody locked the doors
earlier than usual,
and I didn't want to
wake everybody up.
So when I saw your window open--
You're not going to
tell Father, are you?
How in the world
did you climb up here?
It's how we always
got into this room
to play tricks on the governess.
Louisa can make it
with a whole jar of
spiders in her hand.
Spiders?
Oh.
Liesl, were you out
walking all by yourself?
You know, if we wash
that dress out tonight,
nobody would
notice it tomorrow.
You could put this on.
Take your dress in there.
Put it to soak in the bathtub.
Then come back here
and sit on the bed,
and we'll have a talk.
I told you today
I didn't need a governess.
Well, maybe I do.
[ Thunder ]
Gretl?
Are you scared?
[ Thunder ]
You're not frightened of
a thunderstorm, are you?
You just stay right here with me.
Where are the others?
They're asleep.
They're not scared.
[ Thunder ]
Oh, no? Look.
All right, everybody.
Up here on the bed.
Really?
Well,just this once. Come on.
All we have to do is
wait for the boys.
You won't see them.
Boys are brave.
[ Thunder ]
You boys weren't
scared, too, were you?
No. We just wanted to be
sure that you weren't.
That's very thoughtful
of you, Friedrich.
It wasn't my idea.
It was Kurt's.
Kurt! That's the one
I left out. God bless Kurt.
[ Thunder ]
Why does it do that?
Well, the lightning
says something to the thunder,
and the thunder answers back.
The lightning must be nasty.
Not really.
Then why does the thunder
get so angry?
It makes me want to cry.
[ Thunder ]
When anything bothers me
and I'm feeling unhappy,
I just try and think of nice things.
[ Children ]
What kind of things?
Oh, well, let me see. Nice things--
Daffodils!
Green meadows.
Skies full of stars...
Raindrops on roses...
and whiskers on kittens...
* Bright copper kettles *
* And warm woolen mittens *
* Brown paper packages *
* Tied up with strings *
- * These are a few
of my favorite things *
- [ Thunder ]
* Cream-colored ponies *
* And crisp apple strudels *
* Doorbells and sleigh bells *
* And schnitzel with noodles *
* Wild geese that fly *
* With the moon on their wings *
* These are a few
of my favorite things *
* Girls in white dresses *
* With blue satin sashes *
* Snowflakes that stay *
* On my nose and eyelashes *
* Silver white winters *
* That melt into springs *
* These are a few
of my favorite things *
* When the dog bites *
* When the bee stings *
* When I'm feeling sad *
* I simply remember
my favorite things *
* And then I don't feel *
* So bad *
Does it really work?
Of course it does. You try it.
What things do you like?
Pussy willows.
Christmas!
Bunny rabbits!
Snakes!
Chocolate icing!
No school!
Pillow fights!
Telegrams!
Birthday presents!
Any presents!
Ladybugs!
A good sneeze!
[ Ah-choo ]
Gesundheit!
See what fun it is?
* Raindrops on roses *
* And whiskers on kittens *
* Bright copper kettles *
* And warm woolen mittens *
* Brown paper packages *
* Tied up with strings *
* These are a few
of my favorite things *
* Cream-colored ponies *
* And crisp apple strudels *
* Doorbells and sleigh bells *
* And schnitzel with noodles *
* Wild geese that fly *
* With the moon on their wings *
* These are a few
of my favorite things *
Oh! Together!
* Girls in white dresses *
* With blue satin sashes *
* Snowflakes that stay *
* On my nose and eyelashes *
* Silver white winters *
* That melt into springs *
* These are a few
of my favorite things *
* When the dog bites-- *
Dog bites--
Hello.
Fraulein, did I not tell you
that bedtime is to be strictly
observed in this household?
The children were
upset by the storm.
I thought--
You did, sir.
And do you or do you not
have difficulty
remembering such
simple instructions?
Only during thunderstorms, sir.
[ Giggles ]
- Liesl?
- Yes, Father?
I don't recall seeing you
anywhere after dinner.
Oh, really?
Well, as a matter of fact--
Yes?
Well, I--I was--
What she would like to
say is that she and I
have been getting better
acquainted tonight.
But it's too late now
to go into all that.
Come along, children,
you heard your father.
Go back to bed immediately.
Fraulein, you have
managed to remember
that I'm leaving in the morning?
Is it also possible
that you remember
that the first rule
in this house is discipline?
Then I trust that before I return,
you will have acquired some?
Captain.
I wonder if, before you go,
I could talk to you
about some clothes
for the children,
for when they play.
If I could just have
some material--
You are obviously many things,
not the least of which
is repetitious.
But they're children!
Yes--
And I'm their father.
Good night.
[ Door Slams ]
Oh!
[ Thunder ]
* Girls in white dresses *
* With blue satin sashes *
* When the dog bites *
* When the bee stings *
* When I'm feeling sad *
* I simply remember
my favorite things *
* And then I don't feel *
* So bad *
- [ Children Giggling ]
- [ Girl ] Where are we going?
Look over here.
Oh, look!
Come on!
Ho!
Fraulein Maria,
can we do this every day?
Don't you think you'd soon
get tired of it, Louisa?
I suppose so. Every other day?
I haven't had so much fun
since the day we put glue on
Fraulein Josephine's toothbrush.
I can't understand how
children as nice as you
can manage to play such
awful tricks on people.
- Oh, it's easy.
- But why do it ?
- How else can we get
Father's attention?
- Yes.
Oh, I see.
Well, we'll have to
think about that one.
All right, everybody! Over here!
What are we going to do?
Let's think of something
to sing for the baroness.
Father doesn't like us to sing.
Well, perhaps we can
change his mind.
Now, what songs do you know?
We don't know any songs.
Not any?
We don't even know how to sing.
Well, let's not lose any time.
You must learn.
But how?
* Let's start
at the very beginning *
* A very good place to start *
* When you read you begin with *
* A-B-C *
* When you sing you begin with *
* Do re mi *
- * Do re mi *
* The first three notes
just happen to be *
* Do re mi *
- * Do re mi *
* Do re mi
Fa so la ti *
Oh, let's see if I can
make it easier. Mmm...
* Doe, a deer *
* A female deer *
* Ray, a drop of golden sun *
* Me, a name I call myself *
* Far, a long, long way to run *
* Sew, a needle pulling thread *
* La, a note to follow sew *
* Tea, a drink with jam and bread *
* That will bring us back to do *
* Oh, oh, oh *
* Doe *
* A deer, a female deer *
* Ray *
* A drop of golden sun *
* Me *
* A name I call myself *
* Far *
* A long, long way to run *
* Sew, a needle pulling thread *
* La, a note to follow sew *
* Tea *
* A drink with jam and bread *
* That will bring us back to *
* Doe, a deer, a female deer *
* Ray, a drop of golden sun *
* Me, a name I call myself *
* Far, a long, long way to run *
* Sew, a needle pulling thread *
* La, a note to follow sew *
* Tea, a drink with jam and bread *
* That will bring us back to do *
* Do re mi fa so la ti do *
* So do *
Now, children, do re mi fa so
and so on
are only the tools we use
to build a song.
Once you have these notes
in your heads,
you can sing a million
different tunes
by mixing them up.
Like this--
Uh...
* So do la fa mi do re *
Can you do that?
* So do la ti do re do *
Now put it all together.
* So do la fa mi do re *
* So do la ti do re do *
Good!
But it doesn't mean anything.
So we put in words,
one word for every note.
Like this--
* When you know
the notes to sing *
* You can sing most anything *
Together!
* When you know
the notes to sing *
* You can sing most anything *
* Doe *
* A deer, a female deer *
* Ray *
* A drop of golden sun *
* Me *
* A name I call myself *
* Far *
* A long, long way to run *
* Sew *
* A needle pulling thread *
* La *
* A note to follow sew *
* Tea *
* A drink with jam and bread *
* That will bring us
back to do *
* Do re mi fa so la ti *
* Do do *
* Ti la so fa mi re *
* Do mi-mi *
* Mi so-so *
* Re fa-fa *
* La ti-ti *
* Do mi-mi, mi so-so *
* Re fa-fa, la ti-ti *
* When you know
the notes to sing *
* You can sing most anything *
* Doe, a deer *
* A female deer *
* Ray, a drop of golden sun *
* Me, a name I call myself *
* Far, a long, long way to run *
* Sew, a needle pulling thread *
* La, a note to follow sew *
* Tea, a drink with jam and bread *
* That will bring us back to *
* So do la fa mi do re *
* So do la fa *
* Ti la so *
* Mi fa *
* Ti re *
* Ti do *
* So do *
The mountains are
magnificent, Georg,
really magnificent.
I had them put up
just for you, darling.
Oh. [ Laughs ]
Even if it's to a height
of 1 0,000 feet,
Georg always believes
in rising to the occasion.
Unless the jokes improve, Max,
I'm taking back my invitation.
You didn't invite me
to your villa.
I invited myself.
Naturally.
You needed a chaperon,
and I needed
a place to stay
where the cuisine is superb,
the wine cellar unexcelled,
and the price... perfect.
Max, you are outrageous!
Not at all.
I'm a very charming sponge.
Hmm.
- Listen.
- [ Men Singing ]
It's the Kloppman
Monastery choir.
They're good.
Very good.
I must explore this territory
in the next few days.
Somewhere a hungry
little singing group
is waiting for Max Detweiler
to pluck it out of obscurity
and make it famous
at the Salzburg Folk Festival.
They get the fame.
You get the money.
'Tis unfair, I admit it.
But someday that'll be changed.
I shall get the fame, too.
[ Laughs ]
[ Laughing And Screaming ]
[ Baroness ]
Good heavens, what's this?
Oh, it's nothing.
Just some local urchins.
[ Sighs ]
This really is exciting
for me, Georg,
being here with you.
Ho ho ho.
Trees, lakes, mountains...
when you've seen one,
you've seen them all.
That is not what I mean,
and you know it.
Ah, you mean me. I'm exciting?
Is that so impossible?
No,just, uh, highly improbable.
There you go, running
yourself down again.
Well, I'm a dangerous driver.
[ Laughs ]
You know, you're
much less of a riddle
when I see you here, Georg.
In my natural habitat?
Yes, exactly.
Are you trying to say
that I'm more at home here
among the birds and the flowers
and the wind that moves
through the trees
like a restless sea, hmm?
How poetic.
Yes, it was, rather, wasn't it?
More at home here than in Vienna
in all your glittering salons,
gossiping gaily
with bores I detest,
soaking myself
in champagne,
stumbling about to
waltzes by Strausses
I can't even remember.
Is that what you're trying to say?
More or less, yes.
Now, what ever gave you that idea?
Oh, I do like it here, Georg.
It's so lovely and peaceful.
How can you leave it
as often as you do?
Oh, pretending to be
madly active, I suppose.
Activity suggests a life
filled with purpose.
Could it be running
away from memories?
Mm-hmm.
Or perhaps just searching
for a reason to stay.
Oh, I hope that's why you've
been coming to Vienna so often.
Or were there other
distractions there?
Oh, I'd hardly call you
a mere distraction, darling.
Well, what would you
call me, Georg?
Hmm. Lovely.
Charming, witty, graceful.
The perfect hostess.
And--you're gonna
hate me for this--
in a way, my savior.
Oh, how unromantic.
Well, I would be
an ungrateful wretch
if I didn't tell you at least once
that is was you
who brought some meaning
back into my life.
Oh, I am amusing, I suppose.
And I do have the finest
couturier in Vienna
and the most glittering
circle of friends.
- And I do give some
rather gay parties.
- Ho, ho, ho. Yes.
But take all that away,
and you have just wealthy,
unattached, little me--
- Searching just like you.
- [ Chuckles ]
More strudel, Herr Detweiler?
How many have I had?
Two.
Make it an uneven three.
Still eating, Max, hmm?
Must be unhappy.
That marvelous mixed quartet
I've been trying for
months to steal away
from Saul Hurok--
What happened, darling?
Yesterday, Sasha Petrie
stole them first.
If there's one thing
I hate, it's a thief.
Max, you really must try
and learn to love yourself.
For this, I had to call
Paris, Rome, and Stockholm.
On Georg's telephone,
of course?
Well, how else could I afford it?
Oh, dear, I like rich people.
I like the way they live.
I like the way I live
when I'm with them.
I wonder where the children are.
Obviously they must have
heard I was coming
and went into hiding.
I was hoping they'd
be here to welcome you.
Uh, Max, do step out of
character for a moment,
and try and be charming.
Well?
Well, what?
Have you made up
Georg's mind yet?
Do I hear wedding bells?
Pealing madly...
but not necessarily for me.
What kind of talk's that?
That is
none-of-your-business talk, Max.
I'm terribly fond of Georg,
and I will not have you
toying with us.
But I'm a child. I like toys,
so tell me everything.
Oh, come on, tell Max
every teensy weensy,
intimate, disgusting detail.
Well, let's just say
I have a feeling
I may be here on approval.
Well, I approve of that.
how can you miss?
Far too easily.
If I know you, darling,
and I do, you will find a way.
Oh, he's no ordinary man.
He's rich.
When his wife died,
she left him with
a terrible heartache.
And when your husband died,
he left you
with a terrible fortune.
Oh, Max, you really are a beast.
You and Georg are
like family to me.
That's why I want to see
you two get married.
We must keep all that lovely
money in the family.
What are you doing there?
Captain von Trapp!
I was just looking for--
I didn't see--
I mean, I didn't know you were--
Heil Hitler!
Who are you?
I have a telegram
for Herr Detweiler.
I'm Herr Detweiler.
Yes, sir.
All right, you've delivered
your telegram. Now get out.
Oh, Georg, he's just a boy.
Yes, and I'm just an Austrian.
What's gonna happen's
going to happen.
Just make sure
it doesn't happen to you.
Max, don't you ever
say that again!
You know I have
no political convictions.
Can I help it if other people do?
Oh, yes, you can help it!
You must help it.
Hello.
You're far away.
Where are you?
In a world that's
disappearing, I'm afraid.
- Is there any way
I could bring you back
- [ Children Chattering ]
to the world I'm in?
[ Chattering, Screaming ]
* Sew, a needle pulling thread *
*La, a note to follow sew *
* Tea, a drink with jam and bread *
* That will bring us back to do *
* Oh, oh, oh *
* Doe, a deer *
*A female deer *
[ Together]
Papa!
Oh, Captain.
You're home.
Come out
of that water at once!
Oh. You must be
Baroness Schraeder.
Oh, I'm soaked to the skin!
[ Blows Whistle ]
Straight line!
This is Baroness Schraeder.
And these...
are my children.
How do you do?
All right, go inside.
Dry off. Clean up.
Change your clothes.
report back here.
Immediately!
Fraulein, you will
stay here, please.
I, uh, ahem,
I think I'd better go
see what Max is up to.
Now, fraulein...
I want a truthful answer from you.
Yes, Captain?
Is it possible--
or could I have just imagined it--
Have my children, by any chance,
been climbing trees today?
Yes, Captain.
I see.
And where, may I ask,
did they get these--
Play clothes.
Is that what you call them?
I made them
from the drapes that used
to hang in my bedroom.
Drapes?
They still had
plenty of wear left.
The children have been
everywhere in them.
Do you mean to tell me
that my children
have been roaming about Salzburg
dressed up in nothing
but some old drapes?
Mm-hmm, and having
a marvelous time.
They have uniforms.
Straitjackets, if you'll forgive me.
I will not forgive you for that.
Children cannot do everything
they're supposed to do
if they have to worry about
their precious clothes.
They haven't complained yet.
Well, they wouldn't dare.
They love you too much.
They fear you too much.
I don't wish you to discuss
my children in this manner.
You've got to hear from someone.
You're never home long enough--
I said I don't want to
hear any more from you
- about my children.
- I know you don't,
but you've got to !
Now, take Liesl--
You'll not say one word
about Liesl, fraulein.
You're gonna wake up
and find she's a woman.
You won't even know her.
Friedrich, he's a boy, but he
wants to be a man like you,
and there's no one to show him how.
Don't you dare tell me
about my son.
Brigitta could tell you
about him,
if you'd let her get close
to you. She notices everything.
- And Kurt pretends he's tough
not to show how hurt he is
- Fraulein--
- when you brush him aside
the way you do all of them.
- That will do.
Louisa, I don't know about.
I said that will do!
And the little ones
just want to be loved.
Oh, please, Captain,
Love them, love them all.
I don't care to hear
anything further from you.
I am not finished yet, Captain!
Oh, yes, you are, Captain--
Fraulein.
Now, you will pack
your things this minute
and return to the abbey.
* The hills are alive *
* With the sound of music *
What's that?
It's singing.
Yes, I realize it's singing,
but who is singing?
The children.
*...For a thousand years *
The children?
I taught them something
to sing for the baroness.
*My heart wants to sing *
*Every song *
*It hears *
*Every song that it hears *
*My heart wants to beat *
* Like the wings
of the birds that rise *
* From the lake
to the trees *
* To the trees *
*My heart wants to sigh *
*Like a chime that flies *
* From a church on a breeze *
* To laugh like a brook *
- ** [ Humming ]
- * When it trips and falls *
* Over stones on its way *
* On its way *
- ** [ Singing Along ]
- * To sing through the night *
*Like a lark who
is learning to pray *
- * I go to the hills *
- [ Children Stop Singing ]
* When my heart is lonely *
*I know I will hear *
* What I've heard before *
- * My heart will be blessed *
- ** [ Children Harmonizing ]
* With the sound
of music *
* And I'll *
[ With Children ]
* Sing *
* Once *
* More **
Edelweiss.
You never told me how enchanting
your children are.
Don't go away.
Fraulein.
I...
behaved badly.
I apologize.
I'm far too outspoken.
It's one of my worst faults.
You were right.
I don't know my children.
There's still time, Captain.
They want so much
to be close to you.
You brought music
back into the house.
I'd forgotten.
Fraulein.
I want you to stay.
I ask you to stay.
If I could be of any help--
You have already.
More than you know.
Marta... curtain!
[ Maria ]
* High on a hill
was a lonely goatherd *
* Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o *
* Loud was the voice
of the lonely goatherd *
* Layee-o-dl
layee-o-dl-o *
* Folks in a town that
was quite remote heard *
* Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o *
* Lusty and clear *
* From the goatherd's throat heard *
* Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-o *
[ Children ]
* O-ho laydee-o-dl-ee-o *
* O-ho laydee-o-dl-ay *
* Laydee-o-dl-ee o-lay *
Marta!
Gretl, the prince!
[ Maria ]
* A prince on the bridge
of a castle moat heard *
* Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o *
[ Children ]
* Men on a road with
a load to tote heard *
* Layee-o-dl layee o-dl-oo *
* Men in the midst
of a table d'hote heard *
* Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o *
* Men drinking beer
with a foam afloat heard *
* Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-oo *
[ Maria ]
* One little girl in
a pale pink coat heard *
*Layee-o-dl
layee-o-dl lay-ee-o *
* She yodeled back
to the lonely goatherd *
*Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-oo *
[ Maria ]
*Soon her mama with
a gleaming gloat heard *
*Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl lay-ee-o *
* What a duet
for a girl and goatherd *
*Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-oo *
* Mm-hmm-hmm-hmm *
* Ho-dl-ay-ee *
* O-dl-ay-ee-ee *
* O-dl-ay-ee *
* Oh-oh-oh-oh *
* Laydee-o-dl-ay-o *
* Laydee-o-dl-ee *
* Laydee-o-dl-ay *
* Oh-oh-oh-oh *
* Laydee-o-dl-ay-o *
* Laydee-o-dl-ee o-lay *
* One little girl in
a pale pink coat heard *
* Laydee-o-dl
laydee-o-dl-ay-woo-woo *
* She yodeled back
to the lonely goatherd *
* Laydee-o-dl laydee-o-dl-oo *
* Soon her mama with
a gleaming gloat heard *
* Laydee-o-dl
laydee-o-dl-ay-mm-hmm *
* What a duet
for a girl and goatherd *
* Layee-o-dl layee-o-dl-oo *
* Happy are they *
* Laydee-o laydee-lee-o *
* O-laydee-o laydee-lay-dee-o *
* Soon their duet
will become a trio *
* Laydee-o-dl laydee-o-dl-oo *
* O-dl-ay-ee *
* O-dl-ay-ee-ee *
* O-dl-ay-dee o-dl-ay *
* O-dl-ay-dee o-dl-ee *
* O-dl-lay-dee-o-dl
lay-dee-o-dl-ay *
- Whew !
- [ Laughing ]
Bravo!
Very good!
Wonderful.
Can we really keep the
puppet show, Uncle Max?
Of course you may, my darlings.
Why else would
I have had the bill
sent to your father?
Can we really keep them?
Well done, fraulein.
I really am very,
very much impressed.
They're your
children, Captain.
My dear, is there
anything you can't do?
Well, I'm not sure
I'll make a very good nun.
If you have problems,
I'd be happy to help you.
Attention!
Attention, everyone.
I have an announcement to make.
Surprise, surprise.
Today, after a long
and desperate search,
I have finally found
a most exciting entry
for the Salzburg Folk Festival.
Congratulations, Max.
Who will you be
exploiting this time?
Ha-ha!
The Saint Ignatius Choir?
Guess again.
Uh..
Let me see...
The Kloppman Choir?
No, no, no.
- No, no?
- No, no.
Tell us.
A singing group
all in one family.
You'll never
guess, Georg.
What a charming idea.
Uh, whose family?
Yours.
They'll be the talk
of the festival.
What's so funny?
You are, Max.
You're expensive,
but very funny.
But you heard them.
They'll be a sensation!
No, Max.
It's a wonderful idea.
Fresh, original.
Max, my children
do not sing in public.
Well, you can't blame me
for trying.
Children, who shall
we hear from next?
Who?
Yes.
[ Clears Throat ]
The vote is unanimous.
You, Captain.
Me?
I don't understand.
Please.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no.
I'm told that a long time ago
you were quite good.
Well, that was a very, very,
very long time ago.
I remember, Father.
Play us something
we know. Please.
Well--
Why didn't
you tell me?
What?
To bring along my harmonica.
* Edelweiss *
* Every morning *
* You greet me *
* Small and white *
* Clean and bright *
* You look happy *
* To meet me *
*Blossom of snow *
*May you
bloom and grow *
* Bloom and grow *
* Forever *
* Edelweiss *
* Bless my homeland *
* Forever **
* Edelweiss *
[ Together ]
* Every morning *
* You greet me *
* Small and white *
* Clean and bright *
[ Together ]
* You look happy *
* To meet me *
* Blossom of snow *
* May you bloom and grow *
* Bloom and grow *
* Forever *
* Edelweiss *
* Bless my homeland *
* Forever **
Anytime you say
the word, Georg,
You can be part of my new act--
[ Chuckles ]
The von Trapp Family Singers.
I have a wonderful idea, Georg.
Let's really fill
this house with music.
You must give a grand
and glorious party for me
while I'm here.
A party?
[ Children Together]
Please, Father! Please!
I think it's high time
I met all your friends
here in Salzburg
and they met me.
Don't you agree?
I see what you mean.
[ Children ]
Oh, please, father!
Children, it's time
to go to bed.
Come, now, say good night.
Good night, Father.
Good night.
Good night, Baroness.
Good night, Father.
Good night.
It'll be my first party, Father!
Hello, Herr Zeller.
Baroness Schraeder.
Good evening, Herr Zeller.
Baroness.
How do you do? Good evening.
I suppose you noticed
the obvious display
of the Austrian flag
in the hallway?
The women look so beautiful.
I think they look ugly.
You just say that
because you're scared of them.
Silly, only grown-up men
are scared of women.
I think the men look beautiful.
How would you know?
Liesl, who are you dancing with?
Nobody.
Oh, yes, you are.
May I have this dance?
I'd be delighted, young man.
Why didn't you children
tell me you could dance?
We were afraid you'd
make us dance together.
The von Trapp family dancers.
What's that they're playing?
It's the Laendler.
It's an Austrian folk dance.
Show me.
Oh, Kurt, I haven't danced that
since I was a little girl.
Oh, you remember. Please?
Well...
Please.
All right. Come on over here.
Now you bow, and I curtsy.
Like this?
Fine. Now we go for
a little walk. This way.
1 , 2, 3,
1, 2, 3,
Step together.
Now, step, hop.
step, hop.
Now, turn under.
Not quite.
this way.
Hop, step, hop,
and under--
Kurt, we'll have to practice.
Um, do allow me, will you?
Mm-hmm.
I don't remember any more.
Your face is all red.
Is it?
I don't suppose
I'm used to dancing.
[ Applause ]
That was beautifully done.
What a lovely couple you make.
Yes. It's time the children
said good night.
Yes, we'll be in the hall
in a moment.
We've got something
very special prepared.
- Right?
- Right.
Come on!
All that needless
worrying, Georg.
You thought you wouldn't
find a friend at the party.
A bit chilly out
tonight, isn't it?
Oh, I don't know.
It seemed rather warm to me.
[ Whistling Through Teeth ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
the children of Captain von Trapp
wish to say good night to you.
* There's a sad sort of clanging *
* From the clock in the hall *
* And the bells
in the steeple, too *
* And up in the nursery,
an absurd little bird *
* Is popping out to say cuckoo *
- * Cuckoo, cuckoo *
*Regretfully they tell us *
* But firmly they compel us *
* To say good-bye *
- * Cuckoo *
* To you *
* So long, farewell *
* Auf wiedersehen, good night *
* I hate to go *
* And leave this pretty sight *
* So long, farewell *
* Auf wiedersehen, adieu *
* Adieu, adieu *
* To you and you and you *
* So long, farewell *
* Au revoir, auf wiedersehen *
* I'd like to stay *
* And taste my first champagne *
Yes?
No.
[ Laughing ]
*So long, farewell *
* Auf wiedersehen, good-bye *
* I leave and heave *
* A sigh and say good-bye *
* Good-bye *
* I'm glad *
* To go *
* I cannot tell a lie *
* I flit *
* I float *
* I fleetly flee *
* I fly *
* The sun *
* Has gone *
* To bed *
* And so must I *
*So long *
*Farewell *
* Auf wiedersehen *
* Good-bye *
They're extraordinary.
What they would do
at the festival!
Oh, young lady, I must
have words with you.
Georg, you're not going
to let this girl get away.
She has to join the party.
No, really, I--
Shh. Stop it.
Georg, please.
You can if you
want to, fraulein.
I insist. You will be
my dinner partner.
This is business.
Franz, set another place
next to mine for Fraulein Maria.
Why...whatever you say,
Herr Detweiler.
Well, it appears
to be all arranged.
It certainly does.
I'm not
suitably dressed.
Uh, well, you can change.
We'll wait for you.
Captain, you must be
very proud of your youngsters.
I am.
Thank you, baroness.
Is there a more
beautiful expression
of what is good
in this country of ours
than the innocent voices
of our children?
Oh, come, now, baron,
would you have us believe
that Austria alone holds
a monopoly on virtue?
Herr Zeller,
some of us prefer
Austrian voices
raised in song
to ugly German threats.
The ostrich buries
his head in the sand
and sometimes... in the flag.
Perhaps those
who would warn you
that the Anschluss is coming--
And it is coming, Captain--
Perhaps they would
get further with you
by setting their words to music.
If the Nazis take over Austria,
I have no doubt
that you will be
the entire trumpet section.
You flatter me, Captain.
Oh, how clumsy of me.
I meant to accuse you.
It's very kind of you to
offer to help me, baroness.
I'm delighted, Maria.
I really don't think
I do have anything
that would be appropriate.
Now, where is that
lovely little thing
you were wearing
the other evening
when the Captain couldn't
keep his eyes off you?
Couldn't keep his eyes off me?
Come, my dear, we are women.
Let's not pretend we don't know
when a man notices us.
Here we are.
The Captain notices
everybody and everything.
There's no need to feel
so defensive, Maria.
You are quite attractive, you know.
The Captain would hardly be a man
if he didn't notice you.
Baroness, I hope you're joking.
Not at all.
But I've never done a thing to--
But you don't have to, my dear.
There's nothing more
irresistible to a man
than a woman
who's in love with him.
In love with him?
Of course.
But what makes it so nice
is he thinks
he's in love with you.
But that's not true.
Surely you've noticed the way
he looks into your eyes.
And, you know, uh...
you blushed in his arms
when you were dancing just now.
Don't take it to heart.
He'll get over it soon enough,
I should think.
Men do, you know.
Then I should go.
I mustn't stay here.
Is there something
I can do to help?
No, nothing.
Yes.
Please don't say a word
about this to the Captain.
No. no,
I wouldn't dream of it.
Good-bye, Maria.
I'm sure you'll make
a very fine nun.
Champagne, darling.
I feel
like celebrating.
Cheers.
You know something?
Perhaps.
Then if you're so clever,
tell me how to get
our little fraulein
to use her influence
with Georg.
I want those children
in the festival.
Elsa, this is important
to Austria.
It wouldn't do you
any harm, either.
I've thought of that.
Well, if it's a matter
of influence,
maybe the one you have
to be talking to is me.
**
- Two.
- Three.
Four.
- Five.
- Six.
- Seven.
- Eight.
- [ Grunts ]
- Four.
- Two.
- Seven.
- Five.
- Two !
- Six.
- [ Groans ]
[ Nervous Chuckle ]
Isn't this fun?
Um--
Four.
I'm number five.
Oh, yes.
Eight.
Two.
Four.
Six !
Ohh!
Two.
Baroness Schraeder,
do you mind if we stop now?
We're tired.
Oh, whatever
you want, dear.
We'll do it
again tomorrow.
The country's
so restful, isn't it?
Have some lemonade.
Oh, there must be
an easier way.
I get a fiendish delight
thinking of you
as the mother of seven.
How do you plan to do it?
Darling, haven't you
ever heard
of a delightful
little thing
called
boarding school?
Baroness Machiavelli.
Mm-hmm.
Uncle Max,
where's father?
I think
he's in the house.
What's the matter
with all you gloomy pusses?
Nothing.
I know what we'll do.
Let's have a rehearsal.
What for?
Let's make believe we're
standing on the stage
at the festival.
I don't feel
like singing.
Not without
Fraulein Maria.
Liesl, get the guitar.
Come on, Marta.
Everybody into the group.
You know your places.
Get in your places.
That's right.
Be cheerful.
Give us the key, Liesl.
Now, impress me.
* Ah *
Friedrich, Gretl,
why don't you sing?
I can't. I've got
a sore finger.
But you sang
so beautifully
the night
of the party.
Come on, all of you.
Try something you know.
Enjoy it. Be cheerful.
All right, Liesl.
* The hills are alive *
* With the sound of music *
*Ah ah ah ah *
* With songs they have sung *
* For a thousand years *
*Ah ah ah ah *
* The hills fill my heart *
* Ah ah ah ah *
* With the sound of music *
*Ah ah ah ah...*
They just wanted
to sing for me,
Bless their hearts.
That's lovely, lovely.
Don't stop.
Hmm?
Uh, something long
and cool, Georg?
No, thank you,
darling.
Father?
Yes, Brigitta?
Is it true
Fraulein Maria
isn't coming back?
Fraulein Maria? Yes,
I suppose it's true.
What have we got here?
Pink lemonade.
Laced with...
lemonade.
Ooh.
I don't believe
it, Father.
Hmm? Don't believe
what, darling?
About
Fraulein Maria.
Oh, Fraulein Maria!
Didn't I tell you
what her note said?
Oh, I'm sure I did.
She said she missed
her life at the abbey
too much.
She had to leave us.
and that's all
there is to it.
I think I'm brave enough
to try some of that.
She didn't even
say good-bye.
She did in her note.
That isn't
the same thing.
Not too sweet,
not too sour.
Just too, uh...
pink.
Father, who is our new
governess going to be?
Well...
You're not going to have
a governess anymore.
[ All ]
We're Not?
No.
You're going to have
a new mother.
A new mother?
We talked about it
last night.
It's all settled,
and we're all going
to be very happy.
Hmm?
Well, all right,
all right, all right.
Now, run off and play.
[ Ring, Ring ]
Yes, my children?
Uh, my name is Liesl.
Yes, Liesl.
We--my brothers
and sisters--
we want to see
Fraulein Maria.
Fraulein Maria?
Oh, Maria!
Come in, please.
Wait here.
I'm Sister Margaretta.
I understand you've been
inquiring about Maria.
We have to see her. Will you
tell her we're here, please?
I'm afraid
I can't do that.
Oh, but you've got to.
We have to see her.
She's
our governess.
We want her back!
She didn't even
say good-bye.
It's very important.
All we want to do
is talk to her.
I'm very sorry, children,
but Maria is in seclusion.
She hasn't
been seeing anyone.
She'll see us.
I know she will.
I want to show her
my finger.
Oh, some other time, dear.
I'll tell her
that you were here.
It was sweet of you
to call.
Please!
Run along, children.
Run along home.
Sister Margaretta!
- Please!
Good-bye, children.
What was that about,
Sister Margaretta?
The von Trapp children,
Reverend Mother.
They want
to see Maria.
Has she spoken yet?
Has she told you
anything?
She doesn't say a word,
Reverend Mother.
except in prayer.
Poor child.
It's strange.
She seems happy
to be back here,
And yet... and yet
she's unhappy, too.
Perhaps I have
been wrong
in leaving her alone
so long.
I think you'd better
bring her to me,
even if she's
not yet ready.
Yes,
Reverend Mother.
Sister Augusta,
take our new postulant
to the robing room.
God bless you,
my daughter.
[ Knock On Door]
Ave!
Yes, bring her in.
You've been unhappy.
I'm sorry.
Reverend Mother.
Why did they send you
back to us?
They didn't
send me back, Mother.
I left.
Sit down, Maria.
Tell me
what happened.
Well, I...
I was frightened.
Frightened?
Were they unkind
to you?
Oh, no.
No, I was-- I was confused.
I--I felt...
I've never felt
that way before.
I couldn't stay.
I knew that here I'd be
away from it. I'd be safe.
Maria, our abbey
is not to be used
as an escape.
What is it
you can't face?
I can't
face him again.
Him?
Thank you,
Sister Margaretta.
Captain von Trapp?
Are you
in love with him?
I don't know!
I don't know, I...
the baroness said I was.
She... she said that
he was in love with me,
but I didn't want
to believe it.
Oh, there were times when
we would look at each other--
Oh, mother,
I could hardly breathe.
Did you let him see
how you felt?
If I did,
I didn't know it.
That's what's been
torturing me.
I was there on
God's errand.
To have asked for his love
would have been wrong.
I couldn't stay.
I just couldn't!
I'm ready at this moment
to take my vows.
Please help me.
Maria,
The love of a man and
a woman is holy, too.
You have a great
capacity to love.
What you must find out
is how God wants you
to spend your love.
But I've pledged
my life to God.
I've pledged my life
to his service.
My daughter,
if you love this man,
it doesn't mean
you love God less.
No.
You must find out.
You must go back.
Oh, Mother, you can't
ask me to do that.
Please let me stay.
I beg of you.
Maria, these walls
were not built
to shut out problems.
You have to face them.
You have to live the life
you were born to live.
* Climb every mountain *
*Search high and low *
* Follow every byway *
* Every path you know *
* Climb every mountain *
* Ford every stream *
* Follow every rainbow *
* Till you find your dream *
*A dream that will need *
*All the love you can give *
* Every day
of your life *
* For as long
as you live *
* Climb every mountain *
* Ford every stream *
* Follow every rainbow *
* Till you
find your dream *
* A dream
that will need *
* All the love
you can give *
* Every day of your life *
* For as long
as you live *
* Climb every mountain *
* Ford every stream *
*Follow every rainbow *
* Till you
find your dream **
Now, it's not like
my children
to be secretive.
We're not being
secretive, Father.
Mm-hmm. And it's not
like my children
to be late
for dinner.
We lost track
of the time.
- Yes!
All right, now
who's going to be
the first one to
tell me the truth?
Friedrich?
Brigitta? Liesl?
Where do you think
we were, Father?
Hmm? Now--
Well, if you
don't believe us,
you must have some idea
where you think we were.
[ Giggling ]
- Aha! Marta!
- Yes, Father.
You tell me.
Friedrich told you, Father.
We were berry picking.
I forgot. You were
berry picking!
- Yeah!
All afternoon?
We picked
thousands of them.
Thousands?
I got the most.
What kind
of berries?
Uh, blueberries,
sir.
Blueberries!
Mmm!
Yes!
Yes, of course!
It's, uh, too early
for blueberries.
They were strawberries.
Strawberries?
It's been so cold lately,
they turned blue.
Aw! Tsk! Tsk!
Tsk! Tsk! Tsk!
Very well.
Show me the berries.
Um, well--
Show me the berries
you picked. Come on.
We don't have them
anymore.
You don't have them
anymore?
Well, what happened
to them?
We-- We--
We ate them!
You ate them?
Yes!
They were delicious!
Very well.
Since you've obviously
stuffed yourselves
full of thousands
of delicious berries,
you can't be hungry
anymore,
so I'll just have to
simply tell Frau Schmidt
to, uh,
skip your dinner.
It's all your fault!
We should have
told him the truth.
And made him
boiling mad at us?
It's better than
starving to death.
We didn't do
anything wrong.
We just wanted
to see her.
My stomach's
making noises.
The least they
could have done
was to let us
say hello.
I wonder what
grass tastes like.
I feel awful.
When Fraulein Maria
wanted to feel better,
She used to sing
that song, remember?
Let's try it.
* Raindrops on roses *
* And whiskers on kittens *
* Bright copper kettles *
* And warm woolen mittens *
* Brown paper packages *
* Tied up with strings *
* These are a few
of my favorite things *
Why don't I
feel better?
* Girls in white dresses *
* With blue satin sashes *
[ Maria's VoiceJoins ]
* Snowflakes that stay
on my nose and eyelashes *
- * Silver white winters
that melt into springs *
- [ Children Shouting ]
* These are a few
of my favorite things *
* When the dog bites *
* When the bee stings *
* When I'm feeling sad *
* I simply remember
my favorite things *
* And then I don't feel *
* So bad *
Oh, children, I'm so glad
to see you!
We missed you!
Oh, I missed you.
Kurt, how are you?
Hungry.
Gretl, what happened
to your finger?
It got caught.
Caught in what?
Friedrich's teeth.
Liesl,
you all right?
Just fair.
Many telegrams been
delivered here lately?
None at all, fraulein,
but I'm learning to accept it.
I'll be glad
when school begins.
Oh, Liesl,
you can't use school
to escape your problems.
You have to face them.
Oh, I have so much
to tell you all.
We have things
to tell you, too.
I'm sure you do.
The most
important thing
is that Father is
going to be married.
Married?
Yes, to Baroness
Schraeder.
Oh, I see.
Oh, Father, look!
Fraulein Maria's
come back from the abbey!
Good evening, Captain.
Good evening.
All right,
everyone inside.
Go and get your dinner.
Dinner!
You left without
saying good-bye,
even to the children.
Well, it was wrong
of me. Forgive me.
Why did you?
Please don't ask me.
Anyway, the reason
no longer exists.
Fraulein Maria.
You've returned.
Isn't it wonderful,
Georg?
May I wish you
every happiness, baroness,
and you, too, Captain.
The children tell me
you're to be married.
Thank you, my dear.
You are back
to, uh, stay?
Only until arrangements
can be made for
another governess.
There you are!
I really must
speak to Cook
about the wiener
schnitzel.
It is entirely too delicious
for my figure.
And it makes you
much too quiet
at the dinner table,
or was it the wine?
Oh, undoubtedly
the wine.
You have no idea what kind
of trouble I'm having
trying to decide
what to give you
for a wedding present.
Oh, I know,
I'm enough,
but I do want you to have
some little trifle
for the occasion.
At first, I thought
of a fountain pen,
but you've
already got one.
And then I thought perhaps
a villa in the south of France,
but they are so difficult
to gift-wrap.
Georg, how do you feel
about yachts?
A long, sleek one
for the Mediterranean,
or a tiny one
for your bathtub, hmm?
Elsa.
And where to go
on our honeymoon?
Now, that is
a real problem.
I thought a trip around
the world would be lovely.
Then I said,
''Oh, Elsa,
there must be someplace
better to go.''
Don't worry, darling.
I--
Elsa.
Yes, Georg?
It's no use.
You and I.
I've been dishonest
to both of us
and utterly
unfair to you.
When two people
talk of marriage--
No, don't.
Don't say another word,
Georg, please.
You see, um...
there are other things
I've been thinking of.
Fond as I am of you,
I really don't think
you're the right man for me.
You're, um--
You're much too
independent.
And I--I need someone
who needs me desperately,
or at least needs
my money desperately.
I've enjoyed every moment
we've had together.
I do thank you for that.
Now, if, um,
if you'll forgive me,
I'll go inside,
pack my little bags,
and return to Vienna,
where I belong.
And somewhere out there
is a young lady
who I think...
will never be a nun.
Auf wiedersehen,
darling.
Hello.
I thought I just might
find you here.
Was there something
you wanted?
Hmm?
No, no, no.
Sit down. please.
Please.
Uh, may I?
You know, I was...
I was thinking
and I was wondering
two things.
Why did you
run away to the abbey?
And...
what was it
that made you come back?
Well, I...
had an obligation
to fulfill,
and I...
I came back
to fulfill it.
Is that all?
And I missed
the children.
Yes.
Only the children?
No. Yes!
Isn't it right I should
have missed them?
Oh, yes!
Yes, of course!
I was only hoping
that perhaps you...
Perhaps
you might, uh...
Yes?
Well, uh...
Nothing was the same
when you were away and...
it'll be all wrong again
after you leave.
And I just thought
perhaps you might, uh...
change your mind?
I'm sure the baroness
will be able to make
things fine for you.
Maria,
there isn't going
to be any baroness.
There isn't?
No.
I don't
understand.
Well, we've, um, called off
our engagement, you see, and--
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yes.
You are?
Mm-hmm.
You did?
Yes.
Well, you can't marry
someone when you're...
in love with
someone else.
Can you?
The Reverend Mother
always says,
''When The Lord
closes a door,
somewhere
he opens a window.''
What else does the
Reverend Mother say?
That you have to look
for your life.
Is that why
you came back?
And have you
found it...
Maria?
I think I have.
I know I have.
I love you.
* Perhaps I had
a wicked childhood *
a miserable youth *
* But somewhere in my wicked,
miserable past *
* There must have been
a moment of truth *
* For here you are *
* Standing there *
* Loving me *
* Whether or not *
* You should *
* So somewhere
in my youth *
* Or childhood *
* I must have done
something good *
* Nothing comes
from nothing *
* Nothing ever could *
* So somewhere
in my youth *
* Or childhood *
* I must have done *
* Something *
* Good **
Do you know when I first
started loving you?
That night
at the dinner table
when you sat on that
ridiculous pine cone.
[ Laughing ]
What? [ Laughs ]
I knew the first time
you blew that silly whistle.
* For here you are *
* Standing there *
* Loving me *
* Whether or not *
* You should *
* So somewhere
in my youth *
* Or childhood *
* I must have done *
* Something *
* Good *
* Nothing comes
from nothing *
* Nothing ever could *
* So somewhere
in my youth *
* Or childhood *
* I must have done *
* Something *
* Good **
Maria.
Is there anyone
I should go to
to ask permission
to marry you?
Well, why don't
we ask--
- The children?
[ Church Bells Ringing ]
[ Organ Plays ]
* How do you solve
a problem like Maria? *
* How do you catch
a cloud and pin it down? *
* How do you find a word
that means Maria? *
* A flibbertigibbet,
a will-o'-the wisp *
* A clown *
* Many a thing you know
you'd like to tell her *
* Many a thing
she ought to understand *
* But how do you
make her stay *
* And listen
to all you say? *
* How do you keep
a wave upon the sand? *
* Oh, how do you solve
a problem like Maria? *
* How do you hold
a moonbeam in your hand? *
[ Church Bells Ring ]
[ Music Playing ]
Herr Detweiler!
Heil Hitler.
Oh. good afternoon,
Herr Zeller.
Perhaps you've not heard.
I'm now the
gulleiter.
Heil Hitler.
Uh...
I have just come from the house
of Captain von Trapp,
Incidentally, the only one
in the neighborhood
not flying the flag
of the Third Reich
since the Anschluss.
But we have dealt
with that situation.
Your housekeeper told me
that I would find you here.
It was the only information
the woman would give me.
What kind of information
are you looking for?
We want to know when
the captain will be returning.
Well, he's on
his honeymoon trip.
Uh, he's not been
in touch with us.
Are you asking me to believe
that the captain
has not communicated with
his children in over a month?
Herr Zeller,
how many men do you know
who communicate
with their children
while on
their honeymoon?
When he does return,
he will be expected to fill
his proper position
in the new order.
Naturally.
And may I
congratulate you--
That is, your people--
on deciding to allow
the festival
to go on tonight
as planned?
Why should it not go on?
Nothing in Austria has changed.
Singing and music
will show this to the world.
Austria is the same.
Heil Hitler.
Come on, children,
Let's go home.
Why was he
so cross?
Everybody's cross
these days, darling.
Maybe the flag with
the black spider on it
makes people nervous.
Is father going to be
in trouble?
He doesn't
have to be.
The thing to do
these days
is to get along
with everybody.
I want you all
to remember that
tonight
at the concert.
Are we really
going to sing
before a whole lot
of people tonight?
Of course.
Look, the von Trapp
Family Singers.
And here are
your names--
Liesl, Friedrich,
Louisa, Brigitta,
Kurt, Marta,
and Gretl.
Why am I always last?
Because you are
the most important.
Oh!
There we go.
Uncle Max,
are you sure Father
will approve of
our singing in public?
Oh, he'll be pleased
and proud.
Liesl,
do you think so?
Don't
you trust me?
No!
You're a very
intelligent girl.
[ Laughs ]
Liesl! Liesl!
Rolfe!
Rolfe,
I'm so glad to see you.
It's been such--
Good afternoon.
You will take this, please,
and deliver it to your father
as soon as he comes home.
He's on his honeymoon.
- I know that.
- You do?
We make it our business to know
everything about everyone.
Who's we?
See that he gets it.
What is it?
It's a telegram
from Berlin.
Don't you want
to come over tonight
and deliver it
yourself?
I am now occupied with
more important matters,
and your father better be, too,
if he knows what's good for him.
But, Rolfe--
[ Children Shouting ]
Father! Father!
- We didn't expect you so soon.
- Hello, hello, hello!
When did you
get back?
Did you bring us
any souvenirs from Paris?
Hello!
How are you?
Why didn't you
telephone us?
We tried to, but we
couldn't get through.
I had nothing
to do with that, Georg.
We came back
as fast as we could.
Well, well, well,
we missed you!
We missed kissing you
good night.
We missed all the noise
you make in the morning
telling each other
to be quiet.
Mostly, we missed
hearing you sing.
Oh, you came back
just in time.
Look,
Fraulein Maria--
I mean, Mother.
We're going to sing
in the festival tonight.
What?
Yes, we've been
rehearsing all--
Surprise!
All right, surprises
for you on the terrace.
Presents!
We'll talk about
this inside.
I would have told you,
but you were away.
I had to make
a last-minute decision.
I was fortunate
to enter them at all.
Max.
They'll be the talk
of the festival.
Imagine,
seven children
in one family.
Max!
Somehow I recall
having made it
quite clear to you
how I feel about
my family
singing in public.
But the committee heard
them. They were enchanted.
Oh, Max,
what did they say?
I have never heard
such enthusiasm.
Oh, darling, don't you think--
Just this once?
Absolutely
out of the question.
Georg, this is
for Austria.
For Austria?
There is no Austria!
But the Anschluss
happened peacefully.
Let's at least
be grateful for that.
Grateful?!
You know, Max...
sometimes I don't
believe I know you.
Father, I forgot.
This is for you.
[ Door Slams ]
Maria, he has got
to at least pretend
to work with these people.
You must convince him.
Max, I can't ask him
to be less than he is.
Then I'll talk to him.
If the children don't sing
at the festival,
well, it will be
a reflection on Austria.
Oh, I know. It wouldn't
do me any good, either.
- Mother?
- Hmm?
That sounds so nice.
I like calling you Mother.
I like hearing it.
- You love Father very much,
I can tell you do.
- Very much.
Mother, what do you do when you
think you love someone--
I mean, when you stop
loving someone,
or he stops loving you?
Well, you
cry a little.
And then you wait
for the sun to come out.
It always does.
There's so many things
I think I should know,
but I don't.
I really don't.
How can you?
Sometimes I feel the world
is coming to an end.
And then you feel
it's just beginning?
Yes.
It was that way
with me, Liesl.
And for you, it will be
just as wonderful, I promise.
Do you really
think so?
* When you're 1 6 *
* Going on 1 7 *
* Waiting for life
to start *
*Somebody kind *
* Who touches
your mind *
* Will suddenly
touch your heart *
* When that happens *
* After it happens *
* Nothing is quite
the same *
* Somehow I know
I'll jump up and go *
* If ever
he calls my name *
* Gone are your
old ideas of life *
* The old ideas
grow dim *
* Lo and behold *
* You're someone's wife *
* And you
belong to him *
* You may think
this kind of adventure *
* Never may come
to you *
* Darling 1 6,
going on 1 7 *
* Wait a year
or two *
* I'll wait a year *
*Just wait a year *
* Or *
* Two *
Liesl.
What is it?
Berlin.
They've offered me
a commission in their navy.
I've been
requested
to accept immediately
and report to their naval base
at Bremerhaven tomorrow.
I knew something
like this would happen,
but I didn't think
it would be so soon.
To refuse them would be
fatal for all of us,
and joining them
would be... unthinkable.
Get the children
all together.
Don't say anything
that's going
to make them worry.
Just get them ready.
We've got to get out
of Austria...
and this house...
tonight.
It strains my back,
it breaks my heart
when I think of
a certain singing group
that will not appear
at the festival tonight.
By the time you've
made the announcement,
we'll be over the border.
I hope you appreciate
the sacrifice I'm making.
You have no choice.
I know. That's why
I'm making it.
Why doesn't Father
turn the motor on?
Because he doesn't want
anyone to hear us!
Shh!
What will Frau Schmidt
and Franz say
when they discover
we're gone?
They'll be able to
answer truthfully.
They didn't know anything
about it if anyone asks them.
Will we be coming
back here?
Someday, Liesl.
I do hope someday.
Are Father and Uncle Max
going to push the car
all the way to Switzerland?
Shh!
Something wrong
with your car, Captain?
Yes, as a matter
of fact,
We couldn't
get it started.
Kobb.
Fix Captain
von Trapp's car
so that
it will start.
[ Car Engine Starts ]
Excellent, Kobb.
I've not asked you
where you and your
family are going.
Nor have you asked me
why I'm here.
Well, apparently,
we're both suffering
from a deplorable
lack of curiosity.
You were sent a telegram,
which you did not answer,
from the navy
of the Third Reich.
I was under
the impression,
Herr Zeller,
that the contents of
telegrams in Austria
are private!
At least
the Austria I know.
I have my orders.
And they are to take you
personally
to Bremerhaven tonight
where you will accept
your commission.
I'm afraid that's...
going to be
quite impossible.
You see, we, uh...
all of us--
The entire family
will be...
singing in
the festival tonight.
As a matter of fact,
that's where
we were going now.
Couldn't possibly
let them down now.
I just hope
we're not too late.
Yes.
And you ask me to believe
that you, Captain von Trapp,
are singing
in a concert?
Believe me,
it will be a performance
beyond anything
even I've dreamt of.
Like you,
Herr Zeller,
I, too, am a man
of hidden talents.
Yes, um... here.
Program.
It says here only the names
of the children.
It says The von Trapp
Family Singers,
and I'm the head
of the von Trapp family,
am I not?
And these, um, travel clothes
that you're all wearing?
Our costumes,
naturally.
Herr Zeller,
this night air is not good
for the children's voices.
Well, a slight delay
in my orders
will not be serious.
Therefore...
you will sing.
You will all sing,
But only because that's
the way I want it to be.
It will demonstrate that nothing
in Austria has changed.
And when you
are finished singing,
you, Captain von Trapp,
will be taken to Bremerhaven.
Now, if you will all
get into your car,
we will escort
the von Trapp family singers
to the festival.
No escort will be
necessary, Herr Zeller.
Necessary?
Apleasure, Captain.
After all,
we would not want you
to get lost
in the crowds,
would we?
No.
* Sew, a needle
pulling thread *
* A needle
* La, a note to follow sew *
* A note to follow sew *
* Tea, a drink
with jam and bread *
* A drink with
jam and bread *
*Jam and bread,
with jam and bread *
* Tea with jam
and bread *
*Jam and bread,
jam and bread *
* Tea with jam,
*Jam and bread *
jam and bread *
- * With jam *
- * A-B-C *
* A-B-C *
- * With jam *
- * Do re mi *
* Do re mi *
* Tea with jam
and bread *
* With jam and bread *
* With jam
with jam *
* And bread **
[ Applause ]
My fellow Austrians...
I shall not be
seeing you again
perhaps for
a very long time.
I would like
to sing for you now
a love song.
I know you share
this love.
I pray that you will
never let it die.
* Edelweiss *
* Every morning
you greet me *
* Small and white *
* Clean and bright *
* You look happy
to meet me *
* Blossom of snow *
* May you bloom
and grow *
* Bloom and grow
forever *
* Edelweiss *
* Bless my homeland forever *
* Edel-- *
* Small and white *
* Clean and bright *
* You look happy
to meet me *
* Blossom of snow *
* May you bloom
and grow *
* Bloom and grow
forever *
* Edelweiss *
* Bless my homeland forever **
I think it'll work.
I shall miss all of you.
I shall miss the money
I could have made with you.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen,
Thank you.
The festival competition
has come to its conclusion,
Except, of course,
we don't know yet
what that
conclusion will be.
And while the judges are
arriving at their decision,
I have been given permission
to offer you an encore.
This will be
the last opportunity
the von Trapps will have
of singing together
for a long, long time.
Even now,
offcials are waiting
in this auditorium
to escort
Captain von Trapp
to his new command
in the naval forces
of the Third Reich.
And so,
ladies and gentlemen,
the family
von Trapp again...
to bid you farewell.
[ Applause ]
* There's a sad
sort of clanging *
* From the clock
in the hall *
* And the bells in
the steeple, too *
* And up in the nursery,
an absurd little bird *
* Is popping out
to say cuckoo *
* Cuckoo *
* Regretfully
they tell us *
* But firmly
they compel us *
* To say good-bye *
* To you *
* So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, good night *
* We hate to go
and miss this pretty sight *
* So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, adieu *
* Adieu, adieu,
to you and you and you *
* So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, good-bye *
* We flit, we float,
we fleetly flee, we fly *
* So long, farewell,
auf wiedersehen, good-bye *
* The sun has gone to bed,
and so must I *
* Good-bye *
* Good-bye **
Ladies and gentlemen,
I have here the decision
of our distinguished
judges.
We will start with the award
for third prize.
For this honor,
the judges have named
the first soloist of the choir
of St. Agathe's Church
in Murbach--
Fraulein Schweiger.
[ Audience Laughs ]
Second prize to...
the Toby Reiser Quintet.
The first prize,
the highest honor
in all Austria,
to The von Trapp
Family Singers.
The Family von Trapp.
They're gone!
[ Horns Honking ]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Come with me.
[ Ring ]
Quickly! Quickly!
I have a place
you can hide.
Slowly.
Slowly...
[ Ring ]
Open this gate!
Good evening.
Hurry up, woman.
Two men in there!
Six of you, fan out
and cover the yard.
You two, cover
the corridor.
Oh, Reverend Mother,
we didn't realize
we'd put the abbey
in this danger.
No, Maria.
It was right for you
to come here.
We thought we might borrow
your caretaker's car.
I'm afraid our car
will do you no good now.
I've been listening
to the wireless.
The borders have
just been closed.
All right,
the borders are closed.
Then we'll drive up
into the hills
and go over those
mountains on foot.
The children.
We'll help them.
They'll be all right.
We can do it
without help, Father.
Maria.
You will not be alone.
Remember, ''I will lift up
mine eyes unto the hills
from whence
cometh my help.''
Yes, Mother.
I'm scared.
Me, too.
God be with you.
- Mother.
- Yes?
Would it help if we sang
about our favorite things?
No, darling.
This is one time
it would not help.
You must be
very quiet.
Hold tight to me.
[ Footsteps ]
[ Rattling ]
Come on.
Let's try the roof.
[ Gasp ]
Rolfe, please.
No, wait!
Maria--
Children--
It's you we want,
not them.
Put that down.
Not another move!
Or I'll-- I'll shoot!
You're only a boy.
You don't really
belong to them.
Stay where you are!
Come away with us
before
it's too late.
Not another step.
I'll kill you!
You give that
to me, Rolfe.
Did you hear me?
I'll kill you!
Rolfe
You'll never
be one of them.
Lieutenant!
Lieutenant,
they're here!
They're here,
Lieutenant!
[ Blows Whistle ]
[ Whistle Blowing ]
[ Engines Stall ]
Reverend Mother.
I have sinned.
I, too,
Reverend Mother.
What is this sin,
my children?
* A dream that will need *
* All the love
you can give *
* Every day of your life *
* For as long
as you live *
* Climb every mountain *
* Ford every stream *
* Follow every rainbow *
* Till *
* You *
* Find *
* Your *
* Dream **