**
How many times we gotta fix
This old fence?
Easier to tear it down and start
Over.
[Barking]
Not you again!
Look'it!
It looks like he wet himself.
That's a big old scaredy cat.
You go ahead and laugh.
He can't bite through that brace
On your leg.
Toto!
Toto, come back here.
Morning, miss Dorothy.
Robert found your dog for you.
I told you; You can't come
With me.
Somebody takin' a trip?
Or running away from home
Again?
You can't run away from home
If you're not home to start
With.
Don't she live here?
Could'a sworn she lived here.
Dorothy Gail, I am too old to
Be chasin' you down.
I swear I don't know who needs a
Leash more; You or that dog.
Morning, miss em.
And why are you three
Standing 'round?
Can't you see the leaves turning
Over?
Storm's coming.
Can't you see?
We're still cleaning up the
Last.
Go on, get everything back to
The barn.
Lock down the shutters and turn
The horses out.
Yes, ma'am.
And take this dog with you.
So, I guess you won't be helping
Me with the laundry today.
Oh, Dorothy.
I don't know what to do with
You.
You don't gotta do nothing.
Well, that'll make a nice
Break from worrying about you
Day and night.
Why should you worry?
You're not my mother.
No, I'm your mother's big
Sister.
And when you get your face all
Balled up mad like that it's
Almost like having her back with
Me.
You're so like her.
Stubborn, strong, smart and
Beautiful...
I don't belong here.
I hate that school and everyone
In it.
I hate this place.
I wanna go back home where I
Come from.
Sweet girl, if I had the
Magic to put your mama and daddy
Back in that house for you, I'd
Snap my fingers and they'd be
There waitin' supper.
But you know as well as me your
Folks are gone.
Gone, baby.
Lost in that accident.
And all the wishin' in the world
Ain't changing that.
Back there's my home.
Back there's nothing but an
Empty apartment.
And my school and my friends,
And nobody riding me to do
Chores or watching over every
Little thing I do twenty-four
Hours a day.
I remember a time, not so
Long ago, you used to like me
Watchin' over you.
Used to be your favorite aunt.
I remember how you come running
To hide yourself behind my apron
At bath time.
Anything to avoid your mama's
Soap and washcloth.
You think I give you chores to
Be ornery?
Being part of a family
Guarantees you always got love,
But you got responsibility too.
Home is something got to be
Earned.
Storm's not waiting on one
Little girl to come to her
Senses.
Let's go, child.
We need to get to shelter.
Much as I love you, much as I
Think I know what's right, I
Can't lock you up in your room
The rest of your life.
All I can do is pray you'll
Choose the path that will lead
You back to the ones who love
You.
**
* put your arms around me
Child like when you bumped
Your shin then you'll know
I love you now *
* as I loved you then
Though you may be trying
Sometimes and I'll need you
And you're not there *
* I may get mad
And turn you away
But lord knows I still care
But you cannot ask *
* for more than can
Come from me I am different
Than you are and one day
You'll see *
* if I lose my patience
With you and suddenly
Start to scream
It's only because *
* I want you to be
Everything I see in my dreams
And I'd like to know
That it's there *
* the feeling we once had
When you know that you can
You can come to me
Whenever you're *
* feeling bad
Don't lose the feeling
We once had
Don't lose the feeling *
* we once had
Though you're growing
Older now and
I'm watching you grow *
* and if I make you
Sad sometimes
I see your feelings show
But one day *
* I'll look around
And you will be grown
You'll be out in the world
Such a pretty little girl *
* but you'll be out there
On your own
You'll be on your own
And I'd like to know *
* that it's there
The feeling we once had
Don't lose the feelin'
When you know that you can *
* you can come to me
Whenever you're feeling bad
The feeling we once had
Don't lose it *
* the feeling we once had
That we had that we had
This storm means business we
Best get inside.
**
Aunt em!
Aunt em?
Aunt em, where are you?
Who's saying that?
Who's saying what?
Who are you?
I'll be the one askin' the
Questions from here on out.
From here on in.
From here on in or out!
This here's a murder
Investigation.
Murder?
Murder!
I don't know anything about
Any murder.
That's what they all say.
Is that there your house?
It's my aunt em's house.
Ask her about these feet!
And are those feet stickin'
Out from under your aunt em's
House?
I don't know.
It appears so.
And is the person attached to
Them feet dead?
How do I know?
I'm no doctor.
There's a house sitting on
Top of her.
You do the math.
Let the witness answer!
I don't know.
It appears so.
And there you have it...
A murder victim, a murder weapon
And a murder suspect.
What say the jury?
Guilty!
You have heard the findings
Of this court.
We declare you guilty of murder
In the house degree.
Bailiff, throw her a party!
What?
Congratulations!
I don't understand.
You just killed evvamean, the
Wicked witch of the east, and we
Can't thank you enough!
**
Where is it?
Where's that house I seen flying
By?
Addaperle!
Atta' girl!
Who is she?
I'm the good witch of the north.
Don't ring a bell?
Perhaps you know me by my stage
Name, "addaperle, the feel-good"
Girl."
I got a little magic act.
[Applause]
I do tricks.
Does she ever!
Could you please tell me
Where I am?
Lost, are you? I know what
That's like.
Sometimes I nod out on the bus
And end up in all sorts of
Unfamiliar places.
But let's see if I can help you
Out.
That there is a munchkin.
And that there is a munchkin.
So I'd say it's a pretty good
Bet that you're in munchkinland,
In the good ole U.S. of oz.
Am I right?
Addaperle, girl, there's
Something I think you ought'a
See.
Yeah!
That's it!
That's the thing almost knocked
Me out the sky!
But lookie here.
Is that?
It couldn't be.
Oh, no, not my sister!
Please don't tell me somebody
Squished my poor, heartless,
Rotten, evil, older, twisted
Sister evvamean!
Somebody tell me who to thank.
She done it!
Really?
You're awful young to be killing
Witches.
Do you have a license?
Do I what?
You ain't lookin' to kill no
More witches, are you?
Of course not.
Good.
'Cause there's only three of us
Left.
Me, the good witch of the north.
[Applause]
Evillene, the wicked witch of
The west.
[Audience booing]
And our other sister glinda, the
Good witch of the South.
Yeah, she's something.
You should catch her act while
You're in town.
Girl's got pipes.
But back to our story... who are
You?
No!
I will tell you with help from
My magic slate.
Magic slate?
It's an apple.
Now, without my touching it your
Name will appear here plain as
Day.
And that name is...
Shirley!
No.
Not Shirley.
Shirleen!
Nope.
Shirletta!
Not even close.
Charmaine?
Champagne?
Chuck!
No.
You sure you ain't Charmaine?
Lemme see some i.D.
My name is...
Did I say don't tell me?
Write it down.
Dorothy.
Dorothy?
Really?
Your name is... Dorothy!
[Applause]
Whatever.
What can I do for you?
For me?
You freed the munchkins from
The evil rule of evvamean.
The least I can do is take you
Out to lunch.
You like Sushi?
Can you help me get home?
Where's that?
I'm trying to get to Omaha
Where I was born.
No can do.
That falls under the heading of
Transporting a minor across
State lines.
I'm afraid you're gonna have to
See the wiz.
The wiz?
Yeah!
The wiz.
I bet he could get you home.
He can do anything.
He's the wiz!
Who's the wiz?
* sweet thing
Let me tell you 'bout
The world
And the way things are *
* you've come from
A different place
And I know
You've travelled far *
* now that you've told
Me what it is
Dot dot da dot dah
I'd better point you *
* toward the wiz
He's the wiz
He's the one
He's the only one *
* who can give your wish
Right to ya
He's the wizard
He can send you *
* back thru time
By running magic to ya
All of the super power's his
Dot dot da dot dah *
* listen and I'll tell you
Where he is
He's the wiz
And he lives in oz *
* he's the wizard
There's a way
To the emerald city
Now that's not too far *
* is it
He's the wizard
Just take your dilemma child
And lay it on the wizard *
* lay it on him
He'll fix a drink
That'll bubble and foam
Oh dot dot da dot dah *
* and in a flash
You'll be home
He's the wiz
He's the wiz *
* he's the wizard of oz
The wizard
He's got magic up his sleeve
The magical wizard *
* and you know
Without his help
The wizard
'Twould be impossible *
* to leave
You need his help girl
Fantastic power's
At his command *
* oh dot dot da dot dah
And I'm sure that
He will understand
He'll understand *
* he's the wiz
And he lives in oz
He's the wizard
He's the wizard *
* he's the wizard
He's the wizard
He's the wizard *
* he's the wizard
He's the wizard
He's the wizard *
* yeah
Evvamean's silver slippers
Are
Now yours.
You got nothin' against second
Hand, do you?
I've never had anything so
Fine.
Girl, put 'em on, put 'em on!
They fit perfect.
But you gotta promise to
Never take them off, not 'til
You get home.
Why?
Because they got super
Special secret powers!
Like what?
What's the point of a secret
If you go around blabbin' it?
Just promise you won't take them
Off for anything, not until you
Get home.
I promise.
And now a kiss for extra
Added protection.
From what?
All kind'a whatnot.
There's some nasty stuff betwixt
Here and there.
You got you somethin' very
Precious on your feet.
Ain't a creature in oz won't
Recognize and want to snatch
Them kicks for themselves.
But now I must go!
So, goodbye.
I said, goodbye!
Reggie?
You get me a new battery like I
Asked?
Give it a shake and lean on
The clutch.
I said good-bye!
Wait.
You didn't tell me where to find
The wiz.
No hay problemo.
Wiz lives in the emerald city.
And where's that at?
Oh, darling, you can't miss
It.
It's big and it's green and it's
Right at the end of the yellow
Brick road.
The yellow brick road?
Just stay on the yellow brick
Road and you can't miss it.
But watch out for the winged
Warriors.
The winged what?
And the kalidahs.
Who are they?
They're shape shifters.
And mind readers.
And they will charm them
Slippers right off your feet.
And don't forget to warn her
About the poppies.
Poppies?
Like flowers?
What I gotta be scared of
Flowers for?
Sometimes the most dangerous
Things are also the most
Beautiful.
That's deep, cuz.
They lure you in, and once
They get their tendrils on you,
They never let you go.
They put you to work feeding and
Watering and plowing their
Fields from sunrise to sunset
Until the first frost sets you
Free.
But it ain't all bad.
You get a lot of fresh air.
Addaperle said something
About the wicked witch of the
West.
Oh, you don't gotta fret
About her.
Seein' how you off'ed her
Sister, if she gets her hands on
You, she'll slice, dice and deep
Fry your butt 'fore you can
Blink.
So, no sense worrying about her.
Have a nice trip.
Regards to the wiz!
Goodbye!
Just follow the yellow brick
Road?
That's right.
Just follow the yellow brick
Road.
But where is the yellow brick
Road?
**
* there's a feeling here inside
That I cannot hide *
* and I know I've tried
But it's turning me around *
* I'm not sure that I'm aware
If I'm up or down
If I'm here or there *
* I need both feet on the ground
Why do I feel like I'm
Drowning *
* when there is plenty of air?
Why do I feel like frowning? *
* I think the feeling is fear
Here I am in a different place *
* in a different time
In this time and space *
* but I don't want to be here
I was told I must see the wiz *
* but I don't know what a wizard
Is
I just hope the wiz is there *
* maybe I'm just going crazy
Letting myself get uptight *
* I'm acting just like a baby
I'm gonna be all right *
* soon as I get home
Soon as I get home
In a different place
In a different time *
* different people around me
I would like to know *
* of their different world
And how different they find me *
* and just what's a wiz
Is it big?
Will it scare me? *
* if I ask to leave
Will the wiz even hear me? *
* how will I know then
If I'll ever get home again? *
* here I am alone
Though it feels the same *
* I don't know where I'm going
Out here on my own
And it's not a game *
* and a strange wind is blowing
I am so amazed *
* by the things that I see here
I don't want to be afraid *
* I just don't wanna to be here
In my mind, this is clear *
* what am I doing here?
I wish I was
Home **
What d'ya know?
A yellow brick road!
**
Why hello there.
Got any spare change?
Loose bills?
Maybe some dirty old dollars
Cluttering up your purse?
Did you say that?
Did I say what?
A talking scarecrow?
Where?
You!
How come you can talk?
And what you doin' up there?
And if you're a scarecrow, how
Come those crows aren't scared?
A bevy of excellent questions
Which it would be my pleasure to
Answer if only I had a brain.
How can you talk without a
Brain?
I'm not sure.
But since I been hangin' up
Here, I've heard an awful lot of
Brainless people talking and it
Ain't stops them.
So how about helping a brother
Out with some cash?
What's it for?
I'm saving my cents to buy me
Some sense.
How much you got so far?
Nothing.
Whatever I get they take away.
That's rent, my brother.
All legit.
Everything on the up and up.
Poles don't grow on trees, you
Know.
Would you like me to help you
Come down from there?
Why he wanna come down?
My man is living penthouse high.
Don't listen to them.
You've got to think for
Yourself.
I would.
As soon as I get me a brain.
But the farmer who made me
Stuffed my head with straw.
Then these crows come along
Filling it with all manner of
Nonsense.
Ever hear such ingrateful
Platitudes?
We fill his head with the
Truth.
The whole truth and nothing but
The truth.
What kind of truth?
Go on.
Elucidate the sister.
"There ain't no gettin' ahead"
"For folks like me."
Gettin' a head!
That's funny, right?
Sit down, girl.
School is in session.
Go on.
Tell her what else we taught
You.
Represent.
I don't want to.
Yeah!
Crow-cede with the crow
Commandments.
**
* you can't win
You can't break even *
* and you can't get out
Of the game
People keep sayin'
Things are gonna change *
* but they look just like
They're stayin' the same *
* you get in way over your head
And you've only got
Yourself to blame *
* you can't win, child
You can't win, child
You can't break even *
* and you can't
Get out of the game
You can't win
The world keeps movin' *
* and you're standin' far
Behind
People keep sayin' *
* things'll get better
Just to ease your state of
Mind *
* so you lay back
And you smoke that smoke *
* and you drink your glass of
Wine
Sayin' you can't win, child *
* you can't break even
And you can't get out of the
Game *
* you can't win
You can't win
You can't win, no way *
* if your story stays the same
You ain't winnin' *
* but it's nice to see you
I'm awfully glad you came
Better cool it *
* 'cause ain't about losin'
And the world has got no shame *
* you can't win, child
You can't break even *
* and you can't get out of the
Game
**
You can't win *
* you can't break even
Ain't the way it's s'posed to
Be *
* you'll be spendin'
Your little bit of money *
* while someone else rides for
Free
Learn your lesson
Refuel your mind *
* before some Turkey
Blows out your flame
You can't win, child
No, you can't win *
* you can't win, child
No, you can't win
You can't win, child
No, you can't win *
* you can't win, child
No, you can't win
You can't win, child
You can't break even *
* and you can't
Get out of the game
Can't get out of the game *
* you can't get out of the
Game **
I've never heard such
Nonsense.
Now, shoo!
Shoo!
Leave him be.
All of you.
You think you scare us?
You listen up, I already
Killed a wicked witch this
Morning and I wasn't even mad at
Her.
Gotta fly.
Catch you on the b-side.
They're gone.
You can come down now.
Thank you.
I need a little help.
Are you all right?
Do I look all right?
Seem a little wobbly.
For me, that's all right.
You know what?
I know nothing.
You oughta come with me to
See the wiz.
The wiz?
He lives in the emerald city
And there's nothing he can't do.
He's gonna get me home.
And I bet he can get you some
Brains.
Brains?
Me?
Man, I'm gonna get me some
Brains.
I hope my hat can handle it.
* come on and, ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* don't you carry nothin'
That might be a load *
* come on and, ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* don't you carry nothin'
That might be a load *
* come on, ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* 'cause there may be times
When you think you've lost your
Mind *
* and the steps you're takin'
Leave you three, four steps
Behind *
* just you keep on keepin'
On the road that you choose *
* and don't give up walkin'
'Cause you gave up shoes *
* come on and, ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* don't you carry nothin'
That might be a load
Come on and *
* ease on down, ease on down
Ease on down, ease on down *
The road **
**
You hear that?
It's coming from over there.
What should we do?
Go over there!
Ohhhhhhhh!
Someone's in trouble.
What is it?
I have seen me some
Dope-fresh crock-pots in my day,
But...
Shh, he's trying to say
Something.
Oil.
What was that?
I need oil.
He said he needs oil.
Could this be it?
And now what?
* slide some oil to me
Let it slip down my spine *
* if you don't have stp
Crisco be just fine
Slide some oil to me *
* hit my shoulder blade
All y'all
That don't have to lubricate *
* sure have got it made
Slide some oil to me *
* let it slip down my side
Standing here in one position *
* sure can make one tired
Slide some to my elbows *
* and my fingers, if you would
Come on, slide some oil to me,
Girl *
* ooh, does that feel good
Slide some oil to my feet
Look!
I got toes again!
* come on and slide some oil
To my knees
And let me see if I can bend *
* slide some oil to me
I'm beginning to feel fine *
* come on and slide some oil
To my throat *
* and let me lubricate my mind
And let me lubricate my mind
And let me lubricate my mind *
Watch me do this!
**
* slide some oil to me
I'm beginning to feel fine *
* come on and slide some oil
To my throat
And let me lubricate my mind *
* and let me lubricate my mind
My mind, let me lubricate my
Mind **
How do I ever thank you?
Start by saying goodbye.
C'mon, Dorothy.
How did you get all rusted up
Like that?
Would you mind?
I was out here fixing and
Tinkering and whatnot when the
Strangest storm come out of
Nowhere and before I could duck
For cover, I was rusted solid.
That's terrible.
That's life.
Let's go.
I've gotta say, I've never
Met a man made out of tin
Before.
And you never seen a talkin'
Scarecrow neither.
Just one of them days.
Can we go now?
What's the hurry, son?
We got a date with the wiz.
He's gonna give me a brain and
Send Dorothy back home.
He can do that?
He can do anything.
He's the wiz.
I wonder...
No, he'd never...
What?
Y'know, I wasn't always made
Of tin.
Was a time I was flesh and blood
Just like you.
I was even in love.
Her name was Bertha.
Bertha?
Shh!
Go on.
Problem was there was this
Other girl.
Well, not so much a girl as a
Witch.
Which witch?
Evvamean, the wicked witch of
The east.
You know her?
You could say we run into
Each other.
So, what happened?
I swear I never encouraged
Her but evvamean was sweet on
Me.
Made no never mind, my heart
Belonged to Bertha.
I know I should've manned up and
Told her, but before I could,
Old evvamean caught us kissing
In the woods.
She let loose a bolt of
Lightning knocked me clear
Across the river.
When I opened my eyes I was like
This, ice cold and steely hard.
Bertha said she didn't mind, but
Turning me to tin wasn't the
Worst thing evvamean done to me.
She said if she couldn't have my
Heart, then no one could.
Without a heart I had to let
Bertha go.
That is the saddest story I
Ever heard.
Come on, Dorothy.
See you later.
You don't suppose the wiz...
Well, of course he can give
You back your heart.
You really think so?
I don't.
But then again, I don't got a
Brain.
You come with us to emerald
City.
When the wiz hears your story he
Will never turn you away.
No.
I can't go with you.
Old evvamean still keeps watch
To be sure I'm never happy.
They don't call her ever-mean
For nothing.
Traveling with me would put you
Both in danger.
But thank you.
Thank you kindly.
Actually, I guess you been
Rusted up so you haven't heard.
Evvamean is no longer of this
World.
See,
What had had happened was
Somebody sort of accidentally
Dropped a house on her.
Come again, say what now?
Those are evvamean's shoes.
It was you?
You dropped a house on evvamean?
I wasn't aiming or nothing.
But, yeah, it was my house.
Thank you.
So how's about coming with
Us?
You mean it?
Could my nightmare finally be
Over?
Why not?
Just show me the way!
* pick your right foot up
When your left one's down *
* come on, legs keep movin'
Don't you lose no ground *
* 'cause the road you're walkin'
Might be long sometime *
* but just stick with me
And you'll be just fine *
* come on and, ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* don't you carry nothin'
That might be a load
Come on and *
* ease on down, ease on down
Ease on down, ease on down *
The **
* ah ah ah ah
Say what you wanna
But I'm here to stay
'Cause I'm a mean ole lion *
* you can go where you wanna
But don't get in my way
'Cause I'm a mean ole lion
You'll be standin' in a draft *
* if you don't hear me laugh
And if you happen
To come around *
* better hope that
I don't frown
'Cause I just might
Knock you down *
* 'cause I'm a mean ole lion
I'm a mean old lion
Don't you know
I'm ready to fight *
* I'll turn your day into night
'Cause I'm a mean ole lion
And if you're half bright
You'll detour to the right *
* 'cause I'm a mean ole lion
All you strangers better beware
This is the
King of the jungle here *
* and if I happen
To let you slide
Don't just stand there
Run and hide *
* now, you just caught
My better side *
* 'cause I'm a mean ole lion
I'm a mean ole lion
A mean ole lion *
Ow.
You hit me.
You dig that?
Don't you know you could do
Permanent damage that way?
And you call yourself king of
The jungle?
You see another cat begging
For the gig?
Man, you've got a yellow
Streak a mile wide.
Do not.
I had it touched up last
Thursday.
You ought'a be ashamed of
Yourself, going around roaring
At folks.
You're nothing but a great big
Coward.
Hey.
You don't gotta scream it for
The whole neighborhood.
I've got to represent here, you
Know?
Don't want all the little forest
Creatures getting wise and
Ganging up on me.
Oh, what's the use?
I'll never be nothing but a big
Ole scaredy-cat.
That's all I'm ever going to be.
I tried to get help from this
Old owl.
But he just makes me lie on his
Couch while he asks a lot of
Stupid questions...
How do you feel?
What do you want?
What do you think it means?
I told him, "I think it means"
That I'm getting ripped off,
'Cause you take all my money and
"Give me nothing."
Oh, you poor thing.
Oh, great.
Now I've got little girls
Pitying me.
It could be worse.
At least this forest is a nice
Home.
And you've still got your
Heart.
And a brain.
What good's all that if I
Ain't got the courage to get out
Of bed?
Maybe, just maybe, if you
Came with us to see the wiz, he
Might be able to give you
Courage.
Really?
Just like that?
I don't see why not.
He's going to give scarecrow a
Brain, and tinman a heart and
Get me home.
* come on and ease on down
Ease on down the road
Come on and ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* don't you carry nothing
That might be a load
Come on and ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* 'cause there may be times
When you wish you wasn't born
And you wake one morning
Just to find your courage gone *
* but just know that feeling
Only last a little while
You just stick with me
And I 'll show you how to
Smile *
* come on, ease on down
Ease on down the road
Come on and ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* don't you carry nothing
That might be a load
Come on and *
* ease on down, ease on down
Ease on down, ease on down
Ease on down, ease on down *
* ease on down, ease on down
Ease on down, ease on down
The road *
* where'd the road go?
Come on and, ease on down
Ease on down the road *
* come on and, ease on down
Where'd the road go?
Where'd the what what?
Anybody seen the yellow brick
Road?
We were just on it.
And now we're not.
It's gotta be here.
Roads don't get up and walk
Away.
Maybe not where you come
From.
Anybody else notice how dark
It's getting?
What was that?
What was what?
I thought I heard...
Don't get all hysterical now.
I'm not getting hysterical
Now.
But gimme a few minutes?
If we're going to get to the
Emerald city, we've got to find
That road.
How about this?
There's four directions, and
There are four of us.
We'll each go a different
Direction and, between us, we'll
Find the yellow brick road.
Good plan.
Yeah, good plan.
Can I go with you?
Snap to, Leroy!
You're embarrassing yourself.
Now, let's move out!
Dorothy.
Who's that?
Scarecrow?
Dorothy, help me, baby.
Aunt em?
That you?
It's me, baby.
Don't you recognize your own
Mama?
Yes, baby.
It can't be.
You're...
I'm right here, baby.
Mama, I miss you so much.
I've been trying to get home to
You.
And I'm trying to get to you,
Baby.
I wanna hold you so bad.
But I can't get down from here.
I'll climb up and get you.
No!
Stay where you are or you'll be
Stuck here, too.
But how can I get you down?
Those shoes.
Shoes?
Them silver slippers.
They're magic.
They'll get me down.
Pass 'em to me.
But i...
Come on, baby girl.
Don't you wanna see your mama?
Baby, I been wanting to hold you
So bad.
I promised addaperle.
Don't matter what you
Promised that old witch.
You listen to your mama.
Hand me them slippers.
Please, baby, please.
Come on, stretch a little bit
More.
Dorothy, no!
It's the kalidahs!
**
Thank you, tinman.
If you hadn't come back when you
Did...
I will mollywhop the fool
Tries to step to you!
And scarecrow, you really
Surprised me.
Weren't no big thing.
And you, lion...
Can't wait to hear what she
Got to say to that quivering,
Cowering mess.
Wasn't my fault.
I had a furball.
That's exactly what you
Are... a great big furball.
Stop.
I saw him knock down one of
Those things.
Knock down?
It tripped on his tail.
He could've run away, but he
Didn't.
He stood tall.
'Till he played dead.
He's right.
Y'all should just go on without
Me.
Ain't no wiz powerful enough to
Fix this mess.
* woo woo woo woo
There is a place we'll go
Where there is mostly quiet *
* flowers and butterflies
A rainbow lives beside it
And from a velvet sky
A summer storm *
* you can feel
The coolness in the air
But you're still warm *
* and then a mighty roar
Will start the sky to crying
Not even lightning
Will be frightening my lion *
* and with no fear inside
No need to run
No need to hide *
* you're standing
Strong and tall
You're the bravest of them all
If on courage you must call *
* then keep on trying
And trying
And trying *
* you're a lion
In your own way, be a lion *
* I'm standing strong and tall
I'm the bravest
Of them all
If on courage I must call *
* I'll keep on trying and trying
And trying *
* I'm a lion
In my own way
I'm a lion
Be a lion *
Yes, you are.
**
Dorothy, look.
Isn't that...
It has to be.
What else could it be
Except...
The emerald city!
I've never seen anything so
Beautiful.
Well, what are we waiting
For?
Let's go!
**
What are these?
Nothing but flowers.
No, they're the poppies I was
Warned about.
What do they want?
I'd say they want us.
Don't let them get hold of
You.
Who's she?
Isn't she beautiful?
No, stay back.
You can't let them touch you.
The munchkins said they're
Dangerous.
Like poison Ivy?
Oh, they are worse than that.
What are they up to?
They're up to no good.
What do you suppose they want
With us?
I know exactly what they
Want, and it ain't happening.
The munchkins said that once
They get a hold of you they
Never let go.
And that's a bad thing?
It's not a good one.
This here's my corner of the
Forest.
Y'all need to
Stand back and let a lion do
What a lion's got to do.
Ladies, would any of you care to
Dance?
No, lion, don't!
**
Ladies, thank you for that
Lovely dance.
We must do it again some time.
And booya!
That's my lion.
Give me some paw, my man.
Good job.
And now, I believe we have a
Meeting with the wiz, yes?
**
And we have arrived!
The emerald city.
Ain't this something?
>>
End of the line, dawg!
You can't be pushin' your way to
The front.
Go on.
Get yourself to the end of the
Line!
There's no one else here.
You saying you're too good to
Get in line?
No, but...
What?
You something special, some
Kind'a vip or whatnot?
I'm not tryin'...
And you ain't cuttin' the
Line neither!
Now step to the end of the line!
Hello.
May I help you?
We'd like to go inside,
Please.
Name?
I'm Dorothy, and this is
Tinman, and scarecrow and lion.
Sorry.
Not on the list.
Move along.
But we've got to get inside.
And when did that become my
Problem?
Either your name's on my list or
It's not.
Now adios, amigos.
Excuse me, my brother.
That's a lady you're talking to.
And what are you gonna do
About it?
I was just makin' sure you
Knew she was a lady.
Peace out.
Look here, we've come on very
Important business.
There must be some way for us to
Get inside.
Oh, there's several ways.
Your name could be on the list.
You could be famous.
You could grease my palm with a
Sizable donation to my
Retirement fund...
Or you could be connected, know
Somebody important.
I know addaperle.
Come on, you don't know no
Addaperle.
I most certainly do.
In fact, after I killed the
Wicked witch of the east, she's
The one who gave me these
Magical, enchanted slippers.
Excuse me, but did you just
Say addaperle?
Wicked witch?
And enchanted slippers?
Girl, you hit the trifecta!
Welcome to the emerald city!
**
Did you ever imagine anything
Like this?
Excuse me.
Can you tell me where to find
The wiz?
What did you say?
The wiz.
He lives around here, right?
What'd she say?
If I didn't know better, I'd
Say she asked where to find the
Wiz.
Why the shade?
The young lady asked a perfectly
Normal question.
**
I don't know what none of
That means.
Excuse me, brother.
We just came...
We need the wiz.
Oh, my.
**
T'ain't nothin' normal about
Wantin' to see the wiz.
Nobody sees the wiz.
Not nobody.
They say he's terrible to
Behold.
He's got the head of a
Fire-breathing dragon.
And the overpowering body of
An elephant.
With wings!
And razor sharp claws that
Can shred a man like tissue
Paper!
I'd hate to imagine what
They'd do to a little girl.
Heard enough.
Who wants to catch a movie
Before we split town?
I hope they don't put butter on
Their popcorn.
I've gotta watch my cholesterol.
But you've never seen him
Yourself?
Nobody has.
Not never.
He's been locked inside that
Throne room since he got here.
Believe me, miss, you don't
Want to go in there.
But we've traveled such a...
You don't want to go in
There!
But unless we see him we...
You don't want to go in
There!
Yes, we do!
Don't we?
We don't want to go in there.
See that right there?
It's a door.
Just a door.
But on the other side of that
Door is everything you've ever
Wanted.
So, are we going through that
Door or not?
[Screams]
Ah!
Look!
Look there!
Are those?
They couldn't be.
Could they?
Pardon, miss, but would you
Mind telling me where you got
Them shiny shoes?
Oh, these old things?
Addaperle laid them on me after
I dropped a house on evvamean.
After you...
My bad.
Go on, miss.
The door ain't locked.
And do give the wiz my best
Regards.
Ooh, snap!
Well, go on.
Why I gotta go on?
You're the only one of us
Wearin' armor.
We'll all go together.
You!
Stop right where you are!
I'm stopped.
I am stopped.
Don't gotta tell me twice.
Who dares disturb my
Meditations?
The man asked a question.
Answer.
I'm sorry if we disturbed
You, but we just want to meet
The wiz.
You want to meet the wiz?
Yes, sir.
If it wouldn't be too much
Trouble.
Child, you don't know what
Trouble is!
* so you wanted to meet? The
Wizard
Let me tell you that you've come
To the right place *
* shall I make you a frog or
Lizard?
You should see the strange
Expression on your face *
* if the way I come on is
Frightening
That's the way I felt like
Coming on today *
* have you ever been kissed by
Lightning?
Let me tell you
That will make you go away *
* I fly, and the magic of my
Power
Takes me higher *
* to a level where the clouds
Turn into fire *
* in the warmness of the fire
I feel fine *
* just keep your eyes open
And the magic you will see *
* it will whistle on the wind
As it emanates from me *
* it's a strong and true
Vibration
You can feel it on your skin *
Now come and take my hand
And we will dance upon the
Wind *
* so you wanted to meet the
Wizard *
**
Is it over?
Can I open my eyes?
They are open.
Oh, no.
I'm blind?
No.
The lights are out!
Silence!
Who dares disturb my sanctuary?
Who dares disturb my peace?
He does!
Silence!
Why have you come?
It was her idea.
I just wanted to see the world.
Dorothy told me that you
Could...
Silence!
Why he ask questions then
Tells us to shut up?
One at a time!
You!
Lion!
What do you want?
To get the hell out of here!
Tell him.
Well, sir wiz, sir, I was
Thinkin', if you happened to
Have an extra spell you weren't
Using just lyin' around.
Spit it out!
Courage!
I would like some courage,
Please.
You tellin' me that the king
Of
The jungle is a coward?
Only when I'm awake.
Or asleep.
Sometimes I have these dreams...
Silence!
And you, straw man.
You lookin' for courage, too?
Me?
Nah.
I ain't got enough sense to be
Scared of nothin'.
Is that so?
Except for fire!
Fire!
Scared of fire!
Would you mind?
Thank you.
Now, your green-ness, what I
Would like is a brain.
What for?
Ain't nobody ever tell you,
"Ignorance is bliss"?
Not that I remember.
And you, little girl.
What do you want?
Hello.
My name is Dorothy and I would
Like to go home.
So, who's stopping you?
Well, sir, I don't rightly
Know how.
See, I was heading from my aunt
Em's farm in Kansas to Omaha,
Where I was born, when this
Storm blew up and...
Where'd you say you were
Born?
Omaha, Nebraska.
And where's the auntie's
Farm?
Kansas.
So, which one's your home?
Well, I could've swore I
Knew.
Well, if you don't know where
You're goin', how am I expected
To get you there?
Step back!
And you, rin-tin-tin, what are
You looking for?
A can opener?
That's very clever.
You are clever.
Scary as hell, but clever.
You think I got time to mess
With fools?
Tell me what you want, what you
Really, really want!
A heart.
A heart, your wizness.
You tellin' me you're
Heartless?
I'm afraid so.
Then count yourself lucky!
Think of what you're avoiding,
Heartburn, heartache, and the
Occasional heartbreak of
Psoriasis.
Oh, but sir, think about
Everything else I'm missing.
* whoa, whoa, whoa
What would I do
If I could suddenly feel *
* and know once again
What I feel is real *
* I could cry, I could smile
And I might lay back for a
While *
* tell me what
What would I do *
* if I could feel
* if I could reach inside of me
And know how it feels
To say I like what I see *
* then I'd be more than glad to
Share
All that I have inside of here *
* and the songs my heart might
Bring
You'd be more than glad to
Sing *
* and if a tear came to my eye
Think of all the wounds they
Mend *
* and just to think
The time I could spend
Being vulnerable again *
* tell me what
What, what would I do *
* woah, tell me what
* what I would do, if I could
Feel
If I could feel *
* if I could feel
**
I, the all powerful wiz, have
Decided to grant your wishes,
But...
Hey!
I said but!
Did you not hear me say "but?"
There's a but coming.
There always is.
But I want a little something
In return.
I will grant all four of your
Wishes, but first you gotta kill
The wicked witch of the west.
Kill the wicked witch?
Ain't no big thing.
You already wasted her sister.
How'd he know about that?
I am the all-seeing,
All-knowing, all-powerful wizard
Of oz.
I know stuff!
You want what you want?
No half stepping.
Kill me that witch!
I have spoken!
Why don't you kill her
Yourself?
You don't think I could?
And I would, except I've got to
Stay here and protect the
Emerald city.
From who?
From the wicked witch of the
West!
Are you not paying attention?
But what's any of that got to
Do with me?
What do you mean?
It's all your fault.
Everything was fine when there
Was a witch for every corner of
Oz.
But then you come along dropping
Houses where they don't belong
And suddenly there's a whole
Territory up for grabs.
Right now evillene is plotting a
Take-over of oz.
She must be stopped.
And you're the one needs to do
It.
Why me?
'Cause I said so, and I am
The all knowing, all powerful
Wiz and I have spoken!
Well, Dorothy.
Good luck.
We're all counting on you.
Me?
The wiz was loud and clear,
This whole mess is your fault.
My fault?
Your tornado.
Your house.
Your fault!
You broke it.
You bought it.
So, good luck killing that
Old
Witch.
Be sure to let us know when it's
Done.
We'll be waitin' in the bar.
Isn't that just typical?
All three of you were fine
Coming along when you thought
You were gettin' something for
Nothing, but now that there's a
Price to pay you want to wait it
Out in the bar?
Cowards!
You calling me a coward?
Yes!
Yes, I'm a coward.
Hasn't that been established?
And I'm sorry, Dorothy, but
You know what my last run-in
With that witch done to me.
And I don't know how to help
You because I don't know how to
Kill a witch because I don't
Know anything!
Y'all!
I thought you were my squad, now
Y'all are wimping out on me?
Lion, courage!
If evillene needs to go, we're
Sending her out together.
Says you!
* I'm not doing this
Even I know it don't make no
Sense *
* breaking a heart got me this
Way
I ain't in a rush to see that
Again *
* just thinkin' 'bout it is
Terrifyin'
Oh you ain't gonna give up on me
Now
I won't let you turn around *
* this won't be easy, no way no
How
But we won't back down *
* when the night is so cold,
Dark and lonely
All you gotta do is look at me *
* and hear what I say
We got it
We got it *
* and I got you
I got you *
* so we got it
We got it *
Together we do *
* so close yet so far
I can see our dreams from
Standing
Right where we are *
* only thing that's in our way
Are these impossible odds *
* I'm terrified this is just way
Too hard
And what if I fail *
* how do you fly
Knowing there's a good chance
We'll fall from the sky *
* what were we thinking
Why do we even try *
* that's what we get
With letting our hopes get too
High *
* I can't believe what I'm
Hearing
Get a hold of yourself *
* woah you ain't gonna give up
On me now
I won't let you turn around *
* this won't be easy
No way no how
But we won't back down *
* when the night is so cold dark
And lonely
All you gotta do is look at me *
* and hear what I say
We got it
We got it *
* and I got you
I got you *
* so we got it
We got it *
Together we do
* ain't nobody givin' us nothin'
If we want it there's just no
Other way *
* I'll be right here come what
May
Together we'll be okay *
* said if you know that I got
You
There's nothing we can't do *
* oh no, oh no
Our dreams are waiting for us
Let's go *
* we ain 't gonna give up on
This now
We refuse to turn around *
* this won't be easy, no way no
How
But we won't back down *
* when the night is so cold dark
And lonely
All you gotta do is look at me *
* and hear what I say
We got it
We got it *
* and I got you
So we got it *
* so we got it
Together we do *
* I can conquer a Mountain
* swim the deepest sea
Together we do *
* there ain't nothin' I can't do
Long as you're with me *
* together, together
Oh yeah, oh yeah *
Together we do *
**
Gerald!
Over here.
I was worried you wouldn't
Make it back.
Why is everybody sneaking
Around?
This here is your factory.
Not since the wicked witch of
The east got demolished.
Her sister, wicked old evillene,
Has declared a corporate
Take-over.
A what?
This side of oz now belongs
To the united witch workers of
The a.F.L-ee-aye-ee-aye-o.
Everything is hers now.
Even the winkies?
Especially the winkies.
Here she comes.
You brought her today's news
Like she asked?
I brung it, but she ain't
Gonna like it.
Make way!
Make way for the wicked witch of
The west!
All hail, evillene!
Hail, hail, evillene.
All hail the wicked witch of
The west.
Hail, hail, evillene.
And all hail right back
Atcha!
Lord high underling?
Yes, your misery?
What's that there?
What's what where?
That there there.
What's that that there?
That there there?
Yes!
That that there!
What's that there there there?
Oh, that there there?
That there there there is
Nothin' but a drop of water.
Nothin' but a drop of...
Do you know what happens if a
Drop a water is left to it's own
Devices?
It dries up and goes away?
You there!
Walk on by that seemingly
Innocent drop of water.
And a killer flood strikes
Again!
Lord high underling, I demand to
Know where it come from?
There seems to be a small
Leak from that pipe up there.
Well, run and fetch the royal
Plumber.
And kill him!
I hate water!
Yes, your eviltude.
And is that my news?
It is.
And when were you planning on
Letting me have it?
Your evilness, I'd be happy
To let you have it anytime.
Oh, you bein' funny?
You some kind of Eddie Murphy or
Something?
Well, don't try me 'cause I am
Evil with all y'all today.
* now, when I wake up in the
Afternoon
Which it pleases me to do
Don't nobody bring me no bad
News *
* 'cause I wake up already
Negative
And I've wired up my fuse
So, don't nobody bring me no bad
News *
* oh, if we're gonna be buddies
You better bone up on the
Rules *
* 'cause don't nobody bring me
No bad news *
* you can be my best of friend
As opposed to payin' dues *
* 'cause don't nobody bring me
No bad news *
* well, no bad news
* now, don't you ever bring me
No bad news*
* 'cause I'll make you an offer,
Child
That you cannot refuse *
* so, don't nobody bring me
No bad news *
* now, when you're talkin' to me
Don't be cryin' the blues *
* don't you ever bring me
No bad news *
* you can verbalize, vocalize
But just bring me the clues *
* but don't nobody bring me
No bad news *
* bring the message in your head
Or in something you can't lose *
* but don't you ever, ever bring
Me
No bad news *
* if you're gonna bring me
Something
Ah, make it something I can
Use *
* but don't you bring me
No bad news *
* oh, no bad news
* now, don't you bring me
No bad news *
* 'cause I'll make you an offer,
Child
That you cannot refuse *
* so, don't you bring me
No bad news *
What are you doing?
Get up from there!
Higher, higher!
Work!
What are you doing?
**
* oh, don't nobody bring me
No bad news *
* if you're gonna bring me
Something
Now, bring me something I can
Use *
* but don't you ever bring me
No bad news *
* 'cause I'll make you an offer,
Child
That you cannot refuse *
* so, don't nobody bring me
No bad news *
* I said, don't nobody bring me
* don't you bring me
Don't you bring me *
No, no, no *
* bad news *
**
'Cause I ain't goin' for it!
Now get back to work!
Now, break it down.
Well, I'm afraid it's bad
News.
Dorothy and her friends are on
Their way here to kill you.
That's not such bad news.
It's not nice news.
But it's not terrible.
I mean, if you're gonna be a
Wicked witch, and you are good
At your job, you're gonna have
To expect to rub some folks the
Wrong way.
I s'pose.
So, Dorothy thinks she can
March her skinny ass in here and
Destroy me?
Well, it ain't my first time
Runnin' the nursery.
I know how to handle a brat like
That.
Unleash my winged warriors!
Not your winged warriors.
Oh, yes, my winged warriors.
Fly!
Fly, my warriors!
Capture the intruders and bring
Them back to me.
Now fly!
Fly!
And don't nobody scuff up my
Sister's shoes!
**
You!
Another bucket here.
And one over there.
If evillene finds water on the
Floor...
Back it up, top cat.
Are those buckets full?
If I get that last one will
That make you happy?
I think you left a spot.
If I get it, will you be
Satisfied then?
Satisfied?
Me?
Right.
Dorothy!
Oh, lion.
That old witch has me scrubbing
And polishing.
I will never complain about any
Chore aunt em gives me ever
Again.
I'm on mop duty.
That old witch is definitely
Afraid of water.
They say she don't even bathe.
She sends herself out once a
Week for dry cleaning.
Excuse me, my lord high
Underling, but did you hear me
Give anybody a coffee break?
No, ma'am.
Not during my lifetime.
Oh, please, Ms. witch.
We haven't seen each other...
Ask me if I care?
Back to work!
No wonder they call you
Wicked.
No.
Know what?
You don't got game enough to be
Wicked.
All you are is plain old
Everyday passable mean.
Well, if I'm mean... what
Does that make you?
Don't make me nothing.
Think not?
Which one of us dropped a house
On the other one's sister?
And which one of us yanked the
Silver heels right off of that
Dead sister's not-even-cold-yet
Feet?
And which one of us gathered up
A crew to put a hit on the other
One?
You're three for three, little
Girl, so before you go castin'
Shade, I'd take myself a good
Look in the mirror.
Now... get back to work.
When are you going to let us
Go?
When you gonna give me them
Kicks?
I promised addaperle...
"I promised addaperle..."
This child still thinks I'm
Playin'?
Lord high underling, send in my
Dinner!
Tell, oh, lord high, what's on
My menu for tonight?
Forest lion stew!
It's a new recipe from
"Witches wear nightly."
This old tin can will make a
Fine stew pot once I pop the top
Off it.
And this useless bag of hay will
Start a good strong fire.
But first...
I got me a lion to filet!
Get away from my friends you
Evil old witch!
Dorothy, always so brave.
You want to be a hero?
You'll be dinner too.
Oh, no, not water!
No!
What have you done?
You've destroyed me.
Stupid girl!
You've destroyed me!
She's dead!
Oh, lord.
Looks like I did it again!
**
You've killed the wicked
Witch of the west and now we're
Free!
Thanks to you, we're free!
**
* everybody look around
'Cause there's a reason
To rejoice you see
Everybody come out *
* and let's commence
To singing joyfully
Everybody look up
And find the hope *
* that we've been waiting
On everybody is glad
Because our silent fear
And dread is gone *
* freedom, you see
Has got our hearts singing
So joyfully *
* just look about
You owe it to yourself
To check it out *
* can't you feel a
Brand new day
Can't you feel a
Brand new day *
* can't you feel a
Brand new day
Can't you feel a
Brand new day *
* everybody be glad
Because the sun is shining
Just for us
Everybody wake up *
* into the morning
Into happiness
Hello world
It's like a different *
* way of living now
Thank you, world
We always knew
That we'd be free somehow *
* in harmony
Let's show the world
That we've got liberty
It's such a change *
* for us to live
So independently
Freedom, you see
Has got our hearts singing *
* so joyfully
Just look about
You owe it to yourself
To check it out *
* can't you feel a
Brand new day
Can't you feel a
Brand new day *
* can't you feel a
Brand new day
Can't you feel a
Brand new day *
**
* everybody be glad
Because the sun is shining
Just for us
Everybody wake up *
* into the morning
Into happiness
Hello, world
It's like a different *
* way of living now
And thank you, world *
* we always knew
That we'd be free somehow
In harmony
Let's show the world *
* that we've got liberty
Its' such a change
For us to live
So independently *
* freedom, you see
Has got out hearts singing
So joyfully
Just look about *
* you owe it to yourself
To check it out *
* can't you feel a
Brand new day
Can't you feel a
Brand new day *
* can't you feel a
Brand new day
Can't you feel a
Brand new day *
* can't you feel a
Brand new day
Can't you feel a
Brand new day *
* feel a brand new day
Oh, no you don't.
No cutting in front.
Go to the end of the line.
Respect, my brother.
We are back to see the wiz.
And before you go tellin' us our
Names are not on the list, allow
Me to elucidate current events.
Dorothy just killed the wicked
Witch of the west.
For those of you keeping score,
That's two wicked witches in two
Days.
So I dare say there ain't a list
Anywhere in oz without our names
On it.
Allow me to apologize.
You sure are on the list.
Right here at the top of the
Page.
"Dorothy, lion, scarecrow and"
Tinman are hereby and forthwith
Legally and terminally banned
From entering the emerald city
By executive order of the wiz.
No exceptions.
No excuses.
"No refunds."
Banned?
Banned!
As in...
Personae non-gracious.
Now, back up and let the other
Folks through.
There are no other folks!
It's no use.
We can't get in.
We'll have to find someplace
Else to spend the night.
Yeah.
I guess you're right.
But what are we going to do
With that big bag of gold that
We got from the wicked witch?
Big bag of gold?
Oh!
The big bag of gold!
Yes.
The big bag of gold is way too
Heavy to carry around all night.
That's no problem.
I dug a hole in the ground
Around the corner and hid the
Gold in there.
Are you sure it will be safe?
Now who would go lookin' for
A big bag of gold in a little
Hole around the corner?
Terrific.
Let's go find a safe place to
Spend the night.
After you, my dear.
Ladies first.
Scarecrow, you are a genius.
There's nothing like greed to
Turn a wise man into a fool.
Mr. wiz?
Mr. wiz, sir?
We're back.
I don't think anyone's here.
He's here all right.
I can smell him.
Hello?
Mr. wiz?
Huh?
Um, who goes there?
It's Dorothy, sir.
We took care of things like you
Told us.
The wicked witch of the west is
Done in.
Eliminated.
One might even say
Liquidated.
So, what do you want from me?
Just what you promised.
I promised nothing.
Oh, you certainly did.
Can't say I recall.
Begone.
What happened?
Lion pulled the plug.
I knew I smelled a rat!
Is that the the wiz?
I am the all powerful, all
Knowing, all seeing, all for
Nothin'...
All for nothing.
Hello.
You don't mean...
Couldn't be...
You mean the wiz is...
A fraud!
And a woman!
And what's wrong with being a
Woman?
Nothing.
That's right, nothing wrong
With bein' a woman!
Don't know where you fools
Learned your manners.
But there's everything wrong
With lying!
Who you calling a liar?
Oh.
Right.
Me.
I'm nothin' but a huckster from
Omaha.
Omaha?
Howdy, neighbor.
But how'd you get here?
Oh, little girl, the places
You wind up when you don't look
Where you're going.
Back in Omaha I had me a job as
A magician's assistant.
"The amazing Alfred & company."
I was "and company."
We'd do magic at night but
During the day we gave folks
Rides in a hot air balloon.
That was the part I liked.
I loved flying.
But unfortunately, I hated
Alfred.
Well, one day he just pushed me
Too far.
I hopped into that hot air
Balloon and took off for the
Sky.
Oh.
I wasn't planning to
Disappear.
I just wanted to teach mean old
Alfred a lesson.
But out of nowhere came a storm
With winds and rain so strong it
Was all I could do to stay in
That thing.
I hunkered down and hid my eyes
For what felt like forever, and
When I landed, here I was.
Folks came rushing from every
Which way to see what had blown
In on the wind.
Not wanting to disappoint
Nobody, I quick put on old
Alfred's black top hat and cape
And did my best to give the
Folks a magic show.
Next thing I knew they slapped
Fancy threads on me, set me up
In these digs and proclaimed me
The all powerful wizard of oz.
Couldn't you tell someone the
Truth?
I tried. But they were so
Happy to have a wizard they
Thought could protect them from
Evillene and evvamean they
Wouldn't hear it.
So here I am, all these years
Later, hiding in the dark lest
Anyone find out what a nothing I
Really am.
We been played.
That's wack, gettin' our
Hopes up.
I never thought you'd be
Brave enough to take on old
Evillene.
Well we did.
Exactly.
Now listen up.
You don't need nothin' from me.
None of you.
Lion, you say you got no
Courage, but you were part of
The team that took out the
Wickedest witch that ever was.
Shakin' the whole time.
Being scared of scary stuff
Is smart.
Respecting danger but still
Takin' care of business?
Ace, that's courage!
What'd'ya know?
I got courage.
And scarecrow, you say you
Got no brain?
The surest sign that you're
Talking to a dummy is when he
Tells you he knows it all.
It takes a quality mind to know
That there's always more to
Learn.
You, my friend, are of that
Brainiac persuasion.
So, knowing that I know
Nothing proves I know something?
What do you know?
And you, tinman.
No heart?
You haven't left Dorothy's side
Since you got here.
If the way you protect her isn't
Proof of a good heart, then I
Don't know what is.
Oh, I know I have a heart
Because, just thinking about
Dorothy leaving, has it
Breaking.
Don't start getting all
Rusted up again.
Besides, I'm not going anywhere,
Am I, miss wiz?
Home is a place.
No fancy words are going to get
Me there.
I'm sorry to say the little
Sister's right.
Excuse me, but didn't you say
You've got a balloon?
The balloon?
Surely
You're not suggesting...
Why not?
And leave all this?
I got a title.
I got a throne room.
I got folks so scared of me they
Dare not knock on my door.
Now that's a great way to
Live.
Locked inside a fancy prison
Lest somebody figure out who you
Really are.
Let her be.
She got a right to choose the
Way she wants to live.
Maybe she don't want no friends
Or family.
Maybe she don't care about the
Wonderful world just beyond
Those doors.
Yeah.
Maybe she don't miss
Conversatin' or sharing a laugh.
Maybe she don't need to feel a
Warm hug or a friendly handshake
Or a loving kiss ever again.
Yeah.
Maybe she wants to be stuck
In this room, alone in the dark,
'Til the end of her days.
Layin' it on a little thick?
All right.
You made your point.
I've had a nice vacation, maybe
It's time to get back to the
Real world.
So, who needs a lift to
Omaha?
Me.
Oh, please, me.
Citizens of oz.
There is a time to every purpose
Under heaven.
A time to keep.
And a time to cast away.
Sadly, I'll admit, now is the
Time to split.
Friends, it is not enough to
Know where you are going.
You also need to know where you
Are coming from.
Today, I go forward to go back.
But before I do, let me leave
You with this...
**
* I got to leave
So I've packed my bag
And I'm goin'
I got a date *
* so don't you ask me to stay
'Cause I'm showin'
You were always ready
For new wizardry *
* you must have thought
That miracles came easy to me
Take what I give you
And put it up on a shelf *
* 'cause now it's time
For this here wiz
To wiz on herself
And I'm wizin' *
* give me a reason
Why I should stay
And I'll judge it
My mind is made up *
* so nothin' you say's
Gonna budge it
Y 'all copped a whole lot of
Magic from me *
* but this the greatest magic
That you'll ever see
If you blink more than
One time *
* the kid will be gone
And you will have to hook up
The rest on your own
And do you know *
* what I think about that
Your work's cut out for you
It's not about
Ifs, buts or ands *
* 'cause when I leave
This town
I'm leaving it all in
Your hands *
* I packed all my clothes
And I packed up my power
I'm leavin' this place *
* in less than
One half an hour
If you look up in the sky
You'll know just who it is *
* it's not a bird or a plane
It's just a little ole wiz
And guess who's on
After that *
* y'all got it
Y'all got it
Talkin' 'bout leavin' here *
* y'all got it
Y'all got it
Talkin' 'bout leavin' here *
* y'all got it
Y'all got it
Y'all got it *
* y'all got it
Y'all got it
Y'all got it *
* y'all got it
Y'all got it!
And now, Dorothy, it's time to
Fly!
Dorothy!
Quick!
No.
Wait!
I don't belong in Omaha.
What?
Dorothy, hurry!
No.
Go on, miss wiz.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
Goodbye.
But, Dorothy, that was your
Ride home.
That's what I thought, but I
Couldn't have been more wrong.
Addaperle!
Dorothy Gale, what are you
Still doing here?
You joined the circus?
These are my friends.
You figured it out, didn't
You?
I think so.
Omaha was the place I was born.
But my home, the place I belong,
Is with aunt em in Kansas.
Is that right?
Good girl.
Home isn't where you live.
It's where you love.
I'm so proud of you.
Does that mean I can go back
Now?
Can you take me, please?
Me?
Oh, no, no, no.
Out of my juris-prudence.
But I may know someone who can.
Oh, she's beautiful!
Did I lie?
Dorothy, this is my sister
Glinda, the good witch of the
South.
Hello, Dorothy.
A pleasure to see you up close
Instead of from far away.
From far away?
I've had my eye on you every
Step of the way.
I think I already knew that.
I always felt someone watching
Over me.
That's the power of love,
Baby.
You are never alone.
Your aunt em and so many others
Are keepin' watch on you.
I'm really tired.
Would it be all right if I went
Back home now?
You've had the power to go
Home anytime.
Addaperle, why didn't you tell
The child?
I thought maybe she'd like to
Meet you first.
It's these shoes, right?
They have the magic to send me
Home.
No, darling.
The magic is inside you.
The magic's in you.
**
* if you believe
Within your heart you'll know
That no one can change
The path you must go *
* believe what you feel
And know you're right
Because the time will
Come around *
* when you say it's yours
Believe that you can go home
Believe you can float
On air *
* then click your heels
Three times
If you believe, oh
Then you'll be there *
* believe in yourself
Right from the start
Believe in the magic
Right there in your heart *
* believe all these things
Not because I told you to
But believe in yourself
Believe in yourself *
* believe in yourself
As I believe in you *
Thank you.
Remember... click your heels
Together three times and think
Of home.
Come along, addaperle.
We got a lot of catching up to
Do.
Goodbye, Dorothy.
Goodbye, addaperle.
Thank you, glinda.
Goodbye.
Could that be all there is to
It?
You just click your heels
Together three times and you're
Home?
It makes no sense, so it must
Be so.
The truth is like that.
But if you'd known before you
Wouldn't have had to battle
Evillene or argue with the wiz
Or even meet me.
Or me.
Oh, I wouldn't have missed
Meeting you for anything.
Promise that you'll remember me.
Keep me in your heart.
And let me, now and then, come
To mind.
And maybe, just maybe, if I hang
On to these shoes, they'll
Lead me back to you someday.
Oh, please try.
I will.
But right now, I think I hear
Aunt em calling.
**
* when I think of home
I think of a place
Where there's love
Overflowing *
* I wish I was home
I wish I was back there
With the things I've been
Knowing *
* wind that makes the
Tall grass
Bend into leaning *
* suddenly the raindrops
That fall
Have a meaning *
* sprinkling the scene
Makes it all clean
Maybe there's a chance *
* for me to go back
Now that I have some direction
It sure would be nice to be
Back home *
* where there's love and
Affection
And just maybe I can
Convince time *
* to slow up
Giving me enough time
In my life
To grow up *
* time, be my friend
Let me start again
Suddenly my world's gone
And changed its face *
* but still I know where
I'm going
I have had my mind
Spun around in space *
* and yet I've watched it
Growing
And if you're listening God
Please don't make it *
* hard to know
If we should believe
The things we see *
* tell us
Would we try and stay
Or should we run away
Or is it better *
* just to let things be
Living here in this
Brand new world
Might be a fantasy *
* but it's taught me to love
So it's real to me
And I learned that we must
Look inside our hearts *
* to find a world
Full of love *
* like yours
Like mine
Like home **
Toto, aunt em!