It was the nicest little
whorehouse you ever saw.
It lay about a mile
outside the city limits,
so everybody could
feel real friendly.
Sheriff Jack Roy Wallace picked it
out for Miss Wulla Jean in 1910,
and she moved there
with her girls from over
the hardware
store on Main Street.
MEN: ♪ Oh, the little house lay
♪ In a green Texas glade
♪ Where the trees
were as coolin'
♪ As fresh lemonade
♪ Soft summer wind
♪ Had a trace of perfume
♪ And a fan was turnin'
♪ In every room
♪ 20 fans were turnin'
They were turnin'
♪ 20 fans were
turnin' in every room
♪ Fevers were a-burnin'
They were burnin'
♪ And they had to
have a way to cool down ♪
(PIANOLA PLAYING RAGTIME MUSIC)
FRED". Right from the beginning,
the little house
was kinda special,
like a home away from home.
Miss Wulla Jean
put a pianola in the
parlor to sorta
help break the ice.
A feller could
ask a girl to dance,
or if he held back a little,
she'd ask him.
And pretty soon they'd
get a little business goin'.
Two dollars' worth.
Yah-hoo!
FRED: It wasn't long
before the place became
one of the better known pleasure
palaces in all of Texas.
So much so that the fellers who
visited during World War I
sent their sons
back in World War ll.
The hospitality and
friendliness never changed,
and neither did Miss Wulla
Jean's strict set of rules.
She liked her ladies,
as she called 'em,
to treat her
customers real good,
but never in an unladylike way.
And she insisted that each girl
check her gentleman for the clap
and wash him off with
soap and warm water.
Some of the fellers claimed
that that was the best part!
Ooh-ee!
FRED: It was only during
the Hoover depression
that the little house
had a spell of tough times.
Miss Wulla Jean put in a
jukebox to spark up business.
But it wasn't always easy in them
days to come up with hard cash.
(CLUCKING)
Well... You just
keep that in the bag,
and I'll take it out back
as soon as we're finished.
FRED: So fora while,
as the story goes,
the girls began
accepting poultry in trade.
One bird, one lay.
And that's how
the place got its name.
The Chicken Ranch.
Of course, if you grew
up anywhere in Texas,
you knew at an early age they was
sellin' somethin' out there,
and it wasn't poultry.
♪ 20 fans were turnin'
They were turnin'
♪ 20 fans were
turnin' in every room
♪ Fevers were a-burnin'
They were burnin'
♪ And they had to
have a way to cool down
♪ 20 fans were hummin'
They were hummin'
♪ 20 fans were
hummin' in every room
♪ Customers were comin'
They were comin'
♪ And they had to
have a way to cool down ♪
(WHOOPING)
♪ Bah, bah, ooh. Ooh
♪ 20 fans were turnin'
They were turnin'
♪ 20 fans were
turnin' in every room
♪ Fevers were a-burnin'
They were burnin'
♪ And they had to
have a way to cool down
♪ 20 fans were hummin'
They were hummin'
♪ 20 fans were
hummin' in every room
♪ Customers were comin'
They were comin'
♪ And they had to
have a way to cool down ♪
Y'all come back now, you hear?
Yah-hoo!
♪ 20 fans were turnin'
They were turnin'
♪ 20 fans were
turnin' in every room
♪ Fevers were a-burnin'
They were burnin'
♪ And they had to
have a way to cool down
♪ 20 fans were turnin'
They were turnin'
♪ 20 fans were
turnin' in every room
♪ Fevers were a-burnin'
They were burnin'
♪ And they had to
have a way to cool down
♪ Hallelujah. Hallelujah ♪
FRED: So,
for over three generations,
the Chicken Ranch went
peacefully about its business,
while the people here in
Gilbert went about theirs.
That is,
until about seven years ago.
I was a deputy back then,
workin' for
Sheriff Ed Earl Dodd.
You wanted me to remind you
about your 2:00 appointment.
FRED".
That was right after I had
lost the fried chicken
franchise here in town,
while Ed Earl had
been Sheriff ever
since old Jack
Roy Wallace retired.
Everybody liked Ed Earl,
especially Ed Earl.
Course,
he sure did know his job,
and he was a big
influence on me,
taught me everything I know.
He used to like to
run a quiet town,
with plenty of time
off for socializin'
and coffee over at
Dulcie Mae's cafe.
Oh, now and again
there'd be a problem,
and we had some tough ones.
Right in front of my car!
Like the time the mule
sat on Miss Modene's car.
MODENE: He just buckled up
his legs and sat right down!
FRED: She was really
havin' a hissy fit,
but it didn't faze Ed Earl.
He just walked over to that
jackass and laid down the law.
You see, Ed Earl always
believed in talkin' first.
Cool reasonin', he used to tell
me, could solve any problem.
Course he did have
a bit of a temper.
(GUNSHOTS) (SHRIEKS)
(BRAYING)
FRED: Anyway, just about
the time he became sheriff,
Miss Wulla Jean passed on.
She left the Chicken Ranch to her
favorite workin' girl, Mona Stangley,
who saw the little house
as a Texas institution
and aimed to keep it that way.
(PIANO PLAYING)
♪ It's just a
♪ Little bitty
pissant country place
♪ Ain't nothin' much to see
♪ No drinkin' allowed
♪ We get a nice, quiet crowd
♪ Plain as it can be
♪ It's just a piddly, squattin'
♪ Old-time country place
♪ Ain't nothin' too high-toned
♪ Just lots of goodwill
♪ And maybe one small thrill
♪ But there's
nothin' dirty goin' on
♪ Nothin' dirty goin' on
♪ We get simple farmers
Local businessmen
♪ Congress folks from Austin
Young boys lookin' for sin
♪ Now, we used to
get a lot of roughnecks
♪ When the oil boom was high
♪ But payday'd
get a little rowdy
♪ Thank God the field run dry
♪ It's just a little
bitty pissant country place
♪ Nothin' much to see
♪ No drinkin' allowed
We get a nice, quiet crowd
♪ Plain as it can be
♪ It's just a piddly, squattin'
old-time country place
♪ Nothin' too high-toned
♪ Just lots of goodwill
and maybe one small thrill
♪ But there's
nothin' dirty goin' on
♪ Keep your
language clean, girls
♪ Keep your bedrooms neat
♪ And don't hang
around the town cafe
♪ And say hi on the street
♪ Mind your p's
and q's and manners
♪ And you don't
need no other tools
♪ 'Cause every girl that lives
here knows my special no-no rules
♪ Yeah, every girl
that lives here
♪ knows Miss Mon♪s no-no rules ♪
Ruby Rae, start 'em.
♪ Beds are not to be wallowed in
♪ That's the kind of thing
that big, fat, lazy hogs do ♪
And it don't make money.
Beatrice?
♪ And I won't
tolerate no tyin' up my
♪ telephone with other
people's business ♪
Eloise, honey?
♪ And please don't
show us no tattoos
♪ No hearts and
flowers on your thigh ♪
It's downright tacky.
♪ Brands belong on cattle
♪ And that ain't what we're
sellin' at Miss Mon♪s r
Do you catch my drift?
♪ I pay the food and
the rent and the utilities
♪ You keep your mind on
your work responsibilities
♪ Don't let your mouth
overload your capabilities
♪ And we can get along ♪
Dawn?
♪ Any bad habits you come in
with Get rid of right now ♪
Taddy Jo.
♪ I can't stand no chewin' gum
It looks just like a cow ♪
Linda Lou.
♪ Anyone takin' sick leave
oughta be real sure they're sick
♪ And every time
you hear that bell ♪
(RINGING)
♪ You better get
here double-quick
♪ And as for pimps. Pimps are
somethin' you don't need
♪ To get your
daily business done ♪
Are you listenin' good?
♪ Keep them
leeches and bloodsuckers
♪ Off the back roads
I know how to use a gun
♪ And nobody
messes with my girls
♪ And any questions you might have
about the way I run this place
♪ Don't gripe and
whine behind my back
♪ Just tell me face-to-face
I'm open-minded
♪ Say it all
Then go upstairs and pack
♪ The door's that away
♪ She pays the food and
the rent and the utilities
♪ We keep our mind on
our work responsibilities
♪ Don't let your mouth
overload your capabilities
♪ And we can get along ♪
Well, howdy, boys.
It's good to see you.
Nice to meet you.
Come on over here.
I'd like you to meet my girls.
♪ It's just a
♪ Little bitty
pissant country place
♪ Nothin' much to see
♪ No drinkin' allowed
We get a nice quiet crowd
♪ Plain as it can be
♪ It's just a piddly, squattin'
old-time country place
♪ Nothin' too high-toned
♪ Just lots of goodwill
and maybe one small thrill
♪ But there's
nothin' dirty goin' on
♪ It's just a little
bitty pissant country place
♪ Nothin' much to see
♪ No drinkin' allowed
We get a nice quiet crowd
♪ Plain as it can be
♪ It's just a piddly, squattin'
old-time country place
♪ Nothin' too high-toned
♪ Just lots of goodwill
and maybe one small thrill
♪ But there's
nothin' dirty goin' on
♪ Nothin' dirty goin' on
♪ Yeah ♪
(CROWS)
FRED". Well, everything was goin'
along fine, just like always,
until that famous
college football celebration.
Some folks think that that's
when the trouble started.
You see, for years,
the winning seniors
of the Texas Aggies-Texas U
football game at Thanksgiving,
they were treated to a night
out at the Chicken Ranch
by their alumni association.
But actually,
the real trouble started
brewin' about three days before.
(CHUCKLES) I can't tell you how
thrilled we are with your contribution.
Here's your receipt.
Thank you, Rita.
Those kids'll be so excited,
and the mayor, too.
Why, the town council will
probably vote you another plaque.
Lord, I hope not. I got
a closet full of 'em now.
(LAUGHS) Hello, Dulcie Mae.
You know Miss Mona.
Oh, yes, of course!
We've met. Mornin'.
Good mornin'.
Isn't this wonderful?
Miss Mona has just
capped the goal for
the Little League fund campaign.
Oh, how nice!
Well, on behalf of my son and his
teammates, I wanna thank you.
You tell them I'll be
well repaid when they
take the championship next year.
Goodbye, Rita.
I'm sorry the sheriff
wasn't here to thank you.
He drove over to Meritsville.
He'll be gone all afternoon.
Well, you tell him I said hi.
Bye.
Hey, Miss Mona.
How are you doin', Deputy Fred?
It's nice to see you.
It's good to see you. Keepin'
an eye on my place at night?
Sure are. The Sheriff's real
particular about security out there.
Well, one of these nights when you
ain't on duty, you drop in out there.
My girls would love to show
you a little appreciation.
Shoot, Miss Mona. You know
I'm a married man! (LAUGHS)
Oh, Fred, you mean to
tell me you don't think
the cows don't
appreciate the time off
when a bull goes
over to another pasture?
(LAUGHS) Miss Mona!
See you later, Miss Mona.
Okay. Goodbye.
Damn it!
What's the matter?
You're in bed already. So?
So, I told you 100 times,
watching you get
undressed is the best part.
The best part?
Well, maybe not the best part,
but in the top two.
(LAUGHS)
Now, would I wanna disappoint
my little honey?
Whoo! Ah. I'm glad I was late.
Me too! You just hold your horses.
I got a surprise for you.
I went by the post
office this morning.
I picked up a package. The very latest
thing from Frederick's of Hollywood.
Yeah?
Just a little something sexy
I thought you might like.
What do you think? Little?
It don't look too little to me.
Well, it certainly
ain't a trainin' bra,
but I do believe
I can fill it out.
I don't think you
got any problem there.
I'll be back with more.
(LAUGHS) You know, Mona,
I've known a lot
of women in my life.
None of 'em has ever been
exciting to me like you are.
Really? Even after all these years
we've been meetin' like this?
I'll tell you something.
A year with you is like
a minute of sheer happiness.
Well, now, that is just about the
sweetest thing anybody ever said to me.
I know.
You know, honey,
you bring out the...
The romantic in me.
Tah-dah!
Whoo! You did that real fast.
Well, honey,
I've had a lot of practice
gettin' in and
out of my clothes.
How do you like the outfit?
Hot damn.
Makes me feel real sexy.
Whoo. (LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING)
Well, you don't look real sexy.
What do you mean?
I look like I always look.
That's just it.
It's them damn
droopy boxer drawers.
I just hate
the looks of them things.
I've worn boxer
shorts for years!
And they look like it.
These are a brand-new pair.
I don't know what you're talkin'
about, "I don't look sexy."
People tell me I have a real
sexy quality about me.
Well, you do,
but them boxer shorts don't.
But when I was gettin' me some
sexy things, I thought about you,
because they have a his 'n' hers
sexy department at Frederick's
and I thought you
might try that on for size.
What the hell is it,
a Japanese slingshot?
(LAUGHS)
No, it's jockey shorts with
little silver snaps on the side.
Mmm. Little is the key word here.
They are real little.
In fact, a guy could hurt
himself wearin' those things.
I don't think so,
thank you very much.
Ed Earl, I paid $20 for these, plus
postage. And I want you to wear it.
Aw, you paid $20 for these?
MONA: Yes!
Well, you got screwed.
Come on, Ed Earl!
ED EARL: No!
If they look half as good on you
as I think they're going to
you ain't gonna have to
wear 'em but a second.
Maybe less.
They're ridiculous.
They're impossible.
They're sexy.
No, no, no!
Well, fine! Then I'm gettin'
dressed and goin' home.
Well, fine! I'm goin' in the
bathroom and... Put these on.
Be like puttin' two bowling
balls in a marble bag.
Braggin', braggin', braggin'.
Well, I saw Dulcie
Mae in town today.
ED EARL: Oh, yeah?
I guess you'll be goin' over
there for Thanksgivin' dinner.
ED EARL: Don't I always?
You know, you better check
that turkey of hers,
because there's a hook
in there that's gonna
drag your ass to
a wedding chapel.
ED EARL: (CHUCKLES) No way.
I don't believe in matrimony.
It screws up a relationship.
Amen to that, Ed Earl.
Ready?
Oh, I'm always ready.
Well, hellfire. ls that it?
How'd you like it?
I didn't hardly
get to even see them!
That's all you're gonna see,
'cause I ain't gonna parade
around like no model.
Aw, come on, Ed Earl. For me.
No! No.
Come on. One itsy-bitsy peek?
What are you doin'? Man!
(CLASP CLICKS)
(LAUGHING) Now, that's what the
little silver snaps are for.
(CHUCKLES) Work, don't they?
Just like a snap.
Come on over here and give me
a little lip-lock.
Oop. Gotta brush my teeth.
Ah. (CHUCKLES)
You know how I am
about my breath.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, Ed Earl, I like
a lot of things,
but these afternoons with you
have got to top the list.
Yeah?
Well, sing it to me, honey.
♪ I like fancy, frilly things
♪ High-heel shoes
and diamond rings
♪ Ragtime bands
and Western swing
♪ And sneakin' around with you
♪ I like beer and rodeos
♪ Detective books and dominoes
♪ Football games and Cheerios
♪ Cheerios?
♪ And sneakin' around with you
BOTH".
♪ Sneakin' around with you
♪ Goin' a round or two
Doin' what lovers do
♪ Whenever they're
sneakin' around
♪ I like lots of cash on hand
♪ And dirty jokes
about the Fuller Brush man
♪ I like stuff I understand
♪ Like sneakin' around with you
♪ You know, I like
a thrill that has no strings
♪ Friendship that
don't ever change
♪ And laughter
from the joy of things
♪ And sneakin' around with you
♪ Sneakin' around with you
♪ Goin' a round or two
♪ Doin' what lovers do
♪ Whenever
they're sneakin' around
♪ Oh, ho! ♪
(LAUGHS)
♪ Mmm, ah!
I like drive-in picture shows
♪ Kissin' long and lovin' slow
♪ Secret places lovers go
♪ Whenever they're
sneakin' around
♪ Whoo! I like
the crazy things we try
♪ And the sexy
things we fantasize
♪ Just a-makin' out
in the broad daylight
♪ And sneakin' around with you
♪ Sneakin' around with you
♪ Keepin' it all brand new
♪ Gettin' the best of you
♪ Whenever we're sneakin around
♪ Sneakin' around That's all
♪ I'm gonna lay down the law
♪ Watchin' the rise and fall
♪ Of lovers sneakin' around
♪ We're just sneakin' around
♪ Oh, we're just
♪ Sneakin' ♪ (LAUGHING)
Sheriff?
Sheriff!
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
It's Deputy Fred. MONA: Fred.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh. Hold that position, hmm?
Don't move. Be right back.
This better be important.
Well, I think it is.
I saw your car
parked from the highway
and I figured your
phone was out, because...
What are you wearin' that for?
Takin' a shower.
Oh, really?
I always take my
shower in the mornin'.
I read in the Reader's Digest...
I don't care!
What do you want?
Oh, it's the mayor.
He wants to speak to you.
Rit♪s been callin' all
over the county for you.
He wants a meeting right away.
Can't it wait?
You mean till after your shower?
Mmm. You go to your radio.
Tell him I'll be
there when I get there.
Nothing can be that important that
it can't wait till this afternoon.
Right, Sheriff.
Nice man, but dumb.
Mona? (LAUGHS)
Mona?
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
Ain't that funny?
All this time Miss Mona
was at the back
knockin' on the screen door.
She said she's in a real big hurry but
just dropped by to give you this.
It's a Japanese slingshot.
Well, look at that! At last!
Okay, Rufus.
What's on your mind?
Something that
could have serious
implications to
the health of this town!
Tell him, C.J.!
Just like you told me.
Well, Sheriff, I have this friend
that works in a TV station
down in Houston.
He tipped me off
that Melvin P. Thorpe's
plannin' an expose
on the Chicken Ranch.
Who?
Melvin P. Thorpe!
He's that crazy
consumer advocate.
Has a report on
the late night news.
He's got a new show now,
a half hour once a week,
The Watchdog Report.
It's on tonight.
The Chicken Ranch on TV.
Now, come on, fellas.
Television is a family medium.
But he's a sensationalist,
Ed Earl.
He shows up with his TV cameras every
time a consumer has a complaint.
He's a menace to
the business community.
He's that feller that put the
peanuts back in the chocolate bar.
What?
He made the makers of the
Peanut Delight candy bar
admit that they put less peanuts
in each bar than
they advertised.
He made them change their ways.
Sounds like a tough customer.
He's got a lot of
influence out there.
If he brings cameras out
to the Chicken Ranch...
Come on, Rufus!
I'll make some phone calls.
I got a little influence
around this state myself.
Well, it's no use talkin'
to me about it, Sheriff!
Melvin P. Thorpe is now the biggest
attraction at this station.
High ratings. Lots of letters.
He doesn't listen to anybody.
Hell, he wants to go national!
Wants to be watchdog
for the whole U.S. of A.
Love to help you, Ed Earl,
but just like you don't want to
mess with the Chicken Ranch,
I don't wanna ruffle
this old bird's feathers.
Here in Houston, he's becomin'
a regular Texas attraction.
Well, now, wait a minute,
Ed Earl.
I'd tread easy on this one. Them
TV boys can be mighty powerful.
And mighty useful,
if you get my meaning.
Senator, roll call.
Excuse me, Ed Earl. I gotta go.
It's that damn
bilingual bullshit again.
Let me give you
a word of advice from
one elected official to another.
Be careful of the box.
Son of a bitch.
What the hell's going on?
This goddam Melvin P. Thorpe's
got the whole state bamboozled.
This is serious, Ed Earl.
You gotta do something.
I intend to.
Deputy Fred. I want you to hold
down the fort for a while.
Me? Yeah, you.
Where you goin'?
I'm goin' to Houston.
I'm gonna take care
of that little
pecker wood myself.
This is it. Thank you.
MELVIN: Come in.
Mr Thorpe?
I know you.
You do?
Sheriff Ed Earl Dodd. They told
me you were here. Come on in.
I hope I'm not...
Interrupting anything.
Oh, please!
It's my pleasure, my honor.
What brings you here to Houston?
Sit down. Anywhere over here.
I, uh... (CHUCKLES).
I'm gettin' dressed.
Sit down.
I've got my TV show to do,
and I'm runnin'
a bit behind time.
ED EARL: It's your show I want
to talk to you about, Mr Thorpe.
Oop. Melvin.
Melvin.
Please. You watch the show, Ed?
Last week Well...
was the best ratin' we ever had.
The city planning commissioner
was drivin' a city car...
Just hold that for me, will you?
While he was on vacation.
Caught him dead to rights.
That pitiful putz.
Would you just pull that up?
What? Just pull that up.
And we broke a 30 share.
It's affectin' my pieces
on the late night news.
Up, up, up. They just
love my little report.
I hear you're very popular.
The power of television, of public
exposure, is so great it scares me.
I swear, I could get the
mayor's own children
to throw rocks at him.
Which show did
you like best, Ed?
I think the one about the...
Nuts in the chocolate bar.
That's one of my favorites.
"Threescore" means 60,
like the Bible says.
So, if it says "60
nuts" on the wrapper,
I wanna see 60 nuts inside.
And I'm talkin' full nuts.
I'm not talkin' a half nut,
or nut bits or nut chips.
I'm talkin' a full nut.
I can see that.
Thank God we still live in
a society where anything
that's phony or dishonest
can't stand the light of day.
Sock. Beg your pardon?
Uh, sock.
Thank you. Yeah.
Most corporations involved
in false advertisin'
would just laugh at a $50 fine.
But you show up
with your TV camera
and give them
a little bad publicity
and they shape up faster than goose
shit slides through a tin horn.
(LAUGHS)
(HUMMING)
Well, Melvin, it's that bad publicity
I want to talk to you about.
That could hurt people.
You take that report
you're doin' on
the Chicken Ranch.
That place is older
than rocks and water.
I wouldn't be surprised if your
granddaddy took your daddy out there
to learn about
the birds and the bees.
(CHUCKLES) I'm from New Jersey.
See, I moved to Houston six years ago.
(CHUCKLES)
Texas suits my style.
The point I'm tryin' to make is
that every schoolboy in
the state knows about it.
Most of the politicians
have slept there.
And the mayor and the people of
my county that voted for me,
they want to keep
things just the way they are.
Hmm. You know something,
Sheriff, it just struck me.
We are in the same profession.
What's that?
Law enforcement.
I'm out there fightin' for the
rights of the public, just like you.
Both of us are interested
in protectin' the public.
You in the old way,
and me in the new.
Uh-huh. The new?
Television.
I'm the electronic
bounty hunter.
I use a camera, you use a gun.
Yeah.
Well, Melvin,
everybody'd be happy
if you'd just drop
the whole thing.
Ah.
I mean, those ladies out there,
they perform
a necessary function.
I mean, right or wrong...
Right or wrong
don't interest me!
I'm no moralizer. I leave
all that to the preacher.
Well, I'm glad.
Anyway, the mayor was
thinkin' maybe
you'd want a little
unnecessary publicity.
(LAUGHS) Unnecessary publicity?
He's got me all wrong!
I'm not one of those sensation
mongers out to boost his own ego!
Clear.
How do you like it?
It's different.
I designed this myself. (LAUGHS)
No, you tell your mayor he's got
nothing to fear from me on that score.
He'll be happy to hear that.
I'm a lawman.
That's my interest.
The law, right, partner?
(LAUGHS)
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
MAN: 20 seconds, Mr. Thorpe.
Oh, I'm on!
Friend Ed, I gotta go.
MELVIN: That's my cue.
(WOMEN SINGING ON SET) Come on!
Apres vous!
Come to think of it, I'd love
to do an interview with you.
I don't think I'm the type.
Oh, nonsense! You're exactly what
the public would like to see.
Really? We'll discuss
it after the show.
I want you to be my guest.
This is the sponsor's booth.
Just go in there,
make yourself comfortable.
Make yourself to home.
See you later, partner.
Thank you.
DOGETTES".
♪ He's out on the prowl
♪ Guards and
checks the best he can
♪ Watchdog is a fighting man
♪ Watchdog will throw
his beam of light around
♪ If some folks
don't toe the line
♪ Watchdog's light will shine
♪ Shine, shine, shine ♪
ANNOUNCER". And now,
the Watchdog man himself.
The eyes and ears of Texas,
Melvin P. Thorpe!
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
(CHEERING)
Thank you, fellow Texans, and
welcome to The Watchdog Report,
with yours truly, Melvin P.
Thorpe,
keepin' an eye
on what's goin' on
in this beautiful state of ours.
This week's spotlight will
shine on a shameful situation
that has been allowed to exist
for close to a 100 years.
I'm talkin' about the
Chicken Ranch, my friends.
The proprietor of this
innocent-lookin' ranch house
is a woman known
only as Miss Mona.
And the man who turns his back
on her illegal operation
is Sheriff Ed Earl Dodd!
Did I say illegal? Yes, I did!
(MUSIC STOPS)
Now, I know that this is TV,
so I'm gonna try to be
as delicate as I can!
Here goes,
and may God forgive me!
♪ Texas has a whorehouse in it
DOGETTES: ♪ Lord,
have mercy on our souls
♪ Texas has a whorehouse in it
♪ Lord, have mercy on our souls
♪ I'll expose the facts Although
it fills me with disgust
♪ Please excuse the filthy,
dark details
♪ And carnal lust
DOGETTES: ♪ Filthy, dark
details and carnal lust
♪ Dancin' goin' on inside it
♪ Don't you see
they've gone plumb wild
♪ I inquired No one denied it
♪ Now I think I'm gettin' riled
♪ Bodies close together
♪ Arms and legs all rearranged
♪ And the Sheriff
does not close it down
♪ That's very strange
DOGETTES: ♪ Does not close
it down That's very strange
♪ Mean-eyed, juiced-up
brilliantined honky-tonk cowboys
DOGETTES: ♪ Oh, no
♪ Mixin' with green-eyed, thin-lipped
hard-as-nails peroxide blonds
DOGETTES: ♪ Oh, no
♪ Not to mention some types that
you'd never guess would venture near
♪ Actin' all depraved and loose
and wild 90 miles from here ♪
And now, our own Melvin P.
Thorpe Singers.
DOGETTES". I Texas has
a whorehouse in it ♪
Oh, my goodness,
he's talkin' about us!
♪ Texas has a whorehouse in it ♪
Suits me, Morn.
♪ I'll crusade ♪
Doreen! Get my heart pills!
♪ Loveless copulation goin' on
Hot damn!
♪ And it must stop
DOGETTES: ♪ Loveless copulation
Loveless copulation ♪
Loveless copulation?
♪ Texas has a whorehouse in it
God, have mercy on our souls
God, have mercy ♪
Ah!
Can you dig it?
Hey!
♪ Loveless copulation going on ♪
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Don't touch that dial!
This is Melvin P. Thorpe
sayin' I'll be back with new
and revealin' information
about this and other cases.
Watchdog never sleeps!
♪ And it must stop
Watchdogs gonna get you
♪ Gonna shine his light on you
♪ Watchdog's gonna get you
♪ Gonna shine his light on you ♪
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Damn. That man is crazier
than a peach orchard sow.
Announcin' it
straight out on TV.
So you been sayin'.
Everybody's talkin' about it.
Not that it's big news to anybody
over three months of age.
But they heard it
in their livin' room.
Sung. Sung to music.
And he actually called
my name on television.
Worse than that. The son
of a bitch called mine!
(MONA CHUCKLES)
You know, Ed Earl, seems like
ever since I can remember,
folks been jumpin' on me
for one reason or another.
Mmm.
But we're gonna beat this thing.
I ain't worried about it.
You know why?
Because I trust you.
Mmm. 'Cause you're my protector.
Do you know he wears
a sock in his underwear?
A sock? Yeah.
All rolled up like
a Jimmy Dean sausage.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Well, I bet he's
runnin' for office.
That's typical of
them crusadin' fanatics.
They flare up every few months.
They're always
confusin' crime with sin.
People just get
sick of hearin' it
and pretty soon it just
clears out of the air.
You're probably right.
Well, ain't I always?
Mmm-hmm.
What? You know what I
was thinkin', Ed Earl?
Just how much I miss
all the little stuff
me and you used to do,
like goin' up to the lake.
Wouldn't it be fun just to go up
there, get a couple of six-packs
and just get
drunker than Cootie Brown?
Girl, that's the best idea you had
all year. When we gonna do this?
Well, I'd like to do it tonight.
So would I.
(SIREN WAILING)
Well, I wonder who that is.
Hey, Deputy Fred.
Morning, girls!
How's your tallywacker hangin'?
Fine...
Uh... (CHUCKLES SHEEPISHLY)
Shoot
Hi, Sheriff.
This better be important.
I think it is.
That Melvin P. Thorpe
is settin' up
his television show
right out in front
of the courthouse!
In front of the... Courthouse!
FRED: He's gettin' some pictures for
a piece on the late news tonight.
He's got a whole posse of TV cameramen.
You better come take a look.
Right out in front of...
Your office!
Son of a... Bitch.
I cannot believe that sucker!
You know, he even
brought his own singers.
Wait'll I get my hands...
Go get him, Sheriff!
Come on, Deputy Fred!
Ed Earl, please don't go doin' something
stupid you're gonna be sorry for!
Watch your temper.
Everything's
gonna be fine, Mona.
Leave that
little shithead to me.
Howdy again, good neighbors. Melvin P.
Thorpe, the old Watchdog himself,
shinin' a spotlight on Gilbert,
the little town
with the big shame.
Who's that fella in
them trick britches?
I don't know, but it's too late
in the year for a carnival.
One of them TV folks,
looks like to me.
We're here at
the Lanville County Courthouse
to ask some of
the local citizens
how they feel about
the infamous bordello
runnin' wide open in their
American home town.
Cut! All right,
now, stay with me, boys.
And when I start the music, I want you
Dogettes to start with me, brisk!
Good people of Gilbert, may I
have your attention, please?
I would like to speak to you about a
matter of great importance and concern.
Let's hear it, Melvin!
Lay it on us.
I'm speakin' to you
about nothin' less
than your
community's moral health!
I'm talkin' to you
about official blindness,
official corruption,
official malfeasance.
He sure is wound up.
Yep. I'm just waitin'
for Ed Earl to get here.
He's gonna kick that boy's ass.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIREN WAILING)
It's no big secret.
You know what's
goin' on in this town
and what's goin'
on is evil, immoral,
brazen and against the law!
Hit it.
♪ Texas has a whorehouse in it
DOGETTES: ♪ Lord, have mercy
on our souls
♪ Texas has a whorehouse in it
DOGETTES: ♪ Lord, have mercy
on our souls
♪ Sin is running rampant
like before the fall of Rome
♪ Someone is
permittin' you-know-what
♪ And it must stop
DOGETTES". ♪ Loveless copulation
♪ Stop that copulation
♪ Loveless copulation
(SIREN WAILING)
♪ Stop that copulation
♪ Texas has a whorehouse in it
♪ Lord, have mercy on our souls
♪ Watchdog smells corruption and
he'll fight it to the top ♪
Now, Sheriff, Sheriff.
Keep a grip on yourself.
Don't get your back up!
Stop whimperin', Rufus.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Well, if it isn't
the man himself.
Would you care to give me
an interview now, Sheriff?
I'm gonna give you 30 seconds,
you fancified fart.
Get you and your singin'
chorus the hell out of town!
Now, wait a minute.
And get those cameras and the
rest of that crap off the street.
You're blockin' traffic!
The only traffic we are blockin'
is that headed out
for the Chicken Ranch.
Right, Sheriff?
Little fat buddy,
up to now you got two tickets.
One for paradin' without a license
and the other for insultin' me.
Now, you better get that
travellin' circus out of town
or I'm gonna lock you up so
fast your corset's gonna pop!
Oh, yeah? We're
perfectly within the law.
As a newsman, I have
First Amendment protection.
(GRUNTS) Get this.
The public has a right to know
what is goin' on out there
and what kind of pay-off
you're acceptin' to protect
that notorious
house of ill repute.
CROWD: Ooh!
First thing. First thing is you're
standin' in Lanville County,
which, by my figurin',
is about a 100 miles west
of that stink hole
you call Houston.
So I can't see
it's any of your business
what goes on out here.
Oh, yeah? Please...
Number two. You ain't the
law around here and I am.
So don't be tellin' me what
my goddamn job is,
or I'll whip your butt so bad it'll
look like the stripes on a barber pole.
BOY: Get him, Sheriff.
May be mean, but he's ours!
Number three.
No sawed-off little pecker
is gonna accuse me of takin' a
bribe and live to tell about it
'cause I wear the badge
in this goddamn county.
So you listen and listen good, you
over-padded, televisin' turd.
If I ever see you or any
of those little bastards
that work for you
in my town again,
I'm gonna knock you
so flat you're gonna
have to roll down
your socks to shit!
(MOANING)
That's tellin' him, Sheriff!
Oh, my goodness!
So get outta here, you goddamn,
wig-wearin',
citified son of a bitch!
(GUNSHOT)
(SPUTTERING) Holy shit!
Oh, my God, that man's crazy!
Oh! Ooh.
Move, you schmuck!
Move it! Come on!
Get outta here! Move this thing!
Come on, move this thing!
I'll get you for this.
You son of a bitch!
You'll pay for this.
You're in trouble, Sheriff!
You're in big trouble!
So long, partner.
(LAUGHING)
Boy, you sent him hightailin'.
I was so proud of you!
Didn't I? Yeah.
Mmm-hmm. (LAUGHS)
Look at them stars.
Mmm.
Well, there ain't nothin'
prettier than a Texas sky.
Ain't that the truth.
Hey, look! Did you
see that shootin' star?
Mmm-hmm.
Yeah. That could've been
a spaceship, you know.
You believe in spaceships?
Sure.
I saw a picture once.
Them fellers that's supposed
to be from up there.
Fly around. Uh-huh.
Tiny little fellers,
bald-headed.
Little feet,
little hands, got no peckers.
Got no peckers?
Well, I ain't interested.
(LAUGHS)
I don't think my
girls would be either.
(CHUCKLES)
MONA: When I was a little kid, I
used to imagine a flyin' saucer
swoopin' down and pickin' me up
and takin' me off to heaven.
Like the angels.
ED EARL: Mmm-hmm.
"L looked, and behold, a whirlwind
comin' out of the north.
"And out of the midst
of the fire came the
"likeness of four
living creatures."
What the hell you talkin' about?
Well, that's from the Bible.
That's what the Bible says
about spaceships in Ezekiel.
Don't you know
nothin' about the Bible?
Yeah, I know about the Bible!
I just don't know nothin'
about no Ezekiel in the Bible.
I knew Ezekiel Peebles
once in the eighth grade.
Think I busted his jaw.
Mmm.
Well, that was
very Christian of you.
Well, most of my
family was Baptist.
Well, I never stayed
with one family long enough
to become
anything in particular.
But I read the Bible.
I believe in Jesus.
I think Jesus was...
Was a real good man.
And he was a heck of a speaker.
Yep. I knew a woman once
that had a vision of Jesus.
He came right in her house, set
right down at the foot of her bed.
Mmm-hmm?
I don't know what I'd do
if that happened to me.
I'll tell you something, honey.
If Jesus comes to your house,
all hell's gonna break loose.
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
You got a point there, Ed Earl.
But you know,
Jesus was really good
to Mary Magdalene,
the fallen woman.
He was always
bein' very sociable.
He went to this big weddin'
once and they ran out of wine.
You know what he did?
Turned the water into wine.
Well, that's a man that knows
how to throw a party.
Now, don't be sacrilegious.
I'm not.
I'm not. He forgives me.
He knows I was kiddin'.
Yeah, I know he forgives you.
That's funny, now,
how God can forgive you,
and people can't.
Now why is that?
Well, because people are not
very God-like, Mona.
I know.
Yeah.
(TRAIN WHISTLE
BLOWING IN DISTANCE)
(CHUCKLES)
What is it?
Melvin P. Thorpe
is a sorry son of a bitch.
(LAUGHS)
(LAUGHING)
You reckon he's gonna
run for the legislature?
Why?
I never told
anybody this, Mona, but...
I was thinkin' of runnin'
for the legislature someday.
Are you serious, Ed Earl?
Yeah.
They say an honest man can't be
elected in this country anymore.
But I don't believe that.
This is a good country.
I believe I could win.
Well, you got my vote.
I might even go register.
Boy, I sure didn't know
you had dreams that big.
Hmm.
People really do
like you, though.
They like you, too.
Really? Sure.
You ask anybody
in town about you.
Say,
"How do you like Miss Mona?"
They say, "Shoot, she's a fine woman.
Fine, friendly and nice."
Huh.
Well, I always just thought if you
see somebody without a smile,
you give 'em yours.
I like that.
Think I'll use that
as my campaign slogan.
If you see somebody without
a smile, give 'em yours.
I'm gonna have that
printed up on a little card.
Oh, you're kiddin' me.
You smart-ass.
I had a dream once.
Yeah?
I'll tell you if
you won't laugh.
Oh, I won't laugh.
Well, I used to dream
of bein' a ballerina.
(OPENS CAN) (SNICKERS)
Now, Ed Earl,
I ain't tellin' you nothin'.
(SNICKERING) A ballerina?
Yes, a ballerina!
(LAUGHS) Well,
I think that's wonderful.
And I think you still could be a
ballerina if you wanted to be.
No, you could!
Oh, don't be ridiculous!
Go into training right now.
Just start jumpin' up and down.
Me? Jumpin' up and down?
I'd black both my eyes.
(LAUGHS)
I couldn't be a ballerina now.
I'm too top-heavy.
I have a hard enough
time balancin' these
things now,
without gettin' on my toes.
You know something?
What?
You know that, uh, I don't
see anybody but you anymore.
Course, now, you can't
say the same, can you?
I haven't been to bed with another
woman besides you in three years.
You didn't know that, did you?
No, I didn't know that.
Nothin' better,
once you've had the best.
Hey, I like that.
Mmm. I thought you would.
Reckon if I was to
run for the legislature,
I could, uh,
put that on my card?
(LAUGHS)
Up next, Melvin P. Thorpe continues
his expose of the Chicken Ranch
with a violent demonstration
in the Gilbert town square.
Great God from Goldsboro!
(PHONE RINGING)
(GRUNTS)
ED EARL: Oh. Yeah?
Ed Earl,
you better turn on Channel 4.
That Melvin P. Thorpe idiot's
got you on TV again.
Well, I don't give a shit,
Rufus!
It's all very well to
take that attitude, Ed Earl,
but this is serious! Honey.
Put on the television.
Channel 4.
(RUFUS CHATTERING)
That Melvin P. Thorpe is
shootin' off his mouth again.
How could what he's sayin'
be so goddamn important?
Calm down, Rufus! It can't
be as bad as all that.
What happened to me as an
individual is not important.
Is this the kind of man we want
runnin' our law enforcement?
Is this the kind of
foul-mouthed example
we wanna set for our young,
innocent children?
Run the film.
Number three.
No sawed-off little (SLEEP)
is gonna accuse me of takin' a
bribe and live to tell about it
because I wear the badge
in this (BLEEPING) county!
So you and you listen good!
You (BLEEPING)!
If I ever see you or
any of those (BLEEP)
that work for you
in my town again,
I'm gonna knock you so flat
you're gonna (BLEEPING)!
(GUNSHOTS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Ed Earl, that man has
made a fool out of you.
(GUNSHOT)
(PHONE RINGING) I've had
calls from four preachers,
six deacons, and the presidents
of two garden clubs!
Thank you for callin'.
The phones have
been ringin' like that
all mornin' long.
Sheriff's office.
I don't know why I let people
talk me into serving as mayor
of this
incorporated sand trap anyway!
What in the heck is keepin' him?
He'll be along.
Well, he'd better!
My wife couldn't believe
what she saw last night.
They bleeped him out,
but she read his lips
on every "hell,"
"goddamn," and "shit."
(GROANS)
There's some folks gettin' up a
petition to close the Chicken Ranch.
All we wanted to do
was keep it quiet.
Now, thanks to Ed Earl,
it's the hottest thing
on the air since The Gong Show.
RITA: I'll tell him you called.
Bye. Mornin', Sheriff.
Mornin', Rita.
Here's your calls.
Reckon you fellas are
waitin' to talk to me.
We sure are!
You don't know
the trouble you caused
on this Chicken Ranch business!
Dad-gum it, Ed Earl! If you
ain't a pluperfect fool!
You may be right.
I got over a dozen
messages here from
outraged citizens,
tellin' me that we got a
whorehouse in Lanville County.
Only been one here
for about 150 years.
Ed Earl, now, you can set up speed
traps to catch the tourists.
You can look the other way when the
wrong kid swipes a car to go joyriding.
Hell, you can even let Miss
Mona run her place out there!
But there's one thing you can't do and
that's broadcast gutter talk on TV.
I didn't know they
was takin' pictures.
What did you figure
the cameras were for?
Damn it, C.J.!
You pious pissant.
I don't have one-tenth the trouble
from Miss Mon♪s that I have from you
for one of your all-night stag parties
over at the Legionnaire Hall.
That ain't fair, dang it!
There's just one thing to do.
And that's close
the place down before
we all go to hell
in a hand basket.
Close it down! She was just fine as
long as she was bringin' in the money
and makin' civic contributions,
but the moment her luck ran sour,
you want to run out on her.
Run out on her like
rats from a burnin' barn!
That's just it, Ed Earl.
Who's gonna put out that fire?
Look, if you won't
close her down, at least
tell her to lay low
for a couple of months!
Yeah, just until the heat
wears off a little bit.
Give it two months.
What's two months?
Nobody tells me how
to run my goddam job,
and nobody gives me advice!
I'll do things my own way. I'm
gonna make up my own damn mind!
Two months. What's two months?
Shut down for two months!
That is a hell of a lot
to ask somebody, Ed Earl.
And that's a hell
of a lot of overhead
to pay out when
cash ain't comin' in.
What d'you think I
ought to tell my girls?
Well, maybe it won't
be two months.
The holidays are comin' up.
Maybe in a couple of weeks the
whole thing will blow over
and then you can let
your regular customers...
I warned you yesterday about losin'
your temper and carryin' on.
Last night you said
you was proud of me.
Last night I wasn't
on the 11:00 news!
Well, I didn't know that son of a bitch
was gonna make an idiot out of me.
I don't know anything about
that electronic bullshit!
How was I supposed to
handle that situation?
That's your job, Ed Earl. Ain't
that what they pay you for?
I know what my job is! Don't be
tellin' me what my goddamn job is!
I could close this place down
in a New York minute!
All I'm askin' for is for you
to give me a little cooperation
so I can get through
a difficult situation
with as little
trouble as possible!
Okay, okay, okay!
I'll shut it down.
You will?
What do you want,
a written contract?
You promise?
Ed Earl,
I am givin' you my word.
I'm sorry, Mona,
about the whole situation.
Don't feel sorry for me.
I started out poor, and I
worked my way up to outcast.
I know what I'm
askin' you to do is gonna
turn out to be
the best thing for both of us.
Just trust me.
You know what burns my ass?
What?
A flame about three feet high.
(CHUCKLES)
Of course I trust you, you big cowboy.
Ain't I always?
Mmm-hmm.
No need to stop now.
Now get out of here. (SLAPS)
Everything's gonna
turn out just fine.
Don't you worry
about a thing, honey.
Everything's gonna turn out
slicker than cat shit
on a linoleum floor.
(LAUGHS)
Well, if it ain't the celebrated
cussin' sheriff
of Lanville County.
How are you, Sheriff?
I'm fine. How are you, Porky?
Oh, Sheriff! I been real good all week.
I've lost six pounds.
Oh, yeah? Well, don't take
nothin' off them cheeks.
Oh, go on.
(LAUGHS)
Whoa!
Well, Jewel,
I just promised the sheriff
that we're gonna shut
down for two months.
What? How can you promise that?
What about the football game
celebration tomorrow night?
(SIGHS) I forgot all about that.
It's the Thanksgiving game, Miss Mona.
And that's real special.
Well I know it's special, Jewel!
But I don't know what to do now.
I did promise.
You think if we just close the
doors to the regular customers,
just went on with the party as
planned, that'd be all right?
I'm sure it will, honey. That party
is a bigger tradition than the game.
(CROWD CHEERING)
65,000-plus on hand
here at Kyle Field,
and we have seen
an amazing ball game.
Texas A&M heavily favored,
but we're tied 12-12.
Aggies have the ball,
second down at eight.
Time is winding down.
SPORTSCASTER: They try the
middle of the Texas defense,
and again, the Longhorns'
break is stopped.
This University
of Texas defense...
Whoo!
(LAUGHS)
We string up the white first
and after we see who wins, we put
up the orange or the maroon.
Yes, m♪am.
(ANNOUNCER CONTINUES ON TV)
I can't stand it
if them Aggies win.
What do you mean?
They're such animals. Always
yellin' and jumpin' about
and sayin' "yee-haw!"
If they have to go for
all the marbles,
they will have to throw to
the end zone right now.
Time running out. Miller rolls
to the right. Pass! Touchdown!
(CROWD ROARING)
Yeah!
Hell! That calls for a drink.
SPORTSCASTER:
Talk about the part
that emotion plays
in a game like this!
Don't let your
mother see you do that.
Well, who won?
The Aggies.
Aw, Shit.
ALL: Yee-haw.
ALL: Yee-haw!
Yee-haw!
Hey, boys!
(ALL WHOOPING)
All right! Hey, boys!
Boys, boys!
That was the greatest victory
since General Eisenhower won!
Senator, you ain't
forgot you was gonna
take us to
the Chicken Ranch, did ya?
MAN: Yeah! How about it?
I always keep my
campaign promises, hmm?
(CHEERS)
Yes, sir. The Chicken Ranch
is a fine institution,
and I'm proud to
have it in my district.
And to hell with what
Melvin P. Thorpe says!
I'll see all you
seniors out at Miss Mon♪s.
(CHEERING)
♪ We're gonna whomp and stomp
♪ And we'll whoop it up
♪ Tonight
♪ Those little
gals won't never ever
♪ Be the same
♪ They're gonna love it
when we whomp and stomp
♪ And whoop it up All right
♪ It's even better than
an Aggie football game ♪
Better than a football game?
♪ And then we're
gonna show them all
♪ A thing or two
♪ We're gonna demonstrate
♪ Just what a champion can do
Yee-haw!
♪ 75 miles
until we get to heaven
until our plans are laid
♪ 75 miles until
we get to the Chicken Ranch
♪ Where history and Aggie boys
♪ Get made ♪
(ALL WHOOPING)
(WHOOPING CONTINUES)
Yee-haw!
Get out of the way!
Look it here! Watch this.
Whoo!
Yee-haw!
Yee-haw! Yee-haw!
Hey. All right! Hey, come on.
Atta boy!
Oh, yeah! Come on! All right!
All right!
(WHOOPING)
♪ 22 miles
until we get to heaven
until our plans are laid
♪ 22 miles until
we get to the Chicken Ranch
♪ Where history and Aggie boys
♪ Get made ♪
(AIR WHOOSHING)
(ALL MOANING)
What the hell happened?
Do we have to wear
these ball gowns again?
Yes, you do, and I don't wanna
hear any more bitchin' about it.
Miss Mona likes to create
somethin' special for the boys.
It's like a graduation dance.
Yee-haw! Yee-haw! Yee-haw!
(SHOUTS CONTINUE)
♪ One more mile
until we get to heaven
until our plans are laid
♪ One more mile until we
get to the Chicken Ranch
♪ Where history and Aggie boys
♪ Get made ♪
(WHOOPING)
ALL: Yee-haw!
Y'all come on in!
(LAUGHING) Oh,
I'm so glad to see ya.
Congratulations!
Hey, boys! I think you'll find
it's a fittin' celebration
for today's victory!
(CHEERING)
ALL: Whom!
Howdy, boys!
Howdy, m♪am.
I'm Senator Wingwood
of the 19th District and
the Aggie class of '49.
Mighty proud to meet you.
To meet me! Charlie, who you
think you're talkin' to?
How's Mary
Margaret and the kids?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Hell, Miss Mona,
I didn't think you'd remember.
Remember? Did you remember
to bring my check?
I got it right here.
Good. You know
it's always a business
doin' pleasure
with you, Charlie.
(LAUGHS)
You boys head on out back.
We've got a nice
surprise for you.
Come on, boys! (BELL RINGING)
(ALL WHOOPING)
Yoo-hoo! Boys!
(BOYS CHEERING)
Hi!
(BOYS SHOUTING) (WHISTLING)
(ALL GASP)
WOMEN; Oh!
(LAUGHING)
BOYS: Yee-haw!
(WHISTLING)
♪ Texas has a whorehouse in it ♪
(VEHICLES APPROACHING)
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
(HUMMING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Yo!
FRED: It's me, Deputy Fred!
Come on in, Fred! (DOOR OPENING)
Evenin', Sheriff.
Happy Thanksgiving.
You want a drink?
Aw, no, thank you. That stuff
always tears up my stomach.
I was readin' in
the Reader's Digest...
What d'you want, Fred?
Oh, I was makin' my
rounds around town,
and I saw that Melvin P. Thorpe
and a bunch of other fellers
and they was all headed out
towards the Chicken Ranch.
Melvin P. Thorpe. Uh-huh.
(LAUGHS) Goin' out to
the Chicken Ranch, was he?
(LAUGHING) Yeah?
He's gonna be real
disappointed! (LAUGHING)
See, there ain't
nothin' goin' on out there.
Miss Mona promised me to close
the place down for two months.
Ah! Well, she didn't. I was out
there earlier this evenin'.
Those Aggies was just
celebratin' to beat the band.
Oh, no.
(LAUGHING) Uh-huh!
Aw, Shit!
Uh-huh!
Shh. Quiet.
Shh. This may be the most important
scoop of my television career.
Not now! Idiot boy.
Give me that. Now.
Good neighbors, we're about to
enter the whorehouse itself.
Cut. Come on.
Stay with me.
Come on. Come on, boys.
No! There's been a party here.
Watch your step.
Shh.
MELVIN: Hold this.
(DOOR CREAKS)
And quiet.
Billy Joe, light switch.
Shh. Come on. No!
(SNORING)
Careful.
Henry. Lights. Light switch.
Watch me.
You know what you gotta do.
Wait. Bingo.
Lights! Everybody up!
(SHOUTING) Let's go!
All right! Come along!
Oh, shit!
Jewel, what in hell is goin' on?
Call the Sheriff! It's that Melvin P.
Thorpe sucker!
Oh! Ooh!
They're smokin'
(SNIFFS) cocaine!
Take their picture!
All right, take this! (SCREAMS)
Take her picture! Thank you!
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
MAN: Oh!
Excuse me, m♪am.
Y'all come back now, you hear?
Come on! Ooh. Look who's here.
Senator, the eyes of Texas are upon you.
(LAUGHING)
Come on, boys! We gotta leave.
Thank you, m♪am.
Oh!
Oh, ho, ho, ho! Miss Mona!
Melvin P. Thorpe. Gotcha!
Let's get to those vans! We're
gonna make the mornin' news!
(SIRENS WAILING)
See you on TV! (LAUGHING)
Holy shit!
God almighty.
Damn it! You gave me your word!
You gave me your
word and I took it!
Now, I'm the law!
The law!
You wanna talk about the law!
A bunch of crazies break into
my house tonight,
comin' in here, takin'
pictures, invadin' my privacy,
and you wanna know what
the law's gonna do about that?
I can tell you. Nothin'!
They'd have no reason
to do nothin'
if you'd done what you
said you were gonna do!
I trusted you. That's what hurt.
I trusted you!
Don't you talk to me about trust!
I trusted you to protect me!
I made a mistake tonight, okay?
If that's your idea of an apology,
it ain't worth armadillo crap.
Well, I ain't apologizin'!
I'm a business woman
payin' out double taxes!
I expect a little
protection for my money!
Where were you tonight? I
couldn't get you on the phone...
I was home in bed,
because you gave me
your word you were closin' down.
Well, if Sheriff Jack
Roy Wallace was here,
none of this
would have happened.
Sheriff Jack Roy
Wallace couldn't
hold my jock!
You can't handle the job!
God damn it,
Mona, you're makin' me mad!
Whoo! Listen at him cuss and shout.
Just like on TV!
You're just a kid
playin' at bein' a cowboy.
You ain't never gonna grow up!
You use me as your mistress.
You use that damn Dulcie Mae
as your in-town wife.
And you even use
that little boy of hers
so you can play weekend daddy!
Leave that boy out of it!
You're playin', Ed Earl.
You're just a big, overgrown
kid playin' at bein' a man!
I don't have to listen to this shit.
Damn it! I'm the law.
If I choose to, I'll close this
place down till hell freezes over.
Don't you threaten me. I'm tellin'
the truth, and you know it!
And all of your big dreams
of goin' to the legislature.
That's all they are.
They're just dreams,
'cause you ain't never gonna be
no more than you are right now.
A chicken-shit sheriff
in a chicken-shit town.
(EXHALES)
You may be right.
It's a hell of a lot
better than bein' a whore.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Legalized prostitution, pro
or con, is in the news today.
For a report, here is Jeff
Gerald in Gilbert, Texas.
The Chicken Ranch, the legendary,
long-running bawdy house,
is showing little activity
after the disclosure yesterday
of the Thanksgiving night raid.
Get away!
The deputy at the front
gate keeps away onlookers
and potential customers,
while up at the house,
the doors are closed
and the principals
are not talking.
The sheriff of Gilbert, Ed
Earl Dodd, refused interviews,
while in Houston, the man
who launched the campaign,
consumer advocate Melvin P.
Thorpe,
held a press
conference this afternoon.
I have a report here that
says that the Chicken Ranch
is involved with and under the
influence of organized crime.
I myself am gonna take
this report to Austin
in the hopes that
the Governor himself
will come out of
his long silence
on this issue
and uphold the law.
(APPLAUSE)
And... Thank you.
Thank you very much.
GERALD". At the capitol today,
the Governor made no statement,
but Senator Charles Wingwood,
who was a principal figure
in the Watchdog news raid,
also held a press conference
explaining his involvement.
I have no independent recollection
of going to the Chicken Ranch.
And I can only say,
as the most dedicated
anticommunist in
the state legislature,
that I must have been drugged
by communists or
communist sympathizers
and placed there to harm
my reputation and good name.
Reaction across
the state is split 50-50.
But here in the town of Gilbert,
the Chicken Ranch
has many supporters.
I ain't never seen anything
bad come out of there yet,
and I've lived here all my life.
Why, they attract a lot of
business to the community.
They pay their taxes. (CHUCKLES)
Just like you and me!
No one. No one was ever
forced to go up there.
My Frank, when he was alive, used
to go up there every Saturday.
I took it as a blessin'. Of course,
things were different then.
Nowadays women enjoy doin'
that sort of thing themselves.
At least, so I've been told.
The Chicken Ranch?
I think it's a good idea.
See, you take a lot of
young boys
and they're gonna be out
there lookin' for women.
If they can't find 'em,
they'll rape 'em.
And if they don't do that, they'll
run to other women and get diseases!
Those girls went to doctors.
Although petitions are being
circulated to save the Chicken Ranch,
already this bumper sticker is
beginning to appear around the state.
And so, as feminists
line up behind the bill
for the decriminalization
of prostitution
already in the legislature, while
traditionalists and fundamentalists
lobby for its defeat, the
fate of the Chicken Ranch
rests with the Governor,
who today, again,
was unavailable for comment.
(PILLS FIZZING)
Jeff Gerald,
ABC News, Gilbert, Texas.
Thank you, Jeff.
If there are further...
Well, I hate admitting
I was wrong, Miss Mona.
But with television broadcasting
this from hell to breakfast,
we should've done what the sheriff
said and kept this place closed.
(SIGHS) It was my fault, Jewel.
It was my decision.
He ain't gonna be able to
stop it this time, is he?
No. He'd like to,
but he's out of his league.
He don't know how to fight 'em.
He's just a good old boy that
ain't never gonna grow up.
Honey, we see
everything in this profession.
But one thing I ain't never seen,
man nor woman, is a grown-up.
Don't be too hard on him.
He loves you.
Well, he ain't never said it.
Some men can't say the words,
honey.
But that don't mean they
don't feel it in their heart.
Well, it's just as
well anyhow, Jewel.
I set my course a long time ago
and I can't go changin' now.
RUFUS: Well,
I don't know what to do.
Seems like folks got nothin' else to
talk about but this Chicken Ranch mess.
Like a broken record. Chicken Ranch,
Chicken Ranch, Chicken Ranch!
And all of this bad publicity's
flat ruinin' business.
I haven't sold a car in a week.
It's ruinin' the town.
No one's blamin' you, Ed Earl.
It ain't your fault.
But we can't just sit around
here waitin' to grow tits!
Now, now, the way I see it, the
Chicken Ranch served a purpose once.
But now everything's openin' up.
Do you know we are in the middle
of a worldwide sexual revolution?
Why, Miss Mon♪s ain't obscene.
It's just obsolete.
She ain't got a handful
of supporters left, Ed Earl.
All this publicity's
makin' folks think twice
about signin' that
petition to keep her open!
Why the hell can't
that station in Houston
turn its cameras to the
cesspool in their own backyard?
And how about Austin? Why, two
blocks from the state capitol,
you can have
anything done to you
for money that you
can get in Tangier!
Well, there's naked massages,
there's tongue baths,
there's somebody ticklin'
your ass with a feather.
If you know that for a fact,
Mr. Newspaper Editor,
it's your duty to expose it!
Well, now, you see here, C.J.!
I don't give a damn
if folks want their ass
tickled with a feather!
I kind of like to think that
that's what heaven is all about.
(LAUGHING)
Boys, I got myself a pretty
good bullshit detector.
And I can tell when
somebody's peein' on my boots
and tellin' me it's a rainstorm.
Now, this thing's gotten way out of hand.
I don't know how.
But I figure there's
only one thing left to do.
Close it down!
No. I'm goin' to Austin.
See the Governor, tell him Miss
Mon♪s side of the situation.
He sure as hell ain't gonna hear
about it from anybody in this room.
You can't go up
and see the Governor!
He don't see anybody!
He'll see me.
Feel like
the country dog in the city.
If I stand still, they screw me.
If I run,
they bite me in the ass.
(CHUCKLES)
I... I wish
there was somethin' I could do.
Thank you.
They want me to close her down,
run her out of town.
How can I ask her to leave when
all I want her to do is stay?
Ladies and gentlemen, His
Excellency, the Governor of Texas.
My friends, I want to thank you
for that sincere and
heart-warming ovation.
No questions, please.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
Governor, what do you think of
the crisis in the Middle East?
I was sayin' just this
morning at the weekly
prayer breakfast in
this historic capitol
that it behooves both
the Jews and the Arabs
to settle their differences
in a Christian manner.
But... Governor! Governor...
Have you seen the evidence
of the disgraceful situation
at the Chicken Ranch?
♪ Fellow Texans I am proudly
♪ Standing here to humbly say
♪ I assure you
♪ And I mean it
♪ Now, who says I don't
speak out as plain as day
♪ And fellow Texans
♪ I'm for progress And the flag
♪ Long may it fly
♪ I'm a poor boy
♪ Come to greatness
♪ So it follows that
I cannot tell a lie ♪
What the hell did he say?
The same as usual.
Not a damn thing.
♪ Ooh, I love to
dance a little sidestep
♪ Now they see me Now they don't
♪ I've come and gone
♪ And ooh I love to sweep
around the wide step
♪ Cut a little swath
and lead the people on ♪
(REPORTERS CHATTERING)
REPORTER: Governor! Yeah.
Jerry Rogers of
the Houston Post.
Hi, Jerry.
Governor, do you plan to take
action against the Chicken Ranch?
♪ Now, my good friends
♪ It behooves me
♪ To be solemn and declare
♪ I'm for
goodness and for profit
♪ And for living clean
and saying daily prayer
♪ And now, my good friends
You can sleep nights
♪ I'll continue to stand tall
♪ You can trust me
♪ For I promise
♪ I shall keep
a watchful eye upon y'all ♪
Did you get any of that?
I hear him talking
but he don't come in.
♪ Ooh, I love to
dance a little sidestep
♪ Now they see me Now they don't
♪ I've come and gone
♪ And ooh I love to sweep
around the wide step
♪ Cut a little swath
and lead the people on ♪
There he is. Come on, boys.
Governor! Governor.
Melvin P. Thorpe. Watchdog News.
Why has the Chicken Ranch
operation been so long ignored?
We seem to be havin' some
acoustic problems in here.
Aren't you afraid of possible
pay-offs and bribes?
Melvin, I'm sorry.
Enough of this pussy footin',
Governor.
What do you intend to do about
Miss Mona and the Chicken Ranch?
(MUTTERS)
♪ Now, Miss Mona
♪ I don't know her
♪ Though I've heard the name
♪ Oh, yes
♪ But of course I have
♪ No close contact
♪ So what she is doin'
I can only guess
♪ And now Miss Mona
♪ She's a blemish
♪ On the face of that good town
♪ I am takin' certain steps here
♪ Someone somewhere 's gonna
have to close her down ♪
MELVIN:
Can you believe that man?
Was that a yes or a no?
That's a possible maybe.
♪ Ooh, I love to
dance a little sidestep
♪ Now they see me Now they don't
♪ I've come and gone
♪ And ooh I love to sweep
around the wide step
♪ Cut a little swath
and lead the people on
♪ Ooh, I love to
dance a little sidestep
sweep around the wide step
♪ Cut a little
swath and lead the people
♪ On ♪
(EXHALES)
WOMAN: Governor? I have
Sheriff Dodd from Gilbert
waiting outside to see you.
He's been here since early this
morning and is very insistent.
Swearin' Sheriff Dodd?
The one on TV?
No, no, no, no... Hi, Sheriff!
Just talkin' about you.
How are ya?
Governor. I know I'm way out of
line comin' up here like this,
but before you closed
down the Chicken Ranch,
I wanted you
to know all the facts.
But I haven't made that
decision yet! Good.
My aides are
still workin' on that.
Well, the Chicken...
The Chicken Ranch has been in my
county since before I was born.
Its doors have been open to soldiers
and presidents and farmers.
Even governors who can remember
what a great institution it is.
No need to bring
that up, Sheriff.
I ain't
threatenin' you, Governor.
Whatever you say, I'm gonna do.
But think of
the people out there.
I've known Miss
Mona for 12 years.
You're never gonna
meet a finer woman.
She never refuses a charity.
The whole town likes her.
Hospital fund, new swimmin'
pool, even the Little Leaguers.
She bought 'em uniforms so they wouldn't
have to play in their overalls.
Well.
I wasn't aware of
her civic generosity.
(POUNDS FIST)
But the law is the law!
Sometimes it's gotta be changed.
I been fightin'
crime all my life,
but let's not confuse crime
with committin' a sin.
You can't legislate morality.
Those girls out there have never
caused any trouble to anybody.
They're healthy, taxpayin',
law-abidin' citizens
who supply
a demand and provide an
economic asset to the community.
Whew. Ed Earl.
You ever think about runnin' for office?
Huh? I swear.
You make that whorehouse
sound like a
damn nonprofit
recreational facility.
Governor, if
the citizens who elected me
found it necessary
for me to close it down,
I would close it down.
If Miss Mona and the girls that work
for her were jeopardizin' the health,
wealth or moral scruples of the
community, I would close it down.
If the place was just
a piddlin' nuisance,
an eyesore, a fire hazard,
I would close it down!
But there's nothin'.
No reason except
the goddam cries
of a muckrakin'
sensationalist on television.
Here they are, Governor.
What you've been waitin' for.
Aha. I'm sorry, Ed Earl.
But the Chicken Ranch loses,
42 to 37, with 21% undecided.
What is that?
The polls. You can't expect
me to go against the polls.
This is what the people want.
Melvin still outside? Maybe I can
catch the television cameras
before they leave.
Good seein' ya.
But it's not
what my people want.
Shaw's over, Sheriff.
Close it down!
CROWD: Hooray! Aha!
♪ Melvin Thorpe
has done it once again
♪ He's shone his
light and now we see
♪ Melvin Thorpe will
go through thick and thin
♪ And lead us on to victory ♪
(DOGETTES CONTINUE SINGING)
♪ Ooh, I love to
dance a little sidestep
♪ Now they see me Now they don't
♪ I've come and gone
♪ And ooh I love to sweep
around the wide step
♪ Cut a little swath
and lead the people on
DOGETTES: ♪ Melvin Thorpe
has done it once again
♪ He's shone his
light and now we see
♪ Melvin Thorpe will
go through thick and thin
♪ And lead us on to victory
♪ Melvin Thorpe
has done it once again
♪ He's shone his
light and now we see ♪
(LAUGHING) I'd love to see
that sheriff's face right now!
That Chicken Ranch
is gonna get it in the neck!
And Miss Mona,
she's gonna get hers, too.
DOGETTES: I' For all to see ♪
(SCREAMS)
♪ Melvin Thorpe will go through
thick and thin He'll lead us all to
♪ Victory ♪
ED EARL: Sorry son of a bitch.
(PHONE RINGS)
(RINGING)
Hello?
Mona, this is an official call.
As the Sheriff of
Lanville County,
it's my duty to tell you that...
Why don't you just get
to the point, Sheriff?
I gotta close you down.
I see.
How long do we have?
Be better to do it
as soon as possible.
I understand.
Mona.
About the other night.
I lost my temper.
I said some things
I shouldn't have said.
I want to apologize.
Oh, it's all right, Ed Earl.
I think we both said a whole
lot of things we regret.
If there's ever
anything I can do...
No, thank you. I think
you've done all you could.
I have to tell my girls.
(BELL DINGS)
Well, the news has come.
Just got a call
from the Sheriff,
and we are closed down.
Immediately and permanently.
WOMAN: Oh. What'll we do?
Well, Las Vegas, here I come.
Damn! I thought
when the Sheriff went
up to Austin to
speak to the Governor,
we'd get a reprieve.
What did you say?
Didn't you know
about that, Miss Mona?
He drove up last night.
The whole town's talkin' about
the way he fought for you.
Didn't he tell you that?
No. No, he didn't.
♪ Hey, maybe I'll dye my hair
♪ Maybe I'll move somewhere
♪ Maybe I'll get a car
♪ Maybe I'll drive so
far they'll all lose track
♪ Me, I'll bounce right back
♪ Maybe I'll sleep real late
♪ Maybe I'll lose some weight
♪ Maybe I'll clear my junk
♪ Maybe I'll just
get drunk on apple wine
♪ Me,
I'll be just fine and dandy
♪ Lord, it's like
a hard candy Christmas
♪ I'm barely getting through
♪ Tomorrow
♪ But still I won't let
♪ Sorrow bring me way down
♪ I'll be fine and dandy
♪ Lord, it's like
a hard candy Christmas
♪ I'm barely gettin' through
♪ Tomorrow
♪ But still I won't let
sorrow bring me way down
♪ Hey, maybe I'll learn to sew
♪ Hey, maybe I'll just lie low
♪ Maybe I'll hit the bars
♪ Maybe I'll count
the stars until the dawn
♪ Me, I will go on
♪ Maybe I'll settle down
♪ Maybe I'll just leave town
♪ Maybe I'll have some fun
♪ Maybe I'll meet
someone and make him mine
♪ Me, I'll be just fine
♪ And dandy
♪ Lord, it's like
a hard candy Christmas
♪ I'm barely
gettin ' through tomorrow
♪ But still I won't let sorrow
bring me way down
♪ I'll be fine and dandy
♪ Lord, it's like
a hard candy Christmas
♪ I'm barely
gettin ' through tomorrow
♪ But still I won't let
♪ Sorrow bring me way down
♪ I'll be fine and dandy
♪ Lord, it's like
a hard candy Christmas
♪ I'm barely
gettin ' through tomorrow
♪ But still I won't let
♪ Sorrow bring me way down
♪ I'll be fine
♪ I'll be fine ♪
FRED: So the girls left
and it was a sorry
day for Lanville County.
It's kinda like
the end of an era.
You know, like when you
graduate from high school?
Things are just
never the same again.
Ed Earl's up in
the state legislature now,
and I became the Sheriff.
I suppose you're wonderin'
what happened to Miss Mona.
Well, Ed Earl drove up
there on her last day.
Hey, Sheriff.
Good morning, Jewel.
I'm so pleased to see ya. I
knew you couldn't let me leave
without a sweet
goodbye for your old Porky.
(CHUCKLES)
Goodbye, Jewel.
Goodbye, Sheriff.
I sure hope you come up north
to visit Miss Mona and me.
Where is she?
Inside.
See you're takin'
the old juke with you.
(LAUGHING) You know I couldn't
leave without my bell and my box.
Ed Earl?
This old place looks
kinda funny, don't it?
Ben Sawtuck bought all
my furniture and fixtures
and Langston downtown
is gonna sell the rest.
Mona, there's
something I wanna tell you.
I want you to
thank your boys for me.
Those sightseers and
reporters would have
got all out of
hand if it hadn't been
for your deputies
down at the gate.
Mona,
you know me better than that.
Ed Earl, I believe
the thing for you to do is
just to put this
whole thing behind you
just as quick as you can.
I've made a little money, I've laughed
some, I've danced to the music.
It's just time to pay
the fiddler, that's all.
Mona, we've been
together a long time.
Sometimes I think you know me
better than I know myself.
So you know how hard
this is for me to say.
I love you.
Will you marry me?
Oh, Ed Earl, I've loved you
since I was 16-years-old.
But I've thought about
this for a long time.
And as much as I'd
love for it to work,
I know deep down in my heart
it ain't never gonna be.
Didn't you hear what I said?
I did, darlin'.
But it's gonna
always be just like it is.
There just ain't no way
in this world it can work.
We could make it work.
Just have to give it a chance.
♪ If I
♪ Should stay
♪ Well, I would only
♪ Be in your way
♪ And so I'll go
♪ And yet, I know
♪ That I'll think of you
♪ Each step of the way
♪ And I
♪ Will always
♪ Love you
♪ I will always
♪ Bittersweet
♪ Memories
♪ I guess that's all
I'll be takin' with me
♪ Good-bye
♪ Oh, please, don't cry
♪ 'Cause we both know
that I'm not what you need
♪ But I
♪ Will always
♪ Love you
♪ I will always
♪ Love you ♪
I know you're
gonna get your dream.
And I know you're gonna do a real
good job in the legislature.
But if you was to marry me...
Wait, a second.
I love you.
I don't give
a damn what people say.
ED EARL: Jewel!
Hold it right there!
JEWEL: What's that, Sheriff?
Which one of them bags is hers?
That one.
And that one there, there...
on, Sheriff! (CHUCKLES)
JEWEL: I always knew you'd
come through! (LAUGHING)
on! (LAUGHS)
FRED". Well, that's pretty darn
close to the way it happened.
The old Watchdog, Melvin P.
Thorpe, got what he wanted.
Miss Mona married Ed Earl
and they got what they wanted.
And the people of Texas, well,
they got what they wanted.
Another legend, the legend
of the Chicken Ranch.
♪ It's just a little bitty
pissant country place
♪ Nothin' much to see
♪ No drinkin' allowed
We get a nice quiet crowd
♪ Plain as it can be
♪ It's just a piddly, squattin'
old-time country place
♪ Nothin' too high-toned
♪ Just lots of goodwill
and maybe one small thrill
♪ But there's
nothin' dirty goin' on
♪ It's just a little
bitty pissant country place
♪ Nothin' much to see
♪ No drinkin' allowed
We get a nice quiet crowd
♪ Plain as it can be
♪ It's just a piddly, squattin'
old-time country place
♪ Nothin' too high-toned
♪ Just lots of goodwill
and maybe one small thrill
♪ But there's
nothin' dirty goin' on
♪ Nothin' dirty goin' on ♪
Y'all come back now, ya hear?