(LAUGHS)
- I'm Statler.
- I'm Waldorf.
We're here to heckle
The Muppet Movie.
Gentlemen, that's straight ahead.
Private screening room D.
- Private screening?
- Yeah, they're afraid to show it in public.
(LAUGHING)
STATLER: Oh, oh. Look at this place.
What a dump.
WALDORF: Bunch of weirdos
around here. Look at 'em.
- Yes, I know you all want to sit with moi.
- Hey, lady. Is this seat taken?
Hey, you! Hey! Bring that back.
I'm so nervous. If I'm not funny,
I won't be able to live with myself.
Well, then you'll have to get
another apartment, won't you?
You know,
I hear this movie is dynamite.
Get your fresh organic popcorn.
Only a buck.
Honey. Buy me some, please.
Sure, Momma.
Nothin's too good for my woman.
Woman! Woman! Woman!
- Well, I like the movie fine so far.
- It hasn't started yet.
- That's what I like about it.
- (BOTH CHUCKLING)
Yie, yie, yie, yie, yie!
Do it. Yay! (LAUGHING)
Oh, hey, Mr. The Frog.
Is it okay for me and my boomerang fish
to be in your movie?
Hey!
I told you, Lew.
Not in the movie or at the screening.
Hey, but watch. Whoa!
(CLEARS THROAT) Kermit, does
this film have socially redeeming value?
Oh, I... I certainly hope so, Sam.
Sorry about that.
- Kermie.
- Oh, hi, Piggy.
Kermie, I tried to save you a seat,
but somebody took it.
Hi, everybody, and welcome to the
first screening of The Muppet Movie.
(ALL CHEERING)
But before we begin, I'd like to thank
everyone who contributed to this film,
starting with the little people,
from the hairdressers to special effects.
That's enough of that, Harry.
- (ALL CLAMORING)
- Boom! Blow it up. Ka-boom!
- MUPPET: Boring.
- To the costume designers.
- To the prop makers.
- MISS PIGGY: Kermie, Kermie.
Speeches are not necessary, dear.
Roll film.
Yeah, but I'd like to thank everybody for
all of their hard work and their patience
- and their...
- Roll film! Roll film!
Roll film.
(SHUSHING)
Excuse me.
Uncle Kermit, is this about
how the Muppets really got started?
Well, it's sort of approximately
how it happened.
KERMIT: (SINGING) Why are there
so many songs about rainbows
And what's on the other side?
Rainbows are visions
But only illusions
And rainbows have nothing to hide
So we've been told
And some choose to believe it
I know they're wrong, wait and see
Someday we'll find it
The rainbow connection
The lovers, the dreamers and me
Who said that every wish
Would be heard and answered
When wished on the morning star?
Somebody thought of that
And someone believed it
Look what it's done so far
What's so amazing
That keeps us stargazing?
And what do we think we might see?
Someday we'll find it
The rainbow connection
The lovers, the dreamers and me
All of us under its spell
We know that it's probably magic
Have you been half asleep?
And have you heard voices?
I've heard them calling my name
Is this the sweet sound
That calls the young sailors?
The voice might be one and the same
I've heard it too many times to ignore it
It's something that I'm supposed to be
Someday we'll find it
The rainbow connection
The lovers, the dreamers and me
(VOCALIZING)
MAN: Help! Hello.
This is a serious call for help.
- Yeah?
- Someone help.
Ah, I... Oh, oh.
You, you with the banjo.
Can you help me?
I have lost my sense of direction.
Have you tried Hare Krishna?
Ha, ha. No.
- No. I mean I'm really lost.
- (FLY BUZZING)
One second.
Darn, I missed. You know,
that's the first thing to go on a frog.
His tongue. The tongue goes
and you can't catch flies.
That's rough.
I'm sorry about your tongue,
but I have to get out of this swamp.
I have to catch a plane.
With that tongue? No way.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
But seriously,
there's a boat dock just downstream.
- Thank you.
- Just watch out for the alligators.
I will.
- Alligators?
- That's right.
Did you say alligators?
Read my lips, alligators.
It's just that I'm not used to alligators
where I come from.
See, I'm an agent.
I... I winged in from Hollywood.
- Hollywood?
- That's right.
Did you say Hollywood?
Read my lips, Hollywood. You know...
Hollywood
The dream factory, the magic store.
Hey, don't you ever go to the movies?
Oh, sure. There's a double feature
in town every Saturday.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
- Wait a minute.
- What?
There's an ad in here
that you should be very interested in.
- Feast your eyes on that.
- Uh...
"World Wide Studios
announces open auditions for frogs
"wishing to become rich and famous."
Well, thanks anyway,
but I'm really pretty happy where I am.
Oh, oh, if I were you,
I would give this audition
very careful consideration.
You've got talent, kid.
Singin', tellin' jokes.
I mean, if you get your tongue fixed,
who knows?
You could make
millions of people happy.
- Millions of people happy?
- Millions.
Hey, if you ever come west
to Hollywood, look me up.
Bernie the Agent.
Hey, well, listen, Bernie, why don't you
say hello to Arnie the Alligator?
- What?
- Arnie.
(SCREAMING)
Arnie, wait a minute. Careful, Arnie.
Stay! Stay!
Arnie, that's okay. Leave him alone.
It's all right, he's from Hollywood.
Hollywood. Gee.
I...
I'd miss this old swamp, but...
Millions of people happy.
(PLAYS NOTE)
What the...
MAN: Okay, okay, you guys.
Now, come on. Do what I tell you.
I don't know where you're...
All right, now...
Don't step on that asphalt!
I told you not to step on it.
We gotta get this... Off the asphalt!
I told you, stay off the asphalt!
Hey, look at him.
Oh, big legs.
MAN: Hey, you on the bike!
Watch out! Watch out!
- Watch out!
- Oh, my... Ah!
Watch out!
Oh!
Hmm.
That's pretty dangerous, building
a road in the middle of the street.
I mean, if frogs couldn't hop,
I'd be gone with the Schwinn.
KERMIT: The El Sleezo Cafe.
Hmm.
Foreign food.
Doesn't smell promising,
but a frog's gotta eat.
(CAFE PATRONS ARGUING)
(GASPS)
KERMIT: Wow.
Rough place, huh?
That's the toughest, meanest, filthiest,
pesthole on the face of the Earth.
Well, why not complain to the owner?
I am the owner.
MAN: Watch out.
Hot plates comin' through. Look out.
All right, you got
your French-fried frog legs on Cotton.
You got your frog legs on Eugenie.
You got your frog legs stroganoff.
- Everybody happy? All right.
- Ugh!
Hello, sailor. Buy me a drink?
Well, you see,
I'm not a sailor, I'm a frog.
Cut the small talk and buy me a drink.
- But I don't even know you.
- Hey. You makin' a move on my girl?
- No, sir.
- He did, too. He touched me.
Ugh! Go wash. You'll get warts.
- No, you see, that's just a myth.
- Yeah, but she's my "myth."
- No, no. Myth, myth.
- Yeth?
What the hey?
(CLOCK RINGING)
Showtime. Showtime at the El Sleezo.
PIANIST: And now, filling in for
the vacationing El Sleezo dancing girls,
the funny, furry, fabulous Fozzie Bear.
Wacka, wacka, wacka, wacka.
Hey, you're a great crowd.
Thank you, thank you and thank you.
- Hey, wacka, wacka.
- (HONKING)
Ah, wacka, wacka, wacka.
Here I am, Fozzie Bear,
to tell you jokes both old and rare.
Wacka, wacka, wacka.
(BOOING)
Ha, ha. Let's start things off with a bang.
Thank you, sir.
Wacka, wacka, wacka, wacka, wacka.
This guy's lost.
Maybe he should try Hare Krishna.
Grief, it's a running gag.
Uh...
There was this sailor who was so fat...
How fat was he?
Uh...
He was so fat that everybody liked him
and there was
nothing funny about him at all.
(CROWD BOOING)
FOZZIE: No problem.
Oh, wait, please.
Oh, please. Please wait.
I'm trying so hard. Please don't do that.
I'm a professional.
I've had three performances.
- Cut, cut, please.
- Do you know any dance routines?
What? Not really. Do you?
- Play something snappy.
- You got it.
(PLAYS JAUNTY MUSIC)
- Now dance.
- What?
- Dance.
- Yes, sir.
Ah! Wacka, wacka.
Aha, wacka, wacka.
Ah!
It's too bad the dancing girls are
on vacation. The crowd is getting ugly.
Ha, ha. You think this crowd's ugly,
you should see the dancing girls.
FOZZIE: Two, three, four.
(CROWD SHOUTS)
- Two, three, kick.
- Kick. Yeah, sorry.
Coming home.
FOZZIE: Argh!
Please. I just cleaned the fur.
Please. Oh.
(KERMIT GROANS)
I hope you appreciate
that I'm doing all my own stunts.
Wacka wacka.
Okay, everybody. Drinks on the house.
(CHEERING)
Drinks on the house!
Man, come on, let's go.
- Drinks on the house.
- Go, go. On the house.
MAN: Drinks on the house.
I don't see no drinks up here.
What's he talkin' about?
The bartender said
there were drinks on the house.
Works every time.
Well... Well, hey, listen.
My name is Kermit the Frog
and I'm on my way to Hollywood.
- Hollywood?
- You wanna join me?
Big-time show biz.
That's always been my dream.
Yeah, well, they're holding auditions
for frogs next week.
And if they need frogs,
they must need bears, too.
Oh.
My car's right outside.
Gee, a Studebaker.
Where did you get it?
- My uncle left it to me.
- Huh? Is he dead?
No, he's hibernating.
You know, Fozzie,
you really do have a lot of talent.
Thank you.
You know, how about you and me
putting together an act?
Oh, no. Sorry. I only work as a single.
Oh, okay.
All right. You talked me into it.
We'll be a team.
Oh, good.
- What's this?
- Hey, you better pull over here.
Yes, sir.
(BRAKES SCREECH)
- (BANGING)
- FOZZIE: Ah.
Hey, what's going on?
Howdy, Mr. Frog.
- I'm a businessman with a proposition.
- What?
Let me show you somethin'
that might change your whole life.
Huh.
Hop right on over here,
my little green friend.
- Listen, mister.
- That's it.
This is the kind of chance
you can't afford to pass up.
- (GASPS)
- No, now, don't be afraid.
- Watch the window.
- Hm.
- KERMIT: What's that?
- FOZZIE: Ah.
- (KERMIT GASPS)
- Hi, I'm Doc Hopper,
invitin' you to hop on down and get
some Hopper's French-fried frog legs.
Right here at the sign
of the bright green legs.
- Good grief.
- Come on.
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry.
(SINGING)
Frog legs, frog legs, frog legs are fine
Hopper's is the place you should dine
There's cheese legs
Bacon legs, chili legs too
French-fried frog legs barbecued
Oh, Fozzie. Ugh.
If you want just a snack
Don't worry.
Then here is the one
A frog leg burger on a bright green bun
(KERMIT WINCES)
That is terrible.
That's the most appalling, disgusting,
revolting thing I've ever seen.
I know. I'm a great businessman
and a sweet fella,
but I do lack the skills of a performer.
You also make a lousy frog.
You, on the other hand,
make a terrific frog.
- What?
- He's right, you know.
- You are very likable, Kermit.
- The bear's right.
You, my little likable friend, are gonna
do all our television commercials.
- No way.
- Hold it. Now, just a minute.
There's $500 in it for you up-front.
$500 is just the beginning.
You could be earning this much
every year.
- Let's go, Fozzie.
- $500?
Would you consider
a bear in a frog suit?
- Fozzie.
- Yes, sir. I just lost my head. I...
Now, just a minute, Mr. Frog.
Everything's negotiable.
- FOZZIE: Okay, here we go, here we go.
- (BANGING)
- FOZZIE: Sorry.
- Hey, that's my Caddy!
- Just get it in gear, Fozzie.
- Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
HOPPER:
Frog, it's money we're talking about.
Max!
- Follow that frog.
- (TIRES SQUEAL)
- Max!
- (BRAKES SCREECH)
Follow that frog with me in the car!
I'm sorry, Doc. I just got excited.
Hey, do you like the frog?
Isn't he terrific, Doc?
Terrific, Max, terrific. Now go!
But you promised me a reward.
Later, Max. Now follow that frog.
- FOZZIE: Oh, it's a gorgeous day.
- KERMIT: Yep, certainly is.
- Yep, terrific day for a drive.
- It's beautiful country out here.
A frog and a bear seeing America.
(SINGING) Movin' right along
in search of good times and good news
With good friends, you can't lose
This could become a habit
Opportunity knocks once
Let's reach out and grab it
- Yeah!
- Together we'll nab it
We'll hitchhike, bus, or Yellow Cab it
Cab it?
BOTH: Movin' right along
Footloose and fancy-free
Getting there is half the fun
Come share it with me
Movin' right along
KERMIT: We'll learn to share the load
FOZZIE: We don't need a map
to keep this show on the road
Hey, Fozzie, I want you to turn left
if you come to a fork in the road.
Yes, sir. Turn left at
the fork in the road.
FOZZIE: Kermit.
KERMIT: I don't believe that.
KERMIT: (SINGING) Movin' right along
We've found a life on the highway
FOZZIE: And your way is my way
KERMIT: So trust my navigation
FOZZIE: California, here we come
Come pie in the sky land
KERMIT: Palm trees and warm sand
Though sadly we just left Rhode Island
- We did what?
- Just forget it.
BOTH: Movin' right along
Hey, LA, where have you gone?
FOZZIE: Send someone to fetch us
We're in Saskatchewan
BOTH: Movin' right along
You take it, you know best
FOZZIE: Hey, I've never seen
the sun come up in the west
Ah.
A bear in his natural habitat.
A Studebaker.
- Hey, Fozzie, look up ahead.
- What is that?
Maybe we should give him a ride.
I don't know. He's pretty big.
- Hey, there. Want a lift?
- Oh, no, thanks.
I'm on my way to New York City
to try to break into public television.
Ah.
Good luck.
BOTH: (SINGING) Movin' right along
We're truly birds of a feather
We're in this together
And we know where we're goin'
Movie stars with flashy cars
and life with the top down
We're stormin' the big town
Yeah, storm is right.
Should it be snowing?
No, I don't think so.
BOTH: Movin' right along
Footloose and fancy-free
You're ready for the big time
Is it ready for me?
Movin' right along
KERMIT: Hey.
Hey, Fozzie, look up ahead there.
There's one of those
Doc Hopper billboards.
- Maybe you'd better pull over.
- Yes, sir.
Oh, look at that.
Kermit, that's you.
(LAUGHING)
You got the picture, boy?
You see what I mean?
Kermit the Frog, symbol of
Doc Hopper's French-fried frog legs.
Isn't that splendid? Just splendid.
Just take a look at it.
All I can see are millions of frogs
on tiny crutches.
Now, listen, boy.
Don't you wanna be rich and famous?
- Not workin' for you, I don't.
- That's right.
- Crutches?
- Shut up, Max.
We're a small-time operation,
but we're expandin'.
Expandin', just like you frogs expand.
Don't you frogs expand?
- That's a myth.
- What?
Myth! Myth!
Yeth?
BOTH: Huh?
- Come on, Bear. Burn rubber.
- Yes, sir.
Hey, Frog!
That's the second time!
Max, I've done my best with that frog.
Now's the time to do my worst.
- Open the door.
- No! You open the door.
- What?
- I'm through, Doc. The frog is right.
You're asking him to do something
terrible. I can't be a part of it.
It's a moral decision and I'll stand by it.
- I'll double your percentage.
- I'll open the door.
FOZZIE: Kermit, where are we?
Well, let's see.
We were just traveling down
this little black line here.
And we just crossed
that little red line over here.
Well, how about...
Let's take the blue line, huh?
- No, we can't take that. That's a river.
- Oh, I knew that.
- Yeah, sure.
- Listen, Kermit, why don't we just go...
- Fozzie. Fozzie.
- Huh. Yeah?
Who's driving?
(BOTH SCREAM)
- KERMIT: Look out! Stop!
- FOZZIE: No problem.
- Okay, back it up.
- Ah, yes, sir.
- Fozzie, where did you learn to drive?
- I took a correspondence course.
This looks like a nice quiet spot.
Uh-huh.
Boy, it feels like
we've been driving for days.
Yeah. Funny, I'm still wide awake.
Yeah, me, too.
(SNORING)
Me, too.
(ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING)
- (BAND PLAYING)
- What? What? What? I'm up, I'm up.
What's that?
They don't look like Presbyterians
to me.
Hey, cool it, everybody.
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Our gentle mornin' melodies
have attracted wanderin' admirers.
- Hey, who are you guys?
- We am, is, are and be
they whom as are known as
the Electric Mayhem.
- (LAUGHING)
- For sure.
He's Dr. Teeth.
Golden teeth and golden tones.
Welcome to my presence.
- Thank you.
- Fozzie.
- I'm Floyd, I blow bass.
- And I'm...
I'm...
Zoot. Sax is your ax.
Uh-oh. Zoot's skipped a groove again.
Wow, like, I'm Janice.
I'm lead guitar, for surely.
(ROARS)
Oh, yeah. That's Animal.
Show 'em what you do, Animal.
I want to eat drums.
No, no. Beat drums, beat drums.
Beat drums. Beat drums.
- Down, Animal. Back. Sit.
- Down. Back. Sit.
MUPPET: Hey, don't forget about me.
I'm Scooter, the band's road manager.
Oh, yeah. The road manager.
We couldn't go anywhere without him.
- He's the man with the contacts?
- No, he's the man with the van.
Yeah, we're takin' this old church
and turnin' it into a coffeehouse.
Yeah, with real good music
and organic refreshments.
It'll be so fine and laid-back
and mellow and profitable.
ANIMAL: Profitable.
Yeah, but what brings you dudes here?
Listen, see, Kermit here,
he was living in the swamp...
- Fozzie.
...and then a fisherman came along.
Fozzie, you can't tell 'em
the whole story.
You'll bore the audience.
Oh, sorry.
But, Kermit,
the band here wants to know.
Well, let 'em read the screenplay.
Ah! Yes, sir.
Uh...
You see, it starts here on page one.
The Muppet Movie, huh?
Hmm. Let's see.
"Exterior. Swamp. Day.
In a long helicopter shot,
"we discover Kermit the Frog
playin' his banjo and singin'.
"A Hollywood agent
starts the frog travelin' west.
"Doc Hopper comes on strong
and they get to this church.
"Interior. Church. Day.
"Fozzie. 'They don't look like
Presbyterians to me.'
"Kermit and Fozzie
come walkin' down the aisle
"to the thunderously loud music
of Dr. Teeth and the Electric Mayhem."
- Which am us.
- For sure, for sure.
This is a narrative
of very heavy-duty proportions.
Yeah. Cosmic, man.
We gotta keep his little froggy self
away from this Hopper dude.
Too true, too true.
It is indeed a problem
for us to probosculate upon.
But it seems to me that the frog and
the bear are temporarily out of service.
(BOTH SNORING)
Oh, wow, like, what can we do
to help them?
- Well, if this were the movies...
- Which it is.
...we'd think of a clever plot device.
Like disguising their car
so they won't be recognized.
Right. Two, three, four.
Oh, yeah!
Whoo!
All right.
(SINGING)
Everybody's lover, everybody's brother
I wanna be your lifetime friend
Crazy as a rocket, nothin' in my pocket
I'll keep it at the rainbow's end
I never think of money
I think of milk and honey
Grinnin' like a Cheshire cat
I focus on the pleasure
Somethin' I can treasure
Can you picture that?
Oh, yeah.
Hey, Floyd. Take a verse.
(SINGING) Let me take your picture
Add it to the mixture
There it is, I got you now
Really nothin' to it, anyone can do it
It's easy and we all know how
Now begins the changin'
Mental rearrangin'
Nothin's really where it's at
Now the Eiffel Tower's
holdin' up a flower
I gave it to a Texas cat
Fact is there's nothin' out there
you can't do
Yeah, even Santa Claus
believes in you
Beat down the walls
Begin, believe, begat
Be a better drummer
Be an up-and-comer
Can you picture that?
Only what you got
All of us are winnin'
Pickin' and a-grinnin'
Lordy, but I love to jam
Jelly-belly gigglin'
Dancin' and a-wigglin'
Honey, that's the way I am
I lost my heart in Texas
Northern lights affects us
I keep it underneath my hat
Aurora Borealis
Shinin' down on Dallas
Can you picture that?
Can you picture?
You gotta see it in your mind
You know it's quick and easy to find
Can you picture?
You don't have to buy a frame
Can you picture that?
- Use it if you need it
- Don't forget to feed it
Can you picture that?
FLOYD: Great job.
Doc Hopper will never
recognize you now.
- I don't know how to thank you guys.
- I don't know why to thank you guys.
Our pleasure, green stuff.
Are you sure you won't
come with us to Hollywood?
Can't, baby,
but when you get rich and famous,
maybe we'll show up
and exploit your wealth.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Movin' right along, Fozzie.
ANIMAL: Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
(CHANTING) Hollywood! Hollywood!
Hollywood!
Hollywood! Hollywood! Hollywood!
HOPPER: Remember,
this frog does everything.
He talks, he sings, he dances.
He tells jokes. He even rides a bicycle.
Max, find me a frog and a bear
in a tan Studebaker.
Gee, Doc. All I can see
is a frog and a bear
in a rainbow-colored Studebaker.
What?
- Fozzie, they're right behind us.
- I know, I know.
- Well, how did they recognize us?
- They recognized you.
- What do you mean?
- There's a hundred bears around.
I'm gaining on 'em, Doc.
I'm gaining on 'em.
- Can't you drive any faster?
- No, sir.
There's a sign up ahead there.
Pull in front of that.
- Move. Now duck.
- What?
- Get down, Fozzie.
- Yes, sir.
Aha!
(CLUCKING)
- GONZO: Oh, yeah?
- (CLUCKING)
GONZO: Uh-huh. Yeah.
Oh, I tell you, Camilla,
great plumbers are born, not made.
I'm a prince of plunger, fair maiden.
(CLUCKS)
GONZO: Yeah, yeah, yeah. We'll do
that. But first, wait till we get there.
Fozzie, look at that funny little truck.
Yeah, it's cute, huh?
- No, it's coming straight at us.
- (CLUCKS)
(ALL SCREAM)
KERMIT: We're gonna hit.
We missed it.
Oh, you call that a miss?
GONZO: Well, I'm getting in your car.
FOZZIE: Oh, boy.
You guys okay?
Why are you hopping up and down?
Because I'm hopping mad.
Guy's got a sense of humor.
- Hey, why don't you join us?
- Where are you going?
- We're following our dream.
- Really? I have a dream, too.
- KERMIT AND FOZZIE: Huh?
- But you'll think it's stupid.
- KERMIT: No, I won't.
- FOZZIE: Tell us, tell us.
Well, I wanna go to Bombay, India
and become a movie star.
CAMILLA: Ah.
You don't go to Bombay
to become a movie star.
You go where we're going, Hollywood.
Sure, if you wanna do it the easy way.
We picked up a weirdo.
KERMIT: Hey, look up ahead.
There's Mad Man Mooney's.
- FOZZIE: What's that?
- KERMIT: It's a used-car lot.
I think we can trade in both these
old cars and get one big one.
FOZZIE: Wait.
Trade in my uncle's Studebaker?
KERMIT: Sure.
FOZZIE: Oh, when he wakes up,
he'll kill me.
KERMIT: You're swinging this turn
very wide, Fozzie.
FOZZIE: Well, hold it, will you?
Just... Here we go. Up the bump.
KERMIT: There we go. Hold on. All right.
Pull up ahead there.
- FOZZIE: Look at these cars.
- GONZO: Kermit, Kermit, Kermit.
- Are you gonna sell my plunger, too?
- There's all kinds of great cars.
FOZZIE: No, he's not
gonna sell your plunger.
KERMIT: Look at 'em up there.
Pull it up a little further here, Fozzie.
FOZZIE: Where should I stop?
- How should I stop?
- KERMIT: A little bit farther.
- GONZO: Easy, easy.
- FOZZIE: Okay. Here?
(ALL SCREAMING)
- KERMIT: Everybody out of the car.
- FOZZIE: Okay. Chickens first.
Oh, my dear friends. Welcome
to Mad Man Mooney's hubcap heaven.
Today... Today is your lucky day.
- It is?
- Yes, it is. You, for example...
- You're driving the wrong car.
- I am?
I can put you in this German
street machine for only $2,000,
less a $12 trade-in on your old vehicle.
Now, this...
This car is one of the greatest...
Detachable fenders for narrow garages.
No, thanks.
Hey, what is this pile of...
Jack, get rid of this heap.
Come out here!
- What? What?
- What's the matter with you?
- That's my jack.
- Oh, hi, Jack.
Jack not name. Jack job.
How many times have I told you
not to talk to the customers?
- Gee, I know, but...
- Just move this.
Move it. You understand?
(HUMS)
FOZZIE: Wow. Ah!
But seriously, friends,
Mad Man Mooney doesn't believe
in all that dealing and wheeling.
No, the price on the sticker
is the price you pay.
- And never more and never less.
- (FLY BUZZING)
Ha.
We'll take that one for $11.95.
What?
Less our $12 trade-in.
You owe us a nickel.
Oh, thank you very much.
Hey, we're all going to Hollywood.
- Do you wanna come with us?
- Hollywood?
That's strange, he just ran away.
Well, movin' right along, Fozzie.
- Yes, sir.
- (CLUCKING)
(FOZZIE HUMMING)
KERMIT: Hey, watch where
you're going now, Fozzie.
FOZZIE: Yes, sir.
Hey!
Hey, where are you goin'?
Hey! Wait for me.
I wanna go to Hollywood.
Hey, wait for me!
Come on, guys. Wait! Please!
I wanna go to Hollywood.
(FAIRGROUND MUSIC PLAYING)
Testing, one, two, three. Testing.
Can you hear me?
Well, it's time to announce
the winner of this year's
Bogen County beauty pageant.
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
MAN: We sure grow 'em purdy
around here, don't we?
All right. Here they are.
- MAN: The first runner-up...
- What's over there, Kermit?
- MAN: Is Debbie-Sue Anderson.
- Over there. See?
Ah! Nice-looking girls, huh?
- Wow. Nice-looking chickens.
- What?
- Oh, no hard feelings, honey.
- MAN: Before announcing the winner,
I think we should thank
the judges of today's contest,
Edgar Bergen and Charlie McCarthy.
You're not gonna believe
who the winner is, folks.
- Come, now, Charlie. It's their movie.
- So it is. So it is.
And here she is, folks.
This year's Miss Bogen County...
Miss Piggy!
Oh. Oh.
Oh. Oh. Oh. Oh.
Thank you.
Wow, it's a pig. Did you see that?
Thank you, everyone. Thank you.
Oh. Oh, Debbie-Sue.
Oh, Elma-Jane.
Thank you. Thank you.
Ohh.
Thank you. Oh, oh, thank you.
Oh, kissy-kissy. Kissy-kissy.
Oh, thank you. Oh.
- Kermit, you know...
- Not... Not right now, Fozzie.
I just want to say one thing.
This is the happiest moment of my...
(SINGING) Never before
Have two souls joined so freely
And so fast
For me this is the first time
And the last
Is this an angel's wish
For men?
Never before
And never again
And where to find the words
To sing its worth
This love was bound for heaven
Not for Earth
This love was meant
To light the stars
But when we touched
We made it ours
And could they take it back?
Oh, no, they wouldn't dare
Why should they take it back
When there's enough
To share with all the world
And fill the heavens above
With leftover love?
Never before
A love that keeps on growing
On and on
To fill each lover's heart
And light the dawn
Is this an angel's wish
For men?
Never before
And never again
(WEDDING BELLS CHIME)
- Oh, oh.
- Thanks. Excuse me.
- Oh, yes. Of course.
- Yeah.
Listen, congratulations
on winning the beauty contest.
Thank you. Of course, normally,
I don't do anything so trivial.
- I am an actress-model.
- Oh, is that right?
Well... I...
I'm gonna be a performer, too.
Oh.
Hey, Kermit.
Who's the cute-lookin' pig?
I beg your pardon.
If you were a chicken,
you'd be impeccable.
Gonzo.
Hey, I thought we were
gonna go get some ice cream.
Oh, well, in a minute. I'll join you.
Um...
Well...
What are you doing in town,
short, green and handsome?
Well... We're headed west.
- Really?
- Yeah, but...
You know, I really should
join my friends for ice cream.
Oh.
You... You wanna come along?
Me? You mean it? Oh.
I'll be right back. Oh, oh.
Don't move.
Hmm.
Hello. I'd like an ice cream.
What do you want? Chocolate, vanilla,
coffee, peach fudge, rum, banana?
- Honey.
- Honey?
I beg your pardon. I hardly know you.
Ah.
But seriously,
I'd like a honey ice cream cone for me.
And a dragonfly ripple
for my friend, the frog.
Okay. One honey cone for the bear.
- And one dragonfly ripple for the frog.
- Ugh!
- Don't get 'em mixed up.
- Gotcha.
(CLUCKING)
(CAMILLA CLUCKS)
All right, all right, Camilla.
I'll get you a balloon,
but you have to pick the color.
Red or green?
- Can I give you a word of advice?
- GONZO: What?
Why not take both?
(GASPS)
What a wild idea.
Yeah. A beautiful chicken like that
deserves two balloons.
- You're right.
- I have guys come in all the time.
Sometimes they get a bunch of balloons
for their girls.
- They go gaga for it.
- Gaga? I'll take the whole bunch.
Gaga. Gaga. Aw.
Gonzo?
Wonder...
Where they went? Fozzie?
FOZZIE: Kermit. Kermit.
Hey, Kermit. Hey.
Where's your pig friend?
Well, I'm not really sure. She said
she was coming for ice cream, but...
Yoo-hoo. Yoo-hoo.
Here I am. Here I am.
- I'm packed. I'm packed.
- Yeah, so I see.
What for?
You said I could come with you.
Yeah, but...
To buy ice cream, not to Hollywood.
- We're going to Hollywood?
- No. I mean, listen...
When I... When I said...
I mean, well, when you heard...
Oh, brother.
GONZO: Oh! Oh!
(CLUCKING)
What? Gonzo?
(GONZO SCREAMS)
- KERMIT: Gonzo! What are you doing?
- MISS PIGGY: What?
About seven knots.
- We'll follow you. To the car.
- Yes, sir.
KERMIT: Gonzo, we're coming!
- KERMIT: Step on it, Fozzie!
- FOZZIE: Yes, sir.
MISS PIGGY: Oh, Kermit.
You're a born leader.
KERMIT: Now, where is he?
(SIGHS) Isn't this great?
Here I am floating in space.
This is the place to be.
Whoopee!
- Fozzie.
- Yes.
- Bear left.
- What?
- Right, Frog.
- What? That's cute.
- Never mind.
This is...
Look at our little car down there.
Oh, this is like flying.
Hey, this is flying.
I'm flying! Whoopee!
Doc, isn't that a frog up there?
No, that's a frog down here.
KERMIT: He's caught in a crosswind,
Fozzie.
We're gonna lose him.
FOZZIE: Oh, no.
- Oh, what are you doin', Doc?
- I'm goin' after the tires.
KERMIT: We're okay now.
The wind's shifted.
- Wait a minute. Stay with him, Fozzie.
- FOZZIE: Yeah.
- He's right above us.
- GONZO: Whoo-hoo!
- He's okay.
- Yeah. Hi, Gonzo.
- Fozzie, come back in here.
- What?
- Come back in here.
- Yes, sir.
Oh!
KERMIT: Why don't you
stay on the road?
Kermit!
KERMIT: Look out for the billboard.
MAX: No!
(GUNSHOT)
- Take off, Fozzie.
- Yes, sir.
Come back, you!
No frog's gonna
make a monkey out of me!
I'm back.
I don't understand any of this.
(SCREAMING)
I just gotta catch up with those guys.
MISS PIGGY: Kermit,
you were so courageous.
So magnificent.
- Gee, I don't know what to say.
- Say the bear was magnificent.
After all, I did the driving.
And I took a 100-foot belly flop
onto a moving car.
Yes, but Kermit assumed the awesome
responsibility of command.
- Gee.
- Oh, brother.
Um...
Why don't we stop somewhere
for the night
and have a quiet little dinner...
For two?
Terrific! I'll eat with you, Miss Piggy.
Not you, buzzard beak.
Just mon capitaine
and moi.
Well... That... That might be nice.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh. Wow.
Good evening, Miss Piggy.
You look lovely tonight.
Thank you.
I'm so sorry if I kept you waiting.
Oh, it... It was worth it.
How charming of vous.
I... I took the liberty
of ordering us some wine.
Mmm.
Oh, waiter.
Yes?
May I help you?
The... The wine, please.
Mmm.
You mad, impetuous thing.
It's champagne.
Not exactly. Sparkling muscatel.
One of the finest wines of Idaho.
Well, you may serve us now, please.
Oh, may I?
- Look how he does that.
- Yep.
- Very suave.
- Mmm.
Don't you want to smell the bottle cap?
Oh.
- Mmm-hmm. Smells good.
- Mmm. Yes.
- Would you like to taste it first?
- Well...
I think he's supposed to.
Would you taste it for us, please?
Ugh!
- Excellent choice.
- Should be for 95 cents.
Hmm.
- And may we have straws, please?
- Yes.
I expected that.
Thank you. That'll be all for now.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
- Here's to you, Miss Piggy.
- Oh.
Drink up.
(SLURPING)
Oh.
Makes me giggly.
The wine?
Everything.
It's a beautiful evening, isn't it?
Mmm-hmm.
The moon is just lovely.
You know, Miss Piggy,
the moon doesn't look like you.
(WHIMPERS)
- WAITER: Miss Piggy.
- Hmm.
Miss Piggy.
- Are you Miss Piggy?
- Yes.
- Telephone.
- Oh.
Uh... Oh...
Kermie, I did place
one phone call to my agent.
It'll only be an eensy-teensy moment.
What the hey?
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(SLOW BLUES PLAYING)
Evenin'. Rowlf, Rowlf the Dog.
Sit yourself down.
- Kermit, Kermit the Frog.
- Pleased to meet you.
I'm no Heifetz, but I get by.
That was... That was very nice.
- (SNIFFS)
- Oh.
A broken heart, right?
- Does it show?
- Listen.
When you've been ticklin' the ivories
as long as I have,
you've seen a broken heart
for every drop of rain,
a shattered dream for every fallen star.
Exactly. She just walked out on me.
Yeah? Typical. That's why I live alone.
- You do, huh?
- You bet.
I finish work, I go home, read a book,
have a couple of beers,
take myself for a walk and go to bed.
Nice and simple.
Stay away from women, that's my motto.
- But I can't.
- Neither can I. That's my trouble.
(SINGING) You can't live with 'em
You can't live without 'em
There's somethin'
irresistible-ish about 'em
We grin and bear it
'cause the nights are long
I hope that
somethin' better comes along
I see what you mean.
It's no good complainin'
And pointless to holler
If she's a beauty
She'll get under your collar
She made a monkey
out of old King Kong
I hope that
somethin' better comes along
Still, it's fun when they're fetchin'
And agree to see an etching
that you keep at your lily pad
There is no solution
It's part of evolution
The pitter-patter of souls
The little feet of tadpoles
Rowlf, tadpoles don't have feet.
Oh, sorry about that. Two, three, four.
There's no limitation
to mixin' and matchin'
Some get an itchin'
for a critter they've been scratchin'
A skunk was badgered
The results were strong
I hope that somethin' better
I hope that
somethin' better comes along
(SCATTING)
WAITER: Phone call for Kermit the Frog.
- Are you Kermit the Frog?
- Yeah.
Phone.
Huh.
It's not often you see a guy that green
have the blues that bad.
- Hello.
- Kermie, please...
- Piggy, is that you?
- HOPPER: Yes, that's her.
And this is Doc Hopper.
You listen, Frog. And listen good.
Step outside the motel right now.
My guys will meet you there.
Well... What if I don't?
Then your girlfriend
will be ham-hocked by breakfast.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Kermie. Don't, don't, don't, don't.
(LAUGHS)
Uh, uh...
Are you the guys I'm supposed to meet?
That's good, Glen. That's good.
That's nice and tight.
- The Professor's here, Doc.
- Show him in. Show him in.
Kermie, I'm not a bit worried.
I know you're planning
something bold and clever.
Well, I got us this far, didn't I?
(LAUGHS)
- How are you?
- Ah, Professor Krassman.
It's good to see you, Doc,
you little rustic devil, you.
Where's my victim?
I mean, patient?
Step this way, Professor.
Let me introduce you to your patient.
Professor Krassman is the world's
leadin' authority
on mind control in frogs.
It's a very rapidly growing field.
You like garlic, don't you?
Tell us what you're gonna do
to our little Kermit.
Well, we're going to perform
an electronic cerebrectomy.
- Hmm?
- A what?
- (GASPS)
- Electronic cerebrectomy.
What's that?
It's something so sensational
that you'll have to hold on to your hat.
Yes?
When a German scientist says,
"Hold on to your hat,"
it's not casual conversation.
Hold on to your hat! Hat! Hold! Good.
Now, what we're going to do is bring out
a machine that's going to wow you.
Bertram! Bertram, you...
Bring out the machine!
Wait till you see this.
You think we're sleeping in Dsseldorf?
You think
we're taking a nap in Cologne?
No, we're working at night.
Each night a new dial, a new knob...
Electronic...
Cerebrectomy, cerebrectomy.
Electronic cerebrectomy.
- What does it do?
- What does it do? What does it do?
It turns the brains into guacamole.
(ALL LAUGHING)
First of all, I'll pull out of this, okay?
Wonderful.
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
Second?
Halt! Argh!
I detest
the surfeit of provincial laughter.
Now, we take your friend,
the little F-O-R-G,
put him in the chair,
clamp on the terminals,
drop the electronic yarmulke,
and throw,
what we call in German, the switch.
(LAUGHING)
Yes, you little green devil. Soon it'll be
a hot time for the old skull tonight.
Thank you, Herr Machine.
Now, the frog will do your bidding.
He will do your every whim,
your every wish.
He will
do your television commercial, yes.
He will sell your frogs' legs.
- Zaparoonie.
- Head full of jelly.
- A noggin full of library paste.
- Let's fry them brains!
Professor Krassman,
you've got a fun job.
I love it, I love it.
If I can inflict a little pain during
the afternoon, I sleep good at night.
- Well, we'll let you get on with it, then.
- My pleasure.
Max.
I'll be back later
to pick up what's left of the frog.
What's left of the frog?
You can have everything,
excuse the brain.
All right. Bring over the frog.
Oh, Kermie.
Whatever happens next,
I wouldn't give up this evening together
for anything.
- Would you?
- Make me an offer.
Oh, Kermie.
- Hey.
- Okay.
I got him. I got him.
Good, good, good, good, good.
And why don't we
take a little seat, Kermit?
Hands down.
- Get the feet into place.
- (WHIMPERING)
Will you stop whimpering?
Go out like a frog, not a little toad.
Okay, Herr Machine.
This is big time here.
Ready to go to work? Hand clamps!
Foot clamps!
(LAUGHS EVILLY)
You can struggle all you want now, frog.
It'll do you very little good.
All right. And now it's time
to drop the electronic beanie.
Soon, there'll be enough voltage
coursing through your little frog brain
to light up Cincinnati.
Oh, please, please. Not my frog. Please!
- Say goodbye to the frog, pig.
- Why should I?
Because in 10 seconds,
he won't know you from kosher bacon.
That does it!
Hi-yah!
Hi! Hi!
Hii-yah!
Hii-yah! Hi! Hi!
Hi-yah!
What the heck's goin' on here?
A pig that goes bananas?
What is this? A luau?
- MAN: Where'd she go?
- MISS PIGGY: Oh, boys.
- There she is.
- Get her!
I must reach the switch. I must...
- Switch. I must reach...
- Oh, no.
Hi-yah!
- Now, Kermie.
- Oh, thank you.
(SCREAMS)
Ribbit, ribbit, ribbit.
Well...
Shall we go now, Kermie?
(PHONE RINGING)
Well...
Just a second.
Hello.
- Piggy, it's your agent.
- Ooh.
Thank you.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(LOW VOICE)
Yeah, Morty, what have you got?
Commercial?
How much? Mmm-hmm.
When?
Take it.
(NORMAL VOICE) Um.
Goodbye.
(SAD MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC WINDS DOWN)
- FOZZIE: What's going on?
- Hey, what happened?
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
Irritated!
Don't worry, Animal.
Your big scene is coming up.
Yeah, yeah. Just be cool
and eat another seat cushion.
Seat cushion!
Well, how do you like the film?
I've seen detergents
that leave a better film than this.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Well, I don't care
what anybody else says.
I'm having a great time.
Oh, good.
Der flim is okey-dokey.
- Good. Roll film.
- Flim is rolling.
- GONZO: Quiet.
- FOZZIE: Quiet.
FOZZIE: Quiet, Gonzo.
- This is the patriotic part.
- Should we stand up?
No.
FOZZIE: O beautiful for spacious skies
For amber waves of grain
For purple mountain majesties
Above the fruited plains
America, America
God shed his grace on thee
And crown thy good with brotherhood
From sea to shining sea
Patriotism swells
in the heart of the American bear.
Hold it, boys. Hold it!
Hold your fire!
Boys, no reflection
on the job you've been doin',
but I decided to bring in a specialist.
Now, boys, this is Snake Walker.
Tell 'em what you do, Snake.
Kill frogs.
FOZZIE: How long is it to Hollywood?
KERMIT:
We gotta be there by tomorrow.
GONZO: Hey, Kermit. Are you gonna
get an agent like that pig had?
FOZZIE: Gonzo, you know
he's touchy about that.
- ROWLF: Hey, who's that?
- KERMIT: I don't believe that.
- KERMIT: Piggy?
- FOZZIE: Kermit.
Kermit.
- That's Piggy.
- Yeah, I know.
ROWLF: Hey, do you think
we should help her with her bag?
- ALL: No.
- Kermie.
(MISS PIGGY GRUNTS)
Kermie,
what an unbelievable coincidence.
FOZZIE: Hmm.
Hello again. It's me.
Would you hold my vanity case?
Hi-yah!
- Well.
- Well, what?
So much has happened to me
since I saw you last.
- Yeah, sure.
- Frankly, Miss Piggy, I don't give a hoot.
My name is Rowlf the Dog and I was
playing the piano... Oh, never mind.
- Kermie.
- Yeah?
- I missed you.
- Yeah.
Don't I get one kissy-kissy?
Uh, no, I... I don't think so, Miss Piggy.
Just one little hug.
FOZZIE: Hmmm.
- Oh, Piggy.
- Kermie.
HOPPER: (ON RADIO)
You've been listenin'
to music to hug frogs by.
And this is Doc Hopper sayin' that
if Kermit the Frog don't
stop right now and call me,
and agree to be
my national spokesman,
he will soon be a frog burger.
Kermie. Ah!
We'll be okay.
Mon capitaine.
(ENGINE SPLUTTERS)
- FOZZIE: Oh, boy. Yeah, what?
- KERMIT: Fozzie?
FOZZIE: No problem. It's okay, it's okay.
No problem. Okay, all right.
- Listen...
- KERMIT: Oh, boy.
FOZZIE: Oh, we're in trouble.
I wish I still had my Studebaker.
ROWLF: Probably somethin' broken
about the engine, I think.
GONZO: Hey, don't worry.
Someone's bound to come along.
Well, I guess we blew it, huh, Gonzo?
Yeah.
But the sky sure is beautiful out here.
Look at that.
We...
We're gonna miss
the auditions tomorrow, right?
Kermit?
GONZO: Boy,
you could get lost in a sky like that.
I wish I had those balloons again.
So much for Hollywood.
Listen, gang.
I never promised we'd make it.
I never promised anything.
(PLAYING HARMONICA)
(SINGING) This looks familiar
Vaguely familiar
Almost unreal, yet
It's too soon to feel yet
Close to my soul
And yet so far away
I'm going to go back there someday
Sun rises, night falls
Sometimes the sky calls
Is that a song there?
And do I belong there?
I've never been there
But I know the way
I'm going to go back there someday
Come and go with me
It's more fun to share
We'll both be completely
At home in midair
We're flyin', not walking
On featherless wings
We can hold on to love
Like invisible strings
There's not a word yet
For old friends who've just met
Part heaven, part space
Or have I found my place?
You can just visit
But I plan to stay
I'm going to go back there
Someday
I didn't promise anybody anything.
What do I know
about Hollywood anyway?
Just the dreams I got from sitting
through too many double features.
KERMIT'S VOICE: So, why did you
leave the swamp in the first place?
'Cause some agent fella
said I had talent.
He probably says that to everybody.
On the other hand,
if you hadn't left the swamp,
you'd be feeling
pretty miserable anyhow.
Yeah, but then it would
just be me feeling miserable.
Now I got a lady pig and a bear,
and a chicken, a dog, a thing,
whatever Gonzo is.
He's a little like a turkey.
Yeah. A little like a turkey,
but not much.
No, I guess not.
Anyhow, I brought 'em all out here
into the middle of nowhere.
It's all my fault.
Still, whether you promised them
something or not,
you gotta remember
they wanted to come.
But that's because they believed in me.
No, they believed in the dream.
- Well, so do I, but...
- You do?
Yeah. Of course I do.
- Well, then?
- Well, then...
I guess I was wrong
when I said I never promised anyone.
I promised me.
(HARMONICA PLAYING)
Hey. Now, wait a minute.
(ELECTRIC MAYHEM PLAYING)
Hey, what... What's happening?
At the moment, we're what's happening.
Oh, great. Wonderful. Yeah.
Zoot, hey, Zoot.
Hold it, hold it.
Animal, cool it back there.
Yeah.
All right, yeah.
Hey, listen, it's wonderful
to see you guys,
but how did you ever find us?
Oh, easy.
We just read the screenplay you left us.
"Exterior. Desert. Night."
We knew right where you were.
Like, can you get behind it?
Hey, listen. When do you dudes
have to be at that audition?
2:00 tomorrow afternoon.
Well, climb aboard the bus. We'll have
breakfast at Hollywood and Vine.
(CHEERING)
ALL: Movin' right along
FLOYD: Oh, yeah.
TEETH: Here we go.
Movin' right along
Kermie, whisper sweet nothings
into my ear.
Motorcycle cop.
Motorcycle cop is a sweet nothing?
A motorcycle cop is chasing us.
(SIREN BLARING)
- Hey, Dr. Teeth, you better pull over.
- Hey, easier done than said.
FLOYD: Uh-oh.
JANICE: Drag city.
What do we do now, huh?
Oh, dear.
TEETH: Hey, hey.
The man with the badge.
The police, the cops, the fuzz, the P.I...
- Don't you dare!
- I wouldn't think of it.
Did we do something wrong, Officer?
(SHOCKED GASPS)
- Kermit, it's him.
- Okay, gang. Let him explain.
This whole disguise
is only so I could warn you.
Oh, yeah. Sure, sure.
I never thought that Doc
was gonna hurt Kermit.
I only thought he was
gonna lean on him a little.
But now he's got this frog killer
in from the coast,
and the man is deadly.
FOZZIE: Oh, no, Kermit.
What are we gonna do?
- It's time to beat feet, green stuff.
- FOZZIE: Let's get out of here, Kermit.
I love it.
Chase music is one of our best riffs.
Hold it, Dr. Teeth. What's up ahead?
- It's only an old ghost town.
- Fine.
Listen, you go back and tell Doc Hopper
I'll be waiting for him there.
- What?
- Kermit, you'll get killed.
- Oh, please, no.
- FOZZIE: Kermit, you can't do that.
- Now, listen, guys.
Listen, I can't spend my whole life
running away from a bully.
It's time for a showdown.
Showdown! Showdown!
Uh, hey, listen,
I'm gonna check things out.
- Everybody stay in the bus, okay?
- Mmm-hmm.
(ROARS)
Hey, Kermit.
Can I take Animal for a walk?
He needs some exercise.
Yeah, yeah, sure.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
What is that?
That's one of my latest inventions.
A musical rotating rain barrel.
Oh, oh, yeah.
You see, I'm Dr. Bunsen Honeydew
and this is my assistant, Beaker.
(MEEPS)
We live here
perfecting useful inventions.
- Come in, come in.
- (MEEPING)
BUNSEN:
Welcome to our laboratory.
Please don't touch anything.
Uh...
- Is this the only street into town?
- Yes, yes.
Hey, what are you dudes doin' in here?
I'm so glad you asked.
We're perfecting our latest invention.
Insta-Grow pills.
Yeah, well, what in the name
of Fats Waller is that?
A 4-foot prune.
A 4-foot prune?
Yeah, man, well,
what else do these pills make big?
Oh, they work on anything,
but the effect is sadly temporary.
Sadly temporary. (SIGHS)
(MEEPS)
Oh, no!
SCOOTER: Hey, Kermit.
Here comes Doc Hopper.
I know. I'll be ready for him.
Okay, Frog. Where are you?
KERMIT: I'm here.
I'll meet you in the middle of the street.
Oh, yeah?
KERMIT: Man to frog.
(CHIMES)
- KERMIT: All right, Hopper.
- All right, Frog.
One last chance.
You gonna do my TV commercials
live or stuffed?
(GUNS COCKING)
Hopper, what's the matter with you?
You gotta be crazy,
chasin' me halfway across the country.
Why are you doing this to me?
'Cause all my life, I wanted
to own a thousand frog leg restaurants,
and you're the key, greenie.
Yeah, well, I've got a dream, too.
But it's about singing and dancing
and making people happy.
That's the kind of dream that gets better
the more people you share it with.
And, well, I've found a whole bunch of
friends who have the same dream.
And...
And it kind of makes us like a family.
Do you have anybody like that, Hopper?
I mean,
once you get all those restaurants,
who are you gonna share it with?
Who are your friends, Doc?
Those guys?
Max.
I got lots of friends.
Max, for instance.
- Max.
- I don't think you're a bad man, Doc.
And I think if you look in your heart,
you'll find you really wanna let me
and my friends go to follow our dreams.
But if that's not the kind of man you are,
or what I'm saying
doesn't make any sense to you,
well, then, go ahead and kill me.
All right, boys.
Kill him.
No, wait, please.
(RUMBLING)
(CRASHING)
Animal!
(ROARS)
Ha! Ha, ha, ha!
(ANIMAL ROARS)
Everybody, on to Hollywood.
ALL: Yay!
GONZ0: Wow! Wicked!
TEETH: Yeah,
next stop is Hollywood and Vine.
FOZZIE: Look at the ocean. The ocean.
Yes, Mr. Lord. I'll have
those deal numbers for you in a jiffy.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- Mmm-hmm.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Mr. Lord can't be disturbed by anyone.
He's packaging a blockbuster.
Mmm-hmm.
- Ah, Kermie, look, it's wonderful.
- Yeah.
Like a dream come true.
Well, don't count your tadpoles
until they're hatched.
- I still have to audition, you know.
- Hey, there ain't nothin' to it, but to do it.
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
And where do you think you're going?
Oh, hi, there.
I'm going to audition for Lew Lord.
You can't just walk in here
off the street, you know.
Especially not with all these animals.
Animals? What's wrong with animals?
ANIMAL: Animal!
This is a movie studio, not a zoo!
Besides...
(SNEEZES)
I'm allergic to animal hair.
Now, get along, all of you.
No. Wait a second. See here, miss.
I may not be one of your
fancy Hollywood frogs,
but I deserve a chance.
And we're gonna stay right here in this
office until you let us in to see Lew Lord.
- Aren't we, gang, huh?
- Yes!
- FLOYD: What he says.
- GONZO: Yeah, come on.
KERMIT: We'll just
sit right down and wait.
(SNEEZES)
Hello, security, it's Miss Tracey.
I wanna report a... (SNEEZES)
GONZO: Shake. Shake.
Shake, everyone.
KERMIT: That's it.
GONZO: Good, good, good. Do it.
- FLOYD: Yeah, go get 'em, Animal.
- KERMIT: Way to go.
FOZZIE: Allergies
are nothing to sneeze at.
TEETH: I'm allergic to cats myself.
(SNEEZING)
KERMIT: That's it, Rowlf.
- We got it.
- (CAMILLA CLUCKS)
- KERMIT: Wow.
- (BUZZER SOUNDS)
FLOYD: Yeah, all right.
- Okay, way to go, guys.
- FOZZIE: All right.
Thanks, miss.
Well, friends,
this is it.
Uh, Mr. Lord,
forgive the interruption,
but I'm here to audition.
MISS PIGGY: Yes, yes, yes, yes.
KERMIT: We've come
over 2,000 miles...
Uh, oh, boy.
Kermie, we're all with you.
Please, sir. My name is Kermit the Frog,
and we read your ad and...
Well, we've come
to be rich and famous.
Miss Tracey.
Prepare the standard
"Rich and Famous" contract
for Kermit the Frog and company.
Yes. We did it. We did it.
I can't believe it.
Oh, just look at all this.
How did a frog make the big time?
(SINGING) It starts when we're kids
A show-off at school
Makin' faces at friends
You're a clown and a fool
Doin' pratfalls and bird calls
and bad imitations
Ignoring your homework
Now that's dedication
You work to the mirror
You're getting standing ovations
You're burning with hope
You're building up steam
What was once juvenile-ish
Is grown-up and stylish
You're close to your dream
And somebody out there loves you
Stands up and hollers for more
More!
You've found a home
at the magic store
Right, everybody.
Production number, okay?
- Off the trucks and on the job.
- On the job!
Hey, whoa, halt, cease, stop.
Wow, let's do it.
- Do what?
- The movie.
FOZZIE: Yes, sir. A foot stomper.
- Makeup.
- Yes, let's do it. Yes.
Hey, Fozzie,
take those wagons out of there.
Yes, sir. I'm off.
(ROARS)
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Scenery over there, right?
Movin' right along. Hey!
Hey, those are the trees for the swamp.
Mellow and profitable.
Wacka, wacka.
- Let's make a scene.
- Okay, hon.
- Watch the tree, Rowlf.
- Careful, Scooter.
Ow.
- Watch it!
- (MEEPS)
- Miss Piggy, you look beautiful.
- MISS PIGGY: Thank you.
Hollywood talk.
Wa ha ha ha.
Wa ha ha ha ha.
- Good.
- Wa ha!
The lights. Yeah.
Good. Save those arcs.
Ha, ha.
Crazy Harry plays with electricity!
Sound is ready. Give me a level.
(YELLS) Testing!
(LAUGHS)
Rolling.
Okay, everybody. Stay in focus, huh?
Okay, Muppet Movie,
scene 1A, take one.
- BEAKER: Makeup ready.
- FLOYD: Scenery ready.
- BUNSEN: Sound is rolling.
- ROWLF: Camera's rollin'.
MISS PIGGY: All ready, Kermie.
Okay, standby. Here we go.
(SINGING) Why are there so many
songs about rainbows?
That's part of what rainbows do
Rainbows are memories
Sweet dream reminders
What is it you'd like to do?
All of us watching
and wishing we'd find it
I've noticed you're watching, too
Someday you'll find it
The rainbow connection
The lovers, the dreamers and...
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Kermit.
(MISS PIGGY GASPS)
(SINGING) Life's like a movie
Write your own ending
Keep believing, keep pretending
We've done
just what we've set out to do
Thanks to the lovers
The dreamers
And you
(LAUGHS)
I just knew I'd catch up with you guys.
(ALL LAUGHING)
- What did you think?
- It was sick and weird.
Kermit, it went swell. It went great, boss.
Congratulations, Mr. The Frog.
You can be in the next one, Lew.
Great show.
Oh, wow.
Woman!
- Did you like my close-up?
- Oh, yes.
Did you like my song?
How about my karate?
Kermit. Oh, Kermie.
Was I funny? Was I funny, anybody?
Fozzie, you were very, very funny.
Just great.
Go home! Go home!