[# Paul Simon:
"Me and Julio Down by the Schoolyard"]
[laughing]
[man] That's me, Walter.
Where... Where'd you go?
Oh, there you are!
[Walter] I have the best life
in the whole world.
[laughing]
[giggles] That's my brother, Gary.
He's the best friend
you could ever have.
Yeah, I know what you're thinking.
We could be twins.
Here's where we live : Smalltown...
...the best town
you could ever grow up in.
Gary and I did everything together.
[bell dings]
[grunting]
[chuckles]
And, as the years passed,
my brother was always there for me.
I got it! Gary, throw me! Throw me!
Aaah!
[Walter] We were a great team.
- Nice job, Walter.
- Thanks, Gary.
[grunting]
[Walter] Oh, don't get me wrong.
It's not perfect.
- That was so fun!
- [Walter] Nothing is.
[man] Sorry, kid.
- [girl] I wanna do that again!
- [man] Come on. I'll ride with ya!
[boy] Hurry up!
[Walter] Even the sunniest days
can have a few clouds in them.
Ride's bogus, anyway.
Hey, wanna rent a video?
[Walter] Yeah. Race you home!
And, well, that night
sorta changed everything.
It's The Muppet Show, with our very
special guest star, Mr. Steve Martin!
[Walter] I found them...
[gasps]
... The Muppets.
[inhales deeply]
I guess you could say
I was their number one fan.
[gasps] Oh, Gary, it's an entire map
of The Muppet Studios.
- [rattling]
- [chuckles]
[gasps]
And they made all the difference.
- [kids] Trick or treat!
- [Walter] Because from then on...
- Hey, guys.
- Oh, hey, Gary.
- Hey.
- Hi-ho, guys. Yay!
[laughing]
[boy] Is that Kermit the Frog?
What is this, 1978?
[Walter]...even on the worst days,
I knew...
[sighs]
...that as the years passed...
[Kermit on TV] Cancel that last remark.
[Walter]...as long as there are singing
frogs and joking bears...
[both laughing]
...Swedish chefs and boomerang fish,
the world can't be such
a bad place after all.
All right, good night, buddy.
Oh, good night, Gary.
[Walter] And as long
as there are Muppets...
[yawns]
- ...for me...
- [man on TV]...hair-growing tonic.
...there's still...
- [snoring]
-...hope.
Aaah. Bye-bye!
- [laughing]
- [Kermit] Somebody get him!
Animal. Hey, Animal, come on.
The show's about to start.
Show! Show! [yells]
Hey, Walter, why don't you join us?
[man] Come on!
No! Wait! I want to be
with you guys! Please let me in!
Kermit!
[screaming, gasps]
Whoa!
Walter, are you OK, buddy?
You're drenched in sweat.
Did you have the dream again?
Ummm. No. Hey, so when are
you guys leaving today?
Oh, um, just a couple hours now.
Oh, wow, Gary, I think it is so cool
you're taking Mary to Los Angeles.
I can't believe you guys
have been dating for ten years.
I know. Yeah, she wanted to do
something special for this anniversary,
and she's always
wanted to see Los Angeles, so...
Hey, don't forget to send me a
postcard from The Muppet Studios.
Oh, yeah, I'm sorry.
- I can't do that, Walter.
- But, Gary...
Because... you're coming with us!
[gasps] Oh, Gary!
- But what about Mary?
- She's fine.
- She said the more the merrier.
- I... I don't know what to say!
The Muppet Studios are there, Gary.
I can't believe this!
Better get a move on.
We don't want to miss that bus!
No way! Who knows?
Maybe Kermit will be there.
I wouldn't get
your hopes up, buddy.
The Muppets haven't put
on a show together in years.
I don't think they use the studios
for anything but tours anymore.
Nah, I think that's
just an Internet rumor.
Like there's a country called Turkey.
Walter, how many times
do we have to go over this?
- Turkey is a very real country.
- Wow, Muppet Studios.
- I can't believe it!
- [up-tempo music plays]
# Everything is great
Everything is grand
# I got the whole wide world
in the palm of my hand
# Everything is perfect
It's falling into place
# I can't seem to wipe
this smile off my face
# Life's a happy song when there's
someone by my side to sing along
[both spit]
# When you're alone
life can be a little rough
# It makes you feel like
you're three foot tall
# When it's just you
Well, times can be tough
# When there's no one there
to catch your fall
Whoooa! [grunts]
# Everything is great
Everything is grand
# I got the whole wide world
in the palm of my hand
# Everything is perfect
It's falling into place
# I can't seem to wipe
this smile off my face
- # Life smells like a rose
- # With someone to paint
- # And someone to pose
- # Life's a piece of cake
[bell dings]
- # With someone to pedal
- # And someone to brake
- # Life is full of glee
- # With someone to saw
- # And someone to see
- # Life's a happy song
# When there's someone
by my side to sing along
# I've got everything that I need
# Right in front of me
# Nothing's stoppin' me
# Nothin' that I can't be
# With you right here next to me
- # Life's a piece of cake
- # With someone to give
- # And someone to... Heavy cake!
- # Life's a piece of pie
- # With someone to wash
- # And someone to dry
- # Life's an easy road
- # With someone beside you
- # To share the load
- # Life is full of highs
- # With someone to stir
- # And someone to fry
# Life's a leg of lamb
# With someone there to lend a hand
# Life's a bunch of flowers
# With someone to while away the hours
# Life's a fillet of fish
# Yes, it is
Life's a happy song
# When there's someone
by your side to sing along
[all] Oooh...
# I've got everything that I need
# Right in front of me
Nothing's
# Stoppin' me
Nothin' that I can't be
# With you right here next to me
# I've got everything that I need
# Right in front of me #
Sorry. I was super excited.
All right, Carlos. Flip the ignition.
[engine starts]
And that is how you fix
a 12-volt starter.
- [bell ringing]
- Oh!
You know what that means.
Spring break.
[all groaning]
It's OK. We'll be back
to studying in two weeks.
Yay!
- Have a nice vacation.
- Bye. Have fun.
- Bye, Mr. Gary.
- Have a good break, guys.
- Hey, great job, Carlos.
- Thanks.
Enjoy your anniversary dinner.
- Hi.
- I got you these.
Oh. Sorry. It's probably from
the dance number I was doing.
It's OK. They're really sweet.
You excited for our big trip to LA?
I have our list.
Me, too. [chuckles]
Oh, this is the
most romantic thing ever.
I've always dreamt
of seeing Los Angeles.
I know. Walter can't wait either.
You don't mind that he's coming, right?
No. No, of course not.
As long as we can spend our anniversary
dinner together. That's all I ask.
Totally. It's gonna be the most
romantic anniversary dinner ever.
I love you so much.
Oh.
- I love you, too.
- I'm gonna go check on Walter.
[door opens]
# Everything's great
Everything's grand
# Except Gary's always off
with his friend
# It's never me and him
It's always me and him and him
# I wonder when it's going to end
# But I guess that's OK
'cause maybe someday
- # I know just how it's going to be
- [horse whinnies]
# He'll ride up on a steed
Get down on one knee
# And say "Mary, will you marry me?"
# Please #
Oh...
# I've got everything that I need
# Right in front of me
# Nothing's stoppin' me
Nothin' that I can't be
# With you right here next to me
# You've got everything that you need
# Right in front of you
Nothing's stopping you
# Nothing that you can't do
that the world can throw at you
# Life's a happy song
# When there's someone
by your side to sing
# Life's a happy song
# When there's someone
by your side to sing
# Life's a happy song when there's
someone by your side to sing along #
[bus honks]
- [man] OK, they're gone!
- [all groaning]
[Walter] Hey, Gary, what should
we do first at Muppet Studio?
'Cause I was thinking that maybe we
could start at Fozzie's Joke Room...
Oh, no, wait, wait, wait.
The lines might be shorter
at Honeydew's Laboratory of Fun,
so maybe we should start there instead.
I just... I just can't wait!
[breaks squealing]
[sirens blaring]
Oh, Walter, don't be nervous.
Oh, I know.
I just can't believe I'm here.
The home of the Muppets!
[speaking foreign language]
What... What happened to this place?
[sign creaking]
Where...?
- Where is everyone, Gary?
- I don't know, buddy. It's so...
OK, well, I guess you guys
are it for today.
[clears throat] Anyway, welcome
to the original Muppet Studio,
where dreams can come true.
[man speaking foreign language]
- Is this the Universal Studios?
- Yes, it is.
OK, now if you'll
just follow me, please.
OK. This used to be Kermit's office.
- Whoa.
- Mm-hmm.
It's really the highlight of the tour.
You should see it sometime.
OK, this next building
is where they kept the rope
and the medium-gauge wire for the
productions. Let's go take a look.
- Come on, buddy.
- [woman speaking foreign language]
Wow!
Oh, boy.
Oh.
Whoa.
- [doorknob rattling]
- [gasps]
There. Now this here is
Kermit the Frog's old office.
- Or so we've been "toad."
- [both laughing]
Well, as you know, gentlemen, I've loved
the Muppets since I was a boy.
And what better way
to honor the Muppets
than to make this beautiful
studio a Muppet museum.
[gasps]
I think I'll call this room
the "Kermit the Frog's
Old Office Room."
- Oh, that is lovely.
- Oh, good one, Mr. Richman.
Now, this here is the standard
"Rich and Famous" contract
Kermit signed 30 years ago,
that contains...
- The deed to this property.
- Exactly.
Now, this contract is 100 percent
ironclad, with one minor exception.
If the Muppets can raise the
ten million dollars it would cost
to buy the building before
this contract expires,
- then they get their studio back.
- You know, if I didn't know better,
I'd say you were reciting some
sort of an important plot point.
Well, I hope so. Otherwise,
I just bored the audience half to death.
You mean half the audience
is still alive?
[laughing]
It's nice doing business with you.
- Yes, sir. Come on.
- Goodbye.
I love geriatric humor.
Gentlemen, there's oil
under this studio.
- Yeah, I can smell it.
- [sniffing]
And more importantly, the geological
survey says there definitely is.
In two weeks, we tear
this place to the ground
and start drilling. Ah, those Muppets.
They think they're so funny.
Well, it looks like
the joke's about to be on them.
- Maniacal laugh.
- [laughs]
Maniacal laugh.
Maniacal laugh. Maniacal laugh.
- [gasps]
- Maniacal laugh.
[screaming]
- [Gary] Walter!
- [Mary] Walter?
- [Mary] Walter!
[screaming continues]
Yeah, so then, when he thought
they were alone, he said,
[mocking] "There's oil
under this studio, see.
I'm gonna tear it to the ground, see.
- Sweet, sweet oil, see!"
- People still talk like that?
Maybe that's just how
he sounded in my head.
Either way, we've got to find Kermit!
He'll know what to do.
How do we find Kermit?
Nobody's seen him in years.
[Walter gasps] Stop the car!
I've got an idea!
[all] Mmm.
These are delicious!
- Great idea, Walter.
- Mm-hmm.
[Gary] We've been doing this
for a long time.
I think maybe we should
call it a night.
- [Mary] Guys!
- We can't give up, Gary.
But it's getting really late. Maybe
we should just go back to the motel.
- Guys!
- It...
- What?
- Maybe he lives there.
- Oh. That's it.
So, what do we do now?
I don't see a doorbell,
and the house looks empty.
- Gary, throw me over.
- What?
- Gary, just throw me over already!
- OK.
- OK, here we go. OK...
- One, two, three.
- [cracking]
- [grunts]
- That's good.
- Sorry.
- No, it's good.
- Guys?
I think that's an electric fence.
Mary, it's Kermit the Frog.
- OK, buddy, head down.
- [both] One, two, three!
[screaming]
- It's an electric fence.
- Yep.
Oh, my gosh. Walter? Walter, buddy?
Walter, can you hear me?
- [raspy] Throw me again.
- No, I don't...
I don't think that's a good idea.
- What kind of throw was that?
- I think there's somebody coming.
[man] Excuse me...
[choir vocalizing]
You OK? That was quite a tumble.
Oh. Look, look. I think...
Hey. Hey, Walter?
- Walter, you all right, buddy?
- Where am I?
OK, this is awesome.
We're at Kermit's house.
- Oh, jeez. Walter.
- No, no, no, no, no. You OK?
This... This is Kermit's house?
- Anyhow, how can I help you guys?
- [gasps]
Let me just say, this is an honor
for all of us to meet you, sir,
but my brother, Walter, has some
really disturbing news for you.
- Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
- Not now, 80's Robot.
Might I offer you a drink? Tab?
- [Kermit] Good grief.
- New Coke?
Listen. Not right now,
80's Robot, please!
Bummer.
- [Kermit] Watch out for the...
- Gag me with a spoon.
- [Kermit] Yeah, head for the door.
- Grody to the max.
- [banging]
- Ow.
Ow.
- I'm really sorry about that...
- [crashing]
...Walter. What were you saying?
- Yes. Tex Richman, the oil baron, is...
- Yes, yes, yes.
Oil baron Tex Richman,
the wealthy philanthropist.
You know, he's about to buy
our old Muppet Show theater
and turn it into a Muppet museum.
Isn't that great?
- No! I mean...
- What Walter's trying to tell you
is that Tex Richman has a secret plan to
tear down the theater and drill for oil.
- What?
- The only way to save the studio
is to raise ten million dollars.
Ten million dollars? That's impossible.
- But...
- The only way to raise
that kind of money would be to...
...would be to put on a show.
And I haven't seen the old gang
in a long, long time.
I guess people sort of forgot about us.
Hm?
# Is there more I could've said?
# Now they're only pictures in my head
# That's why my green is feeling gray
# Sometimes even frogs have rainy days
# Remember when the stage caved in
while you were rocking out?
# Who'd have thought your smorgasbord
would be hard to live without?
# If we could do it all again
# Just another chance to entertain
# Would anybody watch or even care?
# Or did something break
we can't repair?
# Your cannonball trajectory
It always gave me hope
# They may have been unbearable
but I still loved your jokes
# Is there more I could've said?
# Now they're only pictures in my head
I didn't do it. I've been framed!
Ahh. Wocka wocka!
Gonzo the Great
will ride this baby again!
[mumbling gibberish]
Muah!
This legato tune is posolutely,
most transparently bringing me down.
- For sure.
- One, two, and a half...
[all] # Can we do it all again?
# Make'em laugh like we did then
# We can harmonize for one more song
# But I'm standing here instead
# Now they're only pictures in my head #
Well, it sounds like you guys aren't
getting back together anytime soon.
Mmm...
This is going to be
a really short movie.
But, Kermit, you have to try.
I... The Muppets are amazing.
You give people the greatest gift
that can ever be given.
- Children?
- No, the other gift.
- Ice cream?
- No, no. After that.
- Laughter?
- Yes!
The third greatest gift ever!
Kermit, your fans never left you,
the world hasn't forgotten.
All you need to do is show'em again!
Hmm.
I don't think so, guys. [sighs]
Don't you see, Kermit?
It's time to play the music.
# It's time to light the lights
# It's time to meet the Muppets... #
[playing piano]
Please, Kermit.
You're my hero.
You're on my watch.
Well, I... I guess...
...we could try.
- We?
- Well, yeah, listen.
If I'm gonna do this,
I'm gonna need some moral support.
Well, that's perfect.
We're experts at moral support.
- Yeah!
- Good. I guess if we're gonna go,
we better get going.
We got a lot of people to find.
Oh, great! But wait,
how do we find'em?
Didn't you see our first movie?
We drive.
[# Gary Numan: "Cars"]
- So where do we go first?
- I shall take the liberty
of using my modem to locate the Muppets.
- OK.
- Great.
- Oh, stop it!
- [loud beeping, static]
In the name of all
that's sacred, let it end!
R-E-N-O. That spells "Reno."
You have reached your destination.
My guidance ends here.
[Kermit] Well, I guess
this is the place.
[man] Good evening, folks,
and welcome to Pechoolo Casino!
# Why are there such great deals
# On our hotel rooms?
# Free parking for cars
- # Not RVs
# Our wedding chapel is 24 hours
- # No marriage certificate is needed
# We're glad you found it
# Pechoolo Casino
# The owners, the Moopets and me #
Cha-cha-cha!
Thank you, thank you.
We'll be back in six minutes.
- [few claps]
- Hmm.
- Hi-ho, Fozzie.
- Hi-ho, Kermit.
Kermit? [stammers]
What are you doing here?
Well, I... I just want to tell you
that was a great show.
It was... very informative.
I do my best to
keep it fresh each night.
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, I'm Fozzie, by the way.
Oh, I'm sorry.
This is Gary and Mary.
And this here is Walter.
He's a personal friend.
- Yeah.
- So I said, "What are you looking at?"
So I punched him in the face! I mean...
- Let's talk in my dressing room.
- Sure.
- OK.
- Here we are.
Make yourselves at home.
- Wow.
- [distant sirens blaring]
This is not quite what I expected,
- based on your Christmas cards.
- Oh, yeah. About that...
Oh, but it's nice, and... and airy.
Maybe we should give them some space.
I know, but I wanna hear
what they're gonna say. OK.
[Fozzie] Sixty-four shows nightly
can get pretty grueling.
Fozzie, an evil oil baron wants
to tear down our old Muppet studio.
- What? Oh, no!
- [sirens blaring]
- I mean, that's a shame.
- [gunshots]
[policeman] Step out of the vehicle!
Hey, Fozzie...
I'm sorry I haven't
been in touch more.
It's fine, Kermit. Look at me!
Living the dream!
- [thunder claps]
- Uh-oh.
Oh, no! Not this again!
- Quick, save the cushions!
- The cushions?
I'm sorry, Fozzie.
If I'd known you were here
in this place...
That's all right, Kermit.
It's not your fault.
- We had a good run.
- Yeah.
Yeah, it's just that...
Well, we haven't seen each other
in a really long time, and I...
I just thought maybe we could raise
the money to buy the theater back
if we all got together
and put on one last show.
A show? But I've spent years
building a solo career.
I have a whole new show-biz
family that loves me.
Fozzie! What the heck
are you doing, hibernating?
Next show starts in 30 seconds.
We hired you, and we can fire you,
so get your butt in here now!
- [door slams]
- [shuddering]
- They terrify me. Let's go.
- Let's go.
- Watch out for the forklift, Fozzie.
- [Fozzie] Oh, thanks.
Wow! Gonzo's doing really well!
According to 80's Robot,
he's the richest plumbing magnate
in the Rust Belt.
You! Order 28,000 tons of
plumber's putty from Beijing.
- [man] Right away, sir.
- And, you, send the 28,000 tons
of Silly Putty back to Beijing.
- [man 2] You bet.
- Oh, and you?
A memo to the waterless
toilet department.
I don't care about the mess,
just keep trying.
- Hi, Gonzo.
- Kermit? Fozzie? This is a surprise.
- We need to speak to you.
- All right. Have a seat.
Ah. Thank you!
- I think I'll stand.
- No, really, you should try one! Comfy.
It's our executive line of used toilets.
Anyway, I'm very busy.
I've got 30 seconds. Go.
Uh... Gonzo, I'm not quite
sure how to say this, but...
Don't forget to mention
the evil oil baron.
Yes, Fozzie, I was about to.
Just give me a moment, OK?
[clears throat]
Gonzo, it would appear...
Remember, evil oil baron.
Fozzie, I'm going
to get to that. Please!
- As I was trying to say...
- Evil oil baron.
- [buzzer sounds]
- OK, time's up. Thank you, guys.
Gonzo, we're trying to get the
old gang back together again.
- We really need you.
- My answer is no. Good day!
Come on, guys. We should go.
I just want to say, when I was a kid,
I saw you recite Hamlet
while jumping your motorbike
through a flaming hoop, and...
...it made me feel
like I could do anything.
Thank you. Yeah.
[clucking]
- Good try, Walter.
- [Gonzo] Hey, guys, up here!
- Ya-haa!
- Huh?
I've been wearing this under
my suit every single day for years!
Look out below!
- [yelling]
- [clucking]
Whoa, where you going?
You threw me off-balance!
I can't see! Apollo 13!
- [clucking]
- [grunts]
Citizens of Earth,
the Great Gonzo is back.
I pledge never to hold a plunger again!
[beeping]
Run! Run! Run for your lives!
Run, run, run!
- Run, guys!
- Run!
Oh, my gosh, run everybody!
It's gonna be big!
It's gonna be a big one!
[coughing]
Wow! That was an
expensive looking explosion!
I can't believe we
had that in the budget.
[woman] So maybe if you
look inside yourself,
the person you should be
most angry at is you.
Is you.
How have you been feeling?
Any more control issues?
In control.
- Good.
- [Kermit whispering] Psst. Animal!
- [woman] Excellent.
- It's me, Kermit.
Hey, we're having a meeting here, man.
You're being really rude, frog!
Pardon us, please. Animal,
I need to talk to you for a second.
We're getting the Muppets back together.
We need you to drum again.
- Animal drum?
- Yes!
- Please, sir.
- Drum! Drum, drum!
- Drum, drum, drum!
- OK, OK.
- In control.
- Good.
I'm Animal's court-appointed sponsor.
We don't use the "d-r-u-m" word.
- It's his trigger word.
- His trigger word?
Excuse me, Mr. Black.
I'm so sorry to interrupt,
but it's very important to these guys
that they get their drummer...
Gary!
It's my trigger word, too.
Jack, we talked about this on Tuesday.
Tuesday's another one
of my trigger words!
Oh, I don't think so!
Sorry.
- Let's go, Animal.
- Bye-bye!
- Animal, heel.
- Go, Animal! Be free, man!
But remember! No drumming!
Mr. Kermit, may I suggest
we save time and pick up
the rest of the Muppets using a montage?
[Kermit] Great idea, 80's Robot.
[# AC/DC: "Back in Black"]
We greatly appreciate
your financial support.
[80's Robot] Eighty-seven point three
miles to go. Eighty-seven point two...
[Kermit] 80's Robot,
do you have to do that?
...the secrets of the universe...
[screaming]
I guess we're in.
Welcome to this week's edition
of "Everything Stinks."
Whoa!
Bye, Lisa.
Off to the TED Conference.
Three, two, one.
[cackles]
Think we should've rented a bigger car?
Hey, wait for me!
I wanna help save the studio!
I wanna go with you! Oh, not again.
Wow. I can't believe
we're all back together.
Even all you guys
who weren't in the montage!
Yeah, how come you
didn't use me in the montage?
I thought my story
was pretty interesting.
- [snoring]
- Rowlf? Wanna get back together?
- OK.
- Good.
[chuckles] Classic.
Anyhow, looks like we got everybody,
so we can plan our telethon
and raise that ten million dollars.
- Well, not everybody.
- No, I think everybody's here.
- Where's...?
- All good!
- Miss...
- All done here!
- Piggy?
- [sighs]
Kermit, we're going
to get Miss Piggy, right?
OK, OK, OK, you're right.
We'll go get Piggy!
- [phone dialing]
- [all exclaiming]
My Minitel tells me
she is in Paris, France.
Oh! Well, then we drive to France.
- You can't drive to France, Walter.
- Yeah. It's way too far.
Then maybe we should travel by map!
- Good idea, Fozzie.
- Yeah!
[exclaiming]
[gasps]
To Paris!
[Animal] Paris! Paris!
[man speaking French]
[Walter] Look at these ceilings!
[Fozzie] Yeah. They must
be very tall here.
- [Kermit] Yeah, very nice.
- [keyboard clacking]
Uh... Hi there. Excuse me.
Miss? Pardon me, ma'am?
Hi there! We're here to see
Miss Piggy, and it's urgent.
Urgent! Urgent!
- Is it urgent?
- Very. Yes.
Let's have a look then, shall we?
She has an opening in...
- ...early September.
- Early September?
That's like six months from now!
That's nothing. Once I waited
a whole year for September.
She is the plus-size editor.
She's a huge deal and extremely busy.
You can't just pop in
without an appointment.
- OK, then.
- Thank you.
- [woman] All right.
- [Animal] Mean lady.
- Close the door on your way out.
- [Kermit] Thanks a lot.
- She wasn't very nice.
- [Kermit] Yeah.
Guys! Muppet Man!
- Yeah!
- That could work!
[knocking on door]
Hello.
[grunting]
I have an appointment.
Oh, OK.
Um...
Will you wait here a moment?
[Miss Piggy] Decisions, decisions.
- Eeny, meeny, miny, mo. I choose you.
- [knocking]
- [door opens]
- [laughing]
- [chomping]
- Mademoiselle Cochonnet?
- Can't you see I'm busy?
- [woman] Of course.
There's a... man here to see you.
He does have an appointment.
An appointment? That's weird.
Well, why didn't you say so?
Send him in!
Right away. Sorry.
- Ahahaha.
- Remember, left foot, right foot.
Hello.
- Whoa.
- [crashing]
- What the...?
- [Fozzie] Sorry.
That looked expensive.
[grunting]
- You look familiar.
- So do you!
Please, have a seat.
Yes, we're going to have a seat now.
- No, no, no, don't sit down!
- Oh, sorry! Whoa!
Uh-oh.
Message to head. Left leg in trouble!
Going down. Left leg going down!
What?
- Ohh!
- [grunting]
I can't believe I fell for Muppet Man.
- [Mary] You guys OK?
- [Gary] Is anyone hurt?
Kermit?
- Hello, Piggy.
- Kermie!
Oh, Kermie, Kermie, Kermie, Kermie,
Kermie, Kermie, Kermie, Kermie, Kermie!
Mm, mm, mm. Kissy-kissy.
Mm, mm, mm!
Wait! What am I doing?
I promised myself I'd never go back!
I am woman! I am strong!
You must leave at once!
[speaks French]
- OK.
- No, no, wait, wait!
Miss Piggy!
The Muppet Studios are in danger.
In danger? Our studios? Kermit!
It's true, Piggy. And we need
to do The Muppet Show again.
We need you.
Oh.
Before I decide anything,
I need to talk with you, frog.
[speaks French]
Alone.
[chattering]
Piggy? Last time we were together,
I said some things I regret.
No. No, Kermit.
You were just being honest.
You never intended to marry me.
Not even after I built us a house
where we could raise tadpoles
and grow old together.
Well, who do you think's been looking
after that house all these years, huh?
Piggy, why do you have to always
be so overdramatic about things?
You know, it leaves me no choice
but to do things that hurt you.
I am who I am. Why can't
you accept that about me?
Look, this is not about you and me.
It's never about you and me, is it?
It's always we. We this, we that.
"We" need you. You can't even say,
"I need you," can you?
Piggy...
I'm sorry, Kermit,
but I have a life here.
A life I've made for myself.
Piggy!
Just remember, Kermit,
I cannot be replaced.
[door closes]
Kermit? What happened?
Where's Miss Piggy?
- She's not coming, Fozzie.
- [all gasp]
But, Kermit, we always worked together.
We can't do this without Miss Piggy.
No one will give us a show without her.
We'll be fine, Fozzie.
We'll be fine.
We just...
We'll just have to
come up with something else.
[sighs] Kermie.
[Kermit] OK, I've got an idea.
We need a pig that can sing.
[Fozzie] But, Kermit, who could
possibly replace Miss Piggy?
[# George Thorogood: "Bad to the Bone"]
[metal scraping]
Hey, what's everybody so quiet about,
huh?
- Well, she's sorta like Miss Piggy.
- Come on, everybody.
Let's go pitch our telethon
and get the Muppets back on TV, OK?
- No.
[speaking Spanish]
[gasping]
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, that's wonderful!
That means no.
[groans]
- Come on, guys.
- Awkward.
Listen, Kermit, I like you.
I remember you guys
from when I was a kid.
- [chatter]
- So I'm gonna shoot straight.
- You guys aren't famous anymore.
- [groans]
I wish she'd shot a little more curvy.
Take a look at this diagram
the research department drew up.
This circle represents
everything that's currently popular.
And this tiny speck is you guys.
So the answer's no.
It's not gonna happen.
Take a look at the shows that
are popular now. Punch Teacher.
- Oh! I love that show.
- It's time to punch teacher!
- Finish him!
- It's my favorite.
[man] I just thought
I could make a difference.
I'm sorry, but in this market, you guys
are no longer relevant. Have a good day.
[groaning]
Before I go,
I'd just like to say something.
I think kids are smarter and better
than all this junk, and if you...
Veronica, bad news. Punch Teacher
has stopped production.
It's being sued by the
Teachers Society of America.
- What's their problem?
- No idea. I just found out.
What are we supposed to do
with that 120-minute black hole
in the schedule coming up in two days?
OK, Muppets.
You've got yourselves a show.
- All right!
- Oh, yes!
Thank you so much. You will not
be sorry, I promise, I promise!
OK, enough! One, no more going nuts
in my office. These are new carpets.
- Yes, ma'am.
- And two, you need a celebrity host.
OK. Whatever, whatever.
Come on, guys, let's go. Yeah!
- [man] Let me wipe that.
- [man 2] You've missed a spot.
- I don't see it.
- Just a little lower!
- Oh, I am so sorry. Did I get you...
- Yes.
Well, gentlemen. It appears
we have some competition
on the Muppet property.
The Economist says they've
gotten back together again.
- The Muppets got back together?
- Remember?
# Together again
Gee, it's good to be... #
Gentlemen, please!
No singing in my office!
- Yes, sir.
- But, of course, it was all his fault.
- Mostly his fault.
- No matter.
Point is, that studio
and that oil belong to me.
Yeah, those Muppets are gonna be
running home with
their tails between their legs.
Some of'em literally.
Because those ones have tails.
Maniacal laugh, maniacal laugh.
[laughing]
That's a maniacal laugh moment.
[Kermit] OK, this is it. 80's Robot,
let's park around back.
[Kermit on TV] It's The Muppet Show,
with our special guest star,
Mr. Bob Hope!
[Bob Hope] Time once again
for Veterinarian's Hospital,
the continuing story of...
And now, Pigs in Space!
Gary. Can you believe it?
- The Muppet theater.
- Yeah.
- Welcome back, everyone.
- Thanks.
Well, I know the old place is
not quite at its best right now.
Yeah! Who cancelled
the maid service? [laughs]
But don't worry. We'll be fine.
Kermit, there's no way we can
rehearse with the place like this.
Wait. Kermit, don't say another word.
Mary, Walter and I, well, we would be
happy to help you rebuild the theater.
Honestly, it would be an honor
for all three of us.
- So would.
- OK. Well, let's clean this place up!
Yeah!
[humming]
- This is boring.
- But don't you guys remember?
You're the Muppets!
You do this to music!
Well, all right!
[# Starship: "We Built This City"]
- Hey, Animal!
- Yeah?
Look what I found!
[screaming]
- Beauregard!
- Scooter! Good to see you!
Where's everybody been?
Celebrity... celebrity!
Hello! Yes. Could I speak
with President Carter, please?
He moved? Well, you don't happen to have
a number where I could reach... Hello?
Walter, I thought we were gonna
clean the balcony.
- Doing a great job, pal.
- [Walter] You're doing a great job.
- Wocka wocka.
- Hey, guys!
Look at these old photos I just found.
Oooh.
Can you believe that 80's
haircut I used to have?
I looked totally ridiculous!
Yes, it's Kermit. The frog.
Could you come to our celebrity
telethon this weekend?
Sure. Sure, I understand.
[mumbling]
- Hey, shut the door!
- What is that?
Say hello to the little friend.
There goes dinner.
[chuckles]
- [song continues]
- [vocalizing]
[gasping]
Wow! Great job, everybody!
Oh, hey, Kermit.
Listen, have a great night,
and I just want you to know,
Walter and I are really good sewers,
so we'll have those costumes
ready for you in no time.
- Good. You two have a great night.
- OK. Thank you!
- Bye.
- [man] Kermit?
Gary, I was kind of hoping
that we could go to the beach tomorrow
- or see the Hollywood Sign.
- We'll have plenty of time
to do that stuff. It's just, right now,
I don't wanna leave Walter.
You know, he needs me.
I don't know, sweetheart,
he seems pretty happy.
[laughing in background]
- [Fozzie] Like that.
- [Walter] Oh, OK.
[Fozzie] Now you.
Yeah, that's it!
Yeah, yeah, good job!
Well, just one more day, OK?
And then I'm all yours.
Tell you what. Why don't you get
a head start on sightseeing tomorrow,
and then I'll be waiting
for you when you get back.
OK. Just...
don't forget about me.
Never.
Well, we're still on
for dinner Friday, right?
Yeah, of course.
- Oh, Walter!
- Oh, yes, Kermit.
Hey, listen, Walter,
I just wanna tell you
that none of this would have happened
without you, so thank you.
- Oh, well...
- And welcome aboard.
Night, everybody. Just sleep
anywhere you can find a spot.
"Welcome aboard"?
[snoring clucks]
[clucking]
[snoring]
Hey, Kermit. You awake?
- Yep.
- What's the weather
- supposed to be like tonight?
- I don't know. Why?
I just don't want it to rain
through the hole in the ceiling.
Stars sure are pretty, though.
We're gonna be OK, right?
We haven't done this in a long time,
and I really don't
wanna go back to Reno.
Don't worry, Fozzie. We'll be fine.
Look how we cleaned this place
up today, you know?
Same old team, all pulling together.
I guess you're right.
Night-night, Kermit.
Good night, Fozzie.
[sighs]
OK, gather round, troops! Everybody,
time to get this rehearsal going.
- Scooter, is everybody here?
- Almost everyone, chief.
- Yeah...
- Hey, anybody got any kerosene?
I wanna take these old pig
dresses out back and burn'em.
[Miss Piggy echoing]
Hold it right there, sausage snout!
- Piggy?
- Huh?
Well, look what the cat dragged in.
Come on. Keep it up, Maurice.
Sorry, Miss Piggy, but you've
been replaced... permanently.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah!
I don't think so... sister?
Who you calling sister, sister?
- Oh, look, an omelet station!
- Oh, where?
- Hiya!
- [grunts]
There's only one Miss Piggy,
and she is moi.
Yeah, well, you ain't seen
the last of me! I'll be back!
Yeah, yeah. Heard of mouthwash?
- Welcome back, Miss Piggy.
- [all chattering]
All right, all right, don't crowd me!
Wow, she sure hasn't changed.
Piggy? You came back.
I'm not here for you, Kermit.
I'm here for them.
[door shuts]
And, besides,
when this show's done,
I'm catching the next plane
back to my life in Paris.
OK, Piggy, OK. Places for the
opening number, everybody!
[growling]
Oh, good morning, Veronica.
- Morning, Frog.
- OK, everybody, take it from the top.
- [playing music]
- Oooh!
- You missed your cue.
- I know!
[crashing]
There's kind of
a rhythm to this, you know?
Uh... Oh, and if you like that one,
what's the bear capital of the world?
Mos-cow!
[laughing]
Ha.
# It's time to play the music
- # It's time to light the lights
- Two, three, four.
# It's time to put on makeup
# It's time to dress up right #
Hey guys, stop. Cut, cut, cut,
cut, cut. What's the problem?
We can't keep time without
the drums, man! We need drums!
- Sorry, Animal.
- [grunting] No drums! No drums!
- Jack Black said no drums!
- Animal, heel! Sit!
[sighs]
- Who's next? Oh.
- [Animal] In control.
- Hey, Walter?
- Oh. Yes, Kermit?
You think you might
wanna help us out here?
- Maybe do something in the show?
- [sighs]
Kermit, you know,
you've been so nice to me,
but I have to face the facts.
See, the Muppets are so talented...
Hey, guys, check it out! Fart shoes!
[flatulence sounds]
- Patent pending!
- And...
...I don't have any talent at all.
The truth is... [sighs]
I can't perform with you guys.
I feel like a phony just being here.
Walter, just because you haven't
found your talent yet,
doesn't mean you don't have one.
If you look inside yourself,
I'm sure you'll find something
that you're really good at.
OK, Kermit. I'll try.
[woman] Take my picture!
Welcome.
How many in your party? Two?
Uh... No, just the one.
[chuckles]
All right, party of one, follow me.
# I look around, and once
again I'm on my own
# My man ain't here
He's gone and done me wrong
# No one's gonna stop this girl
from having fun
# I throw my hands up high
and have a party for one
# I'm having a me party
A party by myself
# A me party
I don't need nobody else
I'm the first and last to show
# There's no one at this party
that I don't already know
# I'm not gonna sit around
by myself and wait for you
# Haven't you heard?
One is the new two
# I'm gonna make a scene
I'm gonna make a fuss
# Tonight I'm gonna celebrate
with just the one of us
# I'm having a me party
# Haven't I seen me here before?
# A me party
# I'm the last one on the dance floor
- # Me party
- # A party just for moi
- # It's a solo Mardi Gras
# I'm having a me party
I'm such good company
- # A me party
- # I saved the last dance for me
[vocalizing]
# What happens at a me party
stays at a me party #
Excuse me, miss, are you
expecting anyone else?
Oh... no.
No, it's just me. Party of one.
- [bell dings]
- [man] Order up!
- OK, cue 17 is Fozzie's intro.
- Hey, Scooter? What's left?
Oh, uh, it's you, chief!
- Hm?
- Your duet. With Piggy.
[knocking softly]
[Miss Piggy singing
"(I've Had The) Time of My Life"]
- Miss Piggy?
- Hm?
We're all out front practicing our acts
and seems that everybody expects
you and I to do a duet, so...
Oh, that's so lovely,
but I'm afraid I can't.
No, no, you see, I'm already doing
a duet with my new dance partner.
Hola. [laughs]
OK, come on, rehearsing,
let's go. We gotta break it up.
- Excuse us.
- 'Scuse us.
Let's try that lift again, shall we?
[scoffs] The lift again.
OK, on my count this time, OK?
- In three, two... Wait for me!
- [crashing]
Good grief.
Kermit! There you are. I've been
looking for you everywhere!
So nice to see you, Veronica.
Who's hosting?
Did you find a celebrity?
Yeah, well, I've wanted to talk to you
about that, you see, because...
Well, actually, I'm kind of a celebrity.
You? [scoffs]
No. Kermit, listen.
I will not air the show unless
you find a real celebrity host.
I will rerun Benson if I have to.
Yeah, you see, the thing is, Veronica,
that's kind of impossible
because the show's in 12 hours!
Twelve hours!
I might as well just go and ask Tex
Richman to give us the studio back!
And the Muppets are like a big family.
Well... And for us,
that theater is... is like our home.
Which is why, in conclusion...
...we humbly ask that you
give us back our studio.
It would certainly mean a lot to us.
Hmmm.
Well, Mr. The Frog, let me see.
[singing]
Correct!
The answer is no.
Well, you could've just said that.
- Contract.
Contract.
- Nicely done, sir.
- You see, Muppets,
according to this contract,
it's not just this studio
you lose the rights to tonight,
- it's the Muppet name itself.
- What?
And all characters
under the Muppet name.
Wait a second. What possible use
could you have for our names?
[beeping]
Told ya I'd be back.
Well, now I am...
...back.
And I see you've met Mr. Richman,
our new business partner.
The Moopets are a hard, cynical act
for a hard, cynical world.
Hey, Fozzie! I want you
to meet a friend of mine.
[laughing]
- Wocka wocka.
- You're relics, Muppets!
The world has moved on,
and no one cares about
your goody-goody, hippy-dippy,
Julie Andrews and Dom DeLuise hostin',
singin'-and-dancin' act anymore!
You're dead!
- [gasps]
- And I just come to bury you.
Now, get out of my office.
- What?
- What is that supposed to mean?
You said you were gonna talk to the man!
Guys! OK, so maybe
Kermit signed away the theater
and the Muppet name, but as long
as we have a celebrity host,
we can still pull off a heart-warming,
last-minute triumph, right, Kermit?
Well, actually I
don't see how we can, Fozzie.
- Huh?
- [man] What?
Guys, the show's in six hours,
and we're barely rehearsed,
and, well, I...
I couldn't get us a celebrity host.
- Oh, no!
- What?
I'm afraid Tex Richman's right.
The world's moved on.
I'm sorry I dragged you guys
into this mess.
Kermit?
All right, listen up, you freaks!
I didn't come 5,000 miles
to not be on TV.
All we need is one stinkin' celebrity,
and by any means necessary.
Now, the frog's gone.
We're doing things my way from now on.
Let's move!
[alarms blaring]
- Hey!
- Hi.
- How was your day?
- Oh, it was great.
I went to Guinness Book
of World Records... alone.
Then Ripley's Believe It or Not... solo.
And then I ate lunch unaccompanied,
and then I walked back here...
independently.
Listen, I got you these.
You know, to make up for the
other ones. The broken ones.
Thanks, sweetie.
Listen, Gary.
I was just wondering what
the plan was for dinner tonight.
Oh, I don't care.
What do you feel like?
OK. That's fine.
That's just fine.
That's... that's perfect.
I'm going to go for a walk.
- Individually.
- [door opens]
[whistling]
[humming]
- Walter, hey.
- [Walter] Gary.
Oh, where have you been? I need you
to help me figure out a talent.
A talent for what?
For the show. Kermit asked me
to do an act in the show.
I... I could be a Muppet.
Wow. Wow, Walter, that's amazing.
Yeah, but I need to
figure out if I have a talent.
Well, you know what?
I'm sure you'll think of something,
but right now I actually...
I need your help.
I'm starting to get the feeling that
Mary's upset with me about something,
and I don't know what, and I was hoping
maybe you would talk to her for me.
Gary, I'd love to help you out,
but I can't leave the theater now.
This is important.
Well, hold on a second.
I mean, my life is important, too.
Yeah, but the whole reason we came here
was to see the Muppets.
No, it wasn't!
The whole reason we came here
was to take a vacation where
I took Mary out to a fancy dinner
because it's our tenth
anniversary, and then...
- Walter, what day is today?
- Friday.
Yeah. Yeah, that's it.
This is bad.
Walter, this is really bad. I have to...
- Mary? Mary!
- Wait.
Gary, I need you.
OK, is everybody ready?
Commence Operation
Celebri-nap. Masks on!
- Masks on!
- Except for moi.
Nothing covers this beautiful face.
- [gasps] No maskin'?
- No maskin'.
[man] Check the door on Stage 28.
- [man 2] I'm going over there now.
- [man on radio] She's done in makeup...
[panting]
I told you, I'm not done
putting on my balls!
Oh, hey, Animal.
What are you doin' here?
Acting. Natural.
[Miss Piggy] Now!
Whoa!
- Hiya!
- [yelling]
[grunting]
[yelling]
[mumbling]
Hiya!
Mary, surprise! I figured out
why you're mad... at me.
[Mary] Gary, I've gone home.
I love you, but you need
to decide, are you a man
or a Muppet?
# I reflect on my reflection
# And I ask myself the question
# What's the right direction to go?
# I don't know
# Am I a man
- # Or am I a Muppet?
- # Am I a Muppet?
# If I'm a Muppet
Then I'm a very manly Muppet
- # Very manly Muppet
- # Am I a Muppet?
- # Muppet
- # Or am I a man?
# Am I a man?
# If I'm a man that makes
me a Muppet of a man
# A Muppet of a man
# I look into these eyes
# And I don't recognize
# The one I see inside
# It's time for me to decide
# Am I a man
# Or am I a Muppet?
# Am I a Muppet?
# If I'm a Muppet
Well, I'm a very manly Muppet
- # Very manly Muppet
- # Am I a Muppet?
- # Muppet
- # Or am I a man?
# Am I a man?
# If I'm a man that makes
me a Muppet of a man
# A Muppet of a man
# Here I go again
# I'm always running out of time
# I think I made up my mind
# Now I understand who I am
# I'm a man
# I'm a Muppet
- # I'm a Muppet of a man
- # I'm a very manly Muppet
# I'm a Muppet-y man
I'm so sorry.
- Oh, Gary.
- Mary.
# That's what I am #
Kermit. We have our celebrity!
Mr. Jack Black has graciously
agreed to do the telethon!
Oh, my gosh, that's amazing.
Where is he?
- In the trunk.
- [Jack] Get me outta here!
You kidnapped Jack Black?
That's illegal!
But, Kermit, what's more illegal,
briefly inconveniencing Jack Black,
- or destroying the Muppets?
- Kidnapping Jack Black, Fozzie!
Kermit, listen. Whatever
I may think of you right now,
these guys are counting on you.
You inspire them.
- What, to kidnap people?
- To work together.
- To kidnap people?
- Mr. The Frog, we all agreed
a celebrity is not a people.
And now that we have a celebrity,
the show's back on.
Come on, Kermit.
Don't let these guys down now.
[sighs]
All right. Well, what are you
guys still doing here, huh?
- It's showtime!
- All right!
That's it!
- Nicely done, sir. As usual.
- En garde.
Ow! Ow.
OK, very nice. [grunts]
Halt! Point left!
Well done, sir. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
[man on TV] And coming up next on CDE,
The Muppet Telethon.
Kermit and friends host
a celebrity-studded gala,
- with special guest, Jack Black.
- Oh! He's pretty good.
[grunts]
- We're going to phase two.
- Yes, Mr. Richman.
[groans]
So do you think we're
working for the bad guy?
Hurry! The show starts in ten minutes!
[tires squealing]
Where did you learn to drive?
Hang on, everyone!
Come on, guys. OK, listen up, everybody!
This is it! Five minutes to curtain!
- Kermit?
- Get ready for the opening number.
- Yes?
- I need to talk to you about my act.
Listen, Walter,
I know you're gonna be fine.
In fact, I'm sure you'll be great.
Scooter, who's up first?
- Come on, come on, come on!
- No...
[Kermit] Fly in the arches!
- [sighs]
- [clucking]
- OK, first we have the opening theme.
- Of course. Yeah.
- You come out and introduce Fozzie.
- Right.
Then we have...
TV executive at six o'clock!
- What?
- The show is a disaster, Frog!
- Veronica...
- Where's the audience?
I knew you guys
weren't popular anymore.
I should have trusted that chart.
There's no one here!
- What about Hobo Joe?
- Who?
Why does everybody
forget about Hobo Joe?
- Just a second. Scooter!
- Yeah, chief?
- Did you hand out all those flyers?
- Of course. Every last one!
Don't worry.
We'll think of something!
- You better.
- [grunts]
Yoo-hoo! You've got audience.
It's me! What am I, invisible?
- [knocking]
- Jack Black.
Fifteen seconds to curtain, Mr. Black.
- Hi!
- Ah! Where am I?
Why am I so fancy? What are you doing?
You're ruining my look!
- We'll see you out there! Good luck!
- [Jack] Stop cleaning me!
- You sure got nice teeth, Jack Black.
- Yeah.
We're here!
- Start the show!
- Ready for some kind of entertainment!
All right, good luck, everyone,
and cue Scooter.
OK, we go live in three, two...
[man] Ladies and gentlemen, please
welcome your host, Kermit the Frog.
It's The Muppet Telethon,
with our very special guest,
Mr. Jack Black! Yay!
[up-tempo music playing]
# It's time to play the music
# It's time to light the lights
# It's time to meet the Muppets
on The Muppet Show tonight
# It's time to put on makeup
# It's time to dress up right
# It's time to get things started
# Why don't you get things started?
I always dreamed we'd be back here.
Dreams? Those were nightmares!
# It's time to get things started
# On the most sensational
inspirational, celebrational
# Muppetational
This is what we call The Muppet Show #
[Tarzan cry]
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to The Muppet Telethon!
We have Muppets standing by
to take your calls.
- Yes, we are.
- Hi. Hello.
Could I have a large pizza
with ham and...?
Yes, and, boy, do we have
a wonderful show for you,
with our special guest, Mr. Jack Black!
- [horns sounding]
- [laughing]
I'm being held captive by these weirdos!
Now you know how we've felt
for the past 40 years!
Somebody, anybody, please call
the police. This is real rope!
- Man, this 3-D is incredible!
- This is real!
Oh, and by the way, folks, we have
plenty of room here in the audience,
so if you'd like to come down
and see the show live...
There's no audience in the theater.
Look, it's totally empty.
Poor Walter.
Maybe we should go back.
No way, Mary.
I've made my choice already.
I just sang a whole song about it.
I wanna stay here with you.
So thank you.
[band plays]
Ladies and gentlemen,
prepare yourselves
for the Great Gonzo's
most amazing feat ever.
- Head bowling.
- What? No!
I have not signed off on this!
- [laughing]
- Drumroll, please.
- [dinging]
- And a one and a two and a three!
Uh-oh. Uh... My fingers got stuck.
All part of the act, folks. Stay tuned.
[laughing]
Please, make this end! Please!
This is great. Call'em.
- [telephone ringing]
- [all mumbling]
[buzzing]
Hello?
You wanna give us some money?!
Uhhh...
- Say yes!
- Yes! We will take that money!
[laughing]
Hey, guys, we got us some money!
Oh, yeah, tickets. Here we are.
Tickets. Thank you.
Five dollars to show you your seat.
It's up there somewhere.
- Help!
- OK, thank you, Gonzo.
Thank you very much. Ladies and
gentlemen, we will see what happens with
head bowling
a little later in the show.
Up next is our furry funny man,
Mr. Fozzie Bear! Yay!
Thank you, thank you, and thank you.
Boy, did I go to
a bad seafood place last night.
The catch of the day was salmonella.
Wocka wocka!
- OK.
- Ah! That joke's like 50 years old!
[laughing]
[Fozzie] So how'bout
those shopping centers?
You seen one,
you seen a mall! Take it.
Make it stop!
[laughing]
- Wocka wocka wocka wocka!
- [Jack] Make it stop! No!
- We're not a team! I'm not with him!
- What is happening?
People are actually watching this?
Deadly! Bring the car!
What am I gonna do?
- What am I gonna do?
- [knocking]
Walter? Sixty seconds
till you're on, Walter.
You ready?
No. Yes, yes, yes...
Whoopi Goldberg?
Selena Gomez? And... hi there.
Yeah, look, somebody said there
might be a career opportunity here,
- something about saving a theater.
- Yes, yes, of course.
I don't really know who you guys are.
My agent just told me to show up.
- That's great.
- Are you one of the
Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles?
Yes, I am, and let me
show you how you can help.
And don't worry. It's just your
one shot to go on live TV
before millions of people
to prove you have what it takes
to become one of the Muppets.
Good luck.
Up next, folks, I am proud
to present a brand-new act
to the show. Introducing Walter.
- [applauding]
- [inhales deeply]
- [screaming]
- [crashing]
[Fozzie] That's not good.
[clears throat] It appears that
Walter has stepped out, so it's...
Well, it's back to the days of
yore down at the old barbershop.
[applause]
[vocalizing]
- [laughing]
- [mumbling]
Oh, no! It's a barbershop quartet!
Get me out of here!
[vocalizing "Smells Like Teen Spirit"]
Wait a minute.
What are you doing?
Is that Nirvana? Stop it! No!
You're ruining one of the
greatest songs of all time!
Ow!
Careful around the ears!
[groans]
[high pitched]
Ah! That was hot!
Hey! What's going on here?
Why is my body so big?
What'd you do to my voice?
I sound like a chipmunk!
Wait a second.
Did you guys shrink my head?
[Kermit] Ladies and gentlemen,
Jack Black!
[applause]
Nice work, everybody. [mumbles]
Chickens, you're up next!
It's going rather nicely.
We might just make this.
And now I am
pleased and proud to present
those princesses of poultry,
Camilla and friends!
["Forget You" playing]
[clucking in tune]
[applause]
Let's hear it for Camilla
and her farmyard friends!
No, I... I don't know
why I'm not hosting this.
So remember, folks, keep on calling
and you'll help us reach our goal
of ten million dollars by midnight.
And if...
- [power failing]
- [gasping]
Oh, dear.
[Kermit] Ladies and gentlemen,
don't be alarmed.
We will get this sorted out
just as soon as we can. Scooter!
[crackling, sizzling]
Well, that's that. Nice try, Muppets!
- [laughing]
- [growling]
[Fozzie] Kermit, how are we going to
raise the rest of the money
with no electricity?
[Kermit] All right,
calm down, everybody.
- Is everybody OK?
- Yeah.
Well, we can't do the show
without power.
- Anybody got any bright ideas?
- Not now, Fozzie.
Ten-gauge gator grip.
I love it when you talk shop.
[exclaiming]
[sighing]
Oh! [clears throat]
- # La la la la la la la
- # Mee mee mee mee
[Tex] What? How'd they get
the power back?
[grunts]
We're gonna have to get up on that roof
and shut'em down for good!
Bolt cutters!
Bolt cutters.
Deadly! You come with me.
That's it.
Hm.
To the end of the Muppets!
[grunts]
Deadly! What are you doing?
Enough!
Just because I have a terrifying name
and an evil English accent,
does not preclude the
fact that, in my heart,
I am a Muppet, not a Moopet!
Looks like it's I who
will have the last laugh!
- What does that mean?
- It's an idiom, you idiot,
because you cannot laugh!
Ha ha!
- [thudding]
- Oopsie.
[Deadly laughing]
Deadly.
Now that's a maniacal laugh for you!
Hey, Gary, Mary, how'd
you guys get here so fast?
We travelled by map.
We thought it'd be quicker.
Hey, I'm sorry I bailed. I just...
I realized you don't let
the most important person
in your world slip away.
- Hey, Scooter?
- Yeah?
Could you do me a favor
and take over hosting duty?
But, chief, I don't go onstage.
Well, just do what I do.
Pretend that the audience is naked.
Yeah, but, I...
Ha... ha... ha...
[knocking]
Uh, Miss Piggy?
[audience applauding]
[stuttering]
- You are all naked.
- [gasping]
[Scooter] Well, sorta.
OK. Great!
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome, a real hero...
[Miss Piggy] You saved it?
After all this time?
Oh, Kermie.
[clears throat] I guess I'm not
that good at saying this kind of stuff.
- Yes, Kermie?
- Well...
...over the last week,
I realized that...
...I... I miss you.
And I need you.
And maybe you don't need the,
the whole world to love you.
Maybe you just need one person.
It's time for our song,
and if we don't raise the money tonight,
it might be the
last time we sing together.
[murmuring]
And... Well, are you ready?
Oh, Kermie.
[banjo playing]
# Why are there so many
# Songs about rainbows?
# And what's on the other side?
# Rainbows are visions
# But only illusions
# And rainbows have nothing to hide
# So we've been told
# And some choose to believe it
# I know they're wrong
Wait and see
# Someday we'll find it
# The rainbow connection
# The lovers, the dreamers and me
# All of us under its spell
# We know that it's
# Probably magic
# Have you been half asleep
# And have you heard voices?
# I've heard them calling my name
[panting]
Hey, these are yours, man.
I kept'em for ya.
- Drum.
- No drum.
- Drum!
- No drum!
- Drum! Drum!
- No drum! No drum!
[yelling]
You know what to do.
# I've heard it too many times
to ignore it
# It's something that
I'm supposed to be
- Aaah!
- # Someday we'll find it
# The rainbow connection
# The lovers, the dreamers and me #
[all vocalizing]
Drum! Drum, drum! Drum!
Ah ha ha ha ha.
- You still got it, man!
- [applause]
Piggy? Will you stay... for me?
- For you, Kermie?
- Yeah.
Of course!
Woo hoo!
Thank you, everybody.
Thank you, all.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's almost midnight and we haven't
quite reached our target yet,
but if you'll all just stick around,
we'll be right back with our final act.
[man on PA] The Muppet Telethon
will return after these messages.
Walter? Walter, where are you, buddy?
Listen, everybody, the show ran short,
and we don't have anything else planned.
[gasping]
We need one last act
to bring us home.
I'm gonna go check on Jack Black
and see if he has any ideas.
You guys see if you can
come up with something.
We have two minutes! Two minutes!
- Think, think, think!
- [Fozzie] What am I thinking?
Walter. Walt!
- Walter!
- Gary?
- Wha... You came back.
- Walter.
What are you doing down here?
They just need one more act. You gotta
get out there and help those guys.
I can't. What if people
laugh at me? I...
I'd rather go back home to Smalltown.
With you.
Look, Walter, you're my brother,
and I'm always gonna love you,
but you belong here, with these guys.
Hey, you're the one
who got Kermit to do this.
You're the one who brought
everyone here together.
You always believe in other people,
but that's easy.
Sooner or later, you gotta
believe in yourself, too,
because that's what growing up is.
It's becoming who you want to be.
You have to try. Please, Walter.
You're my hero.
[ticking]
- [ticking]
- [bell dings]
OK, Jack Black's got nothing.
What did you guys come up with?
- Bunsen can set Beaker on fire.
- No, no, no, we can't do that.
- I could break out the fart shoes.
- No, no, no, that will never work!
[man on P.A.]
We're back in three, two...
Oh, no!
[slow whistling]
[whistling]
It's Walter.
[whistles up-tempo song with orchestra]
[whistling higher octave]
- [hitting high note]
- [glass shattering]
[finale with orchestra]
[applause]
Thank you.
- He's all grown up.
- Oh, that was wonderful!
[Kermit] Ladies and gentlemen, Walter!
It looks like we're going
to get our studio back!
This just in: the Muppets are
about to take back their studio.
- [engine starts]
- [tires squealing]
[80's Robot] Help! I've been mugged.
Alerting authorities.
- [woman on phone] We're sorry...
- What happened? Hello?
- Hello?
- Guys, my phone is dead.
News flash: My phone is also dead.
Repeat, my phone is also dead.
[all] Ooh...
- [bell ringing]
- [groaning]
[audience gasps]
I did it. I beat you.
Game over, Kermit. You lost.
[groaning]
Chicky!
Too late, Muppets. I won!
Turn that thing off!
- The show is over!
- [audience gasps]
But we were so close!
- [whirring]
- [audience gasps]
Or not.
It kinda makes me
feel better, honestly.
I mean, we were
nowhere close at all.
You artists formerly
known as the Muppets
are standing on private property.
My private property.
And I'm telling you to leave. Now!
[whimpering]
He's right, everybody.
He won. We gotta go.
[sighs]
[sighs, sniffs]
[flatulence sounds]
[Rowlf] Not now, Fozzie.
[flatulence sounds cease]
- I can't believe this.
- I know.
Well, that's that.
[door slams]
This isn't right.
It can't end like this.
But what can we do?
[chattering]
Listen, everybody, we've got nothing
to be ashamed of. And you know why?
Well, because thanks
to Walter here, we tried.
And if we failed, we failed together,
and to me, that's not failing at all.
And I don't care what anybody says.
And I don't care if no one
believes in us, because I believe.
- I believe in you.
- Huh?
- And you.
- Me?
- [sighs]
You know, what's important
isn't this building or a name.
It's each other. So I say, fine,
let's just start at the bottom
and work our way back up to the top.
- [all] Yeah.
- Let's all walk out through these doors
with our heads held high. As a family.
- Because that's what we are.
- [all] Yeah. Yeah.
[sighing]
- [cheering]
- [cameras clicking]
[all] Muppets, Muppets, Muppets!
Wow.
All right.
[chanting continues]
- Wow.
- [laughs]
- Hey, where's Walter?
See? Your fans, they love you guys!
Hey, Walter.
Aren't you gonna join us?
- [Fozzie] Yeah! Come on!
- [Rowlf] Come on, Walter!
- Come on, Walter!
- Yes. Come!
What're you waiting for, buddy?
Get over there.
Yeah, go ahead.
[crowd cheering]
[all] Muppets! Muppets!
Muppets! Muppets! Muppets!
Hm? Oh.
How charming. A finale.
# Everything is great
# Everything is grand
# We've got the whole wide world
in the palm of our hand
# Everything is perfect
# It's falling into place
# I can't seem to wipe
this smile off my face
# Life's a happy song
# When there's someone
by your side to sing along
[grunts]
# Everything is great
And we'll live happily ever after
# And we'll keep giving the world
the third greatest gift
# Laughter
# Ze movie's almost over
It's time to say, "So long"
# Will you please stop singing?
You've already sung this song
# Life's a happy song when there's
someone by your side
# To sing along
We're happier when you don't sing.
# We've got everything that we need
# We can be whatever we want to be
# Nothing we can't do
# The skies are blue
when it's me and you and you and you
# And you and you and you and you
Well, all of you. Yeah!
# La la
La la la la la
[Jack] Hey, remember me? I'm Jack Black!
No, what are you doing? Whoa, whoa.
No, no, no. Put me back down.
- All hail the Hobo King.
- What are you doing? This is insane.
# We've got everything that we need
# We can be whatever we want to be
# Nothing that we can't do
# The skies are blue
when it's me and you and you and you
- # Life's a happy song
- # When there's someone
- # By your side to sing
- # Life's a happy song
# Mee mee mee
Mee mee mee
# Life's a happy song
when there's someone
- # Someone
# By your side
# To sing along
[whistling]
I just have one question
I need to ask you.
Will you, Mary... marry me?
- # Mahna Mahna
- # Do do do-do-do
- # Do do-do-do
- # Mahna Mahna
- You're breaking the law!
I own that name.
Hey, guys, I think I've finally
worked out how to... [yells]
"Oil" bet that hurt.
[laughing]
[man] This just in: "Richman gives
back Muppet theater and name.
Change of heart.
Nothing to do with head injury."
- # Mahna Mahna
- # Do do do-do-do
- # Do do-do-do
- # Mahna Mahna
- Hey, Richman! We had a deal!
- Yeah, for reallies!
- Yeah, you owe us money, man.
- What the wocka?
- [grunting]
Thank you.
- # Mahna Mahna
- # Do do do-do-do
- # Do do-do-do
[man] Breaking news: "Miss Piggy
promises to stay out of the limelight.
Kermit says,'We need some time alone. "'
- Oh, Kermie, I'm so happy.
- What are you talking about?
Let's share our happiness with ten of
the world's largest news publications.
- How's the quiet life, Kermit?
- Piggy, froggy!
- How are you enjoying your time alone?
- Piggy!
- # Mahna Mahna
- # Do do do-do-do
- # Do do-do-do
- # Mahna Mahna
- # Do do do-do-do
# Do-do-do, Do-do-do
Do-do-do
# Do-do
Do-do-do-do
# Mahna Mahna #
[# Bret McKenzie: "Life's a Happy Song"]