["Arabian Nights" playing]
# Follow me to a place
where incredible feats #
# Are routine
every hour or so #
# Where enchantment
runs rampant #
# Yes, wild in the streets #
# Open sesame, here we go! #
# Arabian nights #
# Like Arabian days #
# They tease and excite #
# Take off and take flight #
# They shock and amaze #
# Arabian nights #
# Like Arabian days #
# More often than not
are hotter than hot #
# In a lot of good ways #
[Neighs]
# Pack your shield,
pack your sword #
# You won't ever get bored #
# Though get beaten
or gored you might #
# Come on down, stop on by #
# Hop a carpet and fly #
# To another Arabian night #
# Arabian night #
[Neighing]
[Jingling]
This night
has been quite rewarding,
Ha ha ha!
We have never stolen so much,
We have gathered
much loot tonight,
No thanks to our leader,
[Grunting]
Aah! Oof!
[Crash]
Well,  it only looked  expensive.
[Creak]
Is this a haul or what,
my surly band of desert skunks?
Grr! How is it you get
the jeweled flower, Abis Mal?
Why, this is my bonus
for being your beloved leader,
This and that and that
are my beloved leader bonus,
And what is our reward?
ALL: Hmm?
Here you go, Good work, boys,
Very successful raid,
ALL: Grr!
[Gasps]
-The chest!
-lt moves!
-It cannot be!
-What is holding it up?
Aah! Ghosts!
Eek! Hello,
You stupid monkey!
ALADDIN:
Put him down, Abis Mal!
[Grunting]
[Screeching]
Who are you?
My friends call me Al,
You can call me Aladdin,
Gaah! Hurt him!
[Yelling]
-What?
-Where did he go?
-There!
-He has our loot!
ABIS MAL:
Don't let him get away!
-He must not escape!
-Stop him!
[Neighs]
Unh! Unh!
-Why, you--
-Hey!
Aah! Unh!
[Grunts]
[Shouting]
He's getting away!
ALL: Aah!
There he is!
-We've got him now!
-Ha ha!
[Abu screeching]
[Shouts]
A flying carpet?
He's got a flying carpet!
Nice catch, Carpet,
[Ping]
[Screech]
-Hey!
-Pbblltt!
ALADDlN: Pardon me!
Aaah!
Yeah!
[Gasps]
Come back here! Yaah!
[Screech]
Th-that's mine! Whoa!
Oof!
[Cracking]
[Crash]
[Clang]
Next stop, Agrabah,
-Shut the door!
-He's escaping!
[Whoosh]
Ha!
[Wind blowing]
Ptoo! [Coughing]
Finally! Ooh! Aah! Ohh!
This is terrific! Unh!
[Clanking]
Ohh! I got sand in places
I didn't even know I had,
JAFAR:
Spare me your prattling, Iago!
Are we out yet?
"Are we out yet?
Are we out yet?"
Yes, we're out!
No thanks to you,
If it Weren't for me,,,
you'd be stuck
down there forever, Oof!
JAFAR: Iago!
You will now release me...
so that I may have my revenge.
Yeah, yeah,
when I'm good and ready,
Do as I say,
you worthless pipsqueak!
You know something?
You're nothing without me,
What?!
Who comes up
with all the good ideas? Me!
Who does all the work? Me!
If it weren't for me...
you still be in a cage
at the bazaar...
squawking,
"Polly want a cracker!"
# That's it, I've had it #
# I hate to be dramatic #
# But it's time for me
to fly the coop #
# Terrific, fine #
# I'm drawing the line #
# Before I wind up
in a parrot soup #
# I was a fool to let you
run the show #
# I'm cuttin ' you loose, pal #
# Look out below #
# Arrividerci,
C 'est la vie #
# Hope all goes well #
# I'm lookin ' out for me #
IAGO : Agrabah...
just a juicy golden goose
ready for plucking,,,
and I'm the one
holdin' the tweezers!
I'll be runnin' this town
inside a Week!
What's your problem,
liver lips?
You don't think I can do it?!
# OK, I'm little #
# Been playin' second fiddle #
# And I don't get no respect #
# I turn the other cheek #
# But this busted beak #
# Is the only thanks
that I get #
# I never found a friend
that I can trust #
# They promise caviar
and leave me eating dust #
# That's some reward
for loyalty #
# From here on in #
# I'm lookin' out for me #
# Ohh,
I don't need nobody else #
Huh? Grr!
# I'll never fail #
# I'll cover my own tail #
# I can take care of myself #
# You know, it just don't pay
to give a hoot #
# I've given all my heart #
# What do I get? The boot #
# I'm through with that #
# I'm flappin' free #
# From here on in #
# I'm lookin' out for me #
[Splat]
Steal from us again,,,
and your scrawny body
will be dinner for the jackals!
Sure, No problem,
Oof! [Crash]
[Dramatic music playing]
[Screech] Huh?
[Clattering]
[Screech]
No! No!
-Abu!
-No!
We're not the ones
who need this money,
Ohh,,,
[Gasps] A miracle,
-Rain on me!
-Ohh!
MAN: Gold from the heavens!
Don't worry, Abu,
I'm not throwing everything,
Yes!
This is for Jasmine,
No!
Whoa!
[Growling]
Uh-oh,
Easy, Rajah,
You know me, Aladdin?
[Growling]
Aah!
[Slurp]
Ha ha! OK, Rajah, OK,
I'm glad to see you, too,
Phew!
Ahem, How do I look?
Huh?
-I think you look fine,
-Jasmine!
Where were you?
I missed you,
I had to pick up a few things,
This is for you,
Oh, Aladdin! It's lovely!
"It's lovely,"
It must have cost a fortune,
Oh, no, it was a steal,
JASMINE: Father wants you
to join us for dinner tonight.
He's going to make
a royal announcement,
And he wants me there?
It's about you,
Am I in trouble?
Let's just say,,,
this is a dinner
you don't want to miss,
ALADDIN:
Jasmine, what's going on?
I promised Father
I Wouldn't spoil his surprise,
Unh!
You've made quite
an impression, you know,
[Clinking]
Hmm?
ALADDIN:
So I'm not in trouble?
JASMINE: Of course not.
You defeated Jafar,
saved Agrabah...
and rescued a princess,
Aladdin, you are a hero,
Yeah, I guess so,
That's me,
Ready for anything!
[Snarling and screeching]
Abu!
Pbblltt!
[Boing]
[Poof]
[Coughing] Eww!
You may want to change
before dinner, though,
[Laughs] Uh-oh,
IAGO:
Seems like only yesterday...
Jafar was runnin' Agrabah.
And I was his right-hand bird,
But then he had
to go and mess things up!
Now I'm stuck on the outside
looking in,
I gotta get back
into the palace!
Back into power!
Well,  my dear Abu...
shall we see what
the common folk are doing today?
Let's go! [Chattering]
Ha ha ha!
We have time for a stroll before
our audience with the sultan,
The street rat is living
in the palace now?
Aah! That does it!
All reports are in!
Life is now officially unfair!
Wait! Wait a second here!
This is perfect!
That kid is my ticket
back into power,
I'll just get Aladdin on my side
with a little sympathy act,
Then I'll be back
in the palace again,,,
quicker than
you can say "Easy Street,"
-Aladdin!
-Huh?
Kid,,,finally,,,got free,,,
of,,,Jafar, [Cough]
Iago!
What are you doing here?
Where are you?
Getting dark,,,
Hold me--Aah!
Hey, I meant gentle-like!
You're not fooling anyone!
No, wait, I'm serious!
I was under Jafar's power!
He mesmerized me
with his snake staff!
Just like the sultan,
[Screeching]
You traitor, you!
-Oof!
-Unh!
[Thump]
Ohh,,,
You look familiar,
BOTH: It's Aladdin,
Where?!
It is? I knew that!
Hurt him a lot!
Hurt him and his monkey
and his bird, too!
[Screeching]
Aah! Oh!
-Yaah!
-Unh!
BOTH: Uh-oh,
Raah!
[Yelling]
Aah!
Unh!
[Crash]
Ohh,,,
Treacherous parrot!
Aah!
Look, I'm not with him! Aah!
-Unh!
-Aah!
-Ha ha ha!
Monkey, help!
They're after me!
Yaah!
-Aah!
-Yaah!
[Thieves yelling]
Unh!
[Growling]
You won't dance
out of this one! Ha ha ha!
[Splat]
That's it! Now I'm mad!
Ptoo!
Rreee!
[Squish]
[Groans]
[Struggling]
-Ha ha!
-Ohh,,,
Mess with this bird, huh?
[Grunts]
Whoa!
Huh?
ALL: Oof!
[Chickens clucking]
IAGO: And I got more
where that came from!
My eggs--ruined!
Who will pay for them?
Oh, go away,
Guards! Guards!
[Grunts]
What is the trouble here?
It is that thief Abis Mal!
[Neighs]
Whoa!
After them!
[Coughs] Jerks,
Uh, thanks for your help,
You saved me,
I did? Right! Oh, yeah!
Of course I saved you!
It's my nature,
I'm always rescuing things,
Cats, babies, guys like you,
always rescuing,
Hey, what's going on?!
Oof! Is this any way
to treat your rescuer?!
You owe me, pal!
I saved your life!
Abu, wait!
[Sighs] He's right,
I do owe him,
Huh?
I'll see that the sultan
gives him a fair hearing,
What?!  The Sultan?!  Ow!
Don't worry, I'll talk to him,
Soften him up a little,
Are you kidding?
He hates me!
[Crash]
And what about the princess?!
Hmm? No problem,
I just have to make sure
that Jasmine doesn't see you,,,
until I've gotten her prepared,
JASMINE:
Gotten me prepared for what?
Aah! Uh, I mean, uh,
for the--for the stain,,,
Abu got on
the brand new vest you gave him,
Eek! I did not!
I don't see a stain,
Ah, well, no problem, then,
Off to dinner,
Can't wait for that surprise,
-ls something wrong?
-Huh? Wrong? Oh, come on!
No, no, no,
everything's just fine,
You aren't hiding anything
from me, are you?
Any more secrets?
S-secrets? Heh, Ahem,
Of course not!
I almost lost you once that way,
I'll never make
that mistake again,
What?
[Rumbling]
Yee-haw!
[Boing]
He's big and
he's blue and he's back!
-Genie!
-You came back!
Ooh! Aah! Ooh!
Watch the sunburn!
A-ha! Kidding!
Did you miss me? Be honest,
Take care of these,
my good mammal,
Whoa!
Careful, they're heavy!
Hang on, I got souvenirs
for everybody!
Whoo! She dances!
You saw the whole world already?
# It's a small world
after all #
But Agrabah has something,,,
that no other place
in the world has,
[Trumpet plays]
GENIE: You guys!
[Music playing]
# I parachuted down
into the Taj Mahal #
# I Rollerbladed all along
the great Great Wall #
# I even made
the famous leaning tower fall #
# But who was with me
through it all? #
# Nobody #
# The Moscow Circus hired me
to fly trapeze #
# On Mount Olympus,
won a race with Hercules #
# It's easy when you're chased
by killer bees #
# Who said "Gesundheit"
when I sneezed? #
# Ah-choo #
# So now I'm home #
# Home again with you #
# You chase the clouds away #
# Whenever I am blue #
You're always blue,
# Land of the pyramids #
# I highly recommend #
[Poof]
# There is nothing
in the world #
# Quite like a friend #
# Slept like a babe in Bombay
on a bed of nails #
# Moroccans loved my daring
Dance of Seven Veils #
# Why, single-handedly,
I even saved the whales #
# No one was there
to hear my tales #
[Sobbing]
# In Acapulco,
joined a mariachi band #
# I rode the raging rapids
down the Rio Grande #
# Flew in an air balloon,
but when I tried to land #
# Nobody laughed
or lent a hand #
# Without you,
the Amazon is just a trickle #
the Sahara's not so hot #
# Without you, Niagara Falls
is just a leaky faucet #
# The QE2 is just some yacht #
[Crash]
# Now that I'm home #
# Home  again,  it's  clear #
# All I ever wanted #
# Seems to be right here #
# I've traveled east and west #
# And now I'm back again #
# And there's nothing
in the world #
# Quite like a friend #
# There's nothing
in the world #
# Nothing in
the whole wide world #
# There is
nothing in the world #
# Quite like a friend #
# Nothing in
the whole wide world #
So, Genie,
how does it feel to be free?
Seriously? I love it!
OK, maybe my powers
aren't what they used to be,
Let's say
they're semi-phenomenal,,,
nearly cosmic,
but don't sell me short,
I may be free, but I still have
some magic in me,
I can still do this!
[Gulp]
[Muffled] Hey!
Hate to lose face
in front of you guys,
Give me another chance,
Who's first? I can do this!
-Genie, we have to go to--
-Dinner! We're late!
Ohh, you probably have,,,
a romantic dinner for two
planned,
You don't need a big blue lug
gumming up the works,
-But, Genie--
-Three's a crowd,
You kids go on,
Genie, I would be honored
if you'd join us for dinner,
You would? Ooh!
Come on, everyone!
Get in here!
Home cookin'? Let's go!
ABU: Oh, boy! [Chatters]
Not you, Abu,
You have a job to do, remember?
-Huh?
-You have to guard lago!
Ohhh,
[Chattering]
Giddy-up, slow-poke,
What's keepin' ya?
Nothing!
Well, something,
but I'll tell you later,
[Horse neighs]
ABlS MAL:
That stinking Aladdin,
First chance I get,
I'll slice him in half,
That stinking Abis Mal,
First chance we get,
let's slice him in half,
ABIS MAL:
Hey, get over here and wash up!
It's bad enough
I have to look at you,,,
without having to smell you,
Come, we do it now,
No witnesses,
[Clank] Ow!
Ooh, What is this?
So help me,
I'll sue whoever runs this well,
A lamp, Well, well,
it might be worth,,,
a few shekels
once it's cleaned up,
It will be of
little use to you, Abis Mal!
Except to light your way
to the Valley of the Dead!
-Aah!
-lt is bewitched!
[Jafar laughing]
[Neighs]
[Crackling]
I am free!
Free to exact vengeance
upon he who has imprisoned me!
Unh! [Grunting]
It is the curse of the lamp.
All the power in the universe,,,
and I am bound
by the rules of the genie!
Which means I can't kill
that upstart Aladdin!
Unless I have someone
arrange it for me,
Take me to Agrabah at once!
Aah! [Whimpering]
[Gibbering]
I suppose I am a bit too much
for his limited mind,
I trust you'll find me
a little less overwhelming now?
You're,,,a genie?
You are astonishingly
perceptive,
[Rattles]
Um,,,Ahem,
If you're a genie,
then don't I get wishes?
Yes, three wishes,
That is a minor formality,
But, first,
I must go to Agrabah,
You will take the lamp
there for me,
Then,,,ahem,,,you need me,
I'll take you to Agrabah,,,
but, first, I want my wishes,
[Crackling]
[Yelling]
Why, you,,,
You shall have your wishes,
I shall?
I mean, of course I shall!
Ha ha! Oh, I want--
I want riches, treasure!
Let's see, I know, um,,,
I wish for the legendary
sunken treasure ship,,,
of Coeur du Mer!
Your wish is my command,
[Bubbling]
Aah!
[Growls]
Poor sweet baby,
Aren't we enjoying our wish?
Aah!
Perhaps you wish me
to return you to the desert?
Yes!
Very well,
That was two wishes,
Take your time with the third,
Or you will wish
you had never been born,
[Gulp]
On the other hand,
if you cooperate with me,,,
I will see
that you are amply rewarded,
Rewarded?
First, you will help me
get revenge,,,
on a certain street rat
by the name of,,,Aladdin,
[Gasps] Aladdin?!
I want revenge on him, too!
He robbed me,
turned my men against me,,,
and he fought dirty!
My brilliant swordsmanship
availed me nought!
Ooh!
I--I hate When I do that,
Let's not be too hasty,
my simple-minded friend,
It's not enough
that we simply destroy Aladdin,
After all, there are things
so much worse than death,
[Laughing evilly]
[Laughter echoing]
OK, prepare yourselves
for a real culinary treat,
Hyah! Hyah!
Oh-ho-ho-ho, my!
[Snick]
GENIE: Whoopsie.
[Tapping]
Ha ha ha! Most amusing!
Ha, Amusing, right,
Excuse me
while I pull myself together,
Ha ha ha!
Absolutely delightful!
Now, to business,
Aladdin, you have proven
to be a man,,,
of strong moral character,
That is why I've decided
to make you,,,
my new royal vizier,
Me? Really?
Isn't it Wonderful?
[Whoosh]
Wow! Royal vizier!
[Poof]
Aladdin would like
to thank the Academy,,,
for this great honor!
You want 'em? We got 'em!
Royal vizier t-shirts!
[Aroo] All hail
Aladdin, the royal vizier!
So, uh, what's a royal vizier?
Uh, well, uh,,,
he will be
my most trusted advisor,
Well,that  makes sense.  Pfft!
He's bound to be better
than that Jafar character,
Quite so!
GENIE: And Iago--
talk about a rat with wings!
-Uh, Genie?
-Whoo! That bird was mean!
Sultan want a cracker?
Remember that?
I can still taste them!
The traitor!
Yes, sir!
You don't see this guy,,,
hanging out
with any evil parrots!
Heh, It's funny
you should mention lago,
[Crickets chirping]
Oh--oh, monkey!
Woo woo woo!
Come on! Monkey, little birdie
want to talk to monkey,
Have nice banana,
Woo woo woo!
Birdie get monkey
a pretty banana,,,
if monkey open cage,
Yum yum!
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Come on!
I've got a wife and three eggs!
Imagine them hatching,
never knowing their daddy!
Come on, open the cage!
Open it! Open it! Open it!
[Squeak]
Yeah, that's more like it,
Aah!
[Snarling]
Close the cage!
Close it! Close it! Close it!
ABU: Ow!
[Snarls]
Yaah!
-Aah!
-Uh-oh!
Your monkey's trying to kill me!
I saved your life!
It's payback time, Aladdin!
Aah!
Whoa!
Aladdin!
[Screech]
ABU: Ow!
JASMINE: Rajah!
You know better...
than to tear around
the palace like that!
IAGO: Help! Hey!
SULTAN: So, Aladdin...
why did you bring up
that deceitful parrot?
Sultan, I have to tell you
something about lago,
[Ah-choo]
[Gulp] He's here,
[Gasps] lago! Guards!
-No, wait!
-Get that bird!
Yes, Your Highness,
It would be my pleasure,
ALADDIN: No, Sultan! No!
Move out of my way, boy!
You don't understand!
Just listen!
-I have a--
-Your Highness!
I trust he has
a fitting explanation,,,
for this--this scandal?
He had better,
Your Highness,
I think lago was, uh--
Mesmerized,
Yeah, yeah!
He was under Jafar's spell,
Remember the snake staff?
Iago was only, uh--um--
Look, I just--
Iago's not all that bad,
At least
I don't think so anyway,
Shoulda stuck
with the snake staff defense,
"Not all bad"?
He only served
my greatest enemy, that's all!
We can't allow that
traitorous bird to run free!
Then I'll Watch him! Uh--
You Highness, I meant,
with your permission,,,
I'd like to take
full responsibility for lago,
You would?!
Your priorities
seem questionable to me,,,
but so be it,
Aladdin, you will watch
lago every moment,
And if the bird
makes one wrong move,,,
you shall be
the one I pluck, boy,
Uh, that could've gone worse,
Oh, Jasmine,
I thought I was sunk,
Ooh, not good!
You were hiding lago
all along, weren't you?!
I think it just got worse,
Well,yes,  but--
How could you?
More secrets? More lies?
Aladdin,
I thought you had changed,
Jasmine, wait!
Back in the marketplace,,,
Iago--he--
He saved my life,
[Sighs] Some grand vizier
I'm gonna make,
Everybody's mad at me,
Hey, Jasmine's
just a little steamed,
She'll cool down,
Care for a cup?
Uh, this isn't
cheering you up, is it?
Uggh!
I don't get it, Genie,
I try to do something good,,,
and it--it blows up
in my face!
Ohh, that's the problem
with doing the right thing,
Sometimes you do it by yourself,
That kid saved my life,
Nobody's ever looked out
for me before,
Now, it's--it's like I owe him,
Nah!
Just let your conscience
be your guide,
Conscience?
Never had one, Never,
Whoo ha ha ha ha!
Whew! What are you trying to do,
give me a heart attack?
A-ha! You do have a heart!
An itty-bitty one,
but it is there,
[Poof]
Can you quit
with the hocus pocus already?
Look at him,
Would it kill you to do
something nice for him?
Possibly, I don't do "nice,"
Oh, come on! It'll be fun!
I don't do fun, either!
We have to get Al
and the princess back together!
Look, I definitely don't do
mushy stuff!
It's not me!
I know,
but it's going to be tricky,
Tricky is good,
Tricky I can do,
[Crickets chirping]
[Jasmine crying]
[Sniffling]
IAGO : Come on, Princess!
Don't waste your tears on him,
You! You get out of here!
Hey, don't take it out on me!
He's the creep,
I never should have
saved his life,
Saved his life?
Yeah, He owed me one,
That's why he stood up for me,
But he didn't have to lie to me,
You are so right,
# Forget about that guy #
# Forget about the way
you fell into his eyes #
# Forget about his charms #
# Forget about the way
he held you in his arms #
# Walking on air's obnoxious #
# The thrills, the chills #
# Will make you nauseous #
# And you'll never get enough #
# Just forget about love #
She's buying it!
Now make with the magic!
IAGO : # Forget about romance #
# Forget about the way
your heart begins to dance #
# Then you feel the blush #
# When he's spouting out
some sentimental mush #
# Love really is revolting #
# It's even worse than
when you're molting #
# Enough of this fluff #
# Just forget about love #
# I had almost forgotten
the way it felt #
# When he held out
his hand for mine #
# My heart all a-flutter #
# Oh, how I shudder #
# The first time we kissed #
# It won 't be missed #
# Forget about his touch #
# I can 't forget about
his touch #
# In the scheme of things
it doesn 't matter much #
# It matters so much #
# You're better on your own #
# A meal becomes a banquet
when you eat alone #
# Mmm mmm mmm mmm #
# Love's filled
with compromises #
# And don't you hate
those big surprises #
# A cozy rendezvous #
# Oh, please #
# Candlelight for two #
# Oh, jeez #
# Look,
you're calling my bluff #
-# I can't #
-# Just #
BOTH: # Forget about love #
Uh, Jasmine, I'm sorry,
I shouldn't have kept
lago a secret, Please--
Aladdin,
you don't have to--Shh!
# I can't forget
about my heart #
# And how it felt to fall
for you right from the start #
# I'm still falling #
# Whatever we may do #
# You are here for me
and I'll be there for you #
# I'll be there #
# To wish, to want,
to wander #
# To find the sun
through rain and thunder #
# A cozy rendezvous #
# Yes, please #
# Candlelight for two #
IAGO : # Oh, jeez #
# Enough is enough #
# We can't forget about love #
[Footsteps]
[Grunting]
[Creak]
Unh! [Thud]
We  did  it!  We're  in!
It's about time,
It was getting hot,
How very like lago,
He's lost no time endearing
himself to those in power.
Which fits in perfectly
with my plan,
I'm sorry, Jasmine,
Shh,
GENIE: Ahh, love.
Don't mind us,
Yeah, well, this is kind of
a special moment,
Right, Got it, Say no more,
Enough said,
Roger, Over and out,
[Ding]
[Click]
Rolling!
[Clack]
Today's special moments
are tomorrow's memories,
Looking great, Jas,
More emotion, Al,
Tilt your chin a bit,
What does he have to do,,,
to make it clear
to you lunkheads?!
The show's over,
They want to be alone!
Break it up!
Are you sure about him?
Move it, primate!
Shoo! Go on!
[Screeching] Aah!
That takes care of
the peanut gallery,
If you need me,,,
I'll be lazing about
in the lap of luxury,
I'm sure about this,
Ohh, yeah!
Being one of the good guys
has its advantages,
Ahh, advisor to Aladdin,,,
the new grand vizier,
And when
Aladdin becomes sultan,,,
that will make me
the grand vizier,
Only I'm not gonna blow it
like that idiot Jafar,
[Gulp] Mm-mm,
I'll never have to stand
in his shadow again,
[Whoosh]
Awk!
Jafar!
Buddy?
Ah-heh,
A funny thing happened,
You see, this guy took the lamp,
You probably
thought it was me,,,
'cause
it sounded a lot like me,,,
but a lot of people
sound like me,
Anyway,
he took the lamp and--Aah!
Calm yourself, lago,
I haven't come
for revenge against you,
Ha ha!
So that's good to hear,
I got it! I could wish for
the famed treasure chest,,,
of King Malakhan!
[Thump]
[Yelling]
[Gasps]
Oh, I am dreadfully sorry,
I thought that was your wish,
Are you quite all right?
No, I am not quite--
Wonderful,
Good to see all is well,
Abis Mal here
is my new friend,,,
and I couldn't help
noticing,,,
that you've made
some new friends, too,
Like,,,Aladdin,
Friend?
Friend is such a strong word,
He's--he's more like
an acquaintance,
I'm arranging
a little surprise for Aladdin,,,
and your job is
to lead him to the party,
You know, I don't think
I'm the guy for this job,
You know, you should talk to,
uh, the monkey!
Yeah! The monkey's really got
Aladdin's ear!
No, lago,,,you!
You know,
Aladdin--ahem--Al,,,
h-here's an idea,
I--l--I was just thinking,
ahem--
GENIE: Focus... focus.
Focus... focus...
focus,,,focus,,,
Aiming,,,and,,,
Shoot!
Aah! Mmf!
[Zoom]
Oh, sorry,
little feathered friend,
I'll get that out,
Uh-huh! Hah!
Unh! Oh, it's stuck good,
Cueball-ectomy! Nurse!
Abu!
Iago here's our friend now,
We can trust him,
Now, let's get that ball,,,
out of his beak,
What do you say?
Uh,,,OK,
Ptoo!
GENIE:
Brilliant, Nurse Heimlich!
[Thud]
[Coughs]
Thanks,,,Bobo,
-It's Abu,
-Whatever,
That's the spirit!
We're all one big family now!
Uh, yeah, sure, Family,
ABU: Oh, brother,
Yeah, well, I gotta find Al,
Your shot, [Poof]
Pool's a man's game...
so being a rug,
you'll be at a disadvan,,,
Oh, pool's a dumb game anyway,
ALADDIN:
I can't explain it, Jasmine.
I think we can trust Iago.
Well...
then I guess
I can give him a chance,
[Door squeaks]
Iago?
Uh, l--I was just thinking,
Maybe it's time you patched
things up with the sultan,
Uh, he might enjoy,,,
a nice scenic carpet ride?
-Hmm, that's a good idea,
-And I'll bring Genie,
He was a big hit
with the sultan.
No, no, no!
Um, I mean, Genie's--
he's too flashy!
He's too loud!
You'll never get a word in,
Good point, lago,
You need some quiet time
with Father,
Let him get to know you,
Yeah! And l,,,
I can take you
to the perfect spot,
-Great!
-Come on, let's get Father,
Just a minute,
Iago?
This isn't easy for me to say,,,
but I was wrong about you,
Aah! Wait a second!
Yes, lago?
Uh, I'll be along in a minute,
Excellent,
JASMlNE:
Give them a chance, Father,
SULTAN:
Ohh, I'll try, dearest,
After you, Your Highness,
Oh! Ha ha ha! Hooo!
All right, Carpet, let's go!
-Whoopee!
-Have a good time!
GENlE: Hey, hey!
Clear the way!
Make room for the picnic boys!
[Chatters]
They already left, Genie,
[Gasps] Without us?!
ABU: Without us?
No problem!
I'll catch up in a flash!
Wait! Without me, too!
Aladdin needs some time,,,
alone with Father
to patch things up,
You know what this means,
monkey boy?
More food for us!
ABU: Oh, boy!
[Chomping]
I'm sorry, Did you want some?
I'm,,,not hungry just now,
You two go ahead,
[Chomping]
[Wind blowing]
Ha ha! Come on, my boy!
Show me what this thing
can really do!
[Whoosh]
BOTH: Aah!
IAGO: That's the spot!
On top of the waterfall!
Aah!
I'm losing my feathers here!
You're lucky you haven't lost
more than that!
Whoa!
SULTAN: Ha ha ha ha!
Oh! Oh, what fun! Ha ha ha!
[Groans]
ALADDIN: Iago,
I have to hand it to you.
This is a nice place,
Ahh, it doesn't get any better
than this, eh, Shaggy?
How about a nice drumstick?
This could use
some secret herbs and spices.
Eww!
[Screeching]
[Skittering]
Spiders?!
Things could get ugly!
[Hissing]
[Poof]
-Jafar!
-Uh-oh!
Sorry to spoil
your picnic, boys,,,
but I can't have any genies
mucking about,,,
ruining my plans,
Don't worry, Abu,
He's a genie,,,
and genies can't kill anyone,
[Roars]
[Coughs]
But you'd be surprised
what you can live through,
Ha ha ha! You always
were good for a laugh,
Oh, yeah?!
[Panting]
Ha ha ha!
Who's laughing now?
Ha ha ha ha!
Why, I believe it's me,
[Screech]
# I must admit #
# Your parlor tricks
are amusing #
# I bet you've got a bunny
under your hat #
# Now, here's your chance
to get the best of me #
# Hope your hand is hot #
# Come on, clown,
let's see what you've got #
# You can try to slam me
with your hardest stuff #
# But your double whammy
isn't up to snuff #
# I'll set
the record straight #
# You're simply out of date,
you're only second rate #
# You think
your cat's a meanie #
# But your tiger's tame #
# You've got a lot to learn
about the genie game #
# So for your education,
I'll reiterate #
# You're only second rate #
# Men cower at the power
in my pinky #
# My thumb is number one
on every list #
# But if you're not convinced
that I'm invincible #
# Put me to the test #
# I'd love to lay
this rivalry to rest #
# Go ahead and zap me
with the big surprise #
# Slap me in a trap,
cut me down to size #
# I'll make a great escape,
it's just a piece of cake #
# You're only second rate #
# You know, your hocus-pocus
isn 't tough enough #
# And your mumbo-jumbo
doesn 't measure up #
# Let me pontificate
upon your sorry state #
# You're only second rate #
# Zaba-caba-dabra #
# Granny's gonna grab ya #
# Alakazam-na-bus #
# This thing's bigger
than the both of us #
# So spare me
your tremendous scare #
# You look horrendous
in your underwear #
# And I can hardly wait
to discombobulate #
# I'll send ya back and
packing in a shipping crate #
# You'll make a better living
with a spinning plate #
# You're only second rate #
[Snick]
Hello? Hello?
[Screeching]
Ahh, that was invigorating!
Come, Abis Mal,,,
we have other lives to ruin,
Sultan,,,
Look, I'm sorry for
not telling you about lago,
Hmph!
I guess
I saw some good in him,,,
just like you saw
some good in a street rat,
The good I saw in a,,,
Well, oh,yes, I--I  suppose.
Well said, my boy!
Oh, you'll be a fine vizier!
This was a great idea, lago,
Thanks,
Oh, don't thank me, Really,
[Neighs]
[Gasps]
-Aah!
-Sultan!
[Neighs]
Abis Mal?!
Aladdin! Oh!
[Coughing]
-Awk!
-You traitor!
Traitor is such a strong word,
Aladdin! Help!
I'll settle with you later,
-Awk!
-Come on, Carpet!
Look, they're trapped
on the cliff!
When they stop, we'll--What?
[Neighing]
Abis Mal knows magic?
Who-o-o-a!
[Whoosh]
What? Get him!
Get the sultan!
Hang on, Sultan!
This is where we lose them,
[Neighing]
Aah!
Sultan!
We have to go back, Carpet!
[Yelling]
Aah!
[Coughing]
ABIS MAL: Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
[Laughing]
Yes!
Huh?
ABIS MAL:
What are you doing?!
[Splash]
Are you nuts?! You saved him!
He Was this close,,,
to being a greasy
little smear on the rocks!
Look, you little--
I mean, my dear Abis Mal,,,
if you remember the plan,,,
it is not yet time
for the boy to meet his end,
Um, I knew that,
Soon, our revenge
will be complete,,,
and you shall have
your third wish,
Ooh, ooh,
my little wishy! Hee hee!
And you, lago!
You have done well,
Please, don't mention it,
[Coughing]
Sultan!
Iago,
[Groans]
SULTAN: Jafar, you fiend!
I should have known
that this was your treachery!
But I couldn't have done it
without lago,
Uh, l--I played
a minor role, really,
Jafar!
This,,,rug won't cooperate!
Oof!
[Rattling]
Ooh, when Aladdin returns,,,
I think we have ample time
to prepare for his arrival,
Hey! That was a nice hat,
I could have worn that hat!
We need this for our plan,
Couldn't we use another hat
for the plan?
Oh, no, The sultan's turban
and this dagger,,,
are exactly what we need,,,
to seal Aladdin's doom.
[Music playing]
[Panting]
Razoul! The sultan's been--
Seize him!
You are under arrest,,,
for the murder of the sultan!
What?! No!
And then you went
over the waterfall, eh?
Ha! How did you survive?
I,,,l don't know,
How very convenient,
It's the truth!
Why won't you believe me?
JASMINE:
Because we know you're lying!
-Huh?
-I found this in your room,
My father's turban--slashed!
-You can't think--
-I thought you loved me!
But now I see
that all you wanted to do,,,
-was rule Agrabah!
-I never wanted--
He shall die at dawn
for the murder of my father,
Jasmine, please!
You're in my hands now,
street rat!
Ha ha ha!
Oh, you should have seen
the look on Aladdin's face,,,
when Princess Jasmine
sentenced him to death,
[Gasps] No!
Oh, yes!
And then I get my wish,
Yes, and then you get your wish,
Iago! I swear one day
you will pay for this!
Heh, I really think
you're making,,,
too big a deal out of this,
Such spirit! Aah!
Perhaps after
a few days in chains,,,
you'll be more kindly
disposed toward me,
Especially if you want
your father to remain healthy!
Ah, lago,,,
you betrayed me and
allied yourself with my enemies,
Then you turned on them,,,
as soon as it was in
your best interests,
That's what I love about you,
You're so perfectly predictable,
A villain through and through,
Thank you, Thank you, Ooh,
[Rooster crows]
[Clang]
[Sniffs] Ahh! Dawn!
[Shackles rattling]
[Poof]
I'll tell your boyfriend
good-bye for you, Princess,
[Grunting]
When  I  get  hold  of you,  Jafar...
[Screeching]
I'm so Worried,
Whew!
[Dramatic music playing]
Raah!
How could you
double-cross Aladdin,,,
after all he's done for you!
[Screeching]
Hey, do I insult your mother?
Ack! Mmm,
[Tap tap tap]
[Clang]
[Sighs]
What are you doing now?
Oh, what does it look like
I'm doing?
I'm trying to free
the chump genie,,,
so he can save
your chump boyfriend! Aah!
[Metal clanging]
[Scraping]
[Whoosh, thump]
[Dramatic music playing]
[Shackles rattling]
Oh! Aah! Gaah!
[Boing boing boing]
You have to lift it higher!
[Gasping]
Sure, No problem,
-Wait!
-Jasmine!
I knew you wouldn't
go through with this,
I just wanted
to say good-bye,,,street rat,
[Gasps] Jafar! It's Jafar--
[Straining]
Unh! Mmf!
[Grunting] Yaah!
Unh! Thanks for saving me!
Oh, come on, Al,
You know I had to,
Oh, that no-head look
is just not you,
For my next trick,
bibbidy bobbidy boo!
Oh-ho,
and everybody's safe and sound,
Aladdin!
[Chattering]
Ha! Good to see you, too, Abu!
There's somebody else
who wants to talk to you,
Hello,
You set me up!
How could you show your face?
You're nothing but a--
Aladdin, lago rescued us,
He didn't have to, but he did,
Rescued? Him?
Please note--
"Did not have to, but did,"
Now we should be fleeing
for our lives,,,
if you don't mind!
No! We have to stop Jafar!
But how? He's so powerful!
GENIE: His lamp.
You destroy Jafar's lamp,
you destroy Jafar,
Then that's What We'll do!
Reality check,
Jafar is large and in charge,
Ah, yes, There's no telling
what Jafar will do to Agrabah,
We have a responsibility!
Maybe you do, but I don't!
I'm only responsible
for me, myself, and nobody!
I understand lago,
You've done enough,
And thanks!
Hey, I did my good deed!
I don't owe you a thing!
You hear me!
Not a thing,
[Laughter echoing]
Now that my revenge
is complete,,,
there is one little matter
left to resolve,
Yes! The wish!
Indeed,
You will now wish me free
of this wretched lamp!
ABlS MAL: No! My wish!
You got what you wanted!
Now it's my turn!
But you don't need to waste
your third wish,
You want the sunken treasure
of Coeur du Mer?
It's yours!
[Jingling]
[Giggles] Wah ha ha ha!
Ha ha! Yes, yes, yes!
Yes! I love it!
I love it! Whoo!
Silver!
Lots and lots of it!
Oh, I'm so excited!
So this means
I could have more stuff?
Oooh! I always wanted
one of those!
Nice! More! More!
[Rattling]
Ooh!
Oh, dear!
[Clink]
Now, if it's
obscenely excessive enough,,,
perhaps you'd care
to grant my freedom,
Huh? What? Oh, yeah, right,
Wish you were free,
Sure thing, yeah,
[Screech]
I wish for Jafar to be...
Wait,,,how do I know
that these things,,,
won't disappear
once I set you free?
The more pressing question is,,,
how will you stay alive
if you don't?!
But--but you said
genies can't kill!
You said that!
You'd be surprised
what you can live through,
What?!
Huh? Hey!
I'll take that!
My lamp! Gimme!
The street rat?
Still alive? No!
Yaah!
[Cracking]
Aah!
[Screeching]
Ooh!
-Aah!
-Help!
Thanks, Genie!
Where's the lamp?
[Muttering] Aah!
[Rumbling]
Raah! Ha ha ha ha!
Aladdin!
Not so fast!
Oh!
ALADDIN: Give it up, Jafar!
We're obviously too much
for you to handle!
You!
You're a fool to challenge me!
I am all-powerful!
Some all-powerful,
You can't even get rid of
a lowly street rat,
A problem
I mean to rectify right now!
JASMINE: Aladdin!
Unh! Aah!
-What?
-Gotcha!
GENIE: Go, Al!
-Yaah!
-Aah!
JASMlNE: Genie!
Faster, Carpet!
[Crackles]
Unh!
[Snap]
Carpet, no!
[Grunting]
Aladdin!
Unh!
-Whoa! Whoa!
-Ha ha ha!
ALADDlN: Aah!
-Genie, wake up!
-Wake up!
Aah!
Unh!
Ha ha ha!
Give it up, boy!
Unh! Aah! Ohh!
You shall
never have my lamp...
and there is no one
to save you this time.
Hey, Jafar! Shut up!
Iago?
Traitor!
Aah!
Awk! [Clank]
No!
[Groans]
Ha ha ha! Good help
is so hard to find these days,
Isn't it, Aladdin?
Ha ha ha!
[Gasps]
Unh!
JAFAR: My lamp!
Aah!
Iago!
Unh!
Rrraaahhh!
[Sizzles]
[Screaming]
[Stretches]
[Abu chatters]
[Rumbling]
Aah!
[Screaming]
[Crash]
[Crackling]
Unh!
Oh, boy!
Iago,,,
No!
But I thought a genie
couldn't kill anyone,
[Coughs]
You'd be surprised
what you can live through,
[Coughs]
All right!
-Oh, boy!
-Oh, lago!
Ha ha ha! He's alive!
[Dramatic music playing]
IAGO: And so the bird
lived happily ever after...
wallowing in luxury
as Aladdin's palace pal,
Now, my dear boy,,,
or should I say,
my new vizier?
Oh, say it!
Sultan,
I'm very honored, but--
But?! What but?
"But" is such a strong word!
Why, I oughta--
I can't be your vizier,
What?! Sultan,
the boy's talking crazy talk!
Don't listen!
What more do you want?
The World,
Look, personally,
I'm with you, kid,,,
but let's take it
one step at a time,
I mean,,,
I Want to see the World,
I can't just stay in the palace,
There's too much to do,
too much to see,
Hey, what about your girlfriend?
Do you think
that this lovely princess,,,
is just going
to wait around here? Aah!
I most certainly will not!
There, you see?
I'm going
to see the world, too,
OK, that's it!
The madness is spreading!
Arrgh! Crazy talk!
Why do I keep getting hooked up
with these warped people?
Shouldn't somebody ask what
the brave parrot wants to do?
[Music playing]
Does this mean
I don't get my third wish?