Long, long ago,
in a faraway land
a young woodcarver took
secretly to the forest.
His name was Geppetto,
and he was shy and quiet.
Oh, and very much in love.
l carve this heart
for dear Leona...
while in this
peaceful meadow.
With dreams and hope...
my love endures.
Forever yours, Geppetto.
Sooner or later, though,
when the heart is full...
and the heavens are listening,
magic... is bound to happen.
Legendas : Jdacd's
For many years after,
Geppetto kept to his chores,
and the forest
kept Geppetto's secret.
But the forest knew one thing
that Geppetto did not:
that miracles
don't grow on trees.
Miracles are made
in the heart
A log underneath the wheel.
Oh, l got to take you home.
A very good one, too.
All right.
Here we go.
@ My wife's the blushing,
blooming rose of dawning
@ Without the sting
Morning, Luigi
Put a sock in it, Luigi!
@ Welcome, welcome
@ Blessed morning sun
@ New day just begun
@ Buon giorno, life
@ Buon giorno, sun
@ Buon giorno, wife
@ My Little one
@ That's my little song
@ Good day,
buon giorno, everyone
@ Housework, homework
@ Off to work we go
@ Buying, selling
@ Making money so that we can eat
@ And we can drink
@ and we can have a little fun
@ l've sung my little song
@ And now my little song is done
@ Buon giorno, Life,
buon giorno, sun
@ Buon giorno, wife,
my little one
@ That's my little song
@ Good day,
buon giorno, everyone
Watch this
Oops, looks like you've
dropped your wood,
Signor Puppetmaker.
Maybe l should be
morecareful next time
Let's go boys.
Hey, last one to the bridge
gets dunked.
Yoo hoo, everybody.
l'm home.
All right, don't say hello.
Hello, little one.
How was your day?
Ah, that's nice. Me...
l got lost in the forest.
Used to be a time
when west was west.
Are you two fighting again?
What's the problem this time?
He said l have a funny nose.
l said you have a funny toes.
Funny nose.
Funny toes.
Now stop it. l'm tired of
hearing you two argue.
Stop it!
You know what happens
to bad little boys who fight?
They go to bed
without being sandpapered.
lt's chilly.
There.
lt's going to be a chilly night.
This log has a will of it's own.
Let's see if we can find
a face to match.
Our heart.
Anyone who wants a new brother,
say so now.
All right, all right,
don't everybody talk at once.
l'm going to make
the most perfect nose.
A world of wisdom
could be told in a nose.
Open wide.
Give me a big smile.
Nina, go find yourself a mouse.
Blue eyes, just like your papa.
Bellissimo.
Now would you like your papa
to show you how to walk?
Yes?
Very nice.
What a smart little boy you are.
Excuse me, coming through!
Now say hello
to your brothers and sisters.
Say hello.
They'll keep you company
while l'm at work.
Now what shall we call you,
dear child, hmm?
You're made of pine.
That's a start.
You have beautiful eyes.
Occhi magnifico.
We'll call you...
Pinocchio!
Pinocchio.
Better to have puppets...
than noisy little boys
running around.
Oh, my back is...
l'm not as young
as l used to be.
Nina, leave that puppet alone!
Behave yourself!
Excuse me,
coming through.
Ah, get the soap.
Thank you.
Now get me the scrub brush.
Scwub-bwsh.
lt's happened.
l've finally lost my mind.
Mind...
lt's impossible!
You can't be real!
Real.
But you're a puppet!
Pup-peh...
Pa-pa!
No, l'm not your papa!
Wait, Pinocchio.
Stop!
Come down right now!
What are you doing?
Come down this instant,
young... man.
Come down here!
l'm not going to go
chasing after you.
Luigi, please, put a sock in it!
Pinocchio, hold on, l'll save you!
No!
Take off my underwear right now!
Pinocchio, listen to me.
Pinocchio?
Right. Listen to me.
Papa.
No, l--No, that's not--
Well, yes,
in a manner of speaking.
No, l'm not your papa.
Papa, papa, papa...
You are a puppet.
You're not a real boy.
Real boy.
No! And be glad for it.
lf you were a real boy,
you'd have to have doctor
istead of--
Sit still!
Look at this mess! l'll have
to wash all over again.
Ciao, Geppetto.
Quite a new puppet.
He's amazing.
He still needs work.
So do you. Look at you,
you were up all night again.
- l slept a little.
- You were up all night.
l made these
for Lorenzini's puppets,
but l think he needs them more.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Wouldn't want
his head to fry, either.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Bet your house
is full of sawdust.
l'll come by and sweep it up.
Leona, l'm not a child.
The Little one,
does he have a name?
Pinocchio.
Enchanted.
Leona
Leona...
You even gave him your heart.
Our heart
What did you say?
Nothing.
Come, Pinocchio.
Come, Papa.
Seems a little stiff, Leona.
Just like his father.
Marco, look!
Look here.
Wow! Look at that.
Wow!
Stop it!
What are you doing?
lt's your color.
- Did l ask for a scarf?
- No.
Then get rid of it.
l'll take that one.
He's magnificent, Geppetto!
Do you see what l see?
Yes!
What?
He is more than--
he's just--
he's...
Well, l--well...
How did you do this?
l don't know.
Where are the strings? l--
You don't know.
l don't know.
Tino, am l going crazy?
l have no idea
how this happened.
They're going to
burn me at the stake!
No, no,
they've stopped burning people.
They might hang you, though.
Excuse me, coming through.
Then you'll know where
the strings are.
Are you real boy?
Yes. Are you?
Yes
Hello
Oh, my, what an intriguing
little item you are.
May l?
Empty as a witch's dowry.
Oh, and look how smoothly
his arms move.
Volpe, Felinet...
Excuse me, but haven't you two
got a pushcart to rob?
We've already done that.
Come, Pinocchio.
Oh, but, Geppetto, darling,
we were just playing with him.
He'll play with
his own sort, thank you.
And what sort would that be?
Pinocchio, don't
wander away like that.
l don't want you to do that.
l don't get it.
ls he a boy or a puppet?
He's a puppet, furface,
and he's worth a fortune.
And l know exactly
where to cash him in.
Don't worry, son,
l'll get your ball back.
Take my kid's ball, would you?
Listen closely.
Next week's puppet show...
must be the most
spectacular ever.
Every single boy
must be in attendance.
Lorenzini, darling.
Felinet, looking for employment?
l see my timing is purr-fect!
What l've seen
will assure you...
more curtain calls
than Rome has rats.
Do tell.
There, there. That's better.
That's didn't hurt, did it?
No. Didn't hurt.
What does he want?
Open up.
No good can come of this.
Be very quiet.
Stay here and be quiet
Don't even breathe.
Do you understand?
Open up!
Signor Lorenzini, uh...
Geppetto, my friend.
To want do l owe this honor?
The honor is mine
to call a gain on the man...
with the magical hands.
l bring good news, Geppetto.
l am mounting my grandest
production ever,
and l want to purchase
your newest creation...
whatever that might be.
l've been spending a great deal
of time in the forest lately.
l will carve you something very
special the first chance l get.
l was looking
for something with,
shall we say, thinner strings.
Thinner strings?
Why-- why didn't
you say so? Come.
l've gotjust the thing.
These wonderful pieces
are made of cherry wood,
and they are on sale
this week only.
Don't toy with me.
l didn't buy those puppets
from you two years ago,
and l'm not going to
buy them today,
so show me your best...
and show me now.
Excuse me. Coming through.
lncredibile.
He is perfect.
Stay.
- Boys do little bugs.
- Bugs
Don't they?
They like to tease them...
and twist them and--
Please, Lorenzini.
Name your price.
He's not for sale.
- Geppetto, everything is for sale.
- Stay, Stay!
Not him.
Not at any price.
Stay, bug.
You can have the emperor
and his daughter, and that's it.
You are making a big mistake,
Geppetto.
That's my last offer.
Take it or leave it.
Very well.
l will take these lovely puppets
off your hands.
l'm just burning with ideas.
Thank you.
Good afternoon, Geppetto.
Pinocchio.
Pinocchio
lnfantino is a creep.
Hey, fatty!
You're late, dimwit.
Pinocchio, show
yourself right now...
because l'm noot leaving this
house to look for you again.
Would someone please
like to tell us...
of a characteristic
which separates humans...
from the rest of
the animal kingdom?
Cages.
Humans cry tears, professore.
Ah, tears.
Expressions of the soul.
Do any other creatures look
so deeply within themselves?
No, professore. Only humans.
We must always decide
what is right and wrong.
Excellent.
Hey, Woody.
You ever get termites?
What are termites?
They're bugs.
l like bugs.
Not these kind, you don't.
They eat wood like you.
Hey, lay off my friend, Woody.
Lay off my friend, Woody.
What is going on
in my classroom?
The new kid punched Lampwick,
professore.
ls that true?
No
Hey, how'd you do that?
Silence.
Now, you're not lying to me
by any slim chance, are you?
There are two kinds of lies--
lies that have short legs
and lies that have a long nose,
and yours are clearly the kind
that have long nose.
Now, l will give you one
last chance to redeem yourself.
lf you didn't punch Lampwick,
how did he end up on the floor?
Nobody punched Lampwick.
Lampwick punched himself.
l--l mean, a man climed
in the window and punched him.
And Lampwick tried
to kick him back,
but he missed and fell
on the floor, and--
Silence.
lnfantino!
Silence!
lnfantino, go on, go on.
Handkerchief. Go on, quickly.
Run, run, run, run, run!
Right, l did punch Lampwick,
professore,
and l'm sorry
Well, it's too late
for that now.
lf there's one thing
l will not tolerate...
in my classroom, it's a liar.
Out.
And...
l'm sorry that
l kicked him, too.
Out.
And l'm even more sorry
that l told a lie.
Out, out, l said.
But l want to stay and learn.
Now, class, we will review
what we have learned today.
lf anything happened to him,
he's going to be
in big trouble.
lf l don't find him, l'm never
talking to him again.
Pinocchio!
lt's finished.
lsn't it beautiful?
Everything you bake
is beautiful, dear.
You know, l sold it to
the magistrate by the pound,
and the best part is,
l cheated on the weight.
You're very good at that, dear.
lt reminds me of the cake
that we had on our wedding day.
Don't eat that.
- l'm not eating anything.
- Not you!
Look!
Mmm, more?
l'll give you more.
You're a bad boy, huh?
Real bad boy.
Little mischief maker.
Your father's going to
pay for this!
Got him.
Even better.
Pinocchio.
Papa, want some?
Geppetto, he's yours?
Arrest him.
Arrest both of them.
You're under arrest, signore.
Wait.
Papa.
Come on. you, too, little one.
Hey, stop him!
There goes our commission.
Au contraire.
l have a feeling ourjob
just got easier.
Come on, now.
lt's past your bedtime.
lnto bed.
Good night, son.
l love you, Papa.
l can't do anything right.
The human dilemma.
Who said that?
Or is it the puppet dilemma?
You've still got cake
on your face.
What?
Say, do you always
squish someone...
before being
formally introduced?
Are--are you a termite?
Oh, please!
So you're not going to eat me.
Thanks for the offer,
but li'm on a low-wood diet.
Let me introduce myself.
The name is...
Pugnacio Elecuzio P. Elegante.
Give me a ''P,'' an ''E,''
a ''P,'' an ''E.''
Put'em all together
and call me...
Pepe.
- Pepe?
- You don't like it?
- lt's OK.
- l'm very sensitive, you know.
No. lt's--it's fine.
We can't all
be called Pinocchio.
Now listen to me.
l'm here because you are
one tumult little puppet.
Your papa's in jail,
you're all alone,
you trounced me
in the alley,
and l'm here to see that we get
our friendship back on track...
right this very second!
Sorry.
Didn't meant to holler,
but insects are people,
too, you know?
And l'm a lot more than your
standard garden-variety cricket.
l'm a teller of truths.
l'll be your best friend,
pine cone.
l'll open your eyes.
l'm not a pine cone.
l'm a boy.
Not yet, but it's
a top-notch goal...
for such a cute little puppet,
which is why it's time
to get to work.
You ca become a real boy
one you get the tools.
l'll advise you
and be your regal guardian,
but you've got to do
the hard work.
You, my little sapling,
will have to shed something blood,
sweat, and tree bark.
Total eclipse.
Visitors. How wonderful.
Get the door, and be polite,
and smile, now.
Show those pearly whites.
No, stop.
- Let me go.
- Come on. We've got you now.
Court is now in session.
Case number 491, your honor.
The People versus Luca Antonio
Renaldo Geppetto Baldini.
My papa.
lt will be all right, Pinocchio.
There he is, your honor,
the little mutilator.
He ruined my cannolis.
He ruined my fruit tarts.
Silence, woman.
He even ruined my grandmother's
torta della nonna...
with the pinoli
and the chocolate--
Are you done?
No, l am not done. l would--
Arrest her!
Now l'm done.
Now...
Since you, Geppetto,
are responsible
for this, uh, puppet,
how do you plead?
Guilty, sir.
You will pay 20,000 lira
to the bakers...
and 10,000 to the court.
l--l don't have it.
That--that's
three years' wages.
lf you cannot pay, then you
will go to debtors prison.
Three years locked away.
Your honor.
l propose the court
allow me to pay the fines...
for this poor,
impoverished peasant.
This is most generous
of you, Signore Lorenzini.
Kindness is my weakness.
Of course, no good deed
should go without obligation,
so all l ask is to keep
Pinocchio in return.
Lorenzini, please,
take any other puppet.
l will work for you day
and night the rest of my life.
Geppetto, is itjust
money for you?
Pinocchio needs a home.
All you can offer him...
is table scarps
and cold winter nights,
but with me,
he will have a family.
What's a family, Papa?
My goodness,
such a heartbreaking question,
one no one should
ever have to ask.
Pinocchio, l can
give you a life...
other little boys
only dream of.
What is your decision, Geppetto?
Listen to me.
You're going to go
with that man now.
But l want to be with you.
l know,
but you see--you see,
there--there's no other choice.
You're my papa.
l can't be your papa.
You're made of wood.
You're not flesh.
You're not a real boy.
Now go, for everyone's good!
Let's go.
Son.
Good boy.
l love you, Papa.
l'm sorry.
Why does everything good
get thrown to the beasts?
@ No to tyranny
@ He shall not have his pleasure
@ for goodness shall prevail
l see gold out there--
little pieces of gold.
Yeah, Woody!
@ All the world is waiting
@ A maiden l must save
@ No time for hesitating
@ lf only l were brave
@ For now is the hour
@ l must be the hero
@ lt's my call, that's my cue
@ lt's everything or nothing
@ Look out, he's coming through
Sorry.
Excuse me. Pardon me.
Coming through.
l'll save you--
Sorry.
Puny peasants!
l'll save you, princess.
@ Oh, the giant
@ Please stand up
in defiance
@ The princess shall be mine!
Hey, you up there
with the beard.
@ l was made of freedom
@ Nobody pulls my strings
@ And l can equal any man
@ ln all the grown-up things
@ And l will do or die
@ For l know one thing after all
@ The bigger any giant comes
@ The harder he may fall
@ My hero
@ He saved me
@ My hero, my hero, my hero,
my hero, my hero
l love being a star.
Of course you do.
All real boys love being stars.
Now this is all yours,
Pinocchio.
You can buy anything you want,
and after tonight,
there will be more.
Here.
Now hurry, son.
Get ready for the next scene.
Champagne.
OK, kiddo, now we're
in the swing of things.
Lesson number one--
beware of temptation.
Applause may be good
for the moment,
but love is everlasting.
l do have love.
Lorenzini loves me.
That's not love.
He's fooling you.
He's got evil plans
in the works,
and he's using you
to make them come true.
Why do you have to
make everything so hard?
No pain, no gain.
They love us.
To success.
Wait till they see
what l've got for them next.
Pinocchio, you're on.
@ What are we made of?
@ Can we know what we will be?
@ Whar are the chances
@ l can find the better path
@ The better life
@ The better me?
@ What are we made of?
@ lf you think you know the answer
@ Turn arround
@ Think again
@ Carabonza!
@ The fire-breathing monster
@ Alas, we are undone
Stand by for fireworks.
Here's your proof, Pinocchio.
This is how much
Lorenzini loves you.
You can save the others,
if you want.
This is your chance, Pinocchio.
You can do what's right.
Those puppets are
your brothers and sisters.
Stop it.
Brilliant acting, Pinocchio.
Geppetto made them.
l won't let them burn.
Good work!
- No.
- Yes.
ls it hot in here,
or is it me? Ciao!
Come here, you little--
There.
Get him.
Signor Lorenzini,
l'm sorry things
didn't quite work out.
l don't know. l think things
turned out rather well.
l guess you'll pay us
our commission now, huh?
Pay you?
l will kill you if you don't
bring me that puppet.
l thought you were burned.
Where's my Pinocchio?
There he is! On the bridge!
Grab him!
@ What are we made of?
@ Just for this moment
@ Take your life
into your hands
@ You'll decide
what you are made of
@ What it is that l can be
@ Turn arround
@ Think again
Pinocchio?
Oh, Leona
l've been all over town.
So have l.
l hope you had more luck.
l asked Carmella
if she'd seen Pinocchio.
She said no.
But then l went to see Tino.
He said no.
But then l went to see
Maria, the witch--
the one who hasn't
spoken in years.
- What did she say?
- Nothing.
But... she gave me this.
A stick?
What's it mean?
Think about it.
Pinocchio probably feels like
he can't come home,
like he'd only be
in trouble if he does.
Yes...
Where would you go
if you felt that way?
l... don't know.
Someplace safe.
And where would that be,
given the fact that
you're made out of wood?
The forest.
Thank you, Maria.
What are you waiting for?
Let's go.
Smell that pine.
You know, they ought
to bottle that scent...
so you can spray it
arround your house.
Have l told you what an honor
it is to be your cricket?
You were brilliant last night.
You stayed cool
when things got hot.
You did the right thing,
and you deserve to be proud.
This is where l belong.
You know, l prefer
the beach myself,
but property there
is so expensive.
You've gone back to your roots.
l know you feel lost, Pinocchio.
Believe me, it's only natural,
but you can't stay here.
Go away, please.
l fell happy here.
You can't sleep
your problems away.
You've got to get back
to your papa.
Bye.
We've got to roll.
Let's make tracks. Let's go!
Follow me! Off we go!
Run. Run. Run.
Pepe?
Where are you when l need you?
Quit it!
Peck on someone your own size.
''Let's get into
the puppet business,'' you said.
- l never--
- Shut up!
- ''We'll be rich,'' you said.
- l didn't...
Shut up. ''He's worth
a fortune,'' you said.
Why do l always listen to you?
Get off!
Go away.
Who do you suppose
that might be?
Are you serious?
Go away.
Pinocchio!
Out of my way.
Let's put Lorenzini off
forjust a few more minutes.
Hey, l know you.
You're friends with Lorenzini.
We're finished with him now.
- We're repugnant.
- Repentant.
Yeah, that, too.
And we're here to
ask for forgiveness.
What's forgiveness?
Forgiveness means that when
you did something really wrong,
you want somebody to tell you...
that it wasn't
really, really wrong,
when you know what you did
was wrong because you did it!
Please forgive me
for being a puppet,
instead of a real boy
for my papa.
l miss my daddy, too.
You know,
it is possible...
for you to become a real boy.
How?
All you need is a miracle.
What's a miracle?
A miracle is--
Miracles make your dreams
come true,
and you could buy one...
with enough of these.
Look... l have four more.
Very good.
Will you people be quiet!
Unfortunately,
you're just a little short.
But you might have enough if...
lf what?
lf you planted them
and let them grow.
Where?
Why, in the field of miracles,
of course.
The field of miracles.
Faster.
Found the perfect spot.
Stop. That's deep enough.
Now cover the hole
and let it cook.
For one hour.
Exactly.
Just keep going this way.
Leona, please, don't tell me
about the forest.
l've been coming out here with
my brother, Enzio--
may he rest in peace--
since l was a little boy.
Stop.
He was here.
Maybe he's not far off.
Now you stand here
and watch that clock.
The big hand will go
all the way around...
and come back to the top,
and that's an hour.
Got it?
Got it.
@ Our souls are like
a cup of cappuccino
@ Strong and dark
Out of the woods, huh?
What are you doing now?
Watching the clock.
Why?
So l can buy a miracle.
Any particular brand?
Real Boy brand.
Here's how it works--
You dig a hole, you plant
your gold, you let it cook--
The first lesson about trust
is learning whom to trust.
Didn't this gold deal
seem a little shaky?
l don't know.
A little.
And let me guess...
you ignored your instincts.
- Didn't you?
- Maybe.
You just don't give maybe to the
president of the Cricket Union.
Now, let's say we regroup
and talk about your papa.
Or l'll be falling down
on the job.
Look, my papa wants me
to be a real boy.
l'm staying right here
and waiting for my miracle.
Your papa want you,
no matter what you're made of.
Be a loving son,
and the real boy stuff
will take care of itself.
So remember,
you heard it here first.
Miracles don't grow on trees.
Miracles are made in the heart.
Stupid me!
Miracles don't grow on trees.
Hey, Woody!
Stop!
Come on. Come with us.
We're going to
the greatest place.
lt's great. There's no school.
No rules.
You can do whatever you want.
And it's just for boys.
Just for boys?
Yep. Real boys.
Look. Look. There he is.
Where? l don't see him.
l'm sure.
l'm going to be a real boy!
Hey, Woody,
watch out for your hat.
Welcome to the Terra Magica!
New boys.
[ Skipped item nr. 770 ]
Wait a minute.
l thought there were--
l forgot the biggest rule
of them all!
There are no rules.
That's more like it!
[ Skipped item nr. 775 ]
[ Skipped item nr. 776 ]
He's out there.
Not necessarily.
What do you think this is?
lt's his hat,
the one l gave to him.
l'm going to go find him.
Now wait one minute.
You're going to kill youself
for one of your puppets?
He's my son.
l've already let one great love
slip through my fingers.
l don't want it to happen again.
You've never been in a boat
in your life.
You can't even swim.
l can row.
But, Geppetto...
you may never come back.
ln that case,
l'll tell you why...
you should never
have married my brother.
Why?
Because you should have
married me!
The day l carved that heart
in the tree,
you accepted
my brother's proposal.
25 years you take to tell me,
and l'm supposed to wait?
You're too late.
l'm not waiting!
This is foul.
Foul?
Come on, Woody,
you're missing all the fun!
Hey, your turn, Woody!
Rather cruel of you to shoot
my cousins into outer space.
All l'm doing
is having a little fun.
Fun? Your idea of fun...
puts my antenna
way out of whack,
and what about your papa,
since you brought him up?
l didn't bring him up.
Precisely my point!
You know he wouldn't want you
acting like ajackass,
and if you act like one,
you'll become one!
This is how you light it,
Woody.
Taht's it.
l can't go on a trip.
l forgot to go to the bathroom!
Act like ajackass,
if you have the nerve.
Drink up the water.
Get what you deserve.
Be wicked, be naughty.
Come drink from my fountain,
then l will be rich--
king of the mountain.
Let mr try.
Nice shooting.
Look. No, look...
l'll show you how.
No!
Sorry.
That's my gun.
No, it's mine, Lampshade.
Nobody calls me Lampshade.
You give me the gun.
Nice shot.
Hey...
l can see right through him.
What's all this?
He sarted it.
You liar.
Stop! Let's settle this.
Tokens for
the ride of your life.
You have all earned it.
For you...
and you.
Hey, swiss cheese,
we're going on the big one.
Me, too.
Sell these jackasses
to the circus...
and at the market--
20,000 lira each--
then skin one...
for a new pair of boots.
We're going on
the big one, Woody.
The big one.
Here we go.
Aw, yeah.
Coming through!
l'm a real boy.
Come on! Whoa! Faster!
All right!
Hey, Woody, you're leaking!
l guess some guys
just can't hold their water.
Faster!
What's wrong with you?
l don't know.
l don't feel so good.
You don't
look so good, either.
Where'd you get that?
Here's another batch, signor.
Corral them.
l don't want to be ajackass.
Don't panic, Pinocchio.
Keep your wits.
Please, Pepe,
get me out of here.
You can do it. Be brave.
Don't let fear tie you up.
Yikes!
One of them didn't
drink their water, signor!
- Catch him!
- He's gone.
Don't let him get away!
Go and find him!
There...behind the donkey.
Calm these donkeys!
Of course, signore.
Go. Go. Go.
Come on. Go.
Run!
Get him!
l will break you
into firewood...
puppet!
Come here. Over here.
No, this is all wrong.
You got to believe me.
Look, they're
trying to trick you.
They wants us
to behave badly.
Don't go on the ride. Please!
We've been acting
like jackasses,
so that's what we turn into.
Well, well, well...
Here l provide you with the most
wonderful place to frolic,
and this is the thanks l get?
You steal my donkeys?
They're not your donkeys.
This one's Lampwick.
Pinocchio, a good boy does not
go around spreading lies.
lt's not a lie.
My nose grows when l lie.
Come on, boys. Take the ride.
Drink the water.
No, don't!
Be yourselves!
Lampwick...
Go on.
He's turning into a monster.
Look at his face.
Lorenzini's turned
into a monster.
Lorenzini was a monster.
He was a monster
and got what he deserved.
Jackasses!
l'm going home.
Thanks, Pinocchio.
Home home home home!
l don't care if l never
become a real boy anymore.
l just want
to get home to my papa.
There you are.
l knew you didn't go out to sea.
Where have you been?
We were so worried,
and look at you.
Have you eaten?
You're so skinny.
Where is my papa?
He's out there somewhere,
looking for you.
Wait, Pinocchio!
lt's too dangerous.
lf you think
l'm going to wait...
for both of you--
You don't even know how to swim.
l'm not scared.
l smell seaweed.
Are--are we at the beach?
Pepe, l thought you left me.
Ahoy, captain.
Where are we now?
Boy, you sure get
into a let of trouble.
You know,
it smells an awful lot...
like rotten
chili peppers in here.
Lorenzini, he must be
the sea monster.
OK. Fine. Enjoy yourself.
l'm playing
cricket this afternoon.
Hey, l'm a clamophobic.
Quiet.
We're in this together, now.
But--but--but l'm
afraid of the dark.
Papa!
Oh, sure, like he's
just around the corner.
He might be.
Oh, you two had plans
to meet here for dinner?
- Quiet.
- Sorry.
Excuse me.
Coming through.
lf only it were true.
Where were you?
Let's try to find
a way out of here.
Come.
lt smells like
rotten chili peppers in here.
The throat.
hold on.
Pinocchio, hold on.
Go, Pinocchio.
Not without you.
Go, l said.
No. Push it open.
l can't get through there.
Now, do as l say!
l hate you, Papa.
What?
l never, ever missed you.
That's a lie.
l wish l never found you.
l never wanted to be your son.
l want to stay a puppet.
Lies, all lies.
Don'tjudge my cooking
by this, OK?
Are you OK, Papa?
Wake up.
Forgive me, Pinocchio...
for doubting my heart
and letting you go.
l'm sorry, too, Papa.
l'm sorry for not...
for not being a rea boy.
But you're real to me,
my son.
Real to me.
Oh, l love you.
l love you, too, Papa.
l'm a boy.
Tell me it's true.
Miracles are made
in the heart, Papa.
Yoo-hoo, hello.
l'm in the dark in here.
What am l missing?
Have the pilgrims landed?
l don't even want
to know what happened.
Keep it to youself.
Nice to know you, junior.
Lots of luck.
You look good in the flesh,
a real doll--uh, boy,
but l got to go. Ciao.
You're leaving again?
l'm just starting
to have a good time.
Leaving?
That would make me
a hypo-cricket.
Union rules--
l'm with you forever.
l just got to get some sleep.
Papa! Pap, stop the cart.
- What?
- Please stop the cart.
There's just
one more little thing...
l need to take care of.
lt'll only take a minute.
l'm not going
to sleep in no barn.
Fine, then sleep
in the doghouse.
Hello.
Don't you answer back
when a person greets you?
Hello.
Haven't l seen you
somewhere before?
No. Believe me,
l just got here.
That sure isn't very much gold
you've got there.
Excuse me, sonny. We're rich.
That's not rich.
This is rich.
That's nothing but a rock.
Yes, but if you take this road
five miles, there's a valley.
l've been there.
Drinking the water
turns bad boys into donkeys.
Get out of here.
Fine, then l won't
tell you about the gold.
Gold?
Keep this to yourselves.
lf you drink the water
while holding onto a rock...
Yeah?
lt turns into gold.
Gold?
Would l lie?
Bye.
See you later, Papa.
Pinocchio,
where are you going?
To play with Lampwick.
Did you do your studies
and all of your chores?
Yes, Papa.
Sometimes l wish
that nose still grew.
Lampwick.
Come on, Woody, let's go.
Careful!
We're--we're very sorry, sir.
Yeah. Let us pick these up.
- Donn't you just hate that kid?
- Not as much as l hate you.
Papa, Papa,
l've got a great idea.
How about carving me
a girlfriend?
You've been a boy two minutes,
already you're
thinking about girls?
Am l going
to have trouble with you!
And there you have it.
Geppetto and Leona
lived happily ever after.
Luigi ate a lot of socks,
and all the donkeys
turned back into boys.
lt took some hard work.
They had to do many good deeds
to earn the privilege.
As for me,
l took a house on Lake Como...
and played canasta
with a couple of locusts.
So, ciao, my little saplings.
Arrivederci!
And when you need me,
give me a holler.
We'll see if we can
arrange something.