NARRATOR: Previously on Fear the
Walking Dead...
TRAVIS: What'd you see?
NICK: Everyone was dead.
MADISON: He was high.
TRAVIS: We're gonna get him in
rehab.
TOBIAS: They don't know if it's
a virus or a microbe.
TOBIAS: ..they don't know, but
it's spreading. People are killing...
LIZA: Talk to your father.
TRAVIS: We're all building a
family, Okay? All of us.
MATT: Ya like it?
ALICIA: We get each other.
PRINCIPAL COSTA: Lot of kids out sick
today. Thought you were another victim.
(tires screeching, body thuds)
MADISON: What the hell is
happening?
(static crackling)
(distorted chatter
over walkie)
All clear here.
(distant siren wailing)
(birds chirping)
"Beacon" playing on headphones
♪ Hoping the legacy stands ♪
♪ But all he could do
is write his initials ♪
♪ With a stick
in the sand... ♪
(low rumbling)
(music continues
in headphones)
(helicopter blades whirring)
♪ Make letters in my head,
twisting up the poinsettia ♪
♪ I'm getting high
off the nature of the rhyme ♪
♪ I'm a nation in my mind,
I'm a major in my prime... ♪
(music stops)
Matt?
(raspy breathing)
Oh, my God.
(theme music playing)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
- (tires screech)
- (horn honks)
- Whoa!
- (honking continues)
- Travis! (sighs)
- I'm sorry! Sorry.
Chris, it's an emergency, man.
Call me right back.
- Recording: It's Alicia. Leave a message.
- (beeps)
Baby, call me back.
Call me back right away.
- Try the house.
- Yeah.
Man on radio:
There's been a massive spike
in the officer-related shootings
in the last 48 hours.
Travis:
Nick, stop, please.
- (tunes radio)
- Man #2: And people act like this doesn't
change everything.
It does.
This is a catastrophe
of biblical proportions.
We are losing the best
pocket passer in the league!
(tunes radio)
- Nick!
- (radio turns off)
No one's talking about this.
No one's saying anything.
Travis: We need to get
away from the city.
We need to get away from people.
Just grab Alicia, Liza, Chris,
and just go until we know
what this thing is.
- The desert?
- Yeah.
It'll be okay there.
We'll be safe.
(phone rings)
Alicia, where the hell are you?
- Mom. - Listen, we got Nick.
We're coming to get you.
I need you to pack some things for
us, load up some groceries, okay?
- No, I can't.
- We're going out of town.
- What? No. I can't.
- Why? What's wrong?
He's sick.
He's really sick.
- Who? Who's sick?
- Matt.
His fever's, like, 103.
- What's wrong?
- I tried to get him in the bath,
but it hurts when I touch him.
Don't-- don't touch him.
- I need you to call 9-1-1.
- I tried. It-- it's busy.
His parents are in Vegas.
They're not picking up.
Okay, we're coming to get you,
but just stay away from Matt
until we get there, okay?
(static crackling)
- (Matt coughing)
- Mom?
Alicia. Alicia!
We're 10 minutes away.
(car engine revving)
- (music playing on headphones)
- (chatter)
- Really?
- (boy snickers)
(boys laugh)
(ringing)
(music resumes)
(coughs)
Alicia, move away from him.
What's wrong with you?
People are getting sick.
It could be contagious.
If he has it, I have it.
Alicia, can I talk
to him? Please?
Hey, Matt.
Where are your folks?
They should be home soon.
They're driving home today.
When did this start?
He was supposed to meet me
at the beach yesterday and...
never showed up.
(coughing)
Here we go.
Alicia, would--
would you?
Come on, come on.
(groans)
What are you doing?
Is that a bite?
Matt:
Yeah.
- Is that how it happens?
- Travis: I don't know.
I mean, Calvin was shot.
It wasn't-- wasn't like--
it wasn't like this.
Get Alicia.
What are you talking about?
I'm gonna call 9-1-1
from the car.
- Okay, I'll wait for them here.
- No, go outside.
- Mom. What the hell are you doing?
- Don't do this.
- Are you psychotic? He's sick.
- Alicia.
It's okay.
You want some water?
Listen to me.
My parents will be home soon.
You know I'll be fine.
You know that.
No, I'm not leaving you.
I love you.
I love you, too.
That's why you gotta go.
Okay?
You gotta go.
Go.
Thank you.
(coughing)
(sirens wailing)
- (music playing on headphones)
- Man: Come on, let's move it!
(horns honking)
(siren wailing)
(honking)
Man:
What's going on?
Cops shot some homeless dude.
Shot him, like, 20 times!
(chatter)
(helicopter blades whirring)
(dog barking)
Alicia.
- Hey, Travis.
- You're having a party?
Yeah.
You should come by.
Gladys is nine. You believe that?
It's so scary.
- That's great.
- Got a ton of food.
We're getting a bunch of cancels
'cause of that bug going around.
So we'll see you.
Okay.
Okay, thanks.
Peter's got the right idea.
(coughs)
(door opens, closes)
Mom, are you gonna
tell her? Mrs. Cruz?
- Tell her what?
- What's happening.
Nick, we don't know
what's happening.
Well, we know more
than she does.
Okay, I'll talk to her.
I'll tell her.
It's just like no one
is paying attention.
It's-- it's like
it's not real.
It is.
It's real.
Hey.
(distant siren wailing)
(helicopter blades whirring)
You saved us.
You had no other choice.
(breathes heavily)
(sighs)
I'm about to step into...
a world of shit.
You know that, right?
Yeah.
Travis: Damn it.
No one's answering.
No Liza, no Chris.
He's pushing my calls.
Did you try Liza at her house?
Of course I tried the house, Maddy.
Of course I did.
Okay, go.
Travis, go get them now.
- (Madison mutters)
- (touch-tones beeping)
Mrs. Cruz:
There goes another one.
- Where is everybody?
- I don't know.
Mrs. Cruz: Well,
should I get the cake?
Call me if you're
gonna be longer.
If I'm longer, go without me.
- I'll catch up.
- No.
(engine starts)
- (tinkling)
- (children playing)
- A little busy, Trav.
- (alarm chirps)
I'm on my way over.
What? No.
We agreed he was staying
with me this weekend.
Is Chris home from school?
- Did Nick go AWOL again?
- Look, I'll explain there.
Something's happened.
I'll explain when I get there, okay?
No, no, no.
You can't keep moving the goal-post.
Liza, Jesus.
Just--
Our settlement agreement
was very clear.
- Is Chris home?
- It's clear, Travis. It is defined.
- You're not listening to me.
- You get him three weekends a month.
You can't just pick and choose.
Can you just please call him?
- (horns honking)
- Call him, tell him to get his ass home.
Liza:
He'll be home any minute.
(honks horn)
Travis:
Now, Liza!
I'll see you next weekend.
(helicopter blades whirring)
Man: T.J., let's go, go.
Check it out.
Woman:
Yeah, another homeless.
(EMT radio chatter)
(people chattering)
Madison: Alicia. Alicia.
We need the bucket.
Alicia?
Alicia, get the bucket.
Dr. Han.
Hi, it's Maddy Clark again.
Listen, uh, Nick is
really hurting right now,
and I just need you to call in the
prescription so I can pick it up,
but I'm really worried about him, and
I think he really, really needs it.
- Hang in there, big brother.
- (breathing heavily)
We're gonna get
your medicine, okay?
Alicia: Longer we leave
him, the worse he gets.
- I know. I'm aware.
- He won't be able to travel.
- Alicia.
- I gotta get under the blanket.
Mom, what are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Dr. Han's not calling me back,
and now I can't
even reach Travis.
Yeah, I mean, it's like
after an earthquake.
Circuits are overloaded.
- Got anything stashed?
- No.
Vicodin for my wisdom teeth.
I flushed 'em.
It's dangerous for him
to go cold turkey like this.
- I know. I know.
- Mom, I--
- It's okay.
- The doctor's. You can pick 'em up.
Mom.
I don't even know--
I think they're closed.
They're not calling me back.
By the time I--
(distant sirens wailing)
Watch him.
- Prom-- do not leave the house.
- I wo-- I won't.
- Alicia, promise me.
- I'll look after him.
(horns honking)
(horn honks)
(bell dings)
God damn it.
Woman:
Yo, Officer.
- (honks horn)
- What's going on out there?
Was there an accident?
It'll clear up
past Sherman Oaks.
I don't even know
why I asked you.
(distant siren wailing)
(alarm beeps, stops)
(banging echoes)
(clang echoes)
(distant clang)
(creaks)
Oh, my God!
- Hello, Miss C.
- Tobias.
Can I have my knife back?
(exhales)
- (police radio chatter)
- (car horns honking)
- (siren wailing)
- (chatter)
Man:
You know this ain't right.
Yo, this is wrong, man.
Wrong, wrong, wrong.
Back away, sir. Get on
with your business.
- This is his business. This is all our business.
- Officer: Stay back.
That man never hurt a fly.
That man was unarmed.
- LAPD's out of control.
- (crowd agrees)
Officer: We're gonna need
to clear this area now.
Man: Yo, we ain't
clearing nothing.
Officer:
This is a crime scene.
Man #2: Yeah, and we're
all behind the tape.
Officer: I will not
tell you people again.
Man #2: Good, 'cause we
people aren't moving.
Hey, kid, put the camera down.
No, no, no, homie.
Keep that camera up.
I'm gonna give jackboot over
here a little civics lesson.
You wanna go to jail, son?
Jail? For what?
Freedom of speech?
Right to lawful assembly?
He ain't breaking any laws.
Man, he ain't
threatening nobody.
Oh, call your
little buddy, yeah.
(drawer slides open)
(drawer slides shut)
Be careful.
Thank you.
Here.
Oh, can't do hot now.
I'll make gazpacho next time.
Yeah. It's gonna end
up in the bucket.
Okay, drink some water.
I'm not thirsty.
Water is not what I need.
Yeah, I know
what you need, Nick.
Mom's working on it.
(child crying outside)
(moans, retches)
It's her party, and she'll
cry if she wants to.
(Nick retching)
(groaning, retching)
Whoa, whoa.
Where are you going?
- Hey. Alicia.
- I'll be fast.
No, no, no, no. Hey, you
can't go back there.
Hey! You promised Mom.
Alicia, come--
You make promises
all the time, Nick.
- Lie down!
- I'm an asshole. I'm an asshole.
Okay, but listen. Alicia, if you
leave, you won't come back.
Please.
You let Mom go.
Not safe. No, Matt!
Matt is not safe.
- Oh, Jesus... - No, Alicia, you don't get
what it makes people do.
- You don't know what I had to do, Alicia!
- What did you have to do?!
Matt will hurt you! He will
kill you, Alicia. I'm--
- (thuds)
- (objects clatter)
(door opens)
No, no, no, not now!
Not now!
Don't do this to me, Nick.
Don't you do this,
you stupid son of a bitch!
(grunting)
Stay still.
Shh.
Why do I bother speaking?
Seriously,
why do I waste my breath?
- Is he here?
- You think I'm lying to you?
We gotta find him.
It's not safe.
This virus that's going around,
the shootings the past few
days, it's connected.
What are you talking about?
Didn't you see what happened
on the freeway last night?
I studied till 2:00,
passed out.
Well, people are getting sick.
They get sick,
and they get violent.
- And the cops shoot them.
- I've seen it.
You know what I've seen?
Nothing.
- It's getting worse.
- Well, I don't know what to tell you.
- What are you looking for?
- (touch-tones beeping)
Hey, just give me a second.
(all chanting)
Hell, no! We won't go!
Hell, no!
We won't go!
(phone rings)
- Mom! Mom!
- Travis: Where the hell are you?
Dad, why do you
have Mom's phone?
I'm with your mother. We're coming
to get you. Tell us where you are.
There's a protest.
I'm at a protest.
- A protest?
- Where is he?
- Where? - The cops, they shot
some homeless man, Dad.
This poor guy,
he wasn't doing anything.
Okay, let us come and get you.
The people were taking action.
This is important, Dad!
Yeah, I get it.
I get it. Okay, but--
Dad, I'm part of it, okay?
I gotta go.
I gotta go, Dad.
Chris--
(chanting continues)
I know where he is.
Cafeteria food's designed
to survive a nuclear strike.
Expires in, like, the year 3000.
What did you come back for?
Uh, Nick, my son,
is not feeling well.
Well, that's smart.
LAPD lockup,
they have pharmaceuticals.
Nick was here
when I was a freshman.
He seemed nice.
Yeah, he's a good kid.
Yeah.
Uh, the looters
hit pharmacies first,
then gun shops, liquor stores.
The less you go out, the
less chance you get exposed.
(Tobias grunts)
Hey, Miss C, have you
seen any of 'em yet?
I mean, I've only
seen 'em online.
No.
Let's hurry this up.
Mother lode.
Wow, you're stocking
up for a while.
It's gonna be a while.
So your mom's back, then?
My uncle's been around.
You should stock up,
too, Miss C.
No, we have food.
(scrubbing)
I'm sorry.
She should have been
back by now.
Yeah, I know.
Someone should have called...
by now.
Thank you.
(sighs)
Mr. and Mrs. Cruz:
♪ Happy birthday to you... ♪
- I hate you.
- ♪ Happy birthday to you... ♪
I know.
♪ Happy birthday, dear Gladys ♪
- ♪ Happy birthday to you. ♪
- (sirens wailing)
(cans rattling)
Tobias: The desert will be safer
because things
will fall apart now.
No satellites, no Internet,
no cell phones.
Communications will fail 'cause no
one's there to manage the servers.
The electrical grid will
collapse for the same reason.
It's all gonna go to hell.
And that's what they don't get.
When civilization ends,
it ends fast.
They're gonna contain it.
The same "they"
that's supposed to warn us?
- Come on.
- (distant rustling)
(groaning)
No, wait-- Miss C.
(groaning on speakers)
(groaning continues)
It's one of them.
(static crackling)
(groaning continues)
(distant alarm beeping)
Let's go. Let's go.
Go, go, go, go.
- Let's go.
- (beeping continues)
Let's go. Go.
Oh, God.
Leave it.
Tobias, leave it.
Oh, God.
Okay, get the door.
Okay.
Oh, God.
Artie?
Artie.
- (raspy breathing)
- Oh, we-- we gotta go. We gotta go.
(door rattling)
Artie, can you hear me?
He can't hear you.
You know he can't.
We'll get you help, Artie.
Artie, stop.
We're gonna get you help, okay?
We'll get you--
Tobias:
No, no.
- No, stop!
- Tobias: No, no!
Madison:
No, Tobias!
- No, no, no, no! Ah!
- No! Tobias!
Oh, no, no, no!
(screaming)
(grunting)
Help me!
Oh, no.
No, no!
(grunting)
- (grunting)
- (squelching)
(panting)
(engine starts)
(crowd shouting)
(Travis, echoing) Chris!
- Chris!
(distorted voices)
Chris!
Liza:
Christopher James Manawa!
Christopher James Manawa.
- We gotta go, man.
- Dad, he was unarmed, but they shot him.
No, they shot him
like a dozen times.
- Tell us on the way.
- No, I'm doing what you taught me.
This is what you taught me.
Dad, we stand up for people.
Travis: I know, I know, but
there's a time and a place--
Chris: Right now. This
is happening right now.
(conversation continues
indistinctly)
(sirens wailing, horn honking)
Travis:
Liza!
Enough.
(continues indistinctly)
- Okay, we gotta go.
- This is important.
Come on, man.
You're important, okay?
Christopher,
listen to your father.
(police radio chatter)
Christopher, now!
What is wrong with you?
What is wrong with you guys?
- Are you kidding me?
- No, wait, wait. Stop.
- Come on. Come on.
- This way.
- Where are we going?
- (canister fires)
(rasping)
Stop. Right now.
On the ground! On the ground!
Stop!
- (gunshots)
- (crowd screams)
- (woman screaming)
- Man: Get out! Get out!
(helicopter blades whirring)
- (woman screams)
- Man: Go! Go, man! Let's go!
- Where are we going?
- This way.
- (people shouting)
- (sirens wailing)
- Okay?
- (woman speaks Spanish)
- Thing of beauty.
- Looks good, looks good.
Man:
Kick this wall down!
Man #2: Man, what's
going on out here?
Take the side.
Go to your right.
(people shouting)
Chris:
Jeez!
Excuse me, sir.
Can we come in, please?
We're closed.
Please, it's not safe out here.
I mean, it's dangerous.
Go to the police.
No, I think they're the danger.
I mean, they're not
letting anyone leave.
We just need somewhere
to ride it out.
Please. Please?
(speaks Spanish)
Please.
Okay, come in.
Thank you.
- (shouting continues)
- (horn honking)
(crowd shouting, cheering)
Do you have a back door?
Access to the alley?
- There is no other door.
- Travis, please.
Woman:
Hey, hey.
- (man speaks Spanish)
- Liza: Travis, this is their home.
- (woman speaks Spanish)
- Do you have access to the roof?
Travis, can you please
not go in there?
We can see what's coming there.
You will be fine in there.
I think it'll be safer if we
stay away from the front door.
No, I think you will
be safer in there.
Papa, I thought
you were locking up.
(speaks Spanish)
- Are you okay?
- We're fine.
- Who are you?
- I'm-- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm Travis.
This is my family.
We just need somewhere to ride
it out, and then we'll go.
- (siren wailing)
- (distant shouting)
(distant banging)
It's okay, Papa. Please,
have a seat in there.
Thank you, thank you.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Just take a seat.
Thank you.
(both speaking Spanish)
Woman on radio:
LA County health officials
recommend Angelinos stay inside.
If you don't
need to travel, don't.
If you must leave your house,
take precautions.
Local neighborhood watch
programs are being established
in many neighborhoods
throughout the city...
(radio turns off)
You can stay with us, Tobias,
until this is over.
This doesn't end.
There's room.
It's safe.
You gotta take care of your son.
I'll be okay.
You?
Yeah.
(car approaching)
- (praying in Spanish)
- (distant shouting)
(car alarm blaring)
Thank you.
Thank my wife.
(distant tires screech)
This is insane.
- Chris, get away from the window.
- (horn honks)
- Can't make anything out.
- You don't wanna see anything out there.
Okay? Just, come on, step away.
Sit down.
Read something.
(siren wailing)
What do you know?
What have you seen?
(distant shattering)
- I've seen what people do.
- (engine roars)
What they don't do.
- It doesn't make sense.
- (glass shatters)
They don't die, Liza.
They...
(glass shatters)
- ...come back.
- (fire crackling)
Gotta get far away
from what's outside.
(car alarm blaring)
All of us.
- (man shouting)
- (officer on P.A., indistinct)
(tires squealing,
engine revving)
(sirens wailing, horn honking)
- Alicia: What took you so long?
- Shut the door.
How's your brother?
Never better.
He went grand mal on me.
I'm sorry.
- Travis call?
- No.
(pills rattling)
We ration those.
Oxy? Oxy's good.
How much?
It's enough to get us
to the desert.
And then what?
Hey.
(snaps fingers)
She tried to leave.
Yeah.
I stopped her.
(tapping)
Alicia:
Hey, Matt, it's me again.
Can you give me a call?
I wanna know how you're doing.
(crying)
No. No, God.
(cell phone ringing)
- Travis?
- Maddy. Maddy?
- Travis? Hi.
- You can hear me?
Yeah, baby, where are you?
Are you okay?
Yeah, no, we're good. I found Chris.
He's safe.
Where are you?
You okay?
Yeah, we're okay.
Can you come home?
We're stuck.
The freeway's jammed,
and highway patrol's
figuring it out.
I, um...
Well, where are you?
You're at Liza's?
No, no.
We're waiting in a shop.
I-- how's Nick?
Is he okay?
Did you find him the meds?
Uh, yeah.
Uh...
I got him enough,
you know, to wean him off.
I mean, to take him to the
desert and just wean him off.
- (explosion)
- Oh, shit.
Madison: Wait, Travis,
what was that?
- Tell me what that was.
- No, it's okay. It's okay.
Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
Look, Maddy, I want you to go.
Go to the desert, now.
Don't wait.
No, I'm gonna wait for you.
I'm gonna wait for you.
Okay, I don't know
how long we're gonna be.
Just go ahead. We'll catch up.
We'll find you, okay?
No, Travis,
just-- no--
- (gunshots)
- Whoa! Travis?
- Maddy?
- (screaming, shattering)
Officer over P.A.
By order of the LAPD,
you must clear the streets now.
(crickets chirping)
(beeps)
(sighs)
(sighs, sniffles)
What the hell happened?
Mom?
Mom, are you okay?
Mom.
"Wait For Me" playing
(static hissing)
(woman vocalizing)
♪ I'm gonna ask you
to look away... ♪
- (crowd shouting)
- ♪ Mm-mm ♪
♪ I love my hands,
but it hurts to pray... ♪
- (touch-tones beeping)
- ♪ The life I have isn't what I've seen ♪
♪ The sky's not blue
and the field's not green... ♪
(sighs)
Dead again?
Phone lines
keep going off and on.
Power cuts out.
Tell me.
What's going on?
(distant woman screams)
Oh, God.
- (screaming continues)
- Oh, my God.
(man grunting)
(Mrs. Cruz screaming)
Don't look.
Mom, Mr. Dawson's
hurting them.
(screaming) Get off!
No. Alicia!
- (screaming escalates)
- No.
What are you doing?
Mom. Mom!
(woman praying in Spanish)
(prayer continues)
(distant siren wailing)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com