¶ ¶
- Come on, babe.
Look at the camera.
- What?
- Camera. Come on,
make love to the camera.
- Ah! Stop it.
- Camera. Come on,
make love to the camera.
- Oh, come on, stop it.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing. Turn around.
Turn around.
- Okay, what? What do you want?
What should I say?
- Uh, send a message.
Something to our children.
- Our children? Really?
- Well, the ones
we're gonna have, you know?
- Wow.
- We fall in love, we move in,
we get married, we have kids.
Those kids go
through our things
and find the old shoebox
filled with tapes years later.
Forever. Just say your name,
say your age. Turn around.
Say your name, say your age,
blow a kiss to the camera.
- Hi, I'm Eve.
I just turned 21.
- Uh-huh. Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
¶ You can ride on
till you get old ¶
¶ It'll hunt you down
and nail you to the road ¶
¶ Falling on
you might fall apart ¶
¶ It'll hunt you in your dreams
and in the dark ¶
[humming]
¶ Sundown on a life before ¶
¶ Union men came riding
to the door ¶
¶ Left a man with fire
all around ¶
¶ His wife and son
left buried in the ground ¶
¶ You can ride on
till you get old ¶
¶ It'll hunt you down
and nail you to the road ¶
¶ And the season's
here and gone ¶
¶ But not the winter
of your broken heart ¶
¶ And the seas
will roil and turn ¶
¶ Just like your soul.. ¶
¶ Just like your soul ¶
¶ Watched it burn ¶
- Oh!
¶ You watched it burn ¶¶
Ah!
[humming]
[whistling]
[continues whistling]
- Sorry, I couldn't get here
before. Too much work.
[man sighs]
You -- you didn't die
on me, did ya?
Poor sick little puppy.
Come on now, I bought
the vegetables you wanted.
I cooked the soup
like you like it.
It's all for you.
There's no reason to share
anymore. It's -- it's for you.
Just eat something, okay?
I'm -- I'm coming back later
to see if, you know..
You know,
I know you're starving..
[grunting]
[grunts]
[man coughs]
[dramatic music]
[panting]
[coughs]
Come here.
[girl grunts]
Eve, Eve, listen to me. Wait.
[door creaks]
[panting]
- No!
Come on.
Please!
No!
Fuck!
[screams]
Please, somebody, help!
[dramatic music]
- This is gonna happen.
- Come on, please.
I don't wanna --
- No, no, no, come on.
Come on.
...happen, I promise.
You trust me? You trust me?
Not that you.. What's gonna..
Come on. Come on!
- Ladies first.
- I can't.
- Don't make me do this.
- You're just a little nervous?
- What are you doing?
- Stand here. Stand here.
- Oh, my God.
Why am I doing this?
- No reason to fear here.
There is no fear here.
I got ya.
[music on radio]
[music stops]
[grunts]
[panting]
- Keys.
[sobs]
Ronnie.
Do you love me?
- No.
- Do you love me?
Yes. Yes, I love you.
- How much do you love me?
- Alright, no, no, no,
I'm not answering that.
[dramatic music]
[music continues]
- I can go all night, bitch.
[screams]
[sobs]
[dramatic music]
[water splashing]
- Now what?
Coming back to apologize?
- What happened
to these girls?
- Girls.
You did have fun upstairs.
What'd you find?
- How many girls
did you take here?
- Hmm. Here?
What makes you think
I would bring them here?
- Tell me where they are.
- Why would I do that?
- Because if you don't,
I'll kill you.
- I think you're forgetting..
...I'm the only one who knows
where they are.
So...if you kill me..
...then you're killing
all the rest of them.
You didn't think about that.
- Oh, God.
- So what now?
You gonna let them all die?
Just like you did before.
Remember over there
in the corner?
Go ahead.
End it right here.
All you want
is your own little piece
of revenge, isn't it?
Go ahead, kill me.
Kill them.
Bang.
Fuck!
- Tell me where they are.
Last chance.
- You're losing it.
- Talk.
Yeah, I talk and you shoot me
in the head.
- Shut up!
- And one more thing.
I promise you..
...you'll never find them
without me.
Oh.
What are you gonna do now?
- Reload.
- So what's the plan?
- You are gonna take me
to the other girls.
- You think I'm just gonna
let you drive me around town
like a dog on a leash?
And then we just
set the girls free
one by one?
Is that your plan?
- Hand me the keys to the van.
Right now!
- Yeah. Hey, where you going?
You know, you don't want
this on you.
I mean, 4 dead girls? God!
Because you ran away?
Because you left them?
[instrumental music]
- Put it on.
Put this around your neck.
- Oh.
- I'll put it on. You take me
to the hospital, I'll put it on.
Where'd you learn how to do
the brick thing?
- Put this around your neck.
- Yeah, I'd love to.
I'd love to do that.
- Fuck off! Put it on!
- Wanna make a deal?
- Put it on.
- You take me to the hospital,
I'll show you the girls.
I'll take you to the girls,
you take me to the hospital.
- Deal. Put it on.
- Deal. Okay.
No!
[gagging]
Wait a minute.
- Open the lock.
Unlock it right now.
No more talking.
Get the fuck up now!
You fuck with me,
it'll be the last thing
you ever do. You hear me
- Come on.
- Go!
- I'm going.
- To the driver's seat.
Now!
- I can't even breathe.
- Get the keys.
Go.
- Getting there.
Innate there.
- Let's go.
- Where to?
- What?
- I mean, we can either go
to the girl that's the closest
or we can go to the one
that hasn't eaten in a week.
- In a week?
- Yeah.
I never could get top dollar
from any of those girls
like I did for you.
You are one special girl.
- Just take me to the closest!
[engine revving]
[dramatic music]
- Wow, you look like you know
how to handle a weapon.
I like tough women.
- You better.
- Yeah.
- Oh!
Come on. Please?
Calm down.
Everything's gonna be fine.
You trust me, right?
- Yeah.
Oh, my God!
[dramatic music]
How much further is it?
- They're all pretty close
together.
No sense driving
all over town, right?
[music continues]
- Stop right here.
Turn it off.
- It's off. It is off.
- Come here, fucker.
Get over here!
- Alright. Loosen it up.
[grunts]
- Who's in there?
- Who's in the house?
- What?
- Nobody's in there. I mean..
Ah, well, the girl is,
of course.
- She's the black one.
- Where's the light?
[man coughing]
- Alright, ease up.
I can't remember her name.
What's her name?
- Nina. Her name is Nina.
- Nina. Yeah. Yeah.
- Go, move.
- You know she is..
- Move, fucker. Don't even
think about trying anything.
- I'm not trying anything.
- Open the door.
- Oh, God!
There are..
- Let me get the keys, okay?
- Shut the fuck up.
Open the door.
- The right keys.
[grunting]
- Let's go.
[panting]
Jesus Christ!
- Yeah, she's a bad host.
[man grunting]
You're gonna remember
our deal though, right?
[man grunting]
- Open the door.
- Alright.
[man grunting]
[both grunting]
This is too tight.
[girl sobbing]
- I'm not..
I'm not hearing anything.
I'm not seeing anything.
- No, no.
- No, don't!
- Calm down. Calm down.
- No, no.
- You're getting her--
- Just stop, stop, stop.
It's okay. It's okay.
- Look, look, look.
- She's done!
- You can't help her.
- Shut up!
- No. No. No.
- Please. It's okay. I'm here
to help you. Please, look.
- She's broken! Don't do it.
- It's okay, it's okay.
- Don't do it.
- No, no. Nina! Nina! No, Nina!
Nina! Nina!
Nina! No.
No, Nina!
No. No!
No, stop!
Nina, stop!
- Wait.
Did she escape?
Where is she?
[intense music]
[sobbing]
[groaning]
- Oh, my God.
[sobbing]
[intense music]
Oh, shit!
[rattling]
[groaning]
- Hey, Eve. See this..
It's not all hero shit here,
is it, sweet cheeks?
Yeah. You thought
she was gonna help you?
[coughs]
Huh?
- Get up!
- Wait.
I'll get up.
[grunting]
- Get up, asshole.
[intense music]
- Oh, shit.
- Get in the van now. Let's go!
- Jesus! Fuck!
- So who you gonna save now?
- The closest.
- The closest. Okay.
That would be little Laura.
[instrumental music]
- How much further
till the next one?
- Couple of blocks.
So you gonna do the same thing
with this girl
that you do with Nina, huh?
Nice job, by the way.
- Shut up.
- The best thing that girl had
going for her
was that room back there.
And you fucking took it away.
[chuckles]
Ah.
You know, but don't worry
about it.
Nobody'll miss her.
It's always like that.
Nobody cares.
Unless you're white, rich.
Anyway..
...hope you got
a new plan 'cause..
...here we are.
Beautiful little Laura.
I gave her that name.
Pretty, isn't it?
Remember, they're not all
as sweet as you are.
- Get out.
- Going to the long route.
- Move.
Take the keys.
- Hey, look..
- Take the keys! Go.
- This thing's choking.
[coughing]
- Move.
Where is it?
- It's this way.
[intense music]
Right this way.
Over here.
Do you like what she's done
with the place?
[man panting]
You gonna kill
this one too?
- Move.
- Laura.
Laura.
[coughing]
Laura, here.
- Get that thing off of her!
- Won't do.
- Get that fuckin' thing
off of her!
- Alright.
I will.
Laura, listen to me.
Listen to my voice.
Uh, let me get this.
Huh?
I'm gonna get this off of you.
[man coughing]
Okay. Okay. There we go.
I got that off of you.
Listen to me
- Hurry up.
- We have...company.
I want you to meet Eve.
- Hurry up.
- This is Eve.
- Unchain her.
- Why are you here?
- Unchain her, right now.
- Okay.
- I'm here to help you, okay?
- What do you want?
- I wanna set you free.
- I've been warning you.
They are not all like you,
sweet cheeks. Alright.
- Get over here.
[grunting]
- Let's get this off.
- Who is this slut?
- Oh, you didn't have
to say that.
She's a nice girl.
Eve is a sweet, sweet girl.
And she has come here..
She is here..
...to take your place.
- Nobody takes my place!
- No, no, no! Stop!
[grunting and groaning]
- Get her! Get her!
Kill her! Kill her!
- No.
[grunting and groaning]
- Get her!
[Laura screams]
[intense music]
[gunshot]
[grunting]
- You shot me!
- You piece of shit.
- You shot me, sweet cheeks!
- Fuck you!
I hate you. Fuck you!
You piece of shit.
Die!
- Oh, I missed you.
- I missed you too.
- No, stop it.
Don't leave.
- I don't want to.
[intense music]
[girl screaming]
[girl sobbing]
- You have to fight me now.
- I don't want to..
[indistinct yelling]
- You gonna scream?
- No.
- This will hurt.
[grunting]
Don't worry.
You'll get used to it.
- What?
- The pain.
- Those girls aren't anything
like you.
You're different.
Just nicer.
You wanted this.
- You set me up.
- Kind of.
Okay.
Seems like your plan
is not working.
Just...take me
to the police station, huh?
All this will be over.
- At least I can finish this.
- Alright.
Okay.
You win.
I give up.
I never meant to hurt anybody.
I never wanted it to end up
like this.
You gotta believe me.
I'm not a great man, okay?
I have no life.
No money. Nothing.
- So that's why you destroy
other people's lives?
- You suffered.
I suffered, too.
I did.
I watched my mother..
...rot away
with cancer for 5 years.
It wasn't quick.
It was slow
and it was painful.
And I couldn't do anything
about it.
I was broke.
I couldn't ease her pain.
I couldn't help her.
I couldn't even give her
a proper funeral.
Listen to me.
I didn't take you.
I don't do that.
I take care of you.
I never touched you.
I'm not the hunter.
I'm only a..
...zookeeper.
It wasn't personal.
All I ever wanted
was a decent life.
A family.
Maybe a son.
Just like..
...Ronnie would have wanted.
- What the fuck
did you just say?
- Ronnie.
- You know what,
now it's your turn.
- No, no, no, no, no.
- Yeah, come on.
- My name's Ronnie.
I'm 25.
- What the fuck do you know
about Ronnie?
- I'm just saying
your boyfriend..
Nothing.
I just saw him on TV.
Listen, I'll give you
something big.
It's bigger than me.
It's bigger than these girls.
Ronnie knew about it.
- What the fuck
are you talking about?
- Ronnie, he went to look
for you when you disappeared.
All over town.
He never found you.
But he found some things.
Horrible things.
I can show you what he found.
After the next house,
after we get Lea.
No more tricks.
No more surprises.
- Oh! Oh! Oh!
- Wait! Hey, now.
Come on, come on, give it back.
- No..
- This is my home video.
- Oh, come on.
Do you love me?
- No.
- Do you love me?
- Come on.
[intense music]
[music continues]
[panting]
[girl screaming]
- Turn off the light.
- Turn it off.
- They kidnapped me.
- Calm down. It's okay.
- It's okay, calm down.
- Help me.
-  Calm down.
- Okay, it's okay.
Look, I'm here to help you.
I'm gonna get you the fuck
out of here. You gotta relax.
Okay, just relax.
- They're gonna come back.
- Who's coming back?
- They're gonna come back!
[breathing heavily]
- Okay, but
what's his van doing here?
- Even old Phil, he probably
wanted to ride a show.
- Come on, man.
He always takes the first ride.
- What the fuck was that?
- Did you hear that?
- What the fuck?
You.
- Give it to her.
Give it to her now.
I'm gonna give it to her.
- Give it to her.
- I wanna give it to her.
[laughter]
- I -- I can
go all night, bitch!
[screaming]
[gunshots]
[grunts]
[intense music]
[shell clinks]
- Motherfucker!
You fucking..
[breathes heavily]
[chain rattling]
- It's okay, it's okay.
[intense music]
- Fuck you!
You fucking piece of shit!
Fuck you!
[breathing heavily]
Like that?
- We gotta go.
- Fucking like that?
- You got any real clothes?
- Who are you?
- Here.
Change.
- Who the fuck are you?
- Look, we don't have
much time, okay?
Let's go.
- I don't give a shit
who you are, okay?
I just want to know
who to thank for saving my ass.
- Help.
Help me.
- Come on. Shoot him!
- Help.
- Shoot this motherfucker!
- It'll be more painful
if you just leave him.
[music continues]
- Hey! Why aren't we
calling the cops?
- I'm sure they were gonna
rape me in there.
What's wrong with you?
- Where are you going?
- Do you know
what they did to me in there?
- What the fuck
is your problem?
- Hey! Are you fucking
listening to me?
- Get in if you're getting in.
[engine sputtering]
- Christ.
Fuck!
[engine sputtering]
- Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck! No!
No!
[dramatic music]
- You killed them.
- You fucking bitch.
Every one of them.
- Wait, I feel like I'm gonna
be sick. Stop.
- Hey!
- What?
- Hi.
- Oh, I missed you.
- Are you okay?
[breathing heavily]
- Okay! Whoa!
Whoa.
- Are you alright?
- Yeah. Thanks to you, right?
- Is this you?
Do you know this girl? Katrina?
- How did you know where I was?
- What the fuck!
That's the guy who grabbed me.
What the fuck
is he doing here?
- Wake up!
Fuck.
- Are you listening to me?
- Hey!
- Why is this
piece of shit here?
We gotta fucking kill
this piece of shit.
- No!
- We made a deal.
- Told you, no tricks.
- Just shut up!
- I don't give a shit
about your deal.
- Stop.
You're as crazy as he is.
- You are crazy.
You would kill her to save me?
You know, she killed
those other two girls.
[screams]
- Don't you get it?
I found you!
And now we need to find her.
Are you in or are you out?
- Okay.
- I'm not going
anywhere with her.
She's not part of the deal.
How do I know
you won't just stand there
while she beats me?
- You know what?
That's a fucking good idea.
- Shut up.
Both of you. Can you drive?
Then, do it. Let's go.
- You gonna kill her too?
Another dead body.
- The only dead bodies
are in the house.
- What dead bodies?
- Shut up.
[engine revving]
[instrumental music]
- Now, tell me
what Ronnie found.
- Who the fuck is Ronnie?
- Tell me where he went.
Or lose it.
- Fuck you!
[groaning]
- Now, we're gonna try again.
If you tell me to fuck off
one more time, I swear to God
they'll be calling you lefty
for the rest of your life.
- Other ones are closer,
you fucking lunatic.
- What others?
- The ones Ronnie found.
- What are you talking about?
What'd he.. Who did he find?
When? Why is he there?
- 101 South.
- Why was Ronnie there?
- Take me...to the hospital.
We had a deal.
- Hey, do you want me
to turn around?
- Drive, just drive.
- If you don't take me there,
I'm not gonna make it.
- Fine. I'll keep you alive.
Even when you're begging me
to kill you.
- 101 South.
[music continues]
- What is this place?
- Somewhere you don't wanna be
for very long.
Door 4.
You can't miss it.
Ronnie even found it.
- Let's go.
- What about him?
- He's not going anywhere.
- This is a bad idea.
- Yeah, this whole night's
been a bad fucking idea.
[dramatic music]
- What if there are
more men in there?
- Then, I kill them.
- Oh.
- Come on. Come on.
Goddammit.
- Let me try.
[grunts]
- Okay.
[music continues]
[keys jingling]
[door slams]
[groans]
[beeps]
[thud]
[doorknob rattling]
- Be careful.
Stay behind me, okay?
I think it's here. Come on.
[grunting]
[intense music]
[dramatic music]
[breathing heavily]
[coughs]
- Who did this to you?
Who runs this place?
- Eve.
What if they're still here?
- What are you doing here?
- We wait for the big man.
He bring us here.
New girls come every few week.
- He bring them here, then..
Girls come and go as they buy.
Men come here,
they choose girl..
...prettier girls go first.
- Is there anyone else here?
- It's okay.
We're here to help.
- A man, a t -- tall man.
H -- he run off.
- What?
- Shit!
- We gotta go.
- What?
Wait here, okay?
We'll call the police.
What? Are we just
gonna leave them in here?
- There's someone else here.
We gotta go.
- We can't leave them here.
Where are you going?
- Look, we can't stop.
We have to go to the next house.
- Why? Why should
we keep going?
- Because there are more girls
I have to save.
I have to save them.
And I had to save you
because I had to try!
I gotta go.
- Are you really gonna
leave us here?
Eve, what happened to you?
I'm sorry.
Just...thank you. Okay?
For saving my life.
- Look, just stay here
and get some help, okay?
There's got to be a phone
around here somewhere.
Ju -- just wait
for the police to arrive.
Be careful.
- What about the douchebag
in the van?
- Yeah, I got a bone
to pick with that asshole.
[dramatic music]
[panting]
- Sweet cheeks.
Sweet cheeks.
- Stupid motherfucker,
don't move!
- Watch out.
This hero stuff is harder
than it seems, huh?
You already killed two women..
...you wrestled a giant and..
Guess what?
Wanna call the cops now?
[muffled screaming]
- Now, bring her to me.
[screams]
Bring her to me.
[instrumental music]
[Eve screams]
- Help!
No!
- You probably
should have killed me
when you had a chance,
sweet cheeks.
- I love it when they wiggle
around like that.
- Yeah, she's a lot of fun.
- Let's just shoot her
in the face right here.
- After what she did tonight?
Fuck her.
Let's take our time.
- You're the boss.
- Shoot her in the leg.
Right where she shot me.
- Yeah.
[screams]
[grunts]
[panting]
[music continues]
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Hey, now.
- I will be.
- Wait, we had a deal, right?
You're not gonna forget that.
- Yeah, we had a fucking deal.
- Katrina, the last girl,
she wasn't here. Where is she?
Last chance, tell me
where the next house is.
- Well, well, I..
[screaming]
Oh, God!
- Try to fuck with me again,
motherfucker.
[groaning]
[breathes heavily]
- 1404..
...Brown.
Fuck.
1404 Brown.
It's the last house.
I'm sure you're gonna love
the last house.
[grunts]
- Yeah, that wasn't so bad.
- Yeah, I know.
[laughs]
[gasps]
- You went to Spain?
- I did.
- That's what I wanna do.
I wanna travel.
I wanna travel,
I wanna see the whole world.
- It changes your perspective,
you know.
- Yeah.
Look how beautiful that is.
- Hurry up. The cops
will be here any minute.
- Make sure they find
the girls, okay?
- Eve, are you sure about this?
- The last girl,
she didn't make it.
Okay? I -- I can't --
- Eve, you saved me.
And you've saved those girls.
Do what you gotta do, okay?
[engine revving]
[beeping]
- You have one
new voice message.
- Phil, where are you?
Are you still at the office?
Anyways, don't forget
to get the cereal..
...for our little munchkin.
Oh, and your mother
called again.
I -- I think she's coming
for dinner tomorrow..
[beep]
- What makes a man like you?
- You know, we're not
as lucky as your Ronnie boy.
- Stop saying that name.
- Ronnie boy? Why?
Ronnie boy's a good guy.
I'm sure he misses
you so much.
- I'm gonna end this.
- You are, huh?
You're gonna end your little
fucked up revenge thing?
Good.
But the truth is,
you killed those girls.
I guess it was your fault.
You could have avoided
all that.
You should have shared
your food
a little more at least or..
That one in the corner, huh?
You can't blame me for that.
[exhales]
Definitely your fault.
- It's over.
- It's not over.
You have no idea
what you're dealing with.
Not even close.
Not until you see
the next house.
You...are really gonna love
[dramatic music]
[door creaks]
[music continues]
- Don't fucking move.
Ronnie?
What the fuck
is going on here?
- You're alive!
I was looking
everywhere for you.
Oh, God.
God, you're covered in blood.
Do you need an ambulance?
Are you okay? Are you bleeding?
I'll call the police.
- Don't fucking move!
- Okay, easy, baby.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Put the gun down.
You're safe here.
Okay?
- Why are you here?
- Eve.
This isn't your house.
- Why does he know you?
- What do you mean?
- He keeps saying
your name all the time.
Do you know him?
- Eve..
...I spent 6 months
looking for you.
I lost my job.
I spent everything I had.
I lost my home.
Eve, what happened to you?
Tell me what's going on.
- I..
I escaped.
- Baby, come here.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Put..
Just.. They're not gonna
hurt you anymore.
- I was kidnapped.
They...they
did things to me. They..
- Hey. Just come sit down.
Alright?
[breathes heavily]
[thud]
- What the fuck was that?
- Easy, easy.
- Easy.
Okay. Just..
[woman groans]
I'm sorry, I..
I met someone.
Honestly. I thought
that I'd never..
- Show me.
What the fuck is that?
What are these pictures?
- Alright.
Hold on. Let me explain..
- Then, fucking start talking!
- You were
gone for a long time.
I searched for you.
The police...they didn't help.
Okay, there were more girls
that disappeared, like you.
And I went
to look for them
to look for you.
[breathes heavily]
And I...Eve..
But I couldn't..
...I couldn't find you.
Look at me. Stop.
I already searched the photos.
There's nothing in there
that you won't find
that I already have
gone through.
Let's just get..
- Who is she?
[breathes heavily]
[grunts]
- I told you.
I met someone.
- Katrina.
Is this the girl you met?
That's how he knows you, right?
- Eve.
- Move.
- What...what can I do?
What can I do?
- Open the door.
- No, don't do this.
I'll do anything.
What can I do?
- Move.
Tell me what you want.
I'll do anything.
Wait..
- Open the door.
Open the fucking door.
[grunts]
[groans]
- Goddammit!
[door opens]
[groaning]
[breathes heavily]
- Turn the lights on.
[engine sputtering]
[breathing heavily]
- Eve..
[sighs]
- It wasn't personal.
Say your name
for the camera and your age.
- Why?
- Come on, please?
- You're just,
you're just so beautiful.
But could you smile
at least a little more?
There you go. Look like
you're having some fun.
- What..
[groans]
[Eve screams]
[gunshots]
[engine sputtering]
[grunts]
[birds chirping]
[engine sputtering]
[instrumental music]
[singing in foreign language]
[gunshot]
[gunshots]
[singing continues]
- Kids, never
point a gun at anybody else.
It's a bad thing.
Now, don't.. Oh, wait.
Come on. Come on, give it back.
[grunts]
- I guess I...have your
boyfriend to thank for that.
- Yeah, you knew
him pretty well, right?
- What were his last words?
- Tell me what you want.
I'll do anything.
- Yeah, I need something.
His last words
were an address.
I need an address.
- Okay. Okay. I'll
give you whatever you want.
- The final house.
- Oh, what's..
[panting]
- What the -- what the
hell are you doing?
- One more stop.
- No.
Don't do that.
I'll do anything you want.
Don't do it.
Please!
Don't take me there.
Don't take me there. Please!
Don't you understand?
You can't do this.
I won't tell them anything
if you..
...if you don't stop this.
And there's girls out there.
There's so many girls
out there just like you.
And they're scared.
And they're hurt..
...and they need your help.
This is bigger
than me and you.
And you can save them.
You can do this.
But you gotta stop.
You gotta stop
what you're doing.
I know what you're doing.
Goddammit!
I'll give you the names.
I'll -- I'll give you money.
All my contacts.
Please.
I'm begging you.
I'm begging you now.
Don't do this.
It wasn't personal.
[doorbell ringing]
- Oh, my God. Phil!
What happened, Phil?
No! Oh, my God. What happened?
[screams]
What happened, Phil?
Oh, my God! Phil!
Oh, my God. Are you alright?
Look at me.
[instrumental music]
[music continues]
- I bought
the vegetables you wanted.
I cooked
the soup like you like it.
And it's all for you.
There's no reason
to share anymore.
It's for you.
You don't have to worry
about your sister...anymore.
Not anymore.
- Yeah.
- So how was your trip?
- It was awesome.
Completely
changed my perspective.
Europe
will do that to you.
- Yeah. So what's
next, college or what?
- I don't know.
- There's so much stuff
I want to do.
For right now I'm just gonna
focus on having fun.
- Well, I'm happy
you're back.
- Aw, I'm so happy.
- Yeah.
- Aw, this is just
so cute.
Why don't you give her a kiss.
- Cool. Alright,
now make out.
- What?
That's so gross.
So gross. That's gross.
Stop it.
- Okay. Alright.
Alright. Okay.
Fine, I'll give it to you.
- This is my sister.
- Alright, so Dylan
you just look at the camera,
give me your name and age..
- My name's Dylan, I'm 19
and I finished high school.
Happy?
- Yes.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, not..
Come on.
- Okay, now it's your turn.
- Give that. Yeah,
that's -- that's not funny.
- Come on,
you love me, right?
- Yes, I love you. Is that --
is that a good answer?
- Yeah, I thought
it was pretty good.
- Your sister's approval?
- Come on, you know
what to do.
Come on..
Yeah!
It's slowing down.
- Okay, slow down.
- The worst is over.
¶ ¶