[Bird Screeches]
[Scanning Radio Transmissions]
The heat wave continues.
It's 109 degrees
in Los Angeles.
[Screaming And Gunfire]
As drought-ridden Los Angeles...
swelters in agonizing heat...
drug lords wage warfare
in the streets.
Yet another open conflict...
Fuck this.
Get me out of here!
Aah!
We're in a war zone.
Two motorcycle officers
horribly wounded...
in a deadly cross fire...
the police seemingly unable
to rescue them...
in spite of several
desperate, heroic attempts.
It's completely
out of control down here.
My beautiful cantina,
everything I own...
they shot it to pieces.
My microwave...
my tamale steamer, my grill...
you fucking pendejos!
[Automatic Gunfire]
Ah ha ha!
Fuck you!
Tony Pope,
live with Hard Core...
on the scene
and in your face.
It's like Dante's Hell
down here...
Smoke, fire,
oppressive heat...
As Colombian
and Jamaican drug fiends...
once again transform
the streets of L. A...
into a slaughterhouse.
Who the hell's in charge down here?
The cops? Uh-uh.
They're outmanned, outgunned...
and incompetent.
Mr. Mayor, on vacation
at your home in Tahoe...
get off your butt,
get down here...
and declare martial law.
Don't keep me in suspense,
Danny boy.
It has not been a nice day.
Two motorists
pulled over a truck...
stumbled in the middle
of a narc stakeout.
You know, 10 Colombians
and Scorpios...
Told them to fuck off.
They're trying to get
inside their headquarters.
We're keeping them
pinned down...
but those officers
are bleeding to death.
Fuck, they're dying, man.
And where the hell
is Special Weapons?
They're tied up
with that shootout in San Pedro...
getting their ass kicked
by the Jamaicans.
They shot down a chopper.
Mills and Johnson
won't last much longer.
We need an assault vehicle
to go get them.
I'm going to have a chat
with these assholes.
- When I give the signal, give me some cover.
- Got it.
Too small.
That's it.
Come on!
Get them
out of here! Now!
¡Vamanos!
Get them out!
Ahh!
Hey, assholes!
Mike, are you okay?
Yeah. Let's get
the rest of them.
We can't.
Orders from
Chief Heinemann.
He says secure perimeter,
surround building, and wait.
Wait for what?
I don't know...
some bullshit special unit...
the Feds, the DEA.
If we let them dig in...
we'll have to level
the building.
¡O, me gusta!
No, es para mi.
¡Vamanos!
¡Venga!
[Speaking Spanish]
Come and get it.
El Scorpio is ready.
[Glass Shatters]
Sarge, any of your people
in the building?
No.
Let's go.
Can't let you in there.
Heinemann's on his way.
Heinemann can
kiss my sweet ass.
Come on.
Goddamn it.
Go with him.
[Screaming]
3, 2, 1...
go!
[Whimpering]
Shh. Shh.
Back, back, back.
Back.
Shh.
Next door.
Take this room!
Officer down.
We need backup.
Freeze!
I said hold it!
Now lay your guns down.
You can walk down or fly.
It's your choice.
I said
put it down, asshole!
No!
Ohh.
El Scorpio's down!
Take it easy.
Damn, it's hot.
Must be losing it.
Mike!
Spread out.
Secure the roof.
Just take it easy.
I'm right here.
All clear here.
I'll clear the site.
Oh, Danny boy.
Got to get down
from here.
Shit.
Okay, search the roof.
Check every floor.
There may be
someone else.
Seal it off.
No one leaves.
Danny, get me off
this damn roof.
Well, you get
the rest of them?
Somebody beat us to it.
Leona.
Oh, shit.
What happened
to El Scorpio?
He's out front
having lunch.
What the hell is this?
I don't know.
They've been cut to pieces.
Must be the Jamaicans.
Yes, but where the hell
did they go?
Nobody gets in here
until forensics arrives.
Nobody.
Okay, you know the drill.
[Tapping]
Mike.
Up-Up there.
He must have been
killed out here...
then someone... phhtt.
That's about 35-40 feet.
No rope, no ladder.
The guy weighs about
190-195 pounds.
You couldn't
carry him up there.
Lieutenant...
Deputy Chief Heinemann's
downstairs.
He wants you
and your people...
out of the building now.
Ah, son of a bitch.
What the fuck is going on?
This is not good, Mike...
not good at all.
We want a real name
on this joker, okay?
You got it.
Mike.
Phil, this is quite a surprise.
What brings you down
from the palace?
You let me down, Mike.
You're making me look bad.
I thought
we had an understanding.
I put my ass on the line
to get you here...
and all I expect
is a little cooperation!
You were told this
was a federal matter.
You disobeyed a direct order...
to stay out of the building.
Don't let this get out.
It's a war down here.
You're a soldier,
and you take orders.
We're fighting
for our lives down here...
and you're downtown
pushing pencils and kissing ass!
I don't roll over for anybody...
especially the feds...
without a goddamn
good explanation!
Take this equipment up
to the third floor now.
Let's move!
Let's go.
Excuse me, sir. Sir!
What the hell's
going on here?
Insubordination.
Disregard for direct orders...
from a supervising officer.
Now get back to your cage
at Alvarado.
I'll show you
insubordination...
you son of a bitch!
No, no, no!
Where you running to?
You don't need this, Mike.
It's not worth it.
Relax.
Oh, fuck!
¤ [Spanish Rap]
[Tony Pope]
Here's an update.
In the midst of a shootout...
five members
of one Colombian drug gang...
were apparently ambushed
by their bloody rivals...
the Jamaican Voodoo Posse...
who escaped
without a trace again...
making total fools...
Back there.
Listen, lady,
you got a backed-up toilet...
call a plumber, not the cops.
This license is expired.
Bullshit.
I paid that fee
six months ago.
I'll kick your ass!
Sit down!
Right now!
Move!
Just calm the fuck down!
And all you got to do...
is tee it high and let it fly.
Ah-ooh!
Dead solid perfect.
Now, remember,
for distance...
you got to hold it
gently, but firmly.
Lieutenant Harrigan!
Detective Lambert,
Rampart Division.
Kid, just have a seat.
I'll be right with you.
Hey, Cap.
Don't start with me, Mike.
Heinemann's
so far up my ass...
I won't sit down
for a week.
We're not
winning this war.
You have to play
the game on this one.
"Effective immediately,
a federal task force...
"under the direction
of Special Agent Peter Keyes...
"will be investigating
criminal activities...
"involving the trafficking...
and distribution of
controlled substances. "
And you will extend him
your full cooperation.
You're cutting off my dick
and shoving it up my ass.
The feds are calling
the shots on this.
My hands are tied.
Yeah?
Captain Pilgrim.
Peter Keyes.
Well, it's good
to meet you.
Nice to meet you, sir.
Lieutenant Mike Harrigan...
Special Agent
Peter Keyes, DEA.
I've heard
a lot about you.
I'm sorry for this
jurisdictional intrusion.
Don't mean to be
stepping on your toes...
but we're attempting...
to prevent King Willie's
voodoo gangs...
from taking over
the entire West Coast.
I wish I could tell you more...
but we have a large number...
of deep-cover operatives
involved here.
You know how it is.
We all have a job to do.
I'm sure we can respect
each other's situation...
and act responsibly.
Well...
um, cooperation...
is my middle name.
I'll see you around.
Lieutenant,
I'm the new transfer.
Have a seat.
I'll be right with you.
Who is this dude?
Yeah, what an asshole.
All right, Danny,
what we got?
What do we got?
Five lowlife Scorpions
make it into the building.
The next minute...
they're all shish kebab...
not one bullet wound.
Wasn't the drugs or money.
There's a shitload
of that.
Maybe King Willie
brought in some outside talent.
He's making his big move.
A pro would have split
the moment he heard the action.
More than one
we would have seen.
Whoever did this
waited until the last minute...
and then took out four men armed
with machine guns by hand...
and then got by us.
Maybe we should
give him a job.
Me and my partner
bolt up the stairs...
somebody's screaming
bloody murder...
- you got to hear this. You got to hear this.
- What?
Hey, I forgot to tell you.
See that guy there?
That's Freddy's replacement.
This guy's Jerry Lambert...
the Lone Ranger
from Rampart station.
That's the Lone Ranger?
I thought he was here
to fix the air conditioner.
I said,
"Lady, you are under arrest. "
And she said, "Why?"
I said, "Your husband's dead.
You killed him. "
- Know what she said without missing a beat?
- No.
She said, "I stabbed
that son of a bitch plenty of times.
- He never died on me before. "
- [Laughs]
Uh-oh.
Looks like he's putting
the moves to Leona.
His first big mistake.
I have heard about you.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Like your last partner got shot.
What?
Well...
Oy!
Try that cowboy shit
with me, fucker...
and you can
kiss these good-bye.
- Got it?
- Yeah, yeah. I got it.
Well, well, I see
the three of you have met.
Lambert,
if you're feeling up to it...
why don't you
limp your way in...
and go see the lieutenant.
- He wants to talk to you.
- Yeah.
Aah!
You're a bad girl.
Ooh, I liked that.
No, no, no!
Goddamn, is that bitch
on the rag or what?
This is what
I call the speech, kid.
I only give it once,
so pay attention.
Until now, it's all
been fun and games...
cops and robbers,
Dunkin' Donuts...
but you're in the shit now.
Metro Command
is a war zone.
I've paid my dues.
I busted my ass
to get my transfer.
And that scares
the shit out of me.
Nobody
requests to come here...
unless they're looking
for a reputation.
There's no room
for showboats...
or anyone looking
to prove himself.
Now don't get me wrong.
We need good cops.
They say you're good...
but the team comes first.
You live by that,
and you'll be okay...
and we'll all be there for you.
The door swings both ways.
That's it.
Hey, kid.
Welcome to the war.
[Moaning]
Ohh!
Aah!
[Speaking Spanish]
No!
Okay, guys, this has
gone too far now, huh?
Hey-Hey, guys...
I- I know you're
trying to scare me, huh?
Well, you did
a pretty good job, man.
I'm scared now.
Stop it now.
I can pay you...
$2 million, man.
In cash...
right now.
This is not about money.
This is about power.
There's a new king
in the streets.
This is a message
he has for your people.
You are history.
Fucking history...
you goddamn puto.
What the fuck
are you doing now, man?
You're crazy.
King Willie says...
not only do I have to kill you...
but I have to take your soul.
Voodoo magic...
fucking voodoo magic, man.
But you know what?
I tell you what I believe.
Shit happens.
[Twittering]
[Screaming]
Shoot it!
Aah!
Fucker!
Shit-Shit happens.
Shit happens.
Aah!
We're standing outside
a penthouse complex...
involving as many
as 20 people.
It's uncertain
who they were...
but one report indicates...
it might be the feared
Jamaican Voodoo Posse.
I go in for my physical,
and the doctor says...
"I need a semen, stool,
and urine sample. "
I say,
"Gee, doc, I'm in a hurry.
Can I just
leave my underwear?"
Oh, God.
Achtung, mein Kapitän.
Word is there may be
50 more dead bodies up there.
Oh, man, it's Pope.
That parasite
must live in his car.
I'll handle it.
P.R.'s my specialty.
They want your ass
off the job.
- Tony, my man!
- Who are you?
Catch your show
all the time.
I got a job to do.
Root for garbage
somewhere else.
You get inside?
We were going
to go in there...
but we were told
on a radio transmission...
nobody goes in
under any circumstances.
[Police Radio] All units
responding San Pedro and 5th Avenue...
be advised federal officers
will handle investigation.
We didn't hear that.
Let's go.
You're the boss.
This is Cheryl Tyre
reporting live...
Hey, nice flashlight.
Mind if I borrow it?
Okay.
Look familiar?
Aah!
Oh.
Oh, God.
Ramon Vega,
the crack king...
biggest operator
in East L.A...
100 keys a week.
Why isn't he skinned...
and who
are these assholes?
They're Jamaicans,
King Willie's boys.
That doesn't make sense.
This was a voodoo ritual.
I've seen it before.
They took his heart out.
What for?
Terror tactics...
to scare the shit out
of their enemies.
King Willie.
Who the hell is King Willie?
King Willie, voodoo priest
of the L.A. Posses.
Ran the terror gangs...
for Edward Ciega in Jamaica...
until he got too powerful.
The Jamaican chiefs won't make
a move without his approval.
So what the fuck happened?
Shit!
Hey, we got a survivor!
What's she saying?
I don't know.
She's not making any sense.
"El diablo vino por ellos. "
The devil came for them.
If the Colombians did all this...
why did they leave their
boss Ramon hanging ten...
and his girlfriend naked
on the floor?
It wasn't the Colombians.
- Our friend from the armory.
- Right.
We got a new player in town.
Come over here, Mike.
Check this out.
What is that?
Looks like
a spear tip or something.
This is restricted area.
I want it cleared immediately.
You're walking
on physical evidence.
- We'll take care of her.
- Just back off.
Lieutenant, I'd like a word
with you in private, please.
They say that persistence...
- is one of your most... outstanding qualities.
- I know it's your show.
You're not listening! Your big
nose is too far in my business.
Maybe you can hear this.
Next time you cross me...
you're going to turn up missing.
The man with the camera,
get him right now.
Yes, sir.
All right.
Come on. Let's go.
Stay away.
Hey, fuck you, man!
Give me my camera!
Shut the fuck up.
Wait a minute!
I got my rights!
I'm a journalist...
Harrigan!
Shut up. Let's go.
Smells like a cover-up.
The press has
a right to know!
Take him out of the building.
Search him.
Now get the hell
out of here.
Who the hell are you, Keyes?
The last person in the world
you want to fuck with.
You want to
make me proud, kid?
Take your bag of tricks,
stay with them...
find out
where they take her.
Meet me later
at the Sea Toast.
Be careful. They're good.
Don't worry.
Surveillance is my specialty.
Okay, then. Just get going.
Hmm. Go get them,
Lone Ranger.
Hey, Danny, look here.
We got to take this real cool.
These guys
sure aren't the DEA...
but it's still Keyes' party.
Stick around.
Stay out of sight.
I'll meet you at 1:00.
We'll take a good look
at that room, okay?
Hey, wait for me.
Danny boy, no hero stuff,
understand?
Danny boy,
Dan-Dan-Danny boy.
Watch your ass,
Danny boy.
She never made it.
The feds were waiting.
Hustled her off in a chopper.
- Let me guess... the silver Alouette?
- That very one.
Guess what? Your pal Keyes
was running the whole show...
and his butt boys.
Son of a bitch.
You done real good, kid.
Now, tomorrow,
start a tail on Keyes...
Everything he does,
everywhere he goes.
Who knows? You
might just get lucky.
Lieutenant...
luck...
is my specialty.
Yeah. I bet it is.
Now if you'll
excuse me, Lieutenant...
I've got some
serious police work to attend to.
Come to papa.
- Hey.
- Hey, are your balls okay?
- Fine. How are yours?
- Ha ha ha.
Hey, do you mind?
It's my sister.
Oh, you're not
my sister, are you?
Son of a bitch.
Who you really chasing, Keyes?
Time to go to work.
Danny boy.
Mike? Whoa!
Whoa! Oh!
Whoa! Uh!
Oh, God!
No. No. Oh!
No! Oh, God!
[Gunshots]
Please, no!
Oh!
Aah!
[Screeching]
[Woman's Voice]
Lieutenant Michael R. Harrigan...
Violence prone...
obsessive/ compulsive personality...
a history of
excessive physical force...
throughout his 18 years...
as a Los Angeles police officer.
Also responsible...
for the destruction
of 11 patrol cars...
a city bus...
What about
10 commendations for valor...
and the best
felony arrest record...
in the history
of this department?
That and my intervention
on your behalf...
are the only reasons
you still have a job.
The chief would charge you...
with Detective Archuleta's
death and suspend you.
As it is,
he left it in my hands.
Now this
John Wayne attitude...
flagrant disregard
for policies...
is going to end now.
No one
under my command...
is going to impede
the progress...
of this federal task force
headed by agent Keyes.
No one.
That's it.
Dismissed.
Mike, you're
too close to this.
Stay out of it.
It's a police matter.
They can't keep
the department out of it.
We'll find Danny's killer.
Captain, Danny and I
came up together...
15 years
on the fucking street.
Whoever killed him's
going to pay.
I'm going to finish it.
Hey!
Hey, come on.
What is this?
Listen, shithead. I don't give
a fuck who you really are...
what you want
with this asshole.
Because now it's personal...
and he's a dead man.
What you're dealing with
is way over your head.
You don't know
what you're dealing with.
And I'm warning you.
Stay the fuck
out of my way!
I'll take care of him.
No. Let him go.
We're too close.
[Tony Pope] ... Claiming as
his, turf already controlled...
by the bloodthirsty Jamaican
and Colombian drug lords.
Watch as we
continue our report.
Yes, the word is out.
L.A. Is up for grabs...
the spoils
of our once fine city...
going to the ruthless scum who can
spread the most carnage and blood.
Our latest update
on the scoreboard...
5 assorted trash
and 1 good cop.
One of the best
on our force.
Who's next?
Where's the mayor?
He's not even in the city...
Forget it. It's over.
Mike, goddamn it.
This ain't your personal
little war, you know.
I loved Danny, too.
You said the only way
you survive down here...
is because you're a team.
Door swings
both ways, remember?
All right.
We'll do it together.
Come on.
Talk to me about Keyes.
He's been everywhere.
We've been on him for three days.
- They're not looking for drug dealers.
- Yeah.
They're setting up
radar sensors all over downtown.
I used my whole repertoire
to keep up with them.
I had scanners on them.
They scrambled my shit up.
They had equipment
I can't begin to touch...
and then this morning...
I lost them.
- We lost them.
- Lost them where?
Vernon and industry.
They fuckin' disappeared.
The slaughterhouse
district?
Yeah, and in
this heat, whoa!
I mean B.O. And barbecue.
Whatever Keyes is looking for...
he's found it
or damn close to it.
Leona, I want to meet
with King Willie.
Willie and I seem
to have the same problem.
In the meantime,
you come with me.
- Mike, it's impossible.
- Just do it.
Oh, fuck.
Omega 1.
We need an extension.
This is Omega 1.
Please make sure...
we've got
22 minutes remaining...
on safe window
of operation.
Yes, sir.
Verify that
final telemetry check.
Start your test now.
Scan track 3... 2... 1...
mark.
Number 6, power up
on the U.V. Banks.
We're complete on the lower
U.V. Banks. Ready for testing.
Second level, check
for ambient temperature variations.
You got two minutes.
Now get going.
To all units...
all units, you have
approximately 20 minutes...
to finish your task.
Increasing U. V.
Confirmed.
Up 42%.
Your friend's death
was the result...
of a massive intrusion
in the chest cavity...
by an edged weapon...
that nearly cleaved
the heart in two.
Death was instantaneous.
He was boned like a fish.
I've never seen anything like this.
Please do not touch anything.
[Glass Breaking]
Doctor, what about
the other victims?
Anything there?
The federal team brought in
their own forensic examiners.
I am the medical examiner...
and chief pathologist in the city.
They've cut me out completely.
Any way to look at evidence
the feds have collected?
They must have run tests.
- It won't be easy.
- Doctor...
I pried this
from Danny's hands.
It's what took him
into the rafters.
It has no weight.
But it cuts like steel.
Let me see.
We are now at 150,000 times
normal magnification.
Astonishing.
This material doesn't
correspond to anything...
on the periodic table.
Lieutenant, what
the hell is that thing?
- You don't buy it in a hardware store.
- Military?
Good guess... I'm assuming it
got away from them...
or something
they want real bad.
Keyes. We're getting
closer to what happened...
Don't.
Easy, kid.
Put your gun away.
King Willie
will see you now.
¤ I'm tired
of the rat race ¤
¤ I wanna have fun... ¤
It's okay.
I'll go with you.
I'll call you later.
I'll follow you.
¤ I want to run away ¤
¤ I can't take my mind
off my problems ¤
You want some ganga?
Ha ha ha!
License plate number...
1-8-8...
No, no. 1-8-8-3...
Oh, fuck!
Ha ha ha.
Door swings both ways,
my ass.
This door
swings both ways.
¤ I don't believe your friends ¤
¤ With their plastic smiles ¤
¤ I'm taken back 'cause I
don't like your style... ¤
[Coughing]
Thanks for the ride.
You know...
you guys really ought
to cut down.
¤ I trusted you,
but you let me down ¤
¤ I don't want you around ¤
¤ When things get rough ¤
¤ You come runnin'
back to me... ¤
They say you want
to talk to me.
They say you
offering me favors.
Tell me why, Babylon,
Mr. Policeman?
I want some information.
Information.
Hmm.
About the one that's
doing all the killing, are you?
He killed your people...
now mine.
I think you know who he is.
- [Laughs]
- I want him.
I don't know who he is...
but I know where he is.
- The other side.
- What are you talking about?
The spirit world, man.
You see...
it's always the same.
There's no stopping
what can't be stopped...
no killing what can't be killed.
Hey, make sense, man.
This thing that's killing
your people and mine...
is from the other side.
I can feel him
all around.
You can't see
the eyes of the demon...
until him come calling.
This is dread, man,
truly dread.
Nothing else
for you here, policeman.
Time to go.
Prepare yourself.
He saw distant light
in the holy mountain.
Selah.
Aah!
This is Tony Pope
live from L. A...
the city of fear.
The psycho vigilante killer...
continues his daily diet
for murder...
Bodies strung out...
bodies with the skins
ripped off...
the hearts torn
from the cadavers.
Just recently, King Willie...
the vicious drug lord...
found in an alley
just around the corner...
with his head cut off...
and his spinal column
torn from the body...
A fitting demise to
the prince of powder.
First Danny, then came Willie...
and you were right there.
He's playing with you, Mike.
You've got to be careful.
We all got to be careful.
What about Keyes?
- Anything there?
- There's definitely something slippery...
about our brother Keyes.
Seems there's
a Peter J. Keyes...
Ph. D., physical sciences,
Cornell.
Hot out of college, then right into
bed with strategic defense systems.
Then two years later...
commissioned as a captain
in air force intelligence.
This is a dead end.
We're way out
of our league.
I don't care
who's involved.
He killed Danny.
He's going to fall.
- Now, what about the good doctor?
- Yes, I'm here, Lieutenant.
The federal authorities
erased everything...
from the computer file
except for this...
Part of a chemical test...
on a fragment of wood
from the penthouse...
and it contained traces
of cattle blood...
and heavy traces of steroids.
I believe that whoever killed
Detective Archuleta...
had recently been
in a slaughterhouse.
That's where
I lost Keyes the first time.
we'll find him.
Take the Metro.
I'll meet you
at the Burns Station.
Just because you
don't see Keyes' boys...
doesn't mean
they're not around.
I just want you
to stay in the car.
Your mom and I
won't be very long.
You sit still.
We'll be back in a few minutes.
- Come on, honey.
- Yes, dear.
- Which way was it?
- Down there.
[Imitates Machine Gun]
Take that,
you scum-sucking dog.
[Breathing]
Want some candy?
Brian?
You come here
right this minute!
Mommy, I saw a ghost.
Want some candy?
Rest.
[Distorted Cries]
Danny's necklace.
I hate the subway
at rush hour.
It's hard enough
to find a seat...
and if you do, it's been
pissed in or thrown-up on.
This damn heat
is killing me.
Hey, it's me!
I look great!
Shut up.
No autographs, pop.
Look.
There's two seats right there.
Don't touch me! Hey!
The shit never ends.
After you.
Excuse me. Police business.
Get out of my way!
Hey, baby.
Besame mucho.  Come on!
You look like
a sympathetic dude.
My, uh, partner here
needs an operation...
but we're a little short of cash.
Know what I mean?
No need for that.
Get the hell away from me!
I know how to use this!
Don't make me use this thing!
Mine's bigger than yours!
I'll take that.
[Guns Cock]
Hold it. Police.
We're in trouble now.
Nobody move!
Hands up!
Everybody take a deep breath...
loosen your sphincters.
We don't need any
rush hour rambos.
Ytu tambien,
motherfuckin' baby.
Drop it and sit down!
[Metal Crunching]
Leona, you okay?
Let's get these people
out of here!
Get out!
Move it!
Get out of the way!
Leona!
Leona,
get them out! Go! Go!
Jerry!
Get out!
Leona, do it!
Now!
Hey! Over here!
Yeah. That's right.
Come and get it.
Come on! Move it!
Let's go! Let's go!
¡Vamos!
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
What the fuck are you?
Wait!
¡Vamos! ¡Vamos!
Come on!
Keep walking!
Come on! You, too!
¡Vamanos!
Come on,
motherfucker!
Want some candy?
Let's dance!
Aah!
Come on,
get out of the way!
Get out of the way!
- [Alarm Sounds]
- [Brakes Grinding]
Out, out, out.
Out of the way.
Towards the light!
The light!
Come on! Get out!
¡Vamos!
Oh, God.
Oh, no.
Jerry.
Aah!
[Heartbeats]
God. Not again.
Okay. Move your ass!
Move out of the way!
What's happening?
What the fuck
is going on down there?
Oh, God!
Hey, Jerry!
Oh, Leona! Leona.
Oh, please.
Leona. Oh.
How-How's she doing?
Deep shock,
but she's alive.
I'm picking up
fetal heart sounds.
This woman is pregnant.
Let's move.
L.A. County. Stat!
Stand back.
On 3. 1, 2, 3...
Load up.
Out of my way!
Whoa. Whoa.
Let me see.
Where's Jerry?
I don't know.
We found his badge.
Who got hit
this time?
Five gang members...
bunch of commuters.
It doesn't make sense.
They were all armed.
What do you mean?
It's the chief.
Wait here.
Yeah?
What the hell's going on?
- It's a damn nightmare. Civilians this time.
- Were they all killed?
Just like the others.
[Crunching]
Aah!
Oh! Jerry!
Holy shit!
What the hell
is going on here?
Hey, guys.
Get the camera.
Get the camera on that.
Hey, Harrigan!
More victims!
More mutilations!
Fuck you!
Pope. Are you there, Pope?
Pope, what's going on?
Arrrgh!
Sir. The cop is back.
God...
Harrigan.
Don't you show up in
the damndest places.
Come here, Lieutenant.
I got something
you might find interesting.
What is this?
How many times do
I have to tell you?
You don't know what
you're dealing with.
There's your killer.
Wonderful, isn't it?
Pheromone signature
left by his body.
Punch up three.
10 years ago,
one of his kind...
stalked and eliminated...
an elite Special Forces crew
in Central America.
There were two survivors.
They indicated
that when trapped...
the creature activated
a self-destruct device...
that destroyed
enough rain forest...
to cover 300 city blocks.
Remarkable weaponry.
That's right, Lieutenant.
- Other-world life forms.
- Huh?
A fucking alien.
Iwo Jima,
Cambodia, Beirut.
Drawn by heat and conflict.
He's on safari.
Lions.
The tigers.
The bears.
Oh, my.
Trophies.
That's the game, isn't it?
You're the lion.
This is his jungle.
Why can't we see him?
Defensive adaptations
are astounding.
It's somehow able to bend light.
Perfect camouflage.
- You admire the son of a bitch.
- Not what he does...
For what he is.
For what he can give us...
A new era
of scientific technology.
I've waited
a lifetime for this...
and I'm not going
to miss the chance.
And I'm not going
We're picking up something
on the pheromone scanners.
Target one
is on the roof.
It's taken us over two weeks
to learn his patterns.
He comes here every
two days to feed.
Seems he likes beef.
I didn't think
he was vegetarian.
We've prepared
a trap for this predator.
We're certain this being...
can see in only one
spectrum of light...
Infrared.
Infrared?
He hunts by
seeing our heat.
Block the heat,
and he's blind.
These suits
insulate body heat...
making the team invisible
to the creature.
We've flooded
the packing house...
with radioactive dust.
We've also installed
ultraviolet lighting everywhere.
The dust adheres to his body,
making him visible.
Liquid nitrogen.
You're going
to freeze him.
We have
to capture him.
He's moving.
Finally.
Grab a seat.
Enjoy the show.
This is history.
Capture and isolation
is our objective.
Defensive action
only on my orders.
Power up.
Lights on.
Let's get him.
We're in.
Switch to ultraviolet.
Radio silence.
Out.
Engage ultraviolet units
"A" through " J."
What's all this interference?
Correcting the problem, sir.
They're moving
to the second level.
Target's still moving toward
the number two stairwell.
Playing right into it.
[Creaking]
Wait a minute.
It's stopped.
Arrgh!
Now you will die.
It's moving
back against the wall.
It's backing up.
It's moving away from them.
Your boys have been made.
It's circling behind them.
Get them out, Garber!
They're walking into a trap!
Keyes...
he's right behind you.
Third floor structure.
Who is this?
Clear the line.
He sees the damn lights.
Turn them off!
Shit!
Stop him!
Door.
Open it.
Go fuck yourself.
Okay. Okay.
Door.
Yes, sir.
You don't know
what you're doing.
It's open.
You'll ruin everything!
Fuck yourself!
Defensive formation
number one.
Nitrogen guns... safeties off.
Everyone else, watch out.
This is it.
He's moving on you
from the right.
Garber, where is he?
I can't see him.
He's right there!
Goddamn it!
Where is he?
Watch out!
Oh, my God.
Watch your cross fire!
Damn. My line.
I'm losing my pressure.
Keyes, you all right?
Come on, damn it!
Switch over!
They're gone.
They're all dead.
You want me? Here I am!
You are one...
ugly motherfu...
Arrgh!
Motherfucker.
Guess who's back.
Too late to go home now.
Get out of here, Harrigan.
I'm going to save your ass.
This is between me and him!
Birds.
Damn birds.
Okay, pussy-face...
it's your move.
Shit happens.
[Beeping]
[Buzzing]
[Buzzing Faster]
Aah!
Arrgh!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
That's all
I need is birds.
You can do it.
I can do it.
Just like falling off a log.
Oh!
Like a 30-story log.
Damn.
Maybe I'll get
lucky and fall.
Damn it.
Arrgh!
The final jeopardy
answer is this...
Berengaria, who never
set foot in England...
was its queen
for eight years...
after marrying
this king on Cyprus.
Good luck.
[ Jeopardy Theme Music Plays]
- Herb.
- [Snoring]
Herb, wake up.
There's somebody
in the bathroom.
Herb.
Arrgh!
Aah!
It's all right.
I'm a cop.
I don't think
he gives a shit.
Shit!
Get back inside!
Holy Moses. Not again.
Shit!
Son of a bitch.
Oh, God.
Why can't this guy
stay on the ground?
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Come to papa.
Stop the elevator!
Stop it!
Aah!
Now where the hell am I?
Where are you?
Jesus Christ.
[Crash]
Get it straight, asshole!
Shit happens!
Arrgh!
Okay.
Who's next?
Take it.
"1715."
[Growls, Indistinct]
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
[Coughing]
[Helicopter Engine]
Harrigan!
What the fuck
happened in there?
[Sirens]
Goddamn it.
We came so close!
Don't worry, asshole.
You'll get another chance.