COGLIOSTRO: The battle between heaven
and hell has waged eternal...
...their armies fueled
by souls harvested on earth.
The Devil Malebolgia
has sent a lieutenant to earth...
...to recruit men who will turn the world
into a place of death...
...in exchange for wealth and power.
A place that will provide enough souls
to complete his army...
...and allow Armageddon to begin.
All the Dark Lord needs now
is a great soldier...
...someone who can lead his hordes
to the gates of heaven...
...and burn them down.
[CHATTERING IN CHINESE]
[BLEEPING]
[BEEPING]
COGLIOSTRO:
Like him, l killed in the name of good.
But the violence of my life pulled my soul
towards the darkness.
But l fought and freed my soul.
Now I watch for others like me.
Men are the ones
who create evil on earth.
It is the choices they make
that enslave their souls to hell.
This is the test.
WOMAN [ON TV]: The leader of
the Algerian Revolutionary Front...
...was killed yesterday
along with 26 innocent civilians...
...in a vicious rocket attack
in an airport in Hong Kong.
There has been an outpouring
of anti-U.S. sentiment...
...sweeping across the globe.
Protesters in Libya, Bosnia,
France, Moscow...
...and the United States are joining together
to denounce this blatant act....
Simmons is the best.
CLOWN:
Simmons is not the problem.
He's overseas killing the bad guys
like the hero that he thinks he is.
We made a deal, Wynn.
Where the hell is the ultimate weapon
you promised us?
This isn't a game we're playing.
Engineering a biological weapon
is an exact science.
You want it done right,
you do it my way.
CLOWN: But this five-year plan of yours
just chaps my buttocks.
I'm making you a guarantee.
All you have to do is keep certain
agencies off my back...
...and make damn sure
I get all that I've been promised.
CLOWN: This is me you're talking to.
If I say you're the man, you're the man.
You do for me, and in no time,
you'll be running this place.
And when the big piñata breaks,
you'll get it all.
Just make sure you
keep your end of the bargain. Ha-ha-ha.
PS, there's one more item
on our to-do list.
It requires your personal attention.
We need you to help recruit
a very special soldier for us.
Your all-time favorite killer, Al Simmons.
Simmons?
He's doing a great job where he is.
Why do you want him?
CLOWN:
Why do you people always question?
Why ask "why"...
...when "how" is so much more fun?
[LAUGHING]
TERRY:
Wow. Not again.
[R&B MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO]
-Hey, Wanda, do me a favor.
-Yeah?
Buy your man a watch.
-He's on his way out. Now do me a favor.
-What's that?
-Make sure he's back for dinner tomorrow.
-I'll do my best.
Make sure he's back for dinner
tomorrow night, Terry.
Yes, ma'am.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[DOG BARKING]
SIMMONS:
Hey, Spaz.
Same routine, all right?
Guard the house, guard Wanda.
TERRY:
Great guard dog.
Here.
[WHIMPERS]
TERRY: Hey, Al, what happened last night?
Look at this.
What a frigging mess.
We were supposed to be taking out
the bad guys, not innocent bystanders.
Another Jason Wynn special.
What do you mean?
Seems like an awful lot of Wynn's ops
have screwed the pooch lately.
Don't worry, Al, lighten up.
I got your back.
Semper fi. Good to go.
All right.
I'm gonna keep my eye on Wynn.
[SCANNER BEEPING]
SCANNER:
Vehicle secure.
The airport kill zone
was supposed to be clear of civilians.
An unfortunate but necessary sacrifice.
You want someone filling body bags,
you send Priest.
If you can't handle it, l will.
WYNN:
I will send whoever wherever l choose.
You will follow orders and do your job.
Got a problem with that, soldier?
Yes, l do, sir...
...and I want out.
[SCOFFS]
I always knew you'd lose your nerve.
You don't quit us, son.
We are not the U.S. Postal Service.
Have you read your profile recently?
You are a borderline psychopath...
...perfect for government service.
No guilt, no fear.
You're a killing machine.
-You're wrong about me, Wynn.
-Am l?
Have you ever stopped to consider that
you won't be happy doing anything else?
I made up my mind.
Nothing l can say
to make you change it?
Nothing.
All right, I'll arrange for your transfer...
...right after we've run
this last operation.
North Korean refinery
secretly producing biological weapons.
It's up to us to take out the plant...
...and carefully destroy
all the biochemical viruses.
Come on, son. This is top priority.
Let's get it over with.
[MEN SPEAKING IN KOREAN]
[NECK CRACKS]
[BODY THUMPS]
[BEEPING]
What the hell is going on here?
-Wynn.
-Priorities have changed, Al.
There's a town
less than a mile away from here.
If you release the virus, they'll all die.
A town with approximately 8000
experimental hosts.
Are you out of your damn mind?
I'm not gonna let you do this.
Unh!
-Unh!
-Looks like I'm up for a promotion.
You wipe his ass too? Unh!
You son of a bitch.
You knew what was going on all along.
I do believe he's catching on.
[LAUGHING]
WYNN:
Enjoy your retirement, old friend.
Oh, and by the way,
don't worry about Wanda.
I'll take good care of her.
You touch her, and you're a dead man.
You're the dead man.
See you in hell, Al.
[GRUNTING]
Wanda!
[SCREAMS]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
[GRUNTING]
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
Aw. Look who was left
in the oven too long.
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
I told him well-done, not burnt.
I'm gonna have fun with you.
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
Boo!
[GRUNTING]
[PIGEONS COOING]
[RATS SQUEALING]
Huh?
Hey, mister, you don't look so good.
-Ugh.
-Hey, mister, you thirsty?
Hey, mister, you thirsty?
Get the--
Get lost, kid.
What are you looking at, old man?
You tell me.
You've been gone a long time, friend.
SPAWN:
What are you talking about?
-Where am l?
ZACK: Rat City.
Part of the alley. l sleep over there.
COGLIOSTRO: This is a holy place.
All are welcome here.
ZACK: What you got there?
WOMAN 1: Here, Zack.
ZACK: Looks good.
WOMAN 1: For you.
Yeah, right.
[GRUNTS]
MAN 1:
Understand.
It's getting dark.
Screw this.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
MAN 2:
Unh!
COP:
Don't loiter! Let's go! Let's go!
[WOMAN 2 SCREAMS]
MAN 3:
Take that!
You're welcome to join us...
...if you choose.
I got a home.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
COP: You, you, go on.
WOMAN 3: Officer.
COGLIOSTRO: A new Hellspawn
has emerged from the darkness.
Reborn on earth...
...drawn to the alley
by an unknown force...
...his necroplasmic body
wracked by pain...
...his memories fragmented.
To him, North Korea was moments ago.
But Malebolgia kept him secluded
in darkness for five long years...
...while things on earth changed...
...in ways that will only feed his anger
and desire for revenge.
He sets out to reclaim his humanity.
How much is left remains to be seen.
CLOWN:
Okay, step right up.
[CLOWN HUMMING]
[GRUNTING]
CLOWN: Hocus pocus, abracadabra
and all that jazzy crap.
Come here, little girl.
You'll be my assistant. Ha-ha-ha.
Now the magic rings.
[KIDS CHEERING]
WOMAN: Good job.
-Okay, baby?
ALL:
One, two, three.
[LAUGHS]
[ALL CHEERING]
SPAWN:
Wanda.
SIMMONS:
I don't have a choice.
WANDA:
I'll always love you...
...forever.
TERRY: What's this doing here?
-I don't know. I'll get the troops lemonade.
[SPAWN GRUNTING]
WANDA:
Mmm.
I'll take some.
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
[BARKING]
Spaz.
All right, kids, l got more tricks
than your local hooker. Here you go.
They say it's a trick, but it's not.
Little girl, where you going?
[DOG WHIMPERS]
Want some candy?
Cyan!
-You okay, baby, huh?
CYAN: Yeah.
WANDA:
Terry! Terry!
CLOWN:
I like children fried.
WANDA:
Terry!
Wanda.
TERRY:
What's going on?
WANDA: l came out and this man
was lying next to Cyan.
-You okay, honey?
-Uh-huh.
What are you doing back here, huh?
SPAWN: Wan--
-What is it?
Beat it before I call the cops, huh?
Get out of here.
CLOWN:
There you are.
I've been looking everywhere for you.
Bad Crispy! Bad Crispy!
Clown not like. Heh-heh-heh.
Sorry for the turbulence, folks.
He's harmless.
Safe as milk.
Just a freak accident with Jiffy Pop.
Just get your stuff, get out of here,
take him with you.
Oh, what an adorable little girl.
-Oh, look at her. Can keep her?
TERRY: Hey, hey, hey.
Oh, of course, not. No pets allowed.
A little something for Lolita here.
Baby exorcist.
Ha, ha. All right.
Come on, my barbecued friend.
Don't wanna keep that side order
of potato salad waiting, now, do we?
Terry...
-...he knew my name.
-Are you sure?
Come on. Let's get the kids inside.
[GROANS]
You can't get married.
SIMMONS:
Wanda is the best thing to happen to me.
TERRY: I'm there for you, buddy.
SIMMONS: This is my last mission.
Wait for me.
-I just don't wanna lose you, baby.
-You will never lose me.
I promise.
[MOANS]
Oh, yes, we are.
The master and l are gonna have words.
He knows l hate clowns.
God, I hate them. l hate them all.
I hate Bozo, Ronald, Chuckles...
...with their freaking dumb noses
and their lousy party hats.
Ugh!
I don't mind being short, fat and ugly,
but the pay sucks.
[LAUGHS]
What--?
Hey, easy with that face. I'm eating.
What does this remind you of, huh?
No, naughty boy.
[CLOWN FARTS]
Oops. A wet one.
I hope l didn't stain my underwear.
Look at that. Skid marks. Ha-ha-ha.
Get away from me, you freak!
CLOWN: Oh, coming from a monster,
that really hurts my feelings.
Come back here, scrotum face.
I'm not done with you yet.
Unh! Feels like my skin
is about to explode.
That's just your viral necroplasm
going through its larval stage.
Move over.
Soon you're gonna get hair in funny places
and start thinking about girls.
Getting a chubby, studly?
Come on, a half guy, a semi? Ha-ha-ha.
Just get me to a hospital.
A hospital?
Have you looked in a mirror lately,
burnt man walking? Ha-ha-ha.
Even the entire cast of ER
couldn't put you back together again.
How do l put this to you?
You're pushing up daisies.
You're in permanent nap time.
You're fertilizer.
Hey, is any of this sinking in?
You're dead.
D-E-D. Dead.
I guess five years feeding earthworms has
eaten what little brain there was in there.
What are you?
Well, allow me
to kick-start your memory.
Hang on, these flashbacks can be killers.
You're the dead man.
See you in hell, Al.
Wanda!
[GROWLING]
MALEBOLGIA:
This is the bargain.
If you lead my army,
you can see Wanda again.
[GRUNTING]
What is your answer?
Yes! Yes, l will lead your army!
Anything for Wanda!
MALEBOLGIA:
If you fail me...
...you will die.
Avenge your murder.
Kill Jason Wynn.
So Malebolgia spent five years
preparing the earth for your arrival, mister.
A little death, a little destruction.
Perfect marriage.
Speaking of marriage,
guess who's not your fiancée anymore.
Eh! And the winners
are Wanda and Terry.
Multiplying like rabbits.
[SINGING]
And humping and porking
And doing it and liking it
You stay away from her.
I don't want Wanda.
I want you to take care of Wynn.
And then you and the army can kick
some angelic buttocks. Heh-heh-heh.
And in return for your services...
...we'll get Wanda back for you.
Heck, you can have every Wanda
on the planet. Why settle for leftovers, huh?
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
I love this guy. You kill me.
Go ahead, stud. You do-- Ah!
This is all some sadistic game of Wynn's.
And when l catch him, he's gonna wish
he had killed me when he had the chance.
That's it. That's the spirit.
Just think of me as your guardian angel.
The clown from hell.
You're Jimmy Stewart and I'm Clarence.
[MIMICS JAMES STEWART]
"Oh, well, uh.
Every time somebody farts,
a demon gets his wings."
[CLOWN FARTING]
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Oops, twins. Ha, ha.
Get away from me,
you fudge-packing midget.
You still don't get it, do you,
Amnesia Boy?
We're gonna have to dig a little deeper.
[GRUNTS]
SPAWN:
What is this?
This is where old folks go
after Florida, son.
What is that you say?
"Can I dig up my body now?"
Why, certainly. Of course you can.
And if you strike oil, half of it is mine.
Start digging.
MAN:
Hail Satan, lord of all that we can see.
In the name of Luther,
Bialy and Levinson...
... I command thee to appear!
[THUNDER CRASHING]
Told you we need a bigger pentagram.
Hey, how about we get back
to that sacrifice-a-virgin idea?
[HOWLS]
-I like that.
-Here we go.
You know what l need here, man?
A fresh skull, man. Ha-ha-ha.
-Yeah, a fresh skull. A fresh skull.
-Hey, dude, get away!
[THUNDER CRASHING]
Argh!
[SHRIEKS]
[LAUGHS]
WANDA: Every time you go out there,
you come back a little bit more dead inside.
[SCREAMING]
Oh, come on, you scream like a girl.
Do it like this:
[SCREAMING]
Someone's a little angry
because they died and went to--
[SINGING] Hello, my mutant
Hello, my carcass
Hello, my bug-infested corpse
Did, like, Satan send you guys?
How come God hogs up all the good
followers and we get all the retards?
-Hey, what's up with that face?
-Get your hands off me.
[GRUNTING]
Argh!
MAN:
Help.
[GRUNTING]
What is that?
What is that thing?
Shocked and amazed
at the wonders of necroflesh?
You're not alone.
For a limited time only...
...you, too,
can have this handsome epidermis...
...for the eensy price of your soul
and a buttload of pain.
MAN 1: Let's get out of here!
MAN 2: Go, go, go!
MAN 3:
Oh, my God!
I hate weekend Satanists, don't you?
Look at you. Look at you.
From spawn larva to full-fledged
Hellspawn in record time.
-Ha-ha-ha.
-What is this?
You were tied to the tracks...
...and that stupid train
just kept running over you, now, didn't it?
Running over you.
In the name of the people
and things of hell...
... I dub thee Spawn,
general of hell's army.
Arise, Your Crispness!
Arise, Duke of Deep-Fried!
Sultan of Sizzling!
Emir of Ooey-Gooey!
All right, so l suck as a clown. Bite me.
Now, look.
You do your job
and I'll be the first to kiss your black butt.
But if you can't hack it...
... I'll gladly FedEx your worthless carcass
back to the frying pan...
...where Malebolgia will be waiting
for both us.
Shh. You'll wake up the dead.
Oops, that's you.
You know, dead people can still die,
schmecky.
All l gotta do is cut off your head.
Ha-ha-ha.
SPAWN:
Oh, God.
Ah! Ah! Did you have to use the G-word?
La, la, la.
Wanda.
What have l done?
[THUNDER CRASHING]
You done with this Hallmark moment?
I can't take any more
of this sentimental crap. Come on.
I'll come back when your armor hardens.
And don't play with it or you'll go blind.
I have a few more details to attend to
and then we can play. Heh-heh-heh.
Yuck.
I hate anchovies.
Mmm. Mmm.
That tastes so good,
I could kick some puppies.
[BOTTLES CLATTERING]
Good.
[SCREAMING]
This freak stuff is gonna come in handy
when l get my hands on Wynn.
You're letting them get to you.
Easy, friend.
Every choice has its consequences.
Who are you?
An assassin, like you.
Only I killed for the kingdom of Saxony
500 years ago.
I am Cogliostro.
That's all you need to know. For now.
Are there any normal people
left on earth?
Or is everyone just back from hell?
SOLDIER 1:
Get it out.
SOLDIER 2:
Halt!
Clear!
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
How do you address accusations from some
that the CIA only acts...
...to protect the government's economic
interests in regions of conflict?
I think the government
has been as attentive...
...to the sensitivities
of the nations involved as possible.
Since the unfortunate incident
in Southeast Asia last week...
...Director Wynn has been meeting
with world leaders...
...to quell the proliferation
of global conflicts.
NATALIE: And has this produced
any positive results?
I heard that last week's peace summit
between the Arabs and Israelis...
...was disrupted by bomb threats
from the Christian Coalition.
[TV TURNS OFF]
Fitzgerald may be a spineless bureaucrat,
but he's doing a great PR job for me.
The world is going to hell
in a handbasket.
But thanks to him,
it's just another story on the 5:00 news.
Like lambs to the slaughter.
The best is yet to come.
[BEEPING]
There it is, Jess.
Finally ready.
Heat-16. Heh.
Makes the Ebola virus look
like a skin rash.
That North Korean biochemical operation
really paid off.
We have harvested the ultimate weapon
from those diseased bodies...
...and now we have the only vaccine.
[WYNN LAUGHS]
-Was there ever any doubt?
-Never.
Now we have weapons in place
to disperse Heat-16...
...over half of this godforsaken globe.
Soon the whole world
will be at my command.
Anyone who refuses to join my consortium
won't be around to argue.
[WYNN LAUGHING]
SOLDIER:
Okay!
Time to get reacquainted, Jason.
WOMAN [ON INTERCOM]:
Director Wynn, Terry Fitzgerald is here.
PRIEST:
Send him in.
WYNN: Speak of the devil.
Come in, Terry. Good to see you.
-The car is waiting downstairs.
-Good.
-You know Agent Priest.
TERRY: Yes.
-Could I have a word with you alone?
-Of course.
Would you excuse us?
Glad you dropped by, son.
I commend you on the way
you've handled the media.
Those rumors about me were becoming
a real headache. Have a drink.
Thank you.
I know we've been covering up problems
with our missions overseas.
-I really can't keep lying like this, sir.
-Lying? Really?
I'd like to put a team together, analyze
the field op data, get to the bottom of it.
But you're not an analyst anymore, Terry.
Well, there's no reason
not to take a look, sir.
-On the contrary.
-Beg your pardon?
Tell me...
...how are Cyan and Wanda?
Little girl just had a birthday, didn't she?
-They're both fine.
-I'm glad to hear that.
Now let's get something straight.
I run this organization the way l see fit.
And I will do whatever is necessary
to keep it that way.
Your job is to make damn sure
the public agrees with me.
That clear enough?
-Yes.
-Good.
The car is waiting.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
Achmed and Abdullah.
WYNN:
Achmed, my friend. Good to see you.
Abdullah, good to see you.
TERRY:
Up.
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
MAN:
This one here.
-Excuse us.
MAN: What--?
-Excuse me, sir.
-Yes?
Urgent call.
Gentlemen.
Have you made a decision?
Your Heat-16 test was very impressive.
Tell me, how do you
control delivery of the weapon?
It's the latest in nanotechnology.
Let me assure you, gentlemen,
the weapon is problem-free.
We've already placed orders
with several of our allies.
You're becoming quite a powerful man,
Mr. Wynn.
Your consortium will soon rival
the United Nations.
Not at all, sir. I'm just a facilitator.
Thank you.
My partners are the beneficiaries.
To my partners, gentlemen.
-Fitzgerald.
MAN: Code red security breach, sir.
-Where?
-At the armory.
-A detail is en route.
-I'm on my way. Damn it.
MAN:
Agent Priest has arrived.
Wait here.
There's been a break-in at A-6,
the armory.
-Who?
-We don't know.
There's a security detail downstairs
with Priest.
Let's get out of here.
MAN 1:
Hey!
You.
WOMAN 1: Oh, what is it?
MAN 2: Get out of the way!
Who are you? Unh!
SPAWN:
What's the matter, Jason?
You don't recognize
your own handiwork?
You left me to die in that biochem plant.
-Remember?
-Simmons.
Ugh! You sent me to hell, Jason.
I'm here to return the favor.
MAN 3:
Ah!
[CROWD GASP]
I trusted you.
-Jesus.
-How could you marry Wanda?
How could you?
Al, when you died...
...Wanda was devastated.
Do you know about Cyan?
Time to die, Jason.
[WOMAN 2 SCREAMING]
Nice outfit, asshole.
Unh!
Damn.
WYNN: Jessica!
-What the hell is that?
It's Simmons!
-What are you talking about?
-That thing is Simmons!
I want you to nail him now!
[BOTTLE CLINKING]
[SCREAMING]
Unh!
It's a little early for Halloween, Simmons.
Where you're going,
every day is Halloween.
[CHUCKLES]
You don't have the guts.
You're right.
CLOWN:
Coming, coming.
Will that be the same
or separate checks, lady? Ha-ha-ha.
Just when I was getting sick of you
whining about Wanda, you do us proud.
So congrats on your first mission.
-Go ahead and spank them.
SOLDIER 1: Run!
SOLDIER 2:
Look out! Move! Move!
Get back!
Unh!
SOLDIER 3:
Let's move!
[POLICE SIRENS WAILING]
SPAWN:
Holy shit.
Go! Go!
COP 1 [OVER RADIO]:
Shoot on sight.
I say again, shoot on sight.
COP 2:
Get a light on him!
There!
COP 2: You see him?
COP 3: No, sir!
COP 4:
Where the hell did he go?
COP 5:
Negative, sir!
COP 6:
Argh!
COP 3: There he is!
COP 2: All right, take him!
Come on, let's go, go!
[SCREAMING]
[SIRENS WAILING]
-All right, what have we got here?
-Gunshot wound to the head, doc.
-Oh, she's dead. Come on.
EMT 1: Right.
-Let's go.
EMT 2: Okay.
-Easy.
EMT 3: Here we go.
EMT 2:
There. That's it.
DOCTOR:
Make some room here. Make some room.
CLOWN:
Psst! Psst!
DOCTOR: Put her around the back.
Keep her around back.
Psst. Psst.
Psst! Psst!
Why didn't you warn me about Simmons?
Spawn was ready
sooner than I expected...
...so don't get your panties in a wad.
Always bitching at me.
"Why didn't you tell me about Simmons?
Why didn't you tell me it was gonna hurt?
Am l gonna go to hell?"
Oh, grow up, you syphilitic ballsac.
-At least you had fun compared to them.
-Fun?
-Does this look like playland to you?
-No.
No, he killed Priest!
He damn near killed me!
You say that like it's a bad thing.
No, Jerky. Jerky, Spawn is a big idiot.
Look, he's been through hell. Ha-ha-ha.
As soon as he finishes
one more little detail...
...he'll be ready to join us.
Now I've done my part.
How about yours?
How we doing on your front?
COP 1:
Would all the authorized personnel....
Heat-16 is ready to go.
It better be. The army is ready.
The Spawn is ready.
The Heat-16 completes the picture.
Congratu-freaking-lations.
What's Simmons got to do with all this?
Oh, he's just the highest-scoring killer
of all time, that's all.
If we hadn't recruited him,
the other side would have.
I almost forgot again.
Memo from Brimstone Breath:
We're gonna rig
a fancy-schmancy device...
...that connects your heartbeat
to the Heat-16 bomb...
...so if your heart stops ticking,
the bomb goes off.
We don't want any smart-ass fruitcake
taking you out ahead of schedule.
Sort of an insurance policy from hell,
the good hands people.
That's a good idea. l like that.
I want your special attention
dealing with Spawn.
-You hear me?
-Gladly.
Good. Now stay sharp.
The night is young.
-Ladies.
WOMAN 1: Ooh.
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
WOMAN 2: Ooh. Clowny.
-Oh, yes.
Have you ever ridden
a clown's pink pony?
Well, I think it's about time.
WOMAN 1:
Ride them, cowboy.
CLOWN:
Oh, it's all good, baby. It's all good.
When all the world is mine...
... I will personally fry your lard-ass.
As you've seen, the terrible
North Korean biochemical disaster...
...unleashed a whole host
of new diseases.
Ten thousand people died in the first month
after the disaster five years ago.
Since then, millions of people
have contracted these fatal diseases:
Diphtheria, cholera, smallpox.
Diseases that had been
virtually wiped out....
Thought I was getting rid
of the world's vermin.
And I turn out to be one of them.
WANDA:
--with outbreaks around the world.
And the number of sick and dying children
continues to grow.
It's up to us to put an end
to the suffering of these innocent children.
CYAN:
Spaz! Ah! Ow.
[DOG WHIMPERING]
What happened to you?
CYAN:
I was playing with Spaz and I fell down.
SPAWN:
You all right?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Wow, your face is weird.
Heh.
Cool.
What's your name?
Spawn.
I'm Cyan.
You have your mother's eyes.
I knew her...
...a long time ago.
Let's get you back to your mother.
CLOWN:
My, my, my.
What a pretty little dress.
I wonder if she's got it in my size?
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
Spawny, Spawny, he's our man
If he can't kill them, no one can
Yay, Spawny!
S to the P to the A to the "awn"
Go, Spawny! Go, Spawny!
MALEBOLGIA:
You fool!
I put you on earth...
...to make sure Spawn
keeps his end of the bargain.
CLOWN: Why'd you pick him
to lead the army anyway?
What are you thinking?
It should be me. It should be me.
I had the tenure.
It's not fair! lt's not fair! lt's not--!
And that's exactly the kind of talk
we don't tolerate around here, right, boss?
MALEBOLGIA:
Enough!
Spawn must choose to murder Wynn
and release the virus.
Then my army will be complete.
Now, now, boss--
This is your last chance.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you, thank--
Excuse me.
Cyan!
Cya-- Honey,
didn't l tell you not to leave my side?
I was playing with Spaz and I fell down...
...and Spawn came and helped me.
You're not supposed to talk
to strangers either.
Spawn's not a stranger, Mommy.
Wanda.
-We're going home right now.
WANDA: What's going on? Terry.
Terry, what is going on?
-I'll explain later.
-Explain now.
I am not going through this again.
No secrets.
There was trouble at the reception.
Wynn was attacked.
I don't wanna take any chances.
Trust me.
Okay.
WOMAN:
No problem. Are you parked up here?
Go home.
[WHIMPERS]
TERRY:
Fix your seat belt, honey.
What the hell is going on?
Daddy, what about Spaz?
WANDA: What's happening?
-Spaz?
[WHIMPERS]
-Spaz!
-Go home, Spaz.
TERRY:
Spazzy! Spaz!
Honey, he knows the way back home
better than we do.
-Okay?
-Okay.
WANDA:
Let's go, Terry.
You don't wanna be where I'm going.
[BARKING]
Okay, but it's your funeral.
[SQUEALING]
[COUGHING AND GAGGING]
Hey, what the hell are you doing?
-Puking up decent food, boy?
-It's rotten.
Tastes fine to me. Think we eat so good,
you can just spit up what you like, huh?
-No.
-Now, don't talk back to me.
Eat this.
[SCREAMS]
No, don't! He's my dad.
MAN 1:
He's crazy. He's crazy.
MAN 2:
Keep away from him.
DOCTOR:
BP and heart rate?
NURSE 1:
One-thirty-four over 77, heart rate, 60.
DOCTOR:
Let's increase the flow to 3.5.
-Twenty-three gauge IU cap, please.
NURSE 2: Yes, doctor.
DOCTOR:
We're ready for the monitor.
[BEEPING]
DOCTOR: I'm gonna make a small incision
so that we can insert this heart monitor.
Now, you're going to feel a slight pinch.
[CLICKING AND WYNN GRUNTS]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[GUN COCKS]
Whoa, awesome hardware.
What are you gonna do with it?
Throw someone a going-away party.
You need any help?
Listen, kid...
... I'm not looking to make friends.
Hey.
-What's your name?
-Zack.
I'm Al.
That's Spaz.
[DOG BARKS]
ZACK:
Hi, Spaz. Hey.
NURSE 1:
Breathe normally, director.
[BEEPING]
DOCTOR:
The system is now operational.
As per your orders, director...
...if your vital signs flatline
for any reason...
...the device will uplink
and detonate the Heat-16 bombs.
No one would dare kill you.
Good work, doc.
CLOWN:
What a double-cross.
First l got Wynn to kill Spawn
and create the Heat-16 bomb.
Now l get Spawn to murder Wynn
and release the virus. Ha-ha-ha.
If all goes well, it should hurt like hell.
I can't believe I actually got Wynn
to get operated.
What a maroon.
It's gonna send the earth into a tailspin
of death and destruction.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
It's time.
You know, sometimes I wake up at night
down in the alley and wonder.
Is this hell?
Not yet.
But soon. Ha-ha-ha.
Heads up.
[SPITS AND WOMAN GRUNTS]
Got one. Ha-ha-ha.
So who's your new friend, Spawn?
-Get out of here, Zack.
ZACK: But--
Go!
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
CLOWN:
Miss me?
Here's Clowny. Ha!
So it was you who told Wynn to kill me.
Guilty as charged. Ha-ha-ha.
Before l blow your fat circus ass away...
... I wanna know why you picked me
to lead your war.
Well, well, if it isn't Curious Crispy.
Well, the evil has been there ever since
you were soup in your mama's crotch.
Your DNA spelled DOA.
We just nursed it along.
All those assassin missions
were just training for what's coming.
Now, let's get down to business.
Wynn has finally got that Heat-16
virus bomb working.
Made especially for you. Get things started
with a big, wet, infectious kaboom.
And all you have to do
is just lead us to the holy land...
...so we can burn it down. Ha-ha-ha.
You filthy little piece of vermin.
What makes you think
I would join your army?
You can take this army of yours
and shove it.
Sounds like a country song.
[SINGING]
You take that army of yours and shove it
You take that--
Oh-oh. You've got that "I wanna beat
the fat little man" look in your eye.
Ah!
I'm gonna cut you into 50 pieces
and mail you to every state.
I'm gonna take your intestines and--
I don't know how you put up
with all this crap.
You're a bigger fool than l thought
if you think you're gonna wreck my plans.
-You're gonna do just what you promised.
-Put down my dog.
Heh-heh-heh. Nice doggie.
Heel, fetch.
No, I got it.
[CLOWN CHUCKLES]
Play dead. Ha-ha-ha.
Ah!
So you wanna do it the hard way.
I warned you.
I'm just gonna have
to teach you a lesson.
No more clowning around.
I'm not the Vindicator or the Victimizer...
...or the Vaporizer or the Vibrator.
I'm the Violator!
Argh!
[ROARING]
[GROWLING]
[BARKING]
[GROWLS]
[DOG WHIMPERING]
MAN 1:
Good Lord.
WOMAN:
Run!
[GROWLING]
MAN 2:
I'm not staying around for this.
[GROWLING]
[VIOLATOR GROWLING]
MAN 3:
Let's move out, yeah.
[VIOLATOR GROWLING]
[GROWLING]
GLEN:
Get back!
[GLEN GRUNTING]
[GLEN SCREAMING]
No.
MAN 4: Got him.
MAN 5: Whoa, hey, hey!
MAN 6:
No, stay out here!
-Damn alley ain't safe no more.
-Oh, my God.
Okay, okay, okay. We're going.
[VIOLATOR GROWLING]
[DOG WHIMPERS]
[GROWLING]
MAN 7: You think?
MAN 8: Go, man.
[VIOLATOR GROWLING]
SPAWN:
Unh!
Ah! Unh!
[ROARS]
[SCREAMING]
Violator, 1, Spawny-boy, zero.
[GRUNTING]
[HUMMING]
[GRUNTS]
[LAUGHS]
You've been violated, girlie-man, huh?
I could have killed you like that.
Is that a little more surprise
than you wanted? Ha-ha-ha.
Twinkle, twinkle, little Spawn
Gosh, you look like crap
Go fertilize my lawn
Ha-ha-ha. What, you're not excited yet?
Helter-skelter is coming down
with or without you.
Either you lead the army
or Wynn plays Pin the Tail on Wanda.
"Hey, Wanda, how about giving me
some of that sweet stuff, baby?"
[IN FEMALE VOICE]
"Oh, no.
Oh, please, Wynn, don't.
Please. Somebody help me. No."
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Forget Terry.
It's my turn to ride
the Wanda carousel of love.
[GRUNTING]
You stay away from her.
Your choice.
See you at Wanda's. Last one there
gets her rotten eggs. Ha-ha-ha.
Wynn and Wanda sitting in a tree
S-U-C-K-l-N-G
First comes love, then comes marriage
Then comes the monster in a baby carriage
COGLIOSTRO: It seems the truth
has taken its toll on you.
I'm gonna kill that asshole.
You still haven't learned.
Argh!
[GROANS]
[COMPUTER BLEEPS]
COMPUTER:
Clearance granted.
[BLEEPING]
Downloading secure files.
Yes.
Gotcha, Jason.
I can't afford to be wrong.
Still with us, I see.
[CHATTER OVER EMT RADIO]
EMT 1: All right, move out of the way.
Let's move here.
Your vengeance...
...their pain.
Wynn, Wanda,
none of this is worth the cost.
Those are the only things
that matter to me now.
Al Simmons is dead.
Let him go.
I am Simmons, old man.
EMT 2:
Get up there.
COGLIOSTRO:
You're Spawn now.
But that doesn't mean
you have to be what they want.
You're still letting them get to you.
Your anger is your weakness.
And they'll use it to rob you
of any humanity you have left.
Simmons knew that violence
only makes for more pain and suffering.
No matter which side gives the orders.
He tried to leave off killing,
give himself a second chance.
Your old life is gone. Accept that.
I still love Wanda.
Put her in the past.
It's the only way you can be free.
She's the only reason I'm here.
The war between heaven and hell
depends on the choices we make.
And those choices require sacrifice.
That's the test.
Hey.
I didn't know this was gonna happen.
I'm gonna nail that scumbag.
Kiss it goodbye, Clown.
This is just what they want.
You're playing their game.
Then I'll play dirty.
-Guns are useless.
-You got a better idea?
I might.
[GRUNTS]
COGLIOSTRO: You see, you've been using
your armor only by reflex.
You must learn to control it.
It has trillions of neuroconnections...
...that are living extension
of your own instincts...
...instantly translating your thought
into physical reality...
...so long as you stay clear and focused.
-So that's how it works.
-Yes.
ZACK: Cool.
-Now try your chains.
[GRUNTS]
COGLIOSTRO:
You must visualize your objective.
The armor does the rest.
All right, Yoda. Just wait a second.
You ready?
All right, go!
Not bad.
Don't get cocky.
You have a lot more to learn.
Your cape has its own powers.
SPAWN:
I have to get to Wanda's, old man.
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
MAN 1:
Right there!
Take care of your powers.
When you drain them, you die.
Won't be needing these.
You're catching on.
SPAWN:
Or this.
WOMAN: Well, this is him.
MAN 2: Tell him, then.
WOMAN:
Just the money. That's all.
I want you to return Spaz to me.
No matter how you find him.
Understand?
[MOTORCYCLE REVVING]
MAN 3: Hey! Help!
MAN 4: Hey! Come back!
-Get back here!
-Now...
...the final test.
[TRUCK HORN HONKING]
Hey, hey, hey, get out of my way.
I'm gonna get Spawn so worked up,
he'll kill Wynn without blinking.
When I'm done with you,
they're gonna change your name to Stain.
Huh?
Look, Ma, no hands.
[WHOOPING]
I love the smell of burning asphalt
in the morning.
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
Send a boy to do a clown's job,
will they?
It's an honor to be a Hellspawn,
you hear me?
Hey, that's not fair!
Time for some necro-goo.
Open wide and say "ah."
Whew.
[CHUCKLING]
See you at Wanda's. Ha-ha-ha.
[COMPUTER BLEEPING]
COMPUTER:
Reading secure files.
Christ.
Wynn is out of his mind.
Wanda.
I'm thirsty.
[SIGHS]
Okay, baby.
You want some water?
COMPUTER:
Establishing connection.
NATALIE:
What have you got?
Black bag ops, assassination lists.
Everything. Wynn's been using A-6
to run some sort of criminal consortium.
He's got some biological weapon,
calls it Heat-16.
And it's all there?
I wanna get it on tonight's news.
I'm e-mailing you a copy right now.
It should be enough to bury Wynn.
-Let me know if it gets through.
-Great.
Daddy?
Hey, sweetheart.
What are you doing here?
Some unfinished business.
[EXPLOSION ON COMPUTER]
You disappoint me, Terry.
You can't release the virus.
Millions of people will die.
Only those who refuse to join me.
-Hey.
-You're a very lucky man, Terrence.
Whatever it is you want,
just take it and go.
I intend to.
[THUMP OUTSIDE]
[DOOR BELL RINGING]
Let's go.
WYNN:
On the floor.
The kid stays with me.
Answer the door.
Go on.
It's all right, sweetheart.
Peekaboo, l see you. Ha-ha-ha.
You know how hard this place
is to find in the dark?
I smell you're not wearing any panties.
Oh, hello, Cyan. Remember me?
Booga-booga-booga!
You were at my birthday party.
No duh. What are you, a regular Einstein?
You sure know how to raise them, don't you?
-What are you doing?
-Don't you touch her.
Back off, hero.
I'm back by popular demand.
Big as life and twice as rotten.
[SINGING OPERA]
[CLOWN GRUNTS]
Does wonders for my asthma.
[WHEEZING]
Where's Spawn?
Let's cut the crap.
Spawn's on his way. You ready to play?
Of course I am.
You better be.
[CHUCKLES]
[HEART BEATING
AND DEVICE BLEEPING]
You don't know how much
your heart means to me.
Boo!
[CLOWN LAUGHS]
Come on. Bring them, Jerky.
Come on.
[LAUGHS]
-Wanda.
-Help me, please.
WYNN:
Uh-uh-uh. Careful.
Don't make me nervous.
I might nick something vital.
-Get away from her.
-I can't do that.
She wants me.
You touch her, and you die slow.
All right, Spawn.
No more fun and games.
Either you join hell's army or she dies.
-After I'm done.
-I will rip your heart out! Let her go!
So, what's it gonna be?
Time is running out.
[MAKES BUZZER NOISE]
-Too late.
-Ah!
No!
[WANDA SCREAMS]
[SOBBING]
No!
It's all your fault, Spawn.
She was doing fine till you showed up.
Now you've got nothing left to lose.
You're a soulless corpse.
Nothing!
You're wrong.
I've still got you.
Cyan.
Don't be afraid.
[WYNN PANTING]
You can't kill me.
Is that right?
If my heart stops, then the virus is released
and everybody in the world dies.
Like you said...
... I've got nothing else to lose.
[SCREAMING]
That's right. Feel the burn.
Get used to it, because it's payback time.
See you in hell, Jason.
If you kill me, you kill her!
[HEART BEATING]
I'm through doing hell's dirty work.
You worthless bag of-- Ah!
How could you let him kill me?
Me, the most important thing
in your entire freaking universe!
Whatever happened to love,
honor, respect?
You pansy bacon crisp!
Ah! You should have killed him.
Popped his head like a zit.
Ooh. It feels so good.
And feel that butt. It feels so hairy.
Oops. Ha-ha-ha.
Okay, joke's over.
You should have killed Jason
when you had the chance.
-Never.
-Never?
What do you mean "never"? Never?
[GRUNTING]
Do you know how hard
I've been working on this?
You set me up, you malignant sow. Unh!
Why do you think
you got the pacemaker for, Jerky, huh?
Your perfect attendance record,
you spoon-sucking dipstick?
I was counting on Spawn killing you.
Then you would get his soul
and kick-start the Apocalypse now.
I say destroy the cosmos,
ask questions later.
But first....
First, I'm gonna slaughter
each and every one of you.
And then I'm gonna have a little
crème de Wanda.
[CLOWN LAUGHING]
I'm gonna let you watch too.
Yummy-yum. Yummy.
Mmm.
Mmm. Tastes like chicken. Ha-ha-ha.
Ah! Cogliostro!
Bleh-bleh-bleh. Come and get me!
[WANDA MOANS]
COGLIOSTRO:
He'll be back.
Concentrate on healing.
Come on!
[SPAWN GRUNTING]
I may not be able to hold him off alone.
[LAUGHING]
CLOWN: Come on down to my world
and die, suckers! Ha-ha-ha.
[GROWLING]
All right, you overgrown gecko,
come and get your throat cut.
[ROARING]
[SCREAMING]
[VIOLATOR SCREAMS]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[ROARING]
MALEBOLGIA:
If you won't lead my army...
...then you must die.
[ALL SHOUTING]
SPAWN:
Never!
MALEBOLGIA:
Bring me Spawn's head.
[ALL SHOUTING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[DEMONS SHOUTING]
MALEBOLGIA:
You will never escape me.
[GROANING]
It's all right now, baby.
WANDA:
Come on.
-You all right?
SPAWN: They belong together.
There's no place for me here.
Maybe you're the one after all.
You were checking me out from the start,
weren't you?
I'm too old for this.
I'm not as quick as I used to be.
I've fought this war long enough.
It's time for someone to take over.
What if I sided with Clown?
I'd have killed you.
Right.
Spaz, hey.
[SPAWN CHUCKLES]
[DOG WHIMPERING]
ZACK: l followed him here.
-Thanks, kid.
ZACK:
Spaz.
[ZACK LAUGHING]
[DOG BARKING]
Daddy!
Hey, look out!
[WANDA SCREAMS]
[GROWLING]
[SPAWN GRUNTING]
Unh!
Use your armor!
Concentrate!
SPAWN:
Bite this!
[VIOLATOR SCREAMS]
COGLIOSTRO:
Cut off his head!
[VIOLATOR SCREAMS]
You're gonna pay for this.
It's not over yet.
I'll gum you to death.
I'll bite you.
[BARKS]
Hey, Wanda,
what do you think about a little head, huh?
This is your last chance to join up.
Think about it. Come on.
[GRUNTING]
You'll pay for this.
Give my regards to your boss.
Tell him he's next.
[GROANING]
CLOWN:
No, no, no.
I'm gonna die!
Not bad for a dead man.
Aw. Beginner's luck.
[REPORTERS CHATTERING]
COP: Move back.
MAN 1: What's your affiliation with Wynn?
NATALIE: Is it true that the documents
you've uncovered implicate Jason Wynn?
Yes, that's correct.
For the past five years...
... I unwittingly participated in Jason Wynn's
illegal manipulation of the A-6...
...to further his personal ambitions
for a worldwide power.
MAN 2: What caused you so long to respond?
WOMAN 1: Mr. Fitzgerald.
The Heat-16 bombs,
are they still a danger?
TERRY: The entire Heat-16 weapon system
has already been destroyed.
MAN 3: Just a couple of more questions.
WOMAN 2: This way.
Do you have any further comments?
Something l should've done
a long time ago.
The documents l release
to all media outlets...
...will take care of your questions.
Thank you.
NATALIE: Thank you.
Natalie Ford reporting live with CNN.
WOMAN 3: Mr. Fitzgerald.
MAN 4: Mr. Fitzgerald.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
COGLIOSTRO: Spawn has stopped
Malebolgia's plans to destroy the earth.
The choice has been made.
For now.
[RATS SQUEALING]
[English - US - SDH]