[RadioSignals ]
I'm sorry.
[ Sobbing ]
Sir, she's breaking out!
[ Men Coughing ]
- Go! Go!
- What are we looking for?
Come on!
Double quick!
She's gone over the fence!
[ Train Whistle Blows ]
Aah!
A couple of trains
came through here
around about the time
she escaped.
You think she could've
gotten this far
in that time?
Is she that fast?
She is that fast.
And this, too?
3.10.
$3.10?
Right.
Here's your change.
Thank you.
Can I help you?
The total's 17 95.
Here's your card.
Are you going to
buy those?
Watch your step.
Have a nice trip.
It's a brown tweed bag
with leather trim,
kind of like a duffel.
Do you see it anywhere?
Porter said he was going
to put it on the cart.
This is the cart,
but there's no bag.
Government authorities said
this was
the largest earthquake
to strike an urban area
in nearly 50--
He's riding
Green Lightnin'.
Whoa! That's
Shorty Kincaid.
Enjoy the view.
Excuse me.
We shouldn't be
seen together.
Father hasn't been dead
more than 48 hours.
Do you think
Arlen suspects?
No. It's not
too soon for us
to be together.
Good.
[ Knock On Door ]
Tickets, please.
Ooh, are you traveling
by yourself?
What, you're 12?
Someone going to meet you
in Los Angeles?
We'll say that you're 11.
That way you only
have to pay half price.
Can't believe
our little girl did this.
She's not
a little girl.
DNA typing and material
found in those wounds
proves it was her.
Well,
she could be anywhere--
Chicago, Las Vegas,
Los Angeles, anywhere.
We should stop
all the trains.
And have the railroad
and local police
ask a million questions
we can't answer?
We'll put key personnel
at every stop
along these lines.
I want a team to track her,
hunt her down.
Good morning, Jill.
Hello.
Thank you for taking care
of my cat.
We'll take very good care
of you, won't we, Lorca?
I won't be gone
for very long.
Take care of yourself.
Bye-bye.
Are you still having problems
with the people at work?
They'll point the finger at me,
saying...
I'm the weird one.
I'm the strange one.
Why, because
I have feelings?
Because I feel?
There's someone
at the door.
[ Knock On Door ]
I won't answer that.
Whoever it is,
they can come back
at the end of the hour.
That's for me.
Sorry I have to
interrupt.
We need
your help, Dan.
I know.
Uh...
got to go.
Oh, God.
Aah!
[ Screaming ]
Ow!
Mr. Fitch
will be with you all
in just a moment.
Well, I guess
we all must be here
for the same reason...
whatever that is.
I'm Dan Smithson.
And I don't know why
I'm here, either,
but they said
they needed me
and that it was very important,
so I came.
What do you do, Dan?
I...
I'm an empath.
Sometimes they
show me awful things
that people have done,
and then I try to tell them
why they did it.
What qualifies you
for that?
I feel things deeply,
that's all.
What am I feeling
right now?
You want to believe
that nothing affects you,
that...
you're not afraid
of anything,
but you're curious,
just like
the rest of us.
Ahem. Steven Arden,
Harvard anthropology
department--
expert in
cross-cultural behavior.
Laura Baker. Hi.
Molecular biologist. Hi.
And who are you,
and what do you do?
Preston Lennox...
and if I'm here,
I think the shit
has definitely hit the fan.
What exactly
is your area of specialty?
Let's just say
I'm a freelance solution
to some of our
government's problems.
And what exactly
might they be?
The kind that people
don't usually like to talk about.
You hunt people,
don't you?
I guess so.
[ Television Plays ]
You in here, honey?
It's a little late for TV.
Aah!
Good evening.
I'm Xavier Fitch.
I'm in charge
of this operation.
Will you sit
a little closer, please?
In November of 197 4,
a small group from S.E.T.I.,
S-E-T-l--
Search for Extraterrestrial
lntelligence--
used the radio dishes
at Arecibo
to send out a message
to whoever
might be listening.
They sent about
a quarter of a kilobyte,
including structure
of human DNA,
map of our solar system,
population of the Earth,
helpful facts like that.
In January of 1993,
Arecibo received
a message back
from an extraterrestrial
unknown source.
That's great.
Intelligent life
beyond this planet.
Yes.
There were two distinct
communications.
The first message
turned out to be
a superior catalyst
for methane.
We now have the potential
to produce
an infinite amount of energy
from this
clean-burning fuel.
This convinced us
that we were dealing with
a friendly intelligence.
The second message
turned out to be
a new sequence of DNA
with rather friendly instructions
on how to combine it
with ours.
Here's some technical data.
You can get feedback on it
from Dr. Baker here.
Basically, the new combined
DNA sequence
was injected
into 100 human ova.
We got seven to divide--
four petered out,
two were stored
in liquid nitrogen,
and we allowed one to grow.
That's its
code name there-- Sil.
That's after two hours.
One day.
Two days.
- My God.
- This growth is amazing.
That's a week.
It's a girl.
Yes, l...
We decided to make it female
so it would be more
docile and controllable.
More docile and
controllable, huh?
I guess you guys
don't get out much.
That's her one month
after she was born.
So you kept her
caged...in there.
We decided it would be safer
to keep her in isolation.
She didn't like
being locked up like that.
being alone.
Didn't she?
She's hiding something,
something inside.
You're right, Dan.
This is three months
after she was born,
and you watch carefully.
Aah!
What the hell was that?
Back the tape up.
Watch her eyes.
Rapid eye movement.
She's dreaming.
Aah!
She's having
horrible nightmares.
It's some kind
of anxiety reaction.
Got me a little anxious.
It made the research team
a little anxious, too,
so the decision was made
to terminate the experiment,
to run more research
so that we could determine
what we were dealing with.
You were going to gas her?
That was the decision.
It makes you feel bad.
It makes you feel bad
you had to kill her.
I don't know.
Wow.
Yes.
Yesterday morning the body
of a transient was found
in a boxcar on a siding
near Salt Lake City.
Preliminary
DNA tests conclude
he was killed
by our creation,
by our Sil.
Have you found
other bodies?
No, we haven't. Not yet.
You will.
She's a predator.
Her eyes are in front.
Her eyes are in front
so she can judge the distance
to her prey.
That's right.
Where did you learn that fact?
I saw it on a documentary
on the Discovery Channel.
I caught that show myself.
Mr. Lennox.
Y eah.
As the, um...
well, the nonscientist
amongst us,
are you at all clear
about what's going on here?
Well, I think so.
You created a monster
with some kind
of formula you got
from outer space,
the damn thing got away,
and now you want us
to hunt it down and kill it.
Is that pretty close?
I guess.
Wait a minute.
You don't want us
to capture her alive
so that we can study her?
Laura, I think
this is strictly
a search-and-destroy
operation.
Nobody ever asked me
to find anything
they didn't want dead.
I'm sorry for you.
Y eah, well...
thank you, Dan.
I'm sorry for her.
Ladies and gentlemen,
may I have
your attention, please?
Welcome to Los Angeles,
California.
This is the terminal stop
for the Desert Star.
All passengers
please disembark.
[ Crying ]
This is
the final boarding call
for train number 12,
the Coast Runner,
to Santa Barbara,
San Jose,
San Francisco, Eugene,
and Seattle.
Something bad
happened here.
No shit.
Crushed her larynx.
She was afraid.
She's scared.
She's frightened.
Hungry, too,
by the looks of it.
She's been eating
like a horse.
Well, our girl
is definitely not on a diet.
She must be storing up calories
for something.
Any ideas?
Oh, my...
[ Coughs ]
Well, that's, uh...
that looks like
some sort of...
chrysalis.
Some kind of cocoon.
What are we looking for,
a giant moth?
Uh...if that is
a cocoon,
she'll be
fully grown now.
Fully grown.
Maybe that's how
she got by our people.
They were looking
for a child.
She is a child.
It stinks in here.
I'm going outside.
Get the conductor's l.D. and
credit card numbers on your computer.
There's no sign of them
on the train.
Let's assume
she took them with her.
I'll see to that.
She kills
if she feels threatened,
and she has no remorse
about it. None.
[ Arden ]
Of course, Los Angeles
is perfect for her.
It's a city of the future.
Anything goes.
Totally mobile population.
Everyone's a stranger.
Very little in this town
is taboo
or unacceptable.
Whatever she does,
no one's going to notice.
Y eah, well, whatever.
So Los Angeles is where
the battle's
going to be fought...
and won.
You look very pretty.
Do you have a hundred?
Here we are.
You ought to be more careful
with your money.
Not everybody's
as honest as me.
Are you foreign?
Do you speak English?
Yes.
Here. You keep this.
Oh, here.
Let me take this.
Be careful here.
Yes.
Watch your step.
Our laboratory, Visitor Base One,
is being moved
to some empty virus research labs
at the university.
They're moving our equipment
as we speak.
It'll be operational
by 8:00.
Check into your rooms.
Everyone out front
in 15 minutes.
We'll go on over.
What exactly are we
going to do?
Process the evidence
we collected on the train.
Couldn't we try
growing this creature
with just its own DNA--
we make up a version
without including ours
this time
so we can investigate
its vulnerabilities?
That would be good.
Like to know
how it feels.
This human life form
could be a mask.
If we could see it
without the camouflage...
Then we'd know what
we were dealing with.
[ Honks Horn ]
Couple of bozos
just ran out.
I got a customer.
Call you back.
Y es, young lady,
can I help you?
I want a room.
62, including tax.
That should just about cover
the honeymoon suite.
[ Television Turns On ]
Hi. Come here often?
What's your sign?
Tired of brunette?
Change. Change the color
of your hair.
Color-tress.
O.K., I've just increased
the magnification.
When I pierce the cell,
the foreign DNA
will be introduced.
Shit.
The camera's just gone down.
Um...excuse me.
Do you have
a replacement camera?
We have
a standby camera,
but it'll take time
for the technician to replace it.
This happens all the time.
It's a simple operation
to replace it.
Are you saying
you can do it?
Well, yeah,
sure, I can.
I just need somebody
to give me a hand.
I don't want technicians in there.
This is classified.
I'll do it.
A man of action.
I like that.
That's me.
Can you get that one
for me?
All right.
Give me the camera.
Something's--
Something's wrong.
Christ,
it's started already.
It's started already.
Get the top back on.
What?
Here you go.
Must have
penetrated the cell
before the camera went down.
What was that?
He dropped the bolt.
Find the bolt.
Get the top back on.
I'm looking, Fitch.
Can they hear me in there?
Laura, Press,
get the top back on.
Then I'm going
to let you out.
I think it fell
through the grate.
Can you lift up the grate?
It's not
going to work.
This isn't
going anywhere.
Press, you got
to get the bolt out
from under the grate.
Can't get to it.
The floor's welded down.
Oh, my God. Press...
Oh, my God!
I've never seen
anything like this.
I can't let them
out of the room.
Press, look.
Come on.
Fitch, let us
out of here!
Open the goddamn door!
Can't let you out till
I know what's in there.
You got to let them out.
Open the fuckin' door!
Let us out!
Tell me it's going to
stop growing, Dan.
Let them out!
Open up the door!
Press! Press!
What the fuck is that?
Laura, get to the other door!
Let her out, Fitch!
Can't let her out, Press.
I can't do that.
You motherfucker!
What's wrong with you?
I can't hold it.
It's breaking out.
Let her out, Fitch!
I'm going to burn it!
Get out of the way!
What is this thing?
If you can't destroy it,
I'll burn the room.
I have to burn
the whole room.
You got two minutes
to kill the thing.
Disconnect the gas line.
Use it as a flamethrower.
Past the table!
It's under the table!
Aah!
Laura, watch out!
Where did it go?
It's in the pipe.
Open the door!
Shut up, Dan!
One minute remaining.
Laura, it stopped moving.
Think I killed it.
It's dead. Open the door.
It's dead, Fitch.
Let them out.
Oh, God.
It's not dead.
What are we
going to do?
30 seconds remaining.
There's not much time.
Open the door!
You got to
let them out.
It might escape.
I have to follow protocol.
What protocol?
You didn't tell them that
before they went in there.
Fitch, let them out.
Fitch, let them out!
I have to follow protocol.
Let them out, Fitch!
Go! Get out of there!
3...2...1.
I hope you realize
I had no choice,
but the protocol's
to burn the room in two minutes
if anything went wrong.
Attention all cars.
Unit 4
should pick him up first
unless he changes course.
Call Unit 4
if you make contact.
Where's a good place
to find a man?
There's plenty of guys
at the ld
around the corner.
You won't have any trouble
meeting somebody there.
Thank you.
Can't miss it.
Just look for the long line.
Hey, I need
your credit card
for room incidentals--
Iong-distance calls,
damage to the room, so forth.
Credit card?
Zip-zap?
Plastic--
American Express,
Visa, MasterCard?
There you go.
Thanks. All right.
Thank you.
Oh, hey,
wait a minute.
Hey! Hey!
You don't want this
falling into
the wrong hands.
No.
Here's Justin Crawl.
Holds it in.
[ Telephone Rings ]
18:.42 left to go here.
Yeah.
The conductor's
stolen credit card has turned up
at a motel in Hollywood.
The van's out front.
Let's go.
You two.
Enjoy yourself.
You, legs,
you're in.
Go on.
I'm down on my knees
I'm beggin' you, please
Hey, hey,
where are you from?
I'm foreign.
You're what?
Foreign, really?
Easy. Easy.
I've got a party to go to
and no one to take me.
I'll take you.
You will?
Yeah.
I'm going to go to
the little girls' room.
You wait right here.
I'll be right back.
I'll be right here.
What's his name,
Greg or something?
Whatever it takes, right?
Hey, all's fair
in love and war.
Buddy.
Aah!
Can't see much on that.
Get this tape back
to the lab. Enhance it.
Let's see if we can get
a better look at her.
She looks nice.
Do you have any idea
where she went?
I'll find her.
Wanted to know
where she could meet a man.
I suggested a club called the ld
around the corner.
Get the tape.
I've got a party to go to
and no one to take me.
Where is this party?
I don't know.
Aah!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You can't park there.
Back that up.
You can't go in there.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What's going on here?
Nobody leaves the club,
and I mean nobody.
There's always
some action
in this part of town.
[ Car Stereo Plays ]
Blue-eyed blonde,
black leggings, pink sweater,
5'10' tall.
Who did she leave with?
Blue-eyed blonde
leaves with a guy,
it's hardly news
around here.
Name the top attractions.
The regulars, no losers.
We should assume
he's socially adept.
We're looking for a friendly guy,
not an asshole.
Robbie left
with a blonde.
That's him.
Let me show you
the rest of the house.
I'm still sweaty
from that place.
So crowded.
[ Music Plays ]
Like it?
Y es.
I feel like a shower.
You want one?
Tell you what.
I'm going to take one.
Want to get in
and take one later?
No problem.
Take off your clothes.
I want to see you.
Very nice.
Can you drive me back?
What are you
talking about?
You knew what
we came here for.
I've changed my mind.
All right.
You said no.
It's duly noted.
Come here.
I said I want to go.
Too late.
You're not leaving.
I said you're not leaving.
All right.
That's better.
[ Shower Running ]
What's happening?
Kills a girl at the club,
kills this guy.
Well, I'd say she fits
the classic definition
of a psychopath.
She's got nothing
to inhibit her--
no moral sense,
no social structure.
Well, she wasn't exactly smothered
with a mother's love
or taught good manners.
Know what I mean?
I asked
what was happening.
He did something to her.
She was angry.
She'll kill
if she feels threatened.
She'll kill anyone
that gets in her way.
Gets in her way of what?
Her life cycle. I think
she's trying to mate...
reproduce.
So why did she
kill the girl
at the club?
Sexual competition.
She's pretty hard
on the competition.
Now she's managed to mate.
Doesn't look like
a successful mating to me.
He's still got his pants on.
- She's frustrated.
- Who isn't?
What is her problem?
He was here,
she was here.
Maybe she rejected him.
She probably has
some special kind of senses.
Rats can sense disease
or genetic damage
in their potential mates.
So we can test his body
for any
hereditary diseases,
any defects that would have
made him a loser, essentially.
Needles.
Maybe he was
some kind of a doper
or diabetic.
Either way would have
made him unacceptable.
Excuse me.
All right.
Insulin. Diabetic.
There you have it.
She could have
just walked out.
Why did she have to kill him?
I guess he pissed her off.
Some men don't like rejection.
They get insistent.
Put an APB out
on this guy's car.
We'll go back to the motel.
I want to check it out
thoroughly.
More docile and controllable,
huh, Fitch?
What do you think, Dan?
What do I think?
I think she'd want to be
alone right now.
I don't think
she's going to
want to come here
with all these cars
lined up out front.
You're assuming
she could find her way back.
She could.
What is it?
Maybe menstrual blood.
If she's menstruating,
she's definitely capable
of reproduction.
Y es, I know.
[ Starts Engine ]
[ Car Stereo Plays ]
[ Engine Sputtering ]
Into my life
Come and go with me
Come into my life
I got so much love
to show you
Come into my life
Boy, I adore you
[ Whistles ]
Shit!
Oh, Jesus.
Excuse me.
Call the paramedic!
Anybody got a phone?
If your homeward commute
takes you westbound on
the Santa Monica Freeway,
expect delays
for up to one hour.
The homeward drive
will be slow
for people heading
to Malibu.
The video enhancement
is not all that great.
How old do you think
she is? 20? 23?
Her reproductive system
should be fully developed.
Her biological clock
must be in hyperdrive.
She wants to have a baby.
If she manages
to have a child,
our problems
have just started.
If her offspring's male
and develops
at the same rate as Sil,
it could be capable
of reproduction in six months.
God knows how many females
it could impregnate.
Fitch.
You see, when a predatory species
is introduced
into a closed
ecological system,
the extinction of the weaker species
is inevitable.
They found
the murdered guy's BMW.
Ran out of gas
in Santa Monica.
And what is her name?
I don't know her name.
So who are you?
She didn't have
any l.D. on her.
Thought I'd come by
to make sure she's O.K.
You think
she's got insurance?
I don't know.
Put it on my credit card
for the time being.
And you don't know
her name.
Guys like you
are hard to find.
Get a lab workup
on that, stat.
Arrange to get her up
to X ray.
I want an X ray on this.
It looks like
a scapula fracture.
Respiratory technician to CCU.
Your sh--
Your shoulder.
What's going on here?
Doctor,
we need you immediately.
A child burn victim
just came in.
What is going on here?
Jesus Christ!
Did you see her shoulder?
Doctor, please.
We need you
immediately.
You're O.K.
I'm O.K.
Well, I was sure you
were seriously injured.
I'm O.K.
You are.
It's a miracle.
Can we go?
Did the doctor say
you could go?
Yes.
We'll send somebody
over there.
A report's come in.
A doctor over
at Parkbay Hospital
called in
with some weird story.
We should check it out.
Laura, Press, take a car.
Check it out.
Parkbay Hospital?
Y eah, Parkbay.
She walked.
She walked that way.
Not too long ago.
Got some fruit
and cheese here.
What is that?
What do you mean,
the hot tub?
Hot tub.
I love this place.
It's away from the traffic
and the business
and all the people.
Sometimes it feels like
you're not in L.A. anymore.
Here.
We'll immortalize
the moment.
Look at the camera.