(DJ OVER RADIO) What's going on? It's
Rickie, Melvin and Charlie on Kiss FM.
So, we promised
we'd play it for you earlier.
Let us know what you think
on the Kiss FM UK Facebook wall.
There's plenty more
new music to come.
We'll update you on what's happening
on the roads in about ten minutes.
(FEMALE DJ) Get your questions in
for this morning's guest.
If you've got something you wanna ask,
tweet @kissfmuk and get involved.
(DJ) Let's keep the Kiss tunes rolling.
This is for all on their way to college.
Turn it up and keep it Kiss.
(MAN) # Kiss #
(ROCK MUSIC OVER RADIO)
Mm-hm.
(CRASHING)
(RUMBLING)
(DOOR OPENS)
- What's going on?
- (JAKE) I think there was an earthquake.
Don't be stupid. Since when
do they have earthquakes in Battersea?
(SARAH) Oh, my God.
What?
- What? What is it?
- (SARAH) Must be a bomb.
(GREG)
Why would terrorists bomb here?
Makes more sense
than an earthquake.
(CAR ALARM BLARING IN DISTANCE)
Do you have a TV?
Shit.
That's my car.
Wait. It could be dangerous out there.
You've gotta be fucking kidding me.
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
(BEEPING)
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(EXPLOSION IN DISTANCE)
Oh, my God.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(DIALLING MOBILE PHONE)
Turn on the TV.
Nick, just do it. Just turn on the TV.
I think there's been a plane crash.
(BARKING)
No, no, no, here. I can see smoke
coming up from somewhere by the park.
Nick, just turn on the TV.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER RADIO)
Oh, shit. Foxy.
Foxy? Foxy, there you are.
Come on. Come here.
What the hell is that?
(FOXY BARKING)
Foxy. Come back. Foxy.
Foxy?
(FOXY PANTING)
Foxy, what is it?
(BARKING)
Foxy.
What is it?
(SHOUTS) Foxy!
- (SLICES)
- (DOG WHIMPERS)
Foxy.
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(HORNS HONKING)
(INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
(OVER RADIO)
# You can look but don't touch desire
(MAKING POPPING SOUNDS)
# Your dreams are dust at dawn
# And now you've got
what you've been longing for
# You don't want it anymore
# But this time
# This time
I cleared the dishwasher Iast night
so your favourite mug's
in the top cupboard on the Ieft.
Great, thanks.
# But this time
you've gone across that line #
You don't know any reason
she might have done this to me, do you?
I'm sorry.
- I just can't believe she did this to me.
- Forget her, yeah?
I mean, you're probably better off
being on your own for a while.
You're never on your own.
You're always either with her or with me.
Yeah.
(CHARLIE SIGHS)
(COUGHS)
Would you mind putting
your window down? It's wafting fumes.
(WINDOW WHIRRS)
I've Iost my deposit. You know that?
Yeah. You've only told me
about 50 times.
Look, Charlie, relationships end. People
change. You can't blame yourself.
You must be the only person
who still uses matches.
They're handy.
If you wanna
burn down a house, maybe.
Hey, and you know what? You know,
I don't blame myself. I blame her.
- I didn't change. I Iook Iike I changed?
- No, you haven't, Charlie. No.
No.
(REPORTER OVER RADIO)
Britain is on high alert...
I'm still the same guy. I'm still Ioveable,
do-it-all-for-his-friends Charlie, so...
At this stage it's not clear
what has happened,
but reports tell there has been a plane
crash near Hyde Park in central London.
We haven't been made aware
of the size of the aircraft...
You hearing this?
- May have been a military cargo plane.
- I just don't get what I did.
A fucking plane has crashed
in the centre of London. PIease!
--attack or hijack,
claiming probable engine fault.
There's someone else.
There has to be someone else.
--alleging that the plane was shot down.
A quarantine around central London
is in effect, we've been told to expect...
Why do these things always happen
when you're trying to get somewhere?
Oh, Iook at this. For the Iove of Chr...
(HONKS)
Man.
Try it now.
(BEEPS)
- Still nothing.
- (SARAH) Oh, you're kidding me.
They're supposed to keep people out,
not in, for fuck's sake.
You couldn't get a better demonstration
of how good the security is. Heh.
(SARAH SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
(BOB) I'II try something else.
You know, something new.
Would you Iook at that?
There's a man's coat in here.
Is that Shelley's car?
- That's a man's jacket. A man's jacket!
- Calm down.
- Let me go.
- Not until you calm down.
I bought this car for us, Mark.
I bought this car.
Maybe that's why she dumped you.
(CHUCKLES)
Too soon, yeah? Sorry.
- You Iousy fucking...
- Charlie! Charlie. Leave it out.
- Feel better?
- Yeah, a Iittle bit.
You're on my... You know.
- Oh, sorry. Sorry.
- Yeah.
(GROANS)
So, what if she's here.
You grin and get your stuff,
and then we're out. AII right?
- Come on, Iet's get it over with.
- Yeah. But if she says one word to me...
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
- Try it now.
- What's going on?
My guess would be the plane crash
has fucked with all the power
and phone Iines in the area.
It's messing up all the security system.
Keeps sending everything
into Iockdown.
There's no rush here (!)
You know, you guys just keep chatting.
I don't need to be anywhere.
Let's try this.
Ta-da.
Thank you.
- We're gonna be able to get out of here?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, don't worry about that.
Cheers for that, mate.
I thought she was gonna kill me.
No, no, no.
Brilliant.
You know what I gotta do now,
don't you?
Is reroute the alarm
to the emergency power system.
Otherwise you're gonna have this
all night. You'II be in a right pickle.
So, where's your basement, kid?
Which one is it?
You don't remember, do you?
(CLANGING)
(MARK) You won't start something
when you see Shelley?
- Of course I'm not.
- You are, aren't you?
Promise me you won't.
- Charlie.
- I promise.
(BOB) Cor.
Stinks, doesn't it?
(JAKE) Well, you Iet me know
if you need anything, yeah?
(BOB MUMBLING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hmm.
(BOB HUMS)
Eh.
Hello.
(CLATTERING)
Hello?
Someone down here?
Mm-hm.
(HUMS)
Hmm.
- What...?
- Easy, Granddad.
I could hear you upstairs.
I think you might be Iooking for that.
AII right?
Granddad?
(MUMBLES)
Here we go.
Ah. Let's have a Iook here.
(CLATTERING)
(ROCK MUSIC OVER RADIO)
(WOMEN CHATTERING)
- Why don't we just move in here?
- So, who gets the couch?
- Uh, I'm getting it.
- How do you know?
I chose it. Charlie doesn't have
anywhere to put it.
He doesn't Iike it anyway.
He has nowhere to put it
because you kicked him out.
Do you wanna start
bringing some stuff down?
No. I'm very happy
helping you up here.
'Cause you're really helping,
aren't you?
Well, hello. Who's this Iittle guy?
I Iike it, put it in there.
- That's the keep box.
SHELLEY: Yeah.
It's one of the first things
Charlie got me.
- Chris.
- It's cute. It's cute.
If someone had bought me this,
it wouldn't have taken me five years
to dump him.
(MUSIC STOPS)
- (WHISPERS) Shell.
- (MARK) I'II take that.
- (WHISPERS) Awkward.
- Yeah. Awkward, buddy, yeah.
- You might wanna mind your business.
- (MARK) Leave it, Charlie. Leave it.
- Yeah, don't stop on my account.
- Charlie, what are you doing here?
- What am I...?
- (SHELLEY) You shouldn't be here.
I Ieft a message
telling you what time I was coming.
So you wanted me to see
all of this, then, did you?
Charlie, what do you want?
I wanna know what happened to us.
That's what I want.
Charlie, now is not the time.
I don't care that everyone else is here.
I wanna know why we're splitting up.
I wanna know why we're standing here
with our stuff in boxes...
I meant, what do you want from storage?
(JAKE CHUCKLES)
What?
(JAKE) You are having a fucking Iaugh.
(MELANCHOLY ROCK MUSIC
OVER RADIO)
Stay.
Oh, you can't be...
(SIGHS)
I hate my Iife. I do.
Gotta get a new job.
This is just fucking ridiculous.
(WHISPERS)
Absolutely fucking ridiculous.
And I deal with absolute muppets.
Honestly.
Work in a storage warehouse.
What a ridiculous place to work.
Looking after people's stuff.
I mean, what...?
Are you done yet, mate?
I can't hear you.
What the fuck?
(GASPING)
(GROWLS)
(SCRAPING)
(BANGING)
(GROWLS)
What the fuck was that?
Probably just air settling
in the pipes or something.
- Charlie, you should go.
- (MARK) Maybe we should all Ieave.
- If the power's down, we should all go.
- It'II be back on.
It's been doing this all day
since that plane went down.
I just wanna get everything sorted.
- So you can get me out of your Iife?
- (SHELLEY) Yes, Charlie.
- So I can get you out of my Iife.
- Just fuck off.
- Hey, watch your mouth.
- (SHELLEY) Mark.
(MARK) Charlie, Iet's just Ieave.
- I don't know why we should...
- Let's Ieave. Get out. Come on. Leave.
- Bye-bye, then.
- Shut up, Chris, really.
Are you all right, sweetheart?
(MATCH STRIKES)
(CHARLIE)
Chris was Iucky I didn't give him a slap.
- You know that was Iucky, right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, it was Iucky.
The stairs are this way, are they?
Are you sure
you don't wanna just go home?
Yes. PIease, Iet's just go home.
No. You go. I just wanna stay
and get this done tonight.
AII right, then we're not going anywhere.
We'II stay and help, yeah?
I'm starving.
There's a vending machine
downstairs by the toilets.
Okay, Iook, I'm gonna go with him
because I need the Ioo.
- You wanna come?
- No.
- Bring me back some water, will you?
- Yeah.
What the hell happened here?
Any sign of the young fellow
who works here, no? Hello?
(VOICE ECHOES)
Hello?
(BEEPS)
(DIALLING TONE)
Line's dead.
Is the engineer's van still there?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, he must be over there.
(DIALLING MOBILE PHONE)
I've got no service. Have you?
Uh, I doubt that because my phone's
at the bottom of the river.
- Why?
- That's what happens
when someone dumps you
over the phone, Mark. Hello?
I don't know, maybe the transmitter
was taken out by the crash.
Well, I don't intend to spend my night
in here, I can tell you that much.
The engineer will be back
and then we'II all be sorted out and...
- What are you doing?
- Get out of the way.
- Charlie, come on.
Well, you definitely scratched it.
I mean, what were you gonna do
if you broke the glass?
There's a metal shutter outside.
Great. So what do we do now?
(CHRIS) He kept making me Iaugh.
(NIKKI) How?
Whingeing at her Iike that.
How will that do anything?
So bad. Great.
Will you get Shell a water for me?
- There isn't any.
- Make sure no one comes in, please.
- No one's coming. Hurry.
- Oh, my God.
What is that? Wh...?
Oh, you want some of me?
Pussy hole.
Yeah, that's right, Charlie.
Mmm.
Fuck.
Chris?
Chris, is that you?
Nikki, you almost done in there, babe?
Yeah, I'II just be a minute.
Chris, did someone come in here?
Hello?
(WATER RUNNING)
(CREAKING)
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
What the fuck was that?
(CLATTERING)
Hello?
Is there someone in here?
(GRUNTS)
Hello?
- We gotta get out of here, man.
- What the fuck are you doing in here?
No, you don't understand.
It's going to fucking kill us.
(CLATTERING)
He's coming.
(CREAKING)
(SCREAMING)
(KNOCKS)
Hi.
- What are you still doing here?
- Security shutters are down.
We're Iooking for the guy who works
here. Thought you might have seen him.
No.
Where's... Where's Nikki and prick-face?
They've gone to get a snack.
Oh, there's the Iamp
from when the time that...
(SHELLEY) Mm-hm.
Yeah.
Hm? What?
Hm. Just...
Charlie wants you
to go and Ieave us alone
so that we can talk about the
relationship that we don't have. Again.
No, I didn't say that. That's not
what I meant. I didn't say that.
But, Shelley,
if you wanna discuss it, we can...
Look I'II...
I'II Ieave you guys to it, yeah?
No. Mark, stay.
Charlie, it's over. Accept it, move on.
I can't keep having this conversation.
Just tell me what I did wrong.
Give me something.
(SHELLEY) Nothing.
Nothing. I just...
I just don't Iove you anymore.
I don't know how to
make it clearer to you.
You don't excite me.
You don't make me happy.
You don't make me anything.
Why won't you accept it?
- (CHARLIE) Shelley, Iet's just...
- Charlie, Charlie, Ieave her. AII right?
Let her calm down.
- Jeez.
- Look, I'II go talk to her. Yeah?
Yeah, thanks, man.
- AII right.
- Thank you.
(GATE RATTLES)
You all right?
I can't take it anymore, Mark.
He's getting on my Iast nerve.
- He's upset.
- Yeah, well, he's not going on
at anyone else all the time.
Why do I have to deal with this Iike
I'm the only one who's done anything?
- You don't.
- Really?
- Mark.
- Come here, get in.
Mark, stop.
When are you gonna
tell Charlie about us?
Not yet.
It'd kill him now if he found out.
You're gonna have to
tell him eventually.
I know.
Are you sure about us?
- You should go back to him.
- In a minute.
Not here.
(NIKKI) What are you doing here?
(CHARLIE) We're Iocked in.
I went down to find the guard
or receptionist, but I couldn't find him.
(NIKKI) Where is everyone?
- Charlie?
- What?
Where is everybody?
I told Shelley how I felt about her
so she had to get as far away
as humanly possible from me.
- And Mark's gone after her.
- Right.
- And Chris, has he come back yet?
- Do I Iook Iike I give a fuck?
Why do you have to
be such a dick, Charlie?
Hey, maybe that's why she Ieft you.
(SCREECHING)
(RATTLING)
(SCREECHING CONTINUES)
Wait here.
(CHARLIE) Mark? Mark?
(MARK) Charlie.
-You all right? Heard a scream.
-Yeah. You?
- Yeah.
- (CHARLIE) Where's Shelley?
She's fine. She's fine. I was, uh...
(NIKKI) Mark!
(SHELLEY) No, Charlie!
(NIKKI) Stop it. Stop.
(SHELLEY) Stop it, guys. Just Iet go.
- Charlie...
- No, don't touch me. Don't touch me.
I'm sorry, it just happened.
It just happened?
Well, how Iong's it been going on?
(MARK) Look, we didn't...
- Shut up.
Shut up, I'm not talking to you.
How Iong has it been going on?
When we were together? Since we
split up? I wanna know. Just tell me.
- It doesn't matter.
- Answer the fucking question.
Handy, yeah?
So just... Just...
Every time you took
one of your work trips to Brighton,
you were going to see him?
Hm?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
- Charlie, where are you going?
- Leave him.
CIassy.
Well, at Ieast he knows now.
I just wanna go home.
Charlie.
- Wait up.
- Yeah.
- Just...
- I didn't know.
You're her best friend
and you knew nothing about it?
Mark's your best friend
and you didn't know.
Well, where are you going?
The receptionist has gotta be
around here somewhere.
- I just wanna go home.
- Hey.
I'm sorry that they did that to you.
(FAINT WHINING)
- Charlie.
- What?
I just heard something.
Hello?
- There's nothing here. Let's go.
- No, wait. I just heard something.
- You didn't hear anything.
- (FAINT WHINING)
I did. There. Did you hear that?
Really?
(NIKKI) Chris. Chris?
Sweetheart, what's up?
Chris. What are you doing in here?
Chris, what are you doing?
He's being stupid. Come on.
No, he's not. Are you all right?
Babe, Iook at me.
Oh, my God.
It's all right. It's all right. I'm here.
What happened? Hon?
(CHARLIE SNAPPING FINGERS)
(CHARLIE) Chris?
- (NIKKI) Hey.
- Chris.
Are you OK?
Stop it.
Babe.
What the...?
(NIKKI) What happened?
Tell me what happened.
(CHARLIE)
Give me his phone. I need some Iight.
There's nothing up here.
(CHARLIE GASPS)
(WHEEZING)
(SHELLEY) Nikki?
Nikki, what's wrong? Where's Charlie?
He's in there.
What the fuck?
(MARK) What happened?
(SHELLEY) Chris.
The receptionist.
His face was ripped to pieces.
We are all going to die.
You think I don't know
who you're working for? Hm?
She sent you, didn't she?
I know she did.
(NIKKI) Guys, help!
I know your game, trying to creep up
on me. I've got eyes in the back of...
- (CHARLIE) What are you doing?
- You can't take me! Let go.
You send her a message from me.
You tell her
you can't get blood out of a stone.
(GROANS)
- Nikki, are you OK?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm OK.
I thought he was gonna kill me.
- (SHELLEY) Still breathing?
- Yeah.
But he's gonna have a hell of
a headache when he wakes up.
- What should we do with him?
- Kill him.
He killed the other guy,
was gonna kill me.
- Kill him.
- CIassy.
And what exactly was he gonna do,
Nikki? Brush you to death?
Let's tie him up.
- (DAVID GRUNTING)
- (MARK) Hey, hey, hey!
Who are you?
Let me go. No.
It's not as much fun
being on the other side of it, is it?
Why did you kill that guy?
Why?
- Who are you?
- Fuck you.
You might have found me,
but I'm not gonna tell you anything.
You tell that poison whore
to go fuck herself.
Which poison whore? Her?
(DAVID) My wife.
- Your wife?
- Who's your wife?
- Mary.
- (CHARLIE) Don't know her.
- That why you killed the receptionist?
- Kill?
- Yeah, you heard what she said. "Kill."
- But I didn't.
Well, I was just... See, I was just
coming downstairs to brush my teeth.
- What the hell are you talking about?
- (DAVID) Hm?
Well, I Iive here.
You Iive here?
My wife, she didn't send you?
- Why would your wife send us?
- She divorced me.
She's trying to bleed me dry,
you see, yes.
She's not gonna get another fucking
penny out of me. No fucking way.
I moved all my stuff in here.
I Iive here now.
She's never gonna find me. Never.
When she attacked me, you see,
I thought my wife had sent her.
- You seen anyone else here tonight?
- No, not a soul.
- He doesn't Iook Iike a killer.
- How many have you met?
It does explain the slippers
and the dressing gown.
Nothing explains that dressing gown.
Do you have to make a joke
out of everything?
- You don't tell me anything anymore.
- Can you shut...?
(CLANGING)
It's coming for us. It's coming for us.
We have to get out of here.
We have to...
(SHELLEY) What is it, Chris?
CIose the door.
Go.
I think it's gone.
(SCREAMS)
It's gonna kill us.
It's gonna fucking kill us all.
Shh! Shh! Shh! Shh!
(NIKKI) Chris!
(CREATURE SCREECHES)
(CREATURE CHITTERING)
(CHITTERING CONTINUES)
(ROARS)
(HEART BEATING)
(CREATURE GROWLS)
(ROARS)
- Won't be seeing him again.
- (SHELLEY) What are we gonna do?
- I just wanna get out of here.
- We can't
because the shutters are down.
My unit's the best bet.
It Iocks from the inside. In case...
In case your wife found you here.
We get it. We get it.
- This way. Down here. Stairwell and up.
- (CHARLIE) Great, further from the exit.
My unit's up on Ievel four.
We'II be safer up there.
Shit.
Where's the key?
- The key. The key's gone. Shit.
- Find it.
(RATTLING)
(CREATURE CHITTERING)
- (DAVID) Shit.
- Open the door.
- Come on. Open the door.
- I'm doing it. I'm doing it.
Come on!
(MARK) Come on.
It's coming.
(DAVID) The key is stuck.
(NIKKI) It's coming.
(CREATURE GROWLS)
Oh, fuck.
What the hell was that?
It came from the plane.
I'd put money on it.
I've been following it
on the news all afternoon.
You see? There's no way
that was a normal cargo plane.
They've Iocked down half of London.
Military everywhere. Snipers, the Iot.
(REPORTER ON TV) --another large
aircraft is heading for UK airspace
and has ignored
all known landing requests.
The MOD now have confirmed
fighter jets
have been scrambled
and are on an intercept mission.
In a surprising and alarming move,
tanks are on the streets of London.
They know there
was something onboard.
Something top secret.
Something classified.
Something Iike that fucking thing
out there.
Are we gonna Iisten to a guy who Iives
in a storage unit and is clearly crazy?
You think the government
hasn't known about this for years?
Hello, perhaps you're the one who's
deranged. Did you not see the fucker?
Hm?
Whatever it is, it's out there,
on the Ioose,
and it's not exactly trying
to make friends with us, is it?
Okay, Iet's imagine for one second
that what you're saying
is even remotely possible.
What do you think it wants?
To survive, perhaps? I don't know.
Fuck knows, I haven't got a clue.
I can't hear it anymore.
Think it's gone?
Maybe it's trying to find
another way in.
We need to get out of here
before it does.
(DAVID) The shutters are Iocked.
Even if we got out of here, we'd still
be trapped. Where would you go?
Wait. Remember...
Remember when we came in,
there was a guy outside, an engineer,
and he had that device and the shutters
were going up and down?
We find him, we find the device,
we can get out.
AII the power systems and wiring
are in the basement.
If the engineer wanted to override
the system, he'd go down there.
Well, there's no way
I'm going back out there.
Hm? Shit, he's right.
What we need are weapons.
- Have you got weapons?
- Hm? No.
But I do know where to find some.
(SHELLEY) Other units.
But that still means
we have to go out there.
Not out. Up.
Okay. What you need to do
is you need to get to the far end.
That's where all the Iarger units are.
That's where all the good stuff is.
Charlie. Look, about Shelley,
things Iike this just happen.
- She has ambition, you...
- Listen,
we may have to work together to get
out of here alive, but when this is over,
I never wanna see you again.
(CLANKING)
Charlie, I really think
that we have enough.
Charlie.
- (CREATURE SCREECHES)
- Shh!
(BANGING)
It's a dead end. It's a dead end!
Up. Up. Up, up.
Help me up.
Help me up. Help me.
Give me the bag. Give me the bag.
(CHARLIE) Shh! Shh! Shh!
(WHISPERS) Help me up. Okay.
(CHARLIE YELLS)
- Charlie, give me your hand.
- Mark.
(MARK) Charlie.
Mark!
Charlie, give me your hand!
Mark, help me up.
Mark.
(DAVID) Here they come.
(MARK) Here, quickly. Take it. Go on.
(DAVID) That's it.
(NIKKI) Hey.
(SHELLEY) Mark, what about Charlie?
- (MARK) He's gone. AII right?
- What do you mean, "he's gone"?
He's gone, Shelley!
He's gone. He's gone, he's gone.
There was nothing I could do.
I tried to save him. I tried to save him.
It ripped through the air vents
Iike they were paper.
We need to get out of here.
We need to Ieave. Here.
Take these. We need to go.
We need to go. Take it!
Here, Shelley, take the knife.
Take it. Take it. Come on.
AII right. We need to get out of here.
(DAVID) AII right.
AII right. AII right.
(BANGING)
(IMITATION GUNFIRE)
(DOLL) I love you.
(BEEPING AND WHIRRING)
(CREATURE GROWLING)
(TOY DOG YAPPING)
Charlie, I thought...
(CREATURE SCREECHING)
- It's coming.
- (DAVID) Come on.
Oh, dear.
(WHISPERS) Go.
Don't Iose track of the others, Charlie.
Go.
I'II be fine. I know what I'm doing.
(GROWLING)
Looks Iike it's just you and me, then.
Look at you.
You're vicious, aren't you?
Nothing but vicious.
You know, you're just Iike my wife.
Yes, you're Iike my Mary. Yes.
Mary. Mary.
(CREATURE SCREECHES)
Never did have a sense of humour,
did you?
(CHARLIE) It'II be down here.
(NIKKI) There is no way
that I'm going down there.
You wanna stay up here on your own?
Okay. You two go that way.
Nikki and I will go this way.
- (WHISPERS) Charlie.
- Shh.
Uh...
We found the engineer.
Well, most of him.
But the device won't be far.
You guys go back upstairs.
I can't see it, Nikki. Hold this.
- (NIKKI) Hurry up.
- Really?
Because I was enjoying
taking my time down here. Jesus.
It's not fucking here. Shit.
Charlie.
- Is that it?
- Yeah.
Charlie.
(NIKKI) Guys, we've got it.
Where's Shelley?
It took her.
There was nothing I could do.
- (NIKKI) No.
- We have to find her.
No, it's too Iate for that.
We have to get out or else we'II all die.
You can't save her.
She's already dead.
What, you think
she came Iooking for you?
At Ieast we can get outside
and call for help.
You always talk about me
never wanting to be on my own,
yeah, and always relying on you.
But it's you, isn't it?
You need me.
It's easy to be the cool one
around boring Charlie, right?
But you couldn't even get your own
girlfriend. You had to go and fuck mine.
Yeah, but she Ioved it.
(CHARLIE) Still doesn't mean I wanna
see her get hurt. And you know what?
I got nothing to Iose now,
so I'm gonna go and fight that thing.
And if I die, at Ieast I'II know
I died more of a man than you.
It's suicide, Charlie.
Suicide.
(CHARLIE OVER RADIO) Shelley.
Shelley.
(CREATURE ROARS)
- Charlie? Charlie, can you hear me?
- (CHARLIE) You're alive.
- (WHISPERS) Shelley, where are you?
- I'm in the lift.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah. I don't know where it's gone.
- I'm coming to get you.
- You might wanna hurry.
(CLANGING)
(CREATURE SCREECHES)
- (WHISPERS) What are you doing?
- (WHISPERS) What does it Iook Iike?
I'm saving your ass.
Have you got a Iight?
No.
(TOY DOG YAPPING)
(CHARLIE COUGHING)
(COUGHS)
- You OK?
- Yeah.
- Do you think we killed it?
- I don't know.
- I'm gonna go Iook for Shelley.
- Okay.
Hurry up.
(FIRECRACKER WHISTLES)
(WHISPERS) Shelley?
Shelley?
- (SHELLEY) Charlie?
- Shelley.
- You saved me.
- You sound surprised.
- Is it dead?
- I think so.
Okay, Iet's get the hell out of here.
(GROWLING)
(BEEPING)
Mark?
(SHELLEY) Mark. Mark.
Mark. Open the door.
(CHARLIE)
Open the door. What are you doing?
- Mark, open the door.
- (CHARLIE) Mark, what are you doing?
(SHELLEY) Mark.
Mark, open the door.
(CHARLIE) Mark, what are you doing?
Open... Open the door.
(SHELLEY) Mark! Mark!
(CHARLIE) Mark! Mark!
- Mark! Mark!
- (CHARLIE) Mark! Mark!
Mark, open the door!
Open the door! Mark!
Mark! Mark, open the door!
Come on, help me with this.
Help me move it.
(NIKKI) Where did it go?
- (CHARLIE) Give me the keypad.
- It won't work.
It will work.
(BEEPING)
(CHARLIE) We're getting out of here.
(MARK SCREAMS)
(MARK GROANING)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTING)
(NIKKI) Fuck you!
(YELLS)
Charlie.
(CREATURE SQUEALS)
I just want to go home.
Charlie, I'm really sorry for everything.
Do you want a Iift?
No, I think I'II walk. Thank you.
Charlie.
Did you break the windscreen wiper
off my car?
Yup.
(EXPLOSIONS IN DISTANCE)