(HEAVY BREATHING)
(EXHALES)
(MOBILE BEEPS)
Hey, it's me. Are you coming down?
(TAP RUNNING)
I know it's hard, Annie,
but we both have to deal with it.
What is that supposed to mean?
Yes. I'm being responsible.
Okay, well, somebody has to take care
of everything.
And we're her children for God's sake.
Hold on.
ANNIE ON PHONE:
I'm not going back to that house.
Annie, we're both supposed to be here.
Stop telling me what I'm supposed to do.
Jesus, you of all people.
What does that mean?
What do you think it means?
When was the last time you used, huh?
You know what? Fuck you,
that was more than four years ago
- before I was pregnant.
- Yeah, and fuck you, too.
So, now that you're clean, you just forgot
about what she used to do to us?
- You forgot how sick she was?
- (SIGHS)
You know what?
I'm just so crazy right now, okay?
I have Eva all on my own. I have work,
and now I have to deal with all this.
You know what, Nicole,
if you want to forgive her, fine. But I don't.
That's enough!
(BEEPS)
It's our mother's funeral.
Are you coming down or what?
(BIRDS CAWING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(WATER BOILING)
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
(FLICKERING)
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
(COMPUTER CHIMING)
- Hey, how are you?
- (CHUCKLES)
Hi. Hi, fine. Is Eva asleep? I wanted to say hi.
Oh, really? I... I just put her down.
I'm sorry. I'm on a neighbour's signal,
I might lose you.
Can you just go get her, please, now?
Okay. Okay, Okay-
- Hold on, I'll get her.
- Thanks.
(SIGHS)
LIZ: Hey, honey. Hey.
Hi, baby. Can you see Mommy?
- EVA: Mom?
- Shit.
Can you see Mommy, baby?
Baby? Can you hear me?
Shit. Sorry, Mommy said a bad word.
- Um, can you see me now, baby?
- No.
- Can you see Mommy?
- I can hear you, but I can't see you.
I just wanted to say how much I miss you.
I love you. I love you so much, okay?
I'm gonna see you in a couple days.
- Baby? Can you see me, baby?
- Yeah.
- Can you see Mommy?
Mommy, who's that behind you?
(GASPS)
(BEEPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(MOTORBIKE STARTS)
Nicole!
Hey! Nicole!
Voice mail.
(MOBILE BEEPS)
LIZ: Hey, Annie.
No one knows where Nicole is,
- so could you just call me?
- (MOBILE BEEPS)
Hey, Annie. It's Liz.
Could you call me right away?
(BEEPS)
Annie, I just... (SIGHS)
I'm really worried about Nicole.
I... I don't know where she is.
Please just call me, okay,
and we'll figure this out.
Oh, shit.
Call Liz.
(RINGING TONE)
(OVER VOICEMAIL) Hey, this is Liz.
Just leave a message,
and I'll call you back. Bye!
It's Annie. I just got to my mom's house.
I don't know where Nicole is.
You know what that means.
Um, just don't freak out.
She'll show up. She always does.
I'll try calling her. Bye.
(MOBILE BEEPS)
(ANNIE SIGHS)
Call Nicole.
(MOBILE RINGING)
(CONTINUES RINGING)
- (MOBILE BEEPS)
- (THUD)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- (CLATTERING)
- (GASPS)
- (BOTTLE ROLLING)
- Shit!
Nicole?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GLASS CRUNCHES)
Shit! (GROANS)
Shit.
(GROANING)
Mom.
LIZ: Annie.
Liz.
Hey.
- It's been awhile.
- Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
Um... Hey, there.
You must be Nicole's little girl.
It's nice to meet you.
You've never met?
No. I mean, I've seen a thousand pictures
every time I checked my email.
Auntie Liz, can I go look at the windows?
LIZ: Yeah, honey. Go ahead.
(BELL TOLLING)
- So, you still haven't heard from her?
- No.
Annie, it's been three days.
Yeah, but, I mean, you know how she is.
She probably just couldn't handle all this.
She'll... She'll show up.
Yeah, yeah.
You want to get out of here?
You know, go to my mom's place
or something.
I don't want to really be there alone.
Yeah. I... I would love that.
(LIZ SIGHS)
Out like a light. I think that time change
really threw her for a loop.
(SEVEN SISTERS PLAYING)
(SIGHS) I found these in my room.
I can't believe
I can actually smoke in here now.
(COUGHING)
(LAUGHS)
Oh, tastes like I'm 15. (SCOFFS)
Let me see that necklace.
A cross? You?
Believe it or not,
Mom gave it to me when I was a kid.
I love it.
Shit.
See, I can't even smoke in here.
I feel like she's gonna try and stop me.
Was it really that horrible for you guys?
Growing up with her?
You have no idea. (CHUCKLES)
Some people just shouldn't have kids.
(LAUGHING)
I don't think you should say that.
I mean, there's a deep love
between a mother and her children.
I... I think it's a beautiful thing.
Mmm. Oh, is it the same deep love
that made Nicole take off on her kid?
Annie. We don't know
what's happened to her.
Yes, we do.
We've seen this over and over again.
This is what we do in my family.
When times get tough, we take off.
My dad did it, whoever the hell he is,
and now Nicole's doing it.
Then why did you come back?
(SCOFFS)
For Nicole. Because we're sisters.
(SHUDDERING)
(MAN SOBBING)
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
- (THUD)
- (GASPS)
(EXHALES)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(SIGHS)
- (LOUD CREAKING)
- (GASPS)
(GROANS) on.
- (CLANGING)
- Shit.
(SIGHS)
(URINATING)
Liz?
(LIGHT FLICKERING)
Liz!
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
(SHRIEKING)
(EVA CRYING)
(GRUNTING)
(CONTINUES CRYING)
Hey. Who's she?
COP: That's Nicole Barlow's sister.
She's crazy.
I can't talk right now. Yeah, I'll call you later.
All right. Bye.
Annie, I'm... I'm Bill Creek.
I know you told your story
to a bunch of people,
but would you mind going over it with me.
Why do you want to know
what happened to me?
I know your sister.
She's been in and out of here
a bunch of times.
I don't need another person
telling me I'm crazy.
I used to smoke.
You know what I do now when I get the urge?
They told me your work as a waitress.
What else do you do?
What do you want to do?
I don't want to make friends.
You remind me of my daughter.
She's a little bit younger than you.
And you guys... you guys are a lot alike.
She's a real fucking bitch, too.
(LAUGHS)
So, where is she?
Your daughter?
She's up in Seattle. With her mother.
It's a sad story.
Let's talk about why you're here.
You show up at 4:00 a.m.
Claiming what you claim.
They send some people over there
to check it out
because you refuse to go back.
I'm not going back to that house.
Your cousin's missing.
They find signs of a struggle.
So, Annie, let me ask you this.
What would any cop in the world begin
to suspect here?
Why are you talking to me exactly?
You came here looking for help.
Yeah. Well, I don't need your help.
So, you're just gonna take off?
Better not leave town.
(SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
I'm gonna stick around.
But it's not because of you.
It's because I want to find out what happened
to Nicole and Liz.
Okay. Okay.
There's another reason to stick around.
She's upstairs.
(COIN CLINKING)
(MAN SOBBING)
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
(TV PLAYING)
(FLICKERING)
- (GASPS)
- (CLATTERING)
(PANTING)
(MOTORBIKE STARTING)
(REWING)
Hey!
You have to wear a helmet.
(TURNS OFF ENGINE)
Merry Christmas.
(SOBBING)
WAITRESS: Are you finally ready to order?
Or did you have any questions?
(DOOR UNLOCKING)
(GRUNTING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(SWITCH CLICKING)
Are you okay to wait here?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
- CREEK: Hey.
- (GASPS)
You lived 16 years in this house.
You have no memory of this room.
I can see into the living room.
These are everywhere.
It's me and Nicole's room.
My mom, she wanted me to find this place.
She guided me here.
There's something here that can tell us
what happened to Nicole and Liz.
Annie, it's gonna take a lot more than that
to figure out where they went.
No. Don't you understand? I was led here.
I can take some pictures. That's about it.
Why don't you believe me?
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Giles?
We spoke on the phone.
You said that Stevie was around.
Sit down.
- Are you here to fuck with her?
- What?
- No.
Come on. Come on.
(HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Stevie? Do you remember me?
Annie Barlow. From high school.
Oh, yeah, Annie Barlow.
I just got back from San Pedro.
And I thought of you.
Can you really do that thing
that everyone said you can do?
(SIGHS)
Take me to your mother's room.
I'm not getting anything.
Well, um, what do we do now?
Where do you think we should go?
Down there.
Don't touch her.
(LIGHTS FLICKERING)
(GASPS)
Oh, she's here.
What's over there?
That's where she used to take us.
When we were bad.
Somebody's in there.
(LIGHTS FLICKERING)
- It's taking all the fucking light.
- She's taking all the light.
Be careful.
(STEVIE BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry for what happened to you.
- What are you talking about'?
I can see in there.
I can see what happened to you.
It's horrible.
Horrible.
(DOOR CREAKING)
STEVIE: What's on the other side?
- Last flashlight.
- What's with all the flashlights?
Electricity. It draws them out.
Hold this.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
There's a second presence.
Oh, God. Your sister.
What about my sister?
Oh, God.
(PANTING)
- (FLASHLIGHT FLICKERING)
- Shit!
(QUIVERING)
# This is where they go down below
# This is where they go, where they go
# This is where they go, where they go,
when they go down below! #
(YELLING) She didn't want anyone to know!
(STEVIE GRUNTING)
Stay away from her!
(GASPING)
GILES: Damn it!
- Can you help me?
- STEVIE: Judas! Judas!
Judas! Judas!
Judas! Judas! Judas! Judas!
Judas! Judas! Judas!
- Judas!
- (GILES GRUNTING)
(SHUDDERING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMS)
Out, now!
- (PANTING)
- GILES: Let's get out!
- Stevie! Stevie! Stevie!
- (SOBBING)
Who was that woman in there? Who was that?
She didn't want anyone to know.
Stevie, who's Judas?
- Why were you saying Judas?
- She didn't want anyone to know.
- Stevie, no, that... that wasn't my mother.
- (STEVIE CONTINUES SOBBING)
Who was that? What happened to Liz?
What happened to my sister?
- Stevie!
- (GILES GRUNTS)
What do you think you're doing to her?
(GRUNTING)
Let me talk to her! Open the door!
Stevie! Stevie! Stevie, what did you see?
God damn it! No! Come on!
Shit!
(GASPS)
(EXHALES)
(BEEPING)
(FLICKERING)
Mom?
"Jennifer Glick."
"Charles Barlow."
(LIGHT FLICKERING)
(GASPING)
(EXHALES)
Okay.
Charles Barlow. Born 1947
at St. Baptist New Hospital.
And Judith Barlow.
Born 1950. St. Baptist New Hospital.
This... So, my mother had a brother?
That's right.
(TYPING)
And I don't see anything on him
after the 1980 census.
(TYPING)
All it says here is he worked
as a longshoreman.
MAN ON PHONE: Hello?
- I want to talk to Stevie. Is she around?
- MAN: Giles!
No. Listen to me,
don't put Giles on the phone.
- Just get her.
- Okay, okay. Hold on.
STEVIE ON PHONE: Hi, Annie.
Stevie. I need your help.
That woman, in the house,
she was killed a long time ago.
And... And she was someone
that my mom knew, and...
What did you feel in that house?
The presence told me
that your mother did something.
Something that she didn't want anyone
to know about.
But... But this thing was trying to kill us,
wasn't it?
No. It was trying to show us something.
Once you understand what it wants you
to know, you'll be free of it.
But how am I supposed to understand?
I mean, what the hell am I supposed to do?
I just want to know
what happened to my sister.
Annie, I can give you a tool
to communicate with the other side.
But you should only use this if you're ready
to go all the way with this thing.
This woman who your mother knew,
do you have anything of hers?
Yeah.
You've got to go back in the house.
If I do this,
you promise me that it'll leave me alone.
Trust me.
Okay. Tell me what to do.
(SIGHS)
Are you Jennifer Glick?
Shit.
(PANTING)
Okay. Okay.
Okay, okay.
What do you want me to know?
(ANNIE GASPS)
Judas.
Wait.
(STUTTERING) Was he my mother's brother?
Oh, God. Um...
Did he murder you?
Okay. Okay. I'm sorry.
I'm... I'm sorry.
What do you need me to know?
Below?
(FLOORBOARD CREAKING)
(SHUDDERING)
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERING)
(FLASHLIGHT FLICKERING)
(SWITCH CLICKING)
(TAPPING)
(ANNIE PANTING)
(FLY BUZZING)
(LIGHTER CLICKING)
(GASPS)
(SOBBING)
(JUDAS SOBBING)
(FOOTSTEPS DEPARTING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(GUN COCKING)
(GUN CLICKING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(SHUDDERING)
(GRUNTING)
- (PANTING)
- (JUDAS SOBBING)
(SOBBING LOUDLY)
(GRUNTING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(PANTING)
You fucking crazy son of a bitch!
(GRUNTING)
Do it already!
(MUTTERING)
(EXHALES)
(ANNIE BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SWITCH CLICKING)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING) No! No! No!
(YELLS)
(JUDAS GROANING)
(GROANING)
(SCREAMS)
(GUN FIRES)
(KEYS JINGLING)
(SOBBING)
(SIGHS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
I'm gonna eat some of your ice cream
with you.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
(HEAVY BREATHING CONTINUES)
(ANNIE GASPS)
(PERIWINKLE PLAYING)