- [ Lori ] ...got after swimming and swimming and he caught it.
- [Franco ] Mmm.
So then I says to her,
"I don't b-"
Said. Said to her.
Said to her...
Mm-hmm.
"I don't believe that your father
dives a thousand feet under water,
Hmm.
and I don't believe that
he caught a whale either."
Do you think I should have
said that, Cookie?
Of course you should have said it.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Man ]
I have no choice.
I'm not interested
in blackmailing you.
I have to pass on
the information.
Of course I realize
this could be
disastrous for you,
but I just can't let-
Wait.
My- My shoelace
is untied.
Lori, I want you
to take a look...
and tell me who you see
in that car we just passed.
[ Whispers ]
Okay.
There's a man
with brown hair.
There's somebody else too,
but I can't see his face.
[ Kissing ]
Night, Cookie.
Good night, Lori!
[ Chuckling ]
Don't work too late.
Don't worry. I won't.
I just want to
finish this crossword.
Go on now. Jump into bed.
Night.
Sleep tight.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Sighs ]
Hmm.
"C." "C."
C-B-C.
"C."
"B."
[ Sighs ]
C-B.
[ Car Door Closes ]
[ Car Pulls Away ]
[ Footsteps ]
Lori?
[ Man's Voice ]
I'm not interested
in blackmailing you.
I have to pass on
the information.
[ Switch Clicks ]
I was in the store,
and there's the girl
that makes my shirts for me.
So I went into the dressing room
to try them on.
All of a sudden she comes in,
looks me right in my eye
and, wham, strips off her blouse.
And she wasn't wearing
a damn thing underneath.
So then what did you do?
What could I do?
Ordered three dozen more shirts.
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughs ]
Well, good night.
So long.
It's all yours now.
[ Water Running ]
[ Water Stops Running ]
GENETICS
[ Horn Honking ]
Mmm. Drunk again.
Oh, my God.
TERZI INSTITUTE FOR GENETIC RESEARCH
ANALYSIS - CONSULTATION - SURGERY
Hey! Look out!
Look out, will ya!
Sorry.
No, no, I'm sorry.
That was dumb.
I beg your pardon?
I said I'm sorry.
That was stupid.
Here.
Oh, that's what I thought
you said.
Yeah.
Uh, here's your cane.
Oh, thank you.
Say, um, can you tell me
what's going on here?
Uh, yeah, an attempted robbery.
Somebody, uh- Somebody
knocked out the night watchman.
What time did it happen?
[ Exhales ] I don't know.
Sometime last night.
I-I just got here myself.
Are you from the police?
No, no. I'm a reporter.
Uh, excuse me, would you, please.
What's your name?
Uh, Giordani.
Press.
Okay.
Hi.
Hello.
Who's the inspector?
Is it Spimi?
Yes, he's inside.
Ah, good.
Thanks.
That's about it.
I didn't see anyone.
He came from behind.
Giordani!
Come here.
Something big
must be going on.
All the top brass
from headquarters is here.
The D.A.'s here too.
How much did they get away with?
Nothing,
as far as they can tell.
Did you get any pictures?
Everything.
I got the big boss, Professor Terzi,
and all his assistants.
Esson- he's English-
Casoni, Mombelli
and a German named Braun.
It's all written down.
That's great.
Great.
[ Chuckles ]
Giordani.
Hi, Spimi.
Hi.
Let's get this over with
so maybe you'll clear out
and leave us in peace.
10:15 p.m.
Dr. Manera reported it.
He was on
the first night shift.
Our man half-killed a watchman,
jimmied a window and then
ran off without taking anything.
Not a test tube,
not a piece of paper.
Nothing.
Not even a paper clip.
Would you b-
Where's my father?
Anna Terzi,
the boss's daughter.
He's in his office.
What do they do
around this place anyway?
Genetics.
Biology.
Biochemistry.
Heredity.
They even perform those
prematrimonial examinations
for people with lots of cash...
who want to keep their offspring
of high quality.
They come here,
they have a pretty nurse,
they make them do
a little something and, bang,
then they study the liquid...
and tell you if you have
a hereditary disease...
or if your gun's jammed.
This bing-bang thing-
Is that all they do?
No.
They do research.
Very high level.
Very hush-hush.
Ah.
DIRECTOR
The research
in which we are engaged...
is of a highly
confidential nature,
and I would ask you,
therefore, to-
Oh, Anna.
Come in, come in.
[ Door Closes ]
My daughter.
The district attorney,
Chief of Police Salmi...
and Sergeant Andressi.
Sit down, Anna.
My daughter assists me
in my work.
We can speak freely.
Now then,
as I was saying,
our research is of a dramatic
and far-reaching importance,
but it is still too early
to reveal it to the general public.
And since nothing
was actually stolen,
I am confident that none of you
will object if I-
Excuse me, Professor,
but if it was a case of
industrial espionage, as seems likely,
somebody could have photographed
the documents that interested him...
without actually
carrying anything off.
Casoni, I am the director
and owner of this institute...
and I am quite capable
of handling this matter
without your assistance.
Quite right.
There's absolutely no evidence
to support the espionage hypothesis.
Not unless you know
something we don't.
Of course I don't.
I was just-
Exactly.
I think none of us
really knows very much.
For my part, I instructed
my entire staff to check very closely...
for the slightest sign that any papers
or documents had been touched.
So far they report
that they have found nothing.
Consequently,
I think that
the best thing to do is...
let the police handle the matter.
If it's necessary.
[ Buzzing ]
But I must ask you to keep
the investigation absolutely confidential.
Hello? Yes, he's here. Just a moment.
I'll do everything that's possible,
but certainly you must know that-
I don't care what the reason was.
I can understand how you feel,
but I told you last night-
I can't see what purpose-
All right. All right.
I'll meet you there at 5:00.
Ah, Bianca.
Hello.
What's going on
around here?
They almost
didn't let me in.
Someone broke into the place
last night.
Really?
What did they take?
Look, I'v-
I've got some things to do.
I have to stay around here
for a while.
Why don't I pick you up
a little later?
I'm sorry.
All right.
Don't tell anybody,
but I'm the only one
who knows what was stolen,
and I know who stole it.
Have you told the police?
No.
And I'm not going to
for the moment.
But this could mean
a big step forward for me.
Uh, what time
does this girl arrive?
In a few minutes.
Ah.
[ Train Whistle Blowing ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Chattering ]
Hey, we've forgotten
about the starlet.
Come on, come on.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, here she is.
Hold it!
Hi, boys!
Smile, please.
How's this for you?
This all right?
[ Photographers Clamoring ]
Or would you
rather have this?
Right, smile, smile.
A man is dead.
[ Blowing ]
Hi, Cookie!
Hello, gorgeous.
Want me to read you
the paper?
No, not now. Later.
Can I try it?
[ Blows ]
Go ahead.
Be my guest.
C-L-
Cloud?
No. No, no, no, no, no.
Here's C-L- ear.
Clear. Huh?
H-R-
He's dead.
Who? Who's dead?
The man you told me
to look at the other night.
You know,
the one in the car.
Yes.
The paper says so.
"Scientist crushed by train."
"Dr. Calabresi,
research analyst
for the Terzi Institute,
was killed in a tragic accident
at the railroad station."
There's a picture of him.
Describe the picture.
It shows the man,
and he's falling.
And there's a train.
Who wrote the article?
Carlo Giordani.
Giordani?
Do you remember me?
Sure. Sure, I do.
How are ya?
Fine.
Well,
who might you be?
My name's Lori.
This is my uncle.
Well, what I came here for
is to ask you-
Uh, no.
C-Come on in the office.
This way.
You told me your name yesterday,
but I never had the opportunity
to tell you mine.
Here.
Sit down here.
I'm Franco Arno,
and to get right to the point,
I'd like to talk to you about
the death of Dr. Calabresi.
What about it?
Well, I imagine
it hasn't escaped your mind...
that a theft at the Terzi Institute
and the death of a man who worked there,
all within the space of a few hours,
is a rather remarkable
coincidence.
Hmm. Yes,
I thought about that.
On the other hand,
the robbery
wasn't successful.
Calabresi's death
was an accident.
Our photographer even managed
to get a shot of the action.
Well, now that's precisely
what I wanted to talk to you about.
I understand that the picture
is a close-up of Dr. Calabresi
as he's falling. Is that right?
Mm-hmm.
Well, do you know
whether that's a, um-
a-a-a, um-
oh, an enlarged detail,
or whether
that's a complete negative?
[ Chuckles ]
What are you driving at?
What am I driving at?
Well, let me try to explain.
You see, I wasn't born blind.
This is the result of an accident
some 15 years ago.
But before that accident...
I was a newspaperman
like yourself.
Oh, I- I didn't know that.
Oh, now come now.
Wipe that expression of sympathy
from your face.
I can't see it,
but I know it's there.
No, look, I-I don't have
any, uh, expression of sy-
That's better.
That's much better.
Now then tell me, do you know
whether that picture was cropped?
Cropped?
Yes.
Uh, I don't know.
It's easy to find out.
Tell him to make sure
to look at the contacts.
Mm-hmm.
[ Phone Ringing ]
Yes?
Hi.
No. I didn't print the whole thing.
I cut off a little bit on the left.
Are the contacts there?
I'll be damned.
You know, I didn't even notice this.
You can see an arm and a hand.
It's a little blurred,
but you can make it out.
It's as if somebody had pushed
the poor bastard under the train.
Print it.
You got that, Righetto?
Print it. The whole frame.
- I'll be there in a minute.
- Okay.
You must have been
one hell of a newspaperman.
Let's take a look at that photograph.
[ Chuckles ]
Why didn't you
go to the police?
Oh, you think the police
would pay attention to a child
and a man like me?
Besides, I'm enjoying it
this way much better.
I like solving puzzles.
[ Rustling ]
[ Gasping, Screaming ]
[ Footsteps ]
[ Arno ]
What happened?
Righetto, my-
my friend the photographer, he's-
he's dead.
He's all cut up.
Murdered.
[ Exhales ]
I called the police.
You two better get out of here.
Then you let the sauce thicken
for about 10 minutes.
You add some pepper, nutmeg,
two tablespoons of melted butter,
a drop or two of brandy.
Meanwhile, you drain the ravioli
and put it in a warm bowl-
Marcel, for Christ's sake,
I don't give a damn
about your wife's ravioli!
Just making conversation.
I don't need it right now.
I've gotta get back to the paper.
How much longer
am I gonna have to wait?
[ Door Opens ]
[ Spimi ]
Okay, Giordani.
Here's the latest
from the coroner's report.
The doctor thinks
we're dealing with a maniac.
First he strangled
poor Righetto.
Then he carved him
with a knife or a razor blade,
something very sharp.
Thanks.
Be seeing you.
Hey, do me a favor, will ya?
Don't tie Righetto's death
with Calabresi's.
No point in scaring off
the murderer, or murderers.
You believe that stuff
about a maniac?
Why not?
That's what the doctor says.
What do you say?
Well, I don't even have
what you would call a lead.
Just a hunch.
What kind of a guy was Calabresi?
Colorless. He lived alone.
He was from Padua.
Any girlfriends or mistresses?
You're pretty nosy, Giordani.
You know that?
Hmm.
He was engaged to a girl
named Bianca Merusi. Nice girl.
That will be all for now.
Mombelli.
About 40.
He's talking to Casoni.
Casoni's younger, about 25.
They seem to be arguing
about something.
Esson's coming out. He's around 45.
Seems to be in a big hurry.
Now Braun's coming out,
the German.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, he's very elegant.
He has a car and chauffeur.
Here's Terzi and his daughter Anna.
Terzi's, um, medium height, about 50.
Anna.
[ Engine Starts ]
Ah, she's something else.
The police
are following Terzi.
Wonder why
they put a tail on him?
It's because they-
they also realize
that the key to the puzzle
is right there in the institute.
Dr. Calabresi was killed
because he discovered something.
Something very important.
[ Door Handle Rattles,
Door Opens ]
Yes? Lori?
Yes, Cookie.
[ Door Closes ]
Come in,
say hello to Giordani.
Hello.
Hello there.
Hi, Cookie.
Hi, sweetheart.
Mmm.
[ Kisses, Sighs ]
How come you always
call him Cookie?
Because cookies are sweet.
And besides, I love them
with chocolate milk.
Ah.
Yeah, she and I
are alone in the world.
I don't have any relatives
and she doesn't have
any parents, so, um,
we find that
we need each other.
Well, I'm off.
[ Arno ]
Where to?
I thought I'd have a little chat
with Calabresi's fiance.
Well, now, I-
I have a better idea.
Why don't you
have a little chat
with Terzi's daughter?
Didn't you say
he was a widower?
Mm-hmm.
Men who are alone sometimes
tell their daughters an awful lot.
Meanwhile,
Lori and I,
we'll drop in on Bianca.
We've got a little hunch,
haven't we, Lori? Say yes.
Yes.
Hmm.
Okay, you follow your hunch.
I'll drop in on Terzi.
[ Chuckles ]
You know, I think
you're really beginning
to enjoy this. Huh?
Bit more exciting than one of your
crossword puzzle games, right?
[ Both Chuckling ]
THE WEAPON: A RAZOR BLADE?
These reporters.
Did you read
the article?
Uh, no.
It says that the guy that did it
could be a barber. Hmph!
That's exactly what it says.
Isn't that right, Giuseppe?
A crazy barber. Hmph.
I wonder where these reporters
get some of their ideas.
What's the matter?
Are you hot?
Uh, no.
What I'm getting at, mister,
is this.
Let's say one of us goes crazy and decides
to go after somebody with a razor.
He wouldn't just go
and cut him up any which way.
Not after all those years
of bending over customers' throats,
being careful
not to make the tiniest nick.
No, sir.
You can take my word for it.
A barber goes off his rocker,
the first thing
he's gonna want to do is...
make a nice, clean slash...
across somebody's throat.
What's the matter?
Did I nick you?
No.
[ Exhales ]
Hey, I haven't finished yet.
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
And then my wife adds
a few tablespoons of chopped ham...
and a bit of mustard!
You like mustard?
Nah, it gives me heartburn.
[ Doorbell Rings ]
Yes?
I'd like to speak to
Professor Terzi.
Your name, please?
Well, that's doesn't matter.
It's important I speak to him.
The professor is not at home.
Well, wh-what about
his daughter?
She's not home either.
It's about the fire
at the institute.
The what?
Where do you think
you're going?
Where's the professor?
He's out, I said.
Is he in there?
No!
I'll bet he's upstairs.
Right. Right.
Wait!
What is it?
It's this man, sir.
He forced his way in.
Who are you?
What do you want?
My name's Carlo Giordani.
I'm a reporter.
It's important I talk to you.
I'm busy.
I can't see you now.
It's about the murder.
What murder?
Calabresi's.
I understood his death
was an accident.
That's the general opinion.
I happen to know it was murder.
All right. Come up.
I'll see you in a little while.
[ Door Buzzer Buzzes ]
Miss Merusi?
Yes?
Uh, would you mind if I have
a little talk with you, please?
Esson, would you come up
for a moment, please?
- Good-bye.
- Thank you.
Somebody ought to teach you
some manners.
Huh!
[ Anna Giggling ]
Poor Esson.
He's so upset.
I just refused,
for the hundredth time,
to become his mistress.
[ Chuckles ]
What's your name?
Carlo Giordani.
Same as before.
Oh.
You always that candid
with people?
Mmm, not always.
What did you and Papa
have to say to each other?
I gave him some information,
he gave me some.
And then?
Then we decided that, uh,
he'd look into certain events,
I'd look into others.
What events?
Hmm. Things that
have to do with the institute.
I don't see why
you have to act so mysterious...
after you forced your way
into my house so rudely.
I don't like your manner.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm not crazy about yours either.
- No?
- No.
[ Chuckles ]
Look at you sitting there,
posing like an aristocratic child...
trying to show off
your legs.
Oh, they're very nice legs.
It's a pleasure to make their acquaintance.
But I don't care
if you don't like my manner.
I've had complaints before.
Doesn't seem to do any good.
That's all.
Hmm.
You really gave it to me.
I suppose I deserved it.
Let's make peace.
Take me out of here.
[ Engine Starts ]
I'm sorry I can't help you,
but if the police couldn't
find anything in this house,
I certainly can't see how
I'd be able to.
Of course. It was just an idea.
Forgive me for intruding.
[ Rattling ]
[ Door Shuts ]
Say, what was that sound
I kept hearing in there, Lori?
A watch she was wearing
around her neck.
Oh.
It's very pretty.
It had a picture
of that dead man on it.
Hello?
This is Bianca.
There's trouble ahead.
Some character came to see me.
[ Engine Racing ]
[ Tires Squealing ]
Do you see that car
following us?
It's the police.
Watch me lose 'em.
He's out of his mind.
This is crazy.
This car doesn't have
a seat belt!
[ Horn Honks ]
Afraid?
Nope.
Are they crazy?
What's the matter
with those bastards?
[ Groans ]
Damn.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So anyway,
that's how my father
founded the institute.
Now he's taken on
four research assistants,
specialists in genetics.
They're working on
two parallel projects.
One deals with
a very revolutionary drug...
and the other
is a research program
for the government.
It's a highly confidential
investigation...
into the chromosome alteration
knows as X-Y-Y,
which apparently indicates
a criminal tendency
in the individual.
Yes, yes, I remember. I, uh-
I read a couple of articles about that.
Sounded interesting.
It is interesting.
It's also explosive.
It's already been brought
into several criminal trials
as an extenuating circumstance.
[ Loud Rattle ]
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I'm just a little edgy.
So many strange things
have happened recently.
Strange? Like what?
Well, nothing important
really.
Maybe it's just
my imagination.
So you wanted to know
about my father's assistants?
Esson you've already met.
He's English.
Already quite well known
in his field.
In his private life he isn't a bit
the humorless egghead you'd expect.
But on the job
he can be very hard,
even violent.
Mombelli's a good technician,
but I don't think he has
any great ambitions.
He lives entirely
in my father's shadow.
Casoni?
He's the child prodigy
of the group.
He got his doctorate
when he was very young.
A spectacular career
right from the start.
All sorts of
international recognition.
[ Organ ]
[Joins In ]
[ Continues ]
Then there's Braun.
He's a strange type.
Strange how?
Well, for one thing
he hangs out
at the St. Peter's Club.
Oh?
[ Soft Jazz ]
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
[ Man ]
You didn't even look at me.
Oh, come here, darling.
Please sit down.
[ Chattering, Laughing Continue ]
[ Continues ]
[ Man ]
Carla! Carla, come here.
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Man #1 ]
A friend gave it to me.
[ Man #2 ] You're jealous.
[ Man #1 ]
Oh, not at all!
[ Man #3 ]
There's a new face
I haven't seen here before.
[ Chattering, Laughing Continue ]
No, I wouldn't imagine
it would be. [ Chuckling ]
Well-
Professor Braun?
Yeah?
I'd like
to speak to you.
Why, of course.
Please join us.
Uh, no, no.
It's, uh...
rather a delicate matter.
Well-
Will you excuse me,
please?
Come.
Let's sit over here.
Now what can I do for you?
Well, you see, I, uh-
You know,
you have very beautiful eyes.
You really think so?
Stupendous.
Blue with a touch of red.
Very rare.
Very rare?
[ Chuckles ]
I hadn't noticed.
Uh, no.
Tell me,
what brings you here?
Well, I'm a reporter.
Now hold on. Hold on.
I just wanna talk to you about some things
that have been happening at the institute.
That's all.
All right, Manuel.
It's nothing.
I have proof that Calabresi's death
wasn't accidental. He was murdered.
So?
So I have an idea.
I think maybe someone at the institute
is selling information about
that secret drug you're working on...
to a foreign
pharmaceutical company.
What would you say to that?
That's your opinion.
What am I supposed to say?
Well, whether you think
I'm right or wrong.
It doesn't interest me.
If somebody's a spy,
it's his business.
I'm a scientist, not a detective.
In any case, it may interest you
to know I have already been
questioned three times by the police.
A very embarrassing business.
What'd you tell them?
Everything I know.
[ Chuckles ]
That is,
nothing.
You want some advice?
Let them
do the investigating.
If it really is a question
of industrial espionage,
it's a dangerous business.
You could get
your fingers burnt.
[ Man At Table ]
Naturally I was furious.
But who wouldn't be?
The car! Of course!
At the station.
Stop.
Wait here.
5:00 P.M. - STATION
APPOINTMENT WITH-
All right,
here's what we got so far.
Five scientists...
plus Anna...
makes six.
Bianca Merusi,
seven.
Missing photographs,
eight.
Mm-hmm.
Attempted robbery
at the institute, nine.
Think of anything else?
No. No. Nothing else.
That's it then.
Nine leads to follow.
[ Scoffs ]
It's a cat with nine tails.
[ Laughing ]
A cat of nine tails,
like the old naval whip.
If we could just latch onto
one of those nine tails,
we'd be on our way
to solving the puzzle.
Yeah, but which one?
Mmm.
And we'd better hurry...
because whoever it is
is getting desperate.
[ Phone Ringing ]
Want me to get that?
No, I'll get it.
Hello.
I've discovered
who murdered my fiancé.
Yes. Of course.
[ Loud Banging ]
I'm-
[ Whispers ]
Just a moment.
Don't hang up.
I- I heard something in the other room.
I'll be right back.
[ Banging Continues ]
No, it isn't just a suspicion.
I found a note
that is absolute proof.
But I'd like you to turn it over
to the police for me.
Yes, I want the murderer
to be punished,
but I have personal reasons
for staying out of it.
Okay.
I'll explain when I see you.
All right.
I'll be right over.
[ Sighs ]
[ Click ]
[ Bead Bounces On Floor ]
[ Groans ]
[ Gagging, Screaming ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Giordani ]
Bianca Merusi was murdered last night.
That's why she never showed up.
Word's out the police picked up
something interesting
in her apartment,
but I haven't been able
to find out what.
I have some news too.
This came this morning.
THERE ONCE WAS A PUZZLE ENTHUSIAST
WHOJOINED FORCES WITH AJOURNALIST
AND TO DISCOVER THEY TRIED
WHY CERTAIN PEOPLE HAD DIED
SO BOTH ENTHUSIAST ANDJOURNALIST
ALSO WOUND UP ON THE LIST
I thought we kept ourselves
out of it, but...
no such luck.
No, I guess not.
You worried?
No.
No, not for myself.
But I- I-
I sent Lori away.
I sent her to a friend,
a dear old friend.
That's good.
Well, what do we do now?
What we ought to do is drop everything
and think of our own skins.
You're right.
That would be
the sensible thing to do.
I have some news about our scientists,
bits and pieces.
Yes?
Mombelli, he's- he's clean.
Checks out okay.
But it seems Casoni was fired
from his last position.
Couldn't find out any details,
but something fishy there.
Isn't there something fishy
in all our lives?
I also discovered
Braun's living very high.
Villas, yachts, parties, Jaguars.
The works.
Wonder where he gets
all his money.
Professor Terzi,
I would like to speak to you.
Uh, does it, uh,
have to be now?
It's important.
May I come in just a minute?
All right. Come in.
Thank you.
What I'm telling you
is strictly confidential.
I must have your word
that you won't publish it.
You have it.
First of all,
we're well on our way
to developing
a new wonder drug...
which will solve the problems
of hereditary diseases
and malformations once and for all.
Second, X-Y-Y.
You must understand
that each individual's
chromosome structure...
is composed
of X and Y genes.
To simplify this,
as you see here...
a triangle is formed...
and 99% of the time...
it terminates
with an X and a Y combination
here at the point.
But in very rare,
abnormal instances...
it ends with an X and two Y's.
Well, recently an American research team
examined the entire criminal population
of a federal penitentiary...
and they made
a sensational discovery.
Of the 200 convicted murderers
they examined,
an extraordinarily high percentage
had this X-Y-Y pattern
which is usually so rare.
So what you're saying is,
this X-Y-Y pattern indicates
a tendency toward violence.
Well, it certainly
represents a tendency
to be abnormally aggressive.
You realize, of course,
that this revolutionizes
psychoanalytic and penal theory.
Eliminating most crimes of violence
would seem to be simply...
a matter of examining
all children at birth...
and isolating all those
with the X-Y-Y triad.
I see.
Tell me, do you have any idea
about the things that have been
happening around here lately?
Yes, I do.
But I have no intention
of telling you.
I value my life too highly.
No, I don't suspect anyone.
I think this has just been
a series of accidents...
and coincidences.
You newspaper people and the police
are trying to find connections...
where there aren't any.
So according to you
everything's perfectly normal.
Absolutely.
Have you given the X-Y-Y test
to many people?
Who has been talking to you
about X-Y-Y?
Professor Terzi.
About 500 people in all.
How about the people
at the institute?
Have you all been tested?
Yes. All of us.
And now if you'll excuse me,
I have some work to do.
Thanks for your help.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
- Good evening.
- Oh, good evening!
How's everything?
Not so good.
This humidity's bad
for my rheumatism.
[ Door Slams ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Dialing ]
Yeah, is Inspector Spimi there?
[ Door Buzzer Buzzing ]
Just tell him
Carlo Giordani called him.
Have him call me
as soon as he gets in.
Thanks.
Hello.
Come in.
Nice place.
Thanks.
How come?
What?
[ Scoffs ]
I mean,
you paying me a visit
at this hour.
I wanted to have
a little chat with you.
A little chat?
Aren't you out of your territory?
Wrong side of the tracks for you, isn't it?
Does there have to be a wrong side?
What are you doing here?
Don't be so defensive.
[ Chuckles ]
Uh, it's just I never expected
to see you here, that's all.
Well, I am.
Yes.
Look, uh...
would you like
something to drink?
I, uh-
[ Chuckles ]
I have some milk.
No, thank you.
[ Clears Throat ]
Do you know how many people
are together right now
making love at this very second?
No.
780, on the average.
Really.
I don't know
if you're aware of it or not,
but that was an invitation.
I'm perfectly aware of it.
I was just wondering what devious device
you'll think up now to get me to bed.
The couch is very comfortable.
Milk?
Yes, thank you.
[ Scissors Snip ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Coughing ]
Hello?
This is Arno. They tried-
[ Coughing ]
They what?
They tried to kill me.
They tampered with
the main switch of my gas heater.
I- [ Coughing ]
Barely had time
to open the windows.
My God.
[ Coughing ]
Tried anything with you?
Uh, no. No.
Be careful. I-
[ Coughing ]
I'm sure they will.
Okay.
Thanks, Arno.
Don't!
[ Shatters ]
Did you drink any?
No.
[ Spits ]
How about that?
What's going on?
They tried to kill me.
The m- The milk.
Damn near got you too.
They're playing a little rough.
You stay as far away
from the city as you can.
Do you think I should?
My father wanted me to go away
for the weekend with him.
We've a villa in the country.
Then go, for sure.
You said for the weekend.
Uh, when do you think you'll be back?
Sunday night.
Ah.
Polecat! Hound dog!
Skunk! Coon!
Turd! Kraut! Slime!
Bed-wetter! Snot-nose!
[ Sighs ]
The priest, 125.
Gigi the Loser,
137 insults without stopping.
Gigi the Loser
is the winner.
[ Spectators Murmuring ]
And ball-breaker!
I left that one off.
[ Spectators Chattering ]
It's about time, huh?
Yeah!
Choice, Gigi. Really choice.
I see you picked up a few new ones.
Yeah. I had a Tunisian cell mate
last time I was in.
He knew a couple
I'd never heard before.
[ Chuckles ]
Ah, here.
Gigi, I need a favor.
Sure.
For old times' sake. You know.
What can I do for you?
Well, you see, uh-
There's a little job
I need done.
What, are you crazy? Not me.
I'm going straight.
Listen, I gotta get back
and help Mama at the store.
No, no, wait, Gigi. This is important.
You need watermelons?
I got watermelons.
Anytime you need
watermelons-
No, no, Gigi. It's easy.
It's very, very easy.
Nothing's easy for me.
I can't even knock over a chair
without getting caught.
Are you kiddin'?
They don't call me
Gigi the Loser for nothin'.
No, no, no. This is something special.
Don't even have to steal anything.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Just open a couple of drawers.
Locked?
Well, probably.
Breaking and entering.
Two years and three months.
Ahh!
Wouldn't it be a riot...
if all of a sudden
if Professor Terzi came back
and surprised us? [ Chuckles ]
[ Gasps ]
Come on, come on!
You sure nobody's home?
Absolutely.
[ Lock Clicks ]
[ Switch Clicks ]
[ Whispering ]
Nobody's at home, huh?
Thanks a lot.
[ Whispering ]
Hell, I didn't know.
Gigi, wait!
We're already inside.
Might as well finish it.
But we're locked in.
Are you telling me
you can't even open a door?
Come on. Let's hurry.
[ Drawer Opens ]
Gigi.
Here.
[ Can Clatters On Floor ]
Callard and Smith, 1953.
Nothing to it.
[ Clicking ]
[ Lock Clicks ]
[ Giordani's Voice ]
"Decree of adoption.
Juvenile court of Rome...
declare Anna Marini, minor,
subject to legal adoption."
A judge "declares Fulvio Terzi...
adopt Anna Marini."
Ah! Gigi!
[ Can Clatters ]
"I founded the institute.
It will carry my name.
I hope it will be successful.
There is something wrong with me.
I am unable to have
normal relations with women.
Professor P. says it's a question
of  induced fantasies.
Anna is a very beautiful girl.
She will become a splendid woman.
I adore her.
I often ask myself,
are these the sentiments...
that a father normally
feels for his daughter?
Why does Anna despise me?
I feel I am going mad.
She doesn't love me. I'm sure of it."
Let's get out of here.
Okay.
[ Drawer Slides, Closes ]
[ Switch Clicks ]
What'd you find out?
Well, you're not going to like this,
but I can't tell you yet.
Tomorrow we're having
a press conference for everybody.
A press conference?
Mmm.
Spimi, you promised me-
I know. I promised
to give you the news first.
But I can't do that.
It wouldn't be right.
[ Sighs ]
You're a real bastard.
Naturally.
Cops are all bastards.
We beat confessions out of people.
Take bribes.
We oppress minorities.
Of course, I can't deny I've got
some pretty talkative assistants.
That Morsella, for example-
He can never keep any news
to himself.
Just can't keep his mouth shut.
One of these days
I'm gonna put a muzzle on him.
I bet if you went to see him,
he'd probably tell you...
that in a closet
in Bianca Merusi's apartment...
we found 10 million lira
in cash.
And a complete file
on the Terzi drug.
How about that?
And she seemed so innocent.
She took up with Calabresi
just to get into his laboratory.
I thought you didn't drink.
I don't.
[ Chuckles ]
And if you really push him,
I'm sure Morsella
will also tell you...
that Braun and the girl
used to meet often.
And it sure as hell wasn't sex.
He's queer.
Have you picked him up yet?
Don't ask me.
Ask Morsella.
He might even
let slip the fact...
that we haven't been able
to find him since the girl died.
[ Typing ]
[ Spimi ]
You see what I mean
about Morsella.
Good thing I'm around
to keep an eye on him.
[ Machinery Whirring ]
GERMAN SCIENTIST UNDER
INVESTIGATION FOR THREE MURDERS
Giordani?
Yes.
May I come in?
I'd like to tell you something
that may interest you.
I'm sorry. I, uh-
I don't remember where we-
Oh, you haven't forgotten.
We've never met.
May I?
And I don't think my name
would be of any interest to you.
I've just read your article
about Professor Braun.
I know you're looking for him,
and I can tell you where he is.
Only you have to hurry,
because he's about to leave.
Look, uh, the paper I work for
is not very rich-
I'm not interested in money,
if that's what you mean.
I just want you to hurry.
And for reasons
which I won't trouble you with,
but which you
can probably imagine,
I'd prefer not to have
dealings with the police.
That's why I've come to you.
If you hurry, you can still
find Braun in a little villa
on the outskirts of the city.
The address is Via Rovereto 20.
Thanks.
You may feel contempt for me.
Perhaps you think
I'm despicable, an informer.
No.
What I'm doing
is contemptible,
but I can't help it.
You know that boy
who was with him?
Manuel?
Yes.
Braun stole him from me.
"Stole" is the word.
Manuel had been with me
for three years.
Once Braun is in jail,
I hope Manuel
will come back to me.
If he doesn't, I'll kill myself.
Braun?
Professor Braun, you here?
No need to worry.
I didn't bring the police.
I'm alone.
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Groaning ]
All right, where is he?
Where's Braun?
You son of a bitch!
You know where he is!
I don't know anything.
I was told he was here.
You mean...
you've never been here before?
No, I haven't.
Now where is he?
Over there.
[ Groans ]
Zero, zero, zero.
When you add it all up,
we're right back
where we started from.
You want me
to help you with that?
No. No, no, no.
I'm no invalid.
Besides, I like them
cooked a certain way.
You like this cheese?
You know, we've uncovered
a lot of  muck, but no murderer.
Mmm. Grapes are good.
Help yourself.
There's still one clue
nobody's come up with.
What's that?
The note Bianca told us about.
[ Chuckles ]
How do we know the murderer
doesn't already have it?
We don't.
That Bianca
was a shrewd operator.
I'll bet she hid that note
in a damn good-
[ Chain Rattling ]
[ Girl ] A watch
she was wearing around her neck.
It's very pretty.
It has a picture
of that dead man on it.
[ Giordani ]
Hey, look out!
I have a hunch.
Come on!
[ Gasps ]
Hey.
Oh, okay.
[ Gasps Softly ]
Hey, wait a minute.
[ Grunting ]
Okay. Okay.
Here.
Here's your cane.
Wouldn't you know
they'd bury that girl...
with that damn locket
around her neck?
[ Chuckles ] Talk about
taking secrets to the grave.
Yeah. That's it.
Sure wish we didn't
have to do this at night.
Did you ever hear
of grave robbers
working in the daytime?
Oh, that's great.
So now we're grave robbers, huh?
Exciting, isn't it?
[ Both Chuckle ]
You know, if suddenly somebody
jumps up in front of us,
you're gonna be
standing here all by yourself.
I hope you don't mind.
I don't mind.
[ Footsteps ]
[ Gravel Crunching ]
Sure is quiet.
Nice, isn't it?
I hear things.
You do?
[ Footsteps ]
[ Shatters ]
Did you hear that?
Yes. Stand still.
Must have been a cat.
Maybe.
Yeah, cats love cemeteries.
Don't they?
Uh. Wait a minute.
That's it. Straight ahead.
[ Giordani ]
It's locked.
Shouldn't be
hard to open.
[ Door Creaking ]
Guess I'd better go in, huh?
Yes. Yes.
Go on. Go.
What are you waiting for?
All right, all right. I'm going.
Listen, you hear anything,
you let me know right away, okay?
Yes. Yes. Hurry. Hurry, hurry.
Hey, we're in luck.
They're haven't
walled her up yet.
Good. Good.
[ Screw Turning ]
[ Groans ]
[ Arno ]
How's it coming?
You hear anything out there?
Nothing. Nothing.
Doesn't smell very good down here.
You won't find it by smelling for it.
Look for it.
[ Groans ]
[ Exhales ]
I found it!
Open it.
There's nothing!
The back.
Open the back.
- There's nothing there!
- Bring it here. Give it to me.
Bring it here.
What's this?
Hmm?
It's some kind
of a metal plate.
Take it off.
It's there! I found it!
What does it say?
I can see some writing there, but it's-
it's taped. I'm afraid I'll rip it
if I try to pull it off.
Give it to me.
We'll read it later.
Put the lid back on the coffin.
Do you think I have to put
all the screws back on?
[ Lock Clicks ]
Arno?
Arno, open the door!
Arno! For God's sake,
open the door!
[ Pounding On Door ]
[ Pounds On Door ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Piece Clatters On Ground ]
[ Inhales Sharply ]
[ Inhales, Sighs ]
Oh, shit.
[ Footsteps, Faint ]
[ Door Knob Clicks ]
[ Door Creaking ]
[ Switch Clicks ]
Giordani?
Speak up.
Where are you? Speak up.
This is no time to be playing games.
I'm here.
What's the matter?
For God's sake,
let's get out of here!
What went on out there?
He's got Lori.
- [ Slap ]
- Lori?
He asked for the note.
The note? But you
didn't give it to him.
Of course I did. I had no choice.
But, hell, that's the only way
we had of finding the murderer!
It's not the only way!
Not the only way?
What do you mean?
I stabbed him. I know I did.
I got him. I got him good. I- I-
I heard him yell. Please-
Please get me out of here.
I must find Lori.
Yes, she just left
a little while ago.
But I told you not to
let her out of your sight.
But the taxi driver
brought me your letter.
What letter?
Here.
Let's see.
[ Door Closes ]
Are you taking me to Cookie?
Why don't you answer?
If you won't answer me,
I won't get in!
[ Slap ]
[ Gasps ]
Will the driver who answered the call
to Via Frentani 12 45 minutes ago...
please report immediately
to Piazza Duomo?
Okay, thanks.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Phone Rings ]
Hello?
[ Man Whispering ]
The child's with me,
and I'll kill her...
unless I can be sure
you won't inform the police.
We won't inform anyone.
I'm going to hold her hostage
for a few days.
You two behave yourselves
and keep your mouths shut
while I settle some business.
If anything happens,
you'll get her back
with her throat cut.
[ Handset Rests In Cradle ]
What?
[ Shouts ]
What did he say?
When somebody...
has committed four murders,
he won't hesitate
to commit the fifth!
Do you have any friends
at the police station?
That wound is absolute proof!
And whoever it is won't be able
to get rid of it in a hurry.
All right, I'm game.
I'm sticking my neck out,
but I'll help you.
All right, Spimi,
but remember-
Don't worry.
We'll handle it your way.
No publicity.
Morsella!
Morsella?
Morsella, come up here.
[ Object Shatters ]
I want to talk to you.
What's wrong?
In there.
Well? What happened?
Plenty.
I'm beginning to think
a lot of it has to do with you.
[ Sighs ]
To start with the least of it,
you're not
Terzi's daughter, right?
I was going to tell you.
Yeah, were you also going
to tell me you're considerably more
than just a daughter to him?
Yes. I would have.
In fact, let's talk about it.
Yeah, let's talk about it.
We'll do that sometime.
Right now there are other things,
things that are beginning
to fall into place.
First, the night
you came to my apartment,
I heard the murderer
going out the front door
after poisoning the milk.
- A little later, you showed up.
- What are you saying?
Second, that glass of milk
was in your hand one full minute...
before I knocked it away,
but you didn't even take a sip.
Maybe you knew it wasn't
gonna taste very good, huh?
Another thing-
Earlier this evening,
Arno wounded the murderer.
How's your hand?
You started putting
two and two together...
right after you found out
about me and Terzi, didn't you?
Let's just say
it started me thinking.
You petty, narrow-minded
little reporter.
You figured it all out, didn't you?
A neat equation, Italian style:
Whore equals liar equals murderer.
I thought I'd finally run into somebody
reasonably civilized, but I was wrong.
Excuse me.
I found this broken vase upstairs.
Is the cut serious?
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Spimi ]
Giordani?
Giordani.
Let's go.
[ Squeaking ]
[ Heavy Breathing, Muffled ]
[ Squeaking Continues ]
[ Muffled Whimpering ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
[ Tires Screech ]
[ Man ]
No, everybody has to come in
by the main entrance.
Except for the directors.
They have their own keys.
They can come in
through a side door.
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Come on.
Where now?
This way.
No, wait.
You go ahead.
I think I'd better wait.
All right.
[ Door Knobs Clicking ]
Nothing.
Mm-mmm.
It's no use.
She's not here.
Now...
the only thing is to call headquarters
and put out a general alarm.
Then we'll start
a full-scale search.
Right?
Where's the telephone?
There's one downstairs
on the fifth floor.
[ Switch Clicks ]
[ Pattering ]
[ Drops Patter ]
[ Raspy Wheezing ]
[ Wheezing Continues ]
[ Grunts, Gasps ]
[ Groaning, Grunts ]
[ Groaning ]
Casoni.
Yeah.
[ Screams ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Yelps ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Groans ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Muffled Sob ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
[ Groans ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Groans Weakly ]
[ Spimi ]
Giordani!
Giordani, you all right?
[ Gasps ]
Stop where you are.
Don't move.
Don't move!
Oh, don't move, or I'll
run this right through you.
[ Groans ]
It's you, huh?
Let him go, Arno!
Stay where you are,
or I'll kill him!
No. No, no.
I had- I had to do it.
It wasn't my fault.
Calabresi was the only one
who knew I had the X-Y-Y triad.
Me, of all people!
After all his years of research!
I would have been ruined!
What have you done
with my little girl?
Huh? Speak up!
I broke into the lab
and replaced my report sheet
with a negative one.
No one would ever
have found out.
But Calabresi knew.
He knew and he tried
to blackmail me.
And I- I had to kill him,
don't you see?
Never mind all that.
And then the others-
Now tell me-
What did you do with Lori?
I killed her.
Arno! Can't you see
he's out of his mind?
You'll never see her again.
I killed her.
An innocent child?
You could... kill an innocent child?