[ FOOTSTEPS, DOOR OPENS ]
LAUREN: Yes. Uh-huh.
I'm not kidding.
That's where this "class act"
brought me.
Yeah, you heard me.
Hooters.
This is the first date
I've been on since the divorce,
and the guy brings me
to a Hooters.
[ TOILET FLUSHES ]
Is Tyler asleep?
Whoa! Oh, yeah! Whoo!
Not all the way.
What's he doing?
Yeah!
♪ This t-shirt's
on fire! ♪
Why is he singing that?
[ ROBOTICALLY ]
Must save planet earth.
No, it's all good.
It's out.
What's out?!
Oh, God, I'm coming home.
Intruder alert.
[ WHIMPERS ]
Yeah, maybe that's
not actually a bad idea.
Okay, here's the plan.
You're gonna call me
in 10 minutes
so that I can tell this dope
I have an emergency.
[ NORMAL VOICE ] Can you
give me my bath now?
Make it five minutes.
♪ I ain't complainin' ♪
♪ but I'd sure like to find me ♪
♪ a true, fine love ♪
♪ someone another ♪
♪ that's as sweet
as your mother ♪
♪ a true, fine love ♪
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
Got you, uh, buffalo shrimp
with the sauce on the side.
They'll do that
for me here.
I didn't know
how you took it, so...
You realize that
you're not actually
looking at my face
right now.
Very tight game goin' on up
there. I don't wanna miss it.
ANNOUNCER: Well, I know you
really gotta swing the axe hard
to get those, uh, hits in deep
on this quick turn.
Hi, Jim.
WOMAN: Hey, Jim.
WOMAN #2: Hey, Jim.
Cheese sticks
in the shape of a heart.
From me, bunny, Bethany,
and Britney.
Thank you, bubbles.
That's very nice.
Bye.
Have fun.
See ya.
[ CHUCKLING ] All right.
Hey, I noticed that you made
eye contact with boobles,
but I'm... I mean,
I'm not sure it was her eyes
you were looking at.
So...
You... Organize closets
for a living.
Yes.
Is it hard to find people
who can't organize
their own closets?
How does that work?
Well, it's not that they can't
do it for themselves.
It's that they don't
have the time
or they don't do it
efficiently.
Did you start with organizing
glove compartments
and just work your way up
from there, or...?
Listen, I'm sorry.
I know this is not going well.
[ CHUCKLING ] I, uh...
I haven't been on a date
in 20 years.
since senior year.
You get married in college?
Yep.
Me too.
Really?
Yes.
Is this not the weirdest feeling
in the world right now?
Like weird Al
starring in "weird science."
[ CHUCKLING ] Yes.
I like that.
You just came up
with that?
Yes.
Very good.
You know, I think I will have
one of these buffalo shrimp.
And I'll have it
with the sauce.
Excellent.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Oh, my God.
[ COUGHING ] Oh, my God.
It's hot.
Oh, my God!
Who makes sauce this hot?!
I just...
did you drink my beer?!
No. No, no.
I think you did.
Boobles! Buddy! Britney!
Can you get me some water?!
Here. Have
some French onion soup.
[ GURGLING ]
[ SPITS ]
You know... I'm curious.
With so many
possible reasons,
which one's the one
your wife left you for?
Cancer.
I'm sorry.
I...Naturally just assumed
you were divorced.
It's okay.
I naturally assumed
your husband shot himself,
so we're even.
[ SIGHS ]
[ CELLPHONE PLAYS TONE ]
I gotta take this.
Hello.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Calm down!
An avalanche?
In our backyard.
I'll be home right away.
It's an emergency.
I'm sorry.
$20 should cover my half.
JEN: He used
the emergency excuse on you?
Like he's the one
that had to escape.
Like I'm so horrible.
Huh.
Well, everybody has
a bad blind-date story,
and this loser is yours.
Who set you up?
[ SCOFFS ]
One of the mothers
in Tyler's class.
Every time I see her,
she tells me
about her "friend Jim."
And "oh, I just have to
meet Jim."
Well, she's a liar
and an idiot.
You should roofie her
and shave her head.
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
Dick?
Hi.
No, I can talk.
I'm just at work.
Great.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I know. I'm so sore.
[ GIGGLES ]
I-I "l" word you, too.
Okay.
Talk to you later. Bye.
Did you just use
the "l" word with dick?
We said it last night.
Jen! That's great!
Why didn't you tell me?
Oh, you know.
I mean, you finally went
on a date, and it was so awful.
I didn't want
to make you feel lonelier
than you probably
already feel.
No, I'm fine, actually.
And I'm not lonely.
I have two wonderful men
in my life, Brendan and Tyler.
Brendan needs a girlfriend,
and Tyler needs ritalin.
You're suggesting sex
and drugs
as a remedy
for my children's behavior?
[ GASPS ]
Oh, my God.
This is the dress
I've been wanting forever!
Oh.
What?! No!
[ SCOFFS ]
Who has
that kind of money?
Dick.
Try this on.
This is a total milf dress.
We don't try on
the clients' clothes.
It's one
of our selling points.
"We won't wear
your underwear
while we're organizing
your closets."
I'm just sayin'.
Back to work.
I think right at the bottom
of this rack,
we could fit some
more shoes and storage.
Jen!
Kanye, come
and change the baby.
North is wet,
and I don't want to drop her
on camera again.
[ LAUGHS ]
Okay, take it off.
No.
Look, this whole rack
still has the price tags on.
Technically, she hasn't
taken ownership yet.
And besides,
she's at the tennis club.
Now, try this on.
This dress can change a woman
from the kind a man cheats on
to the kind
a man cheats with.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I'm gonna go pee.
Expensive. Expensive.
Ooh, most expensive.
[ SNIFFS ]
[ SPRAYS ]
Wow. I didn't know you were
gonna look that good in it.
Oh, honey, what's wrong?
[ SOBBING ]
I should have tried harder.
I should have
dressed sexier.
You didn't do
anything wrong.
Mark is a pig.
But the kids
don't know that.
[ SIGHS ]
They just...
[ VOICE BREAKING ] They want us
to get back together.
And I don't know how
to explain it to them.
Well, it's time for them
to learn
that their dad
is a big pile of crap.
Just... I get so depressed.
I-I need to wear
high, sexy heels.
Stop jogging.
It helps.
It's freaking me out.
[ CRYING ] Look at me.
I'm ridiculous.
Come here.
[ SNIFFLES ]
Jen's got you.
Now I see why they call you
closet queens.
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING ]
Instagram!
Facebook!
Yes!
It was awful, man.
There was no connection at all.
I was so happy when you came up
with the avalanche thing.
That saved my life.
[ LAUGHS ]
And the way she dressed
was like an assistant principal
or something.
I felt like
I was in detention.
I got a girl for you.
Yeah?
Blonde lady.
From
my belly-dancing class.
A little bit
on the plus size.
But when she gets
to moving,
all that flappin'
can make it happen.
No good.
That big girl'd hit that Hooters
like a hurricane.
[ BLUBBERING ] Chicken!
Yeah.
Steak! Fries!
[ BLUBBERS ]
And a diet coke!
[ SMOOCHES ]
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
All right! Gotcha!
I'm out, man.
No more dating for me.
It's time and money I should be
spending with my kids.
Look who it is.
Hey. Larry!
My all-star!
Give me some.
It's hilary, dad,
which is bad enough.
You gonna
leave me hangin'?
Boom.
Guess what.
The new kodiak tents
just arrived.
In time for spring break.
We're going camping in our
backyard again this year?
Why? Are you
too old for that?
No. It's just some kids in
my class are going to Florida
or to Colorado
or even Switzerland.
Okay, you got a lot of rich kids
in your school.
What do you want from me?
We don't got that kind
of money.
I know.
It would just be nice
to go someplace.
Oh.
You know where you could
take her that's cheap?
My belly-dancing class.
Oh. Put that away.
Seriously.
Excuse me. Sir?
I'm here to pick up
my basketball uniform.
Did you
just call me "sir"?
Yeah.
I'm a girl.
[ SIGHS ]
That's one fugly girl.
Hey, man,
that's his daughter.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
LAUREN: Hey, honey, how's
the math homework coming?
Are any of the tutor's
shortcuts helping?
Did you go on a date?
A date?
Who told you
I went on a date?
You should really change
your e-mail password,
little miss
oh-seven-two-oh-nine-nine.
[ SIGHS ]
That is the last time
I use your birthday
as a password.
I can't believe
you read my e-mails.
Brendan, I love you,
but we have to learn
to respect each other's privacy
in this house.
Who's Jim?
Nobody, honey.
A buffoon.
Trust me.
It was nothing.
You promise?
Promise.
Whoa!
Whee-ooh! Whee-ooh!
Hey!
No wheels in the house!
I've told you this!
Yeah!
Tackle him, mom!
Get him!
Hey! Hey!
Did your dad take you
for ice cream
on the way home from school?
Spank him!
Rocky road
and mint chocolate chip!
Take him to the ground!
I'm on top of the world!
Goose, goose!
Aah!
Yeah!
You're dead!
No more titty twisters, guys!
You only have two titties
for the rest of your lives!
We need to learn to love
and respect them.
I always did.
How many times
have I told you
not to pump him full of sugar
before you drop him off?
Oh, come on.
Goin' out with dad
for an ice cream cone
is a lasting memory
for a kid.
Oh, okay.
Well, if dad spent
more time with him,
then the memories wouldn't
have to be so "lasting."
Boom. Zing.
Got me again.
It's so great spending time
with you, Lauren.
That doesn't go there.
What are we gonna do?
Ah. Oh, man.
It's gonna explode
in three, two...
oh, thank God.
That was close.
It was almost unorganized
for a minute.
Hi.
How are you?
Good. Are you going
to Tyler's game on Saturday?
Yes! Of course!
Great.
I'm putting you down.
It's what you do best.
On the board, mark.
On the board.
Lauren, the boys
don't need a board.
They don't need a list.
They know they can count on me.
That's it.
TYLER: Dad, can you help me
with my homework?!
Oh, I can't, bud!
Sorry!
I gotta go to a thing!
Ask your mom!
This is not an example
of my behavior.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
Did you leave?
♪ I'll never be
that girl again ♪
♪ no, oh, oh ♪
♪ oh ♪
♪ I'll never be
that girl again ♪
♪ no, oh, oh ♪
♪ my innocence
is wearin' thin ♪
♪ but my heart
is growin' strong ♪
♪ so call me ♪
♪ call me ♪
♪ miss movin' on ♪
♪ oh, oh, oh ♪
Larry, wanna shoot
some hoops?
Dad!
Aah!
Oh! Sorry!
Stop! Get ou...!
Why wouldn't you knock?!
I'm sorry, honey!
I didn't see anything!
Oh, thanks a lot!
No, no, no!
There was plenty of stuff
to see!
Uh, uh...
I mean, I didn't see
any gellin' goin' on!
How 'bout a fist bump?
No!
Larry, we both need
this fist bump.
We're cool.
ESPN:
What do you want?
Oh, I just wanted
to say hi.
Now, well, you did,
now leave. You know?
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
Hey, how we doin'
in here?
I'm talkin' to mom.
Great. What are you guys
talkin' about?
It's girl stuff.
Okay.
Well, just so you know,
I'm pretty good
with girl stuff, too.
[ SIGHS ]
Excuse me for a second.
Thanks, dad, but...
I just want to talk to mom.
Sure, sure.
Say hi for me.
[ SIGHS ]
I'm all out of stickers.
You're all out of face.
What happened to you?
[ GRUNTS ]
Can I play
with ESPN now?
ESPN is having
her quiet time.
Oh.
With invincible mommy?
"Invisible." Yes.
It's not fair only ESPN
gets to see her.
I know.
I wish I could see her.
Me too.
Come here.
Mwah.
[ GIGGLES ]
Mwah!
Mmm!
[ GRUNTING ]
Mac and cheese?
Mac and cheese.
Yeah!
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ BASEBALL BAT CLANKS ]
[ CHEERING ]
LAUREN: I mean,
he's looking around here.
Looking for you.
I... you knew it was today.
I published the calendar.
MARK: Lauren, the meeting
went longer than expected.
What... what do you
want from me?
You know what?
I just want you to be a dad!
I can't take it!
[ CHUCKLES ] Why don't you
hop over to the snack bar
to see if they sell
any chill pills?
Chill pills?
[ CHUCKLES ]
Why don't you bust a move
back to 1990?
Hi.
Do you want to...?
[ LAUGHS ]
You're at a baseball game?
I'm going on a mystery trip
with dick!
That's so great.
I have no idea
where we're going.
He's so much fun.
Aah! I'm so excited!
[ CHUCKLES ]
Now batting, number 23,
Tyler Reynolds!
Okay! Come on!
Go, Tyler!
Whoo! Come on, Tyler!
They're putting
this kid in?
League rule.
Every kid has to play
two innings.
Even kids like him.
I'll kick your ass
for two innings,
you better shut
your pie hole
you Burt Reynolds
scrawny reject!
Or I'm gonna stuff my entire
fist in your mouth!
Hey, how old
is that pitcher?
He looks like
a nascar driver.
Stee-rike!
Come on!
That's okay, buddy!
Shake it off!
It's okay!
Oh, no.
He's not gonna have one
of his meltdowns, is he?
No, he has two more swings.
It's gonna be okay.
Okay,
I better go now, then.
Oh, by the way,
I need a week off.
Oh, yeah, sure.
When's the vacation?
Two weeks from today.
Wait, no.
That's not gonna work
'cause that's spring break
and I've got to take care
of the boys.
Stee-rike two!
Why?!
It's okay, cutie!
You got this!
Check out what happens
when this kid strikes out.
One more comment like that
and it is go time,
you have been warned,
ratso!
Do you understand me?!
So check it!
I will crush you!
Checkity check it!
I thought mark was taking
the kids white-water rafting.
Oh, shocker.
He canceled.
Business trip.
Now I'm racking my brain
trying to figure out
how to compete with that.
You won't.
There's no time.
And why should we both
stay at home?
You are the bestest
business partner ever.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ SIGHS ]
Stee-rike three!
I hate this! I hate this!
I hate this!
I suck!
No.
Aah!
Oh, boy.
Here we go again.
Aah! Aah!
Aaaah!
[ SIGHS ]
Maybe you should try
badminton.
mouthwash!
And deodorant!
And some testosterone
supplements!
And some Cialis!
I'm just assuming!
And shave your neck!
It's very hairy.
LAUREN: Oh, God.
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ SIGHS ]
What?
Ugh.
No. No.
[ WHIMPERING ]
Damn it.
Rip that little loop
off the back of your shirt.
And step three...
Daddy?
Yes?
What do you miss
about mommy?
What do I miss
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
Hmm.
Everything.
I miss her laugh
and her smile,
and I miss her little nose
that she gave to you.
Luckily
you didn't get mine.
You'd look very weird.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Yeah.
I miss every time
"the wizard of oz" was on.
I love that movie.
I know.
She would sing
all the songs to us,
especially
"somewhere over the rainbow."
You know what I miss most
about her?
What?
Getting to tell her
how much I love her.
Are you allowed to do that
with anyone else?
Am I allowed?
Your mother,
before she left...
That's all
she would talk about
was me
finding somebody else.
But I would tell her
I can't
because
she's my one and only.
What did mommy say?
Your mom would say
my heart is so big
that it has room for two.
That's another thing I miss
about your mother.
She actually thought
I was awesome.
I think
you're awesome, daddy.
Thank you.
Hey, dad?
Um, I-I have
a personal errand to run,
and I need
to borrow the car.
Well, you can't drive
without me yet,
and somebody's got to stay here
with your sisters.
Dad,
I have a personal errand.
What does that even mean?
Eh, you taking a hit out
on somebody?
Dad, she's monsterating.
What?
I have my period!
Oh!
I-I forgot you get those.
Tampax pearls.
Douches. Fresh scent.
Medicated and sweet romance.
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
Yeah, let's not be doin' the
sweet romance douches quite yet.
"Poy-see" feminine wash.
Poy-see?
That's a little close, guys.
"Always clean"?
I could actually use those.
Uh...
What's a diva cup?
Is that to make coffee?
I don't under...
what kind
do you guys use?
[ SIGHS ]
No!
Hi.
Don't tell me.
Lauren.
Mr. Hooters.
Jim.
What's goin' on
in the sweater?
Just for the articles?
Uh, no.
These, um, actually
are, um, for my son.
Wow.
What a progressive mother.
No, I-I found a centerfold
under his bed, and I tore it up.
From a magazine,
not the Internet?
He's old school.
I respect that.
Why'd you tear it up?
Because as a woman,
I was totally offended.
You don't have to be.
It's a normal part
of growin' up.
Okay, but he taped a picture
of our babysitter's face on it.
Okay. That's sick.
He needs help.
Borderline
dahmer situation.
I'm sorry to report that.
Oh, very funny.
Okay, but if you had kids,
you'd understand it's...
Three daughters.
...Complicated.
You have three daughters?
Yes.
Do you have any other children,
or just the masturbator?
He has a younger brother.
Uh-huh.
Well, maybe you'll do
a better job with that kid.
I'm just jokin'.
So, what?
You're here to replace it
before the kid finds out?
Yes. But I can't tell
what magazine it's from.
I-I-I just...
[ SIGHS ]
Do you have any
of the centerfold remnants?
Yes, I do.
I, um... I tried
to tape it back up.
Did a great job.
You can hardly tell.
Snapper magazine.
How can you tell?
From the staple placement
and the, uh, the way
the paper feels,
and I already have this copy
at home.
How about a fist bump, uh?
Yep, that's the one.
Great.
Excuse me. Actually,
I thought of something
that might help us both,
um, to save us
some embarrassment.
How about I bring that up
to the cashier
and you bring this up
for me?
Whoa. Are these
for your daughter?
Yeah. She's 15,
and her "friend"
just paid a visit.
Okay. Well, these are
for a much older "friend."
A much heavier "friend"
staying in a much bigger "room"
than your daughter has.
You lost me.
You found me.
Oh.
Can I get a bump?
No.
Okay.
So you will do this.
That'll be $13.
Hi, I'm tom.
Here's your change.
Yeah, you told me.
Next.
Oh. I remember
the slender fit days.
You must be doin'
your kegels.
Nowadays I need six of these
taped together.
[ SCANNER BEEPS ]
Okay. Moving on.
Yeah. And we got...
That and, uh, card.
Rockin' Saturday night,
huh, lefty?
Oh, that's not mine.
That... that's her...
for her kid.
Ooh, pretty progressive mom.
[ SCANNER BEEPS ]
Yeah. That's what I... Said
to her, too.
Why would you do that?
I'm sorry.
What is wrong with you?
I'll get you out of it.
She just takes her homeschooling
real serious,
so that's why...
we get those back?
She's gotta get home to the kid
and get him going, so...
Take care.
Yeah.
Hi, I'm tom.
[ SIGHS ]
Thanks a lot for selling me out
back there.
Oh, she didn't even
hear about...
I panicked.
I'm sorry. Here.
Oh, I noticed.
Thank you.
I can't believe
you have three girls.
What does that even mean?
I just can't imagine you
with three girls.
Don't, then.
[ SIGHS ]
I'm sorry.
What are their names?
Hilary, Lou, and ESPN.
"Espin."
Mm-hmm.
That's unique.
Is it biblical?
No.
Named after
my favorite network.
[ HUMS "ESPN SPORTSCENTER"
THEME ]
ESPN.
No.
Yep.
[ LAUGHS ] What?
[ CHUCKLES ]
Pretty cool.
[ LAUGHING ] Oh, my God.
Your wife
must have been a Saint.
She was.
Your husband must have been
very patient dealing with...
Oh.
Another charming sentiment
from captain cheese sticks.
You know what?
Hooters is too good for you.
I'd never
bring you there again.
Oh, well, then I guess
I'll just have to learn
to get through life
without Hooters.
You've been doin' a pretty
damn good job so far!
That doesn't make
any sense.
No, they... I didn't realize
they were that big.
[ BOTH CARS CHIRP ]
Oh, whatever.
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
LAUREN:
Guys, unfortunately,
your dad had a business trip
that came up,
so your whitewater
rafting trip
is gonna get postponed
till this summer.
What?!
So we're stuck here
doing nothing all week?!
I have plans. I have
great plans actually.
Like what? Bowling
and going to the mall?
How did you know?
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
Bet that's dad!
Maybe he'll take us
on his business trip!
Oh, hey.
Is your mom home?
What do you mean,
"is your mom home"?
Who are you?
I'm Jim.
Jim?
"Jim66@dsg. Com"?
What is this, "dateline nbc"?
Yes, you got it right.
What do you want?
I need to talk to your mother.
Not a big deal.
She said
she's not interested in you.
Well, believe me, Frodo,
I don't like her either.
Unfortunately, I have to sort
something out with her.
Brendan, honey,
who's at the...
hey.
Jim.
You lied!
Liar! You like him!
What? I didn't lie, honey.
He's a buffoon.
Just like I said.
Don't talk to me!
Ever!
What?
No, sweetie, come on.
Great.
Which one was the masturbator?
The big one?
Why are you here?
What do you want?
The old bag at the pharmacy
mixed up our cards.
Well, that's impossible
because I keep my cards
very organized.
In fact, I keep them
in color-coded sleeves...
all right, I'll give this back
to whoever it belongs to.
Lauren Reynolds.
You know her?
Have you met her?
Oh.
[ SIGHS ] God, I...
I don't know what's wrong
with me lately.
I feel like
I'm losing my mind.
Just come in.
So wait.
How do you know where I live?
I googled you
and "closet queens" came up.
You're a lesbian?
No.
We organize "closets."
And we're the best,
so we're "queens."
"Closet queens."
Maybe the picture
was confusing me.
What picture?
Oh, those little weasels.
Your girlfriend, like, does
she know we went on a date?
Is she gonna kill me?
She looks nuts.
Lauren!
Well, here she is.
I have to talk to you!
Uh...
I-I never touched her.
Sh-she repulses me.
What?
Jen, what's wrong?
It's over
between me and dick.
Over?
I thought you don't like dick.
But you guys just started
using the "l" word.
"The l word."
I saw that show.
You guys love that one
I'm... I'm guessin'.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
Are you here
to fix something?
'Cause you should probably
just go and do that.
I'm Jim.
I'm not a threat.
Jim?
The blind-date guy.
You said
that was a disaster.
Oh, it was.
You said
he was a chubby loser.
He is.
You didn't mention he has
that high phlegmy voice
like he drinks
a lot of dairy.
I know...
standin' right here,
ladies.
Hearin' everything.
All right, our cards
got switched,
so we're just dealing
with that.
What happened with dick?
He just dropped
a major bomb on me.
He's married.
No, worse.
He's got kids.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
Oh, you're still here.
Why?
You still have my card.
"Why?"
Wait.
You're just gonna break up
with him
because he has children?
Five children.
Five.
What am I, Julie Andrews?
I'm gonna sew
matching outfits
and sing
to escape the Nazis?
He asked me if I wanted to be
"part of the team."
No, I don't!
Well, maybe you should
just go on the trip
and, you know, spend
some alone time with dick
and then...
oh, no.
See, he wanted the kids
to come with us.
He wanted me
to get to know them
in a "fun and neutral
environment."
Eh, eh, eh, five kids?
Is his last name
theodopolis?
Yes.
That's incredible.
That's my boss.
What?
He owns all
the dick's sporting goods.
I-I manage the one
in Ridgefield.
Of course you do.
Dick takes a lot
of special-needs people
and makes them "managers"
of something
so they can have a business card
and feel important.
Good for you!
That explains it.
That explains a lot.
You know, actually I applied
to work at closet queens,
but they said there's already
a gorilla [CHUCKLING]
Filling that position.
[ VOICE BREAKING ]
It's a thyroid thing.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Where was he gonna take you?
Africa.
It was gonna be incredible.
Look at that.
My God.
Sun, sand, safaris.
Wow.
Oh, my God.
What do we got?
He must really
like you a lot.
Sorry, I'm not gettin' it
at all.
Okay. And this
concludes our business.
Thank you.
Africa.
So he's just gonna go here
all by himself
with his kids now?
No.
He's heartbroken now.
Nobody gets to go.
Oh, damn it!
[ SIGHS ] Why does he have
to have joint custody?
I thought the mother
always got the kids.
I mean,
this is a week away.
I hope
he gets his money back.
A week out?
Aah!
Not a chance.
Well, maybe they do things
differently in Africa.
Oh, I forgot you were an expert
at closets
and African refund policies.
Okay. Kick him out.
Don't let him talk
to you like that.
Get out.
I'm leavin'.
Jen.
My boys would give anything
to go
on a vacation like this.
Mr. theodopolis. Hi.
It's Jim Friedman.
I don't mean
to be a vulture
picking on the carcass
of your dead relationship,
but I wonder...
...if you'd be willin'
to sell me the vacation
you were gonna go on
with Freddy krueger's sister?
I mean, I have been
saving and saving.
I could never give him
full value for it...
...but somethin's better
than nothin', right, sir?
It would just be
the three of us.
It would just be the four of us,
so we'd only need one room.
Oh, my God.
[ PANTS ]
Wait until
I tell the boys!
Oh.
Wait till I tell the girls!
BOTH:
We're going to Africa!
Aah!
Yeah!
[ "YEHLISA UMOYA" PLAYING ]
I can't believe
we're here.
This is
pretty cool, mom.
♪ Africa ♪
LAUREN: Yeah.
♪ Welcome, welcome,
welcome, welcome ♪
so I did good?
This is better than, like,
bowling and the mall?
Oh, yeah.
♪ Welcome ♪
♪ welcome, welcome ♪
Africa! Africa!
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
This is terrific.
This is great.
What the fu...?
Brendan!
What the fudge
is he doing here?
[ LAUGHS ]
We're going on family vacations
together now?
I-I have no idea why
they followed us to Africa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Is this a sick dream?
What is happening
right now?
You're stalking my mom!
You're a predator!
Hey! Don't talk to my dad
like that, butthole!
Language!
How about you don't correct
my daughter, okay?
She can say "butthole"
if she wants to.
Butthole! Butthole!
Not you.
I hear thunder on the Mountain.
[ LAUGHS ]
Welcome to South Africa.
Mfana at your service.
Mfana.
Uh, Jim.
Uh, I mean, uh, uh, dick.
Dick theodopolis.
Welcome, dick theodopolis!
And you are traveling
with, uh, one little girl
and two, uh...
Big girls.
[ LAUGHS ] Of course.
And you must be miss Palmer.
Yes. Jen Palmer.
Oh, I see what you did.
I see what you did, too.
Are you ready for
the most exciting, amazing,
and romantic week
of your entire lives?
♪ Exciting, amazing, romantic! ♪
Yeah, we're here
for the zero romance package.
You still haven't told
the children, my friends?
Told the children what?
Do I have a new mommy?
Mfana.
Will you do us a favor?
Just leave us alone
for just two secs.
Kulungile,
which means "of course."
Thank you.
All right. Listen.
Would you just reassure my son
that we're not dating?
We are not dating!
I promise you.
This is not a face I want
to wake up to every morning.
Wow.
You'd be lucky to wake up
to that every day.
My mom is friggin' hot.
Did you just say
your mom was hot?
No! Not hot!
[ CHUCKLES ]
That's just wrong.
Tyler! Tyler!
Whoo! Yeah!
Get down from there!
Whee-hee!
Oh, God!
Please, please, please...
Whoa!
...please get down!
Whoo!
Aah!
BRENDAN:
This place is ginormous!
TYLER: Oh, my God!
MFANA: Follow me.
Right this way.
Welcome to your familymoon.
Whoa!
Whoa! Whoa!
BRENDAN:
This is so cool.
JIM: Whoa-ho!
Now we're talkin'!
[ CHUCKLES ]
This is Africa, baby!
We'll take this room.
No!
We want this room.
Silly theocropolises!
This is for the children.
This room is
for the mama and the papa.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BRENDAN AND TYLER: Whoa.
ESPN: Look at that bed.
HILARY: Huge!
TYLER: Yeah!
Awesome.
Look at all this candy.
Here is where you make
more theopotamuses.
[ LAUGHS ]
My bad.
What part of "not dating"
does this bed fit into?
Oh, boy.
Okay. You know what?
Everybody fall into line.
Brendan, Tyler, honey,
I need you on the couch.
Hilary, uh, c-span, Lou...
ESPN, ESPN.
E-e-e-excuse me...
ESPN.
I'm sorry, honey.
Oh, my God.
Dick was gonna propose to Jen.
A family honeymoon.
A "familymoon."
And your dumb friend
ruined it.
So here's what's
gonna happen.
The first room we saw,
we're gonna take that.
And you
and your deranged boys
can have wilt Chamberlain's
headquarters.
Dude,
what are you eating?
Mm. "Cherry panties."
What are "cherry panties"?
Let me see that.
Oh, no! God!
Spit it out!
Why?
Spit it out! Just...
no cherry panties ever!
Out, out, out!
BRENDAN: Hey, mom.
I guess this
used to be a firehouse.
Aaaaah!
Look at this place.
Wow.
Hello, Mr. snuffleupagus.
Uh, theodopolis.
Hello...
Girls.
They're girls.
That's twice.
Let's go, guys... girls.
23.
Lookin' for 23.
There it is.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
Oh! Hi!
Hey.
How you doin'? I-I think
we're sharin' a table with ya.
Yeah. Hi!
I'm eddy wernick,
and this is ginger wernick
and our son, Jake.
We're from Vancouver.
'Kay.
I'm your son, all right?
Ginger would've had to give
birth to me when she was 6.
She's not my mom.
Okay. Get it out there
for everyone.
Sharin' it, lovin' it.
No holdin' back.
That's good.
All right, all right. Let's do
our thing. Come on. Come on.
Isn't this place fantastic?
So romantic.
Ahhh.
JIM: Good.
Gonna have a nice trip here.
Um, dad?
Hey, sweetie.
Where should I sit?
You can sit
anywhere you want.
What about mom?
Where does she sit?
Uh, where do you want her
to sit?
Next to me?
Then, that's where
she'll sit.
Go ahead.
You... you s...
get right next to Lou.
Your mom's right there.
Okay.
Okay?
Mm-hmm.
All good.
Ignorin' it.
Ignorin' the weirdness.
Ah. Where's the funeral
at, boys?
Where's the golf tournament
at, girls?
Oh, no.
No, no, no, no.
Mfana. Mfana!
Yes! Mrs. uh...
Reynolds.
Palmer!
Just not his wife, okay?
I don't wanna sit here.
Not gonna happen.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I'm afraid it must happen,
ma'am.
All tables are filled,
a-and this is your family.
Please sit with us.
You give it a try.
Okay.
Every family fights.
You make it better.
Mm-hmm.
Yes?
Yes.
Try the chakalaka.
Hi, new people.
Hello.
This is Lauren, by the way,
and her children,
the karate kids,
wax on and wax
[CHUCKLES] off.
Oh.
[ LAUGHS ]
Isn't this place fantastic?
Oh, it's so romantic.
Sorry,
wh-what'd you say?
So romantic!
[ GIGGLES ]
Easy.
Keepin' it classy,
huh, ginger?
Oh, jakey, you have something
on your face.
Oh, it's a mole.
Hey!
You can't sit there.
Why not?
My mom's sitting there.
Is she in the bathroom
or something?
No. She's sitting there
right now.
Are you on meds or...
ow!
It's okay, ESPN.
We'll get Brendan another chair.
Thank you.
Whatever.
I'm just gonna go
to the buffet.
Tyler, come with me.
They eat
fried caterpillars here.
Hell yeah!
JIM: Very nice.
Girls, why don't you hit
the buffet also?
Larry, make sure you have
plenty of beef, 'kay?
Gotta bulk up
for the season.
Love ya.
Go on.
"Bulk up for the season"?
What is she? A bear?
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
She's trying out for
girls' varsity this year.
A lot of big ladies
out there.
Oh.
So she's gonna eat her way
into the starting five.
My God.
[ SINGING IN ZULU ]
Hello, everybody!
My name is nickens.
And we are thathoo!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
We play traditional
South African isicathamiya music
with a little bit
of American soul.
Yebo! [ CHUCKLES ]
[ LAUGHS ]
Whoo! It is getting
a little hot in here.
Whoo!
Yes.
Finally, my huge African arms
are free.
Yeah, baby!
Yes, they are.
No.
I would like to welcome you
to our fourth annual
blended familymoon week!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Yebo!
What's a blended family?
I don't know.
It sounds painful, though.
I am looking out at all
you beautiful stepchildren...
Stepdads...
Stepmoms...
Half-brothers,
same-sex domestic partners...
...and good old-fashioned
Booty calls gone wrong.
[ LAUGHTER ]
Now, even though the emphasis
is on family,
we here, at the beautiful
sun city resort,
want to make sure you get
some alone time.
Oh!
Because alone time
can sometime take a long time.
We have many
supervised activities
for the young ones to do.
We have a fabulous
jungle play zone.
[ SHOUTING ]
NICKENS:
A nightly pool party.
Hey, ESPN.
Why aren't you getting in?
Is your mom afraid
of the water?
[ CHUCKLES ]
Good one, mom.
Magical animal time.
Little one,
wouldn't you like
to try petting
a living animal?
He's dead?
[ SOBS ]
NICKENS: And our famous
tekula teen disco!
Hey, dude.
There's a lot
of hot chicks out here.
[ MAN CHUCKLES ]
The best time. Yeah.
[ SPLASH ]
What the heck is...
what is that?
Are you kidding me?
Oh, my God!
Oh, God!
Crocodile!
Crocodile attack!
Help me!
Somebody help me!
Please don't kill me!
God! Oh, my God!
Mr. bellyflopolis,
the crocodiles are fake!
They're fake?!
Yes, they're fake!
Why would you make
them look so realistic?!
Well, to scare
the baboons away.
You just scared a zebra stripe
into my underwear!
Don't worry!
What happens in Africa,
stays in Africa.
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ LAUREN BREATHING HEAVILY ]
Oh. Oh. Tyler. Okay.
Excuse me.
Oh!
Okay.
[ HEAD THUNKS ]
Oh! Oh!
Uh, that's one way to get him
to sleep through the night.
You saw that?
No, I actually heard it.
I think they heard it
in Uganda. [ CHUCKLES ]
It was a lot easier
when he was Lou's age.
Of course,
let me help ya out here.
Here ya are.
You're home.
Thank you.
Absolu... uh-oh!
Whoa!
Too late.
Oh, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa, all right,
all right, all right.
Pick... pick... pick him up.
Three-second rule.
Oh, God!
[ CHUCKLING ]
Three-second rule.
Good, good, good.
You're fine. He's fine.
[ SIGHS ]
Okay,
now I'm getting scared.
Okay.
[ SMOOCHES ]
Sleep, sleep.
Too hot in here.
No blanket, okay?
Shh.
Here's your buddy.
Love ya, love ya.
Mom's sleeping there.
Okay, can I sleep with her?
No, you'll crush her.
No, I just... I could get in
with her and spoon with her.
It would be nice.
I don't wanna see that.
No.
[ SMACKS LIPS ] Okay.
We'll let mommy rest.
I'll, uh, I'll figure it out.
I love you.
I love you too, dad.
Good night.
Sleep good.
[ GRUNTS ]
Me and you there, shorty.
Okay, that's right.
Right on my neck.
That's gonna make a nice evening
for me.
[ SIGHS ]
Hey, guys.
It is time to wake up.
Africa awaits us.
It's a beautiful morning.
Is he crazy?
HILARY: Go away.
It's way too early.
Lou, will you wake up
with daddy, please?
[ GROWLING ] In the name
of Lucifer, let us sleep.
Up, up, up, you two.
I have quite a day planned.
[ SIGHS ]
I need a coffee.
Morning.
Big day planned?
Oh, yeah.
7:15 nature walk.
8:30 petting zoo.
10:00 A.M. native crafts.
Ah.
The boys,
they're so excited.
Oh, really? My girls
are ecstatic also.
They're just jumping
up and down on the bed.
Can't believe
they're here.
Cream?
BOTH: No, thank you.
Sugar?
BOTH: Yes, please.
Couldn't get the boys
out of bed, could you?
No.
The girls?
The girls are probably sleeping
the rest of the trip.
So... Possible exorcism coming
for the little one.
We'll see what happens.
Well, it's beautiful here.
Oh, yeah.
[ RHINOCEROSES GRUNTING ]
I'll see you around.
Yeah. Have a good one.
You won't see that
in New Jersey.
Okay. All right.
All right. Here we go. Okay.
Here you go, baby.
That's it, sweetie.
Take him down.
Take him!
That's it. Back him.
Use your weight!
Muscle him!
[ GRUNTS ]
Use your body.
Oh, yes!
Finish it!
[ GROANS ]
And bam!
That's it! Yes!
Yes!
Way to go, Larry.
Winner's up. Let's go.
Gimme the ball.
Buddy.
Up top.
And we go in.
Let's go. Get loose.
Cut. Cut!
Larry! Move!
Come on.
What are you doin'?
Larry?
Just cut!
Go! Break it.
Shake him off. Come on.
Are you...
are you voguing right now?
What is happening?
Here!
Just take the ball.
Work the kid. Work him.
Lose him.
Cross him. Cross him over.
Cross him.
Don't skip!
Yo!
Why you moving like that?
Is it the bra?
'Cause if... if it's the bra,
just take it off.
You don't need it anyways.
What?
[ SOBS ]
What are you doing?
We just started.
Is your boy okay?
Why does he wear a bra?
She's a girl.
You suck.
♪ You suck, you suck, you suck,
you suck, you suck, you suck ♪
[ SINGING IN ZULU ]
♪ Your boy has no skills ♪
♪ you schooled
by a little girl ♪
♪ you suck, you suck, you suck ♪
Tyler, slow down!
Come on, mom!
We're going four Miles
per hour.
That's plenty fast enough.
Fast and safe.
MFANA: Miss Palmer!
It's okay to go fast.
Oh, okay, mfana.
Watch me!
[ LAUGHS ]
Whee!
WOMAN:
You're going the wrong way!
Watch out, grandma!
Aaah!
My bad.
WOMAN: The blending process
is really going well for us.
My husband's 13-year-old
still has some hatred issues
towards me.
But it is becoming
less physical.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
So it's a start.
That's great.
WOMAN #2: Good for you.
Yeah. I woke up this morning
with a pillow pressed
against my face.
But I could sense some guilt
afterwards.
So that's progress.
Yeah.
Hang in there, ladies.
There's a light at the end
of the tunnel.
This little angel here is
finally starting to think of me
as her second mom.
Not just her former
gymnastics teacher.
Wha-what are you drawing,
honey?
It's a picture of elephants
stomping on your head
and making you dead.
[ GIGGLES ]
Stop it.
[ SIGHS ]
Don't worry.
What happens in Africa
stays in Africa.
Bump my fist?
[ GIGGLES ]
Jim's so funny.
Yeah.
[ GROWLS ]
[ SQUEALS ]
[ "BANAMANGA" PLAYING ]
TYLER: [ GRUNTS ]
My head is boiling, mom.
Get it off.
I'm trying.
Why did you tie it
with so many knots?
'Cause I didn't want it
to come flying off.
Oh, my God!
What happened to her face?
I painted it.
Sh-she's a kitty cat.
Are you wearing
eye shadow?
I made daddy a princess,
but he washed the paint off.
Well, not all the way off
because he looks a little
like lady gaga.
Why is this kid
wearing a helmet?
Are you carryin' him to bed
again or somethin'?
No, I tied the chin strap
too many times.
It's...
I can't get it off.
Best thing about workin'
at a sporting goods store...
Swiss army knives.
Just... just be careful.
I'll go easy.
Aah!
Oh!
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Sure.
Daddy, I gotta go
to the bathroom.
You do? Okay.
Can she take me?
Umm, she's got, uh,
her own life to live.
What do you gotta do?
One or two?
Number one.
I can handle this.
Okay.
Will you watch him?
And I mean watch him.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I got it, home slice.
Okay.
For sure.
What's number one again?
Um, it's, uh...
it's a pee-pee.
LOU: And sometimes,
he wipes too hard.
Aw, I'm sure
he doesn't mean to.
No, he's a good daddy.
He just doesn't have
a bagina.
[ TOILET FLUSHES ]
[ SIGHS ] Okay, honey.
Let's wash your hands.
[ GASPS ]
[ SOBBING ]
He's a bad daddy!
He made me look like
the walking dead!
Oh, no!
Oh.
Okay.
All right.
Let's see what we have
in the magic bag here.
Oh, perfect.
All right.
LA-da-da!
You're pretty.
You're prettier.
[ GROWLING ]
I said you are.
[ GROWLING ] Shut up
and let me do your makeup.
[ GIGGLES ]
LOU: Don't worry.
They're around.
LAUREN:
Oh, I'm not worried.
Maybe that's
where they are.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
TYLER: Aw, yeah!
Whoo! Yeah!
Tyler?
JIM: Hold on, now!
Excuse me.
Hold on, big time!
[ GASPS ]
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
[ YELLING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Oh! Oh, my God!
I'm gonna kill him.
[ YELLING CONTINUES ]
Yeah, baby! Hold on, now!
Whoa! Whoa! Easy, homey, easy!
Tyler! Get off that dodo bird
right now!
Oh, whoa, whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Everything's fine.
The safety instructor's
on top of it.
[ SNORES ]
[ SNARLS ]
Look at me, mom!
I'm a cowboy!
Well, partner, I bet I can
stay on longer than you!
It's on, sheriff.
No "longer"! No "staying"!
[ TYLER YELLING ]
JIM: I can't be beat!
I can't hear you!
You're going down!
I'm never gonna fall off!
Never!
[ LAUGHING ]
JIM:
Yeah! Aw, shut up! Whoo!
Whoo! One hand, mama!
Whoo!
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CROWD OOHS ]
Good!
Yes! I win!
I'm the king of Africa!
[ YELLS ]
Tyler!
[ CROWD CHEERS ]
[ GASPING ]
A winner!
Are you kidding me?
Yee-haw! Yee-haw!
Wow. Whoooo, boom!
You're a moron, okay?
Because he could've
broken his neck!
Mom, mom, mom!
Did you see that?
I stuck the landing
and did the bull dance.
Yes! I saw it and I just...
you can't...
thank you so much for taking me
on this trip, mom.
This is the best day of my life!
Okay.
Great! Oh, good! Oh good.
I love you so much.
I'm so glad
you're having fun.
Awww.
You're welcome.
Thank you so much.
Why you flipping
my dad off?
Huh? I'm not.
♪ 2 o'clock
on a Friday mornin' ♪
♪ come a gun man ♪
♪ come a knife man ♪
yo! Check out white girl
in the neighborhood.
Am I right, my brothers?
[ HIGH-PITCHED VOICE ]
Woot-woot!
I can't believe
your dad's into my mom.
He doesn't like her.
She's into him.
No way. He's goofy
and flabby all over.
My mom's gorgeous
with a rocking body.
[ CHUCKLING ]
Hey, hey, that's sick, man.
That was out of context!
Was it?
[ LAUGHS ]
[ CHILDREN PLAYING ]
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
You know, you should just
go talk to him,
because he probably
won't bite.
Oh! [ CHUCKLES ]
No, no. I-I can't.
Got a boyfriend
back at home?
Please.
All the guys at my school
pretty much assume
I'm a lesbian.
And not the hot kind.
Well,
have you ever considered,
say, like... Changing
your hairstyle?
Our barber
only really knows
how to do this
and crew cuts, so...
A barber?
Like the kind
with a pole outside?
He cut
our grandfather's hair.
He cuts my dad's hair and...
Now he cuts our hair.
[ CHUCKLES ]
May I just...?
Yep.
You have such
a beautiful face.
[ CHUCKLES ]
You know, it's funny
because I was actually
on my way to the salon.
Do you wanna come
check it out with me?
For what?
For a hairdo... For a girl...
In this century.
I-I would, but, um,
I-I'd have to ask my dad
for the money and...
No. N-n-no.
I don't...
it's on me.
Really?
It would make me
so happy.
Because I don't get to do this
with my boys.
Come on, prince Valiant.
[ CHUCKLING ] I don't know
who that is, but okay.
[ CHUCKLING ] Okay.
Where do you buy
your clothes?
Oh, dad gets most
of our clothes from work.
Oh, then I guess
we should be grateful
he doesn't work
at Hooters.
No, my mom
worked at Hooters.
She what?
Oh, my mom.
She used to work at Hooters.
She managed the one
over on lake street.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Oh.
So then he gets down on one knee
and proposes.
Right in the middle
of kickboxing class.
[ CHUCKLES ]
He's lucky he didn't get kicked
in the nuts.
Ooh.
[ STRAINED ]
Oh, my nuts! [ GIGGLES ]
ESPN.
This is the best passion fruit
I've ever tasted.
Try it.
And I got some
for your mom too.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So how'd you two
sexicans meet?
Yeah! Hittin' 'em
with the hard questions.
I like it.
Well, we met on a blind date.
Ugh.
Huh.
Those are the worst.
Oh.
I've been on ten blind dates
in my life.
All fatties.
Ten for ten.
[ CHUCKLING ] All fatties.
[ LAUGHTER ]
No offense, Jim.
What?
So what happened?
Where'd he take you?
Actually... Hooters.
Here we go.
Which was
wonderful service,
nice people... Really great.
Aw, how romantic.
Oh.
Aw, everyone's shimmying now.
[ GIGGLES ]
Shimmy, shimmy, shimmy.
Why you no shimmy, Jimmy?
Shimmy. Jim?
♪ I'm every woman,
it's all in me ♪
♪ I can read your thoughts
right now ♪
♪ every one from "a" to "z" ♪
♪ I'll make love to you
like you want me to ♪
♪ and I'll hold you tight,
baby, all through... ♪
♪ it's the end of the world
as we know it ♪
♪ it's the end of the... ♪
where's Larry?
What happened to Larry?
I'm right here, dad.
Why w-w-were the, uh...
how did this, uh...
w-what's happening
right now?
Um, well, Lauren gave me
her salon appointment...
Uh-huh.
...And they put in
hair extensions
and [CHUCKLING] makeup
and she even told them
how to style it
and what to do,
what not to do.
She was pretty amazing.
She was amazing, huh?
Do you want to go get some Sushi
from the bar?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Easy, scarecrow!
She's gotta bulk up!
Pork chops!
Lamb chops! Tri-tip!
Uh...
Let's go get our beef on?
[ CHUCKLES ]
Yeah?
[ SIGHS ]
Uh-oh. I think someone new
came to dinner.
A flying baby
named cupid.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
[ IMITATES FLYING ARROW ]
Oh, cu-ping!
Aw! You got me!
[ GROANS ]
[ MIMICS STABBING ]
[ GIGGLES ]
Now we're both in love.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
[ RETCHES ]
What's the matter?
I just looked at my daughter,
and I didn't really
recognize her.
Kinda threw me off for a minute.
Well, she's 15,
you know?
She's bound to grow up
at some point.
I know.
Call me crazy,
I just thought maybe
that would be my decision
'cause she's my kid!
Okay!
Awkward moment.
Uncomfortable. Tension.
I'm leavin' the table.
Who's with me?
Me.
Me, me, me.
I'm going.
Fine.
Wow. Whoa. I just...
can I ask ya?
What made you think
you could tart up my daughter
without my permission?
You're right.
I'm sorry.
I am.
I just find it hypocritical
from someone
who nearly killed my son.
Oh, so it was getting even?
Is that it?
No, it's not getting even,
but I just...
oh, my God.
She's beautiful.
Right.
With that pageboy prince Valiant
haircut you gave her
and the tracksuit,
are you kidding me?!
She looked very nice
with that haircut.
Dying on the inside
to come out!
Her mother was tomboyish
at her age,
and that was fine
with me.
You knew your wife
when she was 15?
I knew my wife
when I was 13.
I had a crush on her.
I have no idea
why she liked me back.
I was 90% goofy
and 10% loser.
Well, I was 60% urkel
and 40% screech.
PUT IT TO YOU THIS WAY:
If I didn't have braces,
my teeth would be hitting you
right now.
[ LAUGHS ]
I'm sorry
I yelled at you.
I feel like a jerk
because I put your kid
on a gooney bird
and I didn't ask your permission
and, and, uh...
no, but listen.
You're right.
I need to let go of the reins
a little bit.
I just want to say on behalf
of thathoo how happy we are
to see you two lovebirds
finally blending.
[ CHUCKLING ]
No, we're not blending.
We were just having
a conversation.
Just happy we haven't
killed each other yet.
♪ Blending, blending ♪
♪ yes, yes, you are blending ♪
♪ they're finally blending,
blending, blending ♪
♪ yes, you'll be touching ♪
he doesn't... we don't feel
that way about each other!
♪ Like wine and bobotie ♪
okay.
All right, let's go
get our beef on!
♪ And like malva pudding ♪
all right, thank you.
Oh. I think they're blending
over there!
Come now! Come now!
They're blending over here!
♪ Blending ♪
LOU: Daddy, look!
Oh!
JIM: Hey!
BRENDAN:
Oh, that is so cool!
[ HOT WATER'S "WAMKELEKILE"
PLAYS ]
[ LAUGHING ]
Woo-hoo!
What?
I thought I saw an eagle.
I saw a camel!
[ LAUGHS ]
JAKE: Hey, hilary.
Uh, you wanna come
in our truck?
Shouldn't you be in your coffin?
The sun's out right now.
Take a walk, homes.
Eh, eh, eh, yo, yo.
Go ahead.
[ GASPS ]
[ GAGS ]
Oh, my God.
[ HILARY LAUGHS ]
Look, children.
The bush pig has lost
its parents,
so it is being cared for
by mama and papa lion.
Even in nature,
there are blended families.
That's nice. Aw.
EDDY: That's sweet.
[ LIONS ROAR, PIG SQUEALS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
I may have misread
that situation.
You think so, buddy?!
[ ALL YELLING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ UPBEAT DRUM MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ WHISTLING ]
HILARY: Yeah, Lauren!
Yeah, baby!
No!
BRENDAN:
You can do it, mom!
Go Lauren! Go Lauren!
Whoa!
[ "WAMKELEKILE" CONTINUES ]
[ NO AUDIO ]
Yeah!
Emotional.
Jesus.
Time passing. Changes.
[ SIGHS ]
It's... it's... it's hard.
You gotta let it go.
Turning the page.
Movin' on.
She was a little kid
just a...
processing it.
Accepting it.
Mm-hmm.
The circle of life.
Painful, though.
It hurts, right?
Nah. Not for me.
I got a boy.
But you're
in the shithouse.
Thanks.
MFANA: [ LAUGHING ]
Whoo! Ha! The view is splendid!
Ubani omunye ozayo?
Which mean "who's next?"!
[ LAUGHS ]
Please, mom?!
What? That?
Are you crazy? No.
If mfana can do it,
I could do it.
It's totally safe.
There is no way I'm going to
let you do that.
Unless I try it first and
make sure you can handle it.
Yeah.
Yes! Yeah!
Cool!
Your mom is gonna do it.
You have nothing to worry about.
You are in tight.
You got 50-gauge
webbing here.
Possibly malaria is the only
thing you gotta think about.
Don't swallow anything
weird up there.
Okay. What happens if, like,
I wanna signal for help,
or, uh, like, if I decide to
change my [ RISING PITCH ] mind!
Oh, yeah, baby!
You look good!
Oh, my God!
I change my mind!
[ CHEERING ]
That's awesome!
Aah! Aah! Ah...
Oh!
Oh! Wow!
Oh, my God!
It's beautiful!
Go, mama, go!
Whoo!
Oh! Oh!
There are giraffes!
Jim, there are giraffes
right there!
I can see them!
Well, say hello for me!
[ LAUGHS ]
Oh, wow!
[ GASPS ]
Oh, this is so pretty!
[ LAUGHING ]
Oh, my God!
Elephants! Elephants!
Oh!
[ IMITATES WOLF HOWLING ]
Thatta girl!
Why is she screaming?
She's not screaming.
She's howling.
She's having fun.
[ IMITATES WOLF HOWLING ]
[ ALL HOWLING ]
Lookin' good up there,
baby!
Fly, Mrs. thorpopolis!
Fly like the wind!
[ LAUGHS ]
Tyler!
You've gotta try this!
[ ENGINE SPUTTERS ]
Why you slowing down?!
We're out of gas.
You're out of gas?!
What does that mean?!
Uh, we used to have gas.
But now we're out.
[ LAUREN HOWLING ]
Oh!
Oh! Oh, my God!
What's happening?
Jim!
We're out of gas!
What?!
Oh, no.
Oh.
Oh, my God! No!
This is all your fault!
Don't worry! My dad's gonna
come up with a plan!
What's the plan?!
Look for a gas station.
You suck.
Why did I let you talk me
into this?!
Listen to me!
When you get close to the
ground, start running fast!
I have the legs
of a corgi dog!
It doesn't matter
right now!
Move those little babies!
You cannot let your kids
see you die like this!
[ SCREAMING ]
Go! Go!
Now!
Get those legs goin'!
[ ALL CHEER ]
Oh, my God!
Rhino!
[ ALL YELLING ]
No!!!
Spread 'em!
Oh, my God!
Spread the legs!
Her bagina!
[ THUDS ]
Ow!
Yeah!
[ GRUNTS ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
Go, go, go, go, go!
Dad!
[ SNORES ]
[ DRUMS BEATING ]
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
Whew!
Ah.
I didn't have you pegged
for the massage type of guy.
It's the first massage
I'll ever do in my life.
I have to.
To see if they can rub
my pancreas out of my neck.
My God.
You're welcome, by the way.
[ SMACKS LIPS ]
For what?
"For what?"
For saving you.
You didn't save me.
You told me
to keep running.
Oh, my God. I did.
Why didn't you catch me?
I was supposed
to catch you?
Who am I, Batman?
Comin' at me like
700 Miles an hour.
You know, you're weighin'
about a buck fifty.
The inertia would rip
my arms off my body.
Yes. That's me.
I weigh a buck fifty.
If I'm holding
your left ass cheek.
[ LAUGHS ] I don't know
what women weigh.
You don't know anything.
Mm-hmm.
Have a nice massage.
We'll see.
WOMAN: All right.
Now do the same on your partner
while making sure to continue
to look deeply
into each others' eyes.
[ ALL MOANING ]
What is this?
A scene out
of "the doors"?
I-I-I don't know.
Uh-uh, I... ma'am?
Yeah.
I-I booked a massage.
Yes. You've booked for
the art of couples massage.
Oh! Actually there was an
avalanche in my yard, so I-I...
I just got a call from my
babysitter and there's...
...was comin' to my...
...An emer...
come on! This is exactly
what you guys need.
We'll form a massage train.
I'll be the caboose.
Unacceptable.
[ CHUCKLING ] I'm jokin'.
[ IMITATES
TRAIN WHISTLE SOFTLY ]
[ GIGGLES ]
Join us.
No, no, ma'am, seriously...
I'm so good. I...
I think you should.
This way.
And... There you go.
Oh, my God.
[ GRUNTING ] Ow!
Like that. There.
I... I guess.
Okay!
Let's, uh, loosen things up
by stroking your lover's neck.
[ SMACKS LIPS ] Okay.
Come on, now.
Don't be bashful.
Give yourself over
to the pleasure
of your loving partner's touch.
Yeah.
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
[ CHUCKLES ] Hello.
How are you?
[ TIGHTLY ] Ow.
Remember to keep
the touch soft, uh?
Lightly brush your fingers
against her skin.
[ SCOFFS ] It's so...
oh, God!
What's happening?!
Is there a bug on me?!
[ CHUCKLING ] No.
There's no bug.
I was just...
Tryin' to get...
Some skin, like she said.
Well, that hurts
the jugular.
I won't do it.
I'm sorry.
I-I-I don't know...
How to give you a...
[ ALL MOANING ]
Okay, so...
[ MOANS ]
There you go.
Oh.
That's actually
really nice.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Good.
Oh, God.
Oh.
I feel like I'm relaxing.
It's just...
oh, it's wonderful.
Excuse me.
Am I gonna get
some sorta rub action here
or does the guy do all the work
in Africa?
Very funny, Mr. moptopolis.
[ CHUCKLES ]
But he's right.
Ladies, it's time for you
to join in.
As your partner moves down
to your shoulders,
reach out and touch his ears.
Gently rub the lobes between
your thumb and index finger
as if you were rubbing
the morning dew
off a flower petal.
Uh-huh.
Are these
your flower petals?
Yes.
Now rub the dew.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ CHUCKLES ] Do the dew.
I'd be doing you
a really big favor
if I just yanked these
goofy things right off.
Oh, just sh-sh-shut up,
schlumpy shoulders.
I do have
No, you don't.
They're very nice.
I do.
But you know what helps
if... if y...
if you need to work
on your posture?
Here, just lift your arms
a little bit.
Watch, I'll show you.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
All right.
Aah!
[ LAUGHS ]
God. Feels very good.
You have nice shoulders.
Really?
No, you really have
a lot of muscle.
Eh, no.
Not as much as you.
From carrying that kid around
and smashing his head.
[ EDDY GRUNTS ]
GINGER: Oh, yeah!
Work 'em.
Mr. wernick. Those are not
your wife's shoulders.
Busted!
[ GIGGLES ]
Lovin' it, though.
Respect the vision.
I get it.
Gotta go for it, right?
You do!
[ SIGHS ]
[ HIGH-PITCHED VOICE ]
Whoa!
[ INHALES ] Mm,
that was so relaxing.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah.
I hope I put your pancreas
back where it belongs.
[ CHUCKLING ] I don't even know
where it is right now.
[ GINGER AND EDDY GIGGLING ]
EDDY: Are you
my sexy little wormhole?
GINGER: Yeah, I'm your sexy
little wormhole!
[ GRUNTS ] Sexy...
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
[ SIGHS ]
They have fun.
[ CHUCKLES SOFTLY ]
That's very pretty.
[ GIGGLES ]
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
You were...
you were very nice.
Thank you.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Oh, you know.
You're a strong woman.
Strong hands.
I'm glad
you like my hands.
Daddy?
Can Lauren put me to bed?
Sweetheart, daddy will put you
to bed in one second.
But I want Lauren.
Lauren w...
another time,
Lauren will do that.
[ WHINING ] But I want her
to put me to bed tonight.
And daddy said no.
[ GRUNTS PETULANTLY ]
No.
No!
[ GRUNTS PETULANTLY ]
[ GROWLING ]
I want Lauren.
I'm flattered.
[ LAUGHS ]
That's good.
You're all right.
Okay. How's that?
Are you all cozy now?
Yes.
Daddy?
Can you give us
some alone time?
I could go
to the bathroom outside.
Is that what you want?
You got it.
Thrown out
of my own tent.
I own him.
It seems that way.
Can you rub my head
so I have good dreams?
Of course.
What a cute little head.
[ JIM URINATING ]
[ WHINING ] Ew.
Couldn't go a little further
from the tent?
[ SCOFFS ]
What do you want from me?
There could be gorillas
out here, ready to kill.
[ URINATING STOPS,
RESUMES, STOPS, RESUMES ]
Well,
why don't you get them
to give you some Flomax
or something.
Yep, gettin' older.
I'll give you that.
Can you sing to me?
Um, sure.
What should I sing?
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪ way up high ♪
♪ there's a land
that I heard of ♪
♪ once in a lullaby ♪
♪ someday
I'll wish upon a star ♪
♪ and wake up where the clouds
are far behind me ♪
♪ where troubles melt
like lemon drops ♪
♪ away above
the chimney tops ♪
♪ that's where ♪
♪ you'll find me ♪
there's a gorilla
right there!
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CHUCKLING ]
I'm just kidding!
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry, I just...
I couldn't handle how
emotional it was getting.
I just... [ CHUCKLING ]
I'm so... get some rest.
I didn't mean
to do that to you.
[ APPLAUSE ]
JIM: So get in your stance.
That's right.
And spread your legs just
a little bit. Like an inch.
Elbow up.
It's all about balance.
That's right.
Keep your weight
right there.
How do you even
play cricket?
We're not playing cricket.
We're playing baseball.
The only thing at the hotel
they had
was this stupid...
Battle thingamajiggy.
Who's that guy?
He's some guy named Dale.
Uhhh,
he'll be pitchin' to ya.
Yeah, in cricket
we don't pitch, we bowl.
Hey, Dale.
How much am I payin' ya?
Five Brooklyn t-shirts from
your sporting goods store.
Okay, I'm gonna make it four
if you correct me again.
All right, Dale.
Pitch... or bowl one in.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
I stink at this.
No, it's not you.
It's not you.
Dale, you think maybe
you can reach the plate?
That would help.
Actually, in cricket
we bounce the...
I'll try. I'll try.
All right.
Elbow up. Come on.
Get there.
I don't wanna do this!
Hey, hey.
What are you doin'?
You don't throw your bat.
Or whatever this thing
is called.
A bat.
Thank you.
You're an athlete.
You're a sportsman.
You gotta respect
your equipment.
[ SIGHS ] Yes, sir.
We ain't leaving here
till you hit the ball
as good
as you ride an ostrich.
Pick up the bat.
Hey.
I know you're up there
all alone.
It's scary. You feel like
all the pressure's on you.
But guess what?
The pressure is on him.
Doesn't look like
he's feeling the pressure.
Oh, he's feeling it
all right.
He doesn't think he can get
the ball past ya.
I want ya to look him
right in the eyes
and let him know
you own him.
Go ahead.
That's it, big time.
Give him the stink eye.
[ GROWLS ]
What's his problem?
[ SCOFFS ]
Well, look at that.
You rattled him.
Okay. Dale, pitch it in
if ya got the guts.
Whoa!
Yes!
Did you see that?!
I killed it!
Let's do it
a hundred more times.
If I hit like that,
my dad's gonna start
comin' to my games.
What's goin' on here?
Jim just taught me how to make
the pitcher my bitch.
Ah-ah-ah-ah-ah.
My brother doesn't need you
to teach him how to hit!
Okay.
You wanna show him how to do it?
Let's see what you got.
I don't need to prove
anything to you, d-bag.
Dale, did he really
just call me a d-bag?
This shit just got real.
BRENDAN:
I'm gonna kill you.
JIM: Okay, we'll see.
Let's get your gloves up.
Face protected.
Kick his ass, Brendan!
What's that?
Kick his ass, Jim!
Uh-huh.
[ GRUNTS ]
Whoa! Whoa, whoa.
You see, you gotta...
you gotta look at your target.
How 'bout I put a picture
of your babysitter on my face?
Will you look at it then?
Huh?
[ GRUNTS ]
Oh! Oh, yeah, yeah.
Just leave her
out of this!
Use your right hand.
You're better with that one,
aren't you?
[ GRUNTING ]
All right, all right.
Boom.
Ow.
Oh!
You seem pissed at me.
You just hit me!
No! Before that.
Before that,
like when we first met.
Just think that my mom
could do better.
First of all,
she can't do better,
'cause no one's better
than me.
I am the greatest.
Secondly,
I think it's nice
that you wanna protect
your mommy.
I hate you!
[ GRUNTS ] Oh!
Oh. Whoa, whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Calm down. Calm down.
That was good, though.
Showin' a little somethin'
in there.
Listen... Being a man ain't
about pissin' and moanin'
anytime somethin's
botherin' you.
It's about dealin' with
what's in front of you.
So deal with me.
[ GRUNTS ] You...
are you okay?
[ PANTING ]
That was sneaky.
But I'm fine.
Does that make me a man,
now, jimbo?
No. Askin' me if I was okay,
that was a start.
♪ They are blending ♪
♪ they're blending and bonding
they're blending and bonding ♪
♪ they are bonding ♪
♪ they're blending and bonding
and learning ♪
yeah, that's great.
Didn't know you guys
worked out together,
but it makes sense.
♪ They're blending and bonding ♪
♪ when one person
meets another ♪
♪ blending and bonding ♪
♪ come together ♪
♪ oh, they are blending ♪
[ VOCALIZING AS BED VIBRATES ]
And then what happened?
TYLER: [ VOICE VIBRATING ]
The bowler threw it,
and I hit it
like a mile away.
[ VOICE VIBRATING ]
Yeah.
And then Jim taught me
how to box.
And after five minutes,
I basically knocked him out.
Yeah!
Well,
that was nice of him.
Kinda worked out well,
they came on this trip.
Yes, it did.
[ BOTH VOCALIZING ]
[ GASPS ]
JEN: "Lauren, you looked so hot
in this dress
"I had to buy it for you.
And by 'buy, ' I mean 'steal.'"
[ CHUCKLES ]
"Hope you're having fun
on my vacation."
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
So its... its tongue
was ridiculous.
[ CHUCKLES ] It got me,
like, all over.
It was, like, in balls.
They were like... [GROWLS]
Oh! Like a stick...
like a stem.
Like... like a stem going
against each other,
head-to-head.
HILARY: Dad.
Did you comb your hair?
No. Got out of the shower
like this, I guess.
You took a shower?
I shower!
I'm allowed to shower.
My God.
I haven't taken a shower
since we got here.
I know. You stink.
I love it.
Yeah, I stink bad.
Yeah, you stink real bad.
Your breath
smells terrible.
[ BOTH EXHALING ]
Where's Lauren?
♪ I'm every woman,
it's all in me ♪
♪ I can read your thoughts
right now ♪
♪ every one from "a" to "z" ♪
♪ I'll make love to you
like you want me to ♪
♪ and I'll hold you tight ♪
♪ it's the end of the world
as we know it ♪
♪ it's the end... ♪
♪ I kissed a girl
and I liked it ♪
♪ the taste of her
cherry chapstick ♪
♪ I kissed a girl... ♪
wow.
Look at mom.
[ SINGSONG VOICE ]
Hello.
Dad!
Say something to her.
Yes, yes.
You look very, very nice.
Oh, well, thank you.
You showered.
Am I really known as
[CHUCKLING] the non-shower guy?
I shower all the time,
guys.
[ LAUGHS ]
NICKENS:
Ladies and gentlemen...
Don't listen to her, okay?
...it's the final night
of our blended family experience
here in Africa.
[ CROWD BOOS ]
Boo!
Our tradition is to invite
the kiddies to the pool area
for our famous kids-only
safari buffet
and ten-foot chocolate
rain forest fountain!
Can we go, dad?!
All right, go ahead.
Stay with your sisters,
though.
Oooh! My boy
here's a chocoholic.
You better watch out.
Or he's gonna jump in
and come out lookin' like
a handsome hershey bar.
[ EDDY LAUGHS ]
Did you see that?
I made him smile.
He tried not to,
but he couldn't help himself.
We're gonna be
a great family.
Yes, we are.
Love you.
All of the little ones
have gone.
Tonight
the dining room is...
[ DEEP VOICE ] Adults-only.
[ CROWD OOHS ]
Yeah, now
we're gettin' there.
Let's have all you blended
lovers on the dance floor.
[ SINGERS HARMONIZING ]
♪ Love is a many blended thing ♪
♪ it's the April rose ♪
♪ that only grows... ♪
it's crazy, huh?
The song.
He took the word "splendid"
and replaced it with "blended."
So clever. It rhymes!
But the real word is
"splendored."
So wouldn't it be
"blendored"?
What's this now?
[ CHUCKLES ] I'm just rambling.
I'm sorry. What...?
[ LAUGHS ]
Are you ready,
Mr. chiapetolis?
"Chiapetolis"?
All right. That was...
he finally got it.
[ LAUGHS ]
Ready for what?
You scheduled
a star-gazing experience.
So... Mrs. Chiapetolis, would
you like to come join me?
Oh. Yeah.
All right.
♪ Once high
on a windy hill ♪
♪ or two hills, that's good ♪
♪ on a morning mist ♪
♪ two lovers kiss ♪
[ LAUGHING ]
Just a little bit farther.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Here we are.
Dinner for two.
Oh, yeah.
Wow.
It's good.
I gotta give it up
to dick.
He's probably the most
romantic guy on the planet.
Yeah, he's got the moves.
No doubt about it.
[ GASPS ]
I bet this is where he was
gonna ask Jen to marry him.
Maybe.
We were able to get everything
you asked for this morning,
except the sticks of cheese
in the shape of a heart.
Shh, shh!
Cheese sticks?
Did you set this up?
I wanted a do-over.
For that
first date fiasco.
I'm better than that.
Izithandane ziyafuna ukuba munye
mfana ngomoya nagemiza.
WHICH MEANS:
"Lovers long for the moment
their souls may blend
in a whisper."
Mm.
May this be your moment.
Did you eat pork chops
with... Tuna fish
today at lunch?
Yes, I did.
I can tell.
Apologies.
I will brush my teeth
presently,
Mr. lollipopolis.
I'd brush 'em twice.
And did you really [LAUGHING]
call me "lollipopolis"?
[ LAUGHTER ]
It's theodopolis.
Just for the record.
I know. I just like to have fun.
Jim Friedman.
Wha...?
Whoa!
What?!
That was good.
Thank you, mfana.
NICKENS:
♪ ...Be my endless love ♪
how 'bout thathoo
showin' up everywhere?
They were in my shower
this mornin'.
I had a very nice time
with them too.
There she is.
Oh, thank you so much.
Hey, bubbles.
Nice wiggle,
but you grew a tail.
Here's lookin' at you.
Uh-huh.
No, really. Looking at you,
'cause you're actually
looking at me this time.
You... Have the most
beautiful...
...kids.
Oh, thank you.
Sure.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
You're a great mom, too.
You're a pretty good mom
yourself.
I'll take that.
Tyler has a playoff game
on Saturday...
[ INHALES ]
Yeah?
...and I think that...
For the very first time,
he won't actually be
completely dreading it,
thanks to you.
Tell your, uh... his father,
the more he works with him,
the more he's gonna get
confident,
the more he's gonna belt the
ball anytime he gets up there.
Yeah, well, his dad's
not really into working
with him, you know,
'cause to do that,
he'd have to show up,
which he's just...
[ SIGHS ]
Not good at.
You gotta show up
for your kids.
It should be boring how...
Reliable a parent is.
I... it's funny to me that
some people don't get that.
You do!
I mean, your kid
needs to come first
100% of the time.
Absolutely. 99%.
1% of the time,
I think we are allowed
to get what we want.
Ah, God.
I forgot what it was like
to want something.
I vaguely remember
it... Feels good.
I can't do this.
I'm sorry.
I really...
I'm... I'm...
it's not you.
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
I thought I could do this.
I just...
[ "CARELESS WHISPER" PLAYS ]
Sorry about them too.
They're still awesome.
Sorry I did that to ya.
He didn't kiss you?
He's an idiot.
Although,
you have to admit.
The monkeys playing
the violins and stuff?
[ CHUCKLING ]
That is hilarious.
I can't believe that we both
found these great guys
and we're not gonna end up
with them.
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
Are you gonna get that?
Hi. It's not a good time
right now.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Yeah.
I "l" word you so hard.
And you know what?
I am gonna make
"l" word to you
for at least
an hour and a half.
[ GIGGLES ]
[ CHUCKLING ] Okay.
Hmm.
That was my mom.
And she's doing good.
[ SIGHS ]
All right.
I'm giving dick
another chance.
To do what?
Get rid of his kids?
I'm gonna meet
his children.
[ SCOFFS ]
You should try saying that
without contorting
your face so much.
I'm gonna meet
his children.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Better.
I'm sorry about Jim.
Me too.
[ SIGHS ]
Why didn't you
kiss her, man?
I couldn't.
I just...
I was afraid it wasn't
the right thing to do.
What did Africa do
to you?
[ CRYING ]
LOU: Ow!
JIM: That doesn't hurt.
Stop.
Ow!
I'm trying my best.
Just sit still.
Does it look pretty?
It looks fantastic.
Yeah.
Yay.
[ HILARY LAUGHING ]
No.
You look nice.
Oh, thanks.
Where you off to?
Oh, I'm goin' on a date
with Jake.
How can you go out
with Jake?
He lives in Vancouver.
Hi, Mr. Friedman.
Yay there, skeletor.
Listen, make sure
plenty of beef.
Seriously.
She's got tryouts this week.
Lamb chops,
pork chops, tri-tips.
You got it.
That's the way.
Garbage twisties?
I-I don't know how to...
you're awful.
Just fix it, then.
So, when are we gonna
see Lauren again?
Something happened
between you guys.
No.
What are you, crazy?
Nothin' happened.
Dad, come on.
I saw the way you looked at her,
and I saw the way
she looked at you.
It's undeniable.
You guys are infatuated
with each other.
Jake, butt out.
Sorry, sir.
Don't you guys have
anything better to do
than look at people
looking at each other?
Besides, wha-what am
I supposed to do?
Change our whole lives just
because I'm in love with her?
Yes!
Wow.
[ GINGER SQUEALS ]
So romantic!
Lovin' it!
Takin' a risk.
Go get her, baby!
I know I confused you.
I just...
I had to make sure.
For my wife
and for my kids.
And for your kids.
And for you. And...
Just so we have no lies.
It was me who drank your beer
at Hooters.
I dunno why I did that.
I get free beers there,
so it was just panic then.
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
Yeah?
This is 323, right?
Yeah.
I was lookin' for l-Lauren.
You and me both.
TYLER: Jim!
Big time!
Look at you!
Mom's not home.
This is my dad.
Mark.
Yeah. Who are you?
Jim!
The cool guy from the safari.
Do you wanna "bowl" me
a few pitches?
Uh... I'm sure your father
wants to do that with ya.
Mm. No, he doesn't.
No, no, no, no.
Go get your bat, big time.
Hey! We can all play!
I'll get Brendan's glove.
He never uses it.
Boy, he hasn't shut up
about that Africa trip.
Your kids are... Incredible.
Yeah.
That's why Lauren and I
are, you know, trying to make
things work again.
For them.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
I'll tell her
you came by.
And, uh...
I'll put these in the bedroom...
Next to where we make love.
Okay.
Tell, uh, Tyler
I said goodbye.
Where's Jim goin'?
He had stuff to do,
I guess.
Can you and me play,
then?
Yeah, of co...
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
Oooh! Saved by the bell.
Hey, what's up?
You busy?
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
Hi.
Oh! Hi.
[ CHUCKLING ] Is there a gq
photo shoot going on here?
No... oh, no.
I'm just, uh...
I'm just chillin'.
I'm sorry
that took so long.
Thank you for watching
after the boys.
I'm done now
and I'm guessing
you have somewhere
you gotta go, so...
How do you always
look so great?
Yeah?
It's my haven't-washed-my-hair
in-three-days look.
Thanks for noticing.
[ CHUCKLES ]
You're so funny.
It's hard for me to imagine you
with someone else.
Really?! It wasn't hard for you
to imagine yourself
with someone else
when you cheated on me.
No matter what I say, you
always bring it back to that.
I could say, "hey,
look at that house."
And you'd say,
"oh, we lived in a house
when you cheated on me."
Or I could say,
"pass that pickle."
And you could say...
something about a pickle
and you cheating on me.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
It's fun to laugh with you
again, Lauren.
We used to do that
all the time.
You brought flowers?
Yeah.
Why'd you bring flowers?
Because you deserve
flowers.
Lauren, when you went away
to Africa,
I did a lot of thinking.
You and I, we have so much
history together.
Two boys.
One receptionist.
I... look,
I made a mistake! That's...
you made at least four mistakes
that I know of.
Made. Past tense.
I-I was a jerk.
Lauren...
You were the best thing
in my life.
You and the boys.
And boys need
their fathers.
They do.
I know
that I'm a good father.
I just need
to prove it to them.
Well, you can!
It's not too late.
Is it too late...
For this?
[ CHUCKLING ]
What... Are you doing?!
I'm comin' home, baby.
Oh! G... mark!
Get off of me!
You don't live here
anymore!
Is there someone else?
[ CHUCKLES ]
No. And that's none
of your business anyway.
You're interested
in being a good father?
Tyler has a game
on Saturday. Be there.
Dad?
I didn't mean to wake you.
Sorry.
I was talking to mom
before bed.
Mm-hmm.
And she says she has
a lot of stuff to do.
She does?
Y-yeah.
So she might not be able
to hang around as much.
[ SIGHS ]
Okay.
She also said you need to
increase my allowance to $5.
She's very generous.
[ VOICE BREAKING ]
I just...
[ SOBS ] I don't want her
to disappear.
Sweetheart, she's never
gonna disappear.
Never ever.
You can let her go.
She will always
be right here.
And I will always be
here.
I promise you.
[ SOBS ]
By the way,
mom loved the Africa trip.
So did I.
I miss her.
Your mother
was the greatest.
I mean Lauren.
Me too.
We don't have to let go
of her, too, do we?
Come here.
Brendan, don't forget that
I'm picking you up for scouts,
so don't take the bus home.
[ CHILDREN SNICKER ]
Thanks for telling everyone
I'm still in scouts, mom.
You're a good boy.
Be proud of who you are.
Say one word
and you're dead.
You're driving a minivan.
It's dick's.
I'm off to buy toilet paper
for team theodopolis.
When the team
needs toilet paper,
the co-captain goes
and gets it.
And believe me, those kids
never stop crapping.
Kids need to crap.
You need anything from...
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
...Walmart?
I'm good.
See ya
at the pta meeting.
Okay, foxy.
[ CROWD CHEERING ]
MAN: Yeah.
You've got this one.
MAN #2: Yeah! Base on!
Please stop that.
Uh, this is so good,
honey. This...
that's okay. Great.
This is family.
This is fun for me.
WOMAN:
All right, all right!
MAN #3:
Way to make contact.
Way to go, dad.
GIRL: One out to go,
but standard fence
has a rally going.
MAN #4: Standard fence,
let's do it!
Now batting, number 23,
Tyler Reynolds.
[ PLAYS "BEETHOVEN'S FIFTH" ]
Hey, that's not nice!
Aw, shut up.
That kid's awful.
Go, Tyler!
MAN: Go, Tyler!
Tracy.
What's your head
doing here?
MAN: Easy out.
MAN #2: New batter!
MAN #3: Easy!
You got him, Kevin.
Strike one!
I'm so sorry
mark didn't show up.
LAUREN: I mean, he just
doesn't get it, you know?
Your kids have to come first
100% of the time.
Well, like 99%.
You get 1% for yourself.
That's great news.
Well, no matter what, you have
to show up for your kids.
Like him.
Hey, hey!
All right, big time!
Come on, Tyler!
Lookin' good out there!
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
Get that elbow up!
Elbow up!
Incredible.
ESPN: Yeah!
Eye on the ball!
Come on, Tyler.
Strike two!
All right, all right!
Nice cut, nice cut.
Slow it down a little bit.
Bend those knees.
Balance, okay?
Take care of this.
That's it.
Elbow up.
Higher, higher.
Now,
remember the stink eye.
[ GROWLS ]
The mustache is rattled.
Come on, Tyler, let's go!
Come on, Tyler!
Take 'em deep.
[ YELPS ]
You hit it!
Run, Tyler, run!
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CROWD CHEERS ]
Keep goin', brother!
Go!
Whoo!
Don't hesitate.
Come, come!
Come to me, big time!
Go!
Run to me!
Keep it goin', Tyler!
We're goin' home, baby!
We're goin' home!
[ GRUNTS ]
Safe!
[ CHUCKLING ] Yeah!
Yes!
Do you believe in miracles?!
Yeah! Whoo!
Yeah!
That's my brother!
Thank you.
All you in there,
big time.
Oh, my God!
What are you doing?!
I love you!
That was amazing.
I'm so sorry
to show up like this.
I-I was at your house
the other day
and I saw your ex-husband
blow off Tyler
when he wanted to practice
and I know you guys are trying
to work it out, but it just...
it just broke my heart.
We're not working it out.
That's never gonna happen.
Really?
What were you doing
at my house?
I came by
to tell you that...
I think it's okay now.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Okay for what?
Okay to have one
of those rare, rare moments
where we get
what we want.
Oh. Well,
what do we want?
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
You know what we want.
Yeah.
I think the kids
want it, too.
Not as much as I do there,
schlumpy shoulders.
[ LAUGHS ]
Wait.
I can't do this.
You're kiddin' me.
[ CHUCKLES ] Totally.
I just had to get you back
for Africa.
Come on.
[ CHUCKLES ] You know somethin'?
Your mom is hot.
Your dad's
pretty hot, too.
Not hot.
[ LAUGHTER ]
Come on,
you deserve a nice massage.
[ LAUGHING ] Ow!
Oh, it's good.
Come on, you like that,
you like that.
Oh, it hurts so good.
[ LAUGHS ]
Ah, sorry.
♪ They're blending ♪
♪ look, they're blending ♪
♪ are mending ♪
♪ hearts are mending ♪
♪ sad times ending ♪
♪ good times
spending with love ♪
♪ are friending ♪
♪ kids are friending ♪
♪ wedding ♪
♪ wedding trending ♪
♪ blending, friending,
blending, friending ♪
♪ movie ending ♪
yebo!
[ SCREAMING ]
Yeah! Yebo!
♪ I will take your side ♪
♪ you make me feel like ♪
♪ I've been waiting
my whole life ♪
♪ I will take your side ♪
♪ you make me feel like ♪
♪ I've been waiting
my whole life ♪
♪ and I could die ♪
♪ to find that simple kind
of love ♪
♪ you can't deny ♪
just say it.
♪ Been talking about it
until I killed my voice ♪
♪ but it didn't change
a single thing ♪
♪ it's that simple truth ♪
♪ that always means
the most to you ♪
♪ and you know it ♪
♪ so just say it ♪
♪ and we were spilling wine
on your best friend's bed ♪
♪ when you said
this was ridiculous ♪
♪ and you kissed me ♪
♪ just because
you knew it'd shut me up ♪
♪ all right, well, then say it ♪
♪ just say it ♪
♪ I will take your side ♪
♪ you make me feel like ♪
♪ I've been waiting
my whole life ♪
♪ and I could die ♪
♪ to find that simple kind
of love ♪
♪ you can't deny ♪
♪ and I could die ♪
♪ to find that simple kind
of love ♪
♪ you can't deny ♪
just say it.
♪ I don't love wonton soup
that comes from a can ♪
♪ I don't love to hear stories
about the bogeyman ♪
♪ I don't love the smell
of aunt lizzy's minivan ♪
♪ but I love you ♪
♪ I don't love
falling off a seesaw ♪
drinking chocolate milk ♪
♪ without a straw ♪
♪ I don't love when grandma
walks around in just her bra ♪
[ LAUGHTER ]
♪ But I love you ♪
♪ I don't love that you guys
are better than me at math ♪
♪ I don't love when a horse
makes a poopy on the path ♪
♪ I don't love when my sister
pees in the bath ♪
♪ sorry! ♪
♪ But I love you ♪
♪ I love it when you put
together my toys ♪
♪ I love it when we listen
to the backstreet boys ♪
♪ I love it when you let me
eat breakfast for dinner ♪
♪ daddy's pleasure ♪
♪ when I kiss your head ♪
♪ I love it ♪
♪ when I jump on your bed ♪
♪ when I let you skip
Hebrew school ♪
♪ and go to the movies
instead ♪
♪ I love it ♪
♪ when your timeout ends ♪
♪ when your boo-boo mends ♪
♪ I love it ♪
♪ when I rip a juicy fart
♪ in front of all
your mommy's friends ♪
I don't love it.
♪ We do! ♪
♪ When you and mommy
do dancing shows ♪
♪ I love it ♪
♪ and she lets you wear
all her clothes ♪
♪ I love it ♪
♪ when I fall asleep
on the couch ♪
♪ and you guys
paint all my toes ♪
♪ I love it ♪
♪ I love you ♪
♪ I love it! ♪
[ HOT WATER'S "WAMKELEKILE"
PLAYS ]