Are you okay?
- I'm executive of my mother's estate,
and as such,
it would mean the world
if I could set up a college
fund for the girls,
if for no other reason than taxes.
Ladies, this is Sam.
He's our new R.N.
You know I dismissed him because
he was wacked out on benzos.
He successfully completed
a rehabilitation program.
I have a stack of glowing
recommendations on my desk.
Can we get something
straight right now?
- You and I are not buddies.
- If you say so.
- You missed one.
- It doesn't matter.
The sun's going to explode and eat
up all the other planets anyways.
Wow, that's nice.
- The ring I could never afford to give her.
Still can't.
How am I supposed to know?
He wears a big fucking bracelet
that says "I am diabetic."
I need to lodge a formal
complaint against a nurse.
Super.
- What do we got?
- Jackie, really, go.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
( phone buzzes )
( hisses )
Goodness, that took a long time.
I was using an iron
that was not plugged in.
Fiona says Grace has
been getting up at night
and unplugging appliances.
Is that true?
Faulty wiring
causes more house fires
than cigarettes and arson combined.
Where'd you hear that?
This is the best smoke detector
they make.
It's also
a carbon monoxide detector.
I've been saving my allowance
to buy it.
( sighs ) Sweetie, thank you,
but your allowance is for fun
things like toys and stickers.
Here, sit down, sweetie.
Eat your breakfast.
Hey, Gracie, let Mom and Dad worry
about smoke detectors, okay?
Put your money away.
I just don't want the
house to burn down.
Wow.
You know the #1 ingredient
in hotdogs is cancer?
I partied like a
20-year-old last night.
Managed to score
some grade-A ecstasy.
Dvornoff in Psych told me
it would only last six hours
and it's been nine!
Still going strong.
You know...
I think my mother's death
ripped something open in me.
You have wonderful daughters, Jacks.
Cherish them.
I will. Oh my goodness.
Do they know I'm their godmom yet?
Well, as it turns out,
I have not had that conversation--
Just call them. Call them.
And then let's all go
to the St. Regis for lunch,
just us girls.
- Huh?
- The girls are in school.
Oh, we'll yank 'em out.
Love is more important than reading!
( garbled ) Maybe
I'll just catch a taxi
- and then go-- no one will notice--
- Right now? No.
You're staying right here.
Do not go anywhere.
- Stay right here.
- Taxi!
(Jackie:) Stay here.
( muffled ) Hey, guys.
Was that a walk of shame?
I don't want to know.
Do we think Zoey got
her pipes cleaned?
Dyahhh.
That's like seeing Santa naked--
It's not right.
( babbles incoherently )
- That's paper.
- Oh.
Hi. You the parents?
What can I do for you?
It's our son Harry.
He has a history of
breathing problems.
Our pediatrician said it
could be cystic fibrosis.
We scheduled a sweat
test to be sure,
but it isn't for another month.
He woke up choking. Could you help him?
- Sure.
Harry, my name is Jackie.
Can I listen to your chest?
Okay.
Okay. Well, it's restricted,
But he's definitely
getting some air.
Harry, do you like coloring books?
Okay. Why don't I get
you some coloring books
and I'll have a doctor come and take a look?
- I don't like doctors.
- Yeah, me neither.
- ( mother chuckles )
Lennox Hill has newer equipment,
but we can certainly bule him up
and give him a sweat test here
- if you like.
- That--
that-- that would be great.
Okay. You just sit tight.
I'll take care of that.
Dr. Cooper will be right in.
( humming, singing softly )
- Oh!
- ( shrieks ) Oh my God!
Dr. O'Hara, I'm so sorry!
Zoey, ma petite fleur!
- Zoey, get back to work.
- But she's--
( giggles ) here.  Come here.
You, come with me.
Dear Dr. O'Hara,
I would like to take
this opportunity
to thank you for the lovely scarf.
Ooh. Stationery
and stamps.
Mmn, stamps!
There are little hearts there.
Hey, Jackie, Dr. O'Hara.
Hello.
- Can I help?
- Actually--
No, we are good.
Your accent-- London with
a touch of Sussex, right?
Indeed.
- I spent my junior year in England.
- I'm kind of an anglophile.
- How convenient.
I'm an anglo.
- So what's going on?
- Nothing.
We're good. You can leave, please.
Went clubbing. Tad dehydrated.
Feel like humping the world.
- Did you do a little X?
- ( exhales slowly )
Chasing your GnTs with a
little Thai stick. Impressive.
Does she have a little problem?
- No, her mother just died.
She went out clubbing last night--
You know what?
Get the hell out of here.
Go!
( softly ) Bye.
Jacks.
Bored. Need magazines.
Thor, give me your magazines.
What magazines?
Give them to me, including "In Touch".
How can you read this crap?
Please don't amplify my shame.
I know you like "In Touch".
Whoo!
Oh, look. Goldie and Kate--
mother and daughter
together just...
loving each other.
I should've called
my mother more often.
Did you know that when
I was at university
we used to speak to
each other every day?
No, I didn't.
I'd forgotten how affectionate
she was on the phone.
Speaking of, I can't figure out
how to delete her from my contacts.
Clearly, you need to give
yourself some time to grieve.
In the meantime: CT scan, CT scan,
this one needs a full workup,
this one needs a shitload
of Haldol and a psych eval.
Sign off on these.
Then you can read your crap.
Hey. Need a hand?
Oh hey, man. How you doing?
- Great. How are you?
- Good.
Oh no, I think I can
handle this one.
Thanks.
Strong man.
There you go.
So how's everything?
How's the family?
How's your wife? Jackie, right?
Yeah. Good memory.
Yeah, she's good, man.
We're good.
Things are great--
better than ever.
That's nice.
Hey, did she like
that ring you got her?
Did I show you that?
You do pay attention.
Yeah, man, she loved it.
- She loved it.
- That's great.
So how about you, huh?
Haven't seen you for a while.
Yeah.
I, uh-- I tried to kill myself.
I OD'd on some drugs trying
to get a girl's attention.
You believe that? Didn't work.
Man.
Yeah.
I'm just fucking with you.
I didn't try to kill myself.
Jesus.
You are a sick fuck.
I know, I know.
I got a sick sense of humor.
( chuckles ) How about a beer?
Yeah. You got a bud?
Yeah.
To love. To women.
To Jackie. Cheers.
Cheers.
How you feeling, little buddy?
Hot.
I guess that was a silly question.
Anyway, it seems strange, I know,
but it is the standard test
to confirm or eliminate
the diagnosis of cystic fibrosis--
we force Harry to sweat
and then we measure
the amount of chloride
in his perspiration.
We know.
Jackie explained everything to us.
Good.
How much longer does he
have to wear all this?
Uh, not much longer.
Then I'll do everything I can
to get you the test
results quickly.
And I'll do everything I
can to make sure he does.
- But I'm on it, so...
- And I'm on him.
- I got it.
- I'll just check
and double check.
A little bit O.C.D., but not a
bad thing if you're a nurse.
Your son's in good hands.
- What are you doing?
- Tweeting.
People follow my life online.
I'm sharing my thoughts
with the world.
Are you blogging about
that little boy?
It's not a blog; it's Twitter.
You can't do that.
It's private.
Everyone remains
anonymous except for me.
If I said "cys fib," would you
know that's "cystic fibrosis"?
If I said "eff you,"
would you know that's "eat shit"?
( slaps button )
Bee-yotch.
- That's a nice scarf.
- Well, thanks.
It's from hermès,
Which I think is a
pretty good store.
Dr. O'Hara gave it to me.
- Oh, cool.
- Mm-hmm.
Does Dr. O'Hara have a problem?
I mean, with drugs.
No.
- Does Jackie?
- No.
- You sure?
- Positive.
And since you're asking,
I don't do drugs either.
Although, when I go to great adventure,
I do take Dramamine
'cause once on rolling
thunder I yacked
and it was a huge bummer.
( man shouting ) I see your sins,
For I am God!
That's God.
It's 12:53 pm.
Vermin!
Huh.
- I used to be totally scared of him,
but now, not so much.
- ( ranting continues )
- Oh, and he's crazy.
Hey, you! Yeah, you,
Sir with the misshapen head,
how do you wake up in
the morning?!
I love this guy.
And you! Hey you, pizza-face!
You shall never marry!
You won't even be engaged!
I am God!
Bow bow bow to me,
you sinners and slu--
( groans )
Uh-oh! God's down!
A lake of fire will
swallow you up!
Pimps and whores!
- On my count-- one, two, three.
- Get the fuck off me!
I'll smite every one of
you fuckin' assholes!
Psychosis. Can I have some
vitamin H over here, please?
- Haldol-- shaken not stirred.
- Getting the IV.
This is God, age unknown.
He's probably about 50.
He lives across the street.
Schizophrenic, currently off meds.
I know this guy.
- Got hit in the head with a bottle.
He told me I was super handsome,
like Clark Gable.
I retract!
Let's stitch him up.
You are an angel.
Will you stop fucking
twittering and focus, please?
"Bitchy nurse being bitchy again."
Don't do that.
Don't you dare twitter about me.
Thanks for telling me I'm an angel.
When I was younger,
I actually thought I was an angel
because I had a round face.
And I thought about
becoming a nun--
( whispers ) "Sound of Music"--
But I really like boys,
So I didn't.
Not all boys. There's one boy.
More man. Man-boy.
He's totally...
Picka picka picka picka.
It feels really inappropriate
Talking about this with you,
God, Sir.
You know, when I hit my head,
I seen something.
Like what? Like a bottle
whizzing towards you?
I seen this tunnel
with this incredibly bright
light at the end of it,
but it didn't hurt to look at.
And at the end of the tunnel,
I met the most loving presence.
And I just knew it was God.
I saw God.
But I thought you were God.
I mean, I thought you
thought you were God.
- I am God.
- So you saw yourself?
- No.
- So you saw God
and it wasn't you.
Yeah.
So... ( clicks tongue )
I guess that means
That you're not God.
Oh my God.
Oh my-- I'm not God!
- I'm not God!
- Wait.  Calm down.
I'm not God!
- ( yells )
- ( shrieks )
I'm not God!
( yelling )
- Zoey, handle it.
- ( groans )
I'm not God! ( yells )
Hey, Jackie, I found these.
Okay.
Where?
- Right over here on the floor.
- Good catch.
- I'll take 'em.
- Are they yours?
- Are they mine?  No.
What is hospital policy
Regarding lost or found drugs?
Don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
- Oh, why so desperate?
- Excuse me?
Well, you just seem really
anxious for me to hand them over.
Do you want to get your ass kicked?
Give them to me. Now.
Come with me.
Any unidentifiable drugs or
substances go into the slot.
That is hospital procedure. Got it?
Pain in my ass.
- Hey.
- Hey, babe.
Listen, Luis is a firefighter, right?
- Yeah.
- Is he there?
- Yeah, he's here.
Can you do me a favor?
Can you ask him to go over to the house
and explain to Grace that the
house will not just burn down?
Maybe that'll ease her
mind a little bit?
- That's a great idea.
- All right.  Love you.
Love you too. Bye.
- The wife?
- Yeah.
I fuckin' love beer nuts.
- ( knocks on door )
- Come in.
Hi. A few things.
First of all, Coop will
not stop twittering.
It is interfering with work
and it's pissing me off.
That's interesting.
Dr. Cooper lodged a formal
complaint against you.
Against me? Really?  For what?
Insubordination and
general bitchiness.
Insubord-- fuckin' A.
Twitter tweetering
fuckin' dickhead.
- Anything else?
- Yes.  This Sam guy,
like every newly-sober person,
he's convinced that everyone
around him is an addict.
It's like the born-again
guy we had last year.
I'm just sayin'.
Also, one of my nurses needs
a pediatric psych referral.
- Which one?
- She'd rather not say.
Be helpful if I knew
how old the child was
before making a referral.
Yes, well, she's a
very private person
and she would rather not have
everyone know her personal life.
I would say the kid's between,
I don't know, 7 and 12.
Gender?
- Look, she wants a list of shrinks
that take our insurance and
she wants it anonymously.
You know what? Forget about it.
Jackie.
Here is the best child
psychiatrist I know
and she takes our health plan.
Thank you.
She was tremendously
helpful with my boy.
Thanks.
Hi, I have the family
of a little boy
waiting for the results
of a CF sweat test.
I would really love
to send them home.
I can only give the results to
the doctor who ordered the tests.
I know. Dr. Cooper
really wants the results,
but he's in with a
trauma right now.
And if the test is positive,
I need to set up an IV--
Look, I'd really like to help
you out here, but I can't.
( sighs ) Okay.
Everything's really
preliminary at this point,
So it's just better not to give out.
Sorry.
- How old?
- Oh.  Three months.
- Smiling yet?
- Mm-hmm.
It's really awful
when they get sick.
- What's the name?
- Miller; first name Harry.
Well, the whole run's not complete,
but the prelims look good.
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Okay, so I went to the lab
and talked to the tech.
You have to keep in mind that the
doctor has not seen the results yet,
But so far they are
looking very good.
- Thank God.
- Why don't you all go home
- and get some rest?
- Thank you so much.
You've been--
you've been so wonderful.
Really? We can take him home?
- I would.
- Just... Thank you.
See ya, Harry.
- ( whispers ) Say bye.
- Bye.
I'm telling you, man, it's great.
You can see the
lights of Citi Field.
It's way brighter
than Shea used to be.
You been yet, to Citi?
- Mmn, not yet.
- You want to go sometime?
My brother gets me tickets.
Well, I would love that.
Cool.
- Islanders too.
- No shit.
Would I shit you?
( chuckles )
( plastic crinkling faintly )
- Thor?
- ( crinkling stops )
( meekly ) It's not what you think.
Donuts.  Really?
You already lost one eye,
am I right?
- How'd you know?
- Today in trauma
with God,
I had my hand next to your face
for about 20 minutes
before you saw it.
Also, I just kind of
used my spidey sense.
You are the only one who knows.
I haven't even told
my new boyfriend yet.
Thanks for covering.
It's a shell.
It's porcelain.
They paint it to
match my other eye.
It's great. You would never know.
- You wanna see?
- Sure.
Ooh, look at you.
( sighs )
What do you think of
the new guy-- Sam?
Oh.
Uh, well, I think he's really smart
and incredibly cute.
And I think he's probably
an excellent nurse.
- I don't like him.
- Yeah, he's dead to me.
Go on, yell at someone.
I don't want to.
Oh, come on.
You're so good at it.
Ooh.
Look at the bald dude.
Say, "Hey, baldy, you're all bald.
Grow some hair, you idiot."
What's the point?
I'm not God.
Oh, sure you are.
I'm not.
I've seen God and he wasn't me.
- That doesn't mean anything.
- It means everything.
It means I'm not God.
It means my life is a sham.
Well, Jesus wasn't God.
So?
- But he's still, like, really important
in the religious
hierarchal stratification.
So maybe you're like Jesus.
Uh-huh?
Hey, Jesus was the son of God.
So maybe you're like
the nephew of God
or the brother-in-law of God.
I like where this is going.
Hey you, strumpet with
the thinning hair!
I can see your soul!
You whore!
Lather, rinse, repeat!
That's how they'll get you!
Where's the sweat-test kid?
I sent them home.
Why don't you run to Akalitus
and lodge a formal complaint?
What do you mean
you sent them home?
What don't you understand?
They were sitting here for over six hours
while you were dicking
around somewhere.
So I went to the lab,
I got the results,
Which were negative in
case you're interested,
- and I sent them home.
- Negative.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Excuse me?
- Those test results were preliminary.
I was waiting for the final results which,
by the way, were positive.
Kid's got cystic fibrosis.
Oh fucking God, no.
Yeah. Harry and his family
are home celebrating
and now it's my job
to pick up the phone
and tell 'em that their kid's
not gonna live to see 30.
What's the matter?
No snappy comeback?
( sighs )
Let me call them?
Have a nice goddamn night.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com