BARNEYS VERSION
(RINGING TONE)
BLAIR OVER PHONE: Hello.
BARNEY: Blair, I'd like to speak with my life.
-Oh, Barney, it's 3:00 in the morning.
-Put my wife on the phone.
She's not your wife
-and I'm not waking her.
-All right.
Well, then just ask her
what she wants me to do
with all these nude photos I have of her.
Come to think of it,
you actually might want them,
if only to see
what Miriam looked like in her prime.
(BLAIR HANGS UP)
Hm.
(ALARM BUZZING)
(BARNEY GRUNTING)
-Fuck.
-(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Son of a bitch.
-Hello.
-KATE OVER PHONE: Daddy,
Blair had a heart attack last night.
-Really?
-Yes, really.
-How bad?
-Minor.
He thought it was indigestion.
(LAUGHS)
Putz.
-Dad, it's still a heart attack.
-Yeah, that's true.
You know, the long-term effects
of these things
don't often show up until later.
Impotence is still on the table.
Are you... Are you not at all concerned
that you might have caused th is?
Why would I be?
Mom told me about the phone call last night.
The one that woke Blair up
at 3:30 in the morning.
-Dad...
-Listen, sweetheart, I...
I got to call you back.
-I'm on the elevator.
-You better. And Michael.
-He's been trying to reach you, too.
-I will.
-I hope it doesn't swell up.
-(SIGHS) It already has.
Okay. Cut!
-How was that?
-Appallingly bad.
Great. Moving on.
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR:
Moving on to the next set...
You know I...
Barney... Excuse me...
-Barney, good...
-SOLANGE: I want to talk to you.
Have you seen today's paper?
We need to go over the opening
for next week's episode.
The teaser is over a minute long.
BARNEY: Morning, everyone!
Yes, I know about the book!
And yes, I've seen today's paper.
No, I don't give a flying fuck
and neither should you.
Let that be the end of it.
Barney, the network wants to make
a really big deal about the 30th season.
They want to bring in a new face.
Somebody young.
Maybe... Maybe Solange has a sexy,
young niece who comes to live with her.
No. No way.
They want to write her down
in favour of a new character.
So they want to bring in
some tits and ass, huh?
Isn't that why you hired her
in the first place?
I want a word with you now!
Oh.
What language is this?
They're from Bulgaria.
Press clippings about me
and they just keep coming.
They love me over there.
And this proves what I'm really worth
to the foreign market.
Well, I will give this my utmost attention.
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO: Five games into
the National Hockey League last night...
In their last regular season home game,
Montreal squeaked by Calgary.
A score of seven to six.
You get home okay last night?
I got home. Thank you.
He's already had more than a few.
That's for you. I even signed it.
See that review in the paper today?
Not bad, eh?
Ah, why do you have to be like that?
I even wrote you a nice little note.
"To Barney. None of this
would have been possible without you."
"All the Best, Detective Sean O'Hearne."
Very sweet.
This is a big day.
Just wanted to buy you a drink,
share in the moment, be a mensch,
like you people might say.
Oh, for someone
who professes to hate me so much,
you certainly do go out of your way
to come around here a lot.
I just want to know
what you did with the body already.
Why don't you just leave him alone?
Because he got away with murder, sweetie.
You screwed over everyone you ever know
or cared about.
Now the whole world's going to know what
a cock-sucking murderer you really are.
You could use a mint.
-It's a real page-turner.
-Yeah.
(MEN TOASTING IN ITALIAN)
(EXCLAIMING)
(LAUGHING)
-Boogie!
-BOOGIE: Barney!
-CEDRIC: Boogie, what's happening?
-Hey, Cedric.
-Leo!
-Welcome back.
-Dr Smooze.
-Dr Smooze is back.
You're back.
(CHATTERING IN ITALIAN)
-I'm good. I'm good...
-Boogie...
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
-Okay.
-Hey, come here. Come here. Sit down.
Boogie! Boogie, who is that?
-Who's that? That's The Countess.
-CEDRIC: The Countess.
-LEO: Wow.
-Yeah.
-Where did you meet her?
-Ah...
Somewhere between my black out
in Lake Como
and my hangover in Sainte-Maxime.
(LAUGHS)
Listen, if someone could find out
for me and get her name, please,
-it would be great.
-My man.
Leo. How was your showing?
(SIGHS)
The show was a bust.
I only sold one piece, to Barney.
Oh, his work is too bold for that crowd.
Barney, our very own patron of the arts.
otherwise known as our only friend
with a real job.
(ALL LAUGHING)
LEO: That's true.
To Barney,
living the lessons of the Bard,
"Be as great in act
as you have been in thought."
(ALL TOASTING IN ITALIAN)
(LEO THANKING IN ITALIAN)
What about you, my High Priest? Did you
get through those books I sent you?
-A few of them, yeah.
-A few of them?
I sent you Gogol, I sent you Heine.
What have you been doing with yourself?
(CLEARING THROAT)
Well, actually, I'm getting married.
-To who?
-To me.
LEO: Oh, it's trouble.
Prince Charmingbaum here knocked me up
by way of a magical 30 seconds of friction.
Where the hell have you been?
You didn't come home last night.
Who remembers?
Has he told you what he's doing now?
No.
Exporting olive oil to some guy, Hymie,
back in Montreal.
-It's like a bad Jewish sitcom.
-Well, someone's got to make a living.
He comes to Europe and sells oil.
It's fucking humiliating.
You're not one of us. You're a voyeur.
All right. A toast to the newlyweds.
To your health, to your happiness.
And a three-inch prick.
(CHUCKLING)
(ALL TOASTING IN ITALIAN)
Why did you agree to marry her?
-I got her pregnant, man.
-So?
BOOGIE: It's Clara Chambers, man,
she's crazy.
She's a conversation piece,
she's not a wife.
And how do you even know it's yours?
-It's mine.
-All right, if you say so.
-BOOGIE: He's coming with me.
-(LAUGHS) Don't let him knock you up.
BOOGIE: You got any money?
BARNEY: Some. Why?
BOOGIE: Provisions.
BOOGIE: We're going to do it all,
Barney. All of it.
Opium, the horse, the hash.
Everything under and behind the sun,
on and off the table.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hey, we only go around once, my friend.
(TOASTING IN ITALIAN)
BARNEY: Oh, hold on. Hold on.
Don't tell me, your novel?
You finished it?
-No.
-Oh!
-Volume one, huh. This is it?
-Not yet. Not yet.
I'm not done with it yet.
Read it so far.
Jesus Christ, Boogie, this is brilliant.
When are they publishing it?
They're not.
Why not?
I'm never giving it
to that ridiculous editor.
Okay. What about the advance
that they paid you?
I wrote him another one.
You're kidding. Which?
"Vanessa's Pussy"?
What's it about?
It's my interpretation of The Book of Job
as told through Vanessa's vaginal lips.
I don't know,
for some reason the editor passed.
Let me guess here,
Vanessa is the editor's wife?
Was.
-Come here, man.
-What?
Quit dicking around
and finish this book already.
Hey, assholes. You want to wait up?
It is my wedding.
BOOGIE: You don't have to
go through with this, you know.
BARNEY: You're saying this to me now?
I'm just saying no one will think
any less of you if you don't.
That's good to know. Give me this.
(LAUGHING)
Barney Ponosski.
Panofsky.
Pinasski.
Off-ski.
Panosski.
-Pan-off-ski. It's fine.
-Panosski.
Clara Charnofsky.
No. No. Her name is Clara Chambers.
Charnofsky?
I was married to a Russian gangster
for five days...
-Charnofsky... Jesus.
-I ran away on the honeymoon.
I just never bothered to do the
paperwork to change the name back.
Did you ever think to mention that?
Don't worry, baby. You still
got yourself a true-blue shiksa.
What else haven't you told me, sweetheart?
Are there any kids I don't know about?
Only two. Yosel and Chaim.
They're locked in our attic.
When you go out to get the hockey scores,
I let them down and force feed them
pork-roast milkshakes through a funnel.
There!
(MEN LAUGHING)
(CONGRATULATING IN YIDDISH)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
I will speak in English.
I'm afraid the infant was a stillborn.
But your wife is healthy,
and will certainly be able
to bear other children.
(COUGHING) I must ask you
if you know the biological father,
-for our records, Signor.
-Well, I'm the father.
Then you must be an albino.
(COUGHING)
Little baby never even had a chance.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Brother.
LEO: Oh!
BOOGIE: Barney, what are you doing?
LEO: Cedric, you okay?
-BOOGIE: Barney, what the hell?
-(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
He just lost his son.
Every four hours they attach clamps to
my nipples and milk me like I was a cow.
I really thought it was yours.
Let's talk about this later.
Oh, Barney, you really
do wear your heart on your sleeve.
Now put it away.
It's disgusting to look at.
Barney, where are you going? Wait.
Barney, I'm sorry.
Barney, please, we'll start over!
Barney, come back!
BARNEY: I got a call today from Montreal.
MyUncle lrv offered
to get me a job in TV production.
Says there's all these tax loopholes
that make it foolproof in Canada.
Could you pass the lighter
off the table, please?
Thanks.
When did this come, man?
Oh, shit. I completely forgot.
It came a few days ago.
Oh...
CLARA: "Dear Barney,
please come for dinner tonight at 8.
"I think it's important we talk."
Clara!
"I'm sorry. I really do miss you.
"I need you. I'll even make latkes."
Oh.
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Are you here about the apartment?
I'm Charnofsky.
The Russian?
From Brighton Beach, in New York.
Your Mechutan.
Your father-in-law. Clara's father.
You going to invite me in?
(SIGHS)
Who'd buy such a disgusting thing?
Actually, Clara made it.
That's me, with the horns.
(EXCLAIMS)
I can only imagine, Mr Panofsky,
the guilt that you are carrying,
but you should know, my Clara,
this is not the first time
she tried to kill herself.
No, no, no. When she was 12 years old,
she used to tear hair out in clumps,
right out of her head, yeah.
She said that we're not her parents,
we should be so lucky.
She said she's not Jewish.
She said,
"Tell me who my real parents are." And
until we told her, she wouldn't eat.
We'd have to force her mouth open
and she was a biter.
(LAUGHING) Let me tell you.
We had to pour chicken soup down
through a funnel.
And she would be gone sometimes for days.
Who knows where? Greenwich Village.
And so I had to lock her up in the attic.
Dr Kupner, thank God for him.
He arranged for the mental hospital,
the latest, the best treatment,
the shocking electric... Something.
Never mind the expense.
We would do without.
But, you know, was she grateful?
No, she would yell in front of everybody
at the hospital,
"Dr Kupner, you felt up my tits."
Language like this, from a young girl,
you can imagine.
And then she would come home.
You know what she did for a thank you?
She sat in the bathtub,
she cut open her wrists,
the ambulance is sitting outside.
People are peeking through their curtains.
My wife was so ashamed, she couldn't
leave the apartment for a week!
Anyway, you shouldn't blame yourself,
Mr Panofsky,
because she did it before.
I think you should leave.
I've upset you.
Get out of here.
Get out? What, do you talk like this
to an older man?
I just lost a daughter.
So high and mighty
you're getting with me, huh.
You couldn't have made her so happy, either,
or she would not have done that to herself.
I'll throw your ass down the stairs.
I don't care.
The man at the embassy told me
it took two days...
Two days for you to find her!
Where were you, her loving husband,
where were you?
-Get out!
-Where were you?
Get out now!
IRV: Abe!
Did you hear what happened last night?
Some Nazi punks took a shit
right on the steps of Beth Zion.
Yeah, that's right.
And that's why you cannot be
complacent with your support.
We need Israel.
Look, I don't need to tell you
where things like this can lead.
Starts out with a turd, next thing
you know, we're wearing armbands again.
Mmm-hmm. Excellent.
And, Abe, I'll see you Friday night
for dinner, right? Great.
Donations go through the roof
when shit like this happens. Let's eat.
IRV: Fundraising, this is how you make
real connections, Barney.
I'll give you the target's annual income,
not the numbers on his tax returns,
the real numbers.
It could happen here, you tell him.
Israel is our insurance policy.
It could happen here.
Israel is our insurance policy...
Who's to say that it can't happen here.
Israel is our insurance policy.
And I hate to sat it,
but it could happen here.
Gentlemen, I need to borrow
my nephew here for a moment.
What did I tell you, producing,
fundraising, it's all the same dance.
Now listen to me.
I've got a girl I want you to meet.
-Darling.
-Hi...
Dexey, back from Florida.
lrv, I don't need to be set up.
Listen, she's got it all,
she comes from a very good family.
She's got a master's from McGill
and she's a good-looker.
Sweetie.
-Yeah, you're right.
-Sweetie, this is him.
-Hello.
-You're Barney.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
So, throughout the entire second year
of my master's degree,
I have a master's degree,
I had this reoccurring dream
where I'm 16 again
and I'm standing in
Reuben's Butcher Shop on St Viateur.
And I have this long pigtail
and it has a ribbon in it,
which my Aunt Sarah brought back
from Saks, in New York City.
And did you know Reuben?
He was such a card.
When I was 10,
he would always come around
from behind the counter and he would go,
"How come a beauty like you
isn't married yet?"
I was only 10, which is...
And I'm not married now.
Oh.
Is your dad really a cop? Is he?
Is that true? 'Cause I heard he was a cop.
That's why you're not a square
like all the other Jewish boys I know.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
-Button up your jacket.
-I don't want to.
-Why?
-Yours isn't buttoned.
Mine doesn't fit as well.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(CONGRATULATING IN YIDDISH)
-It's the housekeeper, Dad.
-Swanky.
Go ahead.
So, Mr Panofsky,
you must have a lot of interesting stories,
you know, having been a detective and all.
Gorgeous, please call me Izzy.
(GIGGLES)
And I was just a beat cop.
I mean, Jews don't get promoted
to detective in this town.
Oh. Did you ever encounter anti-Semitism
in your profession?
What do you think?
Let me give you an example.
One of my first shifts on the job,
I corner four guys
doing a dope deal in an alley,
big score for a rookie.
So, you know, I call in for back up
because the rules say
you can only put three in a patrol car.
And, you know,
I'm playing it by the book.
The dispatcher says to me,
"Your people are good with numbers,
you figure it out."
So I toss three in the back,
and the fourth I throw over the hood
and I handcuff him to the...
Side mirror.
There you go. Haul them all in.
(LAUGHING) Oh, my God,
that sounds so dangerous.
Only when he blocked my view.
(LAUGHS) That's funny.
(LAUGHING)
Are you saying you were gratuitously
violent with suspected felons?
Gratuitously? No, I always got paid.
I ain't going to work for free.
He means unnecessarily, Dad.
Oh, look. When a fellow is young
and you give him authority,
he likes to push people around.
But I always knew
that my name was Israel Panofsky,
and you know,
I knew I had to be extra careful
and I was, most of the time.
FATHER-IN-LAW: "Most"?
Did you ever consider
that your career advancement
was stunted by your professional conduct
and not by imagined prejudices?
I call it as I see it.
But you're the one with the mansion
on the hill, so what do I know?
You got your brains from him
and beauty from her.
And you are one sweet little casserole.
(BARNEY CLEARS THROAT)
Can we make a toast?
To the blessed match of these two lovebirds.
You never know
what tomorrow's going to bring
so get to shtupping and multiply already.
(LAUGHS)
(GLASS CLINKING)
The chicken is great.
It's fish.
No shit? Sorry.
MOTHER-IN-LAW: Darling, I can't
tell you how gorgeous you look.
And did you see Marsha?
Did you see the way she was looking at you?
Did I ever. Poison from her eyes,
she was so jealous.
Did you see what she was wearing?
She looked like a futon.
-What?
-How's that? Is that gonna do you?
What? No, it's cold, it should be hot.
I think it's supposed to be cold.
(CONGRATULATING IN YIDDISH)
Thanks a lot. I appreciate it. Thank you.
(BAND PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC)
(ALL CHEERING)
(SINGING IN YIDDISH)
(SCREAMING)
We're married!
(MAN SINGING POP SONG)
Hey, man. What's the score?
-One-zip. Boston just scored.
-Ah, shit.
(CHEERING)
Give me a shot.
Mmm-hmm.
I'll have another one.
(MAN SINGING POP SONG)
Sorry.
(ANNOUNCER CHATTERING ON TV)
Beautiful. Bring it around.
Let's go!
ALL: Oh!
BARNEY: God damn it!
It was a hell of a save, though.
Barney, your father's with the rabbi.
Will you go do something, now?
Mmm-hmm.
Will you put that out?
A lot of my relatives have asthma.
(LAUGHS)
(CONTINUES SINGING)
IZZY: So, we're shaking down
a rub and tug, you know,
but I never bust the girls
because they provide a valuable service.
But, you know, we do it for appearances.
Anyway, we're doing our thing and one of
the clients, this crazy Hungarian Nazi,
loaded on Slivovitz starts going
ape-shit, comes at me with a chair
and I swear to God, a hard-on the size
of a can of hairspray.
(LAUGHING)
-(LAUGHING) Dad.
-Yeah?
-Can I steal you away for a minute?
-Yeah, sure.
I'll be back in a minute.
If I'm not, you start without me.
All right, come on.
You know, I didn't think
I'd be having a good time.
I thought they'd all be snotty,
but they're a nice bunch of people.
(LAUGHING)
What are you laughing at?
-Jesus Christ!
-What?
Nothing. I love you, Dad.
Oh, man.
(GRUNTING)
-What in the hell's that?
-I almost forgot.
Mmm-hmm.
-What's that?
-(SHUSHING)
Your wedding present.
Jesus Christ.
That was my first gun.
I want you to have it.
I don't know what to say.
Don't say anything.
Give me a kiss and get us a drink.
Come on.
-Single malt.
-Yeah, give the cop a drink.
Your father-in-law said
that neither of you were to have
anything else to drink.
-What?
-Really?
Is that right? Here you go, Dad,
have a party. Where is that asshole?
(CLEARING THROAT) Don't embarrass me.
-Give me a double.
-BARTEN DER: Yes, sir.
(MIRIAM LAUGHING)
(MAN SINGING ROMANTIC SONG)
Barney,
can I help you?
Uh... No. Nothing, nothing.
Why? Forget it.
Yeah. Don't you ever tell my father
what he can and cannot do again.
He traumatised the rabbi's wife.
I don't care if he fingered her
under the goddamn table.
He's my father
and he will have your respect.
(IN DISTINCT CHATTERING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hello.
-Hi...
-Sorry, we haven't met.
-I'm Barney.
-I'm Miriam.
-Thank you for having me.
-Oh, of course.
-Are you all right?
-(CLEARS THROAT) Fine. Perfect. Yes.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
-I understand you're in television.
-Mmm.
-Totally Unnecessary Productions.
-Oh, that's a little harsh.
No, that's the name of my company.
-It's not.
-Yes, it is.
-It is and they are, believe me.
-(LAUGHING) That's funny.
Your cigar is out.
Oh, it's okay.
I wouldn't want it to bother you.
Oh, please,
it's a Montecristo. Go ahead.
Thank you, I will.
Do you know
why they're called Montecristos?
Haven't a clue.
Fine cigars are rolled by hand.
chip in from their own wages
and employ lectors,
these people who read to them
all day long while they work.
It's entertainment to make the day pass.
At the factory
which produces the Montecristo,
the workers' favourite story was...
Ah-ha.
You guessed it. The Count of said name.
Lectors.
Nice touch, huh?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
-I never knew any of that.
-BARTEN DER: Barney!
(SOFTLY) One. One.
(LAUGHS)
-What?
-Thank you! Thank you!
-What's that?
-I'm sorry, it's nothing,
it's the hockey game. Stanley Cup.
Oh. Who's winning?
Habs have tied it up, in fact.
Do you follow hockey?
(LAUGHING) No, but I read newspapers.
Are you doing anything later?
Because we could still catch
a flight to Rome.
Lunch at Dal Bolognese
On the Piazza del Popolo.
To Rome?
Rome.
The bride may take issue with that.
Anyway, I have a train to catch later,
back to New York.
-Congratulations again.
-Thank you.
Thank you for being here, Boogie.
I'll never miss any of your weddings.
(LAUGHING)
Hey.
I almost forgot.
It's a classy dame.
Smart as a whip, too.
Who?
-Let's get you that drink.
-That would be good.
(BARNEY CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Oh, man.
For the first time in my life, I am
truly, seriously, irretrievably in love.
So am I, Barney.
So am I.
(ALL CLAMOURING)
Central Station, please.
-DRIVER: You see this?
-Oh, my God.
You know what, to hell with it.
ANNOUNCER ON PA:
Ready for boarding on...
CONDUCTOR: IDs, tickets?
Wow! I like you with glasses.
-What are you doing here?
-Run away with me.
What?
Run away with me.
Or, or stay with me. I don't care.
Or I could go with you.
-Are you out of your mind?
-No. I'm...
I'm bent over backwards
in love with you, Miriam.
I'm... I'm heels over head, completely...
Don't be ridiculous.
We just met, at your wedding.
(LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY)
It's not funny. Barney,
get off the train...
I cannot believe that this really happens.
It really happens. Just like that.
CONDUCTOR: IDs, tickets?
It's amazing, no?
And I don't care if it happened
On my wedding night,
at a funeral, on my deathbed.
It happened.
CONDUCTOR: IDs. Tickets.
I don't have an ID or a ticket. Sorry.
Then you'll just have
to get off the train, Okay?
Get off the train, Barney.
Among other things, sobriety and regret
are anxiously waiting up for you.
Here, I got it.
You look fantastic in that dress.
CONDUCTOR:
Leaving Montreal in two minutes.
Two minutes, everybody.
Oh!
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Oh, my God.
-We thought you were dead.
I called the police,
I called all the hospitals.
I was so verklempt,
Dr Stein gave me a Valium.
I was supposed to take half,
I took the whole thing.
(LAUGHS)
That was a gift.
So this must be the Via Condotti.
(HUMMING)
Ah!
Would you put that away, please?
It's our honeymoon, not a travel junket.
-I'm embarrassing you?
-Yes.
Like with the bidet?
You didn't have to ask the concierge.
I could have told you what it was for.
-Do you have a master's degree?
-No.
Am I embarrassed? Snap out of it.
We came to Rome to have fun!
Not to mourn the death of your first wife.
MRS P: Yeah, we went to the Vatican.
(SCOFFS) It's old.
Yeah!
Ma. Ma. Ma.
You should see the bathrobes
they got here. Yeah.
And the soap. To die for.
Well, of course I will.
I already stuffed three bars
in my suitcase for you.
Okay, Ma, you know what?
I'm going to talk to you tomorrow.
Okay. I'll talk to you tomorrow.
(EXHALES)
Hmm.
(EXCLAIMS EXCITEDLY)
Hey, you know what?
I was just thinking about the wedding.
-It was beautiful, wasn't it?
-Yeah. Lots of relatives.
-I got a big family.
-Yeah, you certainly do.
-Who was that guy from Chicago again?
-My cousin, Isaac?
Right, Isaac, right. Funny guy.
(CHUCKLES)
And what about that girl?
I think she was from New York,
the one in the blue dress?
Oh, Miriam Grant.
Right. Who is she again?
She was a couple of years behind me
at McGill.
She's the kind of girl, you know,
she subscribes to The Economist,
but she buys Vogue off the stand.
I think Jeff brought her.
-Jeff seems gay.
-Jeff is gay.
Just pretends for the family.
Ah. Good.
Good?
Well, yeah. I mean,
better that the guy lives a lie than he
inconvenience the family. I mean...
Well, yes.
(SIGHS)
I think I'm going to take a quick nap
before dinner.
-Oh, no, no, no, no. I don't think so.
-Why?
I don't think so.
(HUMMING)
-Oh, did you wash it like I asked?
-Yeah.
-With soap?
-Yep.
-Okay.
-(LAUGHS)
-Sorry I'm late. I took a cab.
-It's okay, I just got here.
And how are you,
my favourite offspring?
To tell you the truth, perplexed.
-By what?
-By you.
Before this recent phone incident,
you got Blair a subscription to
Boy Toy Monthly using his work address.
Mmm-hmm.
And before that, you signed him up
to an Al Qaeda website.
The man still can't fly out of the country.
I've upset Claire, is that it?
No, you've upset Mom.
Blair's too much of a chicken-shit
to say anything.
(BARNEY LAUGHS)
See? You truly are my
proudest achievement. Do you know that?
(KATE LAUGHS)
-He stole her from me, sweetheart.
-No, he didn't.
You got divorced, she got remarried.
Look, no one was rooting
for a comeback more than I was,
but it's time to let it go.
-They're happily married, I'm sorry.
-They're married. Stick to the facts.
-An apology wouldn't hurt, either.
-Oh, for Christ's sake, apologise to who?
Hey, why don't you come up
to the country this weekend, hmm?
-Actually, I have a date.
-Oh.
-Nice boy?
-No. He's a nasty piece of work.
-Funny. (CHUCKLING)
-Yes, he's very nice.
We'll see. It's our third date and
I'm not bored silly or madly in love.
I like him.
I think that shows a sign of maturity.
What?
-Where the hell did I park my car?
-You took a cab.
Right. Yeah.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(EXCLAIMS) Well, I definitely need
a weekend in the country, huh?
All right.
(SEAPLANE FLYING)
Oh, thank you, nurse.
Thank you for landing us safely, Constable.
O'MALLEY: Hopefully, the weather will be
more forgiving the next time I pass through.
You can be sure my landing strip
will always be clear for you.
(DIRECTOR SNORING)
-Cut! Great.
-(SOLANGE SOBBING)
DIRECTOR: Moving on to the next setup.
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR:
All right, we'll take this one down
-and we're gonna move 7 5 feet.
-Um...
(SIGHS)
I need a couple of rigs.
What's the matter with Solange?
Her fiancé died in a plane crash.
Oh, come on, that was more than a year ago.
I mean, you look at her,
you would think that she...
(LAUGHS) To let you finish that thought
would be an insult to stupidity.
-Huh.
-Barney, excuse me.
Phone's for you. It's a Miriam Grant.
Miriam?
MIRIAM: Barney. This has to stop.
BARNEY OVER PHONE: You got my flowers.
Yeah, I got the flowers, I got the
gifts, every week it's something else.
I don't know where to start
with how inappropriate this all is.
Why don't you just skip ahead from
where I'm annoying and inappropriate
to where I'm charming and endearing.
No. 'Cause you're a married man and I
won't be involved with you in any way.
No, I'm sorry. I know.
Why don't we talk about it over lunch?
I could be in New York tomorrow.
Are you listening to me?
Every word.
Really? Well, words matter. Actions matter.
If you want people to take you
seriously, then act accordingly.
Understand? What am I saying?
"Be great in act as you have in thought."
Well, yes, exactly.
(LAUGHS)
I have to go, so stop this nonsense
and focus on your marriage.
I'm just so happy that you called.
Thank you, Miriam.
Goodbye, Barney.
-(LAUGHS)
-(MIRIAM HANGS UP)
(LAUGHING)
(SCATTING)
MRS P: Well, tell Daddy not to eat
the bagels if they make him bloated.
Did I say he was fat? Did... I did not.
I actually have to go because I have to
go and vacuum the broadloom downstairs.
Because I had to fire the maid.
Because every time
Barney and I would go out,
his father would come over
and have sex with her.
(SNORTS)
I know it's disgusting. You asked.
-Goodbye.
-(HANGS UP)
(SIGHS)
If you don't throw this out, I will.
I'll take it up to the country house, yeah?
Oh.
Will you tell your buddy, Bernard,
don't throw up all over the place
'cause I just changed out all the carpets.
Absolutely.
You went to the game last night.
You think the score
magically changed overnight?
(SIGHS) I gotta get going.
Barney. Barney, stop, this is important!
-What's important?
-This is... This.
Talking. This communicating.
You don't want Boogie puking all over
the carpets and your father's fat.
Does that about cover it?
Do I talk down to you like that?
I gotta get going.
Okay. I'll be...
I'll see you in a couple of days.
Hi.
Get in. Come on.
I thought you came here to kick.
(LAUGHS)
Come on, man.
I've been on flights for 15 hours.
I had to fix up one more time
Or I wasn't going to make it.
BARNEY: Oh, shit.
I thought I'd surprise you.
Surprise.
Thanks.
So, this is why you brought him here?
BARNEY: He needed some place safe to kick.
Yeah, it's called rehab.
You want one?
Just bring the bottle to the table, Barney,
then you won't be jumping up
every two minutes.
Wow, are we ever in for a jolly time
this weekend.
Oh, you don't know the half of it.
Look what I found
while going through your wallet.
You're going to be very embarrassed
when they show up.
I called the florist.
While she's usually discreet
about her clients,
the ray of sunshine that is you
left the manager eager to tell me
about the standing order of roses
that you have to someone
-in New York every week.
-Jesus Christ.
This is ridiculous.
Are you going to pick through
every goddamn receipt that I have?
I'm not going to sit here
and be interrogated like this.
Schmuck.
(DOOR OPENS)
(CLEARING THROAT)
Sorry I'm late. I have to get a divorce.
What!
Holy shit!
You cheated?
-No.
-She did?
-So what happened?
I'm in love with someone else.
Who?
You don't know her.
Where'd you meet her?
-You don't want to know that.
-Wait a minute.
You asked me here to talk
and now you don't want to talk?
-What do you want from me?
-I don't know.
Give me a hint.
-Some paternal wisdom. How about that?
-Ah. Fine.
Look, you're talking to someone
who knows how hard marriage can be.
In the beginning, it's all briskets
and blow jobs and la-di-da,
ain't life grand?
But soon enough, real life starts, right?
You come home from work,
all she wants to do is talk.
All you want to do is screw, right?
And before long,
every day is like pushing an avocado
through a cheese grater.
It all feels like
you're holding a pile of shit.
Mmm.
This is the paternal wisdom I'm gonna get?
Maybe you should just take a step back
before you do something rash
and take a good hard look at the situation.
You're married to a well-bred woman
who is loaded.
Makes a nice, flaky k ugel,
has a beautiful rack.
And many successful marriages have
been built on far less.
All right. You know what, just drop it.
Forget I even came in here with this.
-Listen to me. Will you listen to me?
-Mmm.
If you divorce her, she's going to
take you to the cleaners.
Oh, come on. Her father is loaded.
She's going to inherit a shitload
of money. She's going to be fine.
You think that's going to stop her
from taking all of yours?
I don't care.
You want to tell me her name?
Miriam.
And is she the one?
Is she the mother of your children?
Absolutely.
All right then, let's do it.
I'll be back tomorrow.
I'm just too drunk to drive tonight.
MRS P ON PHONE:
You're leaving me with a junkie.
Are you with your whore?
-No.
-So you do have a whore?
My father was right about you.
You son of a bitch!
You're not the kind of man
that I should have married.
I should have married...
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO: In local news,
forest fires have been reported
along the shores of Mont Orford,
due to continued dry conditions in the area.
Details coming up
on the morning news at 7.:00.
(BOOGIE MOANING)
(MRS P MOANING)
Oh, God!
(SCREAMING) Get out!
BOOGIE: Oh, shit.
MRS P: Barney!
(CLEARS THROAT)
You bastard son of a bitch.
This is all your fault!
My fault?
Yeah, this is your fault.
You got to be kidding me.
Oh, wow, my wife and my best friend.
Good heavens.
I just... I took in a little tray
of food 'cause I was worried about him.
And he was all trembling and sweaty
and soaked through his sheets,
so I lay down beside him
to try and keep him warm.
And I don't know how he got my robe off!
No, it's a mystery.
Must have been some kind
Of voodoo magic or something.
Wasn't that covered
by your master's degree?
Yeah, didn't you take that class?
Feminist Approaches
to Fornication and Adultery.
I can't hear you!
-Maybe you were sick that day, professor.
-You know,
I don't think we should talk about this
while I am still so upset.
-(LAUGHS) Oh, you're so upset?
-Yes!
You're so upset.
And now I'm leaving!
Where the hell are you going, sweetheart?
I'm going to my mother's!
Oh, well, say hi.
And tell them we're getting a divorce!
Tell her yourself.
But don't do it today,
because she's getting a root canal.
I was coming back to try to work things out.
Oh, bullshit!
I bet you two perverts
cooked this whole thing up together.
(LAUGHING) No, I'm going to kill him
for this and then I'm coming for you.
And just for kicks, your father after that.
Go to hell!
(STARTS ENGINE)
Animal!
(WHISTLING TUNE)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I should kill you for this.
BOOGIE: Oh, no.
What you should have done was call first.
Thank you.
How could you do that to me?
Oh, no, no, no. She did it to me.
Ah.
It was innocent enough to start with.
She brought me something to eat. She
started talking and talking and talking.
Tells me how you've been shirking
your husbandly duties.
So you fucked her?
Well, it was the only thing
that would shut her up.
(LAUGHING)
Try the dining room.
I'm going to need you
to do something for me, Boogie.
I'm going to need you to testify that
I came home to you in bed with my wife.
(LAUGHING)
You sly bastard.
You planned this all along, didn't you?
(LAUGHING) Oh, no, no, no, no.
No. Who could have planned this?
I don't see any scotch, but lookie here?
Lookie, lookie here.
What do you say, huh?
Duel at high noon?
I just don't think we have enough booze
to get us there, do we?
-That's loaded, shmuck.
-Hmm.
Come on, there's more in the kitchen.
Hey, man, hey.
Hey, listen, man,
will you testify for me or not?
I'll think about it.
(SNIFFLING)
You know what? I think that it's time
that you came through for me, for once.
How many times have I bailed you out
Over the years, man?
I don't know, man. I wasn't counting.
Neither was I.
You sure about that?
When I had nothing,
I borrowed for you, man.
You owe me.
Isn't this getting interesting?
Very interesting.
But I'd like to go
for a swim and think it over.
You must have a snorkel and flippers
here somewhere.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey, Balzac, how's the novel coming along?
(COUGHING)
Now, are you asking as a friend,
Or are you asking as an investor?
Both.
Well, I'm still working on it, man.
You're a fraud.
-Have I let poor Barney down?
-Yeah, you have, yeah, fraud.
Well, too fucking bad. Too fucking bad.
-You know what, man?
-What?
-I brought you in. I educated you.
-Mmm. (LAUGHING)
I put all the right books right in
your hands and look what you've become.
What?
A TV hustler
married to a rich man's vulgar daughter.
But not so Vulgar
that you wouldn't bang her, asshole.
Oh, and that's not the only wife
of yours I had. Not at all.
The next time I'm in New York,
I'll call on your little tart
and I'll make it a trifecta.
Fuck you!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
What happened to you?
Boogie, what happened to you?
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing happened to me.
That's what you take
as such a personal offence.
I am not your pet project.
I am not your vicarious life.
You're not my friend?
(EXCLAIMS)
Hey! Do you realise something?
Do you realise
that you haven't even come close
-to giving me a goddamn apology?
-You know what?
Let me recommend another book for you
to stock your shelf with there, Barney.
The Life of Heinrich Heine,
who, upon his deathbed,
was begged by his loved ones
to ask for God's forgiveness
before he passed.
But good old Heinrich, he had only this
to say, "God will surely forgive me.
"After all it's his fucking job."