Ozzie. Come on in.
Palmer. What's up?
You know Peck
and Olson.
Peck, yes, hiya.
Olson, by reputation.
I'm Osborne Cox.
Yeah, hi.
Aren't you with...
Isn't he...
Yeah, that's right.
Have a seat.
Look, Oz,
look.
There's no easy
way to say this.
We're taking you off
the Balkans desk.
What? Why?
In fact, we're moving you
out of SIGINT entirely.
Just... No discussion?
Just "You're out"?
Well, we're having
the discussion now.
Look, Oz, this doesn't
have to be unpleasant.
Palmer,
with all due respect,
what the fuck are
you talking about?
And why is
Olson here?
Ozzie, look...
What the fuck
is this?
I know it's not my work.
- Ozzie.
I'm a great
fucking analyst.
Okay, Ozzie.
Ozzie, things have not been
going well, as you know.
You have
a drinking problem.
I have a drinking problem?
This doesn't have
to be unpleasant.
We found something for
you in State. It's a...
Well, it is a lower
clearance level. Yes.
But it's not...
Look, we're not terminating you.
Hmm.
This is an assault.
I have a drinking problem?
Fuck you, Peck. You're a Mormon!
- Ozzie.
Next to you, we all have
a drinking problem!
What the fuck is this?
Whose ass didn't I kiss? Huh?
Let's be honest!
- Okay...
I mean, let us
be fucking honest.
This is a crucifixion!
This is political!
And don't tell me it's not!
(SCOFFS) I have
a drinking problem!
(DOOR CLOSES)
You're home.
Honey, hang on to your hat.
I've got some news.
Did you pick up
the cheeses?
Huh?
The cheeses?
Were they ready?
I didn't realize you
could be home so early.
Yeah. I left a message for
you to stop by Arnaud's.
The Magruders and the Pfarrers
are coming this evening.
The Pfarrers...
What did Kathleen say?
What?
When you left
the message?
That she would
give you the message.
Well, I don't know, I guess
we had bigger news today.
My day didn't revolve
around whether...
Do you mean that you
didn't pick up the cheeses?
Well, if I didn't
get the message,
then I didn't pick up
the cheeses.
For fuck's sake, Ozzie.
But, honey, hang on to your hat.
What, now I have to go and pick them up?
- I have some news to...
Stay here
and get dressed.
Honey,
we have to talk.
Well, not now. I mean, they're
gonna be here in less than an hour.
Is that goat cheese?
Chèvre, yes,
that is a goat cheese.
'Cause I have a lactose reflux,
and I can't...
You're lactose
intolerant?
Yeah, but I...
- Or you have acid reflux?
They're different things.
- I know what they are.
So you misspoke.
Well, thank you
for correcting me.
You should try the chèvre, Harry.
It's very good.
Yeah. I can
eat goat cheese.
I was just telling your
husband that I have a condition
where I go into
anaphylactic shock when I...
Harry works in the Marshals Service, Doug.
- And my throat...
Oh! I'm on
the legislative side.
I work with
Senator Hobby.
I was with Treasury, dealing
with Homeland Security.
I'm with the Marshals now.
If you want, he'll show
you his great big gun.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
Very funny.
Gun's no big deal.
Twenty years of Marshals Service,
I never discharged my weapon.
That sounds like something you
should be telling your psychiatrist.
I don't have
a psychiatrist.
Boy, I guess my job
is pretty undramatic.
I'm on
the legislative side.
Mrs. Pfarrer,
what do you do?
Do you also
carry a big gun?
(ALL LAUGHING)
No, I write children's...
She writes
children's books.
Yeah. Oliver, The Cat
Who Lives In The Rotunda.
TINA: Those are wonderful!
SANDY: Thank you.
My nieces and nephews
just love them.
Oh! Yeah, it's a
beloved, beloved series.
SANDY: Oh! Thank you.
You should see
the fan mail she gets.
Are you sure
this is goat cheese?
Why don't you let your wife tell
them about her own books, Harry?
Come with me into the kitchen.
- I'm sorry. Was I dominating?
Help with
the crudités.
God damn it. He knows, doesn't he?
These are nice floors.
Knows what?
- About us, he knows about us.
Little prick.
- Don't be such an ass.
He doesn't know
a thing.
What is that, Forbo?
What a horse's ass.
I don't know why
we see them.
Well, she's all right.
(SCOFFS)
She's a cold,
stuck-up bitch.
You quit?
Uh-huh.
Well, thank you
for telling me.
Well, I tried to
tell you this...
You tried?
And then what,
aphasia kicked in?
No. Then our guests
came and then...
Why? For fuck's sake, Ozzie.
- I don't know.
I just got so tired.
You're tired?
Yes, of swimming
against the current.
Uh-huh.
Independent thought
is not valued there.
They resist it. They fight it.
The bureaucracy is...
So they gave you a pension
or severance or something?
I didn't retire. I quit.
I don't want their benefits.
But my benefits, they
will do you, right?
They'll see you through,
is that the idea?
It's not like that's the
only way to make money.
Yes? Yes? Well,
what're you gonna do?
I'll do some consulting.
Consulting.
Yes, to help out while...
I've always wanted to write.
Write. Write what?
I've been thinking
about writing a book.
Or, you know,
a sort of memoir.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
OSBORNE:
You okay there, Dad?
Dad, I left my job
at the Agency.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Government service is not the
same as when you were in State.
Things are different now.
I don't know, maybe it's
the Cold War ending.
Now it seems like it's all
bureaucracy and no mission.
I'm writing a memoir.
I think it can be
pretty explosive.
But I don't think
you would disapprove.
I don't think you
would disapprove.
Katie's had trouble
accepting it.
But sometimes there's
a higher patriotism, Dad.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I know this kind of man.
We've seen this.
Mrs. Cox,
you cannot let this man
take advantage of you,
and he will.
He will.
Yes. This is my fear.
Though he's trying...
Well, he says
he's trying to pull
himself together but...
Yeah. Look, sure, I'm obliged to
tell you to try to salvage things,
and you should.
It's not unheard of
that people turn
themselves around,
but you haven't broached the
possibility of divorce yet.
No.
- Well, that's good.
Because first you should get his
financials before he's forewarned.
Because here is a man...
Here is a man
practiced in deceit.
This was almost,
you could say, it's his job,
and there is no reason
it's not improper.
There is no reason you shouldn't get
a picture of the household finances.
Paper files, computer files, whatever.
That's your prerogative.
You can be a spy,
too, madam.
(KATIE CHUCKLES)
Do this,
before he's put on alert.
Before the turtle can
draw in his head and his...
Feet.
- Feet.
And hopefully
everything will work out.
He will reform.
But if not,
forewarned is forearmed.
We were young and committed and
there was nothing we could not do.
We thought of
the Agency less...
Um...
The principles
of George Kennan,
a personal hero of mine,
like the fabled
Murrow's Boys,
at a time of...
(PHONE RINGING)
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
OSBORNE ON ANSWERING MACHINE:
You have reached the Cox Group.
We can't answer
your call right...
Hello?
MAN:
I'm looking for Dr. Cox. Is she there?
No. She isn't.
Hers is the 5719 number.
This is the Cox Group,
but you can reach her on her
portable or at her office.
(BELL DINGS)
AUDIENCE: She's married!
Number four.
(BELL DINGS)
AUDIENCE: Has a boyfriend!
HOST: And number six.
(BELL DINGS)
AUDIENCE: She's pregnant!
(TAPPING RHYTHMICALLY)
(KATIE MOANING)
(HARRY GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
I should try to
get a run in.
Ozzie!
(MEN SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
ALL: (SINGING)
Let all with one accord rejoice
In praise of Old Nassau
In praise of Old Nassau,
my boys
Hurrah! Hurrah! Hurrah!
Her sons will give
while they shall live
Three cheers for Old Nassau!
(CHEERING)
SURGEON: We take all the chicken
fat off your buttocks, here.
LINDA: Mmm-hmm.
And the upper arms.
- Mmm-hmm.
And a little off your tummy.
- Yeah. Great.
Now, we do
breast augmentation
with a tiny
incision here...
That marker tickles.
...and here.
And what about the upper leg,
the higher inside thigh area?
Well, we can do
liposuction there, as well,
but that area will
respond to exercise.
(LINDA SCOFFS)
The buttocks and upper
arms begin to store more fat
once you get up around 40.
The body just tells it to go there,
but the thighs will
respond to toning exercises.
Yeah, I can work on my arms
till the cows come home, but...
Well, also, there are of
course genetic factors.
The Litzkes have
always been big.
Well, everyone's got...
My mother had an ass
that could pull a bus.
Wow! Well, that's a...
Father's side, too.
I mean, although Dad tended to
carry his weight out in front more,
in the gut area.
Derrière, not so much.
Okay.
And what about the face, you know,
the window to the soul?
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Very well put.
Well, your eyes are one
of your best features,
but we can do something about
the incipient crow's feet.
Baby crow's feet.
Little chickling's feet.
I mean chicks.
Chickie, chickie, chickie.
(CHUCKLES)
Yes, again, well put.
You have a way
with words.
We make a small incision
and then pull the skin tight,
like stretching
the skin over a drum.
Not too tight, though.
We don't want that
"worked-on" look.
You need sufficient slack for
the face to remain expressive.
Yeah, I don't wanna
look like Boris Karloff.
(CHUCKLES)
So you don't want a sex change!
(CHUCKLING)
No, I'm all woman!
So, Linda, what we're talking about
here is four different procedures.
The liposuction,
the rhinoplasty,
the facial tuck, which I would strongly
recommend over the chemical peel.
Yeah, I don't wanna
burn anything off.
And why should you,
with that lovely skin?
And lastly,
the breast augmentation.
Now, we can also do something
about the vaccine scar.
I don't know if you wear
sleeveless dresses much...
Not with these ham hocks!
Yes, well, once they're
nice and svelte, post-op,
you may change
your mind about that.
I wanna talk about
this vaccine thing.
I mean, can you
counsel me on this?
I mean, is it
really that unsightly?
I see... I mean, a bunch
of people have them.
Absolutely!
Some women don't mind it.
It's personal taste.
Chad!
CHAD: Big breath. Exhale.
Hold it.
Hold and release!
LINDA: Chad!
And release.
(BONE CRACKING)
Too much?
I just felt a straining,
a tightness in the front of my ass.
Well, you are pretty
tight down there.
You have to...
Yes, something
snapped in my ass.
WOMAN ON SPEAKER:
Chad Feldheimer to the office, please.
I'm gonna check with my office.
I'll be right back,
and we're gonna work
on opening those hips.
I just got a batch
from BeWithMeDC.com.
Oh, no. Anything good?
I don't know. I'm just
looking. How do I open this?
Click on the...
Click on the... Yeah...
Okay. Oh, my God!
Okay. Loser.
Loser. Loser.
(SNORTING)
LINDA: They should
call this Mr. Loser.com.
Did you have to
send in a picture?
No, only the guys do.
I had to fill out
a verbal profile,
what turns me on,
what turns me off.
I'm really looking for a
guy with a sense of humor.
That guy... Wait. That guy wasn't bad.
- Him?
No, before.
Yeah... He might
not be a loser.
How can you tell?
That's a Brioni suit.
- Yeah?
Shit, yeah.
Does he look like he would
have a sense of humor?
Looks like his optometrist
has a sense of humor.
What does he do?
State Department.
(EXCLAIMS)
That's cool.
His hair is...
- What is that?
Plugs?
This is our cardio area, and
we have a lot of machines,
so, believe me,
there's never a wait.
I mean, what you see now
is like our busiest time,
and there's like
a lot of machines open.
Hey, Chad.
Hey, Linda.
Did you call that guy?
No, not yet.
Chad Feldheimer, he's one of our trainers.
I've been doing this Internet
dating thing, and I...
What service?
BeWithMeDC.com.
Nice.
- Have you used them?
No. Two friends did, though,
and they both got hooked up
with really
special guys.
That's fantastic.
FEMALE VOICE: If you're an English speaker,
please say, "Yes"...
Yes!
I'm sorry.
I didn't understand what you said.
If you're an English speaker...
- English.
Would you like to speak to the
billing department or to an agent?
Agent.
I'm sorry.
I didn't understand what you said.
Agent! Agent!
WOMAN: Hello.
Can I help you?
Yeah, hi.
This is Linda Litzke.
Shall I give you
my account number?
You keyed it in. I have it here.
- You have it up? Okay.
I was told that I needed
pre-approval for these surgeries...
Yes, I'm showing that this
procedure was not approved.
Yes, it was denied.
This operation is an elective procedure.
It's not covered by...
No, those are four different operations.
It's very complicated.
I'm reinventing myself.
This is a whole new look,
so it's not just one thing, but
they're all approved by my doctor.
Your doctor's approval
is not the issue, ma'am.
But this is not... Madam.
Our guidelines specify
that elective
surgeries are...
My job involves
public interface.
This is not...
- I'm afraid you don't understand...
Oh! I understand.
Put your supervisor
on, please.
Hold the line.
(EXHALES)
Alan?
Linda?
Yeah.
MAN: We've been over
and over and over this.
First you say you
can't commit, and then...
Would you come
down from there?
(ALL LAUGHING)
(LINDA GASPS)
(ALAN GASPS)
(SNORING)
(SIGHS)
We were married when I
was in my, what, mid-20s?
A kid.
We were kids, 20s.
You think it's forever.
You get older, you start
to feel your mortality,
and you say,
"There's no more time for dishonesty,
"for subterfuge."
You say, "I'm not that person."
The choices you make...
I'm thinking of
divorcing Ozzie.
(LAUGHS)
Frankly, I'm thinking...
I guess that's what
I should be thinking, too.
With Sandy.
Well, that's what
you were just saying.
Absolutely, yes.
And you're right.
You should dump that bozo.
No question about it.
I agree.
So if I were divorced...
Yes, I should settle
things with Sandy
because of you and me.
- Mmm-hmm.
It's just, you know...
It's hard to inflict that
kind of pain, you know.
Of course, that would
be easier for you.
Why's that?
I don't see that.
Well, because
he's such a dope,
and Sandy is a good lady.
She's a very special lady.
She's a cold,
stuck-up bitch.
That's a little...
You and I should
get things sorted.
I've always told you
it's more than just frivolity.
That's right. That's understood.
You've been very straight.
And I think I've been
loud and clear.
Absolutely.
Not just fun and games.
Agent!
FEMALE VOICE: I'm sorry.
I didn't understand
what you said.
Agent!
Your call is important to us.
(ON SPEAKER) Please stay on the
line for the next available agent.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Ted, can I talk to you
about our Mickey Mouse HMO?
Uh-huh! Hang on.
This is some
heavy shit.
Is that my date list?
No, fuck.
You know, I'm trying to reinvent
myself, and these procedures,
which are so incredibly not cheap...
- What is that?
I can't believe this.
This is like
intelligence shit.
I'm not comfortable
with this.
This is like...
- What is it?
I can't believe
this shit I'm seeing.
Manolo found it.
On the floor there.
Yeah. Manolo found like this
CD just lying in a locker,
a locker floor, ladies' locker.
MANOLO: Just lying there.
I'm like,
"What, someone's music or what?"
And I come in here,
and it's these files, man.
I'm not comfortable
with this.
Talking about SIGINT
and signals and shit and...
"Signals" means "code,"
you know.
It was just lying there.
Talking here about department
heads and their names and shit.
And then there's these other
files that are just, like, numbers.
Arrayed. Numbers and dates and
numbers and number and dates.
And numbers and...
I think that's
the shit, man.
The raw intelligence.
I'm not touching this.
I want this out of here.
Just throw it out?
LINDA: No. You can't do that.
You should put up a note
in the ladies' locker room.
CHAD: Put up a note?
"Highly classified
shit found?"
"Signals intelligence shit?
CIA shit?"
"Hello! Did anybody lose their secret CIA shit?"
I don't think so.
I don't know,
you figure it out,
but I'm not comfortable
with this,
and I want this
out of Hardbodies.
We're running
a gym here. God.
Manolo, you didn't find this.
I found it on
the floor there.
Yeah, I know, but...
Right there on
the floor there.
Just lying there.
SANDY: Harry?
Yeah, it's me.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(CHATTERING)
Absolut Saketini,
please.
Just a Tab.
But if I could get
an advance on my salary,
I could at least get
the surgery ball rolling.
Whoa! There's a payroll
company, you know.
They don't just
advance people money.
They just don't do that.
I mean, sure, I could say,
"Yes, I authorize it,"
but that's not going to
mean anything to them.
Then why do they have us on
this cockamamie health plan?
I need those surgeries, Ted.
You're a beautiful woman.
You don't...
I have gone just about as far
as I can go with this body.
I think
it's a beautiful...
It's not a phony-baloney
Hollywood body.
That's right, Ted.
I would be laughed out of Hollywood.
I have very limited
breasts, a ginormous ass,
and I've got this gut
that swings back and forth
in front of me like a shopping
cart with a bent wheel.
You know, there's a lot of guys
that like you just the way you are.
Yeah. Losers.
I don't know.
I mean, am I a loser? Ted.
You know, I wasn't always
a manager at Hardbodies.
Let me tell you...
Let me show you something.
Is that you?
Fourteen years, a Greek Orthodox priest.
Congregation in Chevy Chase.
That's a good job! What happened?
- Mmm-hmm.
It's a long story.
Anyway,
in many ways,
I'm a lot happier now.
My point is...
My point is,
it's a journey.
That's my point.
I don't want to stay where I am.
I want to find someone
to share my journey.
Well, you know, sometimes, if you
don't look in your own back yard...
I know. That's why I
started this Internet dating.
Uh-huh. But what I'm saying is
maybe, you know, you don't have to...
Look, Ted, I know that you can't
authorize an advance on my salary,
but you could put in
a request, can't you?
It's not going to
do any good, Linda.
Ted, have you ever heard of
the power of positive thinking?
Harry?
It's Monica.
Well, hello.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
Maybe I can get a run in.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
CHAD: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
(SHUSHING)
(WHISPERS) Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Do you know
what time it is?
Uh-huh. So, like,
I couldn't call you
on your totally
unsecure phone,
but I know
who the guy is.
The guy?
The guy, the secret guy.
So, is he high up?
I don't know
if he's high up.
Probably. I mean,
I got his name, not his rank.
So what's his name?
Osborne Cox.
Never heard of him.
Like you're so plugged into
the intelligence community.
I'm just saying
as a layperson...
I think the quality of the
intelligence dictates how high up he is.
Okay.
Not what we know.
I also...
Do you have any water?
I gotta hydrate.
I got tap water.
Are you kidding?
How do you know
who he is?
Sources.
(CHUCKLES) What do
you mean sources?
You got like Gatorade or anything
besides, like, Maryland swamp water?
Do you know how far
this is from my place?
How do you know
his name?
I got this geek friend,
Eddie Gallegos.
He does computer stuff,
hooks up people's computers
and programs
their VCRs and shit.
So he examines the files and pulls off
the digital watermark, which tells you
what computer
it was created on.
Fucking child's play
for Eddie.
Uh-huh.
And...
(SINGING)
I got his number, I got his number
Oh, my God.
That was a bit
more difficult.
Shall we give him a tinkle?
Oh, my God.
Why?
'Cause he's gonna wanna know
that his shit is secure.
He's gonna be relieved.
He might even be so relieved
that he gives us a reward.
I would be very fucking
surprised if he did not.
Wow.
- Very surprised.
Like, you know,
the Good Samaritan tax,
which is not even a tax,
really, since it's voluntary.
OSBORNE: Hello?
(SLOWLY) Osborne?
Osborne Cox?
Yes.
Who is this?
This...
Is this Osborne Cox?
Who is this?
What time is it? Who are you?
Um...
I'm a Good Samaritan.
I'm sorry I'm calling
at such an hour,
but I thought you
might be worried.
Worried?
About the security
of your shit.
What on earth are
you talking about?
Who am I speaking to?
Your files. Your...
- The documents.
I know these documents
are sensitive.
But I am perfectly willing to give
back to you your sensitive shit,
you know,
at a time of your choosing.
What documents are
you talking about?
Osborne Cox?
(SHOUTING) Yes!
Yes, this is...
Hello, it's Osborne Cox.
Who the fuck are you?
What documents are
you talking about?
KATIE: Who is that?
Okay.
"The bureau chief in Belgrade
we all call Slovak the Butcher.
"He had very little rapport with
his staff and his dispatches..."
(ENUNCIATING) Rapport.
"Very little rapport
"with his staff,"
fucking moron!
How did you get this?
Don't blow a gasket,
Osborne.
Who the fuck are you?
Listen to me.
We have...
It's not important where...
You are in way over
your fucking head!
I don't know who
the fuck you are,
but you have no idea
what you're doing!
Oh! Why so uptight,
Osborne Cox?
I'm just a Good Samaritan,
a traveler on the road...
Tell him we're
gonna give it back.
We just thought that he
would like to maybe know,
and tell him about that
Good Samaritan tax thing...
Who is that? Hello?
Ozzie, what's going on?
You tell him he's
inconveniencing us.
Hello!
Who the fuck is this?
KATIE: Ozzie,
what's going on?
You know, this is a major
inconvenience for us,
and we just
thought a reward...
OSBORNE:
So it's money! So it's money!
You want money?
Okay. Listen to me.
Well, yeah, why not?
Am I out of line here?
- Let me...
Listen to me,
you two clowns.
Listen to me very,
very carefully.
You have no idea what you're doing,
and I warn you...
You warn us?
You warn us? You warn us?
Yes. Yes. I...
Let me tell you something, Mr. Intelligence.
- Yes. Let me...
We warn you!
- Listen!
We will call you back
with our demands!
Hello? Listen to me.
Chad! Don't you...
No, Chad. Don't play his game!
- Let me explain
how this will work.
- Sorry.
(SIGHS)
Jeez.
The nerve of that guy!
I am very fucking surprised
he did not give us that reward.
KATIE:
What on earth is going on?
Some clown, or two clowns, have
gotten a hold of my memoirs.
Your what?
Stolen it, or...
I don't know how...
Your what?
My memoirs, the book
that I'm writing.
Well, why in God's name would
anyone think that's worth anything?
It doesn't sound like
he's gonna play ball.
(SCOFFS)
He'll play ball!
We just have to
show him who's boss.
Well, that's...
He sounds very senior.
I think this is
some senior guy
who has screwed
the pooch, big-time.
Yeah, that's why
we got him, you know.
We caught him with his thing
caught in a big, fat wringer.
Yeah.
And us in the driver's seat.
Uh-huh!
This is our opportunity.
You don't get many of these.
You slip on the ice outside of,
you know, a fancy restaurant,
or something like this happens.
- Right.
And right now
this has happened.
Yup.
It sure has.
This could put a big
dent in my surgeries.
Uh-huh.
Big time.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
Honey! Honey!
Huh?
My car is here.
I'm off, mystery man.
What is that thing?
It's top secret, baby.
How many cities?
Seattle, San Francisco,
Los Angeles, Chicago.
Why do they always
send you to Seattle?
It's not a big market.
I don't know. Lots of
independent bookstores.
Rains all the time.
What else are people gonna do?
I can think of
a couple of things.
(CHUCKLES)
You can think of one thing.
Where are they
putting you?
Christ, it better
be the Peninsula,
the money I make for them.
Are you gonna be okay?
I'll be sad,
but I'll be okay.
Not too sad.
Just the right amount.
I am crazy about you, baby.
(ENGINE STARTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey!
BOGUS:
Tony Bennett, Toni Morrison,
Zoe Caldwell.
It was marvelous.
First time I've ever
attended the Kennedy Honors.
Jane Alexander
is a client,
an old friend of Zoe's.
Anyway...
(BEEPS)
Connie.
- Yes, sir.
BOGUS: Would you bring in your
copy of the Cox financials?
Tony sang
The Best is Yet to Come.
Tony Bennett.
I thought I had it
here on a disk.
I don't know
where the disk is.
I'm sorry, I'll have to run
another off my hard drive.
All right. Okay.
So we've drawn up the papers,
and we are prepared to execute service
on Osborne, if you so elect, Mrs. Cox.
But since we are at
the point of no return,
I always urge my clients
in this juncture
to give it one more
day of reflection.
(SCOFFS)
Harry?
It's Linda.
Well, hello.
I did the whole
bodyguard thing for years.
My guy was in State, the
Secretary as a matter of fact,
so I did a lot
of traveling.
"Ironside has left the building."
We called him Iron Ass.
Not to his face,
of course.
Not to his ass, either!
(CHUCKING)
He was okay.
Personal protection's
a young man's game.
These are really good.
You wanna try one?
Yeah? Does that have
shell food in it?
Shell food?
- I got a sensitivity.
I go into
anaphylactic shock.
My larynx swells up and it closes...
What the hell.
Live dangerously, huh?
Can't always wear a condom,
right?
That's right! Not always!
(GUTTURAL)
Yeah. My job now is
mostly administrative.
Not so much PP,
personal protection.
I do still
carry the gun.
Oh, my God.
No big deal.
Never discharged it
in 20 years of service.
Security blanket now.
I don't even think about it.
Of course,
you're not supposed
to think about it.
In a situation where your man is
threatened, the training kicks in.
It's muscle memory.
Just like that. It's reflexes. It's...
Those are outrageous.
You wanna swap?
No way!
Go away. Go away.
Let me touch.
Okay. Saki?
(LAUGHS)
There was a hell of a lot
of political infighting
and petty, petty shit,
and then basically
the old man stepped
on Geiberger's throat.
This is nice.
Is this wide-plank pine?
Yeah. I guess so.
Yeah.
Listen, Linda,
full disclosure here.
Yes, I am not wearing a
wedding ring, but I am married.
Hmm.
I took the ring off about 18 months
ago when we agreed to separate,
we agreed to disagree.
That's about the only
thing we ever agreed on.
(LAUGHS)
Well, thanks for telling me, Harry.
I really appreciate it.
You know,
full transparency is my MO.
That's not gonna
go off, is it?
Well, let's get in the
other room and find out.
(SPANKING)
(VOCALISING)
That's great.
That's exciting.
LINDA: Yeah. He's very,
very communicative.
Very accessible.
He has a sense of humor,
and he agrees 100%
about my surgeries.
Well...
He agrees my ass
could be smaller.
I mean,
not in a mean way.
It comes from
a place of humor.
That's good, but, Linda, what do
you really know about this guy?
I told you, he's in
the Treasury Department.
But, no, I mean...
You know, he could be one of these
guys that cruises the Internet.
Yeah, so am I.
CHAD: What's wrong
with this?
No, you cannot
wear that.
You have to
wear a suit.
You mean,
go home and change?
Yeah!
I was gonna
ride my bike.
(SLOWLY) Osborne Cox.
And you, I take it,
are Mr. Black.
Yes, I am.
You have the money?
$50,000.
That's what was agreed
upon, Osborne Cox.
All right. Let me explain
something to you, Mr. Black.
You know who I am,
I know who you are.
Perhaps,
but appearances
can be deceptive.
Yeah.
What you're engaged in is blackmail.
That is a felony.
That's for starters.
Appearances
can be deceptive.
I am a mere
Good Samaritan who...
Secondly, the
unauthorized dissemination
of classified material
is a federal crime.
If you ever carried out
your proposed threat,
you would experience such a shit
storm of consequences, my friend,
that your empty little head
would be spinning
faster than the wheels of your
Schwinn bicycle back there.
(CHUCKLES) You think
that's a Schwinn.
Now give me the
fucking floppy or the CD
or whatever the fuck it is...
As soon as you give
us the money, dickwad!
You fuck!
Give it to me, fuck!
You fucker.
I know who you are, fucker!
You're the fucker!
(HONKS)
Where's the money?
- He hit me!
He didn't give it to me.
For... Get in the car.
Get in the car.
CHAD: What are
you doing? Shit!
(SHOUTS)
(SCREAMS)
Fuck it!
Fuck! Fucking lunatic!
You fucking morons!
Dick!
(LAUGHING)
That'll give him something to think about.
- Yeah.
I knew this
would happen.
Wait. Wait!
We gotta go back!
My bike!
It's on to Plan B.
That's just a Kryptonite lock.
You can open those fuckers with a Bic pen!
Some people.
What is this?
Russian Embassy.
I told Mr. Krapotkin
I might be stopping by.
Is there a men's room?
Madam,
you are mistaken.
I am assistant
cultural attaché.
The organs of state security
are not allowed to function
within the borders
of your country.
Organs?
Yes.
But what if I had, say,
secrets of a highly...
Secrets that might interest
the organs of the...
Yes?
That's just a taste.
May I ask the source
of this material?
No, you may not.
He's very high up.
- Chad!
What?
I'm just saying he's high up.
PC or Mac?
PC.
Could you wait, please?
I do have a date.
Hey!
The fish has bitten.
Huh?
Yeah, he seems cool.
Chad.
Could you accompany me, please?
There is more material?
There's a lot more.
But we want to
be paid first.
You are not ideological?
I don't think so.
Look, I have
a date, so...
Date.
LINDA: Uh-oh.
A line to check in, towels piling up.
I'm sorry, Ted.
And Manolo running
around like crazy.
What happened to your nose?
This is not acceptable
at Hardbodies.
You two know
better than that.
Yes, we do, Ted.
I'm really sorry.
This is no way...
It was unavoidable, Ted.
It won't happen again.
But you won't tell me
what's going on.
No, we can't.
I know this is
really terrible, Ted,
but I have to go.
I have a date.
You're changing, Linda.
It's very sad.
Which, to my mind, is all the more
reason to lower the boom on Ozzie.
Mmm-hmm.
Is that it? "Mmm-hmm"?
I'm wondering if it's
the right time and...
Well, of course
it's the right time.
Why wouldn't it
be the right time?
Does this threaten you?
- No.
You and me,
we're rock solid.
It's just, I think that's
why we can afford to be big.
We can think about Ozzie and
whether we give him a chance to
get himself together
a little bit,
before you hammer
the hell out of him.
Is that how you see me? Hammering him?
- Of course not...
No, but that was your word.
- Yeah.
I don't hammer.
- No, of course not. Listen,
I'm no friend of the guy,
you know that.
I think he's an
arrogant little geek.
(SCOFFS)
But, you know, we have
all the time in the world,
and he just lost his job.
He didn't lose it.
He quit.
Yeah, well, most of the people
in this town who quit, were fired.
I feel sorry for him,
and I think he'll be a lot easier to
deal with if he doesn't feel cornered.
Maybe. Just as long as we're
talking about Ozzie here, not you.
Of course we're
talking about Ozzie.
I'll do whatever you want, baby.
I adore you.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
You get the check.
- Okay.
Yeah. Yes.
Is there blood in his stool?
Later.
I'm running home.
I love you, baby.
Ozzie?
God damn it, Ozzie, what
have you done to the car?
(SNORING)
All right. All right.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh, my God,
am I really late?
No, no.
It doesn't start for five minutes.
(EXCLAIMS)
You haven't seen
this yet, have you?
This one, no.
No, I have not.
I hear it's terrific.
Great.
MAN: We've been over
and over and over this.
First you say you
can't commit, and then...
Would you come
down from there?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Pardon our dust, the ex is
in the process of moving out.
I told her to
expedite things, but...
Yeah.
Yeah, you know, you try
to act like an adult.
Well,
it's never easy.
Hmm.
You wanna come downstairs?
You like surprises?
Well, I'm always open
to new experiences.
I gotta tell you, I saw an ad for
this in a gentleman's magazine,
1,200 bucks. 1,200 bucks.
I'm looking at this thing and I think,
"Jesus, you gotta be kidding me.
I'm a hobbyist.
"This thing's basically
nothing but Speed-Rail."
I figure I'd go down
to Home Depot
and whip this up myself
for 100 bucks.
What is it?
You sit down there,
make yourself comfortable,
put your feet in
the stirrups and...
(GASPS)
Oh, my God!
That's fantastic!
Something, isn't it?
100 bucks all in.
Not counting my labor
and the cost of the dildo.
Those things aren't cheap.
- Uh-huh!
See, I lack that.
I'm not set up to mold hard rubber.
The Russians? The Russians?
- Uh-huh.
Mmm-hmm.
The Russian Embassy, yeah.
Are you sure?
Hey, the guy was not hard
to follow, as you know.
Why the fuck would they go to the Russians?
Why the fuck?
I'm sorry.
Thank you, Hal.
Hey. No problemo.
Look, Ozzie, I hate to be
the paranoid old spook,
but those two guys seem
very interested in you.
You haven't gone poofy
on me, have you, Oz?
Can I help you?
I'm sorry
if I was staring,
but your face
looks familiar.
It's Princeton? '73?
Yeah.
I can't remember
your name.
Osborne Cox.
I thought so.
Served and witnessed.
You have a real
nice evening.
Ouch.
What the fuck?
Fuck! What the fuck?
Fuck! Fucking...
Why did you tell him
we could get more stuff?
Well, maybe we can.
That's all Manolo found.
That was everything.
What, are we
gonna tell Manolo
to scoop some more secret
spy shit off the locker floor?
Hey!
- What?
I don't like the snideness,
nor the negativity.
I'm sorry. I'm just
trying to work this thing.
If I'm gonna reinvent myself,
I need these surgeries,
and these surgeries
cost money.
And this is not just
fun and games. I'm sorry.
So let's figure
this thing out, okay?
WOMAN ON PA: Chad,
your Berry Blast is ready.
We know who he is.
Right, Osborne Cox.
So we can find out
where he lives, right?
I guess.
You should change into a suit.
- Why?
So you don't stand out
in his neighborhood.
There are certain
elemental things, Chad.
His neighborhood?
Yes. We should take out the
labels and the laundry marks.
Laundry marks?
Deniability.
CHAD: (SINGING)
Shake it down
Shakes right
(HUMMING)
(SLURPING)
What's the odometer say?
Five.
About five or approximately five?
I mean...
For fuck's sake, Harry,
it's five miles.
5.2.
Okay. I gotta do
at least five.
Five and a deuce is okay.
I'm amazed you
have the energy.
You kidding? Pull around the
corner and we'll do it in the back.
You're so coarse.
No. Back of the car,
not a rear entry situation.
Fuck! I'm late.
(CRACKING)
(DOOR SHUTS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(HARRY WHISTLING)
(SINGING)
(HARRY HUMMING)
(HARRY SINGING)
(TAP CREAKS)
(CONTINUES WHISTLING)
(CONTINUES SINGING)
(CHAD GASPS)
(HUMMING)
(WHISTLING)
(SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Hello?
(SHOUTS)
(GASPING)
Oh, my God.
What the fuck?
What the fuck? Nothing?
Oh!
Oh, my fuck.
I killed a fucking spook.
What the fuck are you doing
here, you fucker? You...
Olson, what's up?
Palmer, what's up?
Not quite certain,
sir, but it's messy.
Kolyma Two tells us
they have computer files
from an ex-analyst
of mine, Osborne Cox.
Kolyma Two?
Our man in
the Russian Embassy.
Hmm.
They were brought in
to them by a woman...
The Russians?
Yeah. It was brought in by
a woman named Linda Litzke,
an associate of a guy
named Harry Pfarrer.
Picture's in the file,
with Pfarrer's.
The Russians?
- Yeah.
And who's Pfarrer?
Treasury guy who has
been screwing Mrs. Cox.
That must be how
they got the files.
Or maybe Ozzie
knows about them.
They all seem to be
sleeping with each other.
All right. Spare me.
Yes, sir,
but this Treasury guy,
it's become complicated.
He just shot somebody
in Ozzie's house.
Shot your analyst?
No, Ozzie wasn't there.
Our man surveilling
hears a gunshot,
sees the guy
wrestle something
into his car. Follows him.
He dumps a body in
the Chesapeake Bay.
Well, what'd he do that for?
Don't know, sir.
For Christ sake, did
anyone fish the body out?
Mmm-hmm.
And Russian? American?
Don't know.
Scrubbed of ID.
(EXHALES)
And this Linda...
Linda Litzke.
Yeah, she's Treasury?
No.
We're fuzzy on her.
So we don't really know
what anyone is after.
Not really, sir.
And this analyst,
ex-analyst...
Cox.
Yeah. What's his
clearance level?
Three.
Okay, no biggie.
Just, for now, just keep an eye
on everyone, see what they do.
Yes, sir. And we'll interface
with the FBI on this dead body.
No! No. God, no. We don't want
those idiots bumbling around in this.
Burn the body.
Get rid of it.
And keep an eye on
everyone, see what they do.
Report back to me when...
I don't know,
when it makes sense.
MAN: Go!
And tap. Up, up and tap!
Up, up and tap.
OSBORNE: I'm bigger.
I'm bigger.
Now let's add the arms,
right here.
I'm bigger than ever.
Up, up, again.
And again.
I'm bigger. I'm back.
I'm better. I'm back.
Than ever. I'm back.
- Let's do it again. Come on.
You fuckers, I'm back.
Up, up, down, down.
Up, up, down, down, up!
And last time...
Linda. You okay?
(CRYING)
Yeah, I'm fine, Ted. I'm sorry.
You don't look fine.
No, no, I'm...
But you won't
tell me what's wrong.
You never let me in, Linda.
I know you're trustworthy.
I just...
I don't want to endanger other people.
I mean...
This is the path that I've chosen.
It's not...
You have to isolate,
you know, a firewall.
(SIGHS)
Well, I don't know
what to think.
You both go AWOL on Friday.
And today Chad doesn't even
bother to come in at all.
I know, Ted.
I can't run a gym this way.
I'm going to have to fire him.
No, no, no.
Ted, just...
What?
Give me 24 hours!
To what?
- I don't know. Just give me 24 hours!
Linda...
- Just give me 24 hours to solve this thing.
Linda, I have to tell you.
A man was in here earlier,
asking about you.
Are you in some
kind of trouble?
Is Chad running away
from something?
We know what we're doing, Ted.
- Let me ask you this,
did he know my name?
Well, yes, he was asking about you.
Employment history,
etcetera. Real jerk.
I told him to get lost.
Thank you, Ted.
Well, we just don't give
that out at Hardbodies.
MAN ON SPEAKER:
Linda, a Mr. Krapotkin on line two.
Oh, my God.
Mr. Krapotkin?
KRAPOTKIN: This Linda?
Yes?
Yes, this is Ilan Krapotkin, in the
Russian Embassy, returning your call.
Yes, yes! Hang on.
I'm sorry, Ted. This is private.
Mr. Krapotkin? Is this a secure line?
- Yes?
(KRAPOTKIN CHUCKLING)
Mr. Krapotkin?
Is this a secure...
Are you joking?
No! I'm very worried about
my associate, you know, Chad.
Do you have him?
- Do we have him?
(KNOCKING)
Is he... Was he...
Well, I don't know what the term is.
Did he go over?
I don't understand.
Is he not at Hardbodies?
No. Look, could I come
in and discuss this?
(KRAPOTKIN HESITATING)
I'm very busy
at the moment.
I'm coming anyway.
You seem distracted.
Do I?
Very distracted.
The last few days.
Work.
You think that might
be enough carrots?
What?
For the salad.
You know, you really
are a negative person.
What?
I've tried to ignore it,
to remain upbeat.
Harry,
stop the foolishness.
Stop the foolishness?
- Yes, and behave.
You are not speaking to one
of your "shithole buddies."
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE THUDDING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(PHONE LINE RINGING)
SANDY: Hello?
Honey, it's so good
to hear your voice.
Is something wrong,
Harry?
No. Yeah. Can you come
home? Baby needs you.
Can you please come home?
Harry, you know I can't
just leave the book tour.
I can show you your present.
It's finished.
Harry, I can't just leave.
There are two days left.
There's still Seattle.
Yeah.
I love you, Harry.
Yeah. I love you, too.
Hey! Fucker!
(ENGINE STARTING)
Fucker!
MAN: Fucker!
HARRY: Who do you
work for?
Who do you work for?
(GRUNTING)
Who are you?
Who do you work for?
CIA? NSC?
Tuchman Marsh!
- What?
Tuchman Marsh.
- Tuchman Marsh?
Yes.
Your name is Tuchman Marsh?
Tuchman Marsh
Hauptman Rodino!
I work for them!
You work for Tuchman Marsh.
Yes!
Is that a law firm?
No, a rock band.
Yes, it's a law firm.
Well, why are you
following me?
Divorce action,
numb nuts!
My wife hired you?
No. Your wife hired Tuchman Marsh.
Tuchman Marsh hired me.
I work for Tuchman Marsh.
(HARRY SOBBING)
HARRY: Sandy.
Jesus. Grow up, man.
It happens to everybody.
"And at midnight
of the third day,
"even the sergeant
at arms fell asleep.
"And it was just then, at that very moment,
that Oliver sneezed."
(CHUCKLES) Can we just...
- I'm sorry to interrupt.
You have to let the folks at
home see this illustration.
Can we just get
a shot of that?
There, there it is.
It's Oliver interrupting
the filibuster with...
(LAUGHS)
That's wonderful.
It's wonderful.
The book is Point
of Order Oliver!
And the talented author
is Sandra Pfarrer.
She'll stay with us
for our next segment
when we meet
the Sultan of Salad.
And then it's part two of our very
special interview with Dermot Mulroney.
So keep it where it is.
That was way out of line.
We were so unbelievably clear with them,
"It's just an Oliver segment."
- That's fine.
Del and Connie
are such putzes.
That's fine.
Thank you, we're done.
Well, okay, great.
(SIGHS) I thought that
would never end.
Me, too.
SANDY: Let me get
this crap off my face.
What the fuck?
Yes, madam.
Can we help you?
What kind of Mickey Mouse
embassy are you running, anyway?
I've been waiting
for 45 minutes!
I'm so sorry, ma'am.
An urgent matter.
Well, maybe this
is an urgent matter,
since, you know, Chad's
been missing for 48 hours.
I do not know the whereabouts
of Mr. Chad, madam.
He was gathering information
for you when he was taken.
We're not interested in such
information. It was dribble.
Dribble?
Would you like your
disk back, madam?
Dribble?
I will give you dribble.
You listen to me, Mr. Krapotkin.
I am a US citizen,
and I will not take
this kind of treatment.
My check was returned
for insufficient funds.
No. No, no, ma'am. No.
There're over $40,000
in that account.
The account
is not overdrawn.
When?
But how could she
have access with...
What about our savings...
What about my
savings account?
Mmm-hmm.
No. No, I'm sorry. I don't know
the number to my savings account,
because believe it or not,
I don't spend my entire day
sitting around trying to
memorize the fucking numbers
to my fucking bank
accounts! Moron!
(CLANKING)
(GRUNTING)
No way. No, no way. Whoa!
No way, Linda. No.
Well, I can't do it, Ted.
I don't know anything
about computers.
Linda, this whole
thing is crazy.
It was crazy the first time,
and you want to do it again?
Break into the man's house?
You said the Russians
didn't even want this stuff.
My world is bigger
than that, Ted.
There are other people.
There are the Chinese.
Linda,
these surgeries...
No. It's not about
the surgeries, Ted!
We can use this as
leverage to get Chad back.
What do you mean
get him back?
Information is power, Ted.
Hello!
What do you mean
get him back?
You don't know where he is?
(GASPS)
Somebody has him, Ted.
We can use this to...
You call the police if you
wanna get back missing people.
I can't take it! I can't take it!
I can't take it!
You know I can't do that.
We're operating off
the map here, Ted.
This is higher than the police.
It is higher than them.
Linda, I...
- I need a can-do person, Ted!
I hate your negativity!
I hate your reasons why not!
I hate you! I hate you!
(INHALES)
WAITER:
What will it be?
Seven and Seven.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
- It's Harry.
You think a marriage is...
And then it's...
(MIMICS EXPLOSION)
But this has all been
a long time coming.
Was it? Well, yeah, right.
I'm just depressed.
I gotta exercise.
I haven't run in three days.
Butt crunches,
anything.
You think maybe I could
stay here for a little while?
Oh, my God.
No, no, no, no, no.
It can't always
come from me.
I'm not that strong!
You are not here
for me, Harry.
I need a can-do person!
You're all defeated!
Chad is the only
can-do person I know,
and now he's gone. He's gone.
I'm sorry, baby.
I'll be good.
I'll be better.
I just gotta exercise.
Do you have a pedestrian path or something?
- Who the fuck is Chad?
He's my friend from work.
You can help me find him.
You know law
enforcement people.
You could make a call.
Unofficially.
- Linda, hold on.
What happened?
What's his name?
Chad Feldheimer.
And he just disappeared. He hasn't
been at work or at home for two days!
Okay. You know his
Social Security number?
No! I...
- Okay.
Where was the last
place you saw him?
No, I don't know.
He just disappeared.
The Jamba Juice on K Street.
And now he's gone.
No. Okay.
Now, okay, okay.
We're gonna find your little
buddy. It's a piece of cake.
LINDA: Okay.
Piece of cake. Very easy. Okay.
Open your mouth, open it. Do as the
doctor says. Come on, open your mouth.
Come on. Open your mouth.
Now look here, young man.
You do as I say, or I'm gonna ask
your mother to leave the doctor's room,
and you and I are gonna
sort it out between us.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
I'm with a patient.
And it's the same fucking patient
she's been with since yesterday?
You tell Dr. Cox
I have the new keys.
Hey, there, sunshine.
You seem better.
Yeah, well, I snuck in a
little gym time this morning.
And our exercise
last night didn't hurt.
Why, Harry.
Boy, I tell you. I'm through
banging my head against the wall.
I'm gonna start doing
what's right for me.
I believe that, also. I think you
have to do what's right for you.
Yeah. Hell, yeah. You know,
I had a shock recently,
and I realized that life is not
infinite and that no one is immortal.
I think that it's very important
to maintain a positive attitude.
Always up,
always ebullient.
Don't sweat
the small stuff.
And it's all small stuff.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Just for starters.
Boy.
(EXHALES)
Why, this is where we
first met, you remember?
Of course I do.
And it's hard to know what the
important days are until you...
Now, I told myself that I
wasn't going to be paranoid,
but is that guy
looking at us?
No. Uh-uh.
Have you found out
anything about Chad?
No, nothing yet.
I put in a couple of calls.
It shouldn't take too long.
Really?
Yeah. There are so many
databases now it's a joke.
Back when I was in PP,
there was still an art
to finding people.
But not anymore.
Now with cell phones? I mean,
pretty soon everybody's gonna know
where you are at any given
moment, any given moment.
Mmm-hmm.
All right.
When you left Jamba Juice,
did Chad give you any idea
where he might be going?
I know where he was going.
- You do?
Georgetown. Olive Street.
160 Olive Street.
It's the residence of this guy,
Osborne Cox.
Who are you?
What?
You CIA? NSA? You're military?
Who do you work for?
Who are you?
I'm just Linda Litzke.
(GASPING)
(STUTTERING)
Harry!
(CREAKING)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
For Pete's sake.
And you are my wife's lover?
No.
Then what are
you doing here?
I know you.
You're the guy from the gym.
I'm not here
representing Hardbodies.
Yes. I know very well
what you represent.
You represent
the idiocy of today.
I don't represent
that, either.
Yeah.
You're the guy at the gym
when I asked about
that moronic woman.
She's not a moron.
You're in league
with that moronic woman.
You're part of
a league of morons.
No. No.
Yes. You see,
you're one of the morons
I've been fighting
my whole life,
my whole fucking life.
But guess what.
Today, I win.
(GRUNTS)
Stop!
OSBORNE: Intruder!
Stop! Intruder! Stop!
(SCREAMING)
Wait. Wait a minute.
Where is the Treasury guy?
- Pfarrer?
Right now?
- Right now.
He is in a detention room
at Washington Dulles.
Why?
He was trying to board
a flight to Venezuela.
We had his name on a hot list.
CBP pulled him in.
Don't know why he was
trying to go to Venezuela.
You don't know.
No, sir.
We have no extradition
with Venezuela.
Oh!
So what should
we do with him?
For fuck's sake, put him on
the next flight to Venezuela.
Yes, sir. Okay.
Okay. So the gym manager is dead.
- Yes, sir.
The body is...
That's gone, sir.
Okay.
But there was a snag.
What?
Well,
this analyst, Cox,
was attacking the gym guy.
It was in broad daylight,
on the street.
Our man did not
know what to do.
Felt he had to step in.
Yes?
He...
He shot the analyst.
He shot Cox.
Good. Great.
Is he dead?
No, sir. He's in a coma.
They don't think he's gonna
make it. They don't think...
They're pretty sure that
he has no brain function.
(SIGHS)
Okay. Okay. If he wakes up, we'll worry
about it then. Jesus, what a clusterfuck.
So, that's it then?
No one else really
knows anything. Okay.
Um...
Well, sir, there is...
What?
There is the woman,
the gym woman,
Linda Litzke.
Oh! Fuck, yeah.
God! Where is she?
We picked her up.
We have her.
We have her?
To do what with?
She says she'll play ball
if we pay for some,
I know this sounds odd,
some surgeries
that she wants,
cosmetic surgery.
She says she'll sit
on everything.
How much?
There were
several procedures.
Altogether they...
- Pay it.
Yes, sir. Okay. Yeah.
(GARDNER SIGHS)
Jesus fucking Christ!
Yeah.
What do we learn, Palmer?
I don't know, sir.
I don't fucking know, either.
I guess we learn not to do it again.
- Yes, sir.
I'm fucked if
I know what we did.
Yes, sir,
it's hard to say.
Jesus fucking Christ.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Subtitles by LeapinLar