(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(BIRDS WARBLING)
(BRANCH SNAPS)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(DEER BREATHING RASPILY)
(SIGHS)
Today, the boy is dead.
And in his place
is a man.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(KIDS SCREAMING)
(YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
- (FAINTLY) Here you go.
- (GRUNTS)
Training in 60 minutes.
(BOYS YELLING)
(EXCLAIMING)
(STONES CLINKING)
(BLOWS)
Where's the boning knife?
(SCOFFS) Dad?
Zaja took the boning knife again.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, Jesus.
Pol Pot.
Yeah.
Boning knife.
Mountain beaver, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
You're dead.
Vespyr, Kielyr, pair off.
Get your guard up.
You have to stab to kill.
Aim for the liver or the kidneys,
otherwise she'll never learn.
Shouldn't we aim here?
A knife in the lungs
creates a pneumothorax.
Or next to the sternum,
to penetrate the heart?
That'd be instant death.
If it makes you happy, Zaj, sure.
Aim for the heart.
- Bo, you want to show 'em?
- Over here.
BEN: Okay, let's go.
Disarm her if you can.
- (GRUNTING)
- Ow!
Good.
How is that good? She just stabbed me.
- She fucking just stabbed me.
- (CHUCKLES)
Well, then learn to defend yourself.
- You kill her.
- Yeah, thank you.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Let's try that.
(GRUNTS)
Zaj, page.
(MUFFLED) Three hundred and ninety-eight.
- You still liking it?
- Mmm-hmm.
To stay on schedule for the test,
you're going to have to be
finished in eight days. Okay?
ZAJA: Okay.
Vesp? How you getting along?
I just finished Chapter 12,
"The World on a String."
What?
Are you having any trouble
with quantum entanglement?
Planck length versus Planck time?
- I'm fine.
- Good.
Then tomorrow after lunch, you can
give a brief presentation on M-theory.
Argue counterpoints with Bo and Rell
vis-à-vis Witten and Dirac.
(GUITAR PLAYING)
(EXHALES)
(MUSIC PICKS UP)
(SCREAMS)
Whoo!
Go. Go all the way to the top.
(BEN SCREAMING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
KIELYR: If training is over today,
can we take Steve somewhere for class later?
Maybe.
Why does Mommy have to be gone so long?
She hasn't been gone very long.
Actually, it's been three months,
two weeks, six days, and 11 hours.
Mom is very ill.
Don't talk to us like
we're your inferiors.
BEN: Bo is right. Mom needs
to be in the hospital right now.
But you said hospitals
are only a great place to go
if you're a healthy person
and you want to die.
You said Americans are undereducated
and over medicated.
You said the AMA are avaricious whores
only too willing to spread
their fat legs for Big Pharma.
All of those things are true.
But Mom does not have enough
of the neurotransmitter serotonin
to conduct electrical
signals in her brain.
Exactly when is Mom coming back?
That's what I'm going to go find out.
Be good, monkey butts.
NAI: See you later, Dad.
- ZAJA: Bye.
- Bye, guys.
(CHUCKLES) Sorry.
Are you coming in?
No? Okay. Bye.
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT)
Here, Bo, I got that. Go talk to them.
We got time.
Ask her what she thinks
of the working people
creating an armed revolution
against the exploiting classes
and their state structures?
Well, Marxists can be just
as genocidal as capitalists.
Or whether or not she's
a dialectical materialist
and accords primacy to the class struggle?
Avoid Marxism.
Or telling her you're a Trotskyite.
Trotskyist.
Only a Stalinist would call
a Trotskyist a Trotskyite.
And I'm not a Trotskyist anymore.
I'm a Maoist.
Right.
I forgot, sorry.
(DOOR CLOSES)
JOE: Hey.
Hey, Joe.
I sold all your stuff from last time.
- Great.
- Let's see what you got.
(TRAIN WHISTLING)
(PHONE RINGING)
- HARPER: Hello?
- Hey.
- Ben.
- How's she doing?
(HARPER SOBS)
Harper?
Leslie killed herself last night.
How?
Harper.
Harper, tell me.
She slit her wrists.
You're my brother.
If you need anything from me...
(DISCONNECTS)
Last night,
Mommy killed herself.
She finally did it.
(KIDS SOBBING)
Your mother is dead.
(SNIFFLES)
Nothing is going to change.
We will go on living
in exactly the same way.
We're a family.
No.
Mom!
(YELLING)
(YELLS)
Mom! Mom!
Fuck you! Fucking...
I hate you!
Fuck!
(CHILDREN CRYING)
Daddy.
Jesus fucking Christ.
(BAGPIPES PLAY)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
- BO: Forty-three.
- BEN: Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Forty-four.
ALL: Forty-five.
BEN: Hold plank.
Like boards.
Breathe, breathe, breathe, breathe.
You got it.
Keep holding.
You're strong, you can do it.
Dad, when's Mom's funeral?
JACK: (ON PHONE) The utter recklessness,
the instability and insecurity
that you have brought to her life...
We decided to live here. Both of us.
This is your fault.
Leslie had a disease.
She had to be in a good facility.
You were kind enough to offer to pay
for it as long as she was treated near you.
We did that.
I found her will.
I assume you know
that Leslie was a Buddhist.
That means she wanted to be
cremated, not buried.
It was very important to her...
I have just lost my only child.
I'm in no mood to discuss the particulars
of her funeral with you.
Wherever you are, stay there!
You are not welcome here.
If you show up, I will have you arrested.
Jack? God damn it.
ABBY: Hello, Ben.
Leslie is in Heaven now.
She is finally at peace.
When is the ceremony?
It's in five days,
in New Mexico, at our church.
How are the children?
Did you hear what Jack just said?
It's been years.
He said that he would have me
arrested if we go there.
Did you hear that?
He's very upset.
It's just best to do what he says.
(LINE GOES DEAD)
It doesn't make any sense.
I mean, who are they
to make these decisions?
It's this sick sense of entitlement
that they all seem to have.
This is what we stand against,
this is what Mom stood against.
Mom hated that world.
Clothes on when we eat, please.
BO: It's completely unjust,
that's what it is.
We're in the very unique position
of hating those people.
- Can "unique" be modified?
- ALL: No.
NAI: We don't hate Nana and Grandpa,
but the rest of their tribe
are fascist capitalists.
You're just repeating whatever Dad says.
I'm writing down everything
you say. In my mind.
Do you even know what a fascist is?
Violent, nationalist militants.
Supported by big business and their
totalitarian single-party dictators.
- We're her family, we have to go.
- Grandpa said we can't.
What will happen if they arrest you?
Will they take us away from you?
That's a possibility.
LESLIE: Hey.
Wake up.
Wake up, grizzly bear, my fantastic man.
(CHUCKLES)
What we're doing out
here is so incredible.
The kids are amazing.
But you have to take care
of them for me, okay?
I love you all so much.
I love you so much.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(GROANS FAINTLY)
We want to see Mom.
Plus, Grandpa can't oppress us.
VESPYR: We want to honor her life.
It's the least you could do.
What's that supposed to mean?
You know.
No, I don't.
Forget it. But I know.
- We're strong and we're ready.
- I said no.
Too risky.
We're defined by our actions,
not our words.
KIELYR: Dad, give us the mission.
NAI: Mission: Rescue Mom!
Training in 10 minutes.
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
Oh, fuck!
BEN: Rell?
Can you flex your fingers?
(GROANS)
S-T-O-P.
Stay calm. Think. Observe. And plan.
If you hit the rocks below you,
you'll die from blunt force trauma.
Or internal bleeding
from massive bone fracturing.
Or splenic flexure of the large intestine.
Yes, thank you, Zaj.
I can't, my hand.
There's no cavalry.
No one will magically appear
and save you in the end.
(STRAINS)
BEN: Almost.
(GROANS)
You got it. Good boy.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
All right, let's go.
Class time on Steve.
We're going up to the glacier.
Let's go.
(ENGINE STOPS)
We can't go to Mommy's funeral.
We have to do what we're told.
Some fights, you can't win.
The powerful control
the lives of the powerless.
That's the way the world works.
It's unjust and it's unfair.
But that's just too damn bad.
We have to shut up and accept it.
Well, fuck that.
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
(ENGINE STARTING)
So they know we're coming!
(CHILDREN CHEERING)
KIDS: Mommy! Mommy! Mommy! Mommy! Mommy!
(HOWLS)
(ON PA) Attention all campers,
this is your captain speaking.
Here we have the embodiment
of Calvin Coolidge's statement
that the business of America is business.
Our democracy is one of
the brightest lights
of social justice
in the history of humankind.
And yet most of our fellow citizens
engage in frenzied shopping
as their primary form
of social interaction.
(IMITATING SALESPERSON)
"Come on down, let's go shopping!"
"These prices are insane!"
(LAUGHS)
- KIELYR: What's a bordello? Oh.
- BEN: A whorehouse.
What are you reading?
Lolita? I didn't assign that book.
I'm skipping ahead.
And?
- It's interesting.
- RELLIAN: "Interesting!"
BO: Illegal word!
Dad, Kielyr said "interesting!"
BEN: "Interesting" is a non-word.
You know you're supposed to avoid it.
Be specific.
- It's disturbing.
- More specific.
Can I just read?
After you give us your analysis thus far.
There's this old man who loves this girl,
- and she's only 12 years old.
- That's the plot.
Because it's written from his perspective,
you sort of understand
and sympathize with him.
Which is kind of amazing
because he's essentially a child molester.
But his love for her is beautiful.
But it's also sort of a trick
because it's so wrong.
You know, he's old,
and he basically rapes her.
So it makes me feel...
(SIGHS)
I hate him.
And somehow I feel sorry
for him at the same time.
Well done.
What does "rape" mean?
When a person, usually a man,
forces another person, usually a woman,
to have sexual intercourse.
Oh.
- Who's hungry?
- KIDS: Me!
What's "sexual intercourse"?
When a man sticks his penis
in a woman's vagina.
Everyone keep their eyes peeled for deer.
Why would a man stick his penis
in a woman's vagina?
Because it can give them both pleasure.
And because the combination
of a man's sperm
and a woman's egg can create a baby
and continue the human race.
But that's where she pees.
Pee comes not from the vagina,
but from the urethra,
which is within the outer labia.
But generally speaking, yes,
that is where she pees.
Everyone keep your eyes open
for game of any kind.
Okay.
Now what?
What's wrong with everyone?
Are they sick?
- What do you mean?
- Everyone's so fat.
- Yeah, they are.
- Fat like hippos.
- That's not nice to say.
- But look!
Okay, you can think that,
but we don't make fun of people.
- Right, Dad?
- BEN: That's right.
We don't make fun of people.
Except Christians.
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
Dad? Dad?
Shit.
This, right now,
this is your first real test.
Stay calm, remember your training.
Morning. How you doing today?
Morning, Officer.
Can I see your license
and registration, please?
Certainly.
- Nice rig.
- Thank you.
I pulled you over because
your back left taillight is out.
Did you know that?
No, I didn't. I'm sorry.
I'll be right back.
No school today?
Not yet.
Man, by his sin,
has become separated from God.
And only through personally
accepting the gift
of reconciliation purchased
by Jesus on the cross
can he regain his fellowship with God.
We're home-schooled. Father, may I?
You may.
(SINGING) One day when Heaven
was filled with his praises
(KIDS SINGING) One day
when sin was as black as could be
Jesus came forth to be born of a virgin
Dwelt among men, my example is He
Living, He loved me, dying, He saved me
I really should go.
Buried, He carried my sins far away
Seriously... Look,
I really need to get going.
Sorry about that, I gotta
get back to work. Sounds great.
When you get a minute,
fix that taillight, okay?
I'll do it right away, sir.
- Have a good day, guys.
- God bless.
KIDS: God bless!
Power to the people.
Stick it to the man.
(BLEATING)
They're just standing there.
I miss Mom.
(SNIFFLES)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
Hey.
No. No Esperanto. I'm not joking.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
No foreign language unless
the language is spoken by all.
You know the rule.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
No Esperanto! Please.
I'm hungry.
Well, then maybe one of you
should have shot the fucking sheep.
They have hot dogs!
- What's "cola"?
- Poison water.
VESPYR: Can I have the grilled cheese?
No.
What's a "milkshake"?
Dad, can I have a hamburger and fries?
Can I have pancakes?
Okay, everyone up. We're outta here.
What? No, why?
Because there's no actual food
on this menu. Let's go.
(GROANS)
Are you okay?
An old man's having a heart attack!
Call 911!
- Everyone, get back!
- (ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
My pills!
- I'm okay.
- He's okay now.
- Sir?
- Sorry.
Sir?
- Sir?
- Sorry about the fuss.
Are you sure we can't get you
an ambulance or anything?
No, I just forgot to take my pills.
I'm fine now, really.
Where else can we improve?
Flawed exit strategy.
Everyone went out the same doors.
No one utilized
the loading dock area at all.
- If it got blocked, we'd all be trapped.
- Mmm-hmm.
Inadequately planned extraction point.
We probably shouldn't have
all gone directly to the bus.
Predetermined pick-ups
would have been much less risky.
On the plus side, Mission:
Free the Food, accomplished.
- Mission: Free the Food!
- Top marks all around.
Now, if you'd all do me a favor
and close your eyes.
You may open your eyes.
- Happy Noam Chomsky Day.
- (ALL CHUCKLING EXCITEDLY)
But Noam was born on December 7th.
Well, we're celebrating it today.
(KIDS CHEERING)
Yes!
So good.
(BEN VOCALIZING)
(ALL SINGING) Uncle Noam,
it's the day of your birth!
Uncle Noam, it's the day of your birth!
Uncle Noam, it's the day
of your birth! Uncle Noam!
Uncle Noam, Uncle Noam!
ALL: All hail!
(SCREAMS IN EXCITEMENT)
- Here we go. Nai.
- Yes.
- Bodevan.
- Thank you.
Rellian.
Rell.
Kielyr, Vespyr, Zaj.
All right, go for it.
BO: Dad!
Fifty-five-pound pull,
laminated wood and glass.
ZAJA: Whoa!
A KA-BAR fighting knife?
- BEN: That's right.
- Thanks, Dad!
It's so beautiful.
Seven-inch blade, partially serrated,
well-balanced if you dip when you cut.
Pictures.
Oh.
Those are Black Storm broadheads.
Razor sharp.
What kind of crazy person celebrates
Noam Chomsky's birthday
like it's some kind of official holiday?
Why can't we celebrate Christmas
like the rest of the entire world?
You would prefer to celebrate
a magical fictitious elf
instead of a living humanitarian
who's done so much to promote
human rights and understanding?
Okay, well, let's have a discourse.
- Forget it.
- BEN: No, explain.
Take the opportunity to make your case.
We're all open to hearing your arguments.
And if they're valid and you persuade us,
I'm sure we'd all be willing
to change our minds. Right?
- Yeah.
- NAI: Use your words.
Ah!
- Yes! Thanks, Dad!
- (CHUCKLES) You're welcome.
Do you guys need a hand?
- HARPER: No, we're fine.
- DAVE: No, we got it.
All right.
- Jackson, not at the table.
- Hey.
- Jackson.
- All right.
HARPER: Well, I am so happy
that our family is together.
Thanks for putting on this feast.
It's all local and, um,
organic and non-GMO, so...
How did you kill those chickens?
With an ax or a knife?
(STAMMERING)
I didn't have to kill the chickens.
It's a rotisserie chicken, so you buy it.
It's already dead. Or cooked. On a thing.
(CHUCKLES)
- Dig in.
- DAVE: All right.
- Ben, some wine?
- Please.
Dad, can I have some wine?
- Sure, why not?
- Ben. (LAUGHS) No.
Children don't drink wine.
In France, and other countries, children
drink small amounts of wine all the time.
It's a digestive. It's not crack.
What's crack?
Crack is a crystallized,
highly addictive derivative
of the stimulant cocaine.
In the mid-1980s, it accelerated
the decimation of inner-city neighborhoods.
Crackheads, some of them kids
just like you guys,
were killing each other over
nothing, over their Nikes.
They killed each other for Nike?
The Greek winged goddess of victory?
(LAUGHS)
- Stop.
- He's joking, right?
- They're like Adidas.
- Who's Adidas?
You're serious?
(WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
They're shoes.
(WHISPERS) Now.
DAVE: Ben.
We're, uh...
I'm sorry for your loss.
We're devastated.
- We're just so sorry.
- Thank you, Dave.
I don't know what else to say. I'm like...
It's okay. We all know
you had issues with Leslie.
- What?
- BEN: It's not a secret.
I wouldn't say that. Why would you...
Last time we saw you,
you called her a "fucking bitch."
- Ben.
- BEN: What? It's fine.
My kids remember. Don't you, guys?
ALL: Yeah.
Wait, no. I said that...
We were all having a huge,
uh, fight about sugar.
I had given the kids some,
what, Frosted Mini-Wheats.
And the extremity of her position...
(SCOFFS)
She was yelling at me,
she pushed me, and I said...
"Don't be such a fucking bitch."
- Ben.
- I didn't say that.
They're just words.
Your words, but just words.
Not spoken in this house.
No, it's inappropriate for him
to say that in front of the kids.
Absolutely, understood.
It won't happen again.
Okay.
Dad, how did Aunt Leslie die?
DAVE: Well, Aunt Leslie was sick
and she had, uh,
complications from her sickness.
Yeah.
She had a mental illness.
Bipolar affective disorder.
We think it started
right after Bo was born.
Probably a form of postpartum psychosis.
She'd have violent mood
swings ranging from mania,
where she'd be elated and make
elaborate plans for the future,
to severe depression where
she'd become almost catatonic.
Utterly without hope.
We didn't understand what was happening.
We don't need to talk about
this in front of the children.
- These are details that are...
- (DAVE MUMBLES)
The doctors, uh, put her in the hospital,
they gave her medicine,
but she was really sick.
- Yeah.
- And she died.
Sick people die.
Sometimes they... They die.
She died 'cause of...
(SIGHS)
Because of... Because of the sickness.
BEN: She slit her wrists.
She killed herself. That's what happened.
Or that.
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
Excuse me.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
- Here you go, sweetie.
- Thank you.
Bo.
- To Mom.
- KIDS: To Mom.
(GLASSES CLINKING)
Shh.
(MUSIC PLAYING OVER TV)
ANNOUNCER: (IN VIDEO GAME) Combo!
Extreme combo!
Victory!
(INDISTINCT)
We're just doing the best we can, Ben!
- That's all anybody is doing!
- So am I!
Just the best that we know how.
I'm really sorry it doesn't live up
to your high standards!
I tell the truth to my kids.
I don't lie to my kids.
Protecting children from certain concepts
that they are too young to understand
is not lying to them.
Guys! We have neighbors, okay?
Look, it's a very hard time right now.
Everybody's still a little raw.
Can we just try to, come on,
put this to bed, all right?
I apologize.
I'm sorry for not respecting the way
you guys do things in your home.
Thank you for saying that.
I know Leslie had been sick for a long time,
but I cannot imagine how difficult
- this time must be for you.
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
DAVE: Guys, what are you doing?
We're sleeping under the stars.
But...
We made up the rec room downstairs,
- for a sleepover.
- DAVE: Yeah.
We're fine here. We're fine.
Good.
ZAJA: Why do they have to take showers?
BEN: They're not taking a shower.
I mean, it looks like a shower,
- but it's really a gas chamber.
- (SCREAMING OVER VIDEO GAME)
HARPER: Jackson, put that thing away
or I'm going to put it in the microwave,
press "Popcorn."
All right.
HARPER:
Actually, why don't you take your cousins
and go show them your action figure guys?
Why?
Because they may never
have seen them before.
It might be fun.
So, can we play Xbox afterwards?
One game. Go.
Yes!
- HARPER: Thank you.
- Yeah, try it. (CHUCKLING)
- How are the kids doing?
- They're strong.
How long have you been out there,
wherever it is you're living now?
We left Boulder when Bo was three.
And then we were on that farm
we had in Oregon until he was eight.
So, we bought the land
in the forest 10 years ago.
DAVE: How do you still have money?
- We only buy what we need.
- (VIDEO GAME BEEPING)
Look, Harper and I have been talking.
The kids need structure, stability.
They need to go to a real school,
- so they can get real jobs.
- Oh, for Christ's sake.
You're going to get them killed!
Whoa.
I'm sorry.
But your kids are without a mother now.
I don't think you have any idea
what you're doing to them.
I'm saving their lives,
that's what I'm doing.
Ben, you sound so ridiculous.
Is knowing how to set a broken bone
or how to treat a severe burn ridiculous?
Knowing how to navigate by the stars
in total darkness, that's ridiculous?
How to identify edible plants,
how to make clothes from animal skins,
how to survive in the forest
with nothing but a knife?
That's ridiculous to you?
Jesus.
They have the cardiovascular and muscular
endurance levels of elite athletes.
Who cares? They're children.
They need to go to school,
they need to learn about the world.
Justin? Jackson?
Would you please
come down here for a second?
What?
How old are you now, Jackson?
Thirteen.
Can you tell me what
the Bill of Rights is?
What something costs? I guess.
BEN: That's a good guess.
- Justin, you're in high school?
- Yeah.
- Do you like your school?
- It's whatever.
Do you know what the Bill of Rights is?
It's a government thing, right?
Like, rights that people
have in America and stuff...
- Yep. Hey, Zaja!
- ZAJA: Yes!
Would you please come down here
a moment, sweetie?
I wanted to ask you a quick question.
Zaja just turned eight, by the way.
Bill of Rights.
Amendment 1, Congress shall make no law
respecting an establishment of religion
or prohibiting the free exercise thereof,
or abridging the freedom of...
Stop. Regurgitating memorized
amendments isn't what I'm asking for.
Just tell me something
about it in your own words.
(SIGHS)
Without the Bill of Rights,
we'd be more like China.
Here, at least,
we don't have warrantless searches,
we have free speech, citizens are protected
from cruel and unusual punishments...
- That's enough.
- ZAJA: Are protected...
BEN: Wait a minute. Zaja...
How would you characterize
the 2010 Supreme Court
decision on Citizens United?
Corporations have
the same rights as people,
so there's no spending limit
on candidates.
Which means our country
is ruled by corporations
and their lobbyists who fund candidates
and command their fealty
by demanding that...
HARPER: Jesus Christ.
You made your point, we get it.
It's very impressive. All of you.
(ENGINE STARTING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Is that yoga?
Your breath, they call it pranayama.
It flows with your movements, your asana.
It's supposed to connect the mind
and the body to fuel your Samadhi.
Does that really work?
I'm Claire.
- Bodevan.
- "Bodevan"?
What kind of a name is that?
My parents made it up.
That's weird. Why?
Our names are unique.
There's only one of us in the whole world.
That's really weird.
What kind of music do you listen to?
Mostly Bach.
Mainly the Goldberg Variations,
especially Glenn Gould's versions.
I also like the Unaccompanied Cello Suites,
preferably when played by Yo-Yo Ma.
(CHUCKLES)
Where are you from?
Most recently in Paris, in the Marais.
Near Victor Hugo's house.
We're just back in the States
because of my dad's sabbatical.
He's writing a book on Dr. Spock.
Oh. I love Star Trek, it's awesome.
Which star?
You know, Spock.
The guy with the ears,
he's from Star Trek.
No, Dr. Spock was from Connecticut.
Right after Yale, he wrote
Baby and Child Care in 1947.
It's one of the seminal books
on child-rearing.
(CHUCKLES)
I was talking about that old TV show.
- Oh.
- (BOTH CHUCKLING)
- "Child-rearing."
- Of course.
Yeah, I know that one, it's...
Awesome.
(CHUCKLES)
CLAIRE: And what about your mom?
I can't talk about it.
She works for the U.S. government.
I can't talk about it due
to its highly classified nature.
Seriously?
(STAMMERS) I can't say any more.
I don't even know that much myself.
It's, um...
- I shouldn't have told you.
- (CLAIRE CHUCKLES)
- You can't tell anyone.
- (CLAIRE LAUGHING)
(BO'S BREATH TREMBLING)
Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- (BOTH CHUCKLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
CLAIRE: Okay.
Follow me. We have to be quiet.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(BO SHUSHING)
ELLEN: It's almost midnight.
I sincerely hope you two lovebirds
haven't been doing
what I think you've been doing.
BO: I know what you think.
But I know that your daughter
has taught me many things just now.
She has broadened my mind,
she has helped me grow.
When we just kissed
for the first time just then,
the endorphins that your daughter
sent through my body
were like dolphins swimming
through my bloodstream.
The way she has opened me up,
she has penetrated deep inside of me
and I know that I have penetrated deep,
deep inside of your daughter.
(BO STAMMERS)
Not... Not like that.
I would love to
when is necessary for...
I want kids someday.
Not right now, of course,
but when you're ready and when I'm ready,
because I think this should
be a shared decision.
This is a decision
that we should make together.
But when you are ready, I will be ready.
I am ready for you, if you will have me.
Claire...
What's your last name?
M... McCune.
Claire McCune,
will you be my wife?
(CLAIRE AND ELLEN LAUGHING)
Okay, funny man,
I'm sure your dad's waiting up.
Don't worry, you'll see her tomorrow.
Good night.
(WHIRRING)
(SLURPING)
BEN: It's just a penis.
Every man has one.
We're all animals of the Earth.
Clothes when we eat.
(SNORING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(LESLIE GROWLING PLAYFULLY)
(LAUGHING)
- BEN: You look happy.
- LESLIE: I am happy.
BEN: Are you happy?
LESLIE: Yeah. I'm here with you.
PRIEST: O God, to whom mercy
and forgiveness belong,
hear our prayer on behalf
of your servant Leslie Cash,
whom you have taken out of the world.
And because she put her
trust and hope in you,
command that she be carried
safely home to Heaven
and come to enjoy your eternal reward.
- Amen.
- MOURNERS: Amen.
(DOOR SLAMS OPEN)
(MOURNERS MURMURING)
BEN: Come on, guys.
BEN: Do you mind scooting over, sir?
PRIEST: I did not know Leslie personally
and I am poorer for it.
I understand that she was a loving
mother who gave up her law practice
to raise her children.
Leslie loved her mother, Abigail,
and her father, Jack, and their dogs,
Harvey and Little Bear.
They told me that she also loved gardening
and classical music,
particularly Glenn Gould's versions
of the Goldberg Variations.
She also liked walks
in the moonlight on the beach.
And she loved her husband,
Ben, and their children...
I'll, uh, take that as my cue, if I may.
(BEN CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS)
BEN:
First of all, Leslie practiced Buddhism,
which, to her, was a philosophy
and not an organized religion.
In fact, Leslie abhorred
all organized religions.
To her, they were the most
dangerous fairy tales ever invented.
Designed to elicit blind obedience and
strike fear into the hearts of the innocent
- and the uninformed.
- (INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
To her, the only thing worse than death
would have been the knowledge
that her rotting flesh
was to be trapped
for all eternity inside a big box
- (BANG)
- (MOURNERS GASP, MURMUR)
(LAUGHS) and buried in the middle
of a fucking golf course.
- (MOURNERS GASP, MURMUR)
- (CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Although the absurdity of being eulogized
by someone that didn't even know her
has exactly the kind of comedic flourish
that Leslie would have cherished.
If nothing else, (LAUGHS)
she had a sense of humor.
I want to read something to all of you,
so you'll know what I mean.
Leslie's last will and testament.
And I quote, "In the event of my death,
"I, Leslie Abigail Cash,
"as a Buddhist, wish to be cremated.
"My funeral, such as it is,
"shall be a celebration of the life cycle,
"with music and dancing.
"After, it is my expressed
desire that my ashes
"shall be taken to a nondescript location,
"preferably public and heavily populated.
"At which point my ashes,
promptly and unceremoniously,
(LAUGHS) "are to be flushed
down the nearest toilet."
- End quote.
- (MOURNERS GASP, MURMUR)
Now, that's comedy.
- USHER: All right, that's enough.
- BEN: I'm not finished.
Hey, I'm not finished.
- NAI: Dad!
- You're not listening to me!
- This is not what she wanted!
- NAI: Dad!
- USHER: Just keep moving forward.
- BEN: Let go of me!
Okay, that's it, come on.
- NAI: Dad!
- BEN: She's my wife!
This is her will!
This is against her wishes!
God damn it! We have songs to sing!
NAI: Dad!
PRIEST: If you'll open your books,
we'll read this morning
from Matthew 18, verses 15-20.
(SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING)
You are the worst thing that
has ever happened to my family.
Why won't you respect
your daughter's wishes?
Or your grandchildren's?
Hi, kids.
Hello, Grandpa, I'm Nai.
JACK: Nai. We've never met.
BEN: Gee, Abby.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
JACK: Hi, honey.
- (GASPS, LAUGHS)
- NAI: Grandma!
- ZAJA: Hello, Grandma.
- (ABBY SOBS)
We're all together.
Isn't this wonderful? (LAUGHS)
Abby and I are going to take
the children to the ceremony
and then you can follow us to the house.
They're my kids, they're staying with me.
Children, I'm sorry
that you have to witness this,
but I don't think your father
is fit to attend the funeral.
We're not going to let you
put her in the ground!
Who do you think the police
are going to listen to? Me?
Or some hippie in a clown outfit?
Come on, Abby.
Where are we going?
JACK: We're going to see Leslie.
We have to go.
- ABBY: I'm visiting with the children.
- JACK: We have to see them at the house.
Would you just give me
a minute with the children?
Honey, honey, Leslie is waiting.
Leslie is waiting. Come on.
- NAI: Bye, Grandma.
- ZAJA: Bye, Grandma and Grandpa.
Back on Steve, let's go.
- Dad?
- BEN: Let's go.
VESPYR: Dad, where are we going?
BEN:
We're going to stop this fucking funeral!
- RELLIAN: Dad!
- NAI: No!
Dad!
BO: Dad, we can't go.
VESPYR: Please, just listen to us.
- Why can't we go to Mom's funeral?
- Because of Dad.
- Because of his speech?
- Yes!
Everyone shut up and sit down!
Sit the fuck down!
- Dad.
- Silence!
Put your goddamn seat belts on!
- No! Stop Steve!
- BO: You heard Grandpa!
He'll have us arrested if we show up!
BEN: They are not stopping us
from saving Mom!
Dad, abort the mission!
Let's just go home! Abort the mission!
We are rescuing Mom!
Mom is dead, okay, Dad? She's dead!
This is not what she would
have wanted you to do!
- BEN: They have no right!
- I don't want to lose you!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Please. We can't lose you, too.
(NAI AND ZAJA CRYING)
Motherfuck!
(GRUNTING)
I have memories of Mom
laughing.
I... I can't even remember when that was.
Mom had psychotic episodes.
She had hallucinations.
Of smashing our heads in with rocks.
I heard them talking about it.
Mom was sicker than any of us knew.
Dad made her crazy.
Dad's dangerous.
(BO CHUCKLING)
You think our lives are so great.
You think Dad is so perfect.
(GRUNTS)
(STRUMMING GUITAR)
Yale, Stanford, Princeton, Harvard,
Dartmouth, MIT, Brown.
(CHUCKLES)
(EXHALES)
Well done.
Thank you.
(CHUCKLES) It's very impressive.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
BO: I guess. Yeah.
All this time you've been deceiving me?
- What? No.
- I took you to the library,
and you snuck around behind
my back taking SAT tests
- and contacting universities?
- Dad, it's not like that.
We're not an accredited home school,
(LAUGHS)
I don't know how the fuck you did it.
- I guess you somehow...
- You don't understand.
...managed to create acceptable
transcripts, got your work approved.
Listen.
All without my knowledge and approval.
Listen, Dad, please.
I don't know what's more impressive.
The fact that you got into
all these fine schools
or that for months you've been
lying directly to my face.
It was Mom.
She helped me with everything.
We did it together.
- I just want to go to college.
- You speak six languages!
You have high math, theoretical physics!
BO: Dad! But this is what
I'm talking about!
What the hell are these
people going to teach you?
(SHOUTS) I know nothing!
I know nothing!
I am a freak because of you!
You made us freaks!
And Mom knew that! She understood!
Unless it comes out of a fucking book,
I don't know anything about anything!
NAI: Dad?
You should put some clothes on, buddy.
No, stay on Steve. I'll be right back.
(DOORBELL)
- Where is he?
- No.
Abby, I need Rell.
It won't work like this, you know Jack.
He's my son.
All right.
(GUNSHOT)
JACK: It's all about timing. Just be easy.
- (GUNSHOTS)
- (FLUTTERING)
Follow through.
- Okay, get your things.
- JACK: Just a minute, please.
Come on, Rell.
I said, just a minute.
I've clearly upset you and I apologize.
You killed Mom!
ABBY: Oh.
I heard you.
I heard you fighting about where we live.
Mom wanted to leave. I heard.
Your mother and I made
certain decisions, together,
about what was best for all of you.
I'm going to live here
with Nana and Grandpa.
That's not possible.
Come on, get your stuff. Let's go.
Let's go!
I hate you! I fucking hate you!
ABBY: Rellian.
Rellian.
(THUMP)
What the fuck? That almost hit me!
If I wanted to hit you,
I would have hit you.
You just shot an arrow at me!
You told me they were in school.
They are.
Leslie and I are their teachers.
Are... Were their teachers.
So you're teaching them to steal?
Of course not.
"Mission: Free the Food"?
That was part of their training.
So you're training them to steal?
Their mother had just died.
They were in shock, they were devastated,
they needed a distraction.
So we made it Noam Chomsky Day.
JACK: "Noam Chomsky Day."
I don't even know who that is.
That's the day you gave
my grandchildren real weapons.
(LAUGHS)
How did Rellian break his hand?
He slip... He fell. And it's not broken.
He was climbing
on a rock face in the rain.
It was an accident.
And it wasn't raining
when we were climbing.
He has bruises over his whole body.
Yeah, and scratches. We all have them.
It's child abuse.
Even if they make it through whatever
it is you're doing to them,
they're going to be totally unprepared
for the real world.
And I happen to think
the opposite is true.
Rellian is legally old enough to choose,
and I intend to honor his wishes.
This is my lawyer's card.
Abby and I have decided
that we're going to file
- for custody of the children.
- (SCOFFS)
Now, I know you don't own a telephone,
but I suggest you find one
immediately and call him.
Because I would hate to have
to issue a warrant for your arrest.
He's my son.
(SCOFFS)
I'm not leaving without him, Jack.
Fine.
Who's this? Hey, hello, Bill, how are you?
It's Jack Bertrang from up in Coronado.
Listen, I think I just saw a prowler
wandering around outside on my grounds.
I wonder if you'd send a car.
Thanks. Yeah.
I hope you can explain Rellian's
injuries to the police, because I can't.
- Yes, thanks very much.
- Sure thing, Mr. Bertrang.
Okay, prisoner located.
Second floor, second window,
above the garage.
Target locked.
Bring him home, Vesp.
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTS)
(GRUNTING)
(VESPYR SHRIEKS)
- (CRASHES)
- (CAR ALARM BLARING)
- (THUMP)
- (GROANS BREATHILY)
NAI: (SCREAMING) Dad!
- KIELYR: Vespyr!
- NAI: Dad!
DOCTOR: Mr. Cash?
She's got a decent concussion,
but we did a CAT scan,
and there's absolutely
no damage to the brain.
She does have a slight fracture across
the tibia and fibula of her left leg.
She's going to need a neck brace
and a cast, but otherwise she's fine.
Can I show you something?
Uh, this is the top vertebrae here.
This dark line, it's hard to see,
but that's the fracture line.
What was she doing on a roof?
Just playing.
Well, for a girl her age,
she's unusually strong.
(SOFTLY) Yeah.
There's seven vertebrae in the neck.
A break to any of the first four,
a tear to the spinal cord...
I mean, if this had happened
just a few millimeters lower,
we'd be talking about death or paralysis.
You're a very lucky man.
- JACK: Hey, guys, come on in.
- ABBY: Aw, please come in.
- ZAJA: Hi!
- JACK: Hi, sweetheart.
ABBY: Come right in, darling.
Let me have your bag. Come on, honey.
Slow down, now.
Slow down.
Let's go this way, darling.
This way, honey.
We're going to go right into the kitchen.
Come on, let's get you
something to eat, okay?
You'll have a good night's sleep.
Okay?
- One.
- Two.
- Three.
- (JACK STRAINING)
- BO: Four.
- JACK: Four.
BO: And then you go back, five.
- JACK: Five.
- BO: Like here.
And you jump up and clap your hands.
- Six.
- (JACK SIGHS)
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- JACK: Grandfather abuse.
- RELLIAN: Grandpa down!
(LAUGHTER)
ABBY: There's a lot in here, honey.
I want you to take whatever you want.
There's something I did want to show you.
Just before you called about getting
her treatment, she sent me two letters.
And I wanted to show this one to you.
BEN: "Dear Mom, you don't need
to come get me anymore."
"Burn the other letter."
"What Ben and I have created here"
"may be unique in all of human existence."
"We created a paradise
out of Plato's Republic."
"Our children shall be philosopher kings."
"It makes me so indescribably happy."
"I'm going to get better out here."
"I know I will."
"Because we are defined by our actions,"
"not our words."
(SIGHING)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Like, not going home?
Yeah.
Like not going home.
I am not staying here.
This house is a vulgar display of wealth.
And an unethical use of space.
I think you'll all be safe here.
But we want to live with you.
I almost got you killed, sweetie.
It was an accident.
The tiles just cracked.
(SIGHS)
It's a beautiful mistake.
But a mistake.
I thought it would help her.
I... I thought...
I thought she'd get better
out there, you know?
But, uh...
But it was too much.
It was too much. Too much, uh...
And I knew it.
I did.
I knew.
Why can't we just stay with you?
Because if you do,
I'll ruin your lives.
I'll call you in a few days.
(GRUNTS)
You know where you're heading?
So?
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
I don't know.
Maybe you could take them hunting.
They...
They all like that.
- Okay.
- And, uh...
Bo wants to go to college.
He got in everywhere.
All the best schools.
I don't really know how we're
going to pay for all that.
Ben, I'll take care of it.
We're going to look after your children.
There's really nothing
to worry about, I promise.
You're doing the right thing.
(SIGHS)
Okay, well...
Good luck, Ben.
Thanks.
(SOBBING)
RELLIAN: You shaved your face.
I don't hate you.
I just wish you'd helped Mom.
Me, too.
(SOBBING)
(SOFTLY) I'm sorry.
I love you.
(SOBBING)
We want to complete the mission.
No. There's no mission.
Mission: Rescue Dad and Mommy.
Mom wanted to be cremated.
And we want to honor her wishes.
And flush her down the toilet.
I can't put any of you
in danger ever again.
I'm sorry.
"If you assume that there is no hope,"
"then you guarantee
that there will be no hope."
"If you assume that there is
an instinct for freedom,"
"that there are opportunities
to change things,"
"then there is a possibility that you can
contribute to making a better world."
Noam Chomsky.
Dad, I found her.
"Leslie Abigail Cash."
"May God bless her soul for all eternity."
Let's dig!
Otherwise she has to lie
under that bullshit forever.
(GRUNTS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(ALL PANTING)
Mommy's in here.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(TRIMMER WHIRRING)
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(SOFTLY) Hi, little bird.
It's me.
And I'm sorry.
I didn't know what to do.
I'm sorry if I made it worse.
My face is mine, my hands are mine.
My mouth is mine.
But I'm not. I'm yours.
(BLOWING)
Mom, here's your favorite song.
(SINGING)
She's got a smile that it seems to me
Reminds me of childhood memories
Where everything was as fresh
As the bright, blue sky
(PLAYING GUITAR)
- (HUMMING)
- Now and then
When I see her face
She takes me away to that special place
And if I stare too long
I'll probably break down and cry
Oh, oh, oh
Sweet child o' mine
Sweet love of
Mine
(TEMPO INCREASES)
She's got eyes of the bluest skies
As if they thought of rain
I'd hate to look into those eyes
And see an ounce of pain
Her hair reminds me of a warm, safe place
Where as a child I'd hide
And pray for the thunder and the rain
To quietly pass me by
Oh, oh, oh
Sweet child o' mine
Say oh, oh, oh
(PLAYING HARMONICA)
- (BEN CLAPPING)
- Sweet child o' mine
Sweet love o' mine
Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet
- Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet
- Sweet love o' mine
- Sweet, sweet, oh, sweet
Sweet, sweet, sweet love o' mine
- Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet
- Sweet love o' mine
- Sweet, sweet, oh, sweet
- Sweet child o' mine
Sweet, sweet, sweet child o' mine
Bye, bye, bye, bye, bye, bye
- Sweet child, sweet child
- Sweet child o' mine
Sweet child, oh, sweet
Sweet child
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- Sweet child of mine
Goodbye, Mommy!
- BO: I love you all, okay?
- NAI: We love you.
Why are you going to Namibia?
I just put my finger on a map.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER ON PA)
When you have sex with a woman,
be gentle and listen to her.
Treat her with respect and dignity,
even if you don't love her.
I know.
Always tell the truth.
Always take the high road.
I know.
Live each day like it could be your last.
Drink it in.
Be adventurous, be bold,
but savor it. It goes fast.
I know.
Don't die.
I won't.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Get out of here.
Power to the people.
Stick it to the man.
(LAUGHTER)
- Hey, guys!
- (CLUCKING)
Okay, eat your breakfast.
The school bus will be here in 15 minutes.
(SIGHS)
(SLOW ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)