(UPBEAT SONG PLAYING)
Morning, gentlemen. Feet.
So happy you're here.
This is the third open
house and not one bite.
Well...
Don't worry.
I have everything
under control.
Anna, you are a realtor?
I'm a stager. I stage
apartments for realtors.
I transform ordinary spaces
into something special.
Most people don't know what it is
they want until I show it to them,
and so many places
need my help.
Oh!
Not the Davenport,
of course.
It's just a very fine line
between elegant and dowdy.
I just think maybe
a quarter-inch higher.
Plus an eighth of an inch?
We'll get it right.
Ow!
You did that on purpose.
Knock it off.
WOMAN: As I'm sure
you're aware,
apartments at the Davenport
don't come up very often,
and we have more than our share
of applicants. So, why you?
I have lived in Boston
my entire life,
and I have always
dreamed of living here.
And thankfully, I have found
somebody who shares that dream,
and I can assure you that you will
not find two people more in sync
with your exceptionally
high standards and,
if I may be so bold,
your taste.
Thank you.
Wow!
With a bit of luck,
we might get some offers.
Come on, Charlie.
You know it's not about luck.
It's about preparation.
Put these in the oven half
an hour before you open
and you'll have five offers before noon.
No luck needed.
JEREMY: Okay, say it with me.
Three bedrooms.
- Concierge.
Full gym and swimming pool looking
over the common. I mean, come on!
Don't get cocky.
Why, you don't think
they liked us?
I like us.
Don't you like us?
- We're okay. All right.
- Okay.
Here we go.
Ready? And...
(BLEEPS)
- Ugly!
- Excuse me?
Not you, sweetie.
It's Mr. Sheinbaum
e-mailing me updates
of his double bypass.
I'm glad
I skipped lunch.
No, no, no, this is good. This is good,
because this way I don't have
to go in. We can go to dinner.
Studio apartment,
two offers already.
That's 'cause
you're a genius.
Have you packed yet?
Your flight's at 11:00.
I'm fine, just you don't be late.
We've got an 8:00 rez
and they're strict.
When am I ever late?
When your dad comes out of the woodwork
demanding to see his
daughter, that's when.
I have to go, Jer. I
haven't seen him in weeks.
Okay, just wouldn't want you all
riled up for our very special dinner.
You know I don't
like surprises.
You'll like this one.
See you.
Oh, Anna, this is gonna blow your mind!
What'd you buy?
A lot, I got a lot,
but that's not it.
I wanted to
tell you something.
Guess who I saw coming
out of DePrisco's?
- Who?
- Jeremy!
You did? When?
On the way here.
The cab was stuck in
traffic and I look over,
and he's walking
out of the store
carrying that little red bag.
- The bag.
There's only one reason
people go into DePrisco's.
You're gonna have a better
engagement ring than me, you big jerk!
- Oh, my God.
- Did you know?
No. I mean, I did put his name on
the mailing list a couple months ago
hoping he'd get the hint,
but...
Oh! He got the hint!
I think he got the hint!
Okay, hold on, we gotta
work on your surprise face,
'cause I don't want him
to know I told you...
Okay, ask me.
Ready?
Will you marry me?
(GASPS)
What? Are you scared? That
was awful. Try it again.
- Okay.
- Try it again.
Mmm...
Bigger eyes. And maybe
a little, "Who, me?"
The good news is, you have time
to practice between now and then.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Can I marry you?
No, thank you.
Already married, huh?
Getting engaged.
- Engaged?
- Dad.
My daughter
is engaged?
Garçon! Champagne!
Let's have a couple
of beers, banana.
I'll get them.
(LAUGHING EXCITEDLY)
You're gonna
be married.
Jack Brady. Import-export,
real estate. Glad to meet you.
She's been four years with
the guy. What was he thinking?
I proposed to her mother after a week!
I proposed to her
after half an hour.
JACK: (LAUGHING)
Exactly!
Where's the lucky guy?
Packing. He has a cardiology
convention in Dublin.
It's a good thing that
Jeremy finally came around.
You might have had to follow
him to Ireland this weekend.
It is leap year,
you know.
Dad, do not tell
that story again.
(LAUGHING) Why not?
It's a family myth.
It is the
honest-to-God truth!
That's what Grandma Jane
did to Grandpa Tom.
They'd been dating for a while
and he was dragging his feet,
so she finally suggested they
pay a visit to the old country.
February 29th, Dublin,
Ireland, she hits him with it.
Boom!
Ring on finger, signed,
sealed, delivered.
Well, I'm not going to
have to pull a Grandma Jane.
That's my girl. I'm finally
going to get some grandkids.
(CHUCKLING)
Dad, I've got to go.
Mmm-mmm.
No, I just got here!
Yeah, well, you were late. We said 7:00.
Oh!
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
I'm just happy that we
want the same things.
You know, you always have
it figured out for us.
I mean, even with my
crazy schedule and...
You know I appreciate it, right?
So...
So this is for you.
Jeremy.
- They're earrings.
- Yeah.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
For my ears.
Oh! Sorry.
Oh, God. Dr. Sloane. Hey, Bill.
Oh! Sounds like you're gonna
have to go in from the spine.
Send me a photo. I'll have a
look. Okay? All right. Sorry.
Why don't you
try them on?
Oh! Sorry. Sure.
(CELL PHONE BLEEPS)
(EXCLAIMS) Yikes. There's an aorta
to write home about. Look at that.
Honey, not here.
Yummy.
(CLEARS THROAT)
So, I...
(CELL PHONE BLEEPS)
It's not gonna work.
I'm so sorry, Anna. Bill
says I really "aorta" go in.
Look, he actually wrote
that. He wrote "aorta. "
So I'll pick up my bag and just go
straight to the airport when I'm done.
Forgive me?
- Of course.
- Okay.
I am so sorry.
I love you.
- I love you.
- Love you.
All right.
You "aorta" run.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
(SIGHS)
JACK: It's a good thing that
Jeremy finally came around.
You might have had to follow
him to Ireland this weekend
and pull a Grandma Jane.
It is leap year, you know.
"Leap-year proposals are
an old folklore tradition
"that dates back
to the 5th century. "
Sure.
JACK: In Ireland,
there's this tradition
that in a leap year, a woman can
propose to a man on February 29th,
one day every four years.
Will you marry me?
Yes.
(ALL EXCLAIMING GLEEFULLY)
(ALL APPLAUDING)
That's ridiculous.
FATHER MALONE: Are you traveling
on business or pleasure?
I'm going to propose to
my boyfriend on leap day.
Are you now?
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Jeremy, my boyfriend, is
already there on business.
We've been together
four years. Four years.
It's a long time.
It's not like I'm rushing
anything by doing this, you know.
He bought me earrings. Don't
get me wrong, they're beautiful,
but earrings don't
exactly say commitment.
Not that commitment
is an issue.
I mean, we're buying this
apartment together and it's perfect.
I know exactly how
I'm going to change it.
We're just gonna
knock down that wall.
You see? If we open up
the kitchen a little,
I think it flows better
into the dining area.
Just creates
a more free overall...
(SNORING)
PILO T ON PA: Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your captain speaking.
It looks like there's a
spot of bad weather up ahead,
so we may experience just
a little bit of turbulence.
(ALL SCREAMING)
I'm getting engaged.
I'm not gonna die
without getting engaged!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
This is your captain here
again, ladies and gentlemen.
I may have underestimated
the storm just a little bit,
but I'm afraid we are being
diverted to Cardiff, Wales,
as Dublin Airport
has been shut down.
What?
Once landed, ground staff will be happy
to book you onto connecting flights
in order to get you
to your final destination.
Wales? No, we can't
land in Wales.
At least
we're landing.
Yes, but I'm on
a schedule.
Excuse me. Yeah, I need to get through.
MAN ON PA: Cardiff, Wales
Airport regrets to announce
that due to
inclement weather,
all flights today
have been canceled.
I'm sorry, there's nothing
very much I can do about it.
I'm so sorry.
Yeah, could you move?
AGENT: There are no more
flights until tomorrow.
No flights until tomorrow?
Tomorrow, madam.
Tomorrow.
I think that's what I
said. Didn't I, Beryl?
That is what
you said.
Well, no, that's not
going to work for me.
Look. I'm going to Dublin to propose
to my boyfriend on the 29th, leap day.
It's an old Irish tradition,
and I need to buy a dress
and find a ring
and book a restaurant.
So, between us girls,
I think you can see why I
really need to be there today.
- Oh! Right.
- Right!
Beryl, will you ring
Dublin International Airport
and get them to open a
runway especially for madam?
Right away.
WOMAN ON PA: We regret to announce that
all commercial passenger ferries to Ireland
have been canceled.
Will all passengers booked
for the crossing to Ringaskiddy
please report to
the information desk?
Hi. I'd like a ticket
to Cork, please.
Ferry's canceled.
What is wrong
with this country?
I usually blame
the government,
but this one's the weather. Storm, see?
Well, we'll just see about
that. I'll find my own boat.
We're going to have to go in to Dingle.
But I paid for Cork!
(EXCLAIMS)
Okay. Dingle will do.
(PANTING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
You can take the man
out of the fish,
but you can't take the
fish out of the water!
(ALL LAUGHING)
That a good one,
Dekko?
(ANNA STUTTERS)
Hello.
Are you open?
Australian.
South African.
Actually, she's American.
Anna, from Boston.
I just need someone to tell me
how to get to Dublin from here.
Is there a bus, maybe?
1987.
I'm sorry?
The year the last
Dublin bus left Dingle.
No, no, no. The train
stopped running in '87.
The bus stopped
running in 1989.
It was 1987.
Okay.
Is there a taxi service
or something?
Perfect. Thank you.
My battery's going
to die any second.
Ma'am.
(SIGHS)
Oh, thank you.
Hello there.
Hello.
(PHONE RINGING)
MAN ON PHONE: Hello?
Hello. Yes, I need
a taxi to Dublin.
Yeah, where you
calling from?
I'm in a funny little pub called
the Carack or, I don't know, Caragh?
(CHUCKLES) Carahg?
Whatever.
We don't drive
American redheads.
What do you mean you don't
drive American redheads?
How do you know
the color of my hair?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Of course. You're the taxi
driver. Well, I need you...
I need you to drive me to Dublin.
Dublin, is it?
Mmm.
Well, I'll tell you something
about Dublin, Anna from Boston.
Dublin is a city of chancers and
cheats and backstabbing snakes.
It's where the worst of humanity
collects to poison this fair country.
I wouldn't drive you to Dublin
if you were to offer me €500.
Jesus! I'd sell
me wife for €500!
Trust me,
you'd have few takers.
All right. Anyone else want
to go to Dublin for 500?
I'm your man, missus!
(THUDS)
It's bad luck to start
a journey on a Friday.
Saturday. It's bad luck to
start a journey on a Saturday.
Tuesday!
No, it's Sunday,
to be sure.
Fine. It's late.
I'll just find somebody
to drive me in the morning.
So, if one of you can direct
me to the nearest hotel?
Or bed and breakfast?
Of course. Of course.
This is also the hotel.
(SIGHS)
Bathroom's down the hall. You have
to flush it twice. Seriously, twice.
Just like
the Four Seasons.
Okay.
I noticed a menu
on the bar?
- It's closed.
- Closed.
But given the famous
Irish tradition
of hospitality
and generosity...
I'll do you
a hang sandwich.
What's a hang?
Hang is a verb.
It's not a sandwich.
It did die. Of course.
(IRISH FOLK MUSIC PLAYING)
Huh!
(GRUNTING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(CRASHING)
(COMPLAINING IN IRISH)
There we go.
(EXCLAIMS)
(MUSIC STOPS)
MAN 1: Hey,
the lights are gone!
MAN 2: Oh, Jesus,
the lights failed again.
(EXHALING IN FRUSTRATION)
Women!
SEAMUS: It's over now.
(SIGHS) For the love of God.
What the hell you doing?
Plugging something in.
Give me that.
It's personal.
You fried my BlackBerry.
You fried the whole
village! Idiot!
Jackass.
(SNIFFING)
(ROOSTER CROWING)
JEREMY ON PHONE:
You're here in Ireland?
ANNA: Yeah.
I wanted to surprise you, but it's
turned into a complete disaster.
At this point I'm just glad
somebody knows where I am.
I mean, seriously, you have no idea
what passes for a hotel out here,
or common courtesy.
I can't wait
to see you.
Well, I can't wait
to see you, either.
Well, when will
you get here?
I should be there this afternoon.
I just need to get a cab.
Great surprise, honey.
I love you.
I love you, too. Bye.
TOMMO: Sorry, Declan, you've had
plenty of time to pay your debt.
DECLAN: But I'm almost there. I'm down
to the last of the bloody interest.
Come on, Tommo, be
reasonable, would you?
You can't take
the blessed kitchen!
You'll put me
out of business!
The whole lot, or the kitchen
goes in the back of the van.
Give me a month.
A month? A week.
A week? God!
Ten days, €900,
guaranteed.
A thousand, Dekko.
That's the old interest right there.
The interest on the
interest on the... Oh, man.
Ten days, €1,000.
Okay. Okay.
You'll have it.
You have my word.
Done.
- Later.
- All right, lads.
Come on, then, let's do it. But
only 'cause you're desperate.
I'll drive you
to Dublin.
Will you get out?
€500, like you said.
Yes or no?
You're not a fan
of Dublin.
You've made that very clear,
so I won't inconvenience you.
It's not inconvenient at all.
What part of "get out"
do you not understand?
A simple yes
or no will do.
Yes, you can
drive me, now...
Good. Be outside
in 10 minutes.
God!
(GASPS) Naked here!
By the way,
it's 100 for the room,
and that includes
the vandalism.
I'll leave you to it.
Naked here.
(CAR HONKING)
(MEOWS)
There you are, Bob.
Hop in.
Please tell me that
that is the car
that is taking us around the
corner to the actual taxi.
I'll have you know that is
a Renault 4. She's classic!
Worst fears confirmed.
She's rock solid right there!
Beautiful. Come on.
None of those fancy
airbags to get in the way.
Don't listen to her.
She knows not what she says.
Do you mind?
Ah! Sure.
(HINGES SQUEAKING)
Thank you.
How does that work?
Can you be careful with that?
That was a gift from my boyfriend.
He bought you
a suitcase?
(CHUCKLES)
It's a Vuitton.
What?
A Louis Vuitton?
Come on.
Is it yourself, Louis? Can I give you
a hand getting into the car, Louis?
She named her suitcase.
She's a crackpot.
You can't
go now, missus.
Why not?
A black cat just
crossed your path.
You can't start a journey
when you see a black cat.
Ten years bad luck.
No, it's not a cat,
it's a magpie.
Anyway, it's 15 years bad luck.
Thirteen!
It's 12,
definitely 12.
Then I guess it's a good thing
I don't believe in luck, so...
Well, you ought to, if
you're getting into that, you.
(MEN LAUGHING)
Safe journey.
(SPEAKING IN IRISH)
May the road
rise up to meet you.
See you, lads!
DONAL: Good luck, Declan!
JOE: Bye, now.
(EXCLAIMS)
I tell you
something,
they'll kill
each other!
ANNA: Okay, we're here, on the road.
DECLAN: Uh-huh!
It's only February 27th. I still
have two days to get there, so...
Mmm-hmm.
Where are we?
(IRISH ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO)
(BELCHING)
(SIGHS IN DISGUST)
I may even get there before the stores
close. I could get some shopping in.
That's the reason you're
going to Dublin, is to shop?
No, I'm...
(MUSIC STOPS)
If you must know, I'm going
there to propose to my boyfriend.
He's at a medical conference
there. He's a cardiologist.
We are applying to move into
the most amazing apartment,
and I actually thought he was going
to propose to me the other night,
but he didn't.
Yeah?
Yeah, and you guys have
this great tradition
that a woman can
propose to a man
on the 29th of February
in a leap year.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
So I thought,
"Why not?"
Yeah!
Yeah.
I mean...
(BOTH WHOOPING)
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
That's the stupidest
thing I've ever heard!
(LAUGHING)
No, it isn't.
Yeah, it is.
No, it's a tradition.
It's a romantic tradition.
It's a day for desperate women
trying to trap themselves a man
who clearly doesn't
want to get married.
You've got to know that if
your man wanted to propose,
he'd have done it
already. Fact!
(LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLES MOCKINGLY)
(CHUCKLING)
(IRISH ROCK MUSIC BLARING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
No one touches the music!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Are you crazy? You know
nothing about me or Jeremy!
You know what you are?
You're a cynic.
You're a lonely,
bitter cynic.
Better that than an idiot.
"Leap year, diddly-eye!
"Will you marry me,
diddly-eye?
"I've got a suitcase
called Louis, diddly-eye!"
What are you, the
Lucky Charms leprechaun?
You know what? We are done.
We're not talking anymore.
I'm not paying you to talk,
I'm not paying for your opinion.
I'm paying you to drive, so
just get in the car and drive.
Suits me, Bob.
And what is with
this Bob thing?
(COWS MOOING)
(SIGHS)
Aren't you going
to do something?
I am doing something. I'm
waiting for them to move.
(SIGHS) For God's sake.
Hi, cows.
Look, I have spent the past 24
hours in every level of hell,
and I am not going to let
your black and white asses
drag me any further, so if you know
what's good for you, you'll move.
It comes as a real shock to find
out that you speak fluent cow.
Now!
That's right.
Nice cows.
Let's move. Let's move
along. Come on, cows.
Why don't you propose something to them?
Yeah, you guys are...
Wow, you're big.
We're gonna just...
Oh, yeah,
they're moving now.
(EXCLAIMS)
Must be your personality.
Yours is a bit
more repellent,
so if you want to try...
(COWS MOOING)
That's right. That's
how you get things done.
That's it, girl!
That's right! That is
how you get things done.
You don't just sit around like
some backwoods Irish bumpkin.
You're welcome.
You might want to
just watch your
step.
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
$600 shoes.
Put them in the wash,
they'll be grand.
Put them in the wash?
The wash?
(CHUCKLES)
You do not put
these shoes in the wash.
- Whoa! Whoa!
- Whoa!
- Stop!
- Whoa! Wait!
- Stop it!
- What do I do?
Get in the car
and use the brake!
(GASPING)
Baby! I got you, baby! I got you!
(EXCLAIMING)
Baby!
Don't hurt yourself!
Make it stop!
My purse is in there!
Oh, darling.
Oh, Jesus.
My Renault 4!
Look what you done!
What I've done?
You couldn't just
wait for the cows!
You couldn't
just help me?
It's gonna cost at least
200 to tow her out.
That's not gonna come out of my
pocket. It's coming out of yours!
Oh, like hell. You will have to
kill me before I pay you a dime!
There's an idea.
(GASPS)
Where you going?
Dublin.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Look, this is an easy fix.
All we need to do
is find a phone,
call the garage, get
a tow, hop in the car,
back on the road and we'll
be in Dublin in no time.
Just cool the jets,
would you?
(HONKING)
Wait! Hey!
I wouldn't get in there if I was you!
And I care about
your opinion because...
DECLAN:
Fine, go ahead.
- All right there, sweetheart?
- Hi.
You looking
for a ride?
Yes, I'm going
to Dublin.
Oh!
(SINGING) In Dublin's fair city
where the girls are so pretty
- Yes.
- Now there's a coincidence,
'cause I'm going
there myself.
Let me help you with
the old suitcase there.
That's very sweet of you.
Not at all.
And I didn't
even have to ask.
(CHUCKLING)
Top of the morning to you!
Oh! Morning.
That's a fancy bit of
suitcase, no mistake.
It's quality. You can see that
just by looking at it, you know?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, I'd say
it's been a pleasure,
but I think
we both know that...
Wait. No! Wait! Wait! Come
back here! You can't just...
(GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
(WHISTLING)
They...
There you are.
Soon as I finish this,
I'll call us a tow truck.
Us? There is no us.
I am calling a real taxi.
You leave me alone.
Okay, Bob.
Excuse me.
(MISPRONOUNCING) Eoghan?
Eoghan.
Oh!
Do you have a phone, please? Please?
Thank you.
Safe home.
(SPEAKING IN IRISH)
Yeah, yeah.
(MEN LAUGHING)
So nice of you to
look after my suitcase,
but I'll take it back.
Thank you.
Is that right, missus?
I'll call the
American ambassador.
Oh, is this his?
(GASPS)
Well, I just...
I...
(DOOR OPENING)
DECLAN: Fun's over, lads.
Give the girl
her stuff back.
And who the hell are you?
Nobody.
Just keeping the peace.
Yeah? Well, you can keep
your peace out of it.
(GROANS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
That was
impressive.
Ow!
Out.
Fair enough.
Hi. I just...
Should just get
my things and go.
Must be something special.
Who?
Your fella.
Oh!
Jeremy. He is.
He's...
He's a cardiologist.
(SIGHS)
Hi. When is the next train
to Dublin?
You're just in time.
The next train leaves
in two hours and 43 minutes.
Great.
It's a few bob
to Dublin, mind.
"Bob"?
Cash.
Money. You know?
Mmm.
Hey, fella.
(SIGHS)
Ballycarbery.
Mmm. Same to you.
There.
Ballycarbery Castle.
It's one of the 10 wonders
of Ireland, so I'm told.
Can only be 15 minutes to the top.
I don't want to
miss the train.
Yeah, well, that's a good
point. Don't miss the train.
No.
Only two
and a half hours.
Time is going to fly.
I'll stay here.
Suit yourself.
I will.
(WHIMPERING)
Hi.
(BARKING)
Declan?
Wait! I love castles.
ANNA:
It's beautiful.
DECLAN: I'm sorry you're not gonna
get to Dublin before the shops shut.
I have other interests besides shopping.
I have a life.
A job.
What do you do, then?
I stage apartments.
Stage apartments,
now that's...
That's...
What's that?
Well, when somebody is
selling an apartment or a home,
I bring stuff in and make it
look as beautiful as it can look.
And they get to keep all
the stuff when they buy it?
No, I take it away. I'm just
presenting them with the possibilities.
I put a sheen on it.
Hang on. So you do
your job, yeah?
Yeah.
They buy the house,
yeah?
Yeah.
And then you come along and you
take all the stuff away again, yeah?
Yeah.
You're a con artist.
No, I'm not a con...
That's just
so typical of you.
You think the worst
of everybody.
No.
Oh, no? I'd love to know
who you have a good word for.
I can think of a couple
of good words for you.
Riddle me this.
If your apartment's on fire,
your beautiful apartment,
what would you take?
What?
If your house was on fire
and you had 60 seconds,
what would you take?
Come on.
(EXCLAIMS IN CONFUSION)
I...
Come on. Would it be the
Chihuahua on the duvet?
I'm not playing
this game with you.
There you are.
What would you take?
What would you take? Your
lovely inn is on fire.
Hmm.
What are you going to
take? You know, your...
Flames coming up the stairs.
You've got 60 seconds.
Oh!
The bottles of alcohol
in your pub are exploding.
What are you
going to grab?
I know exactly
what I'd "grab. "
Oh, yeah? What?
Not telling you.
You can dish it, but you
can't take it, can you?
(PANTING)
It's really...
It's a castle!
Told you.
So what's the story
with this place?
Well, hundreds
of years ago,
there was this beautiful
girl called Grainne.
Now, she was promised in marriage
to this fella called Fionn,
who was kind of
a cranky old warlord,
old enough to be her father,
old enough to be her grandfather,
and therefore
(SPLUTTERS)
she wasn't
in love with him.
Anyway, on the night
of their betrothal,
whom did she meet but a
handsome young warrior, Diarmuid.
They fell madly in love at first
sight, but what could she do?
Well, she slips a sleeping
potion in everyone's drinks,
and the pair of them run off
together across the Shannon.
Fionn wakes and there's Grainne
gone. Well, he goes mental.
Takes his army and
heads off in hot pursuit.
But it was the people, you know, the
people in the villages of Ireland,
they took pity on
Diarmuid and Grainne.
They hid them in forests and
in their barns and castles,
where they'd sleep one night
and then they'd move on.
Come on.
Is it safe?
Of course.
Sleep was all they did, 'cause
Diarmuid, good man that he was,
was suffering the old guilt
about two-timing Fionn
and out of respect for him, didn't,
you know, take it any further.
I get it.
Oh, yeah.
(SIGHS)
And then they came
to this castle
and this view.
Wow.
And 'tis said, you know, that,
unable to resist such beauty,
that here,
in this place, they...
They consummated
their love.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(BIRD CAWING)
Oh, my God.
You're hitting on me.
I'm what?
(SCOFFS)
I'm the young woman on
the eve of her engagement
that can't resist a handsome
stranger? Oh, come on.
I'm what?
You didn't honestly think
that was gonna work, did you?
Don't flatter yourself,
darling. The story's true,
but it sure as shite
ain't about you.
- No?
- No, you arrogant...
Arrogant what exactly?
Well, that's a tough one.
Is it American?
(TRAIN HORN BLARING)
Oh, no. The train.
Wait! Wait,
I have a ticket!
I'm very...
You just had to take me
up there, didn't you?
One of the seven
wonders of Ireland!
Okay.
(YELPING)
Oh, no.
(SCREAMING)
Well, that speeded
things up a bit.
I hate you.
(TRAIN HORN BLARING)
In the old days, I could
have held it for you,
but it's all "time is money" nowadays.
(WHIMPERING)
Come on, now. Come on, and
don't be worrying yourself.
We'll get you to
where you want to go.
Forecast said sunny.
FRANK: Here we are. The
best little B&B in Tipperary.
Come in. Come in.
Look what
the cat dragged in.
Oh! My poor dears.
You're lucky,
so you are.
Just half an hour ago, I had
two backpackers at the door
wanting the room.
But they weren't married.
Admitted it right out.
No shame.
So I sent them packing.
Right is right,
rain or no rain.
Hmm.
So, it's Mr. and Mrs...
- Brady.
- O'Callaghan.
Bradycallaghan.
O'Bradycallaghan.
We're not long married, and it's
still quite a mouthful for an American.
I come from a long,
long line of Dingle
O'Bradycallaghans.
We're praying
that one day
we'll be able to have a son and
heir to help keep the name going.
(CHUCKLING)
Anna, Declan to you.
Lovely. Now, let's get you to your room.
Thank you.
After you, petal.
Thank you, sunshine.
Would you like a hand
with the bag, pumpkin?
Well, you're not sleeping in that
bed with me, Mr. O'Bradycallaghan.
Maybe you're not sleeping
in the bed with me.
- Very gallant.
- Gallant?
Welcome to the age
of equality.
You lot wanted the vote.
Live with it, darling.
Comfy.
We'll flip for it, darling.
Okay, fair's fair.
Heads I win,
tails you lose.
Heads.
Heads it is.
Shame. You can sleep
in the bath.
It's a shower.
You can sleep
in the shower.
Fine.
Just so long as I don't have
to sleep anywhere near you.
(SHOWER RUNNING)
ANNA: (SINGING)
I'm washing in the shower
Getting mud off
Love hot water
Got a bruise there
Wait a minute. You lying,
deceiving son of a...
Get up! Get up.
Get up.
Whoa! What?
Oh! "Heads you win,
tails I lose. "
You finally
got that, did you?
Good for you.
Up! Get up! This is
my bed. Liars forfeit.
And take a shower.
You smell.
Mmm-mmm.
You can see right
through the curtain.
(SCOFFING) Can you?
Can you?
Okay, liars forfeit, liars forfeit!
No peeking.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
ANNA: Come in.
Hello, dear.
Everything all right?
Now, for dinner we've got
tripe. Homemade. Family recipe.
Tripe.
Nothing like a bit of cow's
stomach on a rainy day.
Yum. Did you hear that,
darling? Tripe!
DECLAN: Right, tripe.
I was thinking,
Mrs. O'Docherty,
to thank you for taking
us in on such short notice,
why don't you
let me cook?
No, darling,
I couldn't.
Oh, you could. He's a
chef. He's very good.
DECLAN: It's true!
Really?
Well, that's gas.
We've got two Italians staying,
as well. Would that be okay?
DECLAN: No problem at all!
Thanks a million.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Good call.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
What the hell
are you doing now?
This recipe says
three medium carrots,
and I just think this one is a little
large to be classified as medium.
And if you look
at these two,
they're clearly medium,
while this one is slightly...
Watch.
Three medium-sized carrots.
You know, I don't think there's anything
wrong with wanting to be precise.
Okay.
Well, then
you must be very,
very precise.
Here's an idea.
Why don't you stop trying to control
everything in the known universe?
It's dinner.
Have a little faith.
It'll all work out.
Heard that one before.
Well, maybe you
should have listened.
Really? You think?
It'll all work out. My dad was
the king of "it'll all work out. "
Time shares in the Bahamas,
mobile video stores,
whatever the next
big nothing was,
all our money
went right after it.
But don't worry.
It'll all work out.
Cut to me working two
part-time jobs after school
and us getting our house repossessed
on Christmas Eve. Ho, ho, ho.
So you will forgive me
if I don't listen.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
A father's someone you should
be able to rely on, you know?
Anyway, dinner.
We have got
cabbages, a leek,
three medium carrots.
You're not one of those
vegetarians, are you?
No.
Good.
Declan one,
chicken nil.
Sweet.
(NECK SNAPS)
(HEN GROANS)
Coq au vin?
(GRUNTS IN FRUSTRATION)
What?
(SOFTLY) Give me strength.
Don't start telling me that you've
never had chicken stew before.
Of course I have.
I'm wondering where it is that
you think chickens come from.
The freezer section.
I know, I know. I...
You just surprised me.
You keep doing that.
Give me the carrots.
Yes, carrots.
Sorry.
We build up the
temperature a little bit.
You don't need to chop
them. It's hard to hold.
That smells amazing.
Good girl. And...
(INAUDIBLE)
So this is what you call staging, is it?
Sort of.
Not too shabby.
- Here?
- Yeah.
(ALL LAUGHING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN CONTENT)
Impeccable.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
The chicken
was wonderful.
Wasn't it? And I'm
usually awful at chicken.
Jeremy always says
I make it too dry.
Jeremy?
Oh!
Jeremy. Our...
Our next door neighbor.
Who sometimes
comes by for dinner.
Right, Declan?
Mmm. Yeah, yeah.
He's a lovely old soul.
Yeah.
A little bit learning
difficulties, you know.
Tells everyone he's a
cardiologist. It's a scream.
(ALL LAUGHING)
But he's a happy chap,
you know.
He's got a little thing,
bless him, for her.
Antique, Frank?
Antique, yeah. Like me.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
Wedding present,
they were.
It's only 44 years,
you cheeky rascal!
(ALL LAUGHING)
(ALL TOASTING IN IRISH)
STEFANO: See? That's what it
takes to be married for 44 years.
The kiss.
Always kiss like it's the
first time and the last time.
(SPEAKS IN ITALIAN)
Grand.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well, come on then, son.
Show us old ones
how it's done.
Sorry?
Well, I've kissed
my wife.
Stefano has certainly
kissed his wife.
No, we're fine. We did it earlier, kiss.
Done and dusted.
A bit of chivalry, man.
You know what I'm saying?
Oh! That's perfect.
If that was a kiss, I'm surprised
you're still wed to him at all.
No, no, they're shy, that's all.
Yes. Really shy.
You're among friends!
You're young,
married, in love!
Anyone can see that.
Damn it, man.
Kiss the girl!
- STEFANO: Bravo!
- There you go.
FRANK: Now that's a kiss!
It's quite wet.
Show a little mercy,
would you?
All right.
But one snore and you're
back in the shower.
Great.
Who'd have thought it'd take
two days to get to Dublin?
I have to charge you
an overnighter, by the way.
Surprise.
- €100.
- Fifty.
Seventy-five it is.
Running total €675.
Fine. If it's all about
money for you, then 675 it is.
Good night.
Night.
(ROMANTIC SONG PLAYING)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(CLOCK CUCKOOING)
(ROOSTER CROWING)
I'm so sorry
I'm not there yet.
You can't imagine
what I've been through.
JEREMY ON PHONE: Worse than when
they lost our luggage in Barbados?
Like that times 10.
I just... I just
can't wait to see you.
Well, maybe this
will cheer you up.
I just heard from the board,
and we got the apartment!
- What?
- Yeah.
I just got off the phone
with Edith. It's ours.
Ah! Jeremy!
That is exactly what I
needed to hear this morning.
Everything is working out
for us. I'm so excited.
We'll have to celebrate in
person when you get here.
We sure will.
Hurry up already.
I miss you.
I miss you, too.
Morning.
Yeah.
Oh, is this for me?
Morning, lovebirds!
Sleep well, did you?
Yes, thank you.
(FRANK LAUGHING)
So, what's on
the agenda today, then?
Mmm. Off to Dublin
for me.
Well, you can't
do that now.
Why not?
This is Sunday.
Never start a journey on
a Sunday, or a full moon.
Oh, well, I don't believe
in that superstition stuff.
How are you on train timetables?
Do you believe in them?
Sunday.
No trains.
- No trains?
- No.
Oh! For God's sake.
I have to be in Dublin by
the 29th. That's tomorrow.
Why is that
again, darling?
Fine. Okay.
Frank, you have a car, don't you?
- Oh, yes.
- Yes.
Okay. I could...
I would be willing to pay you
a substantial amount of money
if you would
maybe drive me.
No.
Oh! It's not the money,
girl. It's Eileen.
She's got it.
Gone to Mass.
Then the weekly shop,
you know.
Okay, well, then
when she's back, you...
(CHUCKLES) She won't
be back till all hours.
Why?
It's a fair old jaunt
to Dublin.
Where is she?
FRANK: Dublin.
Bingo!
(DECLAN CLEARS THROAT)
What?
Bus station's
that way.
What?
Knock it off.
It's hailstones.
Are you serious?
- Ow!
- Run!
(LAUGHING)
Come on. It's fecking
Murphy's Law with you.
Come on!
I got Louis.
Don't worry.
Ow!
Those sting!
The size
of golf balls!
Jesus Christ!
Is Lord.
Have you any just cause or
impediment why this man and this woman
should not be joined
together in holy matrimony?
No, no, Father.
You carry on.
I'm sure that they know
what they're doing.
Good. In that case, you're very
welcome. Why don't you sit down?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
DECLAN: Come on. Dublin.
We should be making tracks.
ANNA: No. The priest
is gonna give us a ride
to the bus station
when it's over.
We can walk!
I'm not walking another
four hours in these shoes.
Besides, look how beautiful it all is.
I kind of
hate weddings.
Why? Because people are in
love? That's so offensive to you?
Yeah.
You know,
you have all of these random
opinions and a bad attitude.
What do you know? You're
clearly not married,
and you have obviously
never been engaged.
Actually, I have.
Once.
I don't want to
interrupt a good party,
but I want to say
thank you to my husband.
I want to say, may you
never steal, lie or cheat.
But if you must steal,
then steal away
my sorrows.
And if you must lie,
lie with me all the nights of my life.
And if you must cheat,
then please cheat death,
because I couldn't
live a day without you.
Cheers!
Are you all right?
Grand. You know,
it's just hot in there.
Do you want
to talk about it?
Listen,
Bob.
You're not
in America now.
You're in Ireland.
So, have a drink.
Shut up.
I was just
trying to help.
- Help?
- Yeah.
That's hilarious.
The woman who's so desperate, she's
diddly-eying her way to Dublin,
making the most important
decision of her life
based on some
ridiculous tradition,
which, frankly,
is a load of old poo.
So, thank you, but it's not
I who needs the help, okay?
It is not
a load of poo.
It's romantic.
It's really,
really romantic.
(BAND PLAYING UPBEAT SONG)
I'm not good
at weddings.
They're better with
a couple martinis.
Okay, thank you very much!
We're going to do a special
request now for the bridesmaids.
Want a go?
No. No, I don't...
I don't Riverdance.
Do you never let
your hair down, woman?
Yes.
In my way, I do.
Good.
(BAND PLAYING)
Now, this is an easy one. You'll
pick it up. Just follow them.
We're going in a circle
going that way.
(STOMPING RHYTHMICALLY)
(BAND SINGING)
(EXCLAIMING)
ANNA: No, no,
put me down!
(LAUGHING)
(ALL GASP)
(FEEDBACK)
I'm really sorry.
I was spinning.
Forget about it. At least
it wasn't my husband.
Yeah. Right.
At least it wasn't him.
(ALL GASPING)
I'm...
I thought
I was bad at weddings.
(DECLAN CLEARS THROAT)
Aren't you supposed to be
taking me to Dublin?
Well, just tell me when. As
ever, your servant awaits.
You know what,
Declan?
Do you know
what you are?
Mmm-hmm.
You're a beast.
You're a real
beast.
Hmm.
And I cannot
stand you.
- Really?
- Mmm-hmm.
But you know what?
I'm onto you.
Is that right?
(STUTTERING) All your
beastishness is like...
It's an act.
It's a great, big,
massive cover-up.
And you growl and you
snap, but you are in...
You're in pain.
And you've got a...
(CHUCKLES) You've got a big
thorn in your beasty paw.
Like a lion.
A lovely, lovely lion.
(VOMITING)
- Great.
- I'm sorry.
That's romantic.
Up you come. Up!
God, you're a lump.
My suitcase!
Don't worry about Louis.
I'll get him.
(BUS ENGINE REVVING)
(SIGHS)
You're joking me.
Perfect.
You can deduct the coffee from my bill.
Deduct away. Don't forget to
add on for a new pair of shoes,
Pukey.
(IMITATING IRISH ACCENT) Put them
in the wash, they'll be grand.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
You missed your bus.
There's another one
in 20 minutes.
Oh, God. Am I still
coming with you?
I am paying you
to take me to Dublin
and you're taking me
to Dublin.
That's fine.
Thank you.
He's out.
I left a message
with the front desk.
So, Dublin.
Right on time.
So I suppose
I should pay you.
I suppose you should.
There'll be an ATM
at the hotel.
Right, so I'll be
portering again, will I?
Not if you don't
want to.
I didn't say that.
We can get a cab.
You've got legs,
haven't you, woman?
My best feature,
so I'm told.
Who told you that?
It's a beautiful city.
And I haven't seen
one backstabbing snake.
Yeah, well, it's the chancers and
cheats that you have to watch out for.
She's here,
isn't she?
In Dublin. One of the
chancers and cheats.
The blonde in the photo.
Who was the guy?
Oh!
So him and her...
Right.
Sorry.
We were all running the Caragh
together, me, Kaleigh, Ryan.
So we bought the pub and
built it up from nothing.
We really got it going.
I mean, we were flying.
And I thought that me and
Kaleigh were mad for each other.
Apparently not.
So that thing I'd grab
if I had 60 seconds,
it's my mother's
Claddagh ring.
You know, the ones with the two
hands holding the crowned heart.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, she's got it.
Well, you're here now. You
should find her and get it back.
I don't know.
It's your mother's ring.
Anyway, I thought
it was your ring
we were meant to be
worrying about.
Diddly-eye.
Oh, yeah. Right.
Well, I'm glad to see
you're finally on board.
It has nothing to do with me. I'm
just the old bag carrier around here.
Why should I care?
So you don't?
Would it make
a difference?
Come on.
So.
- Here.
- Nah, it's okay.
Declan, take it.
We had a deal. Please?
Tell you what. Why don't you just give
me that one bob and we'll call it a day?
Which one bob?
The one we flipped
for the bed.
Yeah.
Liar.
- Well, best of luck.
- Yeah.
So long, Louis.
Anna.
Yes?
Anna! Anna!
Hi! Finally. God.
I thought I was gonna have to call a
helicopter rescue team to come get you.
- Where have you been? Hi.
- Hey.
- ANNA: Long story.
- JEREMY: Sorry.
It's good
to see you.
- You okay? Yeah?
- Mmm. Yeah.
Hi.
I'm sorry,
do I know you?
Oh!
Jeremy, this is Declan.
Declan drove...
He helped me get
from Dingle to Dublin.
Oh! Okay. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, well, I don't envy that job.
This lady is not
big on adventure.
No.
Nice to meet you, bro.
- Nice to meet you.
- Yeah. Yeah.
So did she
take care of you?
Did you tip him?
Oh!
She paid me.
Great. Well, thanks for
getting her home safe.
Oh, God, I missed you! I missed
you! I missed you! I missed you!
I missed you, too.
No, I really
missed you.
I did. And...
And it got me thinking.
Why aren't we married?
Will you marry me?
Are you serious?
Am I serious? Yeah. Well,
I'm down on my knee. I...
I got this.
No pressure,
but it's all on camera.
Sweetheart.
Sweetie?
I... Were you supposed
to give me an answer?
Yes. Of course.
- Yeah?
- Yes.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
Okay.
Let's try this on.
Ah! It fits!
I have champagne
waiting in the room,
so we should go on up.
- Great.
Thank you.
(PHONE RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
I never thought
I'd see you in Dublin.
Declan.
Kaleigh.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
There you go. And there's
pints. They're on the way.
Thank you!
You are saving the pub.
You're keeping the pans in the
kitchen. I will kiss you later.
Congratulations! Hi!
Let me see it!
(EXCLAIMING IN AWE)
Wow.
Mmm.
Dekko.
Tom. There you are.
You're short.
But not by much.
Sorry. Come on, lads!
Oh, my God,
look at this place!
- Do you like it?
- Do I like it?
I want to throw you out of
your own window and take it.
Hold on a minute there.
You can show us the color
of your wallet for a change.
That's all.
Drinks on the house!
(ALL WHOOPING)
I feel like your
whole happy ending
is gonna be a real test
for our friendship.
I'm pretty sure she
would have been happy
with just this apartment. I
don't think you needed to propose.
Oh! It was kind of
a package deal.
Really? What, buy an
apartment, they throw in a ring?
More like
the other way around.
What do you mean?
Well, I think it was
Edith, from the board.
She called me in Dublin,
probing about our marital status.
Can you believe that? Nothing
specific, just interested, you know?
Like the residents, they're
kind of old-fashioned
when it comes to issues
like this. Blah, blah, blah.
I got the message. Married,
you're in. Unmarried, you're not.
So I just said we were hours
away from getting engaged.
I just said it
and it came out.
And I don't know
where it came from,
but I could almost hear
them cutting our keys.
So I put down the phone
and thought, "Well,
"why the hell not,
you know?"
- Really?
- Sure. I mean,
we'd have gotten around
to it eventually, right?
- Right. Of course.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Oh, Libby, I want
to show you this view.
- Yeah.
- LIBBY: Yeah.
- It's gorgeous.
- Okay.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(ALARM SOUNDING)
Is that the fire alarm?
Really?
Okay, everybody, I guess we'd
better take this party downstairs.
The phones.
Where is the remote
for this thing?
These things are useless
without the remote. Anna!
Do you have
everything you need?
Can you just look
around for valuables?
For laptops,
cameras, whatever.
I think the cameras... Okay,
here's the video camera.
I still haven't put the
proposal up on Facebook,
so let me get that.
Oh, sweetie,
can you get the...
Anna?
We have one minestrone soup, two quiche,
one pie beef, one pie chicken,
one green salad. Go, go, go.
(WHISTLES)
- Dekko?
- Uh-huh!
A customer said
the chicken's dry.
The what's what?
The chicken.
It's dry.
It's a pie.
It's delicious.
Alex, you're in charge.
Don't blow anything up.
All right, which one of you
bollockses thinks my chicken's dry?
You?
ANNA: Me.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Could you maybe be nice
for just a second?
I did fly 3,000 miles to get here.
Is Jeremy with you?
What? No! No.
Jeremy and I...
It didn't work out.
Sorry.
Well,
when my 60 seconds
came around, I realized
I had everything
I ever wanted
but nothing
I really needed.
And I think that
what I need is here.
And I came all this way to see
if maybe you might think so, too.
And if you do...
Well, I don't really have any plans
past that, which is new for me.
So,
Declan O'Callaghan,
and I should probably
learn your middle name,
here is my proposal.
I propose
we not make plans.
I propose we give
this thing a chance
and let it work out
how it works out.
So what do you say?
Do you want to
not make plans with me?
(DOOR CLOSES)
I guess
that's an Irish no.
DECLAN:
Mrs. O'Bradycallaghan.
Where the hell
are you going?
You said no.
I didn't say no.
I didn't say anything.
You walked away.
I was getting something.
Really? That was a good
time to go get something?
Well, yeah,
it was, actually.
I was getting this.
You big idiot.
I wouldn't be holding this
ring if it weren't for you.
I reject your proposal.
I don't want to
not make plans with you.
I want to make
plans with you.
You do?
Yeah. I do.
Will you marry me?
In all my life, I never thought
I'd see you down on one knee.
Yeah, it's getting
a bit damp down here, so...
What's it to be,
Anna from Boston?
Yes.
Yes, I will.
I'm so relieved.
For a minute there,
I thought I wasn't gonna
have a place to stay tonight.
What?
You think you're staying with me?
This might cost you.
Put it on my bill.
Would you
look at that!
On a Sunday, no less. It's good
luck to get engaged on a Sunday.
And end a journey.
Aye, and dig a well.
Idiot! Do they look like
they're digging a well?
JOE: You know what
I'm talking about.
SEAMUS: I never know
what you're talking about.
(CAR ENGINE FALTERING)
Are you sure
she's gonna make it?
Remember,
she's a classic.
And she's good as new,
even after some crazy woman
tried to push her off the road.
I didn't try to
push her off the road!
I was scraping
cow poo off my shoe
'cause some rude man wouldn't
help me with the cows.
Only because someone was being
pigheaded and couldn't wait.
Shut up.
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
There you are.
Right.
Where to?
Just drive.
You got it, Bob.
ANNA: Wait a minute.
Where's Louis?
DECLAN: Louis? He's fine.
Strapped him to the roof.
You strapped him to the roof?
He'll get filthy up there.
Don't worry.
We'll throw him in the
wash. He'll be grand.
(POP SONG PLAYING)