[Scooby chomps and giggles]
[Rock version of Scooby Doo theme song]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Ghost cackles]
DAPHNE: Shaggy!
DAPHNE: Now I really have a wedgie.
Fred! Velma!
Can you guys hurry it up?
This ghost keeps grabbing...
[Daphne screams]
DAPHNE: Please!
Jinkies!
Fred.
VELMA: Come in, Fred.
VELMA: Fred. Can you hear me?
FRED: Fredster here, Velms.
VELMA: Shockingly, Daphne's
been captured again. That's okay.
When the Luna Ghost
rounds the corner with Daphne...
... Shaggy and Scooby
will pop out of the barrel...
And you'll activate the conveyor belt,
spilling the vat of oil onto the floor.
VELMA: Just remember my plan.
SHAGGY: Like, chill out, Scooby Doo.
Stop shaking.
SCOOBY: Hey! That's you.
SHAGGY: Right. It's me. Sorry!
Boo!
[Scooby screams]
[Whispers] Scooby Doo.
What are you doing, man?
SHAGGY: Like, this is no time...
Oh, boy. Like, there's a ghost
right behind me, isn't there?
[Scooby grunts assent]
Run!
SCOOBY: Run! Go!
SHAGGY: I'm trying, buddy!
[Scooby screams]
[Yells] Fred, now!
FRED: I got him.
SCOOBY: Look out!
FRED: Sorry, Velma.
VELMA: I know, Fred.
SHAGGY: Where's the ghost?
He's right behind us! Skateboard!
[Shaggy yells]
[Ghost cackles]
Is he still after us, Scoob?
Banzai!
Zoinks!
SHAGGY: Grab the hook!
SCOOBY: Hold on, Shaggy!
VELMA: Daphne? Are you okay?
I'm so over this
''damsel in distress'' nonsense.
Where's Shagster?
- Like, I'm right here, man.
- Me, too.
Scoob, that was fun. Let's grab another
skateboard and, like, do it again.
[Scooby giggles]
[Fred gasps]
[Tires screech]
[Rock 'n' roll music]
[Fans scream]
FRED: There you go.
And one for you.
Good-looking guy.
FRED: All right, nice to see you.
Thank you so much for saving the factory.
REPORTER: Any comments?
FRED: It's my job.
This is a victory
for any celebrity who wants...
...to make a quality,
ecologically-friendly action figure.
Fred, what's the secret of your success?
Teamwork.
I do a tremendous amount of teamwork...
...and I always have a plan. Come on.
Yeah, my plan.
FRED: I knew there never was a phantom.
The Luna Ghost is, in fact...
ALL: Old Man Smithers?
The creepy janitor?
He wanted revenge
after you refused to go out with him.
How could you, Pamela?
I am a lover boy
of George Clooneyan proportions.
REPORTER: Fred,
how was the ghost able to fly?
VELMA: I can answer that.
VELMA: Watch.
These balloons fill with a highly potent
helium synthesis...
...giving the Luna Ghost...
...his weightless appearance.
I would have gotten away with it too,
if it weren't for you meddling kids...
...and your dumb dog!
I'll get you for this!
[Howls] Scooby Dooby Doo!
[lndistinct chatter]
VELMA: I can't believe you took credit
for my plan again.
DAPHNE: Some plan.
That ghost pawed me for an hour and a half.
FRED: Daph, it's not our fault
you always get kidnapped.
I do not always get kidnapped.
I can't believe you'd say that to me.
Please.
You come with your own ransom note.
- My glasses!
- Who's helpless now?
I'm going to kill you, Daphne!
[Fred yelps]
Watch the ascot!
SHAGGY: You guys, look.
I know I'm just the dude
that carries the bags...
...but it seems to me we all play
an important part in this group.
I mean, we're just like a big,
delicious banana split.
Fred, you're the big banana.
Daph, you're the pastrami and bubble gum
flavored ice cream, and Velma...
...you're the sweet and sour mustard sauce
that goes on top.
That sounds pretty good, doesn't it?
You know what, Shaggy?
You've really put it into perspective for me.
Thanks.
I quit.
No.
No way.
You can't quit.
I was going to quit in, like, two seconds.
Now everyone is going to totally think
I copied off the smart girl.
Now, wait a minute!
Maybe I quit.
I do.
Yeah, I quit!
I'm outta here.
Good riddance.
Don't... No! Don't go!
SHAGGY: Come on, you guys, don't do this!
Please, don't go.
Do I quit?
No, Scoob...
...friends don't quit.
SHAGGY: Well, it looks like it's just you
and me for a while, buddy, old pal.
SCOOBY: What now, Shaggy?
SHAGGY: I guess we'll all just do
what we do best, Scoob.
[Lively reggae music]
SHAGGY: This is primo.
Oh, man.
Talk about toasted.
The only thing I like better
than an eggplant burger...
...is a chocolate-covered eggplant burger.
With hot sauce.
Yeah. Just another beautiful day
in paradise.
ISLAND EMISSARY: I'm looking for a
Mr. Rogers and a Mr. Doo, the detectives?
Like, it's probably somebody else looking
for us to solve some terrifying mystery.
Nobody home.
Quick, Scoob-o.
Grab the food-o, let's scram-o.
ISLAND EMISSARY: I'm looking for a Mr.
Rogers and Mr. Doo.
SHAGGY: Let's go.
I'm sorry, dude.
Look, I'd love to help you out.
You look like a really nice guy.
It's just we're not detectives anymore.
I've been sent by my employer,
Mr. Emile Mondavarious, to invite you...
...to his world-famous amusement park,
Spooky Island.
We don't go near any place with spooky,
haunted, forbidden, or creepy in the name.
Or hydrocolonic.
Right, or hydrocolonic,
but that's for a whole different reason.
Mr. Mondavarious would like you
to solve a mystery.
He'll pay you a fee of $10,000.
It's just,
materialism's not really our bag, man.
- He can provide free airfare.
- No, thanks.
- Room and board.
And all you can eat.
SCOOBY: ''All you can eat? ''
- Fred?
- Velma?
Are you going this way?
How have you...
Been?
Yeah.
Great! Great. I'm on the lecture circuit
with my new book.
''Fred on Fred: The Many Faces of Me. ''
Jinkies, that's impressive.
And yourself?
I've been working at NASA, developing
hydro-powered missile defense systems.
But, more importantly,
I'm on a journey of self-discovery.
NASA, huh?
ANNOUNCER: Charter service to Spooky
Island will begin boarding momentarily.
DAPHNE: What do you mean,
I can't have seven carry-on bags?
DAPHNE: That is so economy.
VELMA: Crap.
Oh, no.
I'm not talking to you guys.
What are you doing here?
VELMA: Isn't it obvious?
We all received the same letter
from one Emile Mondavarious...
...the reclusive owner of Spooky Island.
Unfair! I was going to solve the mystery
all by myself, for the first time ever.
How are you going to save yourself
when you get caught?
DAPHNE: I'm a black belt.
I've transformed my body
into a dangerous weapon.
It's true.
Far out. I guess we're, like, all going
to Spooky Island, man.
Hey, where's Scooby?
[Funky rap music]
[Whistles and catcalls]
Hello.
They don't allow big dogs on the plane.
You've got to be kidding.
No one is stupid enough to believe that.
Who's the ugly old broad?
Say hello to Grandma.
ANNOUNCER:
Flight 3774 to Spooky Island, now boarding.
Listen, I wouldn't have agreed to come
if I knew...
Wait, just think about it for one minute.
Mystery Inc reunites.
We'll be a team again.
Just like the old days.
So, come on, gang.
Let's do that thing where we put
our hands in, lift them up, and we go...
[Shaggy cheers]
Only if Fred and Velma do it.
People are watching, Shag.
[Soft piano music plays]
[Scooby cheers]
Yeah, Scoob! Whoo-hoo!
Come on, buddy.
[Loud rock 'n' roll music]
Now, that is a beautiful work of art, Scoob.
[Soft dreamlike music]
Would you mind me
taking a seat there next to...
To my Grandma? That's my grandma.
Hi, Grandma. Like, no.
- Let me just...
- Thanks.
You're welcome.
Bless you.
I'm sorry. My allergies are...
Well, it's usually only dogs that do it.
Maybe I'd better move.
No. Wait.
It's probably just my grandma's perfume.
Yeah, even I sometimes get a little allergic,
you know. Jeez. Look.
I'm pretty sure Grandma wants to go back
and visit with her old pal, Velma.
Right, Grandma?
Okay.
Boy, oh, boy, those sure do look
like Scooby Snacks.
I know they're for dogs...
...but they're 100 percent vegetarian
and I love them.
Me, too!
Far out. I have never met another person
who loves Scooby Snacks.
Me neither.
I'm Mary Jane.
SHAGGY: That is my favorite name.
MARY JANE: Really?
- Yeah.
- No way.
Hello.
[Scooby barks loudly]
Grandma?
Velma, it's simple behavior modification.
To cause a dog to discontinue any action,
simply flick it on the nose. Observe.
See?
SHAGGY: Sit, Grandma! Bad Grandma!
Don't eat the kitty!
[Tribal instrumental music]
EMILE: Welcome to Spooky Island...
... the frightfully popular spring break spot
for college students!
Catch our Electrical Torture Parade...
... lt's a Dead World After All...
... and the world-famous Splatter Horn.
Scooby Doo and the rest of Mystery Inc!
It's marvelous to see you.
I'm so sorry.
Thank goodness.
Sorry. It's a new toy.
I'm just sort of getting up to speed with it.
EMILE: Welcome.
DAPHNE: Thank goodness.
I was afraid
I'd have to lug those up to the hotel.
But that's what Spooky Island's all about,
realizing your worst fears.
EMILE: I'm Emile Mondavarious...
...the owner of this amusement park.
VELMA: You seem less...
- Spooky!
- Then we'd have guessed.
I can be pretty spooky when called upon.
EMILE: Oh, I can go...
[Emile snarls]
And claws and everything.
You wouldn't want to run into me
in a dark alley.
So you're the one who brought us here?
No.
No, what brought you here was
your insatiable appetite for a juicy mystery.
The truth is, Mr. Mondavarious,
Mystery Inc is broken up.
That's the beauty of something broken.
It can be fixed, and therein lies its potential.
And I need you to fix Spooky Island.
VELMA: What's the problem?
EMILE: I believe somebody
is casting a spell on the students.
EMILE: Now listen and look around.
Can you notice any difference between
those arriving and those departing?
DAPHNE: They look like sober,
well-behaved college kids.
EMILE: Precisely. And they didn't
before they came.
They've changed.
In other words, a magic spell.
BRAD: Carol! How was the Island?
Are you tricking on me?
It's me, Brad. We've known each other
since we were, like, three.
CAROL: Back off my grille!
BRAD: What are you doing?
I'm terrified.
The young people
that come off that barge...
...the people I love the most,
they're in danger.
I will solve this one first.
FRED: Not before I solve it first.
EMILE: Well done.
You guys are going to look like total idiots
when you're captured and I save you.
Thank you. Marvelous.
EMILE: Maybe we can celebrate later
by having a little Spookapalooza.
Spookapalooza?
[Ominous tribal drums]
So, you haven't noticed anything unusual
since you've started working here?
Any weirdoes running around?
SKELETON: No.
[Ominous tribal chanting]
N'GOO: Welcome, dear victims!
My name is N'Goo Tauna...
...and this is my evil best pal, Zarkos.
You may recognize him from Telemundo
as the famous, masked wrestler...
... Zarkos.
This enchanted island...
... is a thoroughfare
to the supernatural realm.
For centuries it was home to creatures...
... who lived on the island, undisturbed.
But then...
...10 years ago...
... Emile Mondavarious...
... antagonized these ancient beings
by building a theme park here.
The creatures are furious, my friends...
...and I assure you...
...while you party...
...they plot their...
...revenge!
N'GOO: Do my friends frighten you?
They would
if it weren't for the holographic projectors...
...there, and there, and there.
What a smart little one.
[Spooky rap music]
Hello. Dead Mike's.
BARTENDER: We got a Mr. Doo here?
I got a call for a Mr. Doo.
Melvin Doo?
No, Scooby.
Hello.
MAN: Got a bag of hamburgers here...
... for you.
Just walk into the dark,
shadowy part of the forest...
... where no one can see you.
Okay.
SHAGGY: Want a stuffed thingy?
MARY JANE: Nobody can win at those.
SHAGGY: Fred says it's a worthless talent.
That I should've learned French instead.
But, I say you don't need to know what
''Voulez-vous coucher avec moi'' means...
SHAGGY: to love that song.
I think being good at crane machine
is way cooler than French.
Voilà.
Nobody's ever given me a stuffed,
dismembered head before.
[Shouting and chanting]
[Chanting and grunting]
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
Now I have to start my voodoo ritual
all over again!
- Voodoo ritual?
- Yes. I was about to sacrifice this chicken.
DAPHNE: But that chicken's not alive.
VOODOO MAN: I know that, smart girl.
You figured it out
when you saw it didn't have a head?
What do you want?
Why are you all up
in my voodoo ritual space?
I'm looking for clues as to who's behind
the strange behavior of the students.
Well, here's a clue. Purple is a fall color.
It's the middle of May!
Pardon?
Do yourself a favor and get off this island.
Go home.
Go home before evil befalls your little,
skinny, aerobicized booty.
VOODOO MAN: And whatever you do...
...do not, I repeat...
... do not go into that Spooky Island castle.
- You want me to go up to that castle.
- Didn't you just hear what I said?
But you're scary and you knew
I'd do the opposite of what you said.
So you told me not to go,
so I'd go up to that castle...
...where you've set a trap to capture me.
Unless...
...you knew I'd figure it out, so you told me
not to go up to the castle...
...so I'd think you wanted me to go,
so I wouldn't go, like you didn't want me to.
DAPHNE: I'll find out what you're hiding
in that castle. You watch.
What in the world?
Hamburgers...
... oh, where are you?
SCOOBY: Hamburgers.
Thank you.
[Ghoul murmurs]
[Ghoul shrieks]
Shaggy, help me!
This has been really nice.
SCOOBY: [Yells] Help!
Monster!
A monster?
Scooby Doo!
Like, quit goofing around, man.
MARY JANE: I guess I should go.
'Bye, Scooby.
Bless you.
Shaggy, Scooby.
[Mysterious howling]
No way.
Shaggy.
SHAGGY: Scoob and me don't do castles.
DAPHNE: Why not?
Paintings with eyes watching you,
suits of armor you think is a statue...
...but there's a guy inside who follows you
every time you turn around.
DAPHNE: How many times has it happened?
SHAGGY: Twelve.
SHAGGY: We're not gonna do it.
SCOOBY: That's right.
Scooby?
DAPHNE: Did you hurt your paw?
- Would you do it for a Scooby Snack?
- Oh, boy!
You'll be fearless?
Fearless?
Hong Kong Fuey,
watch the fists of fury, would you, buddy!
Here you go.
Thank you.
There's plenty more where that came from.
Let's go before someone sees.
SCOOBY: Okay.
You are not going to stay out here alone,
are you?
No, thank you.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
SHAGGY: This place is like, über creepy.
SCOOBY: Yeah, über creepy.
DAPHNE: The only thing missing
is a mindless zombie.
[Door bursts open]
DAPHNE: Fred, get back.
I found this place. I call dibs on its clues.
I've already found some clues.
What?
I followed some weird footprints
up here and it might be dangerous for you.
If anyone messes with me...
...l'll just open a can of 2000-year-old
Chinese whup-ass on them.
Velma!
What are you doing here?
VELMA: This ride was closed
due to dangerous construction.
The most likely place
to hatch an insidious plan...
...and I wanted to scare the patootie
out of Daphne.
Well, since we're all together,
let's split up and look for more clues.
- Daphne, you and I...
- Typical.
What?
Oh, nothing.
I was always picked last for the teams.
FRED: Okay.
Daphne, exit through the entrance.
Velma and I will enter here
through the exit there.
And Shaggy and Scooby...
...do whatever you guys do.
[Door creaking open]
[Distant cackling]
[Mystical instrumental music]
Look at this, Scoob.
SHAGGY: It's like a medieval Sizzler.
Pinch me, I'm in... It's an expression, Scoob.
Sorry.
[Daphne grunts]
FRED: Hey, Velma, I never meant to,
well, you know...
...pick you last.
Don't worry about it, Fred. I know you.
All you care about are swimsuit models.
No! Look, I'm a man of substance.
Dorky chicks like you turn me on, too.
That's a compliment.
Yes!
Oh, yeah! Oh, yeah! Uh-huh!
PHANTOM: And now for our dinner show!
[Evil cackling and laughing]
VELMA: Watch out!
SHAGGY: I got a bad feeling about this.
SCOOBY: Me, too.
PHANTOM: And now for the main course:
You!
Feast on this!
VELMA: Jinkies!
VELMA: They're moving toward us.
FRED: We're trapped!
VELMA: Try the bookcase.
What?
One of these
has got to open a secret passageway!
Velma, this is a ride!
VELMA: You got a better plan, Fred?
SCOOBY: What do we do?
Do what we do best, Scoob! Eat!
It's plastic!
What do you care?
You drink out of a toilet!
So do you!
DAPHNE: I'm not helpless. I'm not helpless.
I am helpless. I'm going to die!
We made it, Scoob! We're alive!
SHAGGY: That was weird.
Fred?
Freddy?
Are you all right?
VELMA: The last book.
I don't feel so good.
Reminds me of the time when we tried
to eat that guy in the hot dog costume.
FRED: Looks like some kind of school.
VELMA: In a spooky castle ride? Fishy.
[Eerie instrumental music]
INSTRUCTOR: Welcome to America.
I am using the language English.
SCOOBY: Shaggy, look.
SHAGGY: Let's check it out.
Oh, boy. Lights, camera, action!
Huh, Scoob?
INSTRUCTOR:
Now that you're a young adult...
... you'll need to learn societal do's...
... and don'ts.
Interaction between young people
is polite and casual.
Sorry, bro.
I will crush your bones into dust.
Let's see how the situation
should be handled.
Remember, today's young people
have a language all their own.
Sorry, bro.
No big whoop, dog.
Yo, did you catch that new vid on the box?
True dat.
I'm up to snizzuff on all popular trends.
Word.
It seems to be a brainwashing facility
of some type.
VELMA: Wherever there's
a brainwashing cult...
...there's always a power-hungry leader
behind it all. The Papa Smurf figure.
Mondavarious.
Then why would he have invited us here?
[Ominous music]
[Mysterious whispered chanting]
[Daphne screams]
[Triumphant music]
Jellybeans.
[Scooby burps]
I'll have whatever he's having.
Are you challenging me?
[Gunslinging duel music]
Maybe.
[Scooby burps challengingly]
Pull my finger. Too late!
SHAGGY: You're in trouble.
SCOOBY: Oh, boy!
[Shaggy farts powerfully]
I'm not stopping until your fur is singed off.
We're here to solve a mystery.
Yes, Scoob.
[Alarm sounds]
Let's get out of here.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
I found a neat and scary clue.
Us, too. We think this
is a brainwashing facility for an evil cult.
Well, maybe this is the sacred relic thingy
they worship.
SHAGGY: We're all gonna be relics
if we don't get out of here, man.
FRED: I got a plan.
ZARKOS: What's this smell?
HENCHMAN: Sir, they found
the Daemon Ritus.
ZARKOS: For your sake,
they better not have gone far.
It is time to summon the big muchachos.
SHAGGY: Oh, no!
[Shaggy farts loudly]
[Lively music]
Mystery Inc. You all seem rather cheery.
Good news, I hope?
- Mr. Mononucleosis.
- Yes?
We have hit a clue smorgasbord.
We have three suspects
as to who's behind this evil hoody.
N'Goo Tauna.
VELMA: He believes your theme park's
been built on enchanted ground.
DAPHNE: The Voodoo Man, who shrewdly
tricked me into going to the castle.
- And you.
- Me?
FRED: Gang, let's split up.
We'll meet back here in a half hour.
I'll interview employees,
see if they've noticed anything odd.
I'm gonna get to work translating
these inscriptions that Daphne found.
I'll go research cults on the Net.
I'm a suspect?
Don't take it personally.
It's mostly just because you creep me out.
Oh, I see.
Fine.
VELMA: Jinkies.
[Eerie instrumental music]
Hey. Your friends ditch you?
No, I always do the brain work.
What's this?
I believe it's called the Daemon Ritus.
BOY: Daemon Ritus? What's it for?
VELMA: I think this describes
a very old race of creatures.
These inscriptions are reminiscent
of ancient Pandamenous texts...
... so I can make some of it out.
It looks like instructions
to some sort of secret ritual.
VELMA: It is fascinating.
BARTENDER: On the house.
Nice sweater.
You really dig doing this, huh?
Like, clues and stuff.
Certainly. Really focusing
on a mystery reminds me of the old days.
VELMA: We were quite a crew back then.
That was the best time of my life.
Shaggy and Scooby. What goofballs!
Kind of like they are today.
And Daphne was so beautiful.
She was the coolest girl at Coolsville High.
Fred. He was so handsome.
And he really knew how to accessorize.
BOY: Sounds perfect.
VELMA: Yeah, but every family has one nut.
Scrappy-dappy-doo!
Ghosts don't stand a chance with me!
Let me at them! I'll rack them!
I'll sock them!
Scrappy, for the 1000th time,
there's no such thing as ghosts.
Sure there are.
And when I find them,
I'll give them a good dose of puppy power!
Oh, God. He's peeing on me!
VELMA: That little egomaniac
had flipped his lid.
Scrappy, I told you.
No urinating on Daphne!
- It was an accident.
- You were marking your territory!
You don't have the scrote for this job, pally.
Listen up, losers. The time has come that
you appoint me your unquestioned leader.
Either that or I'm outta here!
What's the idea? You can't do this to me!
People adore me!
I'm as cute as a Powerpuff Girl!
I'll get my own TV show!
Puppy power, huh?
VELMA: And he wasn't even a puppy.
He had a gland disorder.
[Laughing]
[Whistling]
[Screams] Yikes!
SHAGGY: [Screams] Help me! Help me!
Monsters!
Scooby, this is
the most embarrassing thing you've done...
...since you decided to clean your beans
at Don Knotts' Christmas party.
How many times do I have to tell you?
There are no such things as ghouls,
ghosts, goblins, or monsters.
Now listen up. There is absolutely...
...absolutely no such thing as...
[Yells] Monster!
Fred!
FRED: Scooby!
Save Daphne!
My glasses.
I can't find my glasses.
[Glass breaking]
VELMA: I can't find my glasses.
DEMON: Here we are.
Thank you.
Nice mask. Bad breath.
Jinkies.
Velma!
BOY: Velma!
This is, like, the opposite
of what I wanted to do today.
[Chaotic instrumental music]
[Beasts roaring]
Stand back, sir! I'll protect you.
Mr. Mondavarious!
SHAGGY: Daphne, go!
[Yells] Scooby Doo, where are you?
[Loud funky music]
SCOOBY:
Grammy's suitcase. Grammy's suitcase.
Thank you.
DAPHNE: Where's Scooby?
SHAGGY: I don't know. I hope he's okay.
Right here. Scooby Dooby Doo!
[Yell] Scooby!
I have a sinking feeling these dudes
aren't brainwashed cult members.
Then what are they? And what do they
want with the college students?
We need to follow them.
Say what?
So we can defeat the creatures
and save Fred and Velma!
Well, that's sort of like my plan.
Which is: Get the heck out of here.
Let the creatures eat Fred and Velma!
No way! Fred and Velma
always figured out everything.
Now it's our turn, Shaggy.
For the first time,
they're the damsels in distress.
Not me.
DAPHNE: Help?
SHAGGY: Timber.
- Okay, I'm calling for help.
- No.
No, I got this. I got this.
I don't got this.
Coast Guard, Fitzgibbon.
Hello, sir. We're on Spooky Island.
Our friends were...
...kidnapped.
MARY JANE: We need someone here
right away!
Well, we do have a unit in the vicinity.
Can you meet them at the pier?
They'll be right there.
''Our friends have been kidnapped. ''
[Laughing evilly]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
DAPHNE: Something messed up
is happening.
Is the Coast Guard here?
SHAGGY: What happened to the shattered
windows and the busted walls?
Yo, Red. The ball.
DAPHNE: Let's go.
[Lively rock 'n' roll music]
SHAGGY: Does anyone else think
this is strange?
DAPHNE: Okay. We need to split up.
SHAGGY: Why?
We still need to find Fred and Velma.
- I'll go this way.
- And we'll go with you.
Come on, Scoob.
Fred?
Yo, yo! The bee-atch was like, ''What? ''
And I was like, ''Later on! ''
What up, dog?
And dog.
Keepin' it real.
What happened last night?
We got beats like it was the lizz nizz
on earth.
FRED: Know what I'm saying, G?
SHAGGY: No.
Do you hear that?
Get the dog!
ZARKOS: Damsel in distress.
DAPHNE: Let go of me!
Help!
SHAGGY: Hurry, get the door!
SCOOBY: Why is Fred in a bad mood?
SHAGGY: He is not in a bad mood, Scoob!
He is a monster!
Shaggy, bikes!
SHAGGY: I know, yikes!
SCOOBY: No, bikes!
[Revving bike engines]
[Cheering and whooping]
SCOOBY: Look out!
[Gasps] I saw my friend.
There's something wrong with her eyes.
Hop on!
SHAGGY: What a drag!
SHAGGY: Duck!
[Ominous music]
[Dramatic tribal beat]
[Tires screeching]
MARY JANE: That was great!
SHAGGY: Man, oh man, are you all right?
SHAGGY: You were great.
MARY JANE: You, too.
[Barking]
What are you doing, man?
Mary Jane is a man in a mask!
- ''Mary Jane is a man in a mask? ''
- Scooby!
SHAGGY: Dude, what are you doing, man?
Step off, Scoob.
Shaggy, you're whipped!
I'm whipped? Yeah?
Well, why don't you say that to my face?
Okay, I will. Your mommy eats cat poop!
No, Scooby Doo, your mom eats cat poop!
You want some?
You want a little piece of the Shagster?
Feel the pain, Scoob!
SHAGGY: Come on! Two shots!
Me and you, me and you again.
SHAGGY: I'll give you something.
[Shouts] Scoob!
Scooby's been eaten. I gotta save him.
You stay here. I'll be right back.
[Ghoul voice] No, Shaggy.
I mean, it's too dangerous.
I've got to. He's, like, my best pal.
Friends don't quit.
[Yelling]
[Whispers] Scoob?
SHAGGY: Scooby Doo.
Where are you?
Scoob!
[Eerie instrumental music]
VELMA: Shaggy! Shaggy!
VELMA: Shaggy!
Velma?
SHAGGY: I'll save you.
VELMA: Thanks, Shaggy.
Boy, am I glad to see you.
Let me go so I can return to my body,
and then get out of here...
...before they find you
and steal your protoplasm, too.
VELMA:
I always knew you were a hero, Shaggy.
VELMA: [Yells] Jinkies!
[Ghoul screaming]
[Screaming]
SHAGGY: Hey, buddy.
FRED: Shaggy. Listen, man.
Someone must have spiked my root beer
last night. Talk me down, man!
Talk me down!
Fred, you're a frigging protoplasmic head.
I know.
But I'm still the best-looking
protoplasmic head here.
FRED: How do you drive this thing?
FAKE FRED: The Darkopolypse is upon us.
Gather what you need for the ceremony.
FRED: On your right. The left.
FRED: I'm coming, good-looking!
Thank you so much! You've saved me!
Thank you!
Sorry, I'm looking for my friends.
Put me back, Shaggy.
I'll figure a way out myself.
- Like, how?
- I don't know.
I'll use my tongue as an oar
and swim to the edge.
Sorry.
[Eerie instrumental music]
VELMA: Yo, yo, you, yo.
You could use a little sunlight.
VELMA: That's one part
of the mystery solved.
The creatures must need our bodies
to survive in sunlight.
Like a human suit.
SPF 1,000,000.
But what are they doing here
in the first place?
Daphne, you okay?
FRED'S SOUL: Yeah.
FRED'S SOUL: But I'm not Daphne!
Fred?
FRED'S SOUL: I couldn't get to my body.
I didn't know where else to go. I panicked!
FRED'S SOUL: It's not easy to steer
when you're pure spirit.
FRED'S SOUL: I can look at myself naked.
Oh, brother.
DAPHNE'S SOUL: Get your hands off me.
VELMA: Daphne?
DAPHNE'S SOUL: He planned this
somehow. Didn't he?
FRED'S SOUL: Hey, good-looking.
DAPHNE'S SOUL: Fred! You egocentric...
SHAGGY: Tell me you guys are you.
DAPHNE'S SOUL: Fred keeps touching me.
VELMA: Kind of makes you nostalgic
for the homicidal creatures, doesn't it?
SHAGGY: I stole this. I hope it helps.
VELMA: The Daemon Ritus.
DAPHNE: I'm me again.
VELMA'S SOUL: Yippee for you.
SHAGGY'S SOUL: Man, like,
why am I wearing a dress?
FRED'S SOUL: Everyone remain calm.
Velma, what the heck's going on?
VELMA'S SOUL: If my calculations
are correct...
... due to the unstable nature of protoplasm
in proximity of the Daemon Ritus...
VELMA'S SOUL: we're simply going to
continue randomly changing bodies until...
VELMA'S SOUL: Until the protoplasm
realigns with the appropriate body.
DAPHNE'S SOUL: I'm Fred again!
SHAGGY'S SOUL: Daph, what's wrong
with you? Don't you ever eat?
FRED: I'm me!
DAPHNE: I'm back!
SHAGGY: Like, me too!
VELMA: Told you so!
DAPHNE: Oh, no!
VELMA: Let's go.
Something tells me
that was the wrong ingredient.
Wait!
I know how to handle this guy.
Hey, you!
What are you doing?
Yes. That is masterful.
I'm trying to do a voodoo ritual.
It's important to get the right ingredients.
The only way I can protect myself
is by blessing this dead Arnouki beast.
I'll tell you something.
I got a feeling they're about
to perform their evil Darkopolypse ritual.
VELMA: Darkopolypse ritual?
VOODOO MAN: That's right.
That's what the ancient text describes.
Hold it! Don't open it!
VELMA: They use the protoplasm in the vat
as an energy source.
And the leader needs to absorb
a purely good soul to complete the ritual.
Legend has it, once the Darkopolypse ritual
is performed...
...the creatures will rule all Earth
for 10,000 years.
So I'm bringing this Arnouki
beast up in my house to protect myself.
Do you have another one of those?
DAPHNE: Those creatures are taking
over the world? That is so mean!
Now, they can't do the ritual
without a pure human soul.
Where will they get one of those?
I didn't say human.
Oh, boy.
[Whimpering]
Hello, puppy.
So, if the person behind all this needs
Scooby Doo...
Then that person is the one
who brought Scooby here.
Scoobert!
How are you, my friend? Sit down. Please.
Okay.
EMILE: Scooby Snack?
Maybe one.
We'll need some more of those.
That's me!
It certainly is. And that's because, why?
We love you, Scooby Doo.
Unlike that alleged friend of yours, Shaggy.
He wouldn't believe you...
...about that nasty girl Mary Jane,
would he?
No.
But I believe you, my friend.
And that's why
I've got a very important job for you.
What's that?
That's a cat with a bobbing head.
Please don't touch it.
Scooby...
...I would like you...
...to be a sacrifice.
A sacrifice?
If Mondorajagaga wanted Scooby,
why'd he invite the rest of us?
It doesn't matter.
We gotta, like, go save Scoob.
Shag, our area of expertise
is nut jobs in Halloween costumes.
We're supposed to be heroes, man.
So I'm going to do what I always do.
I'm going to eat myself a Scooby Snack
and I'm going to save my best pal.
FRED: Velmster?
You think I'm going to fall for that?
Giving me my own nickname?
Trying to make me feel like...
...part of the gang?
We could make a plan.
What can I do? The only thing I'm good for
is getting caught.
But you never let that stop you before.
And if that's not a true hero,
then I don't know what is.
Let's get jinky with it.
[Funky rock 'n' roll music]
Okay, so, we use the pulleys
to tip over the vat.
VELMA: Daphne, open the air vents from
the outside and release the disco skull.
The light will refract off the skull...
The creatures will explode, I'll find Scoob
and we will have saved the world.
FRED: Oh, no. The ritual's beginning.
DAPHNE: Quick!
VELMA: Shaggy, attach this to the vat!
We're here to save you!
VELMA: Shaggy, faster!
All systems go!
Wait, no!
Mystery Inc rides again.
[Beating of drums]
VELMA: Quick! Hide the Daemon Ritus!
WOMAN:
Would you like another Scooby Snack?
Okay.
Scooby Doo!
[Chanting to tribal music]
[Whimpering]
[Fred mumbles]
Yo, yo, yo.
FRED: Yo, homedogs!
Y'all forgot the next part of the dance...
...where we do the electric slide,
where, you know...
It's electric.
[Fred cheers]
FRED: And back it on up and drive the bus...
...and stop.
And back it up.
And back it on up. Hurry up, Velma.
EMILE: Fred! Velma!
Welcome to my little
''End of the World'' party.
I've waited a long time for this moment.
Thank you for returning
the ultimate party favor...
...the Daemon Ritus.
EMILE: And now, behold the sacrifice.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hello, thank you.
Thank you. Shaggy?
Let's run for it.
We, like, gotta get out of here.
I'm a sacrifice, you know.
A sacrifice? That's not a good thing, Scoob.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
I'm really sorry I haven't been
a very good friend since we got here.
But listen to me, bro,
you gotta trust me now.
- You don't trust me!
- I do trust you, Scoob.
Now, look. Who's your best buddy?
SCOOBY: Shaggy.
SHAGGY: That's right.
- Who's my best buddy in the whole world?
- Scooby Doo?
SHAGGY: That's right.
You are. And we're, like, two trippy peas
in a far-out pod, man!
And best buddies, they trust each other.
So let's do what we do best.
Let's run out of here, screaming in fear
like a couple of lunatics, okay?
Okay.
On the count of... Let's make it five. One...
...two...
Scooby Doo!
SCOOBY'S SOUL: Hey, look at me!
EMILE: The moment is at hand.
Through the Daemon Ritus,
I shall absorb the energy source.
And now...
...to complete the transformation...
...I shall absorb the Pure One!
Scoob!
Ultimate power shall be mine!
Nobody absorbs my pal!
SCOOBY: Quick!
I'm free!
Look at me!
Come on, let's get the Daemon Ritus!
ZARKOS: Get off my swingset!
Cowabunga!
Look, Velms.
A man in a mask.
We love you, Scooby Doo. We love you...
That alleged friend of yours, Shaggy.
I shall absorb...
Puppy power! I've outsmarted...
VELMA: Scrappy Doo.
SCRAPPY: Correction.
The new, improved Scrappy.
Because I, Scrappy Dappy Doo,
have absorbed enough energy to...
To rule the world
with my all-powerful army!
And I've brought you here, puny,
pathetic Mystery Inc...
...to witness my moment of triumph.
All I need to complete
my transformation is Scooby Doo.
Don't you mean Melvin Doo?
Seize them!
Like, let's get out of here!
SCRAPPY: Take that, pretty boy!
SHAGGY: This is totally ungroovy, Scoob!
Scooby Doo, where are you?
Señorita.
[Loud rock music]
SCRAPPY: Yield to my puppy power!
VELMA: We have to tip over
the protoplasm vat.
FRED: How?
VELMA: The pincer! Come on!
[Rock version of Scooby Doo theme song]
You all need to step back,
because Fredster's got his groove on.
[Daphne grunts]
[Zarkos whines]
Gotcha! You look so much bigger on TV!
SCRAPPY: Come back here,
you lazy beatnik!
Oh, crud!
Told you so!
Like, wow!
Give me the dog!
SCOOBY: Scrappy!
Down! Sit! Bad Scrappy!
Let's finish this puppy! Now!
Oh, no! Not again!
Captured again, señorita?
Not this time!
Now who's the damsel in distress?
- Me?
- Straight up.
SCRAPPY: Mystery Inc, this ain't over!
Not by a long shot!
I'll rock you and sock you...
...and crush you like...
Like, dude.
SCRAPPY: What?
SHAGGY: You're a bad puppy!
I can still take you!
Put them up, you mangy mutt!
Is that all you got?
[Cheering]
FRED: Hey, Daph!
- We did it!
- Yes, we did.
Oh, Fred!
Cut it out!
Mr. Mondavarious, is that you?
Yes.
Thank goodness!
Thank you! Thank you!
BOY: Thank you!
You're fogging up my glasses.
Two years ago, that little pest...
...turns up at a casting session
for our evil elves.
Next, I'm stuck in a hole...
...and he's cavorting about
in a mechanical version of me.
But look, thank you so much!
What a delight! Fantastic!
Fantastic!
Shaggy!
Scooby Doo!
[Laughing]
- I love you, Shaggy.
- I love you, too, Scoob.
Now, get off me, buddy.
Thanks.
You saved my life.
No problem.
And thank you, Scooby Doo.
MARY JANE: My little
schmookem wookem.
Shucks!
[Screaming and cheering]
Fred, can you tell us
how you solved the case?
FRED: Yes.
It all started when I was giving
a speech on my new book and...
I really think the Velmster
should take it from here.
[Whispers] Go.
Through the combined intuitive powers
of Mystery Inc...
... we've discovered
the real villain behind this mystery...
...is, in fact, Scrappy Cornelius Doo...
... who, sadly, was corrupted
by the power of the Daemon Ritus.
SCRAPPY: Get over it!
So, I got a little cranky!
Scrap, it's no reason to freak out like
a jerk and try to kill all of humanity.
I would've gotten away with it, too,
if not for you meddling sons of...
Now that Mystery Inc is back together...
...do you have any comment on the
Mud Bog Ghoul terrorizing London?
Whatever the case...
...Mystery Inc will be there.
- Solving mysteries, man.
DAPHNE: Righting wrongs.
VELMA: Looking for clues and kicking butt.
[Rap music plays]
SHAGGY: How groovy is this, man?
Spooky Island finally came through
with its all-you-can-eat deal.
And there's nobody I'd rather
gorge myself with than you, Scooby Doo.
My best friend.
You're my best friend, buddy.
You're beautiful
like a beautiful piece of pizza!
Zoinks!
Them peppers is, like, hot!
- Wimp!
- Wimp? You think you can handle it?
Why don't you put your mouth
where your mouth is!
Okay!
[Panting]
SHAGGY: Scooby Doo.
Are you feeling okay?
[Yells] Oh no!
Here you go, Scoob!
- How did that taste, man?
- Delicious!
Well, garçon, let's get two more!
On the count of three.
One!
Two!
Three!
[Screaming]
[Rap music]
Subtitles : Filou ;-)