(BLOWING)
GIRL: With every sun comes a new day.
A new beginning.
A hope that things will be better
today than they were yesterday.
But not for me.
My name is Eep.
And this is my family,
the Croods.
If you weren't clued in
already by the animal skins
and sloping foreheads,
we're cavemen.
(ANIMAL GROWLS)
(GASPS)
Most days we spend
in our cave, in the dark.
Night after night,
day after day.
Yep, home sweet home.
When we did go out, we
struggled to find food
in a harsh and hostile world.
(GROWLING)
(HISSING)
And I struggled
to survive my family.
(ALL SCREAMING)
We were the last ones around.
There used to be neighbors.
Uh, the Gorts,
smashed by a mammoth.
(ALL GASP)
The Horks,
swallowed by a sand snake.
The Erfs, mosquito bite.
Throgs, common cold.
(SNEEZES)
And the Croods, that's us.
(GROWLS)
The Croods made it, because of my dad.
(GRUNTS)
He was strong,
and he followed the rules.
The ones painted
on the cave walls.
(GASPS) Anything new is
bad, curiosity is bad.
Going out at night is bad.
Basically, anything fun is bad.
Welcome to my world.
But this is a story about how
all that changed in an instant.
Because what we didn't know
was that our world...
was about to come to an end.
And there were no rules on our
cave walls to prepare us for that.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(YELLING)
(YELLING CONTINUES)
(BONES CRACKS)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(ROARS)
(WHIMPERS)
GRUG: You are supposed to
wait for my signal. Eep?
Boo.
(ALL YELPING)
Ah!
Ow! No!
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
Oh, we've been in
that cave forever.
GRUG: Three days
is not forever.
It is with this family.
Eep, would you come down here?
You're being so dramatic.
(GROWLS)
GRUG: No, Sandy, come back here.
(PANTING)
Remember the signal. Good girls
wait for the signal. Ugga.
As soon as I get Sandy, I'll go back
in, and you can give the signal.
No, I mean,
you're already out now.
THUNK: I'm waiting
for the signal, Dad.
Never mind, Thunk.
Just come out.
THUNK: But if you don't
give the signal,
how do I know you're my dad?
The signal isn't
so you know it's me.
It's so you know I wasn't
eaten by an animal.
THUNK: Then why is the signal
an animal noise?
Doesn't that
just confuse things?
(EXHALES) Oh! I don't know. I'm
still waiting for the signal.
Hoo-hoo! Hoo-hoo!
(YELLING)
(BABBLING)
(CONTINUES YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
UGGA: Mom,
we're ready to leave.
Mom?
(GASPS)
Still alive.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES) It's still early.
And you're still fat.
(GROANS)
Breakfast formation!
(GASPS)
I want to see some real
caveman action out there.
We do this fast.
We do this loud.
We do this as a family.
And never not be afraid!
(ALL YELLING)
Yay, breakfast.
(ALL PANTING)
(WARBLES)
(SQUAWKS)
(SHRIEKS)
(ALL WHIMPERING)
Who's up?
We'll flip for it.
Call her in the air.
(SCREAMS) Heads!
Tails. Thunk is in.
(GROANS)
Positions.
(GRUNTS)
Okay. Thunk...
Go.
(GASPS) Come on, Thunk.
(CHUCKLES)
Ha! Way to go.
Take it to the cave.
(SCREAMS)
Ohh!
Release the baby!
(GROWLING)
Get them, Sandy! Go!
(YELLS)
Ow!
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH CHITTERING)
(YELLS)
Get them, Mom!
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(SNIGGERS)
Old lady down!
Eep, avenge me!
(PANTING)
(YELPS)
Thanks.
(GROANS)
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTS)
GRUG: Eep!
Heads up!
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CHUCKLES)
(ROARS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Oh, hey Dad, can we eat now?
Just wait till we get home.
Eep, put on the brakes.
(BOTH GRUNT)
(YELPS)
Eep!
ALL: Whoa!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
Who is hungry?
ALL: Yay!
All right!
Good one, Dad.
Here you go, Thunk.
Drink up. Oh!
Sorry, Dad.
Looks like fast food tonight.
(SQUEALS)
EEP: Mmm!
Mmm!
(EXHALES)
(GRUG SWALLOWS)
That's all right.
I ate last week.
Two knuckle warning!
Come on, Croods.
Go, go.
(DISTANT ANIMAL CALLS)
Come on, come on. Darkness brings death.
We know this.
The moon is full.
Bath night.
Run for your life!
You too, Mom.
(GRUNTS)
I don't want to lose
my protective layer.
Mom, you've got ants.
(BABBLING)
See?
Sandy doesn't fuss.
(GRUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
Is she still out there?
You know she hates
the cave, Grug.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Please come back tomorrow.
How could she not like the cave?
It's so cozy.
It is a little dark, Grug.
It's not that dark.
Eep!
Eep?
(GROANS)
(ANIMAL CALLING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
Come on, I have to close the cave.
(THUD)
(GASPS)
Eep!
Okay, okay.
Come on.
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
Eep! Come down!
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLS)
(EXHALES)
That was too close.
I was watching.
I was fine.
What were you doing up there, Eep?
I don't know.
What were you looking for?
Nothing.
Then why did you go up there?
I don't know.
Why don't you know?
(GROANS)
Stop looking for things.
Fear keeps us alive, Eep.
Never not be afraid.
What is the point of all this?
Hmm? What was that?
Why are we here? What
are we doing this for?
(ALL GROANING)
No one said survival was fun.
Nothing is fun.
Huh? Would you come down here?
Grug.
Eep.
Yes.
Off!
Yes, I know. (CHUCKLES)
Okay, I'm trying to... Off.
I just don't see why she needs
her own ledge, that's all.
That's what this is about. She's
working through some things...
and she needs her own space.
What things? How long
is this going to take?
(CHUCKLES) Really? She already
doesn't listen to me.
(THUD) Hey!
See? She's listening.
Ugh.
If she wants to survive,
she has to follow our rules.
How about a story?
Eep loves those.
That's a good ide...
How about a story, huh?
Oh, yeah, tell us a story.
Okay. Can I borrow that?
Thank you.
Eep, your old favorite. (SIGHS)
I haven't played with
that thing in years.
Tonight we'll hear
the story of Krispy Bear.
(CLEARS THROAT)
A long time ago, this
little bear was alive.
She was alive because she
listened to her father...
and lived her life in routine
and darkness and terror.
So she was happy (SIGHS)
But Krispy had
one terrible problem.
She was filled with... curiosity.
(ALL GASP)
Grug.
Yes. yes.
And one day,
while she was in a tree...
the curious little bear
wanted to climb to the top.
(ALL GASPING) And no sooner
than she climbed to the top...
she saw something new and died!
THUNK: Just like that?
Yes!
Her last moments of terror
still frozen on her face.
GRAN: Same ending
as every day. (CHUCKLES)
THUNK: I get it, Dad. I will never
do anything new or different.
GRUG: Good man, Thunk.
All right, everyone sharpen
your teeth, and let's pile up.
(GROWLING)
(COOING)
(ALL SNORING)
(SIGHS)
(DISTANT ANIMAL CALLS)
(SNARLING)
(LOUD ANIMAL CALLS)
(GASPS)
(SNIFFING)
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHS)
(SHUDDERS)
(THUD)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(TWIG SNAPS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(THUD)
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
(SNIFFS)
Huh?
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(SHUSHES)
Ow!
(GASPING)
(RASPING) Air.
You talk.
I'm a person, like you.
(GRUNTS)
Sort of like you.
Hmm. (SNIFFING)
Okay, okay.
Hey, hey, hey!
Would you mind not...
(YELPING)
(GIGGLING) That tickles.
Hey, hey, hey!
(CHITTERS)
Ah!
Ow!
(GROANS) Wow!
(WHISPERS) Quiet!
I'm not supposed
to be out here.
Ow!
Oh!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Eep is gone.
What? Grug!
Stay in the cave.
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
Wow.
You are really strong.
Hey! No! It's mine.
Please! Wait.
No!
It's dying! I can fix it!
No! I caught it!
Please! Please.
I hate the dark.
(GASPS)
(BLOWING)
Come on, come on, come on.
It does what you tell it?
Yeah. Sort of.
The sun?
No, no, no. Fire.
Hi, fire.
(CHUCKLES)
It's not alive.
But you said it was dying.
Sorry.
Uh... it comes from
where you come from?
No. No, I make it.
Make some for me.
Ow! Okay.
Make!
It doesn't come out of me.
Make! Make it!
(CHOKING)
(BONES CRACKING)
(RASPING) You do this a lot.
Are you dead?
Can I have your fire
if you're dead?
(CHITTERING)
Clear!
Hey, those are cold!
(CHITTERING)
You think? Listening
shells, activate.
I concur.
Tiger girl, we need
to leave immediately.
I don't even know you.
Mmm.
I'm Guy.
Guy?
And this is Belt. Cook,
conversationalist, navigator.
(CHITTERING)
Also, keeps my pants up.
What are "pants up"?
Who are you?
Oh... Eep.
Let me clarify, Eep.
The world is ending.
What?
I'm calling it "The End."
Dun-dun-dun!
How do you know?
I have seen it.
It's coming this way.
First, the ground
is going to shake.
Then it breaks open.
Everything falls in.
Fire. Lava.
I don't mean to
sound too dramatic, but...
(SCREAMING)
Believe me, everything we are
standing on will be gone.
We got to get to high ground.
I know a mountain, that way.
It's our only chance.
Come with me.
(CHITTERING)
I can't.
Okay.
Here.
(PLAYS LOW NOTE)
If you survive, uh, call me.
(GASPS)
(PLAYS LOW NOTE)
(LAUGHING)
Thank you.
Hello?
Hey!
(GASPS) Dad!
Are you hurt?
What took you?
Nothing.
I left on my own.
You what?
Dad, let me explain.
(ANIMAL ROARS)
(SNIFFING)
(WHISPERS) You
never let me talk.
You're grounded.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS) Hey!
(GASPS) Eep!
Mom.
Grug!
What happened?
You know what, I am so mad right
now that I can't talk to her.
(SNIFFS) Eep?
You will never believe it.
I found something new.
BOTH: New!
New is a big problem!
EEP: Wait, wait!
(GROWLS)
Eep. Stay inside
the family kill circle.
It wasn't bad.
"New" is always bad.
No. He was nice.
What?
Excuse me? He?
I thought he was a Warthog, but
then he turned into a boy.
GRAN: Strange.
Usually it's the reverse.
Eep's got a boy hog.
Eep's got a boy...
(GROANS) There was a boy.
Watch.
I'm going to call him.
(ALL GASP)
(PLAYS LOW NOTE) Ah!
(ALL YELLING)
(SHELL SHATTERING)
(SIGHS)
What is wrong with you?
It was dangerous.
It was beautiful!
You want to see
dangerous? Here!
Ow!
My sniffer!
Okay, that's it!
We're going back to the cave...
and you're going to stay in there
until you're older than...
uh...
her!
What!
You can't keep me
inside forever!
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(RUMBLING)
He said this would happen.
(GASPS)
(GROUND CREAKING)
Get to the cave!
Go!
(ALL GRUNT)
Ah!
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
Look out!
Stop!
(ALL YELPING)
(ALL COUGHING)
Is everyone okay?
UGGA: Yes.
Grug, the cave...
it's gone.
No.
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
You really need to see this.
We should go there!
No. No one
is going anywhere.
(SNIFFING)
What else did that boy say?
(BIRD CAWING)
(ALL GASP)
(GROWLS)
Ah!
(GRUNTS)
Grug?
Just go! Just go!
Go!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL GROANING)
Ow!
(EXHALES)
(GRUNTS)
(GIGGLES)
One, two, three, four, five...
Oh!
Six. (SIGHS)
(GROANS) Where are we?
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
Down.
In a lower place.
But one thing is for sure, we
can't go back the way we came.
(GROWLS)
Sandy? What is it?
No, no, no.
Wait. Come back, Sandy!
(TRUMPETS)
Ah!
Ugh!
(TRUMPETING)
We can't be out in
the open like this.
(ALL TRUMPETING)
We need a cave.
Now, step where I step.
Okay. Stay quiet.
Hopefully, nothing big
knows we're here yet.
GRUG: Wait.
Okay.
Wait.
Wait!
ALL: Whoa!
Wait.
Okay.
(SQUAWKING)
GRUG: Wait.
TRUNK: Um, so, Dad...
just to be clear, are we looking
for the exact same cave?
If it was me... I'm just
throwing this out there...
if it was me
choosing the cave...
(ALL CHITTERING)
I would go with a smaller cave.
(GASPS)
Wait.
(ALL CHITTERING)
Dad?
I'll take care of this.
(YELLING)
Uh...
Hmm.
All right, Dad, get them!
Go get them!
Now you got them right...
Man, they're really...
(CHUCKLES) I'm loving this.
THUNK: Dad, I got it.
Just stop running
into their fists.
Grug, when you're done,
we should get going.
Whoa!
(LAUGHS)
That's right.
You can't get past this!
(GROWLING)
(ALL GASP)
(GRUNTS)
(ROARS)
Climb! Climb! Climb!
(ALL SCREAMING)
THUNK: Whoa!
(ALL GRUNTING)
Cave!
Go! Go!
Come on!
Hurry up. Let's go.
THUNK: Look! This cave
has a tongue. Awesome!
(BUBBLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
Ew! Ew!
(HEAVY FOOTSTEPS RETREATING)
Okay.
That's one, two,
three, four, five, six.
And seven...
if we're counting
Chunky the Death Cat.
(GROWLING)
(ALL GASP)
(WHIMPERS)
THUNK: Ha!
It's scared of the dark.
(LAUGHS)
Wait, we're scared of the dark.
(CHIRPS)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(ALL GASPING)
(ALL SCREAM)
(GASPS) Kill circle!
Eep!
(GRUNTS)
(PLAYS LOW NOTE)
(GASPS)
(CONTINUES PLAYING LOW NOTE)
Eep!
(GRUNTS)
(BLOWING)
(CHIRPING)
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
Ta-da!
(YELLING GIBBERISH)
(YELPING)
Whoa, whoa!
Cavies!
"Cavies"?
Cavemen! Stand back!
They're practically animals.
You see their bony,
sloping foreheads? Yeah.
The huge primitive teeth?
(GROWLS)
Yeah.
The excessive body hair.
Oh... That one
has got a tail.
Yeah.
All right. Close your eyes. I'm
going to have to take their lives.
No! It won't help.
They're my family.
What?
(GROWLING)
(YELPS) The sun
is in his hands!
No, no.
It's "fire."
Where did it come from?
He made it.
Make some for me!
It doesn't come out of him.
(GRUNTS)
Make. Make it!
(BONES CRACKING)
(RASPING) You're a lot
like your daughter.
Oh! Great,
now he's broken.
Ooh!
It's a baby sun.
Whoa! Hey, stay back.
We don't know what it wants.
Now, we'll all sit here and
wait for the sun to come back.
And tomorrow
we'll find a new cave...
and pretend
today never happened.
Isn't this fun, Eep?
Eep, don't touch him.
Goodness knows where he's been.
THUNK: Dad,
Sandy is hurting fire.
Sandy, no.
Fire is not a plaything.
Aw! What
a cute little guy.
Oh, hey.
Stay back.
(SCREAMS)
No, no, no, wait!
(COUGHING)
It likes me.
Hey!
It's biting me!
(SCREAMS)
(STAMMERS)
Thunk! Try hiding from it
in the tall, dry grass!
(YELPING)
No, stop.
Please, I'm only nine.
They're biting me!
(CHUCKLES)
(GASPS) Oh...
More fire babies.
(GASPS)
Hi.
So, your dad,
he is trying to kill me.
Yeah.
But I won't let him.
(GRUNTS)
(THUNK SCREAMING) GRUG: Hold on, son.
Come back!
No, Stop!
Let me go!
Get out!
Out! Out!
Eat up, babies!
Ooh...
GRAN: No, stop touching me!
Die!
(SIZZLES)
I win!
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
They're not so scary
once you get to know them.
Uh... Uh...
Who are you people?
Oh, I'm sorry.
We're the Croods!
And you are?
Uh, Guy.
ALL: Hi, Guy.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL GASP)
ALL: Wow!
It looks like magic.
(SNIFFING)
And smells like food.
ALL: Oh!
THUNK: Whoa...
GRUG: No,
don't eat it, it's new.
ALL: Still alive!
GUY: Come on,
keep eating.
(CHITTERING)
EEP: Hey, where is Guy?
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
(EEP GROWLING)
GUY: No!
Going somewhere?
The mountain? High ground?
End of the world, remember?
That already happened.
It destroyed our cave.
No. That was just
the beginning of the end.
The end of the end
is still coming.
Eep. Drop it.
(GRUNTING)
We can't let him go!
What if we don't find
a cave before sunset?
What if it takes a few days?
(GASPS) What if
the birds come back?
We need his fire, dummy!
Fine. You're staying with
us until we find a cave.
What? No, I'm not. Don't
make me a part of this!
Ooh! Stay here if you
want, but let me go.
I've got a dream...
a mission, a reason to live!
Not anymore.
Um, I've got an idea.
Let's go to that mountain.
It's too far.
Dad really has his
heart set on a cave.
(GROANS)
There are caves
on that mountain.
(GASPS) Have you been there?
It's a mountain.
Mountains are safe.
Mountains have caves.
And water. And sticks.
Mom? Did you hear that?
I can get my own stick!
Yes. Sticks and caves.
Caves and sticks.
Crazy sticks.
Let's go.
(SHUSHES) Quiet!
(RUMBLING)
(ANIMAL TRUMPETS)
(GASPS)
Dun-dun-dun!
(GROWLS)
Ugh!
That thing is weird.
No, no, no.
It's okay, Sandy.
That's just Belt.
(GROWLS)
Uh, I've made a decision.
We're going to that mountain.
Don't ask me why.
Just a hunch.
Just feels right.
I don't know, Grug. We've
never really walked that far.
I don't think
my feet can do that.
I'll never live long
enough to get there.
Let's do it.
Oh, come on, just think.
Our whole family
packed together
on a long, slow,
trip across country?
Days and nights with just each other.
(GRUNTS)
We'll tell stories.
We'll laugh.
Ha-ha-ha!
(GRUNTS)
We'll become
closer as a family.
(GROWLING)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS) Get her off!
If you're not ready
to challenge her,
then don't look her in the eye.
Could you keep
your big giant arms
on your side of the trail?
(GRUNTS)
Isn't this fun? We're taking
our first trip together.
Stop shoving, or I will
pull out your tongue!
Do you want me to turn this
family around? Do you?
Because I will turn this
family around so fast!
Dad, I gotta go!
Come on, you can hold it.
I don't think so.
UGGA: Sandy, take
that out of your mouth.
GRAN: I'm touching...
EEP: Gran.
THUNK: Dad,
I still gotta go!
GRUG: Fine. Just go behind one of
those lumpy things and make it fast.
THUNK: Something bit me!
GRAN: I don't blame it.
EEP: Dad, can I take
a turn carrying him?
GRUG: No.
EEP: How about now?
EEP: Now?
GRUG: No.
EEP: (SHOUTS) Now?
GRUG: I can do this
all day long.
No, no, no and still no.
I'm not dying on
an empty stomach.
Grug, we're all pretty tired!
We'll eat when we get there.
It's taking too long!
I'm grabbing a snack.
Don't do that.
He will cut you.
That's not food,
he's a pet. My pet.
What's a pet?
An animal you don't eat.
(CHUCKLES) We call
those "children."
(GROWLING)
No man should have a pet.
It's weird and wrong.
It's food!
No, please!
Not that. That!
Food fixes everything.
Show me your hunting face.
(MUMBLING)
(ROARS) Not you.
You're still grounded.
Come on, Thunk.
(GROANS) My feet hurt.
Ow!
Ow.
(GROWLS)
You look tense.
I'm not tense.
Angry girl wants to be
doing what they're doing.
I wasn't ready.
(ROARS)
Hang on, Thunk, I'm coming!
Why are you doing this?
GUY: What
are they doing?
Hunting.
THUNK: Get it off!
You stay away from me.
No, seriously,
what are they doing?
THUNK: You've got a ton of eggs.
Just make another egg.
(THUNK PANTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
(ROARS)
Now you're just rubbing it in.
There,
who's hungry for scorpion?
Uh, what happened to
the egg and the bird?
Oh.
We lost him.
But when the bird stepped on me
and pushed me
into the ground...
the scorpion
grabbed a hold of me...
and one thing led to another
and here we are eating him.
So, win-win.
Not enough. Not enough!
I need more.
Oh, look at that. Uh, she's
not going to eat me, right?
You're too skinny.
If she was going to eat
anyone it would be...
(SCREAMS)
EEP: Mom!
She's locked her jaw!
Get a stick!
Stay away!
You sick old monster!
Hurry! Put the stick
in her mouth!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
GRUG: Hold her still.
Use a rock.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS) Ugga, would you
just hit her legs?
Why are you rolling away?
I just want something to eat.
You have bug for dinner.
Plenty of bug!
Please.
I'll let you help me hunt.
Really?
Don't wait on me.
They're all over me.
Tell my story.
(GRUNTS)
Okay.
What do you call this?
A trap.
What does it do?
Well...
(WHISTLES)
(GROWLS)
Thump, thump, thump, thump, thump.
(MAKES SPRING NOISE)
(WHISTLES)
(IMITATES EXPLOSION)
Ta-da!
How long have you been alone?
(CHITTERS)
So, what do we do?
Ooh...
How's your acting?
(CHITTERS)
(WHIMPERS)
(GUY IMITATING FEMALE BIRD)
(SQUAWKS)
(CHUCKLES)
(SQUAWKS EXCITEDLY)
You're good at this.
(CHUCKLES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ooh!
(STAMMERS)
No. Sorry.
Okay.
Yeah, that's yours.
EEP: Excuse me.
Your other hand...
That's my arm.
Okay, I'm moving it.
(BOTH YELP)
GUY: Going under.
(SQUAWKS)
(GASPS)
Uh, it didn't step in
your trap-y thing.
Yeah, I noticed!
Ooh!
(GROANS)
Ow.
Where's Eep?
(EEP GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
She's awesome.
(GRUNTS)
Eep!
Dad, no!
GRUG: Ow!
(SQUAWKS)
THUNK: It's an avalanche
of flavor.
(ALL MUNCHING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Oh! (GROWLING)
(GULPS)
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS) Oh!
(SLURPS)
Looks like we won't
be having any leftovers.
What are "left overs"?
When you have so much food to
eat, you have some leftover.
Oh... We never
have that much food.
(SIGHS)
(BELT CHITTERS)
Grug, how about a story?
Oh, that's a good idea.
How about a story? Huh?
Yeah, tell us a story!
Once upon a time,
there was a little tiger...
who lived in a cave
with her family.
There were a lot of rules...
but the big, simple one was to
never leave the cave at night.
And the door was so heavy, you'd
think it would be easy to remember.
So easy to remember!
I know.
(GROANS)
But, while everyone
was asleep...
she went out anyway.
ALL: No!
Yes!
And no sooner than she did,
their cave was destroyed...
and everyone had to go
on this long, sucky walk...
with some weirdo they met...
and die!
(BOTH GASP)
The end.
(SCOFFS)
GUY: Whoa!
I did not see that coming.
Twist ending.
My stories never end like that.
Yes! Two stories
in one night!
(SANDY COOING)
GUY: Um...
Okay. But it won't
be as good as Grug's.
(SCOFFS)
(CLEARS THROAT) Um...
Once upon a time,
there was a beautiful tiger.
(GASPS) She lived in a cave
with the rest of her family.
Her father and mother told her,
"You may go
anywhere you want..."
"but never go near the cliff,
for you could fall."
And die.
Good story.
GUY: But when no one
was looking...
she'd go near the cliff...
for the closer
she came to the edge...
the more she could hear,
the more she could see...
the more she could feel.
Finally...
she stood at the very edge.
She saw a light.
She leaned out to touch it...
and she slipped.
(ALL GASP)
And she fell.
And she flew.
(ALL GASP)
Where did she fly?
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
A place with more suns in
the sky than you can count.
It would be so bright.
A place not like today,
or yesterday.
A place where
things are better.
(ALL GASP)
Tomorrow isn't a place.
(STAMMERS)
You can't see it!
Oh, yes, it is.
I've seen it.
(ALL GASP)
That's where I'm going.
Ooh...
We are going to shut
our eyes and sleep.
(GIGGLES)
And when we wake up...
we're going to find the place
that has everything we want.
Tomorrow?
A cave.
(GASPS)
(SNORING)
(RUMBLING)
(THUDS)
(MUMBLES)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
That was too close.
It almost caught us.
I was watching.
We were fine.
We gotta move faster.
Do you people have any other
speed aside from "wander"?
I'll take a shamble
at this point.
Hey, um, do you have a minute?
How did the tiger fly?
I only share when
I'm outside the log.
I'm funny that way.
Leave this to me.
Hey, Thunk...
you have a spider on your face.
Ah!
(GRUNTS)
Oops.
(GASPS) He's loose!
(CRUNCHES)
(GASPS)
(YELLS)
Do not step on those
weird pointy rocks.
Do you mean these rocks?
Ow!
Do not step on these rocks!
Step aside, girls.
Mmm!
(SCREAMS)
Hello? Nobody's listening!
No one is listening.
You cannot walk on those!
(GRUNTS)
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
Get back here now!
There goes
our chance for survival.
And our log!
Okay.
(GROANING)
(CHUCKLING)
Ow! Ow, ow.
THUNK: Ow! Ah! Ow!
Jumping doesn't help.
It does briefly...
but it doesn't get better.
(SHRIEKS)
(ALL GROANING)
How about...
Don't walk on your hands. The
hands do not help at all.
(ALL CONTINUE GROANING)
Come on.
I can help you...
but we're going to have to make
a few changes around here.
The log ride is over.
Drop the log.
Now, kick it away.
Farther.
(GRUNTS)
Really?
Okay, smart "Guy"...
now what?
(Booms)
Whoa! Oh...
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
(WHIMPERING)
Good fish, good fish.
Oh! (PANTING)
(GIGGLES)
Okay.
Now you can look.
(SCREAMS)
I love them!
Where are my feet?
They're still there!
(GASPING)
Okay.
Whoa, whoa!
(GRUNTS) You're really heavy.
Really?
Thank you!
Hey. Wait!
Whoa. Whoa!
Whoa!
Oh! Okay.
She's up. We're good.
I'm good.
Oh, these shoes are great!
Where do you get these ideas?
A-ha!
I'm calling it
a "brain."
I'm pretty sure it's
where ideas come from.
Dad, I don't have a brain.
We've gotten along just fine
without brains until now.
Cavemen don't need brains.
We have these.
(LAUGHING)
That's what I'm talking about!
Ideas are for weaklings.
Now, let's get
to that mountain!
Oh, wow!
I love those!
Good fish.
Don't eat my feet.
(WHIMPERS)
Huh!
(GROWLS)
(CHITTERS)
(ALL CHITTERING EXCITEDLY)
(GRUNTS)
Ah!
(SNARLS)
Hmm. Huh?
(GROWLS)
(WHIMPERS)
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
(WHOOPING)
(SCREAMS)
So, how did the tiger fly?
She jumped on the sun...
and rode it to Tomorrow.
EEP: Oh...
(GRUNTS) No, no, no.
(TIGER SCREECHES IN PAIN)
Ha!
(YOWLS)
Ah!
(GASPING ANXIOUSLY)
(SCREAMS)
Ah!
(ALL WHOOPING)
(GASPING)
Hi, Dad!
Bye, Dad!
(GROANING)
You've seen rain before, right?
We don't get out much.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(THUNK LAUGHING)
Eep, looks dangerous.
(GROANS)
Dad, you say that
about everything.
Careful.
Oh.
Really? Okay.
(GASPS)
(GIGGLES)
(GASPING)
(ALL WHOOPING)
(SPLASHES)
Whoa!
(LAUGHING)
No, no, no.
Not cool!
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(SPLASHING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMS)
So, the bear says,
"Your cave?"
"I've been dumping my bones
here since last week."
Last week!
(ALL LAUGHING)
That's a funny story!
It's not a story.
It's a joke.
What's a "joke"?
Just making something up
to make you laugh.
(GRAN LAUGHING)
GUY: One for you.
Thanks.
One for you.
And this one's for you.
(ALL PLAYING LOW NOTE) Okay.
Okay! That's enough!
(SIGHS)
I don't see why the kids
need their own shells.
So if anyone gets in trouble,
we can call the others.
Wait, you're saying
we should split up?
We can try more paths at once.
It's the fastest way through.
Croods stick together.
Your way isn't safe.
They can handle it.
We can do it, Dad.
No, no, no.
It's my job to keep you safe.
I'm still in charge
and we are not splitting up.
Except for you two.
And that's final.
(GRUNTS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(PANTING) Hello?
Is everyone all right? Ah!
UGGA: We're okay, Grug.
Dad? I'm freaking
out a little bit.
Just tell me what to do. What do I do?
What do I do right now?
Stay where you are.
I'll find you.
No. Too slow.
Everybody, keep moving
forward and we'll get out.
THUNK: Dad?
(GRUNTS)
Yeah.
Okay.
Remember, never not be afraid.
GUY: You can do this!
It's going to be okay,
it's going to be okay.
I'm going to pass out.
(COOING)
Sandy.Sandy!
(GASPS)
(ALL GASP) Oh.
(SOBBING)
Ah!
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
(GROANS)
(SNIFFS)
(PANTING)
(GROANS)
(COOS)
(SANDY COOING)
Ah! Ooh...
(MOANS)
(GASPS)
(YELPS)
(BARKING)
(WHISPERS) Give me another one.
You dropped these.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
(CHUCKLES)
(BLOWS)
(GRUNTING)
Come with me.
Here, boy! Catch!
(PANTING)
GRAN: Yoo-hoo!
Gran?
(GIGGLES)
Mom?
Wow.
Grug?
(BLOWS WEAKLY)
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
I'll go get him.
(EXHALES)
THUNK: Oh, good boy!
Who's a good boy?
You are! Yes, you are!
Look at you!
You need a name.
You want a name?
I'm going to call you Douglas.
Can you do tricks?
Roll over.
Come on, Douglas, roll over.
Good boy, Douglas!
I was in love once.
(SIGHS)
He was a hunter.
I was a gatherer.
It was quite a scandal.
We fed each other
berries, we danced.
Then my father
smashed him with a rock
and traded me
to your grandfather.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Croods!
Get down here.
Grug, they're okay.
Guy is with them.
Oh? Guy is with them.
Oh. Phew! Okay.
Ha! Thank you.
Thank you for bringing me
that interesting Guy update.
Oh, okay.
I'm going to go up...
and why don't you join us when
you stop being a big drag!
(SIGHS)
Uh, uh...
Sleep pile?
How about a story? Huh?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Anyone?
And then Torg said,
"Know it? I drew it."
(ALL LAUGHING)
That makes no sense.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I know it was hard for
you to bring us along...
but they had the best
day of their lives.
Thank you for that.
(ANIMALS SCREECHING
IN DISTANCE)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I want to show you something.
(BLOWS)
More suns in the sky
than you can count.
GUY: Every sun that crosses our
sky comes to rest up there.
Tomorrow.
That's where we'll be safe.
I'm going with Guy.
No. Not my little girl.
Come with us.
I can't go without Grug.
That makes one of us.
Count me in.
Really, Mom? Now?
GRAN: Grug has no idea
how to protect us.
In fact,
he has no ideas at all!
UGGA: No, that's not true. What
about that one time when he...
Uh...
(STAMMERS)
Oh, face it.
If he actually had
an idea of his own...
I'd have a heart
attack and die!
Grug?
THUNK: Dad!
EEP: Dad!
He's a big guy. How could he
just disappear like that?
Hey, wait! Let's ask that
ugly lady if she's seen Dad.
Huh?
Haven't seen him.
Ah!
What are you doing?
Yeah. Wow.
I was up all night, because all
these ideas just kept coming to me.
Um, is that a snake?
Belt, new and improved.
(GROWLS)
Ow! It's even
self-tightening!
Ow!
What is that on your head?
It's called desperation.
I call it a "rug."
Rhymes with "Grug."
And this one,
I call it a "ride."
Rhymes with "Grug."
Uh, that doesn't rhyme...
It's going to get us places
faster than shoes. (CHUCKLES)
Yeah! Try to keep up!
(GRUG GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
GRUG: Oh!
I wish I had a ride.
GRUG: And painting
is a thing of the past.
I call this a "snapshot."
(GROANS)
Oh, let's do it again.
I think I blinked.
I call them "shades."
The sun doesn't hurt
my eyes anymore.
Where do you get
these great ideas?
Since I don't have a brain...
they're coming from my
stomach, down deep below...
and then up again into my mind.
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
Grug, we have to keep moving.
See, I got ideas.
I got thoughts.
Like this. I call it
a "mobile home."
Isn't that something?
(GRUNTS)
And I'm calling this
one a "lifterator."
Mom?
I know.
It's bad.
(SCREAMS)
ALL: Ooh!
I almost feel sorry for him.
(GRUG GROANS)
(SQUISHES)
ALL: Oh!
(CHUCKLES) No, I don't.
UGGA: What are you
trying to do, Grug?
GRUG: (SIGHS) See, I thought
if I could have ideas...
like Guy...
uh...
maybe Eep would listen to me.
And maybe she wouldn't
want to go with Guy.
Oh, Grug.
Is that what this is all about?
(SIGHS)
And I also thought
it would kill your mother.
So win-win.
GUY: We're here!
Wow.
(GASPS)
(BIRDS CAWING OVERHEAD)
(EXPLODES)
(GASPS)
(ALL GASP)
(SANDY SOBS)
Cave!
Everyone inside.
Hurry up.
Let's go.
Let's go. Go!
No!
No more caves, Grug.
What?
We're going to jump on the sun and
ride it to Tomorrow with Guy!
Wait. So you're all
going to do this?
Thunk?
Sorry, Dad.
You have to stop
worrying for all of us.
It's my job to worry! It's
my job to follow the rules!
The rules don't work out here!
They kept us alive!
That wasn't living!
That was just not dying.
There's a difference.
Ugga, everyone,
you have to listen to me.
We would be dead
if we listened to you!
We have to follow Guy now.
(GASPS)
Guy.
Guy? Run.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
GUY: This is pointless!
We're running out of time.
Everything is collapsing.
You're being irrational
and counterproductive!
Big words anger me!
Keep talking.
Countermeasures!
Ah!
You remember how you were this morning?
You changed.
Idea man.
Modern man.
I am a caveman!
No, no, no, wait!
Ahhh! (GROANING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(PANTING)
(BOTH GASP)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(STRAINING)
No!
What is this stuff that
saves you from my punches?
Tar.
No. I have to get
back to them.
Stop struggling.
No!
Grug, stop!
(SIGHS)
(WHIMPERS)
No one gets out of this.
Believe me...
I know.
Your...
Family. Yeah.
Sorry.
(SIGHS)
I was little when it happened.
Last thing my parents
told me was...
"Don't hide."
"Live."
"Follow the sun."
"You'll make it
to Tomorrow."
You followed the light.
My daughter is a lot like you.
No.
She's like you.
She loves you, but always
forgets to say it.
Just like you
forget to tell her.
(SIGHS)
I guess I was just busy
keeping them all alive.
It's okay.
That's what dads do.
That's right.
But we can't do that from here.
We need one of your ideas.
Come on.
You can do it.
(ANIMAL GROWLS)
(WHIMPERS)
Belt! Emergency Idea
Generator, activate!
Ow!
Ooh! I've got it.
Ta-da!
Wow.
Yeah, I know. But he's doing
the best with what he has.
Let's go.
There he is.
Belt, I want romance,
drama, sincerity.
Move me.
(PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC)
GUY: Okay, he sees us.
That's our cue.
Now, work it!
(GUY IMITATING FEMALE TIGER)
GUY: He's
not coming over.
I don't think our puppet
looks scared enough.
Scared?
I'll show you scared.
Hand me those acting sticks!
(GRUG SHRIEKING)
(GROANING)
(CONTINUES SHRIEKING)
(CHUCKLES)
(STRAINING) Hold on!
(GRUNTS)
(PURRS)
(GASPS)
(BOTH GASP)
Dun-dun-dun!
(SNARLS)
(YELPS)
(WHIMPERS)
(BLOWS WHISTLE)
Yes! You did it.
(GRUNTS)
UGGA: Grug!
THUNK: Dad!
Hey! We're okay!
Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
We're okay.
(RUMBLING)
(ALL SCREAM)
(BOTH GASP)
Grug, your call.
Take us to Tomorrow.
Hurry!
Come on! We're
going to make it!
(ALL PANTING)
You were right.
There it is!
The sun!
We can do it! We can
ride it to Tomorrow!
(ALL GASP)
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
Run!
(ALL PANTING)
(GASPS)
(ALL SCREAM)
I don't understand.
The sun was right here.
It was right here.
(RUMBLING)
We have to go back to the cave.
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Stay together. Let's keep moving.
Move, move, move.
Everybody, hold my hand.
Thunk, let's go. Go, go, go.
Let's stay together.
Grug.
What's wrong with you?
Grug, we'll die
if we stay here!
(GASPS)
UGGA: Grug,
listen to me.
We've got to get
back to that cave.
No more dark.
No more hiding.
No more caves.
What's the point of all this?
To follow the light.
I can't change.
I don't have ideas.
But I have my strength.
And right now...
that's all you need.
No, we don't know what's over there.
Maybe nothing!
It's too risky!
It's a chance.
Mmm.
(SNIFFLES) Oh...
I'll take that chance.
I've wanted to throw you
away ever since I met you.
(CHUCKLES)
That's a joke, right?
What's a "joke"?
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
He made it!
He made it.
Okay, Thunk.
Your turn.
You're not coming, are you?
When you make it, so will I.
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
No!
Whee!
You did good.
Dadda!
(CHUCKLES)
SANDY: Whee!
Gran...
No mush.
Just throw me.
Wait.
You surprised me today...
lunkhead.
(GRUNTS)
GRAN: Still alive!
Time to go.
No.
I have too much to say to you.
I need to fix everything,
and I don't have time.
I can fix it.
(SOBS)
This works good.
What do you call it?
I was thinking
of calling it a "hug."
(CLEARS THROAT) Because
it rhymes with "Grug."
But you can
change it if you want.
No. I like "hug."
I love you.
I... (GASPS)
(RUMBLING)
Dad...
I'm scared.
Never be afraid.
(GRUNTS)
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
(GRUG YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
There!
I see him!
(SIGHS)
(RUMBLING) Ah!
(GRUNTING)
Ah!
(PANTING)
Hey!
Hey, I did it!
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
Ah!
(BLOWING)
(GROWLING)
(YELLS) Whoa!
Back! Stay back!
Stay back!
(ROARING)
(BLOWS)
(CRASHES)
(BOTH BLOWING)
(PURRS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(CONTINUES PURRING)
(RUMBLING)
(LOW NOTE PLAYING ON SHELL)
(GASPS)
They're in trouble.
Hang on, I'm coming!
How do I get across?
I have to think.
What would Guy do?
What would Guy do,
what would Guy do?
What would I do?
Hold this.
(STRAINING)
(GRUNTS)
I have...
an idea!
(GRUNTS)
(SHOUTING GIBBERISH)
(YELPING)
Run!
(GRUG SCREAMS)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
Yes!
Douglas?
Hey, I know that guy.
(RUMBLING)
(PANTING)
(ANIMAL WHINING)
(BOTH CHITTERING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALL WHIMPERING)
Hold on!
(GRUNTING)
(PLAYING LOW NOTE)
(SNIFFLES)
It's not safe here.
I'll tell her.
(SOBS)
(CONTINUES SOBBING)
(PLAYS LOW NOTE)
(ALL PLAYING)
I never got to tell him.
(SOBBING)
Eep, if your dad were here,
he would tell you to...
GRUG: Get out of the way!
Wow. You sound
just like him.
GRUG: Get out of the way!
Dadda!
He did it!
He's riding the sun.
(GRUG YELLS)
But, not very well.
Everybody out of the way!
(GRUG GRUNTS)
Grug! Dad!
Where's the danger?
Who blew their shell?
I love you, too!
(SIGHS)
One, two, three, four...
five...
six...
and seven.
(CHUCKLES)
(CHITTERS)
And a half.
And eight.
(SIGHS)
Nine.
Douglas! Dad,
you saved him!
A boy has to have a pet.
(PURRS)
(BOTH SCREAM)
Turns out I'm a cat person.
(PURRING)
Uh-uh!
No.
(BOTH CHITTERING)
Ah!
(CHUCKLES)
You really need to see this.
We should go there.
(BARKS)
Yes!
Coming through!
(ALL LAUGHING)
GUY: Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Wait!
This is me.
My name is Eep.
And this is my family,
the Croods.
If you weren't clued in
by the suntans and pets...
we're not exactly
cavemen anymore.
(ALL GRUNT)
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, let's do it again.
I think I blinked.
EEP: Our world is still
plenty harsh and hostile...
(SNARLS)
(CHUCKLES)
but now we know
the Croods will make it.
Because we changed the rules...
the ones that
kept us in the dark.
(GRUNTS)
(PLAYS LOW NOTE)
And because of my dad, who taught
us that anyone can change.
Release the baby!
(COOS)
(BARKS)
EEP: Sort of.
(THUNK GASPS)
(YELPING)
Ha-ha!
So, from now on,
we'll stay out here...
where we can follow the light.
(SANDY GIGGLES)
(PANTING)
BOTH: Dun-dun-dun!
(GIGGLING)
(CHITTERS)
(SHINE YOUR WAY PLAYING)
MAN: Just before the dawn
When the light's still gone
Shine, shine your way
And you may not know
where to go
To shine, shine your way
BOTH: Open road but it's still
dark Build a fire from a spark
Shine, shine your way
Feed the feeling in your heart
Don't conceal it
then you'll start
To find, find your way
WOMAN: No one
can stop what has begun
You must believe when I say
BOTH: All of your tears
will dry faster in the sun
Starting today
Shine, shine, shine
Shine your way
WOMAN: There's an open sky
and a reason why
You shine, shine your way
There's so much to learn
And now it's your turn
To shine, shine your way
BOTH: There's
a feeling deep inside
You can let it be your guide
To find, find your way
And there's no time
tor us to waste
Got to take a leap of faith
And fly, fly away
WOMAN: Don't have to walk
Now you can run
Nothing can get in your way
BOTH: All of your tears
will dry faster in the sun
Starting today
Shine, shine, shine
Shine your way
MAN: Morning is breaking
WOMAN: Darkness is fading
BOTH: We found
a way to the light
It's such a beautiful sight
MAN: Any time, anywhere, Turn
around and I'll be there
To shine, shine your way
WOMAN: Like a star
burning bright
Lighting up your darkest night
I'll shine, shine your way
Now I can see
MAN: You are the one
Sent here to show me the way
BOTH: All of our tears
will dry faster in the sun
Starting today
Shine, shine, shine
We're on our way
That's why we say
Shine, shine, shine
Shine your way
There's a reason why you shine
All of our tears
will dry faster in the sun
Shine your way
(TRUMPETING MARIACHI MUSIC)
(TRUMPETS)