These bank holidays.
It's a problem to decide.
Tell you what, Gromit lad!
Let's have a nice,
hot cup of tea. Hmm?
Kettle should have
boiled by now.
[Humming]
No cheese, Gromit.
Not a bit in the house.
[Gulp]
Gromit, that's it: cheese.
We'll go somewhere
where there's cheese.
Well, where were we:
places you find cheese.
Lancashire, Cheddar,
Wensleydale,
Philadelphia, Tesco's.
Everybody knows the moon
is made of cheese.
[Animal sniffing]
[Door opens]
[lmitates rocket engine]
Oop!
Hmm.
[Whistling]
[Whistling louder]
[Beep beep]
[Clears throat]
[Whistling]
Everything seems to be
under control...
[Loud crash]
Ooh!
60 seconds to blast off.
[Clock ticking and ringing]
Ooh! Unlock the doors.
[Rumbling]
Uh... hmm...
No crackers, Gromit.
We've forgotten the crackers.
Hold on, Gromit. Hold on.
[Breathing heavily]
[Ringing]
Huh?
[Rocket engine starting]
Gromit!
Hmm...
[Sighs]
[Whistling]
One for the album.
[Computer making noise]
Oh.
Nicely done.
[Computer beeping]
Huh?
Oooh.
Huh.
Me?
Adjust angle of thrust.
[Computer beeping]
Steady now.
Easing up.
Steady.
Gently does it.
Nice drop of tea
to get the taste buds going.
Mmm.
Plate.
Knife.
Cracker.
See what you think.
Wensleydale?
Stilton?
Hmm... I don't know, lad.
It's like no cheese
I've ever tasted.
Let's try another spot.
[Wallace humming]
Hmm.
Aha.
Come on, stupid...
Oh!
Oh, daylight robbery.
They always nick your money,
them flipping machines.
Come on, Gromit.
[Television signals and static]
[Gromit snoring]
It's different.
Hmm...
Camembert?
Ooh! Oh!
Huh?
Oh.
[Wallace humming]
Where are you off to now?
Oh, leave me to carry
the basket.
Oh!
Emergency countdown!
10 seconds and counting.
Hold tight, lad,
and think of Lancashire hot pot.
[Ringing]
Oh! The fuse!
You forgot to light the fuse!
[Whimpering]
[Blowing nose]
Set coordinates for
62 West Wallaby Street.
Mmm...
[Snoring]
[Toy train whistle]
[Plays "Happy Birthday"]
[Buzzer]
Oh. It's my turn for breakfast
this morning, Gromit.
WALLACE: I'd like
a 3-minute egg...
Huh? Oh!
Steady on! Ough!
Gromit! Ow! Oh!
Ha ha!
Well...
That went as well as could
be expected, didn't it? Hmm?
Though I might have to make
a small adjustment to the drop.
A touch painful on re-entry.
Mmm... cracking toast, Gromit.
Any post, was there, perchance?
Oh, dear, a bit steep.
Oh, my goodness.
Well, I'll bet...
Ho, ho, they're all bills.
Oh dear, oh dear, me.
We shall have
to economize, Gromit.
I'll have to let that room out.
Oh, dear.
["Happy Birthday" plays, stops]
[Humming]
Oh, just look at that.
I'm down to my last few coppers,
and those presents weren't
cheap, either... [Gasps]
Well, Gromit, let's see what's
on the 9:05, shall we?
[Toy train whistle]
Here she comes now.
I wonder what this can be.
Happy birthday, chuck.
[Wallace chuckles]
I knew you'd like it.
Here, let me help you.
You look like
somebody owns you now.
And that's only the first part.
Come and look in here.
I think you'll find this present
a valuable addition...
to our modern lifestyle.
They're Techno-Trousers.
Ex-NASA, fantastic for walkies.
All you do is attach
the lead on here.
Then program in...
Walkies, 10 minutes,
20 minutes... Whoops!
Ha! Ha! Ha!
Oh, have a nice walk, Gromit.
Oh...
It's no use prevaricating
about the bush.
[Wallace slurps liquid, exhales]
Nice walkies, hmm?
How were the Techno-Trousers?
[Bell ringing]
Oh, there's someone
at the door, Gromit.
I wonder who that could be.
Oh, it's about the room, then.
Well, that's grand.
Uh, would you like to come
this way and inspect?
I'm asking 20 a week.
That will include your
breakfast.
I suppose you like kippers,
do you?
Ha ha!
Partial to
a nice black pudding myself...
with bacon, of course.
I'm sure that we can come to
an amicable agreement.
As I say, it's a bit
dingy at present.
But it's surprising what a lick
of paint will do, isn't it?
Oh, uh, but I don't think...
Uh, wasn't quite
what we had in mind.
Uh, wouldn't you like to see...
oh, dear.
Look... ha ha...
Uh, there's something
I've got to tell you.
It's, uh... no pets.
Uh, does that suit you?
[Radio playing
"Tie a Yellow Ribbon"]
Seems pleasant enough.
Cheer up, Gromit.
Surprising what a lick
of paint will do, isn't it?
Oh, so that's where
my braces went.
Wonderful things,
these Techno-Trousers.
Oh! Oh, I'm sorry.
[Radio playing
"Tie a Yellow Ribbon"]
[Radio playing "Happy Talk"]
[Radio playing "How Much is
that Doggy in the Window?"]
[Glass breaking]
[Music stops]
[Sniffing and crying]
Lovely morning, Gromit.
Ooh... oh... oh...
thank you very much.
Ha, ha, ooh,
that's just grand.
WALLACE: Oh, thank you kindly.
What do you think of
that, then, Gromit? Eh?
Our paying guest.
[Chuckles]
WALLACE: Ha! Ha! Ha! Nice drop
of Bordeaux, this, eh?
[Chuckles]
Here's to paying guests.
More cheese, Penguin, eh?
[Chuckles]
Good night, Penguin, sleep well.
[Bell rings]
[Snoring]
Oh.
That was lovely cheese.
Oh! Oh! Oh...
Yaaah!
It's the wrong trousers!
The wrong trousers.
What have you done
with the controls, Gromit?
Now... that'll do.
Just hold on a minute.
Uh, stop it.
Gromit!
Stop these confounded things!
Uh, this isn't funny, Gromit.
The joke's over.
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Get me out of these trousers!
Lummy day!
Help! Gromit!
Oh! Gromit!
Oh!
Sorry!
[Crash]
[Alarm ringing]
Whoa!
It's the wrong trousers, Gromit!
And they've gone wrong!
Stop them, Gromit! Stop them!
Help me, Gromit!
The trousers have gone haywire.
Get me out!
Help!
Oh! Ah! Ooh! Oh! Ow!
Oh, I'm tired. Oh...
A good doze, that's what I need.
Get me strength back. Oh...
What a... what a shocking
calami... calami... calamity.
[Snoring]
[Wallace stirs]
[Wallace snoring]
[Yawns]
[Alarm]
Ooh! What's the game, then?
Where am I?
What's going on?
Yikes!
Gromit!
I must be dreaming!
Where the devil am I?
Oh!
What? Oh, great heavens above!
Whatever is it?
Help!
Get me down!
What's the game, then? Eh?
Where am I?
That's quite enough!
You'll be hearing from
my solicitor about this.
Oh! Eeh! Oh! Mind how you go!
You can't go taking
liberties like this!
I'm a respectable citizen.
Most definitely not legal, this.
Good grief, it's you!
Now, let me out of
these trousers this minute.
Oh, steady on, will you?
This wardrobe's nearly new,
you know.
Let me out!
Ha, I'll give you what for,
you tyke.
Excuse me? Hello?
And to think so, too... Hey!
Well, this is a fine
how-do-you-do, isn't it, Gromit?
Oh, steady on.
Watch where
you're putting them paws.
Oh! Oh! Careful, lad.
Oh, my goodness,
it'll ruin the woodwork.
Oh, there goes me knotted pine.
Where are we going?
Ha! I can't see a thing.
What's happening?
[Toy train whistle]
Catch me, Gromit!
Ah! Oh!
Don't worry, Gromit!
I'm... ooh! ...right behind you!
Aah! Ooh!
Hang in there, Gromit.
Everything's under control!
I'll have that
if you don't mind, eh?
Aaah!
Oh!
Tallyho!
Leave him to me!
I'll get the bounder!
Aaah!
Aaaaah!
Get him, Gromit!
Aaaah!
Gromit! We're doomed!
Oh, mind the table, Gromit!
Aaah! Gotcha!
Huh?
All yours, Gromit!
That a boy, Gromit, lad!
Well done! We did it! Ha! Ha!
Thank you, old friend.
Many thanks, indeed.
That reward money
paid off all our debts.
No more lodgers, oh, hmm.
More trouble than they're worth.
I could just fancy
some cheese, Gromit.
What do you say?
Cheddar?
Don't forget the crackers.
Ha, all's well that ends well,
that's what I say.
Mmm.
[Techno-Trousers moving]
Hmm.
Oh, I do like a bit
of Gorgonzola.
[Snoring]
[Animals bleating]
[Baa]
[Buzzer]
Porridge today, Gromit!
Tuesday!
Geronimo!
Huh?
Oh!
Ow! Ow!
Turn it off!
Mice, do you think?
[Wood creaking]
I think I'll make
my own porridge.
Well, I'll be.
Have you been peckish
during the night?
Only, someone's been
at me cheese.
[Crack]
Well, I don't know,
there's something
very fishy going on.
[Gromit sniffs]
Huh?
Do you think we should get
the pest control people in?
[Telephone ringing]
Hello,
Wallace & Gromit's Wash'n'Go
Window Cleaning Service.
May we be of assistance?
WOMAN: Hello.
Yes, my windows could do
with a jolly good clean,
the wool shop
in the High Street.
Soon as you can.
On our way, madam.
[Ding]
[Engine starts]
[Tires screech]
[Wallace humming]
Huh?
Oh.
Need wool, don't you, lad?
[Bell rings]
Thank you for
coming so quickly.
Oh, dear!
Oh, allow me, please.
WALLACE: Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh! I'll soon have
these cleared up.
There's no trouble.
WALLACE: How embarrassing.
This is Preston, my dog.
All right, pooch.
WALLACE: Won't take a minute.
BOTH: Oh.
Well...
[Wallace stuttering]
What was it you wanted?
[Bell rings]
[Boing!]
Rumsbottom,
Wendolene Rumsbottom.
Oh, charming.
I'm Wallace...
the windows.
Is this place yours?
Mm-hmm. My father
left it to me,
along with his debts,
and a few other things.
He was an inventor.
Never!
Well, I do a bit
of that meself.
Oh!
I see they still haven't caught
those sheep rustlers yet.
Still, you've got
plenty of wool, eh?
Your dog's waiting.
Aye, I'd better
see to him.
The bounce is gone
from his bungee.
Oh, they're spanking.
You've done a grand job.
Windows are
our speciality.
[Bell rings]
[Sniffs]
[Motorcyle approaching]
WALLACE: Let's get
that kettle on.
Good grief!
What's all this?
Burglars? Thieves?
[Metal clinks]
Oh, what a mess!
I've never seen
anything like it.
Heavens above, Gromit!
Look at this!
The little chap
must be really hungry.
Oh, come over here, lad.
No need to be sheepish.
[Laughs]
We'll have to get you
cleaned up.
There.
Nothing to fret over,
just a quick shampoo.
We've tested this on Gromit.
Haven't we, lad?
Right, off we go, then.
[Sheep bleating]
[Machine buzzing]
Oh, heck!
[Baa]
Oh, do something, Gromit!
Oh, it's too late now.
[Clippers buzzing]
Turn it off, Gromit!
Oh, oh, oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh, dear!
Brilliant, Gromit!
Oh, smashing, this!
A bit tight
here and there.
[Baa]
Ah! Looks OKto me.
[Teeth chattering]
We'll call him Shaun, eh?
Come on, Shaun.
[Metal creaking]
[Thump]
Gromit.
You know we're doing
the clock tomorrow.
Sorry, Gromit!
That was a bit thick!
Back in a tick, Gromit,
won't be long.
[Baa]
[Bell rings]
Tell me about windows.
It's only temporary,
you understand.
Oh, really?
Oh, yes,
I'm inventing mostly.
Only...
Oh, what sort of inventions?
Well, sort of...
Daddy would loved
to have met you.
Poor Daddy.
[Baa]
Of all the women
I've met...
Not that there have been
many, you understand.
[Clunk]
[Baa]
[Sheep bleating]
...so you see,
what I'm trying to say,
in a manner of speaking,
is...
[Baa]
Of all the ladies
I've met...
Whoa!
Ow! Ow!
Same time next week?
[Baa]
[Engine starts]
Caught bang to rights,
you were.
You've really
let us down this time, lad.
[Bleating]
Hey, give over!
[Doorbell]
Shoo! Shoo!
Go on with you!
I'm sorry about this.
For what?
Nothing.
Just stay away from me,
from my shop,
and my silly,
silly windows.
I... well, I...
Forget me.
I'm no good for you.
I'm so sorry
about Gromit.
WALLACE, SOFTLY: Baa.
Whoa!
Oh, Gromit.
Oh, Gromit!
[Door opens]
[Sniffling]
[Electric saw cutting]
[Baa]
Oh, brilliant teamwork, lads!
Whoa!
Aah!
[Sirens]
I suppose you'll have
to skip the country now.
A fugitive, eh?
You'll be hunted down,
like, well, a dog.
[Vehicle approaching]
Wendo...
[Whistle blows]
[Teeth chattering]
[Grr!]
Stop it!
Stop it, Preston!
Oh! Oh, I want no more
of this rustling!
Oh! It wasn't so bad
when it was just the wool,
but this is evil!
Daddy didn't create
you for this.
Ow! You're supposed
to protect me!
Let me out!
You're not going to turn me
into dog meat!
WALLACE: Dog meat?
WENDOLENE: Help!
Don't worry, Wendolene!
[Engine starts]
I'm on my way!
We've lost them!
[Engine starts]
[Truck horn blows]
Ah!
Ooh!
We're at maximum speed!
She won't go any faster!
Whoa!
Oof!
Oh, heck!
WENDOLENE: Wallace,
help me!
Don't worry, Wendolene!
Everything's
under control!
Whoa!
[Baa]
WENDOLENE:
Be careful, Shaun!
WALLACE: Hey, steady on!
Single file!
Oh!
Single file, I say!
Get yourselves
organized down there!
Huh!
Watch out, lads!
[Tires screech]
Oh, no! Ah!
Where'd you
get that from?
That's my machine!
I've got patent
pending on that.
BOTH: Whoa!
WENDOLENE:
Help! Oh, Shaun!
WALLACE: Where's Gromit?
WENDOLENE:
Shaun, do something!
Help!
That a boy, Gromit!
[Motor starts]
Well done, Gromit!
That'll teach him!
[Loud pounding]
He's malfunctioning.
Mal what?
Malfunctioning.
Preston is a cyber-dog.
Cyber wha...
A robot!
Daddy created him for good,
but he's turned out evil.
[Growls]
Ah!
Huh?
It's a sheep-mincing thing!
Now, that's clever.
[Loud whistle]
Huh?
[Engine speeds up]
Do something, Wallace!
[Baa]
Duck!
Where?
Whoa!
[Baa]
By heck!
I thought we were
all for the can then.
[Ring]
I couldn't pass by
without saying thank you.
He's just like
he used to be.
WALLACE:
Oh, don't mention it.
Thanks, pooch.
Give me a shout
if he goes wrong again.
You're very kind.
Oh, won't you come in?
We were just about
to have some cheese.
Oh, no, not cheese.
Sorry, it brings
me out in a rash.
Can't stand the stuff.
[Gulp!]
Not even Wensleydale?
Got to be on our way.
Come on, Preston.
Good-bye...
[Door closes]
chuck.
What's wrong with Wensleydale?
Talking of which...
All the more for us,
and not a sheep to worry us.
Get off me cheese!
Get off! Get o...
Gromit? Gromit!
Go for him!
Gromit! Oh!
Get off with you! Oh!
[Gulp!]
[Baa]
WALLACE: Shoo off!