[# The Gabe Dixon Band:
Find My Way]
[birds chirping]
# I don't mean
to trouble your mind #
# I'm just trying
to find my way home #
# Silently I'm seekin' a kind
of a way to get by on my own #
# Downtown Saturday #
# In a better way #
# Than I ever was before #
# Don't need anyone
standin' in my sun #
# Don't need that anymore #
# Well, it's
a long way I know #
# And there's no
one way to go #
# But it's all gonna show #
# In the end #
# I got to find my way #
# Find my way #
# Find my way home #
- Shit!
- # All those plans
that I made for myself #
# I got nobody else
to lean on #
# Gone so far with
my head in the clouds #
# Now it's time
to come down and be gone #
# Downtown Saturday
in a better way #
# Than I ever was before #
[indistinct chattering]
Andrew, hey.
# Find my way #
Here you go.
Your regular lattes.
Literally saved my life.
Thank you. Thank you.
- # Find my way #
- [honking]
# Find my way #
# Find my way home #
# I got to find my way #
# Find my way
Find my way home #
[elevator dinging]
- Everyone OK?
- Yeah.
- Me too.
Hello, Frank?
How's my favorite writer?
Of course you've been
thinking about our talk
because you
know I'm right.
Frank, people in this
country are busy, broke,
and they hate to read.
They need someone
they can trust to say,
"Hey! Don't watch
CSI: Indianapolis tonight.
Read a book! Read Frank's book."
And that person is Oprah.
[indistinct chatter]
- Cuttin' it close.
- One of those mornings.
Thank you,
Captain Obvious.
- [both grunting]
- Sweet...
- Uh, sorry.
- ...Jesus!
- [laughter]
- [man] Rub some dirt
on it, brother.
Frank, the truth is all
A-plus novelists do publicity.
Roth, McCourt, Russo, and...
Frank! Can I tell you what else
they have in common? A Pulitzer.
I need the shirt off
your back. Literally.
- You're kidding, right?
- Yankees, Boston, this Tuesday,
two company seats
for your shirt.
You have five
seconds to decide.
Five, four,
three, two, one.
- [laughing]
- I know...
- Shh!
- Later.
- [gasps]
- Uh-oh.
- [popping sound]
- [clears throat]
[popping sound
on numerous computers]
Uh, hello. Hello?
Morning, boss. You have a
conference call in 30 minutes.
Yes. About the marketing
of the spring books. I know.
Staff meeting
at 9:00.
Did you call, um...
[groans] What's her name?
The one with
the ugly hands.
- Janet.
- Yes, Janet.
Yes. I did call her.
I told her that
if she doesn't get her
manuscript in on time
you won't give her
a release date.
Your immigration
lawyer called.
He said that
it's imperative...
Cancel the call, push
the meeting to tomorrow
and keep the lawyer
on the sheets.
Oh, and get
a hold of PR,
have them start drafting
a press release.
Frank is doing Oprah.
Wow. Nicely done.
If I want your praise,
I will ask for it.
Um...
Who is, uh,
who is Jillian?
And why does she
want me to call her?
Well, that was
originally my cup.
And I'm drinking
your coffee why?
Because your
coffee spilled.
So, you drink unsweetened
cinnamon light soy lattes?
I do. It's like
Christmas in a cup.
Is that a
coincidence?
- Incredibly, it is.
- [phone ringing]
I mean I wouldn't possibly drink
the same coffee that you drink
just in case
yours spilled.
That would
be pathetic.
Morning.
Miss Tate's office.
Hey, Bob.
Actually, we're headed to
your office right now. Yeah.
Why are we headed
to Bob's office?
- [tsks]
[tsks]
- [popping sound]
- [multiple pops]
[gasps] Oop!
Have you finished the
manuscript I gave you?
Uh, I read a few pages.
I wasn't that impressed.
- Can I say something?
- No.
I've read thousands
of manuscripts,
and this is the only one
I've ever given you.
There's an incredible
novel in there.
The kind of novel
you used to publish.
Uh, wrong. And I do think you
order the same coffee as I do
just in case you spill,
which is, in fact, pathetic.
- Or impressive.
- I'd be impressed
if you didn't spill
in the first place.
Now remember, you're
just a prop in here.
- Won't say a word.
- [clears throat]
Ah! Our fearless leader and
her liege. Please, do come in.
Oh. Beautiful breakfront.
Is it new?
It is English Regency Egyptian
Revival, built in the 1800s
but, yes, it is new
to my office.
Witty.
Bob, I'm letting you go.
Pardon?
I asked you over
a dozen times
to get Frank
to do Oprah,
and you didn't do it.
You're fired.
I have told you
that is impossible.
Frank hasn't done an
interview in 20 years.
[Tate] Well that is
interesting, because I just
got off the phone
with him, and he is in.
Excuse me?
You didn't even
call him, did you?
- But...
- I know, I know.
Frank can be a little scary
to deal with. For you.
Now, I will give you two
months to find another job.
And then you can tell
everyone you resigned, OK?
What's his twenty?
He's moving.
He has crazy eyes.
Don't do it, Bob.
Don't do it.
- You poisonous bitch!
- [all gasp]
You can't fire me!
You don't think I see
what you're doing here?
Sandbagging me
on this Oprah thing
just so that you can
look good to the board?
Because you are
threatened by me!
- And you are a monster.
- Bob, stop.
Just because you have
no semblance of a life
outside of
this office,
you think that you
can treat all of us
like your own
personal slaves.
You know what?
I feel sorry for you.
Because you know what you're
gonna have on your deathbed?
Nothing and no one.
[breathes deeply]
Listen carefully, Bob.
I didn't fire you because
I feel threatened. No.
I fired you because you're
lazy, entitled, incompetent
and you spend more time
cheating on your wife
than you do
in your office.
And if you say
another word,
Andrew here is gonna have you
thrown out on your ass, OK?
Another word and you're
going out of here
with an armed escort.
Andrew will film it with
his little camera phone
and he will put it
on that Internet site.
- What was it?
- YouTube?
Exactly. Is that
what you want?
Didn't think so.
I have work to do.
[all murmuring]
Have security take his
breakfront out of his office
and put it in my
conference room.
Will do.
And I need you
around this weekend
to help review his files
and his manuscript.
- This weekend?
- You have a problem with that?
No. I... just my
grandmother's 90th birthday,
so I was gonna
go home and...
...it's fine.
I'll cancel it.
You're actually saving me from
a weekend of misery anyway,
so it's...
good talk, yeah.
I know, I know. OK, tell
Gammy I'm sorry. OK? What...
Mom. What do you
want me to tell you?
She's making me
work the weekend.
No, I'm not... no.
Listen, I've worked too
hard for this promotion
to throw it
all away, OK?
I'm sure that
Dad is pissed,
but we take all
of our submissions
around here
very seriously.
We'll get back to
you as soon as we can.
- Was that your family?
- Yes.
- They tell you to quit?
- Every single day.
Miss Tate's office.
Oh... Yeah.
OK. All right.
Bergen and Malloy want to
see you upstairs immediately.
[groans] OK. Come get me in ten
minutes. We've got a lot to do.
Okey-doke.
[phone ringing]
Good morning, Miss Tate.
Jack, Edwin.
Margaret, congratulations
on the Oprah thing.
- That's terrific news.
- Thank you, thank you.
This isn't about my second
raise, is it? [chuckles]
Just kidding.
Margaret, do you
remember when we agreed
that you wouldn't go to
the Frankfurt Book Fair
because you weren't allowed
out of the country
while your visa application
was being processed?
Yes. I do.
And... you went
to Frankfurt.
Yes, I did. We were going
to lose DeLillo to Viking.
So... really didn't
have a choice, did I?
It seems that the
United States Government
doesn't care much who
publishes Don DeLillo.
We, uh, just spoke to
your immigration attorney.
Great. So, we're all
good? Everything good?
Margaret, your visa
application has been denied.
- [stammers]
- And you are being deported.
Deported?
And apparently there
was also some paperwork
that you didn't
fill out in time.
Come on. Come on! It's not
like I'm even an immigrant!
I'm from Canada,
for Christ's sake.
There's gotta be... there's
gotta be something we can do.
We can reapply,
but unfortunately
you have to
leave the country
for at least
a year.
OK. OK, well, that's
not ideal, but, uh..,
I can, uh... I can manage
everything from Toronto...
- [Bergen] No, Margaret.
- ...with videoconferencing
and Internet.
[Malloy]
Unfortunately, Margaret,
if you're deported,
you can't work for
an American company.
Until this is resolved I'm
going to turn operations over
to Bob Spaulding.
Bob Spaulding?
The guy I just fired?
We need an
editor in chief.
He is the only person
in the building
who has enough
experience.
- You cannot be serious.
I beg of you.
- Margaret.
We are desperate
to have you stay.
If there was any way,
any way at all
that we could make this
thing work, we'd be doing it.
- [knocking]
- There is no way...
I am begging you.
No, Margaret. Excuse me,
we're in a meeting.
- Sorry to interrupt.
- What? What!
Mary from Miss Winfrey's office
called. She's on the line.
- I know.
- [Andrew] She's on hold.
She needs to speak
with you right away.
I told her you were
otherwise engaged.
She insisted,
so... sorry.
So...
Uh... [mouthing]
[whispering]
Come here.
Uh... Gentlemen, I understand.
I understand...
the predicament
that we are in.
And, um...
And there's,
uh... well...
I think there's something
that you should know.
Uh... we're, uh...
we're getting married.
We are getting married.
- Who is getting married?
- You and I.
You and I are
getting married! Yes.
- We are.
- Getting married.
- [mumbling] We are
getting married.
- Yes.
Isn't he
your secretary?
- Assistant.
- Executive, uh... assistant
secretary. Titles.
But, wouldn't
be the first time
one of us fell
for our secretaries.
Would it, Edwin?
[Margaret] With Laquisha.
Remember?
So, yeah...
The truth is,
you know, Andrew and I, we're...
we are just two people
who weren't meant to
fall in love but we did.
No.
All those late nights at the
office and weekend book fairs.
- Yeah...
- No.
- Something happened.
- Something.
Yeah. Tried to
fight it and...
Can't, can't fight a...
Can't fight a love
like ours, so, uh...
Uh... Are we good
with this? Are you happy?
Because, well...
we are happy. So happy.
- [Bergen] Margaret.
- Yes?
It's terrific.
Just make it
legal. Mmm?
Oh! Legal. [chuckles]
Yeah, well, then...
then that means we...
...we need to get ourselves
to the immigration office.
So we can work this
whole mess out. Right?
[Margaret] Thank you
very much, gentlemen.
We will do that
right away.
Thank you very much,
gentlemen. Thank you.
- Gentlemen.
- Thank you.
[popping]
[woman whispers] Margaret and
Andrew are getting married!
[woman #2] What is that about?
[man whispering] Dragon Lady!
Here they come...
[snickering] Yeah.
[woman #3] What is he thinking?
Mmm-mmm-mmm.
[indistinct chatter]
Dude, for real.
Her? [laughing]
[woman #4] Married? Didn't
even know they were dating...
[Margaret clears throat]
[clearing throat]
What?
I don't understand
what's happening.
[Margaret] Relax.
This is for you, too.
Do explain.
They were going
to make Bob chief.
So naturally I would
have to marry you.
[Margaret] And what's
the problem?
Like you were saving yourself
for someone special?
I like to think so.
Besides, it's illegal.
They're looking for terrorists,
not for book publishers.
- Margaret.
- Yes?
- I'm not gonna marry you.
- Sure you are.
Because if you
don't marry me,
your dreams of touching
the lives of millions
with the written word
are dead.
Bob is gonna fire you the
second I'm gone. Guaranteed.
That means you're out on the
street alone looking for a job.
That means all the time that we
spent together, all the lattes,
all the canceled dates,
all the midnight Tampax runs,
were all for nothing and
all your dreams of being
an editor are gone.
But don't worry, after the
required allotment of time,
we'll get a quickie divorce
and you'll be done with me.
But until then,
like it or not,
your wagon is hitched
to mine. OK?
- [phone ringing]
- Phone.
[indistinct chatter]
- This way.
- Margaret.
- [hisses] Come.
- The line...
Next, please.
Ooh, ooh. Just, uh...
Sorry, I just need to
ask him something.
I need for you to file this
fiancée visa for me, please.
[scoffs]
- Miss Tate?
- Yes.
Please,
come with me.
[woman] Yes, ma'am, I understand
that. We're backed up...
I have a bad feeling
about this.
[knocking]
- Hi. Hello.
- Hello.
Hi.
I'm Mr. Gilbertson.
- Ah!
- And you must be Andrew,
- and you must be...
- Margaret.
...Margaret.
Sorry about the wait.
It's a, uh,
crazy day today.
Oh, of course, of course.
We understand.
And I can't tell you how much
we appreciate you seeing us
- on such short notice.
- OK. [sighs]
# Buh, buh, buh, buh, buh
buh, buh, buh, buuuh #
So, I have one
question for you.
Are you both committing fraud
to avoid her deportation
so she can keep her position as
editor in chief at Colden Books?
- That's ridiculous.
- Where did you hear that?
We had a phone tip this
afternoon from a man named...
Would it be
Bob Spaulding?
Bob Spaulding.
Bob. Poor Bob.
I am so sorry.
Bob is nothing but a
disgruntled former employee.
And I apologize.
But we know you're
incredibly busy
with a room full of gardeners
and delivery boys to tend to.
If you just give us
our next step,
we will be out of your
hair and on our way.
Miss Tate, please.
Let me explain to you the
process that's about to unfold.
Step one will be
a scheduled interview.
I'll put you each
in a room,
and I'll ask you
every little question
that a real couple
would know about each other.
Step two, I dig deeper.
I look at your phone records,
I talk to your neighbors,
I interview your coworkers.
If your answers don't
match up at every point,
you will be deported
indefinitely.
And you, young man, will have
committed a felony...
[woman shouting in Spanish]
...punishable by
a fine of $250,000
and a stay of five years
in federal prison.
[Gilbertson] So, Andrew.
You wanna... you want
to talk to me?
No?
Yes?
The truth is...
[Andrew clears throat]
Mr. Gilbertson,
the truth is...
Margaret and I...
...are just two people
who weren't supposed
to fall in love.
[Andrew] But did.
We couldn't tell
anyone we work with
because of my big promotion
that I had coming up.
- [Gilbertson] Promotion?
- Yeah.
- Your...?
- We... we both felt, uh...
...that it would be
deeply inappropriate
if I were to be
promoted to editor.
- Editor. Mmm-hmm.
- ...while we were...
So...
[clears throat]
Have the two of you
told your parents
about your
secret love?
Oh, I... impossible.
My parents are dead.
- No brothers or sisters either.
- Gone.
Are your parents dead?
- Oh, no, his
are very much alive.
- No... very much.
Very much. They're, ah...
Well, we were gonna tell
them this weekend.
Gammy's 90th birthday, and the
whole family's coming together.
And we thought it'd
be a nice surprise.
[Gilbertson] And where is this
surprise gonna take place?
At Andrew's
parents' house.
Where is that
located again?
Umm... [scoffs] Why am I
doing all the talking?
It's your
parents' house.
Why don't you tell him
where it is. Jump in.
- Sitka.
- Alaska.
- Alaska?
You're gonna go to
Alaska this weekend?
- Yeah.
- Yes, yes.
We are going to Alaska.
Alaska, that's where...
That's where my little...
that's where my Andrew's from.
[Gilbertson] OK.
Fine. I see how
this is gonna go.
I will see you both
at 11:00 Monday morning
for your
scheduled interview,
and your answers better
match up on every account.
- Thank you.
- Hello?
I'm looking forward
to this one.
We're looking forward
Thank you.
Gonna be fun. I'll be
checking up on you.
You got it.
OK... so, what's gonna happen
is we will go up there.
We will pretend like we're
boyfriend and girlfriend,
tell your parents
we're engaged.
Uh, use the miles
for the tickets.
I guess I will pop for
you to fly first class.
But make sure
you use the miles.
If we don't get the miles,
we're not doing it.
Oh, and please confirm
the vegan meal, OK?
'Cause last time they
actually gave it to a vegan,
and they, uh...
forced me to eat
this clammy, warm, creamy
salad thing, which was...
Hey, I'm... Why aren't
you taking notes?
I'm sorry, were you
not in that room?
What? What?
Oh! The thing you said
about being promoted?
Genius! Genius. He
completely fell for it.
I was serious.
I'm looking at a $250,000 fine
and five years in jail.
That changes things.
Promote you to editor?
No, no way.
Then I quit, and you're
screwed. Bye-bye, Margaret.
- Andrew!
- It really has been
- a little slice of heaven.
- Andrew, Andrew! Fine, fine.
I'll make you
editor. Fine.
If you do the Alaska weekend
and the immigration interview,
I will make you
editor. Happy?
- And not in two
years. Right away.
- Fine.
And you'll publish
my manuscript.
Ten thousand copy
first...
Twenty thousand copies,
first run.
And we'll tell my family
about our engagement
when I want
and how I want.
Now, ask me nicely.
"Ask you nicely" what?
Ask me nicely to
marry you, Margaret.
- What does that mean?
- You heard me. On your knee.
Fine.
[honking]
- Does this work for you?
- Oh, I like this. Yeah.
- Will you marry me?
- No.
Say it like
you mean it.
[clears throat]
- Andrew?
- Yes, Margaret?
- Sweet Andrew?
- I'm listening.
Would you please, with
cherries on top, marry me?
OK. I don't appreciate
the sarcasm, but I'll do it.
- See you at the
airport tomorrow.
- Good.
So, these are the questions
that INS is gonna ask us.
Now, the good news is is
I know everything about you,
but the bad news is
that you have four days
to learn all
this about me.
So, you should...
probably get studying.
You know all the answers
to these questions about me?
- Scary, isn't it?
- [Margaret] A little bit.
- What am I allergic to?
- Pine nuts.
And the full spectrum
of human emotion.
Oh, that's... that
was funny. [chuckles]
- Mmm-hmm.
- Umm...
Here's a good one.
Do I have any scars?
I'm pretty sure
that you have a tattoo.
Oh, you're pretty sure?
I'm pretty sure. Two years ago,
your dermatologist called
and asked about a
Q-switched laser.
I of course Googled
a Q-switched laser
and found that they
in fact do remove tattoos.
But you canceled
your appointment.
So what is it?
Tribal ink?
Japanese calligraphy?
Barbed wire?
You know, it's exciting for me
to experience you like this.
Thank you. You're gonna have to
tell me where it is, though.
- No, I'm not.
- They're gonna ask.
We're done with that question.
On to another question.
Let me see, let me see.
Oh, here's one. Whose place
do we stay at, yours or mine?
That's easy. Mine.
And why wouldn't
we stay at mine?
Because I live at
Central Park West.
And you probably live at some
squalid little studio apartment
with stacks of yellowed
Penguin Classics.
[woman on PA]
Ladies and gentlemen,
please fasten
your seat belts.
We are beginning our
descent into Juneau.
Juneau? I thought we
were going to Sitka.
- We are.
- How are we getting to Sitka?
- [rumbling]
- [rattling]
Whoa.
All right.
Here we go.
- Oh, there he is!
- Andrew!
- [woman shouting]
- [laughter]
Hi. Right this way...
- Hi!
- Oh...
- It's so good to see you!
- You're suffocating him, Grace.
- Come here.
- Hey, Gammy.
Ah, Gammy. How are
you doing? Where's Dad?
Oh, you know your father.
He's always working.
Never mind about him.
Where's your girl?
Uh, she's...
right there.
- [Gammy] Ah.
- [Andrew] There she is.
I guess the word "girl"
is inappropriate.
Annie.
- Hi!
- [Margaret] Hello.
- Margaret, this is my mom.
- Oh, hello.
Yeah, great.
This is my gammy, Annie.
- Pleasure.
- Well, hello there.
Now, do you prefer being called
Margaret or Satan's Mistress?
We've heard it
both ways.
[Gammy] Actually we've
heard it lots of ways.
She's kidding.
- Oh! Oh... OK.
- [chuckling]
Thank you so much
for...
allowing me to be a
part of this weekend.
Oh, you're welcome.
We're thrilled to have you.
Let's get you two
back to the fort.
- OK.
- [Gammy] Oh...
- It's so good to see you.
- [grunts] There we are.
[Margaret whispers] Andrew...
[slightly louder]
Andrew. Andrew!
[yelps] Please,
don't do that.
You didn't tell me about all
the family businesses, honey.
He was probably just
being modest, dear.
Oh.
What are we doing? Shouldn't we
check into our hotel right now?
Oh, we canceled
your reservation.
Family doesn't
stay at a hotel.
You're gonna
stay in our home.
Oh, great! Great.
- What?
- [grunts] God.
You're gonna wanna use
your legs to lift that one.
Andrew! Help her
with those.
I'd love to, but she
won't let me do anything.
She insists on
doing it all herself.
She's one of those...
she's a feminist.
[grunts]
Come on, sweetie.
[Gammy] You see the shoes
that broad was wearing?
This is the
last of 'em.
- Oh!
- Ooh.
- [Andrew] Five second rule.
- Got it!
That will
dry right off.
Psst! Psst! I'm not
getting on that boat.
You don't have to.
See you in a few days.
Psst! You know
I can't swim.
Hence, the boat.
Come on.
[Andrew] Come on.
Here we go.
Looking good, boss.
Take your time, though.
Shh.
She comes with
a lot of baggage.
Just gonna give you
a little hand here.
Hand off ass!
Off ass!
There you go.
You're there.
Congratulations. I'm a
hundred years old now.
[boat engine starting]
[Grace] Here we are.
We're home.
That is your home?
Who are you people?
[Margaret] Why did you
tell me you were poor?
[Andrew] I never said
I was poor.
But you never told
me you were rich.
I'm not rich.
My parents are rich.
OK, you know what? That's
something only rich people say.
[woman] Hey, Andrew!
Welcome home!
Hi! Mom, what is this?
Nothing. It's just a
little welcoming party.
Is that a crime?
Just 50 of our closest
friends and neighbors.
And all excited
to meet you.
- Oh, good. Good.
- Come on. Come on.
- A party?
- Yeah, I guess so.
Come on. Let's go. My grandma's
moving faster than you.
Put your back into it.
[# Michael Bublé:
I've Got You Under My Skin]
- [indistinct chatter]
- [laughter]
[woman] So nice to meet you,
Margaret. Welcome to Sitka.
Jill? Hi. Nice to
meet you. My pleasure.
Why didn't you tell me you were
some kind of Alaskan Kennedy?
How could I?
We were in the middle
of talking about you
for the last
three years.
OK, know what?
Timeout, OK?
This bickering Bickerson
thing has got to stop.
People need to think that we
are in love. So let's just...
That, that's no problem.
I can do that.
I can pretend to be the
doting fiancé. That's easy.
But for you,
it's going to require
that you stop snacking on
children while they dream.
Very funny. When are you going
to tell them we're engaged?
I'll pick the
right moment.
Hey, Andrew. Hi!
Mrs. McKittrick. How are you?
Nice to see you.
Nice to see you, Mr. McKittrick.
This is Margaret.
- Hi. Pleasure.
- Margaret!
Hi, how are you?
Pleasure.
So I always wanted to know,
what does a book editor do?
[man] That's a great
question, Louise.
I'm curious to know
the answer myself.
- Hello, Dad.
- Son.
This must be Maggie.
Uh, Margaret.
- Joe. Pleasure to meet you.
- Pleasure's mine.
So why don't you tell us
exactly what a book editor does.
Besides taking writers out
to lunch and getting bombed.
[Louise] Now that
sounds like fun.
No wonder you like
being an editor.
No, Louise.
Andrew's not an editor,
he's an editor's
assistant.
Maggie here
is the editor.
Margaret.
- So you're actually...
- Andrew's boss. Yeah.
Well.
How about that.
[Louise] Huh.
I think I'll
get a refill.
- Charming.
- # And I love you
under my skin #
That's a hell of a
first impression, Dad.
What the hell, Andrew?
You show up here after all this
time with this woman you hated
- and now she's your girlfriend?
- We just got here.
Can we wait two seconds
before we throw the
kitchen sink at each other?
Just never figured you for a guy
who slept his way to the middle.
Actually, I'll have you know
that that woman in there
is one of the most
respected editors in town.
She's your meal ticket,
and you brought her home
to meet your mother.
She's not my meal ticket, Dad.
She's my fiancée.
- What'd you say?
- You heard me.
I'm getting married.
- How are you?
- Good, good. Thank you.
Would you care for
some hors d'oeuvres?
No, I'm fine.
Thank you very much.
It's a tradition.
It's the texture.
I'm not a fish person.
- You'll like it.
- You're very sweet.
I think if you'll
just taste it.
[muffled]
Thank you so much.
[Andrew] Ladies
and gentlemen...
I have a very important
announcement to make.
Margaret and I
are getting married.
It's the paprika.
So sorry.
That's OK.
It's wash-and-wear.
[Andrew] Yep.
Honey? Where you at?
Here it is.
Come on down here,
pumpkin.
- [Andrew] All right.
- OK.
Oh, look at her.
Look at her.
[clapping]
Right there, ladies and
gentlemen. There she is.
[woman]
Congratulations, Andrew.
Thank you.
[Andrew]
Thank you very much.
- [woman] Time to celebrate.
- [woman #2] Get the champagne.
So that was your idea
of the perfect time
- to tell them we're engaged?
- Mmm.
'Cause it was brilliant.
Brilliant timing.
Andrew. Hi.
Gert? Oh, my God.
Hey, hi. Wow.
How you doing? I didn't know
that you were gonna be here.
Your mom probably wanted it to
be a surprise. So... surprise.
- Right.
- And...
...we're being
completely rude. Hi.
- [Andrew] Oh, God.
This is my ex...
- Hi. I'm Gertrude.
- Oh! Oh, wow. Wow!
- You can call me Gert.
Well, congratulations,
you guys.
- Thank you.
So did I
miss the story?
- What story?
About how you proposed.
Oh! How a man proposes says
a lot about his character.
- Yes.
- Yes, it does.
I actually would love
to hear the story, Andrew.
Would you tell us?
- [man] Yeah.
- [crowd murmurs] Yeah.
- [giggling]
- [Andrew] You know what?
Actually, Margaret loves
telling this story...
so I'm just gonna let her
go ahead and do that.
[Andrew] 'Cause I think we
should just sit in rapture.
Huh! Wow, OK.
Wow, where to begin...
this story.
Well... um, wow.
Mmm... yeah.
OK, well, um,
Andrew and I...
Andrew and I were
about to celebrate
- our first
anniversary together.
- [all] Aw...
And I knew that he'd been
itching to ask me to marry him.
And he was scared.
Like a little tiny bird.
So I started leaving him
little hints here and there...
...because I knew he wouldn't
have the guts to ask, but...
That's not exactly
how it happened.
- No? Hmm.
- No. No.
I mean, I picked up on
all her little hints.
This woman's about
as subtle as a gun.
- [all laugh]
- [Andrew] Yeah.
What I was worried
about was
that she might find
this little box...
Oh! The decoupage box
that he made
where he'd taken
the time to cut out
tiny, little pictures
of himself. Yes.
Just pasted all over the
box. Oh! So beautiful.
So I opened that beautiful,
little decoupage
and out fluttered these tiny,
little hand-cut heart confettis.
And once they cleared,
I looked down, and I saw...
...the most
beautiful, big...
...fat nothing.
No ring.
- No ring?
- What?
No. But inside that box...
...underneath
all that crap...
...there was a little
handwritten note...
with the address to
a hotel, date, and time.
Real Humphrey Bogart-type stuff.
[man] Yeah.
- Masculine.
- [grunts]
Anyway, naturally,
Margaret thought...
I thought he was
seeing someone else.
[crowd murmurs]
It was a terrible
time for me,
but I went to
that hotel anyway.
I went there and I
pounded on the door,
but the door was
already unlocked.
And as swung open that
door, there he was...
- Standing.
- Kneeling.
- Like a man.
- On a bed of rose petals,
in a tuxedo.
Your son. Your son.
And he was choking back
soft, soft sobs.
And when he held back the tears
and finally caught his breath,
he said to me...
"Margaret,
will you marry me?"
And she said, "Yep."
The end. Who's hungry?
[crowd cooing]
That is quite a story.
- [Gammy] Oh, Andy!
- Gorgeous.
You are so sensitive.
Hand-cut confetti?
[laughs]
Hey! Let's see a kiss
from you two cuties.
[man] Give her a kiss!
- No. Come on.
- Oh, yeah.
- Come on!
- [all cheering]
OK, all right.
OK. Here we go.
Ready?
What is this? Kiss her on
the mouth like you mean it.
- Kiss her. Kiss her!
- [all chanting] Kiss her!
Kiss her! Kiss her! Kiss her!
Kiss her!
OK!
- OK. All right.
- OK.
- Here we go.
- Mmm-hmm. OK.
- Oh!
- [chuckles]
Andy! Give her
a real kiss!
- [chuckling] Gammy.
- A real one!
- [woman] Yeah.
- [woman #2] You can do it!
Why don't we just do it?
Let's just do it really fast.
Yeah. OK.
- [both] Mmmm.
- [cheering]
- Mmm.
- Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
- [muffled] OK.
- Mmm.
Hmm.
I'm so happy
for you two!
So happy!
[woman] Let's get
the champagne!
So here we are.
This is your bedroom.
Wow. Wow, this is, um...
beautiful. And the view.
And here's the bed.
Wow! Exquisite bed.
Exquisite.
So... where is
Andrew's room?
Oh, sweetie, we're not
under any illusions
that you two don't
sleep in the same bed.
[laughing] He'll sleep
in here with you.
Oh, great, 'cause
we love to snuggle.
- Don't we, honey.
- We're huge snugglers.
- [barking]
- Oh, my God. What is it?
- Calm down, Kevin.
- Whoa! You are cute.
Who is this?
- That's Kevin.
I'm sorry, Margaret.
- So cute.
We just rescued him
from the pound,
and he's still in
training. Sorry.
Just be sure you don't
let him outside,
or the eagles
will snatch him.
No, don't you
listen to her.
She's just pulling
your leg, isn't she?
By the way, there are extra
towels and linens and things
in here
if you need them.
[Gammy] And if you
get chilly tonight...
...use this.
It has
special powers.
Oh, what kind of
special powers?
I call it
the Baby Maker.
OK, well.
Then I guess we...
...gonna be super careful
with that one.
- Yeah, I'm just gonna...
- Don't throw it on the bed.
We'd better turn in.
It's been quite an evening.
So good night,
everybody.
- Good night.
- Good night, Gammy.
- [chuckling] Good night.
- [Margaret] Good night.
- [Gammy] Good night.
- Good night, Gammy.
Thank you so much.
Sweet dreams.
- Bye-bye, now.
- Bye.
[Margaret] So, uh... you haven't
been home in a while.
I haven't had a lot of vacation
time the last three years.
[Margaret] Stop complaining.
Um...
Don't look, OK?
OK.
Are your eyes closed?
Completely.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
Those are the pajamas you
decided to bring to Alaska.
Yes, because I was supposed
to be in a hotel alone.
- Remember?
- Can we just go to sleep?
- Fine.
- Great.
[exhales, clears throat]
Well. [clears throat]
Looks like I won't be
getting much sleep
with the sun
streaming in.
Thank you.
[phone ringing]
[Margaret] Andrew. Phone.
Andrew!
Crap. Andrew,
Andrew, phone.
Andrew!
Yeah... right.
- Andrew, where is it?
- Purse, side pocket.
- [thumping]
- [grunting]
Hello. Hello? Hello.
Frank! Frank, darling.
Darling, Frank.
Are you there?
Hello? Hello? Oh, crap.
I have horrible service, Frank.
Give me just one minute.
Oh, my God!
Margaret!
[whispering] One... one minute.
Frank, hold on just a second.
Frank, hold on.
No, no, no, no.
[door shuts]
Frank. Frank,
I'm sorry you feel
I pressured you into
doing Oprah, but...
Of course I want you
to be happy. Yes, yes.
Frank. Frank. Frank, darling.
Frank? It's going to be fine.
I can just call them
and I can cancel.
[panting]
[Margaret] You are...
you are so right, Frank.
Yes, Frank, of course
I'm listening to you.
Yeah... yes.
I love listening
to you, Frank.
- [yapping]
- Shh! Sit. Sit.
No, not you, Frank.
- No, no.
- [barking]
Frank, if I may
get down to it, OK...
I think it would be
a mistake to back out.
- Because, Frank,
for so many years...
- [eagle screeching]
...you have inspired me
with your beautiful words,
- and I feel that...
- [barking]
Shh! Dog, I'm on the phone.
I think it's time that the world
get to enjoy your words as well.
- They are just so rich
with... passion...
- [dog barking]
And I think that we
should all be privy to.
- Frank, I just, uh...
- [screeching]
I just, uh, want you
to be happy, Frank.
Give me that dog!
Frank, hold on a second.
Can you hold a second?
Give me that dog!
Come on! Come on,
come on, come on.
- Come on! Come on! Oh, oh...
- [squeaking]
Oh, oh! Oh, oh.
OK! OK, gotcha.
Frank, Frank.
Frank? So sorry, so sorry.
So sorry. I dropped the phone.
Now, listen, Frank.
I don't want to
sell you on anything,
but this is your
legacy, this book.
And I think
it's up to you to
present your legacy
to the world.
And call me tomorrow
with your decision.
And my phone is on
all the time! OK, bye-bye.
No! Wait!
No! No! N-n-n... no. No
Take the doggy.
Look at the doggy.
I need that phone.
Take the dog.
I need that phone!
Here. Take the dog.
Take the dog. Take it. Take it.
[Grace] Look at this.
[both laughing]
- Is that cute or what?
- I know.
Morning, guys.
Have you seen... daah.
She's playing with Kevin.
We thought she didn't like him.
Will you
go get her, Andy?
We have a whole day
planned for her,
and she needs
to get ready.
Yeah. Tell her we have
a big surprise for her.
Mmm.
Look! Give me my phone. Come on.
Please, just give me my phone.
- Come on. Right here.
- What the hell are you doing?
Oh, my God. Your grandmother
was completely right.
The eagle came and
tried to take the dog.
But then I saved him. Then it
came back, and it took my phone.
- Are you drunk?
- What? No! I'm serious.
He's got my phone, and Frank's
calling me on that phone.
Relax, all right? We'll order
another phone, same number.
We'll go into town
tomorrow and get it.
- Really?
- OK? Yeah.
- Oh, OK. All right.
Well, you go then.
- [barks]
- You have to get ready.
- For what?
You're going out
with Mom and the girls.
I don't want to go out.
Shopping, sightseeing.
And a surprise.
- I hate shopping.
- You'll love it.
- I hate sightseeing.
- You're going.
- No, I don't want to go.
- I'm not going. I'm not going.
- Yes, you are.
Now give me a nice big hug.
We don't want them
- to think we're fighting.
- I don't want to touch you.
- Come on. Hug time.
- No, I don't want to...
- Hug time.
- I don't want to...
There we go.
Yeah, that's nice.
Yeah. That's nice.
There we go.
Isn't that nice?
- Mmm-hmm.
- [Andrew] Mmm-hmm.
- [Margaret] Mmm. Yeah.
- [Andrew] Boop boop boop.
If you touch my ass
one more time,
I will cut your balls
off in your sleep. OK?
- Yeah.
- There you go.
All righty now. So, uh...
We clear on that?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Such a good fiancé.
Hmm. Ow.
[splashing]
- [Joe] Jeez.
- You want to see me?
Your mom found
these eco-balls.
They dissolve in water.
[grunts]
I don't know how she
comes up with this stuff.
Anyway, she, uh...
is a little peeved.
Apparently, I wasn't the most
gracious of hosts last night.
It was a little
bit of a shock
to find out that
you're getting married...
...especially when none of us
even knew you were dating.
The point is...
I owe you an apology.
Accepted.
There's something else.
I've been going over my
retirement plans recently,
and it got me
thinking.
I've done a lot
of things in my life.
Practically built an empire with
your mother from the ground up.
It doesn't mean
anything unless...
Unless you have
someone to leave it to.
- We already discussed this.
- I'd like to discuss it again.
You have
responsibilities here.
I think I've been
more than understanding
about your goofing off
in New York.
I need you to quit
playing around...
Here we go again.
When are you going to start
taking what I do seriously?
When you start
acting seriously.
I'm sorry.
I feel sorry for you, Dad.
I wish you had
another son. I really do.
One who wanted
to stay here.
One who wanted to take over
the family business.
One who wanted
to marry someone
that you approve of,
but it's not me. Now,
it must seem strange to you,
my life in New York... sitting
in an office, reading books.
But it makes me happy.
You understand?
If that's what makes you happy,
son, I got nothing to say.
Well, that's a first.
You know what? Apology not
accepted. Have fun out here.
[sniffs]
[indistinct chatter]
[Grace] There is no way you
could leave her at home.
She had to be here.
Absolutely.
She's been
coming here forever.
I hope you are ready
for your big surprise...
...because this is one of
Sitka's greatest treasures.
- Right?
- Oh, yes. Oh, yeah.
[# Frankie Goes to Hollywood:
Relax]
[Grace] OK, this is
the big surprise
I was telling you
about. You ready?
[whistling]
[Gammy] Oh, Margaret,
you're gonna love it!
[women cheering]
# Whoa #
# When you wanna come #
[women screaming]
# Relax don't do it #
# When you wanna go to it #
# When you wanna come #
# Relax don't do it #
# When you wanna
suck it to it #
# Relax don't do it #
# When you wanna come #
Ramone's the only
exotic dancer on the island.
[Gammy] But we're
lucky to have him.
# Relax don't do it #
# When you wanna go to it #
Work it, Ramone!
[woman shouting]
- Wow.
- Over here, Ramone! Over here.
[Gammy] Over here, honey.
# When you wanna come #
[Gammy] Show her what
she's gonna be missing.
Come,
my sexy princess.
- Yeah!
- [Margaret]
Oh, no. Not necessary.
It's a really nice gesture,
but I really need to just...
[Gammy] Go on,
Margaret. Get up there!
You come dance.
OK, pluck my eyes out.
OK.
- All right. Here we go.
- [cheering]
[women] Go, Margaret!
Go, Margaret!
[laughing]
Hey.
Hey... oh.
[Gammy] Give it
to her, Ramone!
[cheering louder]
[Gert] Go on, Ramone!
Give it to her!
[women screaming]
Ooh, that's a move
I haven't seen.
- [Gammy] Look at her face!
- [all laughing]
[Ramone] Guess who.
For you. For you. For you.
- [Gert] Yeah!
- [Ramone] Enjoy!
I don't want to touch it.
No. OK, OK. Very sweet.
No, no, no, no, no.
Smack him!
- I'm sorry?
- Smack his ass.
Smack it. OK.
- Smack him, Margaret!
- [woman] Give it to him!
Yeah! Woo!
[Margaret]
Can I get down now?
[giggling]
Free. Be free.
Hey! There you are.
How are you holding up?
Oh, fine. Fine.
Just working on my tan.
Yeah, the Paxtons can be
a bit overwhelming at times.
Yes, yes.
It's a little different
than New York, huh?
Little bit. Little bit.
You ever been?
No. That was always
Andrew's dream, not mine.
You guys were
pretty serious, huh?
Well, I mean, we dated in high
school and all through college,
but we were kids.
And you guys called
it off because of...
Well, um...
the night before we graduated
school, he proposed...
...and said he
wanted to elope
and run away to
New York with me.
And...
You said "no."
And I said "no," yeah.
I've never been anywhere
but here. This is home.
But anyway...
you're a lucky girl.
He really is the best, which
you obviously already know.
Oh, yep.
Yep, very much so, yeah.
Well, cheers to you guys.
Oh... Thank you.
[# MC Hammer: U Can't Touch This
playing inside]
[women shouting]
Looks like Ramone's
wrappin' it up. [laughs]
Go, Annie!
[hoots]
I've never
seen him so...
- No, he really got down.
- ...out there. I mean...
- [Gammy giggling]
- He was wonderful.
Oh, no.
[# Living Colour: Cult of
Personality through headphones]
[Grace shouting]
Andrew!
Andrew, honey,
is everything OK?
What...
What's he doing?
Something's up. It's best
to leave him alone.
Come on, honey.