ANNOUNCER:
The following program
is brought to you
in living color on NBC.
(fanfare plays)
(sheep bleating)
(shouts):
Hello, Annie!
- (sheep bleating)
- Annie!
Whoo!
(excited bleating)
Don't run away now.
Albie isn't gonna hurt you.
(bleating)
You're real purdy.
LITTLE JOE:
Albie!
Why, hello there, Little Joe.
Now, leave her alone, Albie.
You're scaring her.
Now, what are you doing
up here on the mountain?
Just on my way
to Placerville.
Come on, Albie,
you're hurting her.
Oh, I'm the only friend
she's got up here.
Ain't I, Annie?
Leastwise, she don't give me no
back talk like the other women.
She's not an animal
in one of your traps.
Now, let her go.
I ain't hurting her--
I was just saying hello.
Oh, you better not hurt her.
Not ever.
ALBIE:
You don't belong up here.
This ain't your country.
Best you mind your own business.
You bother Annie,
I'll make it my business.
(sheep bleating)
This is my country,
and I'm gonna see
it stays that way.
(theme song playing)
(sheep bleating)
(bleating)
Come on, stop working
so hard, Sam.
You got company.
Oh. Sorry, Little Joe.
I got a touch of fever.
Figured this might...
sweat it out of me.
Eh, feeling any better?
Hey, I brought you that
gun barrel Pa said you needed.
And I got a little present
for Annie.
(chuckles) Waste of time,
bringing her anything.
Just... leave her be.
(chuckles)
Hey, Sam, look.
She's pretending she's a tree.
Foolishness.
Can't hear, can't talk,
don't understand no more than
them dumb beasts she tends.
No use bringing her presents,
Little Joe.
Aw, come on, Sam.
Anybody understands
getting a present.
Suit yourself.
Getting on towards dinner.
You're welcome to share it,
such as it is.
Thank you.
Look, I, uh... I brought you
a little present.
Hey, wait a second,
let me get it.
Uh... I thought I'd bring it
as long as I was coming.
It's not much.
Well, go on,
it's not gonna bite you.
Well, come on, take it,
it's for you.
Here, wait a second.
Here.
It's not much, just...
just a rag doll.
Hey... don't worry,
I'm not gonna take it back.
Yeah, well, you...
y-you go right ahead
and enjoy it.
So long.
I'll-I'll see you.
Yeah, so long.
It's good talking to you,
Little Joe.
Man gets out of the habit
with nobody around to listen.
Why do you stay up here, Sam?
It's best.
Yeah, maybe it's best for you,
but what about Annie?
Must be something
terrible wrong with a man
to father a child like her.
Killed her ma,
bringing her into the world.
I reckon it ain't
too much punishment
for me to raise her.
It was just an accident
the way she was born.
It's not your fault.
No more!
I won't hear no more about her.
Not from you, not nobody.
Okay, Sam.
I'll help you move
the rest of those sheep
before I start out
for Placerville.
- (sheep bleating)
- LITTLE JOE: Come on!
(Little Joe groans)
I never knew a couple dozen
sheep could be so ornery.
They're almost as bad as people.
You know, it's funny.
You know, I've been talking
to you all day, and...
I know you can't hear
a word I'm saying.
Hey, what are you
looking at now?
Hey...
that's what I call
a right pretty girl.
Hey, look over here.
That fella right there, that's
that handsome Joe Cartwright.
This is the guy that's always
watching me when I'm shaving.
I just can't seem
to get rid of him.
(Little Joe laughs)
All right, what are you trying
to fool me with now?
What have you got
behind your back?
Yeah, that...
that's real beautiful.
That sure is pretty.
I guess you don't need to know
how to talk to say everything.
Thanks.
I-I wish I could...
make you understand.
Hey, look.
Look, I'm-I'm trying
to tell you I like it.
Thank you.
(dog barking in distance)
- Oh, howdy, Preacher.
- Albie.
It's good to see you again.
Thank you, Albie.
You been walking
in the way of the Lord?
Well, I-I've been doing
a lot of walking.
Uh, say, you were
up here near spring
the last time you came by here.
I guess it was.
You dropping in on Sam, too?
Well, you don't think
I'd be swapping tales
and telling news
with that Annie?
She's a child of God, son,
for all the way he made her.
Reckon that's a fact, Preacher.
How about you?
About time you married
and raised a family, isn't it?
Plenty of unmarried girls
in town.
Town girl once said I had
the smell of a trapper on me.
It's like...
meat that's not cured right.
You'll find the right girl
soon enough.
Come on, now.
The word of the Lord
will calm your mind...
and your soul.
"For thou writest
bitter things against me
and will consume me
for the sins of my youth."
Amen.
I'm paying for my sins,
Preacher. Paying.
You, Sam? That why you're always
getting them chills and fever?
Every man is tempted
by the devil, Albie.
♪♪
No, Albie,
hearing the word of God
is man's only salvation.
SAM:
True, Preacher, true.
If I could only
read the Lord's word...
I could bear up
under his suffering.
Uh, even if'n
you could read, Sam,
who would you read it to?
Getting cramps,
sitting all this time.
Think I'll go out for a while.
(door closes)
"Man born of woman,
living a short life,
"is filled with many miseries.
"Who will make him clean
that is conceived
of unclean seed?"
♪♪
Now, don't be scared.
It's just Albie.
What else you got there, huh?
Let Albie see it.
Come on, let me see it.
I ain't going to take it.
Oh, it's a button, huh?
I guess you ain't got much
that's better, have you, huh?
(clatters)
No matter what you are,
you sure are pretty.
Look, you must get
lonesome, too.
Look, I'm try--just trying
to be nice to you, that's all.
Come on, come on.
I've been trapping
for over a week.
A man likes a woman
to be waiting when he gets back.
Come on.
Come on!
What are you, some sort of stick
of wood or something?
Come on.
You can't hear, you can't talk.
Haven't you got any feelings?
Now, that's not so bad now,
is it, huh?
PREACHER:
Albie, where are you?
You in there in that shed?
Coming, Preacher.
I'm not finished with you yet.
I'll be back.
(door opens)
What are you doing
in that shed, Albie?
Well, I'm just helping Sam catch
up with his chores, Preacher.
Oh, that's good of you, Albie.
Sam's got a lot of fever.
Be a good idea if you
stop around whenever you can.
Don't worry, Preacher.
I'm going to be around
a lot more now.
Good.
(coins clinking)
What you doing here, girl?
You should be out
with the sheep.
What are you hiding?
Out with it, girl.
I've warned you.
Never touch me money pouch.
Corrupted by a present.
You've done an evil thing.
You must be punished.
At least if you can't hear,
I know you can feel.
I take no joy in hurting you.
I'm your father.
It's my duty to teach you
right and wrong
as best I can.
Thou shalt not steal.
Ah.
Don't look at me
with them sad eyes.
I can't stand to see suffering
written on your face
and not a word
coming from your tongue,
not even sobbing.
Put it back,
so you'll remember,
never do it again.
(door closes)
♪♪
(thunder rumbling)
Hey, Sam!
Sam Croft!
Hey, wait till you see what
I brought you from Placerville.
Come on.
It's really for you anyway, Ann.
Wait till you see what it is.
See, I got to talking
to this doctor in Placerville
and I told him all about you,
and he gave me this.
Here, here, take it.
Hey, Sam!
Sam!
It's a... it's a book
of sign language,
a-and you can learn to talk
once you...
once you understand these signs.
It's not hard either
'cause I learned a whole bunch
of 'em on the way out here.
Yeah, sure, you-you don't even
know what I'm talking about.
Here, come on, come on.
Now, listen.
You can learn to talk
and to hear
just like other people.
(thunder cracks)
Only with these...
with your hands.
Well, let me see
how I'm going to do this.
First page.
Now, now, look.
A flower.
See the picture?
A flower, just like the picture.
(sniffs)
Ah.
A flower, you see?
(sniffs)
Flower--this is the sign.
Flower.
Now you do it.
All right, watch me once more.
Flower.
(sniffs)
Just like you were smelling
a real nice flower.
(sniffs)
(Ann sniffs)
What's the matter?
(chuckles)
Look, there's-there's nothing
in my hand.
I'm not trying to fool you.
F-Forget that.
We'll go-go to another one.
(thunder cracks)
Girl.
You.
Girl, 'c-c-cause your cheek's
real, real nice and soft.
G-Give me your hand.
See, just like that.
Girl, gi...
Wow.
Boy... boy.
(clicks tongue)
Just like tipping my hat--
a boy--
like I tip, tip my hat.
(thunder cracks)
You don't understand, do you?
(sniffs)
This is gonna be a lot tougher
than I thought.
I can't make it any plainer.
I don't know
why you can't understand it.
(sniffs)
That's it!
That's it.
What's this for?
Oh, Annie.
Look, this isn't
some kind of a game.
I'm doing my best to...
to teach you this sign language.
(thunder cracks)
Look, I want you
to be able to talk
and to understand people
when they talk to you.
Can't you see that?
No, I guess you never will.
(thunderclap)
You couldn't hear that.
Why, of course.
Of course, you feel it!
Here.
Here, you feel that?
That's what talking is.
Feel it.
Here.
Feel the ground.
Look, you can talk like that.
(thunder cracks)
Look!
(thunderclap)
See that? I'm talking to you
with my hands.
That's it!
That's it, you understand.
You do understand.
That's girl.
Boy.
Boy--tipping your hat.
A beautiful flower.
(thunder rumbling)
There isn't a person
who can talk or hear
that could ever understand
the way you feel.
I'm so happy.
It's raining.
(thunder rumbling)
Rain.
Rain, just... just like
the drops coming down.
Come on.
Let's go inside.
You want to learn it all?
All right, you will.
It'll take time
and it'll take work,
but you will.
(thunderclap)
You trying to tell me
that there's any hope
when I've lived my whole life
with the weight of her
pressing on me heart
like a stone.
Yeah, well, you watch, Sam.
You see for yourself.
Now, you are going to talk
to your father.
Understand?
Boy.
Girl.
Flower.
Book.
That ain't talking.
That's just like Indian sign.
That's right.
That's right, only better.
You're a fool, Little Joe.
She's just waving
her arms around.
How do you know she understands
what she's doing?
See for yourself,
she understands.
All right.
You know what them signs mean,
do you?
You, girl.
He, boy.
What am I?
What am I?!
Stop scaring her, Sam.
I tell you, she does understand.
No.
No, no!
She's not an animal, Sam.
Help her.
Bring her to town
if you don't believe me.
Let the doctor see her.
SAM: No doctor can give
that poor girl
what she was robbed of at birth.
She'll never change.
She can learn to understand,
but not if you don't help her.
Not if you don't
give her a chance.
Oh.
Sam.
Look at her. She's talking
to you with her hands.
She's telling you
she went out into the rain
and got the book.
Now do you believe me?
She's not one
of your sheep, Sam.
She's your daughter.
(metal clanging)
Whoa. Whoa.
Now, you wait here.
I'll see if the doc's in.
(metal clanging)
MAN: Hyah!
Hyah!
Hyah! Hyah!
Ann!
- Hyah!
- Look out!
Get out of the way!
Oh. Ann!
Ann, you near got killed.
Ain't that the old coot
who lives up in the mountains?
Yeah. Sam Croft.
He only comes down
about twice a year.
You know, I-I thought
he lived by hisself.
He-He's been holding out on us.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, Sam Croft.
Now where did you get a pretty
little thing like her, huh?
You been holding out
on us, Sam?
Uh, what do you want, Tom?
Well, you went out
and got yourself
a little company, huh?
She's-she's my daughter.
Who you trying to fool?
Leave us alone.
Has old Sam
been treating you right?
Hmm?
Well, what do you say?
I'm talking to you.
She... she don't talk
much to strangers.
Well, now how come?
Is she too good
for fellas like us, huh?
Yeah, let me get
a good look at her.
Now let go!
Give-give me that!
You want it, Sam?
Well, you got to come
and take it.
SAM:
Uh, uh, please, leave us alone.
We ain't doing you no harm.
Now, Sam,
if the girl wants her bonnet,
let her ask for it
real pretty-like, huh?
Now, I bet
I can make you talk to us.
No, leave her alone.
Leave her alone. Oh.
Whoa, there, Sam,
where you going?
LITTLE JOE:
Leave him alone!
It's only that old
mountain goat Sam Croft.
Get out of here.
Come on, Pappy.
(chuckles)
He ain't worth shooting.
Aw, we just having a little fun.
You both all right?
Well, we ain't hurt.
Good. Come on, Sam,
the doctor's in.
No, we ain't going to no doctor.
We shouldn't have come here
in the first place.
Shouldn't have listened to you.
What's the matter?
What are you talking about?
We belong in the mountains,
me and the girl both.
We ain't fit for no town
and the town ain't fit for us.
Sam, for once,
think of what's right for Ann.
That's who I'm thinking of.
Now, get out of my way.
How's it coming along, son?
You know, you've been spending
much more time up at the Crofts'
these past few months than here.
Pa, you just
wouldn't believe it.
Why, Ann's learned
so much already.
We can carry on
a regular conversation.
Uh, how's Sam Croft?
Still as stubborn
about it as ever?
That man's impossible.
He told me he'd never let her
see the doctor, not ever.
Sure hope I can get him
to change his mind.
Joe...
You don't think you're, uh...
over your head?
What do you mean?
Well, sometimes it's best
not to push people too hard.
Leave well enough alone.
Why should I leave him alone?
He's not gonna help her.
Somebody has to.
Yeah, I know.
Sometimes helping
looks like meddling.
Don't worry, Pa,
I know the difference.
Joe, take care of yourself
up there.
- (door opens)
- Sure, I will, Pa.
(door closes)
Sam?
Sam, you in there?
Oh, there you are.
I was awful lonely
out on the traps.
What's that,
a new kind of game, huh?
You want me to play
a little game with you, huh?
I got ya!
Ol' Albie's missed you a lot
but he's gonna make it
all up to you.
Now, Sam, there's no need
to bring a gun up on me.
Get away from her.
And keep away!
I don't see you running
Joe Cartwright off of here,
or maybe you think
he's a better man than I am.
Joe Cartwright's
teaching her to talk!
I'll bet you
he's teaching her to talk.
Move or I'll blow
your head off!
All right.
All right, Sam.
Just remember,
with all that money
and all them girls in town,
Joe Cartwright ain't interested
in marrying anyone like Annie.
(Little Joe laughs)
All right,
this is last one for today.
This is going to be a tough one.
Love. Love.
Your father...
helps you.
gives you food.
You... live...
in your father's house.
You love your father.
Your father loves you.
Uh...
Let me see.
I can say, uh...
you love flowers.
Then you'd know
that it was good.
I teach you to talk, yeah.
(chuckles):
No. No, no, you...
That's wrong.
See, you don't love me.
Now that is wrong.
You don't love me.
Now look, you don't love me!
You don't love me,
and I don't love you!
Oh, Annie...
Annie, I'm... I'm sorry.
Please, I...
I-I didn't want to hurt you.
Annie, please look at...
(dog barking in distance)
(chickens clucking)
All-all of a sudden,
for no reason,
she-she tried to kiss me.
She tried to kiss you?
She did kiss me,
as a matter of fact.
I guess she got upset,
and she ran away.
I should have been watching you
all along.
You should have been
watching me?
watching me?!
You should have been
helping me teach her...
instead of being
so stubborn!
Teaching her what?
Kissing? All kinds of sin?
You keep away from her.
All right, Sam.
All right,
I'll keep away from her.
You're her father.
You try teaching her
for a change.
(hoofbeats receding)
(sighs)
Good-bye,
Little Joe Cartwright.
Ann! Ann!
Hello, Sam.
I'm looking for Ann.
I told you I didn't like
a gun thrown on me.
How's it feel?
Where's Ann?
Have you got her?
No, I ain't got her,
but I will have
after you meet with an accident.
You see, Sam,
I'm going to be a hero.
I'm gonna take care of Annie
after you die in an accident.
(Sam screams)
So you just walked out?
Well, what was I supposed to do?
She completely misunderstood.
Oh, and then her father.
I go in and I try
to explain it to him,
and he starts... starts accusing
me of all kinds of things.
It's really funny, he doesn't
try to help her himself.
You insisted
on starting this.
You can't walk out
before you finish it.
I understand that--
I'm not a little kid.
Aren't you?
If you understand it
and still walk out,
then you're just a little kid.
Now wait a minute!
Don't you raise your voice
to me, boy.
Then don't you call me
a little kid.
Joe...
you opened a door
to the world for this girl.
You let her look out
for the first time.
Now, her gratitude for you
must be overwhelming,
to say the least.
All right, fine! Fine!
All I was trying to do
was help her.
You can't shove someone
into the water
and then not wait around
to see if they can swim.
She has a father!
No! You started it.
You were the one who tampered
with those two lives
and you can't
abandon them now.
Well, what do you want me to do,
marry her?!
Help me, Pa.
I don't know what to do.
Go back.
No, I can't.
I can't go back there
and hurt her anymore.
You must make her understand
that what she feels for you
is gratitude, not love.
Oh, she'll be hurt a little bit,
but she'll get over it.
If you don't go back,
she'll remain hurt forever.
I think I'll go for a ride.
(door opens, closes)
(weakly):
I can't hardly feel nothing.
What's to become of you, Ann?
I've kept you up here, hidden.
Ashamed of me own
flesh and blood.
Forgive me, daughter,
if you can.
I love you, Ann.
I always did.
(shallow breathing)
Well, I knew you'd be back
sooner or later.
You still playing games
with me?
I'm going to teach you more
than Joe Cartwright ever did.
You're worried about your pa?
Your pa ain't coming back.
You're gonna stay with me.
All right now, look,
now, just take it easy.
You be nice to Albie, and Albie
is gonna be nice to you.
I'll even buy you a new dress.
(Albie laughs)
(no audio)
(clattering)
Come back!
There ain't no place to go!
(frogs croaking)
(distant coyotes howling)
(panting)
Annie!
Annie.
Annie, Annie, what happened?
Look at me!
Look at me.
What happened?
Your father... hurt.
LITTLE JOE:
Needs help. Where?
He fell.
Stay out of this, Cartwright.
You do this to her, Albie?
What's she trying to tell you?
What happened to Sam?
What are you talking about?
Annie says Sam's been hurt.
Now, don't fool with me.
You know she can't talk.
Can't she, Albie?
(grunting)
(Little Joe cries out)
(blows landing)
(grunting)
(sighs)
(Albie grunts)
Well, what did the doctor say?
Well, he said he'd be all right,
but he'll need a lot of care.
(sighs with relief)
Did you, uh...
Have you spoken to her yet
about...?
Yeah.
Good.
You'd better tell her
her father will be all right.
Right.
Your father...
be all right.
Doctor says...
your father be all right.
What...? What'd she say?
She said she'd help you
and take care of you.
She says she loves you
very much.
Joe?
Yeah?
What's the sign for daughter?
It's easy.
ANNOUNCER: This has been
a color presentation
of the NBC Television Network.