[KETTLE WHISTLING]
[SIGHS]
[KETTLE STOPS WHISTLING]
Hi.
I didn't think you were ever gonna wake up.
- You want a cup of tea?
WALT: Uh...
No. No, no, no. Tea, no.
Uh... No, coffee. I got some, uh...
A good coffee from Sumatra or something.
Let me just, um...
- It's, uh...
- Okay, coffee then.
Yeah, it's good coffee. You, uh...
- Trust me, you don't want that tea.
- Okay. No tea.
You're an excellent salesman, Walton.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
Was it a bad idea, me staying here?
You seem weird.
- No.
- No?
No, it seemed silly for you
to, uh, drive all the way home...
...after you, you know,
dropped me off, so...
It feels weird.
I mean, last night
felt kind of like high school. Heh.
Only without the sex. Heh.
Oh, God. Do you want me to leave?
No, um... Do you wanna go?
No.
WALT: Heh-heh.
- Good. Heh.
[CAR APPROACHING]
- Let that steep for four minutes.
- Okay. All right.
Hi.
I've never been out here before.
God, it's amazing.
- Is all this yours?
- Vic, uh, what are you doing here?
Uh, Ferg got your Bronco fixed.
I'm gonna give him a ride home.
- Anyway, thanks for coming by, so...
- Whose car?
I rented it.
You rented that?
LIZZIE:
Hi there.
- Lizzie, hi. Hi, Lizzie.
- Hey.
Heh-heh. What are you, um...?
You want some coffee?
Walt says it's really good.
VIC:
I would love some coffee.
- Okay.
- Vic's gotta get back to work, so...
FERG:
Morning, sheriff.
Ah... So I, uh,
took all the dents out of here...
...I buffed up the side and I repainted...
Morning, Ferg. Heh-heh-heh.
I'll get two cups.
If anybody has got something
they wanna say...
...I suggest you think twice about it.
[PHONE RINGS]
WOMAN [ON RECORDING]:
You've reached the Longmire residence.
Sorry we're not here to take your call.
Please leave a message.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
WALT:
Hello?
BRANCH [OVER PHONE]: Walt, it's Branch.
Don't hang up. This is about work.
Would've called someone else,
but I couldn't find anyone.
BRANCH:
Mountain bikers found the body.
You're not gonna believe this.
Is that an arrow?
Like, a bow-and-arrow arrow?
BRANCH:
Graphite shaft. Broadhead tip.
Went all the way through
and into the back of the chair.
FERG: Hey, check out this drawing
on his forehead.
It looks like Sharpie.
That's not coming off.
Got a little pot,
probably just for personal use.
- Any ID on him?
- Don't need it.
- We know who this is.
- Who?
Greg Morris, Richard Stark, Jake Lennox
and Paul Carter.
On the count of first
degree sexual assault...
...we find the defendants not guilty.
[CHATTERING]
- You think this is related to the trial?
WALT: That was over a year ago.
- This could be any number of things.
- What trial?
Don't you think it's a little odd
the murder weapon's a bow and arrow?
With an Indian symbol
drawn on his forehead?
Odd, yeah, but it doesn't prove anything.
We should do our work
before we form an opinion about suspects.
- You gonna notify Greg's parents?
- Who's Greg?
- Is this Greg?
- [WHISPERING] Tell you later.
I don't think his family's
gonna wanna hear from me.
Especially news like this.
I think you should take that one.
That's a good idea.
WALT: Vic, you and Ferg need
to tape this scene off.
Comb over the whole area.
Find out if we're dealing
with an amateur or a pro.
I better head to the res.
Uh, I still don't know
what the hell is going on.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- Hi, Walt.
- Ayasha.
I didn't think you were ever
gonna come visit again.
Well, I've been very busy, so...
- Catching the bad guys.
- I'm trying to.
- Is your grandma home?
- She's asleep.
Viho, if you wouldn't mind
waking her up...
...I need to talk to all of you, so...
- Do you want me to make lemonade?
- Why not?
FERG:
So this girl, Ayasha Roundstone...
...she's got developmental problems.
I guess, uh, she had fetal alcohol syndrome
when she was born.
Anyway, she said that these four boys
from high school, they, you know...
- Raped her.
- Yeah.
So then shish-kebab guy down there,
our victim...
Greg. Yeah.
He was one of the rapists.
So this is probably a revenge killing.
There were a lot of people on the res,
pretty angry.
Still are.
We found Greg Morris this morning.
He's been killed.
- One down, three to go.
- Viho.
- You want me to pretend to be sad?
- I want you to show respect.
Go ahead and ask your questions.
See, that's why he's here, Grandma.
- He thinks I did this.
WALT: I don't think anything yet, Viho.
- But I have a job to do.
- I hope you do a better job this time.
VIC: So, what, did Walt screw up the trial
or something?
FERG:
No, no. He did everything he could.
All while his wife
was going through chemo.
Those four boys come from rich families.
- They had a good lawyer.
- Good lawyer, unreliable witness...
- They didn't even get probation.
- Ugh.
WALT: So where were you last night?
- I was here.
- Can you confirm that, Elsie?
- I wasn't home. I work nights.
But Viho is not a liar.
Ask Ayasha, she was here.
She can vouch for me.
Oh, yeah, that's right, I forgot.
She's not a credible witness.
Hey, Ferg, check it out.
FERG:
Ooh, gum wrapper.
Still minty.
Looks like we found
where our shooter was hiding.
Let's measure the distance.
[WALT GRUNTS]
[GRUNTS]
Are you the sheriff?
WALT:
How can I help?
I just got into town about an hour ago
and I got a question.
Where are all the black people?
[LAUGHING]
I'm just messing with you, man.
I'm Detective Fales. Denver P.D.
[FALES CHUCKLING]
Been trying to talk to you for months,
but you don't seem to like the phone...
...so I thought I'd drive up
and talk to you in person.
You're a hard man to find,
Sheriff Longmire.
- Well, you found me.
FALES: Yeah, I guess I did.
And I only need
a few minutes of your time.
WALT:
Well, it's, uh...
It's kind of a bad day.
Things are kind of crazy around here.
I get it, I grew up in a small town.
Smaller than this.
Appearances can be deceiving.
How's that hotel over there?
It looks charming.
WALT:
It is.
I'll go over
and see if they've got a room...
...stick around until things calm down
for you and you're ready to talk.
Tomorrow. That a good time for you?
Talk to Ruby. She runs my life, so...
I've already talked to Ruby, sheriff.
Plenty of times.
What I need is to talk to you.
Have Ruby call me at the hotel
and get me on your calendar.
Okay.
Just so you know...
...we found the man
that killed your wife.
It took you long enough.
Henry, that detective
from Denver's here...
...so I think you and I need to talk.
Call me back.
Well, a little rusty. That's about
a 20-yard shot with a recurve bow.
Arrow speeds can get up
to about 180 feet per second.
Now, how deep did that arrow
go into that boy?
- It went all the way through him. OMAR:
Your killer wasn't shooting a recurve.
Probably a compound bow.
Now, those arrow speeds
can get up to 300 feet per second.
VIC: What's with the pulleys?
- Compound bow. Easier to shoot.
- So, uh, how far away was your shooter?
- About 40 yards.
So how good a shot
are we talking about?
OMAR: Well, let's see,
Vickie's never shot before.
That is the second and last time
you will ever call me that.
Here we go, right through there.
That middle target's about 40 yards out.
Let's see how you do.
- See these marks?
- Yeah.
OMAR: Those are your aiming pins.
It's got about a 50-pound draw-pull.
- First few inches are tough and then...
- Unh! Now it's like nothing.
OMAR:
When you're ready, release.
Whoa. That's pretty good.
OMAR: That's the great thing
about the compound bow.
The great equalizer.
With a little bit of practice,
even a girl could make that shot.
So you're saying just about anybody
could be our shooter.
Sheriff, uh, Cady called twice.
No message.
Henry called once,
uh, said you'd know what that was about.
And, uh, that Detective, uh, Fales
from the Denver P.D. Stopped by.
- Who's Detective Fales?
WALT: Thank you.
- You, uh, notify Greg's parents, Branch?
- Uh, I did. Check this out.
It's Greg's car. A month ago, someone
vandalized it. Recognize that symbol?
Same as on Greg's forehead.
They have any idea who painted that?
Well, they're pretty sure
it's Viho Roundstone.
- They got any proof of that?
BRANCH: No, but apparently...
...Viho's been giving all the boys
a hard time. Phone calls, threats...
I think we gotta bring him in.
Arrest him?
Based on the suspicions
of Greg Morris' parents?
I don't think so.
I disagree.
Those boys are in danger.
Noted.
I wanted you to know that, uh,
we found Greg Morris' body this morning.
- Are you screwing with us?
- I wish I was. Jake.
Any reason you know of that, uh,
Greg was in the ski basin?
- It's been closed for the season.
- Uh...
We used to party up there.
- A lot of kids go up there still.
- Were you up there last night?
You know,
I don't think I like your tone, sheriff.
It kind of sucks.
I just lost a friend
and you're acting like it's my fault.
If I recall, you were all very tight.
No one made a move
without talking to you.
You're freaking me out.
Do you have any leads?
We're pursuing all leads and possibilities.
You know what Greg was doing
at the ski area last night, Rich?
I wouldn't know anything about that.
I was home studying.
This have anything to do with the case?
- How do you mean?
- You know damn well what I mean.
Say what you mean,
I promise not to miss it.
The Indians.
They might be coming for us.
My son was found innocent,
yet the brother of that girl...
...he's been harassing my son.
PAUL:
A few months ago, he spray-painted my car.
Some kind of Indian symbol.
Like a cave painting.
Why didn't you report it?
ALLEN:
We didn't think you'd do anything about it.
Tell me now,
you gonna arrest that Indian?
WALT: So this, uh, detective from Denver
says they found him.
HENRY:
How does he know it is him?
I don't know.
- I didn't ask.
- You should have.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS OVER SPEAKERS]
You should ask him
for every bit of information he has.
That is what a normal person would do
in your situation.
There's nothing normal
about my situation, Henry.
I am talking about not attracting
unnecessary attention by acting oddly.
- Henry, should I be worried?
- No, you should not.
All the more reason for you
to stop avoiding this detective.
I could say the same about Cady.
She told me about Branch.
- You talked to her?
HENRY: Yes.
I learned things I might've learned from
you had you thought to mention them.
It's really none of your concern.
HENRY:
What a rich inner life you must lead.
From time to time, you should consider
sharing some of it with the rest of us.
I got other problems.
I'm getting some pressure
to arrest Viho Roundstone...
...for the murder of Greg Morris.
Based on evidence?
WALT:
Circumstantial.
[PHONE RINGING]
Well, if circumstantial evidence
has become grounds for arrest...
...that detective might have
to take you back to Denver.
It is a beautiful day at the Red Pony
and continual soiree.
Yes, Ruby, he is here.
Branch, come in.
Where do you think you're going?
To the res to arrest Viho.
WALT: I told you not to go.
- You know it's the right thing to do.
Pull over, Branch.
I'm tired of arguing with you.
I'm tired of arguing with you, Walt.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Maybe if you'd done your job better...
...those boys would've all been convicted.
- You want my job?
- What do you think?
Let's cut the bullshit. One punch.
You knock me over, I retire tomorrow.
Best idea you've had. Ever.
Well, go ahead.
Give me your best shot.
I don't think you can even
knock me off-balance.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
There's no one here.
Just you and me, no badges.
Just two men talking it out.
[BRANCH GRUNTS]
Experience isn't something
you can buy.
It takes time. Now, slow down.
I'm tired of waiting.
[BOTH YELLING AND GRUNTING]
Hey!
[VIC GRUNTS]
I should arrest both of you
for public stupidity.
I got new info on Viho.
Works at a hunting store...
...where some compound bow
and some arrows went missing last month.
Are you done debating?
Good.
Because an arrow
just harpooned another kid.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING]
That could've been me.
- Rich, what are you doing out here?
- Paul texted me.
Um, he wanted me and Jake and him
to come out here...
...and talk about what's going on.
- And when you got here?
RICH: Paul was already shot.
I was scared so I just hid in my car
and called 911.
Sheriff, he's gonna kill us all, isn't he?
Not if I can help it.
Branch, I need you to go see Jake Lennox.
Now, he was supposed to be here
and I wanna know why he wasn't.
He's the leader of this bunch.
Maybe he thinks one of them
was gonna talk.
How would that matter? They were
acquitted, they can't be tried again.
No, but someone could file a civil suit.
If one of these boys flipped, that could
cost the Lennox family a lot of money.
What?
How many of these kids have to die
before we arrest Viho?
VIC:
Excuse me.
Ma'am, we have a warrant
to search your house.
Come on.
Viho! Don't leave! Don't go!
- Why are you taking him away?
- I need to talk to your brother.
- You can talk to him here.
WALT: No, no, no. Not this time.
AYASHA:
He's my brother. Stay.
[SOBBING]
VIHO: You got an election coming up
so you arrest yourself an Indian.
It'd make me happy if you could convince me
you had nothing to do with this.
VIHO:
Why would I kill those guys?
Ayasha.
Ayasha's pregnant.
Yeah. We just found out.
Ever since the rape,
she's got messed up ideas about sex.
I can't leave my grandma
to take care of both her and the baby.
How do you explain
that the thing you spray-painted...
...on these boys' cars
is on their foreheads?
Why should I explain anything to you?
[DOOR OPENS]
You're not gonna believe me.
[DOOR CLOSES]
- You talked to Jake Lennox?
- Yeah.
He got the same text message
to meet at the drive-in.
Why didn't he?
His parents wouldn't let him out.
He hasn't been to school or his job
since the first murder.
RUBY: Hi, Henry.
- I understand you are holding...
...but not charging Viho Roundstone.
WALT:
Another one of those boys turned up dead.
You have an eyewitness or the murder weapon
with Viho's prints on it?
You recognize that symbol?
- It appears to be an owl.
- An owl, that's what I thought.
The Cheyenne messenger of death.
How do you explain...
...that, uh, the same owl turned up
on the foreheads of both our victims?
I do not know.
Perhaps to throw suspicion
on a young Cheyenne man?
Viho, did the sheriff read you your rights?
Yeah.
Then you heard the part
about getting a lawyer.
Whoa.
I know you're Walt's friend, Henry...
...but you don't have
any particular rights here.
No, but he does.
Do not say a word to the sheriff
or anyone else until you have a lawyer.
Henry.
GIRL 1:
Get that white bitch.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
- Get that white bitch.
- No! Stop!
GIRL 1: I'll kill you, bitch.
GIRL 2: Get her.
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
Hey! All right! All right, everybody!
Break it up! Hey!
Break it up in here!
- Hey!
- Get back!
Hey! Anyone still standing here by the time
I count to three goes to detention!
Anyone still standing here
by the time I get to five, you go to jail!
- One!
- Come on.
VIC: Two!
FERG: Move it, get back to class.
Hey, miss. Hey, sweetie.
Can we talk to you for a second?
You okay? Okay.
WALT:
You had problems with these girls before?
No.
They hate me because of Rich.
WALT:
Rich Stark?
I used to go out with him.
- But I didn't know.
- You didn't know what?
He and those other boys,
they raped that Indian girl.
That was kind of a big deal around here,
wasn't it?
How'd you not know that?
My family and I just moved here from
Seattle. I didn't know anybody.
And Rich seemed sweet.
But when I found out what he did...
God, I can't believe I let him touch me.
He disgusts me.
All of those boys disgust me.
When did you break up with Rich?
About two weeks ago.
How'd he take that?
He totally freaked.
He was crying and he kept saying
he didn't wanna rape that girl.
He didn't even deny that he did it,
he said that his friends made him do it.
- Did you believe him?
FAITH: Who cares?
There's no excuse for something like that.
I mean, how can someone
seem so normal one day...
...and then they turn out
to be a completely different person?
WALT:
Where's this patch from?
Archery club.
It's from my old high school.
Me and my friends got into it
after reading The Hunger Games.
- You're an archer?
FAITH: Yeah.
- Well, I'm okay.
- What kind of bow do you shoot with?
Uh, compound bow, 55-pound draw.
Where do you keep it?
At home, normally.
But I was teaching Rich how to shoot...
...and I lent it to him before we broke up.
I want it back,
but I don't wanna talk to him.
Right.
Oh, my God.
Has there been another murder?
Did they get Jake?
You tell me.
What?
I wanna talk to you about your hobby.
- What hobby?
WALT: Archery.
I just spoke to a friend of yours,
Faith Dewitt.
She, uh, tells me
she's teaching you to shoot.
Faith and I broke up.
- She didn't leave her bow here?
- No.
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Then how do you explain these?
[DOOR OPENS]
LIZZIE:
Hi.
- Lizzie, hi.
- Hi.
Hey, uh, Walt is actually swamped today.
I know. I read the paper.
I wanted to poke my head in.
[WHISPERING] He's, um, in a
meeting with a murder suspect.
Oh. Heh. Well, wow.
Okay, um, well... Oh, dang it. I just...
I wanted to give him a little surprise.
Can you make sure he gets it?
It's just a little something.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Yeah, sure. It's nice. Heh.
- Um, can I ask you...?
- I'm not telling.
[LAUGHING]
- Go ahead.
- Okay. Ahem.
What are your intentions with Walt?
What are you talking about?
He's just got a lot on his mind,
and I don't want him to get hurt.
Oh. Oh, you are sweet.
I can assure you
we are not rushing into anything.
It was a G-rated kind of evening.
Although, I was hoping
for more of a hard R kind of a night.
Can I ask you something?
What are your intentions?
Sorry?
You pick a career dominated by men...
...move here
and don't wear a wedding ring.
Well, you're not a cop...
...so you wouldn't know that you would
never wear your wedding ring on duty.
Because if you hit someone in the face...
...you could do some real damage
with that wedding ring, so...
My ex-husband
didn't wear his ring a lot.
He wasn't a cop.
What do I know? You look busy.
- If you can see that Walt gets that.
- Yeah.
LIZZIE:
Bye.
RICH:
All of this is your fault, sheriff.
You stood up in the courtroom
and called us rapists.
Even though we were not guilty...
...that's how people
will always think of us.
Rapists.
And that's why that Cheyenne guy
is out there killing us.
I'm not so sure
that Cheyenne guy is killing anyone.
In fact...
...when it comes to actual evidence,
most of it's pointing right at you.
Once wasn't enough for you?
Now you're accusing me of murder?
That doesn't make any sense.
Why would I kill my own friends?
Maybe they're not your friends, Rich.
See, I think you blame them for
everything bad that's happened to you.
I think you blame them
for Faith breaking up with you.
She didn't break up with me.
I shut it down.
What did she tell you?
That she taught you how to shoot
a bow, for starters.
Yeah. Like, once or twice.
That was her thing.
I just did it because she liked it.
- And I couldn't give a shit...
- Sit down, son.
Now, what'd you do with her bow, Rich?
- She said you kept it.
- Yeah, well, she's lying.
Trying to trash me,
just like you are right now.
Why do you hate me?
I mean, I can tell that you don't
wanna believe that Indian is guilty.
You want it to be me.
Why?
What makes you so sure
that I'm such a bad person?
Because Ayasha Roundstone told me so.
You remember her, son?
Because she remembers you.
I can't believe that Rich Stark
has been in our house.
What happened to him?
- My God.
- Jake.
[CRASHING]
JAKE:
Whoa!
- Holy shit.
- Jake, get down!
Dad!
[GUNSHOTS]
[SHOUTS]
I'm gonna kill you, you son of a bitch.
Look at me.
- Oh!
- Look at me.
Now, I will waive all my rights
and confess to everything...
...if you just let Rich go.
I'm releasing him right now, Mr. Stark.
Along with Viho Roundstone.
Good. Rich is a good boy.
He wouldn't kill anybody.
Never would've raped that girl...
...if it hadn't been for those boys.
Those boys are bullies.
Rotten to the core.
Walk around this town...
...swaggering like they own the place
while my boy's broken.
Rich tried to kill himself.
My boy swallowed pills.
Found him on the bathroom floor.
They need to pay for what they've done.
So you decided to kill them.
Yeah. All of them.
After the suicide attempt,
I started monitoring Rich's e-mails.
I wanted to know
what was going on in his life.
I sent Greg an e-mail.
I told him to meet me up at the ski basin.
I knew that's where those kids
like to hang out.
Then after I shot him,
I drew that symbol on his forehead.
You're very calm about all this, Warren.
For someone who's just murdered two boys.
You'd be surprised, sheriff.
Revenge can bring you...
...a tremendous amount of peace.
Hey, punk.
Why?
- Why what?
- Why do you treat me like this?
I just needed some time to get my head
around the whole Branch thing.
Detective Fales came by my house
looking for you.
Looking to talk about Mom's death.
How could you?
How could you not tell me that?
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[CRYING]
I wanted to tell you...
...but I couldn't.
- No, you couldn't.
Because you can't say anything.
Because you bury it.
And I'm sick of it.
You shut me out
when I didn't tell you about Branch?
And the guilt that I felt...
...and the whole time, you didn't tell me
that Mom was murdered?
She was murdered.
The whole year has been a lie.
Dad, I had a right to know.
You did.
So why didn't you tell me?
She didn't want me to tell you.
It was her wish.
It was your secret.
She didn't wanna be a victim.
She wanted to be remembered...
...as a wife...
...and a mother to a beautiful daughter.
She wanted you to live your life with
only the best possible memories of her.
I remember her dying of cancer.
That's a better memory than thinking
she was murdered.
Death is always hard,
but murder doesn't just create sadness.
It's a deep kind of anger
that never goes away.
I've seen what it does to people, Cady.
You...
You have my blood.
This case would've consumed you,
it would've infected you.
Taken over your life.
She didn't want that for you.
I couldn't let that happen.
I just wanted to protect you
from the pain.
I'm your father.
That's my job.
Well, let me relieve you of that burden.
You'll never relieve me of that burden.
Aah!
- What's going on?
- Jake Lennox's dad called me at home.
- Jake's missing.
- What?
VIC:
Once Mr. Stark confessed...
...Jake's mom and dad let him
resume his life. He went to work.
His boss called an hour ago.
Said he never showed up and, Walt...
...I had to tell Jake's parents
that you released Viho.
They're pretty pissed.
Warren, draw it for me.
- What?
- You drew a symbol on those boys...
...after you shot them. Draw it for me.
[WARREN SIGHS]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
- I can't remember.
- Can't remember?
Or you don't know, because your son
never described it to you?
Now, I understand a father
wanting to protect their child...
...and if you wanna protect your son,
you tell me where he is.
I don't know.
It's Rich. We gotta find him.
Branch, go to his house.
Vic, ski basin. Ferg, drive-in.
Think he'll go to the same spots?
Maybe. Maybe he's gone to that other place
those guys used to hang out at.
Look, just let me go, okay?
I'll do whatever you want.
There's nothing to do.
There's nothing to say.
We thought we got away with it,
but everybody knows.
And this is the spot
that changed everything.
- Rich, just cut it out, man.
- No.
That's not what you say.
You gotta say, "Stop! No, stop!"
You remember?
Because that's what Ayasha said.
Stop! No!
Stop it!
- Say it!
- Okay. Stop, okay?
Please, just stop.
It didn't work for Ayasha
either, did it, Jake?
- Help!
- No one can hear us, Jake!
That was the point of coming here.
She could scream her head off
and nobody would hear her.
WALT:
Rich.
- Put down that weapon.
- Sheriff, thank God.
Don't thank God just yet.
Rich, put down the weapon.
You stay back. I'm gonna save
everybody the trouble of another trial.
I'll confess to what I did.
I killed Greg and Paul, not my dad.
I did it.
- And now I have to finish it.
WALT: Listen to me, Rich.
I know you think the only way
you can find peace is by death.
Used to think that myself.
But there's another way to peace.
- Truth.
RICH: Yeah, the truth.
The truth is, we lied last year,
but none of us got punished.
But I did it, sheriff. I raped Ayasha.
And I didn't want to.
Jake made me, but I still did it.
Rich, what do you mean, he made you?
Jake held a gun to my head
and he made me do it.
[RICH GRUNTS AND AYASHA SOBS]
AYASHA:
Stop it!
Why didn't you just shoot me?
- He's crazy, sheriff!
- Rich, I can put Jake away.
I swear to you.
He can't be charged
for what he did to Ayasha.
But I can put him away
for what he did to you.
If someone uses the threat of violence...
...to make you do something you don't want,
technically, that's kidnapping.
Now, Jake will get his punishment, Rich.
And so will you.
That's what you want, isn't it?
What, are you arresting me?
You can't do this.
RICH:
I'm sorry, sheriff.
I'm sorry for everything I've done...
...to Ayasha and Viho.
They're all innocent.
It's gonna be okay, Rich.
I know it is.
[GUNSHOT]
[GASPING]
My shoulder. Oh, my shoulder.
Why did you stop me?
If I let you die,
who's gonna testify against Jake?
Mr. Connally, Jacob Nighthorse
will be out in just a moment.
Thank you, ma'am.
Ah, sheriff, glad you could
finally make it. Have a seat.
Nice job taking those boys in.
Crazy case, it sounds like.
Well, we're all crazy, so...
You will not find a chili cheeseburger
of this caliber anywhere in Colorado.
FALES:
Ah... Mm.
I ordered you a beer.
You're a Rainier man, right?
I said nothing.
You've done your homework.
Well, you're an interesting man.
- How so?
FALES: After your wife died last year...
...the detective assigned to her case
said you wouldn't leave him alone.
You called every day, you gave him
a hard time about not doing his job.
He described you as obsessive.
Then after a month, nothing.
And when I tried to contact you
to give you an update...
...nothing.
- Can't dwell in the past.
Then when I accidentally stopped by
your daughter's place...
...she told me she thought her mother
died of cancer.
You never told her about
the stabbing, Walt.
Can I call you Walt?
We all process grief in our own way.
- Now, tell me about the man you found.
FALES: Okay.
White male, mid 30s, meth-head.
Had a knife. Your wife's DNA
was on the blade, so, you know...
We think he was the one
who did the stabbing.
Well, there you go.
But here's the thing.
He's dead.
We found him with a broken neck,
buried in a shallow grave.
So I've gotta ask you something, Walt.
Shoot.
Did you drive down to Denver last year...
...to hunt down and kill
the man who stabbed your wife?
No.
[English - US - SDH]