Previously on Wynonna Earp...
- Bobo sent me. Name's Bethany.
- (growling)
We're gonna track down the last
of the Seven if it kills me. A spade.
- I'm Dr. Reggie.
- She died because
humans can't survive when their
- organs are removed.
- So what?
In the shape of a
spade, like on a deck of cards.
- I'm shutting your division down.
- I have something else.
- Never before documented.
- (gunshot)
Any idea why your
homestead was targeted?
We should at least get
some breakfast. Then we'll talk.
Wynonna!
(old-timey music)
Devil's hell.
(rustling sound)
Plus an angel incarnate.
Waverly?
Doc?
No, no, you're OK. Hey,
lay back. Lay back.
- What happened?
- Deep breaths, Deputy Earp.
You remember me?
Uh... Dr. Ninja.
- Am I in the morgue?
- Thankfully, no.
You're in the hospital.
Do you remember
anything about the accident?
Accident?
I was at the homestead...
Zombie strippers.
Oh, OK. Some memory loss
is totally normal after such a trauma.
Where's Waverly? Where's
my sister? Where's Doc?
No, no, no. We have to
limit your visitors right now,
until...
Wynonna,
I need you to listen to me.
Why can't I move my legs?
There's no easy way to
say this. You suffered
severe damage to your spinal cord,
causing paralysis from the waist down.
(panting frantically)
Synced and corrected by VitoSilans
- www.Addic7ed.com -
♪ 'Cause I gave you all
I've got to give ♪
♪ And no, that
ain't no way to live ♪
♪ I told that devil ♪
♪ To take you back ♪
- Dolls! Dolls!
- Whoa!
Hold on, son, now
there's no need for hollering.
Wynonna and Officer
Haught, they've been taken.
- What do you mean, taken?
- Abducted,
absconded, whatever the hell
you want to call it, they're gone!
What do you mean, gone?
He's got them, Dolls. The Fiend himself.
You don't understand. I love my legs.
They're what I walk
on. What are you giving me?
- I feel so...
- You feel hungover?
You're very lucky, Ms. Earp.
Lucky you didn't kill anyone.
I wasn't drunk... anymore.
Ask... Nicole.
Nicole was driving. Where's Nicole?
Shh, I have to listen, OK?
(shivering)
So you're like, a full-on doctor?
Morgue duty is just
part of our rotation.
I thought I might go to med school.
My solid D-minus thought otherwise.
- Where'd you go?
- Queens Undergraduate,
Princeton Medical School.
And you chose to
practice here? In Purgatory?
- Lucky for me.
- Indeed. I am actually
pioneering a radical new procedure
at this hospital.
To increase certain brain functions,
and I guess you could say...
shut down others. Certain
areas of emotion
cause a patient to be irrational.
They can be removed.
One question.
Do you only use the cane
as a weapon, or are you hiding
a limp under all that bullshit?
Excuse me?
Princeton doesn't have a
medical school, dickwad.
You're not a doctor, you're
a killer. A revenant.
People think that all it
takes to become a doctor is smarts.
No, no, no, no.
A real doctor pushes boundaries.
Does things that others
find distasteful for the sake
of progress. Take yourself, Wynonna.
You've been a very, very bad girl.
But it's not your fault, is it?
There's something very
wrong, deep inside of you.
And the doctor will search
until he finds it, and cut it
right out.
Off to prep an O.R.
Back in a jiff!
(whistling)
(gasping)
(woman): Hello?
Bethany?
I'll call the Feds and I'm gonna make a
discrete request for
additional resources.
- We need boots on the ground.
- No.
No, we need choppers in the air
and jets and drones and cruise missiles
- pointed right at Bobo's head!
- Wasn't Bobo that took 'em.
Wasn't the Stone Witch neither.
And your fancy weapons won't do anything
against Jack and his knives.
- What kind of man...
- To call him
a man would be to speak generously.
In Dodge City there was a schoolteacher
name of Sally. She laughed like a mule,
but her eyes did shine.
I was sweet on her,
but she went missing. Wyatt and me,
we tracked her to a limestone cave
in the hills. That's where we found her,
with three other soiled doves
that had been thought to have run off.
He had taken their insides out.
Spread them around their own bodies
- like a Thanksgiving feast.
- Oh my god.
Papers called him
'the Jack of Knives'
on account of the fact
that's what he called himself in the
letters he sent, taunting them.
Adept at all manner of blade.
- Great.
- Wyatt and me,
we made it our mission
to hunt him down. We tracked him
through the Cumberland
pass, nearly freezing to death,
and then I got sick.
Real sick.
Wyatt never spoke of
Jack again, but I know
he was the one that
haunted him the most.
Well, Wyatt must've got him eventually,
otherwise the creep
wouldn't be a revenant. He was a serial
killer when he was human. Who knows
what he's capable of now?
Or what he's gonna do to Wynonna.
Or Officer Haught.
The spade.
The spade...
once symbolized a sword
- or unsheathed blade...
- Or knife.
He's the last of the Seven.
Come on.
Whoa, whoa, Waverly. Can't go anywhere
with that broken wing of yours.
Besides, I need you to
stay here and dig deep,
find more on this Jack, alright?
Right. Bring them home safe, OK?
Of course. Alright, Holliday,
you said you tracked this
guy before, right?
You think you can do it again?
You want my help? I figured...
That I'd keep you at arms' length?
Yeah, well, not this time, cowboy.
Come on. Saddle up.
We've found her. Officer Haught.
Status?
She's alive. Barely.
Motorist spotted her on
the side of the highway.
- EMS had to resuscitate on site.
- Damn him.
- I'm gonna need access.
- You'll have it. Two conditions.
- Alright, name them.
- Doctor says
she needs a break, you hightail it.
And when you find the bastard who did
this, you make sure no one else does.
And you.
Move your damn horse.
- How long have you been here?
- Couple days.
- Maybe a week?
- You had any visitors?
- Seen any nurses, orderlies?
- Just Dr. Reggie.
He's gonna fix us.
OK, Bethany, we're in serious shit here.
It's OK to feel
nervous before a surgery.
This isn't a real hospital.
- Reggie's not a real doctor.
- He cares about me.
You know how long it's been
since I could
actually say that about a man?
Park your daddy issues, 'cause
it's time to haul ass outta here.
If he's not a doctor, he's...
- A serial killer.
- (whimpering)
The good news is that you're not sick.
The better news... Bethany.
Better news is that we're leaving.
OK? I'll need you to get
me a wheelchair, though.
(whistling)
- Shit.
- He's coming back.
- OK...
- What do I do?
Run. Get help.
Go!
Bethany, no! Bethany!
I'm not like you, Wynonna.
- I'm not brave.
- No...
(whistling)
Time for the doctor to go
to work. (clicking tongue)
(whistling)
(dramatic music)
♪ Take some love ♪
♪ Just take some love ♪
♪ From me ♪
♪ My heart's ♪
♪ Overflowing Can't you see? ♪
♪ You never love me ♪
What're you doing?
- Oh God, please don't...
- The doctor is
gonna make you feel better, Bethany.
- (heartbeat)
- (machine beeping)
She won't stabilize. I
can't lose another one!
Come on, come on!
(screaming)
(flatline sound)
(enraged screaming)
It's OK. It's OK.
I can fix the next one.
I just know I can fix Wynonna.
I know Deputy Earp
is still out there, and we'll
continue the search,
- but we agreed my Officer...
- Is our only witness.
I need to question her before
her memory becomes more clouded
- than it is.
- I'd feel more
comfortable with a greenlight
- from her doctor.
- Sheriff.
I'm good.
- OK? I want to help.
- Well,
I'll swing by and make
sure that cat of yours is fed.
She doesn't really like men.
Well, who does?
OK. So what was the last thing you saw?
Waverly Earp, smiling at
me from her front porch.
And, uh, a man stepping
out on the highway.
- Flagging us down.
- Description?
No. Just a blank space after that.
Until the woods.
- What happened?
- Somebody was carrying me.
I was blindfolded, I think.
Or just really drugged.
Next thing I know I'm freezing cold,
covered in dirt in a ditch
- the side of the road.
- What about Wynonna?
Do you remember anything
- about Wynonna?
- No.
- I couldn't see anything.
- Sight ain't your only sense,
Ms. Haught.
What did he smell like?
Close your eyes. Take a deep
breath in, let the memories come.
Sour.
- Musty.
- Like death?
No.
Spoiled fruit. And gasoline.
- He kicked me.
- What?
I couldn't figure out
why my chest was hurting. He
threw me down and he said
"You're the wrong kind."
You're the wrong
kind. You're the wrong kind.
You're the wrong kind. Uh...
Serial killers, they, um,
often have a type of victim
that they prefer.
And Wynonna?
Must be exactly what Jack's looking for.
Waverly, I'm so sorry.
No, it's fine. I'm just glad you're OK.
(Dr. Reggie screaming)
Come on, toes... move.
(sobbing)
Now, now. You know she's
tougher than a boiled owl.
He's got, like, a shitload of knives.
- And she's got us.
- Ahem!
Initial tests came
back from Nicole's uniform.
Traces of ethyl alcohol.
Yeah, the...
gasoline smell she remembered.
Common by-product
of chemical
manufacture. Like designer drugs.
- Certain types of explosives.
- Sour fruit.
- Excuse me?
- Nicole also said
she smelled sour
fruit. As in fermented fruit.
- Liquor.
- Ethyl isn't in liquor.
Back in my day it
was. Bootleggers used it
- to make moonshine.
- Doc, you're a genius!
- Let's not get carried away.
- OK, I think I know where he has her.
Right. Late 1930s,
Purgatory gets a new
sewage system. Construction crew
hits what they think is a sinkhole.
They actually found a series of tunnels
used during
prohibition to smuggle liquor
- across the border.
- Prohibition?
From 1919 to 1933 the United States
banned the sale, the making
- and consumption of alcohol.
- Lord, I'm almost glad
- I was in the well for that.
- So Jack went from using
caves to using those tunnels.
- Does this map give their location?
- No, unfortunately.
The town just sealed them
up. But I think I have an idea
who might know where they are.
OK, 1884, Wyatt killed
a corrupt saloon
owner named James Byers.
James Byers.
Same name appears again
in 1925 in connection with
a rumored liquor run.
It could be two guys or...
- Or a revenant.
- Aw, hell.
(chuckling)
- Let me guess. You knew him?
- I know him.
Runs an operation in town.
What kind of
operation are we talking about?
The best kind,
- highly illegal.
- (crowd cheering)
(barking)
There are two rules to this,
- Mr. Dolls.
- Let me guess.
First rule of fight club,
never talk about fight club, right?
Nobody talks about
it, how're fellas gonna
know where it is? No, the first rule is,
You never, ever bring the law.
- And what's the second rule?
- Wait here. Boss is comin'.
- Oh...
- (crowd and flinching)
- (cracking)
- Ooh!
What d'you think, human or revenant?
Kinda hard to tell.
Well, Whiskey Jim
likes to mix it up. 'Course,
the humans have no idea they're
stepping into the ring with a demon.
Adds a bit of whimsy
to your typical
pugilistic festivities, no?
Look who the cat dragged in.
Whiskey Jim.
Doc Holliday.
You being here means one of two things.
Either you got my 10K,
- or you got a death wish.
- Of course,
you owe him money. (chuckling)
- Did I forget to mention that?
- Listen,
this idiot doesn't have what
he owes you, but my division does.
All in exchange for some information.
Is there a place
- we can talk, Whiskey Jimmy?
- Bloody Black Badge?
Rule number one, moron.
(crowd cheering)
Yo. What up, Doctor Murder?
How are you feeling?
Floaty. These drugs are
hella dope. And coming from me,
- that's saying something.
- I need to ask you some questions
- about your personal history.
- Cut the bullshit.
I know who you are.
The last of the Seven. Which
means I'm sure as shit
- not telling you anything.
- You're awfully
mouthy for a girl who just found out
- she's paralyzed.
- Bethany hasn't come back.
I'm just scared, OK?
That's why it's
important to have a healthy
and open patient-doctor dialogue.
So tell me, Wynonna...
- Can you feel this?
- (cracking)
Nope.
You could be giving me a pedicure.
Good. Still,
we should up your meds.
The doctor just wants to understand
you. Don't you want
- to be understood?
- I want to be on a beach in Hawaii
with two very
impressionable cabana boys.
Always with the
jokes. Tell me, Wynonna...
What happened after you
killed your own father?
I was committed. Put under
the care of a 'specialist'.
Every time I told the
truth, I got a nice jolt
of electric juice.
- Was the shock therapy effective?
- Yeah.
Made me good at poker and now I
don't have to shave my left leg.
You use humor as a form of self-defence.
I prefer my Buntline special.
What'd you do with Peacemaker?
Get a good grip on it?
Stings a little, don't it, Revenant?
- Hey, that's mine.
- What is it doing over here?
You must've snagged it on something
when you wheeled me in. Give it back.
Answer my questions
- without any more guff.
- And you won't cut me open?
Wynonna, we have to do the surgery.
- For your own good.
- To fix me, yeah. Did you fix Bethany?
The doctor has ensured that
she's in no more pain.
What is with psychos and talking
in the third person?
I'm not psycho!
Fine, you're not
psycho. You're not psycho.
You're delightful. Top notch.
I'll answer whatever, OK?
Just put my necklace back on me, please.
On second thought, you're
not really in a position
to do any bargaining, are you?
OK, look, we just need the entrance
to your old
bootlegging tunnels, that's it.
Let's say I was willing
to help you. And I ain't.
Those tunnels are of no
use to you or anyone.
They were boarded up a long time ago.
- Nobody knows how to find them.
- Well, somebody does.
That 'someone'
has a very sharp
blade and Bobo's backin'.
- Ain't got nothin' to do with me.
- Look, just tell us where they are
and we'll be on our
way, alright, Whiskey?
This is my place.
(deep voice): I do the asking.
And you owe me plenty.
Look, we are all businessmen here.
Can't we come to some
sort of arrangement?
Hmm...
You do look like you
can handle yourself.
Yeah, I do alright.
(laughing)
Alright. You want my help?
You two need to earn it. Here,
now.
In the ring.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. You
really want me to fight him?
- What, you yella?
- No, I'm being
realistic, and let's
be real, you won't get
- your money's worth.
- Oh, I'll take that bet.
- Shut up.
- Whatever.
Just make sure there's blood.
Lots of it. One of you
leaves on a stretcher, or neither
of you leaves at all.
You give me that?
I'll tell you where my tunnels are.
Rule number two,
don't come if you
ain't willing to fight.
Wynonna!
This fella's been looking for
a chance to give you this.
Boss man sent him.
I guess Bobo wants
you alive for something.
You best read it quick.
_
Dolls,
you slimy motha...
- (bell dinging)
- Place your bets, gents!
Alright, let's go!
Come on!
- That's enough. It's showtime.
- Alright.
OK, look, we're running out of time.
Let's just give this guy what he wants.
- We should make it look real.
- Who says it ain't?
- Oof!
- Heh, heh!
Alright, old-timer. Playtime's over.
(clamoring)
- (cheering)
- (laughing)
I see you've found my missing scalpel.
Know how to make someone show you
where something precious is hidden?
Set fire to their house.
It's the first thing they go for.
Wynonna, don't be rash.
You'll never find Officer
Haught without me.
New deal, Reggimite.
Tell me where she is, and I'll make
your trip back to hell an express.
Screw around, and I will have some fun
before I blow your Revenant brains out.
Hell?
You killed Nicole,
- didn't you, you sonuvabitch?
- No.
Red blood? You're human.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
No need to say sorry, Reginald.
You served your purpose.
And now, you are released.
Who are you?
I've had a lot of names.
But you can call me Jack.
(clamoring)
♪ ♪
(cheering)
What happened to your shoulder, huh?
I'm surprised you don't
know. It wasn't in your report?
- Yeah!
- (crowd cheering)
How?!
Who told you?
Who gave it to you?
(grunting)
You wanna poke and prod me for science?
You wanna put me back in a cage?
You are a dirty,
two-faced son of a bitch liar.
(crowd): Ohh!
What're you waiting
for!? Get up! One of you two
needs to eat this
mat, or this deal's off!
Wynonna will never forgive you
if you hand me over to the authorities.
You didn't help her when it mattered.
She's with Jack because of you.
No wonder why Wyatt left you to die.
(crowd cheering)
Winner!
Ohh! You sir did give me
one hell of a show. You killed him!
We'll deal with his corpse.
Much obliged.
Now, I expect Black
Badge will be snooping around,
asking about their missing agent.
- I'd make myself scarce, ASAP.
- The entrance to the tunnels.
Now, I promised him that information.
- Him's dead...
- Now, goddammit!
(laughing)
Well, you did give me
one helluva good show!
That file Dolls had was classified.
- How'd Bobo get it?
- We revenants
are trapped inside the
Ghost River Triangle.
But Bobo, his reach extends
far beyond that.
He's got friends in
high places, that one.
Oh, oh, oh!
I, uh,
got these off your dead friend.
Don't think he'll be
needing them anymore.
(whistling)
You needed a human to
handle Peacemaker for you.
(whistling)
Somebody lost their head.
(horn honking)
- Jesus H. Christ!
- Nope.
You weren't leaving without me, were ya?
Never touch my stuff.
(whistling)
Your nose is bleeding.
Got a tampon?
Or, you know,
an inkling to get me to a real hospital?
Wyatt's nose bled like
that when I first met him.
I've been studying you for a long while.
We are so alike.
- Insane?
- No.
You work with a team, not because you
want to, but because you have to.
Like me. And you prefer to hunt alone.
Like me.
This is a trick that Reginald taught me.
Surgeons today
like to draw a map on their patients
for where they're going to cut.
- Any chance this surgery is elective?
- It's mandatory, I'm afraid.
Thought doctors had to
take an oath to do no harm.
I've never really been a doctor.
But I did study surgery.
And by study, I mean, I
love to cut open bodies.
I like to see what
makes people... people.
See, even when I was human,
I wasn't.
Not way down deep.
- I owe Reggie
an apology. You're the
sickest puppy in the litter.
- Flattery's not gonna save you.
- What is your damage?
- Mommy didn't love you enough?
- (giggling)
Or is this because every
woman you ever met rejected you?
Maybe.
Your dime-store psychology
is adorable, Wynonna.
I love women.
Can't you tell?
Feast for the eyes. And every man
has a favorite body part
upon which to gaze.
(whispering): I love to
look at your organs.
And I'm gonna keep you alive
just long enough
that you can look at them too.
You dead, and now you are nuts.
Oh, how the tables and have turned.
Army Night Rangers. Elite
paramilitary unit.
They train us in how to lower our
pulse, control our breathing.
- Make the enemy think you're dead.
- Oh, aren't you
- the master of deception.
- Here we go.
If your bosses
have no compunction about
turning a person
into a pin cushion, how are
they better than the demons?
Your body is a
treasure trove for science.
Think about what the
military could do with soldiers
who didn't get sick, didn't age?
It was a decision made for
the good of the many.
I get to choose who I share
my treasure trove with,
not the goddamn government.
If Wynonna
wasn't in danger, I
would shoot you right now.
Yeah. If Wynonna wasn't in danger,
you would be in the back of a van.
Hey, hey, hey! Watch it!
Ooh! Easy now.
I'm just gettin' ready.
But once Wynonna is safe...
Yeah. Once Wynonna's safe.
Now.
How the hell do we get in there?
Reginald always used antiseptic
because he thought that there
was a chance that the patients
would survive the procedure, but...
let's not kid ourselves.
You're not gonna survive this.
Now...
only the best for the heir.
Wait!
Before I die, just tell me.
- Tell you what?
- Why.
Why send the posse of seven?
If Bobo really wanted my daddy dead,
- he could've done it himself.
- Don't forget,
it wasn't the posse that
killed dear old Ward.
It was a scared and
confused little girl.
- It was an accident.
- I know, I was there.
I know you're not gonna believe this,
but I really liked your father.
He wasn't like the other Earp heirs.
He wasn't ambitious like Edwin,
or courageous like Josiah,
but he had something
that they didn't have.
Wits.
When Ward started his little ride,
he realized that in order to survive,
he was gonna have to
make certain alliances.
- With who? Black Badge?
- Don't be daft.
He made a pact with the big man himself.
Bobo Del Rey.
No. My daddy would never make a deal
- with a demon. Never.
- They were very close friends.
(scoffing) Liar.
I'm sorry, Wynonna, that
I break your heart.
Now I'm going to cut it out.
No! No!
(gunshot)
- Took you long enough.
- You're welcome.
Doc Holliday.
I always hoped that I'd
have this pleasure.
Where did you get the
Stone Witch's trinket?
Normally I just carve up women,
but, Doctor, in your case I'm
gonna make an exception.
Looks like it's just
me and you, Jackie Boy.
- Go! Go get it.
- Peacemaker?
Yeah.
It's across the hall. Whisky barrels.
Quick! OK.
Did I get him?
Not your job.
Oh!
It just got a little wet.
Mmm. Oak-aged.
Thank you. Don't kill each other.
Alright...
- So.
- Yep.
- Good talk.
- Oh, we are done talkin'.
I think this would be a
good juncture to remind you
that I am the fastest
gunslinger that ever walked the earth.
Hm. Debatable. What about Billy the Kid?
Ooh, I should shoot you right now,
just for being such an
obstreperous jackass.
So go ahead. Take me out.
Just know they've got satellites.
Predator drones.
You look like you just came out of the
Grand Ole Opry, so
they will find you, Doc.
And you, sir, are an asshole.
But you are not a villain.
So why, Dolls?
It was you. Or her.
I see.
D'you know what Wyatt used
to say? He used to say,
'Doc, well, if you stand for nothing,
you are sure to fall.'
What was I supposed to do?
You do what you do best, Deputy
Marshal Dolls, you fight.
OK.
Well, that was easy.
(grunting and wheezing)
Just think about it. Think about it.
Think about it.
I'm the last of the Seven.
What happens when you kill me?
Order too much Thai
and open a bottle of wine?
Once I'm gone,
you'll have to deal with
the puppet master.
And Bobo Del Rey
makes the rest of us
look like choir boys.
Yeah.
But he'll still make the
same pathetic hissing sound
- when I shoot him between the eyes.
- You're talking tough,
but you're just like me. You're broken.
I can hear the fear in your voice.
- (gun cocking)
- (Jack laughing)
Oh, I wish I could stay!
Watch what's coming next.
A reunion...
an escape.
So much blood.
You attacked my home
and killed my sister.
- Now make your peace.
- What's the hurry, little girl?
Enjoy the moment.
- Savor the kill.
- Who's this,
you do impressions now?
Who is that, Judi Dench?
You've solved a great mystery.
Succeeded where Scotland Yard failed,
and all
by your lonesome.
I ain't interested.
And I'm not lonesome.
I just prefer to hunt alone.
(screaming)
♪ ♪
You have to let go sometime, Waves.
Maybe tomorrow.
Well,
just like that, the Seven are gone.
Just like that, huh?
So what now?
Wynonna?
You stand by this report?
That your Deputy possibly dispatched
the most notorious serial
killer in history?
I said possibly. There's no way
to prove it without a body.
How convenient. Where's my delivery?
Oh yeah. I will be formally withdrawing
the report I filed
on the alleged target. Henry is nothing
but a con artist. A good one, but...
- the real Doc Holliday is dead.
- You continue
to disappoint me.
As long as I keep surprising you.
Always.
(Dolls): I've acquired a local asset.
A revenant from within Bobo
Del Rey's inner circle.
- Trusted lieutenant.
- (whimpering)
I will test the limits of
his physical body. And his mind.
No method will be spared.
After all, there's no danger
of him dying on me... at least,
not permanently.
Seems there's a mole in
my organization, Jim.
And you are going to help me find them.