[Western-style music plays]
[ Music continues ]
[ Bird screeches]
BRIAN: [ Coughing ]
Oh. [ Grunts ]
[ Groans ]
[Coughing ]
[Breathing heavily]
[ Music continues ]
[Siren wailing ]
[Wailing continues]
[ Engine shuts off]
[Suspenseful music plays]
OLSON: [Spits ]
SAMUEL: Fuck me.
OLSON: Paperwork on this one's
giving me
a pain in the ass already.
SAMUEL: Jesus.
What the hell happened?
OLSON:
Well, one thing's for sure...
The Grim Reaper
had himself a good old time.
Samuel...
you better call this in
to the city.
They're gonna want to send out
some CSI technicians.
Don't want us small-town boys
contaminatin' evidence,
do they?
SAMUEL: Yes, sir.
OLSON: Samuel!
Hold on there.
Jackpot. Oh, my God.
SAMUEL: Looks like somebody
tried to rip somebody off
and got killed.
OLSON: It sure looks like it.
Where you goin' now?
SAMUEL: I'm going to call it in.
Why?
OLSON: I said, "Hold on here."
SAMUEL:
With all this blow and cash,
we're just askin' for trouble
just being around it.
OLSON: Not if no one knows it.
SAMUEL: You're kidding, right?
OLSON: [Chuckles]
Just think about it, Samuel.
That must be $3 million in cash
in that van.
At least that much in product
in the other one.
No one knows it's out here.
SAMUEL: Bullshit.
Somebody always knows.
OLSON: Didn't your wife
just have a baby?
SAMUEL: Yes, sir.
OLSON: I got two...
on the way to college.
I don't know how the hell
I'm gonna pay their tuition.
Room and board.
That's a lot of money, son.
And I'll be honest...
I'm feelin' old. I'm tired.
Tired of workin' two jobs.
Tired of pickin' up drunks
at 2:00 in the mornin'
covered in piss and vomit.
Tired of gettin' shot at
by some crazy bitch
'cause her alimony check
bounced.
I'm just tired.
And, son,
that's a lot of money.
[ Chuckles, laughs ]
Had you going, kid, didn't I?
SAMUEL: You son of a bitch.
You almost had me.
I'm gonna go call it in.
OLSON: Sorry, kid.
[Western-style music plays]
Just take it easy, now.
Let's talk this through.
BRIAN: Like you did
with that young deputy there?
OLSON:
I'm not worried about him.
I'm worried about you and me.
BRIAN: Don't even try.
OLSON:
Uh, who the hell are you?
[ Body thuds ]
BRIAN: I have no idea.
[Western-style music plays]
[ Engine turns over]
[ Music continues ]
Fuck.
[ Monitor beeping ]
BLACK: Excuse me, sir.
A moment?
DOCTOR: Yeah.
BLACK: Is that the sheriff?
DOCTOR: He's lucky to be alive.
Being prepped for surgery.
Anything else?
ROCKER: Agent Rocker, DEA.
[Western-style music plays]
The second he wakes up.
I need to know.
DOCTOR: You got it.
ROCKER:
Let's go piece this together -
before the local cops
mess it up.
COLE: We estimate that
nearly 1,000 pounds of cocaine
was brought in
right beneath our noses.
We're on the front line.
And on the front line,
we can't afford to fuck up.
[Western-style music plays]
Breaking up these drug cartels
and stemming the flow
of drugs, weapons, and cash
across the Southwest border
is our top and only priority.
I'm all ears.
TAYLOR: A shit storm
in the middle of nowhere
and a dead deputy.
COLE: Davis, I need you
on traffic cams.
Report back to me A.S.A.P.
DAVIS: I'm on it.
- COLE: A dead deputy?
- TAYLOR: Yeah.
[Western-style music plays]
[Bird cawing]
ROOKER: Looks like
we're missing someone.
TECHNICIAN:
There's a vehicle missing, also.
ROOKER:
You know the make and model?
TECHNICIAN: I believe so.
ROOKER: I want roadblocks
on every highway,
people in trains
and bus stations.
And check the hospitals.
This man is wounded.
BLACK: Copy that.
ROOKER: Take me through it.
TECHNICIAN: We haven't
processed everything yet.
I don't have half the data.
ROOKER:
Tell me what you do have.
TECHNICIAN: Well, right now
it's all guesswork.
ROOKER:
Just... take a stab at it.
TECHNICIAN:
I think our missing friend here
caused most of the damage.
He came out with a two-piece.
Took out perp one and perp two.
Perp three and five,
they got a lot of rounds off.
A lot of shooting.
Nothin' hit. I think they may
have hit one of their own.
I'm still checking
the trajectory on that.
I mean, this guy,
he probably dropped his piece
when he was countin' rounds.
- And that's...
- ROOKER: Smart.
TECHNICIAN: Yeah.
Well, he did take one.
When perp six
hit him in the chest,
perp number seven
made contact down below.
That would explain the blood.
ROOKER:
What about the chest hit?
TECHNICIAN: We found a vest.
Had some damage
and some blood on it.
ROOKER: [ Sighs ]
So he was prepared.
TECHNICIAN: Or lucky.
ROOKER: Okay, so, he was down
and there were
still three men standing?
TECHNICIAN: Clearly he cracked
his head pretty good
when he fell down.
He was down, but not out.
Not immediately.
ROOKER: How long before we have
a more complete
ballistics report?
TECHNICIAN: 24 hours. Maybe 36.
ROOKER: Mm-hmm.
I can live with that.
TECHNICIAN: As of yet,
we still haven't determined
who our mystery guest is.
We're hoping something comes up
on his DNA report.
[ Music intensifies]
ROOKER: Somebody knows.
Somebody always knows.
Ah, great.
MIKE: Just here to lend you
some local support.
ROOKER:
Just don't get in my way.
MIKE:
Heard you were an asshole.
[Western-style music plays]
PEREZ: Find out
how and why this happened.
And find out
where they're taking the bodies.
And I don't care how you do it.
Find a way to get me his body.
[ Engine shuts off]
[ Car door opens, closes ]
BRIAN: [ Coughing ]
[ Bell rings ]
CLERK: Mm-hmm. Yes, baby.
Oh, babe, you make me laugh.
I miss you so much.
BRIAN: You got a bathroom?
CLERK: Yeah.
It's right over there.
BRIAN: Thanks.
CLERK: All right.
I should probably go.
Someone's in the store.
BRIAN: [Breathing heavily]
[ Faucet squeaks ]
[Suspenseful music plays]
[Breathing heavily]
[Pills rattling]
[ Music intensifies]
[ Groans, breathes sharply]
[Gasps, sighs]
[Pills rattling]
Phew.
Brian Barnes?
[ Engine turns over]
CLERK: Thanks for calling
the Streamline Bus Station.
Bus leaves at 11:00.
All right. Later!
[ Door opens ]
How can I help you?
BRIAN: I need a locker, please.
CLERK: 703.
It's in the next room.
Have a good day.
[ Door opens ]
[ Engine shuts off]
[Cellphone buzzing]
[Cellphone beeping]
OFFICER: Excuse me, sir.
This is a fire lane.
You can't park here.
BRIAN: I'm sorry, Officer. I was
just looking at some directions.
OFFICER: Have a good day.
[ Engine turns over]
[ Up-tempo pop music playing]
OLSON: Oh, shit.
ROOKER: Morning, Sheriff.
Well...
[Sighs]
afternoon at this point.
Please don't get up.
No need to bring
anyone else in here.
DEA, they wanted me to wait,
but...
Well, you see, this situation
is a bit time-sensitive.
So, what happened, Sheriff?
OLSON: [Sighs ]
Well, there's not much to say.
We responded to a call.
Couple of hunters saw somethin'
out at, uh, Morris property.
We checked it out.
You know the rest.
ROOKER: See, I don't, really.
Let's just say
you take me through it.
All of it.
CHRISTINE: [ Humming ]
Shit. OW! Oh.
[Western-style music plays]
HOWARD: What's wrong, cupcake?
[ Music continues ]
What's wrong?
Did you burn yourself?
- HOWARD: Ah.
- CHRISTINE: Mm.
- HOWARD: Mm.
- CHRISTINE: I'm fine.
HOWARD: Look, it's not so bad.
Not so bad.
CHRISTINE: That's because
it's not your hand.
That's why it's not so bad.
[ Chuckles ]
Not now, baby.
- HOWARD: Hey, baby.
- CHRISTINE: [ Chuckles ]
- HOWARD: Who's asking?
- CHRISTINE: Not now.
[ Grunts ] - HOWARD: Hey.
What I want...
when I want...
and absolutely where I want...
[ Buckles thuds ]
...is all you need to know.
It's time to come to Daddy.
That's right.
Talk to me like that.
You know what?
I just want this right.
Know what?
I want you to start talkin'
to me like I like it, okay?
No. I don't think so.
Put it down.
Put it down. [ Buckle thuds ]
Okay.
Now nice and easy.
Yeah, one more time.
You're gonna give it to me
just like I like it.
Now you just do
exactly what I say.
Here we go.
[Tires screech ]
[Horn blares]
[Sighs]
What the fuck?!
CHRISTINE: [Sighs]
HOWARD: You just stay here.
[ Door opens ]
Hey!
Hey, buddy!
[ Pounding on window]
Hey, buddy?
Hey!
Hey, buddy, are you okay?
[Horn honks]
Hey! Hey-
Hey. Easy, man.
Easy. I just wanted
to make sure you're okay.
- BRIAN: Back off.
- HOWARD: Just lower the gun.
Let's talk about this.
Easy, easy, okay?!
Just lower the gun, all right?
Just, can we...
Can we talk about this?
BRIAN: Where am I?
- Huh?
- HOWARD: Sorry?
BRIAN: Who the fuck are you?
HOWARD: Look,
I-I fuckin' live here, man.
Look, I'll drive you
any place you want to go.
BRIAN: Get back in the house.
- HOWARD: No, I'll drive you!
- BRIAN: Back in the house now!
- HOWARD: All right, all right!
- BRIAN: You hear me? Move!
HOWARD: Just don't harm us, man.
Shit!
- BRIAN: Let's go.
- HOWARD: All right.
BRIAN: Do as I say,
and no one gets hurt.
- Hey!
- HOWARD: Okay. Okay.
- BRIAN: Get down!
- HOWARD: All right!
Listen, man. I-I can help you.
BRIAN: Shut up!
CHRISTINE: Please don't do this.
You don't have to do this.
BRIAN:
I need to think a second.
I need to think. All right.
I can't call the cops.
HOWARD: Hey, look. We won't
call the cops. I promise.
Just... tell me
what you need, man.
- BRIAN: Okay. You got a garage?
- HOWARD: Yeah.
- BRIAN: You got rope?
- HOWARD: Sure.
- BRIAN: Get up. Get up.
- HOWARD: Yeah. Okay.
BRIAN: Listen to me!
From now on, we all move
as a unit, all right?
You do what I say,
and you'll be fine.
Move! Now.
HOWARD: Just don't hurt us.
Just... Okay. Here we are.
MAN: Fuck.
Fuck.
I knew I shouldn't have
came into work today.
[Suspenseful music plays]
[Chains dangling ]
PEREZ: [ Breathes deeply]
I promised your mother.
I promised her.
[Sighs]
Now look what I let happen.
I wouldn't let you work with me.
So what do you do?
Go join
the fucking police force...
under a different name.
[Voice breaking] It's my fault.
I...
I should have kept you closer.
I should have kept
an eye on you.
[Sighs]
It's my fault.
Tell me you have a name.
JOSEPH: We have someone who
might be able to give us one.
PEREZ: Let's go have
a little chat with someone.
I don't want him left alone.
Someone stays with him
day and night.
And he stays above ground
until the son of a bitch
that did this no longer is.
[Chains dangling ]
[speaking Spanish]
PRISONER: Ah. Please.
PEREZ: Now I'm gonna show you
what happens
when you steal money from me.
PRISONER: I didn't
steal anything from you!
I would never steal
anything from you. Please!
BRIAN: I need y'all to be quiet.
You understand me?
HOWARD: Fuck.
[ Door slams ]
[Suspenseful music plays]
BRIAN: [ Breathes sharply]
[Sighs]
[ Refrigerator door opens ]
[Breathing heavily]
[Sighs]
HOWARD: Today of all clays.
I could be playin' golf
on the back nine.
CHRISTINE: That's what
you're thinkin' about right now,
is golf?
HOWARD: But now I'm tied up
in my own garage.
This is good.
Thank you. Thank you.
You got any ideas?
[ Computer beeps ]
COLE: What are you up to?
Black.
I just got word from my contact
at the hospital security.
The good sheriff
has checked himself out early.
BLACK: Copy that.
Okay.
You are not gonna believe this.
The good old sheriff discharged
himself against doctor's orders.
ROOKER: Mm.
Damn right it was
against doctor's orders.
Now, why would a man,
a drugged-up man,
get out of his hospital bed
and walk around
with his ear blown off?
BLACK: I have no idea.
ROOKER: Because he's running
from something or to somewhere.
OFFICER: Here.
The only vehicle
in that time frame
that has matching tire tracks.
ROOKER:
Just find out where he's going.
Stay on the sheriff.
And be careful.
I'm pretty sure
he's a complete piece of shit
hiding behind a badge.
BLACK: Copy that.
ROOKER: Get me a clear view
of that license plate.
[Pills rattling]
[Suspenseful music plays]
OLSON: Ahh.
Oh.
Baby, I missed you.
Ahh.
[Telephone rings]
[ Ringing continues]
[ Cellphone vibrating ]
[Cellphone beeps]
Hey, Mike.
MIKE: I was looking for you
at the hospital.
OLSON: Yeah, well,
I saw myself out.
That's no place for me
to get better, is it?
MIKE: I hear you.
We've got a bit of a problem
down here, though.
Seems somehow
we misplaced Sammy's body.
OLSON: What the hell
are you talkin' about?
How the hell
do you misplace a body?
MIKE: No clue.
OLSON: You're serious?
Well, what... what
about the ballistics?
MIKE: We never got a chance
to even process him.
OLSON: Now, Mike,
that's just terrible.
Any idea
where the body went now?
MIKE: Fuck if anyone knows.
It's gone poof. Vanished.
OLSON: No shit.
[Doorknob rattling]
Mike, I'm gonna have
to call you back.
I'll get...
I'll get right back to you.
[ Keys jingling]
[ Lock disengages ]
JOSEPH: [ Gasps ]
OLSON: Son of a bitch.
Break in my house?
[Gun cocks]
PEREZ: Hi, Sheriff.
We need to talk.
Sit down!
[speaking Spanish]
You nervous, Sheriff?
You look nervous.
OLSON: Yeah, well,
it's been a long day.
PEREZ: You know,
I heard about that.
But I got a problem
I think you can help me with.
OLSON: Okay. What's that?
PEREZ: Now, you know me.
You know who I am.
OLSON:
Everybody knows who you are.
PEREZ: Someone stole
a lot of money from me.
That I can live with.
But where you can help me is
to figure out who killed my men.
OLSON: First of all,
I'm gonna tell you...
When we got there,
they were already dead...
except for the one...
who shot me in the goddamn ear.
PEREZ:
You're alive, aren't you?
OLSON: Uh-huh.
Look, I just don't know.
I just don't know
how I can help you, Mateo.
PEREZ: One of them was my son.
OLSON:
I'm real sorry to hear that.
But like I said, when I got
there, they were already dead.
PEREZ: My son was with you.
OLSON: I'm sorry. I...
Sam was a good deputy.
I-I didn't know.
PEREZ:
About that guy that shot you...
OLSON:
Look, he shot both of us.
He shot Sammy,
and... and I tried to help him,
and he shot me!
Look, we thought they were dead.
PEREZ: Tell me about him.
OLSON:
I saw his face for 30 seconds.
And then he shot me.
I wish there was more,
but I never saw
this guy before in my life.
I swear to God. I have
no idea who these people are.
PEREZ:
Maybe you can help me find him.
Unless you were planning
on going somewhere.
OLSON:
I don't know what I can do.
The DEA has taken over.
PEREZ: Come on.
You're local police.
Work with them.
I'll really make it
worth your while.
OLSON: Well, uh...
that sounds just fine,
Mr. Perez.
PEREZ: This guy
stole $3 million from me.
Now you help me find him...
and I'll give you
a hefty finder's fee.
And then you can just
go on your merry way.
OLSON: Now that sounds
like a good deal.
You gonna keep pointing
that gun at me, partner?
PEREZ: [ Chuckles ] Okay.
You know me.
So you know what happens
if you don't.
OLSON:
That's a hell of a good deal.
PEREZ: Vémanos.
OLSON: It's gonna be a pleasure
doing business with you,
Mr. Perez.
Ahh.
Damn.
Phew.
PEREZ: Something's wrong.
I don't know, but...
he's hiding something.
JOSEPH: He might be playing us.
PEREZ: You know what?
Keep somebody on him.
Let's find out
where it takes us.
JOSEPH: You really plan
on letting him keep the money?
PEREZ: That's loco!
Hell, no. Come on.
[Telephone ringing ]
COLE: Cole.
BLACK:
I'm at the sheriff's house,
and I got a license plate
for you.
Can you run a history?
COLE: Sure.
What are the numbers?
BLACK: Foxtrot, Golf,
Seven, Nine, Six, One, Hotel.
COLE: Okay. Give it a second.
Huh.
People...
this case just got
a lot more interesting.
Mateo Daniel Perez was spotted
at the house of our friendly
neighborhood sheriff.
Now, what's a drug lord
like Mateo
doing hanging out
with the sheriff?
And to top it all off...
I just found out
that our little dead deputy
is the son of the most
successful drug lord ever.
Now, people...
we've had a guy
on the inside of Perez's gang,
but there's been no connection
with the sheriff until now.
What is going on?
People, I need some answers.
I need you to get
your asses out there,
or some heads will roll.
HOWARD: All right. Look.
Let's... Let's try
and stand up back to back, okay?
CHRISTINE: Hell, no.
You're gonna get us killed.
HOWARD:
Just do what I tell you to do!
When I go, "One, two, three,"
back to back,
we're gonna stand up, and
we're get the hell out of here.
CHRISTINE: Hell, no!
HOWARD: Just do it, okay?
One, two, three.
CHRISTINE: Ow. Stop it!
HOWARD: Look, just...
God damn it. Shut up.
- Stand up!
- CHRISTINE: Ow! No!
HOWARD: Stand up with me.
Stand...
CHRISTINE: OW!
HOWARD: Damn it.
CHRISTINE: Will you stop?!
You are such an idiot.
HOWARD: Shit.
You're callin' me an idiot?
When you're dumb as dirt?
Are you kiddin' me?
CHRISTINE: You just shut up.
HOWARD: You shut up! Look.
Do you want him
to come in here and kill us?
CHRISTINE:
We stay here, we wait it out.
And we don't piss him off!
[ Heart beating]
INMATE: Nice work, fish.
We have a job for you
when you get out.
MAN:
What the hell happened to you?
You haven't checked in.
What's going on?
BRIAN: Aah!
- CHRISTINE: Hey!
- HOWARD: What?
What are you doin'?
CHRISTINE: Shh!
HOWARD:
What do you mean, "shh"?
[ Door opens ]
BRIAN: What?
CHRISTINE:
I need to go to the bathroom.
HOWARD: Shut up!
CHRISTINE:
[Whispering ] Shut up.
BRIAN:
Where's your manners, boy?
You don't talk to a woman
like that.
ROOKER:
The suspect used Highway 5
driving into this area.
So we're concentrating
our efforts here.
We have roadblocks
on every highway,
and we're conducting
house-to-house searches.
OFFICER:
Yeah, but how do we know
he didn't ditch his vehicle?
Or maybe took off on foot?
ROOKER: Since we yet
haven't located the van,
we're still assuming
he's in the possession of it.
OFFICER #2: Do we have an I.D.
on the suspect?
ROOKER: Yes.
We've extracted an image
from a street cam.
Waiting for blood DNA analysis.
Haven't yet identified
the suspects.
Please remember, people, this is
the suspect in the murder
of a law-enforcement officer.
I expect you all to be
on your top game for this one.
[ Clears throat]
Any questions?
Let's go catch this guy
before he kills anyone else.
BRIAN: Hurry up.
CHRISTINE: What the hell
are you doing here, Brian?!
BRIAN: Brian?
How do you know my name?
CHRISTINE: Is this a joke?
You're supposed to get me out.
Get me out of this thing.
I waited four hours for you,
and nothin'.
No phone call... nothin'.
And now you show up here,
and you do this shit?
What the hell are you thinkin'?!
And where's Bob?
BRIAN: I have no idea
what you're talkin' about, lady.
I've never seen you before
in my goddamn life.
CHRISTINE: [ Scoffs ]
Are you joking?
What the hell happened?
[ Gasps ]
BRIAN: Back the fuck up.
You understand me?
CHRISTINE:
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Okay, okay, okay. Okay-
Look at me, Brian.
You know me.
I'm Christine.
I know something
fucked up happened.
But I can help you.
Just put the gun down.
Just put the gun down,
God damn it!
[ Breathes deeply]
Now tell me what happened.
Hmm?
BRIAN: Don't touch me.
CHRISTINE: Just tell me
what happened, honey.
BRIAN: I was shot.
Hit in the head.
I don't know.
It's all just a blur.
CHRISTINE:
Well, what do you remember?
BRIAN: Nothin'. You understand?
I don't remember
a goddamn thing.
CHRISTINE: [ Breathes sharply]
BRIAN: It's all just kind of
faces and noise and shit.
CHRISTINE:
I'm sure it's just temporary.
BRIAN: No! It's not temporary.
I'm in trouble here.
CHRISTINE:
Anything can get fixed.
You'll be fine.
Everything will be fine.
BRIAN: I shot a cop.
I killed him.
I know I shot other people, too.
I just ... I just can't remember!
I can't remember
a fucking thing!
CHRISTINE: Now, why would you
go shootin' a cop?
BRIAN:
What was I supposed to do?
Let him take me in?
CHRISTINE: We'll just have
to figure it out...
one thing at a time.
But first...
we got to take care of Howard.
BRIAN: You said I was supposed
to take you away
from all this, right?
- CHRISTINE: That's right.
- BRIAN: Okay.
Well, that explains the money
and what I was doin' there.
CHRISTINE: Money?
What money?
BRIAN:
I didn't tell you about it?
CHRISTINE: How much money
are we talkin' about?
BRIAN: I don't know.
Couple million.
CHRISTINE: [ Gasps ]
BRIAN: Maybe more.
CHRISTINE:
You really are my hero.
Yeah.
My hero.
[ Chuckles ]
BRIAN: Stand up.
Turn around.
CHRISTINE: [Chuckles]
What are you doin', Brian?
[Zipper unzipping ]
[ Chuckles ]
I am gonna take care of you.
[Moans, giggles]
[Both breathing heavily]
HOWARD: [ Grunting ]
Shit.
ROOKER:
So, the mess was man-made.
What did you do with it?
CLERK: What do you mean,
what'd I do with it?
I threw it in the trash.
The bathroom looked like
someone exploded all up...
ROOKER: I get the picture.
CLERK: Yeah.
ROOKER: You got cameras
in the bathrooms?
CLERK: Now, sir...
you know that is so illegal.
ROOKER: Show me
where you threw the trash.
I'm gonna need to see footage
from that camera.
[Cellphone buzzes]
CLERK:
This guy dangerous or somethin'?
ROOKER: Or something.
CLERK: [ Chuckles ]
ROOKER: The footage
from the security cam...
let's see it.
CLERK: Why don't you tell me
who this guy is first?
Huh?
[Cellphone beeps]
ROOKER:
Do you know a good proctologist?
CLERK: A what?
ROOKER: 'Cause if you don't
put that camera down
and erase that video,
I'm gonna shove it so far up
your ass that you'll taste it...
and realize why the company's
called Apple.
To-fucking-day.
With the security cam
would be just lovely.
CLERK: All right.
ROOKER:
Thank you for your cooperation.
[Sighs]
JESSE: Howdy, Sheriff.
[ Pulsating tone]
[Suspenseful music plays]
[Tone stops ]
OLSON: Jesse!
JESSE: Yes, Sheriff?
OLSON:
What the hell happened in here?
JESSE: Oh.
Those agents came by.
Said they needed some things.
OLSON:
Now, who authorized that?
JESSE: I did, silly.
They had all them badges and
paperwork and, well, you know.
OLSON: Son of a bitch.
JESSE:
Have a good day, Sheriff.
OLSON: Mike.
MIKE: Sheriff.
OLSON: Thanks for meetin' me.
MIKE: Always.
SALLY:
Sheriff, you look like shit!
OLSON: Sally, this is a good day
to mind your own damn business.
SALLY: I heard about
what happened to that kid.
[Liquid pouring]
Sorry about your partner.
OLSON: Thank you, Sally.
Thank you very much.
Listen to me, Mike.
The DEA, they shut me out.
I got zero access.
Now, I want to find
the son of a bitch
who killed Sam and shot me
before they do.
MIKE: Now, they shut you out
for a reason.
Now, I wasn't here...
and you didn't hear nothin'
from me, okay?
Now, I could lose my job
just talkin' to you right now.
- OLSON: Go on, Deputy.
- MIKE: Well, they brought in
some forensics hot shot
from the city.
Now you're suspect.
OLSON:
Oh, you think I'm a suspect?
They shot my goddamn ear off.
I'm disabled. MIKE: I know it.
OLSON: I could take my goddamn
pension and walk away.
But I want to find the son
of a bitch who killed Sam.
Figure that.
MIKE: I know. We all know.
But [Sighs]
There's just something
that don't add up
about that crime scene.
OLSON: You want to know
what don't add up?
They lost the body.
How the hell they want to tie me
to Sam's death without a body?
Tell me that.
MIKE: Well, they lost the body,
but not before
some brown nosin' intern
pulled the slug from the kid
before he was missin'.
Ballistics had a match...
for your gun.
OLSON: I'm being set up, Deputy,
and you know it.
MIKE:
I do, but... rules are rules.
I'm sorry, Sheriff.
I got to take you in.
Now, these things
kind of sort themselves out,
so you got to trust me here.
OLSON: Now, Mike...
you know
that's not gonna happen.
I'd be dead before breakfast.
MIKE: I don't think
the DEA's gonna go that far.
OLSON:
You know who Sam's old man is?
Mateo Perez.
MIKE: The Mateo Perez?
Jesus.
What'd you get yourself into?
OLSON:
Now, he paid me a private visit.
He wants me to find the guy
and hand him over.
MIKE:
Well, what are you gonna do?
OLSON: I'm gonna find this son
of a bitch and hand him over.
MIKE: Well, what if you don't?
OLSON: You and I have seen
enough dead bodies of people
who have tangled with him
to know that you don't tangle
with Mateo Perez.
Now, you know goddamn well
I didn't kill Sam.
I just need a little time
to get out from underneath this.
MIKE: All right.
I'll tell you what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna forget the DEA.
What the hell they doin',
comin' in here
and tellin' us
our business anyway. Right?
You go take care
of that business.
I was never here,
and neither were you.
OLSON: Thanks, Mike.
MIKE: You turn yourself in
once you get this
all squared away, right?
OLSON: I sure will.
But I still need that favor.
MIKE: Just ask.
OLSON:
I want to know where the DEA
is concentratin'
their investigation.
Give me something... anything.
They shut me out,
and time is running out.
MIKE: I'll see
what I can come up with.
OLSON: I owe you.
MIKE: Hell you do.
[ Legree Graham's "Dirty"
Plays ]
[ Heavy breathing ]
CHRISTINE: [ Moans ]
♪ So, do your dirty ♪
♪ Leave your coat on, babe ♪
♪ Bring it down to your knees ♪
♪ So, girl, you're dirty ♪
♪ And you're gonna know it ♪
♪ Have you begging now,
please don't leave ♪
HOWARD: You're gonna be fine.
You're gonna be fine.
You're gonna be fine!
CHRISTINE: [ Moans ]
♪ So, do your dirty ♪
♪ Leave your coat on, babe ♪
♪ Bring it down to your knees ♪
♪ So, girl, you're dirty ♪
♪ And you're gonna know it ♪
♪ Have you begging now,
please don't leave ♪
PEREZ: To life.
[Glasses clink]
[Mid-tempo rock music plays]
Ahh.
[Cheers and applause]
I told you
I didn't want to be disturbed.
[Sighs]
Where is he?
HOWARD: [ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
Okay. Just a little bit...
a little bit more.
Come on, come on.
[ Grunting ]
Oh! [ Panting ]
Fuck. Fuck.
[ Panting ]
[ Keys jingling]
BRIAN: Goddamn, I got to be
more careful with these.
CHRISTINE: We could leave
and take the money
and just disappear.
BRIAN: No.
We talked about that.
Your husband
will come after you.
CHRISTINE:
There are ways around that.
We could just kill him.
BRIAN: No.
We ain't doin' that now.
CHRISTINE:
All right, well, just vanish
and disappear into the sunset
like we planned.
I mean, after that, I couldn't
imagine being without you.
Let's just go.
[Alarm blaring]
BRIAN: What the fuck is that?
- CHRISTINE: Shit!
- BRIAN: God damn it!
[Blaring continues]
CHRISTINE: Shit.
[ Blaring stops]
The phone's dead.
No calls out until the security
company calls and clears it.
They'll send a car
if no one answers.
BRIAN: We got to go now.
You understand? Come on.
- HOWARD: Help!
- CHRISTINE: No. Leave him!
HOWARD: Help.
There's a fire in here!
Help! Help!
Come into my fuckin' house!
[Gun clatters]
BRIAN: Fuck you, man!
[ Spits ]
HOWARD: Aah!
My fuckin' nose.
What are you doin'?
Give... Give me the gun, Chris.
CHRISTINE: Back off.
HOWARD: Wha... What?
BRIAN: Okay.
CHRISTINE: Back the hell up.
I will shoot you.
BRIAN: Really?
CHRISTINE: Plans change.
Sex was good and all,
but you're a little boring.
Plus, that's a lot of money.
Give me the keys... now!
HOWARD: What are you doin'?
How long you been fuckin' him?
Huh?
You pathetic bitch.
I fuckin' hate you.
You know what?
You're gonna end up right back
in that trailer-trash park
that I found you in.
CHRISTINE: I will shoot you.
BRIAN: It was
all about the money, huh, Chris?
CHRISTINE: It's always
about the money, honey.
Now get me the fucking money!
[Soft music plays ]
OLSON: Ohhh.
Oh.
Oh, baby.
You know, maybe we should
just get married.
That way I can get you
your green card.
Things work out, maybe
I'll even get you a boob job.
[Chuckling ]
[Cellphone buzzing]
Aw, shit.
[Cellphone beeps] Yeah, Mike?
MIKE: Now, you didn't
get this from me.
May be somethin'.
May be nothin'.
Got a call about a house alarm
in Madison.
Guy who owns the house
is Mateo Perez's lawyer.
Was gonna do a drive-by,
but I figured...
you might want
to take a look instead.
Like I said, may be nothin'.
OLSON: Great. Thanks, Mike.
MIKE:
Just don't get yourself killed.
OLSON: Right. [Cellphone beeps]
[ Engine shuts off]
HOWARD: I swear to God.
I swear to God.
I won't stop lookin'.
Not until I find
the fuckin' both of you.
BRIAN:
What are you fuckin' doin'?!
CHRISTINE:
You don't know him like I do.
He's a monster.
Fuckin' damned rapist.
He raped me... again and again.
Do you know how that feels?!
You promised
to help me get out of here.
You give me that money
right now!
[ Door opens ]
OLSON: Drop your fuckin' guns.
NOW!
Get over there
with your boyfriend!
Drop the fuckin' gun!
Put it down, motherfucker!
BRIAN: Shit.
OLSON: Did you miss me?
I'm sure glad to see you.
You seriously fucked up
my day, son.
You took my money, and you
left me with Mateo Perez.
You dumb shit. We could
have been partners on this.
BRIAN: Goddamn! I didn't think
I'd see you again.
OLSON: Well, next time
you better kill me all the way.
BRIAN: Well, next time,
I'll remember that.
OLSON: Don't strain yourself.
I could give two shits about the
trouble you got yourself into.
Or why you killed the kid!
BRIAN: Kid?
OLSON: All I care about
is the goddamn money!
Now where the fuck is it?!
- BRIAN: It's right here.
- OLSON: You think I'm stupid?
That don't look
like $3 million, asshole!
Now where's the rest?!
BRIAN: I might have put
that money somewhere safe.
OLSON: Now, where
exactly did you put it?!
BRIAN:
Well, see, that's the problem.
With all this head-trauma shit,
I can't remember.
OLSON:
I'm not gonna ask you again.
[ Muttering ]
CHRISTINE: [ Screams ]
OLSON:
Now I'm gonna count to 5,
and then
I'm gonna paint the floor
with this little girl's brains
if you don't tell me
where the goddamn money is!
CHRISTINE: Please, Brian.
Please tell us
where you put the money!
OLSON: Five...
four...
BRIAN: Go ahead and shoot her.
- OLSON: Three...
- BRIAN: I can't remember.
OLSON: There were three,
four, five bags of money
in the back of that van,
and I only see one!
Tell me
where that fuckin' money is,
or I'll blow
your goddamn balls off,
and you can have this bitch.
BRIAN: Sheriff...
you might want to look outside.
[Western-style music plays]
PEREZ: Nobody touches
the sheriff! He's mine!
OLSON: Fuck! Why can't
I catch a goddamn break?
Shit.
[Gunshot]
[ Gunshots ]
BRIAN: Christine, come here.
Get down, get down.
And don't move.
You understand me?
CHRISTINE: [Breathing heavily]
[ Screams ]
BRIAN: Stay down!
[ Heart beating]
[Gun cocks]
OLSON: Okay, asshole.
Last chance.
Where's the goddamn money?
I'll blow
your fuckin' balls off!
Then we'll see what you do with
that little girlfriend of yours.
[ Chuckles ]
All the money in the world,
and you can't get laid.
[Western-style music plays]
Like father, like son.
[Coughing ]
[Gun clicking]
PEREZ: Para mijo, cabrén.
[ Knock on door] COLE: Come in.
- DAVIS: Long night?
- COLE: Whew.
DAVIS: Pulled all the footage
from the surrounding
traffic cams.
Take a look at photo number two.
COLE: Hmm.
Thank you, Davis.
DAVIS: Yes, ma'am.
[Keyboard clacking]
[ Computer beeping ]
COLE: I think we found our guy.
Several traffic cams show a van
blowing through red lights.
It's now in the parking garage
at The Streamline Bus Station.
I ran the plates,
and the van belongs to Perez.
Rocker...
I need you
to bring him in alive.
CHRISTINE:
Give me the keys... now!
[ Locker door slams ]
ROOKER: Brian.
We need to talk.
BRIAN: How do you know my name?
ROOKER: What do you mean?
[ Body thuds ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
BRIAN: [ Grunts, sighs]
Can I have another, please?
I won't be any trouble.
BARTENDER: Okay, tough guy.
Your funeral.
BRIAN: Yeah.
NEWSCASTER: We're here now
with Agent Imani Cole
from the Drug Enforcement
Administration
with more information
regarding the victims of...
- BRIAN: Hey. Do me a favor, bud.
- BARTENDER: Hmm?
- BRIAN: Turn that up.
- COLE: Earlier this morning,
one of the most successful
drug lords in history,
Mateo Danny Perez,
was killed in a DEA sting.
Unfortunately we lost
several great agents.
We're asking the public...
if you have any knowledge
of the whereabouts of Agent
Brian Michaelson to contact us.
NEWSCASTER: Thank you
very much, Agent Imani Cole.
Earlier, we spoke
with Michaelson's family
as they made a request
for more information.
Agent Michaelson's wife
had this to say.
SARAH: We just want Brian
home ... with his family.
ALEX: I love you.
SARAH:
She's really gonna miss you.
BRIAN: I love you, too.
I love you, too.
SARAH: Promise me
this is gonna be the last one.
One more, and you'll hang it up.
BRIAN: I promise.
One last final mission.
Then I'm on a desk
till retirement, okay?
- SARAH: Okay.
- BRIAN: Okay.
SARAH:
She's really gonna miss you.
BRIAN: [ Smooches ] I love you.
ALEX: Daddy!
BRIAN: Come here, honey.
Oh, my baby girl.
ALEX:
Daddy, please don't leave.
BRIAN: I'll be back, okay?
I promise.
ALEX:
I'm really gonna miss you.
BRIAN: I'm gonna miss you, too.
ALEX:
I'm really gonna miss you.
SARAH: Promise me
this is gonna be the last one.
COLE: What's this?
BRIAN: Transfer request.
I miss my wife and daughter.
My wife needs to know
I'm coming home at night.
I'll do this one last one
in the field, but...
I'm gonna need a desk
after that.
COLE: You and Bob have been
partners for a long time.
NEWSCASTER: Yesterday
Agent Michaelson's partner,
Robert Rooker, was identified
as one of the victims.
BRIAN: [ Sighs ]
Christine
having second thoughts?
ROOKER: No, she'll be fine.
You about ready?
BRIAN: As I'll ever be.
ROOKER: Meet your alias...
Brian Barnes.
We ﬂooded the Web
with this information.
Just memorize it
and burn what you don't need.
Now, remember...
we're in this together.
Whatever happens,
I got your back.
BRIAN: You always do.
CHRISTINE: I'm just scared.
ROOKER:
We can and will protect you.
CHRISTINE: If I do this...
if I help you...
I need to disappear...
'cause Howard would kill me.
BRIAN: I promise.
We'll take you away
from all this, okay?
Get you into Witness Protection.
ROOKER: But we can only push
the paperwork through
if you help us nail
your husband's boss.
It's not enough
to take down the lawyer.
We need someone on the inside.
CHRISTINE:
If they figure out you're a cop,
they won't just kill you.
They'll torture you to find out
how much you know first.
And if that leads back to me,
they'll...
BRIAN: Hey. Hey.
Let's not let that happen.
Where we take you, Howard
will never be able to find you.
Look at me.
You can start a new life.
CHRISTINE: Okay.
[ Breathes deeply]
What do you need me to do?
ROOKER: [ Humming ]
[Grunts]
That's the number to this burner
phone. Completely untraceable.
[ Paper rustling ]
Text your address to that number
tomorrow, and I'll come get you.
CHRISTINE: What about Howard?
ROOKER: Two drops of this
in his food or drink,
and he'll be out for 24 hours.
By then, I'll have the cash.
And we'll be
halfway to Mexico...
to start our retirement.
DRUG DEALER: Product's good.
BRIAN: $2 million in cash
just like we talked about.
Do we have a deal?
DRUG DEALER:
Yeah, we got a deal.
ROOKER:
Brian, your cover is blown.
Your cover is blown.
Do you hear me?
DRUG DEALER: What the fuck
you think you're doin'?
[Western-style music plays]
ROOKER: [ Humming ]
[Gunfire]
Sorry, Brian.
It's a lot of money.
[Siren wailing ]
Brian.
We need to talk.
[Western-style music plays]
CHRISTINE: [Giggling]
[Gun cocks]
[Gunshot]
[ Choir vocalizing ]
[Country music plays]