¶ [ Old-time Country ]
That's enough, boys.
Fellow citizens
of Santa Maria.
Today is a big day...
in the history
of our thriving
community,
for we have persuaded
that noted disciple
of law and order,
the greatest man-hunter
in the Southwest...
to make his
headquarters here,
United States Marshal
Pat Garrett.
¶ [ Resumes ]
Good morning.
Who do you see about
making a bank loan?
Customary to see a banker.
That's not a bad idea.
Where is he?
Right here. Frenger's the name.
Glad to know ya.
Davis is my name.
Uh-huh. Well, just what--
Too much noise out here.
Come on in.
That celebration's
for Pat Garrett.
He's the fella
that gave Billy the Kid
what was coming to him.
Yeah.
Now, then, Davis,
what can I do for you?
I'd like to borrow
a little money.
That's what we're here for.
- How much do you need?
- Oh, about $2,000.
Two thousand? I'd say
that was a lot more
than a little money.
[ Chuckling ]
Yes, I guess it is.
Uh, stranger around here,
aren't you?
Yes, you might say that.
For a loan of that size,
the bank demands
pretty good collateral.
Oh, I got the best collateral
in the world... right here.
[ Trigger Cocks ]
I don't like
jokes, Davis.
That's fine.
This is no joke.
- So, that's it.
- That's it.
You'll never get
aw-- away with this.
I'm not trying to get away
with anything, Frenger.
It's just gonna be
an ordinary bank loan,
legal and friendly-like.
You're gonna give me the money.
I'll give you an I.O.U.
Huh!
Keep your hands
on the desk.
You're kind of careless,
aren't you, Frenger?
Gave me 200 too much.
People get hurt
when they get
too careless.
You and I are going
for a little ride.
Better lock that safe.
A lot of dishonest
people in this world.
I guess it's true that
I have some reputation.
But I'm not claiming
any credit for that.
Because I'm backed
by a force
that can't be beaten--
law and order... and justice.
Head for that
buckskin horse.
Look a little happier.
Talk to me.
What'll I say?
You might try
saying your prayers.
Come on.
Smile.
Well, folks, I guess
I've been up here
talking long enough.
Anytime any of you have
any complaints, you can always
find me in my office.
[ All Applauding ]
Hold it!
Get down.
Take your boots off.
Take 'em off!
Now see here, Davis--
Hand 'em here.
Thanks for the loan.
Adios.
Howdy, Frenger.
What's the matter?
Can't you afford boots?
Today when you were shouting
about law and order,
my bank was held up
by a vicious,
cold-blooded killer.
Made me walk
all the way back
from Coyote Canyon.
Suppose you calm down,
tell me what happened.
What'd he look like?
Well, he was tall.
Wore a-- Oh, looked like
any other cowboy.
I demand a posse.
I'm offering a reward
of $3,000...
for the man who brings him in
dead or alive.
Wait a minute, men.
I'd like to acquaint you
with the way I work.
Sometimes these dead-or-alive
rewards are inclined
to make a man too eager.
I won't stand for any
unnecessary shooting.
I want to warn
every one of you.
If you bring this man in dead,
I don't want to find
any holes in his back.
That's all.
Pleasure to have
known you, Sonny.
[ Rattling ]
[ Train Toots ]
Maybe you want to
move behind,
huh, senor?
Yes. Thanks.
Didn't get your ticket,
did I?
What's the matter
with your arm?
I cut myself.
Say, there's a railroad
nurse aboard. I'll get her.
Oh, never mind--
Hello.
I'm Miss Hollister,
the nurse.
May I see your arm?
Oh, I must have misunderstood.
I thought you accidentally
cut yourself.
No, a rattlesnake bit me.
I had to bleed it myself.
You should have seen
a doctor immediately.
Well, all a doctor'd do
is bleed it.
Perhaps.
How long ago
did this happen?
Not long.
I'll have to clean this.
This may hurt.
Do you feel
nauseated?
No'm.
Don't do that!
Well, it has to be
bandaged.
Yes, but with
something clean.
Would you hold this,
please?
You may feel quite ill
in a little while, but
that's a natural reaction.
Don't be alarmed.
I'll be right here.
Yes'm.
There you are, Mr.--
McEwen. Ross McEwen.
Try to be
as quiet as possible.
If you need anything,
have the conductor
call me.
I hope you feel
better now.
I'm sure I will, ma'am.
That's his saddle.
I remember the markin's.
Looks like he didn't
swap horses, or he wouldn't
have cached his saddle.
We know one thing--
He's still around here,
holed up someplace.
Yes, he wouldn't be fool enough
to get on a train, where
people might see him.
That's right.
Unless he's smart enough
to figure...
that we wouldn't think
he'd do a fool thing like that.
Huh?
Get the horses, Glen.
Can you show us
where you found it?
You'll have to hold
the train a few minutes.
We've got orders to search.
Why? What's up?
Lookin' for someone.
Who?
That's our business.
Oh, all right.
Go right ahead, then.
We ain't lettin' him
cut in on the reward.
You two wait
for the end car.
All right.
[ Snoring ]
Nothing in
the other cars.
Well, I didn't think
he'd be on a train
coming this way.
[ Man ]
He wouldn't get
on any train...
with a $3,000 reward
on his head.
[ Train Whistle Blowing ]
Yes, that's his horse,
all right.
Sure is
a peculiar brand.
Yep.
[ Boy ]
Indians are coming!
You're gonna be scalped!
[ Screaming ]
I'm gonna scalp ya.
Shh. Go away.
Junior!
You sick.
Where have you been?
For goodness' sakes.
I thought you fell off
the train!
I'm sorry he bothered you.
He's had too much train,
I guess.
Well, I think
you'll live, Mr. McEwen.
Kind of looks
that way, ma'am.
Going all the way through
to El Paso?
No. Why? Is that
where you're going?
No, I'll be stationed
at the new railroad hospital
in Alamogordo.
Well, I asked for it.
Back home, it all sounded
so exciting.
Nurse for the railroad,
new frontiers,
the-- the romantic West.
"The romantic West."
Look at it.
I got a sneaking suspicion
you like your East
better than the West.
Like it?
Why, there's no comparison.
All you've got here
is miles of rocks and desert
and hills with no trees.
We've got a lot
of wonderful--
Rattlesnakes?
- Buenas dias, señorita, señor.
- Good morning.
I hope the news of the washout
has not interfered
with your plans.
- Washout?
- Oh, perhaps you have not
heard yet.
Very big rain ahead.
The tracks have gone out.
We will all have to leave
the train at Albuquerque.
[ Bell Dinging ]
Albuquerque Palace Hotel,
right this way.
This way for the Palace Hotel.
Well, folks, looks like
there won't any trains
out of here for maybe a week.
[ People Grumbling ]
Hold on, now. The agent here
has fixed things up for you
so you can stay at the hotel.
The railroad will pay the bills
and take care of the baggage.
Now, if there any of you
who can't wait for
repairs on the road,
there's a mail hack that'll
take you to Gallup on the
other side of the washout.
More than likely save you
a day or two.
What time the hack leave?
5:00 tomorrow morning.
- 5:00, senorita.
- Mr. and Mrs. Winston
and Junior.
- Trotter. Help with baggage.
- We'll take care of everything,
Mr. Trotter.
Put me down for a seat.
Monte Marquez.
How about you, senorita?
5:00 in the morning?
No, thanks.
One for McEwen.
Well, Miss Hollister,
I guess I won't be
seeing you again.
Thanks for everything.
Put me down
for a seat.
Fay Hollister.
Junior!
Where are you, Junior?
Mama!
Junior!
Where's Junior?
Want a bite, Mom?
Junior!
Pa, I'm so worried.
Will you stop worrying?
Everything's gonna be
all right.
I can't help it. I--
Oh, Mr. McEwen.
Have you heard the news?
There's a killer loose.
Is that so?
Who'd he kill?
Ma, there you go again.
Nobody's been killed.
She heard some talk about
a fellow who held up a bank.
You don't say.
Have they picked up
his trail yet?
If they have not,
they will soon.
There's a very big
reward for him.
[ Conductor ]
All right.
Let's get on, folks.
Junior, get back here
where you belong!
Hurry up.
[ Whistles ]
Giddup! Giddup!
Giddup!
Is it much farther
to Gallup?
Naw, we'll make it
in a couple days, easy.
You mean,
we'll be doing this
all day long?
Except when they stop
to water the horses
at Anderson.
You're gonna wear yourself out
if you keep fighting
every bump, Miss Hollister.
Just lean back
and relax.
Relax?
On this bouncy bandwagon?
Sure, you can, if you try.
Just sit limp
and roll with it.
Oh, I'm sorry.
My pleasure, miss.
Here.
Lean against me.
Uh-uh.
I said relax.
There's our stop up ahead.
Right by Inscription Rock.
Howdy, Al.
Where'd you get
all the customers?
Washout on a line.
Think you can fit us?
Be a pleasure.
Might take a little time.
Say, why don't you folks
look around a little?
You might find it interesting.
All right, folks. Get down.
Don't wander off too far.
We'll be eating soon.
[ Miss Hollister ]
"Paso por aqui."
What does that mean
in English?
Uh, paso por aqui
means, uh,
"Pass this way--"
"He pass this way."
[ Chuckles ]
They stopped to carve
their names in the rock?
Oh, Miss Hollister,
this you must know...
about El Moro, this rock.
Very long ago,
many people are unhappy
in their own land.
So they come here
to start a new life...
in this so-wonderful
country of yours.
They reach here.
But out there is wilderness,
and maybe they never return.
Then they look up
at El Moro standing here,
so strong,
and it give them strength.
For here they find
water, shade and shelter.
And so people will know
that they had been here,
that they passed this way,
they carve into the stone
with daggers a record--
maybe a gravestone.
"Paso por aqui."
And the year of it.
Adventurous scoundrels,
but brave men, all of them,
who have left their--
how do you say it--
impression, "imprenta"--
Imprint.
That is it.
Brave men who leave
their imprint on El Moro
for us to read.
Oh, I'm sorry.
The rock, it make me
forget myself.
I hope I have not
talked too much.
No, I was just thinking,
isn't it strange
how everything
worthwhile in life...
is made possible
only by sacrifice.
Sí, señorita.
[ Triangle Ringing ]
Grub's on!
Come and get it!
[ All Chattering ]
[ Man ]
It's good!
Well, not to be
rushin' you folks,
but we'll be rollin' soon.
- More coffee?
- No, thanks.
Hello, boys.
What brings you this way?
Tryin' to catch up with
the mail hack. Got some reward
posters on that bank bandit.
I want you to drop them off
at the sheriff's office
at Gallup.
- Sure.
- Bandit?
Where's Junior?
Junior!
Junior, where are you?
Come here!
Oh, Junior.
It's just like I told ya, Pa.
We'll all be killed.
There ain't nothin'
to get jumpy about,
ma'am.
No. We figure
he ain't nowhere
around here.
Tack these up someplace,
will you, Anderson?
A bank bandit?
What's this all about?
Well, a fella walked into
the Santa Maria bank,
don't fire a shot...
and walks out with $2,000.
He even give the banker
an I.O.U for it,
signed Jefferson Davis.
[ Man ]
Jefferson Davis?
Yeah, and that ain't all.
While he's robbing the bank,
guess who's down the street...
making a speech
about the law?
Pat Garrett!
That ain't so funny
to the banker.
He's put up
a $3,000 reward for him,
dead or alive.
Dead or alive?
What kind of laws
do you have out here?
He only stole $2,000.
Why, it doesn't
make sense.
I think maybe perhaps
the banker means to prove...
it is more profitable
to catch a bandit
than to be one.
Well, of course, crime
must be punished, but
to kill a man for stealing--
You're in the West now,
Miss Hollister. It seems
everybody gets law-abiding...
when there's
a reward at stake.
Time to be rollin',
folks.
Come, Junior.
[ All Murmuring ]
Uh, don't suppose any
of you saw a tall hombre
riding a buckskin...
with a "raft
and wine glass" brand.
[ McEwen ] I figure him
to stay out of sight
of trains or mail hacks.
[ Man ] I just thought
you might have seen him
before you got on the train...
if you happen to come
from Santa Maria way.
- Well, uh, I-- I just--
- Senor.
You will excuse me, please.
Perhaps you have
overlooked one thing.
If your Mr. Jefferson Davis
have the cunning
to rob a bank...
under the nose of the very great
Pat Garrett and escape,
then I think he would
not long remain
on a buckskin horse.
If I were this man, I would be
on my way to México
muy pronto, yes, no?
Yeah, I suppose so.
Anderson, how about some food?
Mister, you aren't wearing
a leather jacket.
Go on, go on.
Your mother wants you.
Ma, that man there--
[ Junior Crying ]
Oh!
- Junior, you get--
[ Indistinct ]
- [ Crying Continues ]
Stop crying, or I'll give you
a good whipping.
Miss Hollister, if we
do not hurry, the driver,
he will go off without us.
I suppose leather jackets
and checkered bandanas...
are rather common
out here, aren't they?
¿Quién sabe, señorita?
But I think soon that eight
or nine innocent men...
who wear them
will be in jail,
or maybe shot or hanged.
[ Man ]
We gotta go.
Senorita, the hack.
Checkered neckerchief.
Say, Mr. Garrett,
there was a fellow--
I remember now!
He cut himself,
and I got a railroad nurse
to fix him up.
Yes, sir. That was
the same night some
deputy searched the train.
Didn't find nothin', though.
That railroad nurse--
What's her name?
Miss Hollister.
Do you know where
she was going?
Yes, to that new hospital
at Alamogordo.
There.
How's that?
Fine.
We'll be getting into
Alamogordo soon.
That's where I get off.
I know.
Card?
I'll take two.
Three.
I'll take four.
I'll bet one white chip.
Call that.
Call.
I am being very foolish.
I will raise the bet.
I guess I'll call.
Ooh! All hearts!
Oh, I guess I won't.
Neither will I.
That's good enough for me.
[ Man ]
Alamogordo, 15 minutes.
Sorry, boys,
I got to leave.
Lovely night,
isn't it?
Yes.
Yes, it is.
Miss Hollister--
Yes?
Do you mind if I smoke?
Not at all.
The night always
changes things somehow.
Everything seems soft,
gentle.
Shuts out other things.
Troubles.
Miss Hollister...
you'll be getting off
soon, and,
well, there's-- there's
something I want you
to know about me.
That day I got on the train,
the day you fixed my arm,
I was grateful,
but I never intended--
You see, when I got
on the train, I was--
I was--
Alamogordo next.
Ten minutes.
[ Door Closes ]
You were saying?
Oh, it-- it wasn't important.
Well, I suppose
I'd better get my things.
I hope everything
turns out well for you.
Good-bye.
Mr. McEwen, I know
I shouldn't be talking
like this,
but I just can't help it.
If-- If you're in
some kind of trouble,
it doesn't matter.
I'd like to help.
Now, now.
Everything's gonna be
all right.
We'll be pulling in
to the station soon, and...
you want to look pretty
when you get off,
don't you?
There.
That's better.
I'm gonna get
your things.
And who knows. One of
these days we might be
taking a buggy ride together.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Train Whistle Blows ]
Alamogordo.
[ Man ]
Aboard!
[ Train Whistle Blows ]
Oh--
Uh, pardon me.
Is there a Miss Hollister here?
[ Woman ]
Uh, no, there isn't.
Excuse me, senor.
That is Miss Hollister.
Oh. Thank you.
Miss Hollister?
Yes.
I'm sorry I'm late,
but I just never seem
to have enough time.
You must be Dr. Eldredge.
Yes, I'm Dr. Eldredge.
I won't say,
"Welcome to Alamogordo."
I'll just say, "Welcome to you."
Oh, thank you.
I'll take the rug.
All right. I have a rig
outside to drive us
to the hospital.
I imagine you Easterners
find our West rather rough.
But I do hope
you'll get to like it.
I'm sure I will.
Senor McEwen, I see
that you have missed
your train.
Well, what do you know.
I guess I did.
[ Chuckles ]
¶ [ Honky-tonk ]
Hi, boss.
Monte!
Glad to see you back!
How you do?
Win or lose?
Lose.
Good.
How are you?
You seem to know
everybody around here.
Sí, señor.
My cousins and I,
we own this place.
You see, the bar,
it is Cousin Phillip's.
The restaurant
is Cousin Jose's.
The tables are mine.
Looks all right.
No matter what happens,
we never run out of cousins.
Same as usual?
Sí.
No, thanks.
And you,
Senor McEwen.
What will you do
in Alamogordo?
Oh, I might get a job.
That should be easy.
I hear great numbers
are hunting that
bank bandit.
A $3,000 reward is
a great deal of money.
Yeah.
There are men
who would kill for it.
But to a gambler, me,
this money would be
most unlucky.
Yeah.
It might be a little
unhealthy too.
Monte, it's good
to see you back.
Senor Burnett, how are you?
I want you to meet
a very good friend of mine.
Ross McEwen.
He needs a job.
How are you?
Know anything about
working cattle?
Some.
I can use a top hand.
You got one.
Fine. The job
may not last long.
Three of my boys quit
to go chasin'
that bank bandit.
Said they'd be back
when they collected
the reward.
I'll make you a deal,
Mr. Burnett. If they catch
the bandit, I'll quit.
[ Coughing ]
I'll shake on that.
Bartender,
how about some drinks?
Mr. and Mrs. Winston
and Junior,
Trotter, Bowie,
McEwen,
Marquez,
Miss Hollister.
Room for two more
on the mail hack
tomorrow morning?
I'll make room.
Good.
[ Burnett ]
Hello, Sheriff.
That your new hand?
Yeah.
Pretty good boy
with the stock too.
Why?
Well, just like to know
who's around.
If you don't mind stopping
in the shade of this
weeping willow tree,
I'd like to fix
my harness.
Ross, I don't want to ask you
what you've done or why,
but if you have
made a mistake,
wouldn't it be better to--
Give myself up?
I didn't want to say it,
but surely it would be better...
than to spend your life
running away.
I've always felt it isn't
what a man has done
in the past that matters.
It's what he does
in the present. Now.
Do you mean that?
Of course I do.
Fay, there's a lot of things
I wanted to tell you
this afternoon,
but I guess
it'll have to wait.
What are you
going to do?
I don't know yet.
You recall a group
that came through here
last week?
Was there a tall
young feller
among them?
'Fraid I can't
help you much.
A lot of folks came past
the rock that week
on account of the washout.
And one of 'em
was a pretty girl.
Ooh, come to think
of it, there was
a tall young fella.
Seemed sort of
interested in her.
You remember what
he was wearin'?
Mmm, can't recall.
He's across the border
by now, Pat.
Maybe.
Deal a good hand to someone
else besides your friend
McEwen, will you, Monte?
My friend has won
also on your deal.
Jim.
On the house.
Pass.
A blue.
Two blue is better.
Are you in?
Hmm?
What's the bet?
Three blues.
Cards?
Come.
One.
How about you?
Is that a pat hand
you're holdin'?
I better take a look.
I'll take four cards.
I'm not afraid
of you, Lou.
Two blues.
I guess I have to sweeten
the pot for myself.
Ten blues better.
It'll cost you just
ten more to see
what I've got.
I'm not that curious.
I'm not either.
You ought to be careful
with a loaded gun.
You might shoot someone.
You question
my dealing, senor?
No, I got enough.
Cash me in.
So am I. I'm quittin'.
That suits me.
I should've quit
before I started.
McEwen. No, I don't
recall the name.
Seen anybody who
matches the description?
No.
Come to think of it,
there's a new hired hand
at the Circle "M."
That might be him.
Want to ride out
and take a look?
Yeah.
I'll get the horses.
Sheriff.
Huh?
Do you know anybody
named Monte Marquez?
Oh, sure. He and his cousin
run the Longhorn Saloon
down the street.
Take us up there.
All right.
I'd like you to
do me a favor, Monte.
You have only to ask.
Uh, a friend of mine
borrowed some money
from a bank in Santa Maria.
I'd like to pay
some of it back
on account, indirectly.
You think you could
mail this from somewhere
outside Alamogordo?
I think
it could be done.
But how will the banker
know who's sending it?
Just sign the letter
"Jefferson Davis."
He'll know.
Will you drink
a little toast with me?
[ Spanish ]
To un caballero
valiente.
Senor Jefferson Davis.
[ Door Opens ]
I'm looking for
Monte Marquez.
Just a minute.
Someone ask for me?
Over there.
You wish to
see me, senor?
Yes. My name's Garrett.
Not Pat Garrett,
the most famous marshal
in all the West?
Well, I'm Garrett, anyway.
Drinks for Senor Garrett
and his friend.
It is on the house.
Whiskey.
That's mighty nice of you,
but my deputy's in
kind of a hurry.
- Like to ask you
a few questions.
- Sí, señor, if I can help.
[ Garrett ]
I'm looking for a fella,
calls himself Ross McEwen.
- I understand you met him.
- Ross McEwen.
Oh, sí, señor.
He was on the train with me.
Very nice fella.
He's working at the Circle "M"
rancho. It is only eight,
nine miles from here.
Thanks. I might have
that drink with you
on the way back.
Be a pleasure,
senor.
Thanks, Monte.
I will miss you,
amigo.
If you will permit me, senor,
you will need provisions
and a horse.
They will be in the back
when you are ready.
Ross!
I was hoping
I'd find you
off-duty.
I have to leave for a while,
but I wanted to see you.
I have a little
present for you.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Oh, no.
Ross.
What is it?
Something's the matter.
I haven't time to explain now.
But I'd like for you
to wear that.
[ Hoofbeats ]
Hey.
Ross, what's happened?
You're running away again.
I'm an outlaw.
I'm the one that robbed
the Santa Maria bank.
Pat Garrett's
in Alamogordo.
I'm wanted dead or alive.
You've got to stay
away from me.
Marshal!
Miss Hollister's not here!
Her bed hasn't been slept in!
- When did you see her last?
- Why, yesterday afternoon,
before she went off-duty.
What do you think happened?
She have any visitors?
No. No I didn't see anybody.
Do you think she's all right?
Nothing for you
to worry about, Doctor.
Yeah, don't worry.
Get your men, Egan. Warn 'em
before they start shooting,
McEwen has a woman with him.
Pick me up
at the telegraph office.
I want that bandit
brought in.
If he's dead,
there'll be some
extra money in it for you.
Here they come,
right into our lap.
Look what's coming.
A posse, probably
from Alamogordo.
Follow me.
Keep going.
I'll catch up with you.
That'll hold 'em.
Spread out, men!
If you find an opening,
take it.
You can't get through
there, Pat.
It's a solid wall of flames.
Let's get to the top!
Come on.
That way's blocked too.
Garrett's forcing us
right back to Alamogordo.
You can't go on.
The longer you keep running,
the worse it'll get.
That's a chance
I've got to take.
You said you paid back part
of the money. Go to Garrett--
It's too late.
You sound as though
you're afraid.
Ross, you're not
a coward.
You'd better head back
to town. They won't bother
you if you're alone.
You can't run away
from yourself.
You're not a criminal,
but if you don't
stop now, you will be.
You'll go on and on.
You'll have to steal
to live.
And then one of these days,
you'll have to shoot
your way out.
And then it will be too late.
You'll be just another outlaw.
A killer!
Maybe I am a coward.
Depends on how
you look at it.
There's only one way
to look at a coward.
Good-bye, Ross.
- It's the girl.
- Come on!
Well, if it ain't
the pretty little nurse.
Better come with us.
Garrett will be
glad to see you.
Not so fast, Ben.
This little lady's
worth money.
Maybe she'd like to
talk to us first.
I have nothing
to say to you!
Help the lady from her horse.
Where'd you leave
Ross McEwen?
Where is he?
Let me go!
You're hurting me!
I get touchy
when it comes to
manhandling women.
What did you
expect us to do?
Treat her like a lady?
Egan! Get 'em
out of here!
Before I lose
my temper.
[ Egan ]
Fescia, Gruber!
You all right, miss?
Sorry this had to happen.
It might give you
an idea of what
McEwen's up against.
These men are only
interested in that reward.
Alive or dead.
You care to tell me
where you left him?
While he's still alive?
Perhaps you don't understand
the seriousness of helping
a criminal to escape.
Unless he forced you
to go with him.
He didn't force me,
and he's not
a criminal.
Why can't you leave him alone?
You don't understand.
I'm trying to help this man.
If I capture him,
he'll go in walkin'.
The others get to him
first, you can't tell
what might happen.
I can't tell you
where I left him.
Well--
Mr. Garrett, I don't know much
about your Western justice,
but I do know this man
wants to do the right thing.
He's paid back part
of the money already.
It's true.
It must be clear, even to you,
that he's not a criminal
to be locked in a cell, or...
shot at like a wild animal.
McEwen's broken the law.
It's my job to bring him in.
And sooner or later,
I will.
Sheriff Egan, see that
Miss Hollister gets safely back
to Alamogordo.
What did you find out, Pat?
Something mighty peculiar.
Seems we're chasin' a fellow
who robbed a bank,
and then gave the money
back to the banker.
Oh.
Well, fella, you come
a long ways without
getting any place.
[ Squeals ]
[ Lowing ]
Thanks, fella.
It's him, Pat.
Looks like he's quit tryin'
to get across the border.
Maybe.
What do you
make of it, Pat?
It might be his.
Looks like he's headin'
for the sands.
On foot?
He's got too much sense
to try that without water.
One chance in a hundred
of gettin' through.
Maybe.
If it was me,
I'd risk it.
I got a notion
this man would too.
Señor?
[ Speaking Spanish ]
The strength--
Dip-- Diphtheria.
That's far enough.
I'm buying your horse.
Tell me, can a man
get through that pass?
Señor, por favor.
Just tell me,
can a man get through?
Sí.
A night's ride.
You turn at the rock.
Señor, por Dios.
Por Dios, señor.
[ Boy Coughing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
I'm here to help you.
Gracias, amigo. Gracias.
[ Boy Coughing ]
Easy, son.
Easy, now.
I'll take care of you.
[ Gagging ]
Easy, now.
I didn't look at the brand
on this steer when I shot him,
but I don't believe...
there's a man in New Mexico
mean enough to make a fuss
under the circumstances.
Ah, come on now.
You're bigger than he is.
You gotta eat more.
That's it.
[ Coughs ]
[ Labored Breathing ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Coughs ]
[ Gasps ]
How are they now?
Oh, I don't know.
There must be something more
we can do for them.
No man could have
done more.
You haven't any sulfur,
have you? It'd do 'em good
to breathe the fumes.
Oh, no, senor.
There's sulfur in gunpowder.
I'll take some out
of my cartridges,
and lead it down, let it dry.
Make a smudge out of it.
That might help.
[ Boy Coughing ]
I want you to breathe deep,
just like he did.
Breathe deep, son.
That's fine medicine.
Helps his cough
and gives me one.
A man can't just disappear.
He's gotta be around
here someplace.
Sounds reasonable,
but where?
Yeah, that's what's
got me worried.
My son,
why do you not rest?
Don Florencio, we need
a doctor and medicine.
It can't be far
to the nearest town.
I'll take the horse--
My son, if you go,
some will surely die
before you get back.
The nearest town
is Alamogordo.
To go there and return
is two days.
They will need someone,
and I will be helpless.
Maybe I can rig up
some kind of a signal.
There must be someone just
fool enough to come and see
what it's all about.
Clint, that smoke--
looks like somebody's
trying to attract attention.
Say, it does at that.
How far do you figure
it is to that signal?
I don't know. Looks like
a pretty long ride.
Maybe for nothin'.
Well, there's one thing
clear-- somebody's
askin' for help.
I reckon that's us,
Clint.
[ Boy Gasping ]
[ Ross ]
All right, son,
I'm coming.
[ Boy Coughing ]
Clint, there's people
dyin' in there.
Looks like diphtheria.
There's a man carin' for them
that's almost as bad off
as they are.
You get to Alamogordo
as fast as you can
and bring back a doctor.
That's fine.
That's fi--
[ Horse Galloping Away ]
I saw your smoke, boy.
Guess you could use
a little help.
Yeah, I guess I could.
They are better?
Yes, them seem
more comfortable anyway.
We'll know more
when the doctor gets here.
Still asleep.
A week of sleep
is what he needs.
The very bullet from his gun
he used to make sulfur to burn.
This boy, Senor Garrett,
there never was one like him.
He's the reason
we are alive.
[ Horses Approaching ]
It is the doctor?
You're a welcome sight,
Doctor.
See to my daughter
and los niños first.
What's your interest here,
Mr. Marquez?
I came to see if I
could help, Senor Garrett.
You see, don Florencio,
he's the only one
who's not my cousin.
He's my uncle.
That's mighty nice of you.
[ Spanish ]
I'm comin'. I'm comin'.
[ Coughing Continues ]
Oh, Carlos, Carlos.
Agua.
[ Mutters ]
My name's Slim.
Who are you?
I am Monte Marquez.
Senor Garrett sent word
there was a sickness here.
I suppose, uh,
you met the marshal.
Yes, but we didn't
get to talk much.
I think he will be out soon.
He's in there with the doctor
and the, uh, nurse.
And Señor Garrett's deputy
is out there taking care
of the horses.
Mr. Marquez, your cousins
are coming along fine.
Doctor wants lots of hot water.
[ Garrett ]
Then we'll need firewood.
I'll get it.
Oh, Slim.
This is Miss Hollister,
the nurse.
How do you do?
I, uh--
I better get the firewood.
Slim.
There's a razor
in my saddlebag.
You're welcome to use it.
Thanks.
[ Ross ]
Who is it?
Senor Garrett.
Where's he going?
[ Mutters ]
But I think the way's
open for you.
If you were Garrett,
where would you look for
this no-account bank bandit?
South. The border.
That's just what I figured.
I think I'll head north.
I could bring you supplies
at Inscription Rock.
Amigo.
Oh.
Senor.
Give me time to get
in back of him.
No. I'll play this out alone.
Leaving?
Yeah.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Adios, amigo.
Vaya con Dios.
Adios.
Well, Doctor,
what you think?
[ Doctor ] Barring relapse,
we should save everyone.
Good.
You look pretty healthy
to me, muchachos.
But it was a narrow squeak.
That, uh, young man
who nursed them through,
why, Monte, no one on earth
could have done a better job,
considering what he had
to work with.
Nothing practically,
but his own two hands.
You are right, Doctor.
This fellow's a man
complete.
He has the courage
to gamble with life.
I think it is with no pleasure
that we see this fellow
ride out of our lives...
and our hearts.
But me,
I will see him again.
I could deliver a message.
Hello, Slim.
I'm not wearing
a gun, boy.
Mind if I ride
a ways with you?
Why?
I'd like to have
a little talk with you.
Suit yourself.
That nurse, Miss Hollister,
she's a nice girl.
She's all right.
Just all right?
Keep her out of this!
That'll be hard to do now.
I figure you're too busy
a man to waste time
riding with me.
I have plenty of time
for you.
That's a mighty fine thing
you did for that
Mexican family.
No more than any
other man would do.
Not any man.
Especially a man
who's running away from the law,
Mr. Ross McEwen.
But your stopping
proved one thing--
you've got backbone
from your neck way down
to the seat of your pants.
Listen. Get this straight.
I paid back some of the money
I stole and I'm gonna
pay the rest of it.
I don't plan to spend
the next ten years of my life
rottin' in a cell.
Don't blame ya.
What are you gonna
do about it?
That's up to you.
Listen, Garrett--
Ever been in Tularosa?
What's Tularosa
got to do with it?
We're headin' that way.
If I was to ride in with ya
and put you on a train, nobody
would think a thing about it.
Just Pat Garrett
waving good-bye to a friend.
You'd be free.
Don't tell me
the law's gettin' soft.
But on the other hand,
if I was to tell a judge
and jury that you're
paying back the money,
that you stopped to help
a sick family,
but you gave yourself up
voluntarily,
well, I'm inclined
to believe that a judge and
jury might be very lenient.
Garrett, there's
someone I have to see
at Inscription Rock.
Go ahead.
What's holdin' you?
I'll meet you at Anderson's.
Amigo,
I got the provisions.
I guess I've been blind.
No, I realized I might...
never see you again.
When Monte told me he was
going to meet you here,
I had to come.
It'll be easier
now that you're here.
I'm giving myself up.
Garrett?
[ Ross ]
He's waiting for me now.
It's funny.
On the way here, I made up
my mind to go with you...
if you wanted me.
Fay, it means we won't
be together for a while,
but... if we can forget
what's happened,
I think it's worth it.
Everything
all right, boy?
Yeah, Pat.
Miss Hollister,
I would not push my smallest
upon this large world.
I did not tell you this before,
but one of these who pass here,
not of the first,
not of the very great,
but one who was also brave,
he was of mine.
My very great, great papa.
I hear this
by the firelight
when I was small.
And this Ross McEwen,
he pass by here
and do good things.
His name too
belong on El Moro.
Un caballero valiente,
Ross McEwen.
"Paso por aquí."
Passed this way.
Ross McEwen.
Valiant gentleman.
Closed captions ripped by
Tantico (Croatia) 07.2011