[Man]
Run!
Hurry!
[grunts]
Come on. Up.
Come on!
[cocks]
[gunshot]
[horse whinnying]
They're still shooting
at us!
Go!
[Man]
There's a boat!
Hey, get on that boat!
- [grunts]
- Let's go! Let's go!
Grab that paddle,
Jimmy!
Grab it! Let's go!
They're following fast!
They're coming!
They're following close!
[cocks]
It's moving.
Go get me the Sharps
with the sight. Now!
I'm gonna do this right.
[panting]
I'm gonna get your gun.
Maybe it's an omen.
Just seems like bad luck
or something, you know?
There ain't never been
nothing like this.
[sighs]
If I don't claim it now,
some other asshole will
and take the fame.
And Snyder didn't pay
for nothing.
I'm telling you, Mooar,
it ain't right.
Frankly, I feel
I walk away right now,
you'll come back
and claim it yourself.
[cheering]
[cheering continues]
Thank you! Thank you!
We'll be right back.
You can have
some more pictures.
[Man] John Mooar!
Little business here.
We'll be right back.
I'll tell you what,
Mr. Mooar.
You put this place
on the map.
I want you
to meet a fella.
He's the one
who led me to the white.
He's a big old boy,
ain't he?
Isn't he?
[chuckling]
Come on inside.
I got plans.
This is a lot of money
for tracking an animal.
So how about a drink?
Snyder, Texas.
That's got
a good ring to it.
He can run your whiskey
up to Granbury.
I'm not sure I trust Barkley
to do it.
No. I got 12 jugs
of moonshine, homemade.
The best there is.
Can you get it
all in your boat?
Yes.
Good.
Then I'll send Barkley
to tell Gordon...
to meet on the river
in three days.
- You come back
with the payment.
- I agree.
This ought cover
the shipping costs.
That's a lot of money too.
Boys, come on.
If you don't mind,
I'd like folks to think...
it was shot
with my father's rifle.
I'll have Barkley
load up the whiskey.
Barkley!
Come on!
We'll load up some whiskey.
[Man]
If I could trouble you
for a few more photographs.
Sure.
[ Man ]
John!
[cheering]
Oh!
[Mooar]
Excuse me. We're gonna
take some more photographs.
Picture, please?
Yeah, yeah.
Please step back.
Make room for
the camera, please.
Thank you.
Step back, please.
A little more.
Excellent. Hold that.
[cheering]
Hey.
[sighs]
Good God.
Mm-mmm.
I got some confessing
to do anyway.
I can think of a few things
gone awry.
I don't think I've seen
such a pretty girl...
since last time I saw
your sister in Spokane.
[Man]
...my whole life.
Charlie Austin,
him and his colored companion--
I want him found,
and I want you
to punish him.
You get revenge
for me and my daughter.
[Man #2]
If you want us to do it,
it's gonna cost you.
If we can do it without force,
won't be much.
All it takes
is one little bullet,
and, bang, double the price.
[Man #1]
Now where did she go?
I can assure you,
we will try to avoid that.
Like I said,
we fire our guns in town,
it's twice the pay.
That's the deal.
We're going to Dallas, boys.
[Men laughing]
I'm real sorry
about your daughter.
Two thousand dollars
for "Champagne" Charlie Austin!
- [Men whooping]
- [gunshots]
Hyah!
[bell tolling]
[footsteps approaching]
[sighs]
[Irish accent]
Can I get a bottle
of whiskey down here?
My own mouth
is trying to kill me.
Pardon me.
Bottle of whiskey.
Anything brown water
whiskey'd be nice.
Ya Irish prick.
Oh, Lordy.
Bless you, darling.
Mmm. Mmm!
[coughing]
Hey!
What the hell is that?
Turpentine.
What are you doing?
Don't drink any more of that.
It was supposed to be a joke.
Yeah, well, I was hoping
it'd kill me.
[chuckles]
You know, there is
a dentist in town.
Yeah, well,
I think doctoring...
is no better
than petty sheep thieving,
which I used to be
really good at.
Isn't the dying man
gonna ask my name?
Pardon me. You are?
Katherine.
Well, Nurse Katherine,
can I offer you a taste?
[chuckles]
Ladies don't drink whiskey.
I like that.
But I bet you're lying.
[exhales]
Well, Jim,
[chuckles]
Doc Seegars is not
too far away from here.
I'm sure he could fix
that dreadful tooth.
I could walk you over there
if you like.
You're kindly persuasive.
Let me pay the man.
[coins clinking]
Shit.
Shall we?
Lead the way.
Thanks for nothing.
[James] You know,
what say we just go back
to my place at the Cherry?
I don't want you
to have a toothache...
when you escort me to dinner
this evening.
Oh, we got dinner plans
this evening?
Unless you have someone else
to take.
I'll see you
at the St. Charles
in a couple hours, Jim.
See you then, Nurse.
Oh, sweet God in heaven,
Lord God help us.
Hello?
Mister-- Or, uh, Dr. Seegars?
[Man, slurring]
He's not here!
He's away for the month to, uh,
wherever the hell.
You need some teeth made?
We don't do that anymore.
No, I'll just keep
my teeth, thanks.
He's gone for a month?
I'm afraid so.
- You're a dentist, then?
- Aye. Dr. Holliday.
That's what they put
on the sign.
I got a tooth that's trying
to put me under.
Well, have a seat.
Let me just grab
some equipment.
[sighs, coughs]
[James]
What are you doing?
What, are you
gonna get drunk?
Uh, no.
This is for you.
And you are gonna
want to have some.
Fires of hell...
mixed with the waters
from heaven.
[coughs]
Ahh.
Tell me, what's your name?
- Greg.
Do you have
a high tolerance for pain?
What?
Never mind.
Open.
[ James ]
Ow!
[screaming]
[grunts]
[groans]
That's heaven.
[sighs]
Uh, 13 dollars
and 14 cents.
That's an old-looking watch.
Well, as done as Ireland
was with me,
this is all I have
left of her.
I like it.
How's your tooth?
Well, besides--
[ Groans ]
not being able to chew,
it no longer feels like
there's a railroad spike in it.
[chuckles]
So I know all that money
isn't from the railroads.
Not all of it.
A lot of it is though.
Good honest money.
Honest money?
I used to steal things--
a lot--
when I was younger.
Well, still do.
I stole booze
down in Boston...
and on into Tennessee.
I didn't really like
who I was back then,
but I never knew
nothing better.
Nobody likes a thief.
Well, looks like
I like a thief.
[laughing]
I didn't know
you carried an arm.
Like I said,
Dallas is dangerous,
and I'm just a lady.
After last night,
you call yourself
a lady in the morning?
[gasps, laughs]
Now you play rough.
I've been ill.
Uh-huh.
Quit trying
to kiss me, girl.
I'm trying to rest.
You know,
I got a brand-new outfit,
and I haven't much
to do today.
You can teach me how
to shoot that pistol.
You know how
to shoot a pistol.
I'm 28 years of age,
and I've never fired
a pistol.
Well, maybe I'll have to
teach you a thing or two.
I'm meeting up with
a friend of mine right now,
but let's meet
later tonight downstairs.
- You're occupied all day?
- Not all day.
Like I said,
I'll meet you later on,
by the harpist.
I'll be in the wash.
I'll come say good-bye
before I leave.
Hey.
You forgot your string
for your hair.
I'll get it when I come back.
Go to sleep.
[bell tolling]
[crowd chattering]
♪♪♪♪ [band playing]
[laughter]
Marty Parks.
We heard you was up in Wichita.
[Man coughs]
Excuse me.
There a man
in here by the name
of "Champagne" Charlie Austin?
[no audible dialogue]
Thank you very much.
All right, boys.
He's in there.
You and me walk in first.
You boys stay here
till we signal.
Tower.
Yeah?
Back us up.
Hey, let me borrow
your sprayer.
No. What if I gotta
let him have it out here?
[Tower]
What if I run out of ammo?
Try throwing your gun
or askin' for some ammo,
getting shot.
Tower, get your own arm.
Asshole.
Me and Bacas can flank them
if they come out the back.
They always run out back.
You stay out here
till we signal.
You got that?
You coming?
[bell tolling]
[crowd chattering]
[chattering]
That's him right there.
The one in the jacket.
Damn cheat!
Don't call me a cheat.
You damn cheat!
Aw, Charlie, don't be sore.
Can someone get ol' "Champagne"
Charlie Austin here a drink?
I don't need a drink!
I want my money back!
- Charlie!
- [gasps]
Easy, Charlie.
- This is your bar.
It ain't no damn alleyway.
- [cocks]
You say another
smart remark...
come out of your mouth,
I'm gonna shove
them teeth down
the back of your throat.
Aw, your breath
is burning my eyes.
Ha, ha!
[Charlie]
Don't you do it now!
[chattering]
Well, let's have a go,
Charlie.
[Man]
Do it, Doc!
Don't do it!
[gunshot]
Is that the signal?
We're about to find out.
Put your pistol
where your mouth is.
[shouts]
He must've found out
about the bounty on Austin.
Get out from behind
the table, Charlie.
- We'll just take turns.
- We stay here
and see who gets shot.
We still take the body.
[Holliday]
Well, let's have a go, Charlie.
[shouts]
- [shouts]
- [women scream]
- [laughs]
- You're a cheat!
[shouts]
[gunshot]
- [laughs]
- Run and get Sheriff Michaels.
And hurry up.
Well, we'll be right back.
I might.
To hell with this.
- Tower, see what's behind
this damn bar.
- My pleasure.
Have you lost your minds?
We are not doing this.
- You boys are gonna
rot in hell.
- Run out of here, old man.
Don't be scared, Will.
It's gonna be payday.
I ain't a thief.
Hey!
[laughing]
You work for me, boy.
Don't you forget that.
Holliday!
All right,
you son of a--
[laughs]
Oh, Charlie Austin.
Hold still.
You couldn't shoot your hand
if you put your finger
in the barrel.
Hold on!
I'm outta bullets!
Well, that's
all right, Charlie.
I'm not.
[Woman]
No! No!
Get away.
Get away! I'm okay!
[shouts]
[laughs]
It's payday, boys!
When you're done counting that,
you get Bacas to
bring up the horses.
You got that?
Oh, I got it.
What y'all doing back there?
Well, our good friend
Charlie Austin...
is worth a whole
lot of money to us,
and since we can't
take it outta him,
we're gonna take it
out of his bar.
We got kind of
an agreement.
You see?
I see.
Good boy.
Will, go around
the other side.
You see Austin come back
in here, you kill him.
You got that?
No. Nobody killing
the boss man.
Tower!
[Woman screams]
[Man shouts]
Greg! Greg, help me, Greg!
[Austin shouting]
Get up!
Katherine, what the hell
are you doing?
I'll talk with you later.
- Tower!
- He's dead!
[gunshots]
Y'all need to put down
your guns!
Tower!
[gunshot]
You gonna be next,
bastard, unless you drop
your gun!
What the hell you doing?
Put a bullet in him!
I ain't killing anybody!
Katherine, come on!
We gotta get you outta here!
Come on now.
I've gotta get him
off the street!
Damn it! Leave us be!
- [Charlie]
Let me go!
- No, no, baby.
We gotta get you
out of here.
Come on! Get up!
[Holliday]
Greg, help! Greg!
You've been lying to me
since the moment I met you.
I'm sorry. Help!
Over here!
He's trying to kill us!
Get your hands up!
You two grab him.
So y'all looking
for Austin, huh?
Well, you found him.
You ain't even Austin.
I am now.
[gunfire stops]
He's out.
- Get your hands up!
- [gunshot]
[gunshots]
[cocks]
- Where's Tower?
- Dead!
[crying out]
[groans]
Come on.
[gunfire continues]
Gonna have to head up
into that brush soon.
We can't outrun them
in this wagon.
But I didn't
do nothing wrong.
I shouldn't be
turning off nowhere.
Listen here, friend.
I ain't stopping,
so you can get off
any time you like.
Yeah, but I was
on here first.
Come on!
Look. This ride
came equipped with a sh--
Shit!
Damn it! Hold on!
Hey.
That wheel ain't
gonna last much longer.
What are you doing?
They're right behind us.
Quite a distance,
but it's that stage.
Let's go.
Hyah!
You wanna come with me,
you can.
If you are, get your ass
out of that seat.
Shit!
[two gunshots]
[horses whinny]
Come on out, you cowards!
I got no gun!
Show yourself!
You wanna be quiet?
I had to shoot the horses.
Shot the horses?
Are you out of your mind?
It'll draw too much attention
to ourselves...
if we ride into town
on somebody else's
branded horses.
Well, we're not exactly
in town, are we, Will?
That there
is the Brazos River,
and on the other side of it
is Granbury.
I tell you, your fella
in this Granbury...
better put some money
in my pocket real quick,
'cause I don't kill people
for it.
I don't kill people
Your gang shot up
the whole place.
That ain't me.
Do you understand?
When we get to town,
my friend can help us out.
But if you go back
to Dallas,
you're gonna have
a real hard time talking
your way out of a noose.
I'm just still trying...
to grasp just exactly
what the hell happened there.
All I know is
I gotta get my money back.
I have to get my money back.
Who am I to say you can't?
But we both know you ain't
never gonna see it again.
Come on. Let's get moving.
Just gotta swim across.
Can't do it.
What do you mean,
you can't do it?
Can't do it.
Not gonna do it.
Well, if you don't swim
across it, you're gonna
have to go around.
You know how long
you'll be walking for?
Two minutes ago,
I had a horse.
I told you, when we get to town,
my friend Benson...
can get us horses, ammo,
whatever we need.
Can't do it. Can't do it.
[chuckles]
You can't swim.
You job-stealing
son of a bitch,
you can't swim.
I can't swim?
I'll see you in town, Will,
but I better get
some real money, real quick.
Here I go.
Mm-hmm.
I'm gonna get in there.
[grunts]
[water splashing]
Oh, it's freezing.
All right.
I can't swim.
[chuckles]
[James, indistinct]
[Will]
Will you just try to swim?
Come on. Help me.
Come on.
Come on. Here we go.
Move it on there.
[men whooping]
Let's go.
Shut up.
Watch your line.
[pins clacking]
[Man]
Past the line!
[Men shouting]
[Man]
Come on, come on.
Knock 'em down!
Right now. Let's go.
Knock 'em down.
I never interfere with a man
while he's bowling.
[Man] Come on, brother.
Knock them down.
[Men shouting]
Come on!
[grunts]
- [clack]
- [Men groaning]
You're losing us money!
Get back! Damn it!
Come on!
I might just place myself down
for a game today.
Take on you and Spears.
I'm not gonna stand here
and let you lose it for me,
you bastard!
Ah. Here's one.
If you would
stop screaming--
"As he was valiant, I honor him.
But as he was ambitious,
I slew him."
Caesar. Easy.
Well, well done.
I'm gonna
slap your face,
my brother, Lord help me.
I would love the challenge,
but I'm enlisted to the bar.
I could use some help.
[men shouting]
[cocking]
Kid?
Whoa.
[cocks]
Damn it!
Ten-Pin Alley will be closed
the rest of the day!
I do not condone killing...
over wagers on my property.
Take it outta town!
Will you have Stillworth
clean this mess up?
Of course.
I'll be at the saloon
this evening.
[Man]
What about my $16?
[Man #2]
What aboutmy$16?
Funny thing, those two
were on the same team.
I'll see you
in the bar, kid.
Hyah!
I told you, Charlie,
if you want my carrots,
get them at the store.
Throw your legs over.
Come on.
Put your weight on me.
[groaning]
I got you. I got you.
Grab his hat, Maggie.
My whole right side...
feels pretty numb.
Right here.
What can I do?
What should I do?
Nothing.
I'm just gonna hold his head.
He's fine.
Hey, hey, hey!
I got his head.
He's all right.
Dad! Messed all over
the storefront, Moon!
Just step aside, Tompson.
Step aside.
Someone's gonna
clean this up.
I'll clean it up.
I got it.
No. No, Maggie.
You get yourself something
nice for your birthday.
Go ahead. Please.
Go on now.
It's gonna be all right, Johnny.
They're gonna fix you up, okay?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about
your birthday, Maggie.
It's okay.
Come on. Let's go.
Can you walk?
Yeah.
Watch your head.
You'll be all right.
[birds twittering]
Hey, Maggie.
Got these birds in
from Tennessee.
You wanna take a look?
Dad!
Got a mess out here!
Just have to put
a little pressure on it now.
[groans]
Moon,
I don't see you in town much.
How's your family?
My son had a fall.
Broke his arm pretty good.
Well, you know Doc Bates
isn't a medicine man.
He's a doctor of the Lord.
I didn't ask you
to come in here, Gordon.
[Gordon]
The building is mine.
I just came by to collect
from the good doctor here.
It's gonna take
a good long while
to heal.
I don't have anything
for pain right now,
but I might have
a little laudanum.
Yes, sir.
Can you sit up?
Gotta sit up.
How those horses
working out for you, Moon?
I got your payment for you,
but I need to get them oats
you promised me.
I need them today.
I tell you what,
why don't you take Kelly here?
And he'll lend a hand for you,
seeing as how your son
is in-- incapacitated.
I'm obliged to you.
I'll be back in town
day after tomorrow.
I'll have some trade
with me.
Mr. Gordon,
I'm supposed to be working
at the saloon tonight.
Well, now you
are helping him.
[Gordon]
Come by later in the evening.
Oh, and, Moon,
never a day goes by...
where my heart doesn't mourn
for the loss of your wife.
Don't you ever mention my wife.
Johnny, you're gonna
need to keep that arm
elevated, okay?
You know what that means?
All right?
The break was really clean,
but it's gonna take a long time
for that bone to heal.
You understand?
Yes, sir.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you, Doc.
I haven't forgotten
what you done
for me, Jones.
Go ahead. Get that door.
I'm sorry. Can I help you?
- It's pretty, right?
- That dress is expensive.
It comes from New York City.
I was just admiring it.
That man was killed by Indians
just outside this town.
So you're gonna
have to forgive
my store policy...
when I don't do business
with savages.
Even half-breeds.
Miss Abigail Peterson,
you come right on in.
You know, I got
that lace in you ordered.
You are just gonna die.
[muttering]
[Jones]
Maggie.
Give him this
with a little bit of honey.
[sighs]
You good to walk
back to town?
Make sure you put those bags
in the barn, too.
[door opens]
Well, it's not raining outside.
You two look smarter
than to bathe
with your clothes on.
But I'll leave explanation
to imagination.
Consider the first one
on the house.
That's very kind of you.
Not at all. I'm obliged.
[bottle uncorks]
[Will sighs]
Uh,
as Shakespeare said,
"So wise so young,
they say do never live long."
Well, I'll pretend
I know what that means.
- Cheers.
[James]
Mmm! All the way down.
Again, I suppose.
For us.
Sorry, friend.
We can't afford to be buying
bartenders drinks.
Tsk, tsk, friend.
On me.
The last bottle
of Gordon's favorite.
God knows
where it comes from.
Can't say I ever drank
with a barkeep before.
Well, gentlemen,
we're not exactly
overrun here.
[clears throat]
I'm feeling a bit under myself.
I could use the medicine.
We're looking
for a friend of mine.
Bill Benson.
Robert Bill Benson.
He lives here.
I can't--
[coughs]
[coughing]
Christ, brother.
I'm due for another.
Bill Benson?
He's dead.
Buried at our cemetery.
I'll take you there.
Five cents.
[laughs]
Look, kid, you know,
I find that hard
to believe.
But I appreciate
the offer.
We're gonna need
some horses while
we're here in town.
Well, see,
that there would be me.
Well, you're a horse,
huh?
"One may smile and smile,
and be a villain."
John, you know Gordon's
got anything...
these fellas might require.
Kelly's good people.
He can help you men find...
what or whoever
you're looking for.
We good here?
[James]
No.
Another round.
It's been quite a morning.
So you say you got horses,
is that right?
Yeah, I-- I--
I got some horses, sure.
I just, um--
Look, I don't
have them personally.
Now, y'all men up
for details?
Cancel them drinks.
Ain't got time
for your bullshit, kid.
Hmph! Kid.
Well, y'all got the questions
I got the answers to.
[coughing]
[Kelly]
John?
John!
Get Dr. Bates!
I'm not gonna lie
to you, John.
This stuff
tastes terrible.
[coughing]
I need you to drink it
all the way down, okay?
[gags]
[coughs]
[John coughs]
[breathing heavily]
Kelly, get out of here.
I'll be a moment.
You heard him. Move.
He's been in
and out of consciousness
for about an hour.
John,
I'm here.
Jesus, you're pale as a ghost.
[sighs]
Funny that you say that,
because I feel...
like I've been one
for quite some time.
There anything
I can do for you?
I just want you
to sit down.
Doc, may we have a moment?
[Bates]
Yeah. I'll be right outside.
I want you
to do something for me.
I can do that.
I think you'd be better off
to just rest now.
Doc Bates says...
I probably won't make it
through the night.
I want to confess
in front of God...
and in front
of someone I trust.
I afraid
I'm not following you.
1865.
Ford Theatre,
Washington.
I walked into
the private seating...
of the president
of the United States.
I pointed a Colt pistol
to the back of his head,
and I pulled the trigger,
point-blank.
I fled to Virginia.
By the grace of God,
I escaped,
and I've lived like a rat
ever since.
What do you want me to say?
I don't want you
to say anything, Henry.
I'm telling you...
that my name
is not St. Helens.
My name is John Booth,
the assassin
of Abraham Lincoln.
Look, John,
you're sick.
You need rest.
I know how this sounds,
and I know you have no
good right to believe me,
but I want you
to understand...
that what I'm saying
to you is truth.
And I'm telling you this,
my friend,
because when I go,
I want a clean slate.
Now, I have prayed...
for God's forgiveness.
The weight--
it sits inside me
where my soul once was.
It gets harder
to carry every day.
I'm sorry, John.
I need to go now.
No. Wait.
And you need rest.
[breathing heavily]
In my room--
In my room, under my bed,
beneath the floorboards...
is all the proof you need.
The gun--
[Gordon]
The gun that shot Lincoln...
was found
at the theater, John.
So I heard.
My secondary shot...
fell from my hip.
It left me helpless,
so I had to jump.
I've contemplated suicide.
[sighs]
I always wanted the bullet...
to come from the same gun.
Then do this favor for me.
I beg you.
Take what's under my bed...
and destroy it.
Give me my peace,
please.
[stomping on floor]
[blows]
[wood creaks]
[mutters]
Dr. Bates?
I don't look
for him to make it
through the night.
So he said.
He's, uh, clearly
out of his mind.
He has family in town.
Cousin. Fannie Rhea.
One of your men
could notify her.
I'm gonna stay here.
I want you to go
to St. Helens's home.
You'll strip every plank
from under his bed.
If you find anything,
come to me.
And if you don't,
stop at the dress shop
and tell Fannie Rhea...
her cousin
is on his deathbed.
Yes, sir.
Where's Kelly?
He stepped out.
Well, find him.
Keep him away.
[door closes]
Gordon.
Fannie Rhea was a widower
to a Mr. William Mugg
years back.
Now married
to Mr. Thomas Rhea.
What's your point?
Well, I was friends
with William Mugg
before he died.
He married
Miss Missouri Fannie Booth,
John St. Helens's cousin.
[chattering]
[sighs]
Yeah, he's dead.
Clear as day
from the cemetery, Will.
I can't believe
I never got word.
So what I'm gathering
from all of this is...
we're here,
not a dime between us,
we got nowhere to go.
What the hell do I do?
[Will]
This ain't the end
of the road.
I know this, uh,
friend of mine in Kansas.
Kansas.
Is that pretty close?
It's a little bit
north of here.
Railroad picks back up
again in a week.
I'm gonna head back to Dallas,
get my $300 back.
[Kelly]
Told you he was dead.
Shot at Ten Pin-Alley
by Jameson Benson.
Killed each other.
Hell, buried next
to each other.
[chuckles]
How long you been sitting there
spying on us?
Oh, I heard everything.
Was it, uh, 300?
Whatever you think you heard,
you didn't.
You understand that?
That's right.
I wanna be straight
with you.
Both of you.
Here.
Bastard shite!
I oughta bury you
where you're standing!
I'm trying to make amends,
and I'm real sorry
about the watch.
I don't got much
neither.
I think you better
get outta here, kid.
Boy, if you would've
scratched this,
so help me God--
I know where
we can get some horses.
Yeah, well, thanks.
Maybe even a means for money.
[Will]
What's that about
a means for money?
[Kelly]
Easy. A farm family
has months of furs.
Good ones. More than they need.
We go in there
and just take them.
They got horses too.
I've seen them.
You wanna steal
from a farm family?
Will, the law's found us!
What?
What you crying about?
They're there.
Right there.
I'm gonna hang, Will.
I'm gonna hang!
Let's just go.
All of us.
Hey!
We just take enough to get by.
You understand?
Come on.
[James]
♪♪ On the road to Cork City ♪♪
♪♪ There I met Will's mum ♪♪
Say, do you hear something?
It's just us here, yeah?
Yeah. Told you.
They said they're taking
the wagon to town today.
Y'all are just
spooking yourselves.
Come on.
g]
♪♪♪♪ [hummin
You know what
I think I hear?
Sounds like humming.
No. Keep going.
Come on.
Gotta tell you,
this is a lot easier...
than I thought
it was gonna be.
Here. I'll tie it.
Wait. Wait.
We should leave
these ones here.
I don't wanna rob them
completely blind.
And I feel good
about that.
All right, Kelly.
That's eight.
♪♪♪♪ [humming continues]
Not only provided
are the means of redbacks.
They also provide
the artillery to defend it.
Is it loaded?
Three.
Well, that makes six
between us.
Save them.
Kelly.
♪♪♪♪ [humming continues]
I never trusted Kelly
from the moment
he stole my watch.
He gave it back,
didn't he?
Because I didn't give him
a fine taste of death.
[chuckles]
You couldn't spin your hat.
- [twig snaps]
- [gasps]
Let's us just
go get them horses.
It'll be easier if Kelly
brings them here.
He's getting them.
[gasps]
Pa!
Son of a bitch.
How many wagons
do they have?
I thought they were
taking the wagon
into town today.
[Johnny]
They're stealing all our hides!
I got a question for you.
[gunshot]
- God!
- They're stealing
from the barn!
Hey! Grab the stuff!
Down!
Maggie, get down!
[shouts]
Stupid!
I told you
not to waste them!
I never shot a gun before!
Wait!
[gunshot]
Kelly, I'm gonna pound
your face in!
Run!
Hurry!
- [horse whinnying]
- They're still shooting at us!
Go!
[Will]
There's a boat!
Hey, get on that boat!
[grunts]
Let's go, let's go!
Come on!
Grab those paddles!
[shouting]
Let's go!
[shouting continues]
Is that your boat?
- Who was that?
- Don't matter now.
John, you got the shells?
- Yes, sir. I'm ready.
- We have to catch them on foot.
It's too thick for the horses.
I can ride to Granbury
and get the marshal.
No, Maggie. No.
You go on back to the farm.
I need you there.
I want you to take
this pistol.
Go ahead.
Where you going?
Half Point bridge,
if we're gonna catch them.
Now listen to me.
You see anybody
come on our land,
you shoot that gun.
You ask questions later.
You hear me?
Yes, sir.
All right then.
Let's go. Go!
Let's go!
Ho! Ho!
I can go with you.
Ho!
You wanna start pushing
some water, kid?
You're sure lookin'
awful chipper for us
to be getting shot at, boy.
Pa, I tied the horses up
behind the tree
like you asked.
All right. Good. Good.
I'm gonna take aim
over the water. Come on.
[laughs]
Look at all that.
[sniffs]
Whiskey.
I take it we came out a lot
better than we had intentions.
We need to get
in the cover of them trees.
We're in trouble
in this boat.
Whose-ever's it is
is gonna be missing it.
Getting more presents
than Maundy Thursday.
[cocks]
You see that log, boy?
- Yes.
- Go right over that log.
So, down to business.
How are we gonna split
all this up?
Oh, well, we'll take as much
as we can carry,
and then you can have
what's left over.
Or I'll just drink
your share myself.
Hey, sit down.
Better do something
about Kelly, Will,
'cause his body's about to be
floating lifeless in this river.
- Let's have it, Irish!
Let's have it!
- That's enough, both of you!
"Both of you"?
You taking up for him?
They were supposed
to be in town.
- Well, then, what the hells
were you doing?
- Shut up!
Now, unfortunately,
we're all in this together.
So if you don't mind,
just paddle.
- What if we missed them?
- Quiet!
Go ahead, boy.
De-cock your gun.
[sighs]
Hey, Kelly, I got this.
Don't worry.
You go ahead and throw rocks
in the river, okay?
I say we go to Palo Pinto,
make some money.
Even more off that whiskey.
With all of this?
We'd need horses,
you fool.
Hey.
Give that here.
That's mine.
Nobody touches that!
[Will]
All right, all right!
Listen now. There's
too much law in Palo Pinto.
That farmer's
probably turned us in,
if he's not right behind us.
Well, what a glorious day
it's turned out to be, huh?
I got everybody in
the entire Republic of Texas...
wanting to throw a noose
around my neck,
Will, 'cause why?
It ain't
the Republic of Texas anymore.
Call it Paris, Texas.
I'm gonna die.
Well, what do we do?
We head east. It's safer.
East? On foot?
It's gonna be two days
before we got anywhere.
Well, then, it'll be two days
before we get anywhere,
but that's what we're do--
[brush crunches]
What is it?
I heard something.
- We're still being tailed.
- The owner of that boat?
Why don't you carry
no gun, kid?
- Ain't got any bullets
in there anyway.
- Would you shut up?
[brush rustles]
Hey!
We got guns on you!
Come on out!
Following
the trail up here.
Crosses the river.
Kid, you almost got
blasted to bits!
Quiet, Kelly.
You almost got shot up to hell.
You youngsters--
you startled us is all.
Matter of fact,
we, uh--
We saw some deer down a ways
when we were fishing.
Y'all better hurry up.
Okay.
Why don't you got
no fishing poles?
We saw a boat.
[chuckles]
Yeah.
Now, uh, them fish
were so big...
we couldn't hold on to them.
- That's right.
- Yeah. Even took our boat.
So, uh, y'all better git.
Saw some Indians netting
about an hour up the stream.
Yeah, well,
we ain't Indians.
Let's go.
Hey, boy.
[clears throat]
Hey, those, um--
Those Indians you seen--
did they look mean?
Come on, Jeral.
Yeah, well, you two shouldn't
be sneaking up on people.
Hey, back to what
I was saying.
Whiskey's ours, kid.
Ha!
Okay. All right.
I can live with that.
So, then, the furs--
that goes three ways.
Not anymore.
We will come
to an arrangement.
Yeah, well,
I'm getting off this bank...
because this muck
smells worse than Kelly.
Now you wait.
We ain't figured
anything out yet.
You never, ever, ever,
ever tell me what to do,
you understand, boy?
Don't forget who almost
got us lynched, ya cur!
[brush crunches]
Frank.
Frank!
[brush crunches]
[Jeral grunts]
Where is my whiskey?
Great. He's spooked. Now--
Stop!
Drop the rifle.
[groans]
Where is my whiskey?
We don't have any whiskey.
Where is my boat?
We don't have a boat.
Take my gun.
You can have my gun.
- Give him your gun!
- Take my gun.
Stop.
We have three squirrels.
That is all we have,
honest.
Men on foot--
you seen them?
No.
Yes.
I mean, yes.
We saw some men.
They had just
gotten out of a boat,
and they sent it downriver.
- Where?
- Down the way, hours ago.
They were fishermen.
Go.
Hurry. Go.
♪♪♪♪ [James singing]
Shh. Shh, shh.
Stop. Stop! Hey!
What?
You really hate melody.
[Native Americans chanting,
distant]
You hear that?
Chanting.
Indians.
Don't worry.
They're not hostile
around here.
Mostly traders.
Beads and jewelry.
And food.
I ain't had nothing to eat.
[chanting continues]
We'll camp here tonight.
I don't want to come up
on them in the dark.
I thought you just said
that they weren't hostile.
They're not.
Usually.
We had many a-troubles
with the Indians
on the railroads.
They're ruthless.
[chuckles]
Hey.
Look what I found.
Oh, James, dear God.
Put that back.
They say it's bad luck if you
find an arrowhead in a creek.
- What? Why?
- [chuckles]
[chuckling]
[James]
Oh, you like that, Kelly?
You like that, Kelly?
That's really funny, eh?
Yeah, well,
you'll get yours, boy.
I'm just funning you,
Irish.
Yeah, well,
Indians are no joke.
I'm telling you that
right now.
I've seen
nightmarish things.
Apaches are the ones
you gotta worry about.
But there ain't no more
of them around here
in these parts.
And all that yelling
and that drumming
that I'm hearing?
Comanche.
They're harmless.
Couldn't be more than a party
of three or four of them.
What are you,
like an Indian know-it-all?
After we cash in,
I think I'm gonna
try to get to California.
Yeah, well,
what's in California, thief?
Gold.
Lots of it.
It's paying out real good
in a town called Bodie, I hear.
How good?
I don't know. Real good.
That ain't nothing
but talk.
[James]
Yeah? Well, then,
what are you gonna do?
Since you don't like gold?
I was thinking, uh,
eventually, I might
become a lawman.
[laughing]
Aye, a lawman.
Deputy James McKinnon here
with Marshal Will Edwards.
And we can let Kelly hang out
in our jail cell, eh?
Whatever brought you
to Granbury anyway?
Y'all, uh, just a part
of that James Younger gang?
I mean,
you come in soaking wet,
no money, no horses.
I mean,
you're just passing through?
Come on.
Everybody's got their secrets.
Yeah, well, we ain't got
no secrets, thief.
Yeah. That's why we hightailed
it out of there so quick, huh?
[chanting stops]
The drumming stopped.
What, y'all rob
a bank or something?
Is that it?
Three hundred dollars?
Y'all are running
from something else.
Yeah, why don't you not worry
about that $300, aye?
If it was your business,
then worry about it.
But it ain't, so don't.
Tell you what
I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna have myself
a sip of this whiskey,
and thank the Lord
that I'm not a ghost today.
Hey, Kelly, why don't you
head up there and keep watch?
What, are you gonna let me
use your gun?
No.
But if you see something,
wake me.
I'll go shoot it.
[laughing]
That's real funny.
And keep your hands
out of my pockets while I rest.
Steal one watch--
Make sure your gun's showing.
I don't have any bullets.
Don't matter.
I don't want them to think
we're hiding them.
I thought you said
that they were friendly.
I said they should be.
Should be.
[whistles]
Kelly.
Grab a couple
of them pelts.
We're bringing the whiskey?
No. The whiskey stays here
till we see what they got.
[James]
Indians are sneaky.
I should stay behind
in case they start
killing people.
[scoffs]
Come on.
Irishman scared of
some mean old Indians?
Hey. Hey!
I'll just stay here,
then, yeah?
Guard the whiskey?
[speaking in native language]
Kutseena! Kutseena!
[shouts]
[shouting continues]
[Kelly]
Morning.
English?
English. Yes.
You have face
of hungry men.
Well, uh, yeah.
If you could spare some food,
we'd be mighty grateful.
My name is Will.
This here is--
This here is Kelly.
Kutseena.
P￩kwimake you strong.
My gift to you.
[rattling]
Take, uh, this fur.
It'll fetch you a big price.
[speaks native language]
[rattling continues]
[screaming]
Snake!
My eyes see three white men.
Why does one hide?
- He is not hiding.
- No, he was just tired.
[James screaming]
We have much to carry.
He has much to trade.
I'll, uh--
Snake!
I'll bring him.
I'll--
Snake!
A snake!
[speaks native language]
You hungry.
Oh.
[native language]
Thanks.
Thank you.
[panting]
It's a-- It's a snake.
I killed it.
Yeah. He came over here,
and I killed him
with my knife.
- I hate snakes.
- Hate snakes.
[donkey braying]
Hello.
[grunts]
How's that fish?
[Kelly]
Oh, it's--
It's real good, actually.
So that right there
is a really fine animal
you got.
Where are your horses?
The horses, they died,
because--
because we ate them.
[chokes, clears throat]
[Will]
What, uh--
[snorts]
What my friend meant to say
was that, uh,
we had some horses
grow sickly,
and we had to put them down.
We would like
to trade you for your mule.
Lighten our load.
Whitepuukunot for trade.
We have beads--
fine beads for trade
for you.
For furs.
[laughs]
Now, listen here, Chief.
That's just not--
Yes!
We will.
We would very much...
like to trade you
for your beads.
And we will make you
many great offerings.
[man speaking
native language]
[no audible dialogue]
- Thanks.
- Well, now, that's
a lovely turtle shell.
Ooh. Yeah.
These are beautiful beads.
Very fine beads.
Yeah. Very beautiful.
Okay. Why don't you
have a look at those?
Ooh.
Hey, uh, James,
you wanna help with this stuff.
Oh, you need some help, Will?
That's okay, Kelly.
Why don't you stay here...
and explain
to these fine gentlemen...
why James ate our horse.
[clears throat]
Oh, um--
You know,
you would never believe it.
We were at the ridge.
You know, back up a ways,
only about a mile out.
You'd never im-imagine...
what we--
[sighs]
ran into.
But it was a herd of cougars.
I never seen anything
like it in my life.
They come after us,
pounce on the horse.
[whispering]
Thing goes down.
I mean,
I really liked that horse.
And we had to
be carrying these furs.
The horse's name was, uh--
was, uh,
you know, uh, Billy.
And it was a good horse.
That's enough.
Good story. Good story.
They-- They--
[clears throat]
Kelly. Okay.
Well--
[clears throat]
Now,
as the sun beats down
on our faces,
I'd like to share
an Irish custom with you,
my new Indian friends.
[quietly]
Now we're trading the whiskey?
Yes. We're trading
the whiskey.
It better be
out of your share.
That's fine. It is.
[James clears throat]
In this bottle
are the fires from hell...
mixed with the waters
from the heavens.
And when you drink it,
you will become
a fierce warrior.
Now, at first,
it tastes like you're dying,
and then
it's Christmas morning...
for the rest of the evening.
[cork pops]
[sniffs]
[clears throat]
[coughs]
[shouts]
[Will]
Hey, hey!
- [laughs] All right!
- Good. Here you go. Here.
Here's a couple more.
[James]
We got plenty of whiskey.
Let's all have a drink.
Yeah. Why don't we
all have some?
Come on, Kelly.
Raise your glass.
[Kelly laughs]
Why don't you
pass that around?
Yeah.
Ugh!
[coughing]
Burns the belly,
don't it, good, Kelly?
[Kelly coughing]
[James]
Drink up!
Drink up, drink up.
Whiskey.
[Men coughing]
[coughing continues]
[no audible dialogue]
[birds chirping]
[rooster crows]
[groans]
You've managed to make it
through another night.
I'm going downstairs,
John.
I'm gonna get myself
something to eat.
[footsteps departing]
[sighs]
[coughs]
[groans]
[breathing heavily]
Where's my satchel?
[footsteps approaching]
Hey, what are y'all doing?
[grunts]
Hurry up.
We gotta keep moving.
I'd gladly trade places
with you, Will.
Come on. Come on.
Hyah!
[whimpering]
You take our food,
our trade.
Why?
I didn't take anything from you.
[shouts]
[cries out]
[groaning]
[Kelly sobbing]
Ourpuuku,
our fur--
gone!
Men you came with--
[coughing]
gone!
They wouldn't just leave me!
They wouldn't just--
They wanted to steal my satchel!
Will!
[cries out]
[shouting in native language]
You...
will take us to them!
And if we don't find them,
pitiful white man,
you will die,
slow.
[James]
Will!
How much further
are you leading us up here?
It'll be faster
if we cut through
those canyon walls.
It's not as easy
as it looks, Will.
It's too much to get down there.
We'll have to go
all the way back around.
[blusters]
If we go around,
we'll have no cover.
Them Indians
are gonna find us.
We're too overloaded.
We're sitting too heavy.
We'd have to leave
some of the load here.
We leave nothing.
We hit that break in the canyon.
We're sitting ducks out here.
[braying]
[thud]
Shit!
You were being
too damn careless!
[sniffles]
I'm-- I'm sure they're
just up ahead here.
[twigs snap]
Wait.
Banshee?
No.
Move.
Hey-- Hey--
Stupid! Stupid!
Damn it.
You're a madman, Will.
Here!
You're a madman if you think...
that we can carry all of this
through that opening...
before those Indians
catch up to us.
We'll be dead in an hour's time.
Are you hearing me?
We gotta move, Will!
Those Indians
will scalp us dead,
and you're trying to lead us
into the gates of hell!
We can carry it!
That money--
That money that was stolen
from me in Dallas...
had been in my pocket
for four days, Will.
For four days.
I stole it from a man
sleeping on a train.
I don't work on the railroads.
I work the railroads.
The money's gone.
The money's gone,
but you know what?
- I'm still here.
- I don't care!
Don't you understand?
Everything that we leave here...
is like leaving gold
in the grave,
and I will go
through the gates of hell...
before I let them Indians
take me down,
and so will you.
Now, pick it up,
and let's move on.
You got three bullets
in that gun, Will.
I don't think you're going
to use any of them on me.
[cocks]
Hey.
Hey!
[shouting]
[arrow whooshes]
[grunts]
[shouting continues]
[gunshot]
[knife blow lands]
[Indians shouting]
[shouting continues]
[grunts]
[gunshot]
[grunting]
[grunting continues]
[screaming]
[cocks]
[gun clatters]
[grunts]
[Men]
Hyah!
[chattering]