(piano plays into "Seasons of Love"
from Rent)
♪ Five hundred twenty-five
thousand six hundred minutes ♪
thousand moments so dear ♪
♪ Five hundred twenty-five
thousand six hundred minutes ♪
♪ How do you measure,
measure a year? ♪
♪ In daylights, in sunsets
♪ In midnights,
in cups of coffee ♪
♪ In inches, in miles,
in laughter, in strife ♪
♪ How about love?
♪ Measure in love
♪ Seasons of love...
♪ Love ♪
♪ Seasons of love
♪ Five hundred twenty-five thousand six
hundred minutes ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
♪ Five hundred twenty-five thousand
journeys to plan ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Five hundred twenty-five thousand six
hundred minutes ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
♪ How do you measure the life of a woman or a man?
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ In truths that she learned ♪
♪ Or in times that he cried
♪ In bridges he burned
♪ Or the way that she died
♪ It's time now to sing out
♪ Though the story never ends
♪ Let's celebrate
♪ Remember a year
in the life of friends ♪
♪ Remember the love... ♪
♪ Oh, you got to, you got
to remember the love... ♪
♪ Remember the love... ♪
♪ You know that love
is a gift from above ♪
♪ Remember the love... ♪
♪ Share love, give love,
spread love ♪
♪ Measure your love ♪
♪ Measure
♪ Measure your life in love ♪
♪ Seasons of love...
♪ Love ♪
♪ Seasons of love
♪ Love. ♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
(steam hissing)
KURT: Three weeks to the
day since his funeral,
and it's the first time
I've had the courage
to even look at the suit
I wore to it.
And now back to Lima
for a special memorial.
Mr. Shue is planning.
We're all going back...
everyone who can.
Being together is hard...
it makes it more real...
but I also need
my friends right now.
People keep asking me,
"How are you feeling?
What are you feeling?"
I have no answers.
Honestly, what can you say
about a 19-year-old who dies?
Everyone wants to talk
about how he died, too,
but who cares?
One moment in his whole life.
I care more about how he lived.
And anyone
who has a problem with that
should remember
that he was my brother.
I only keep that out
when I know she won't come in.
(echoing):
Rachel?
I'm going now.
This isn't real.
I'm not going home for this.
He's going to be there.
I'm going to spend
my entire life missing him.
(school bell ringing)
You know, I've cleared
my entire schedule
to provide my services
to students and faculty,
and not a single person's
come in for grief counseling.
Well, maybe that's because
you're not a certified
grief counselor.
Maybe that's because
you're just the jittery,
mentally-ill bird lady
they turn to
to find out what college
they won't be attending
because they missed
the application deadline.
If students wish to mourn
Finn's passing, they're free
to visit the memorial garden
that I erected.
I planted a tree in
the exact location
where I caught Finn
and Quinn Fabray fondling
each other's breasts.
Come on, Sue. BEISTE:
How can you even
joke at a time like this?
SUE: Oh, take it easy,
Post-Op Michael Chiklis.
I'm grieving.
And I grieve by insulting those
who mean the most to me.
It's just a coincidence
that it's also what I do
when I'm not grieving.
It just feels so surreal.
They don't make 'em like Finn.
He was our quarterback.
We honor Finn Hudson by taking
care of the people he loved,
and the way we do that
is by helping them to move on.
How?
By not making a self-serving
spectacle of our own sadness.
And I think we can all agree,
that's what Finn
would have wanted.
I'm really glad so many of you
could make it back for this.
MIKE: We wouldn't miss it
for anything, Mr. Shue.
The funeral
was for everyone, but I wanted
to do something just for us.
To memorialize him
the only way we know how...
by singing.
(sighs) All week long.
Anyone who wants to
can come up and sing.
Maybe a song he sung,
maybe something that
reminds you of him...
Singing isn't going
to bring him back.
No, it's not.
Nothing is.
Not ever.
But... for two minutes or so,
we can all maybe remember
the best parts of him.
So, think of
what you want to sing,
if you want to sing,
and we'll start tomorrow.
Oh, I-I can't wait
until tomorrow, Mr. Shue.
I've been bawling
for three weeks.
If I don't get this all out now,
I don't think
I'll ever stop crying.
Sure, Mercedes. Start us off.
Um...
I, uh, remember Finn telling me
that he sang this song
to his baby's sonogram.
Well, he thought
it was his baby.
He was the first cool kid
to be nice to any of us,
and he was...
our leader in here.
We love you, Finn.
(The Pretenders'
"I'll Stand by You" begins)
♪ Oh
♪ Why you look so sad?
♪ Tears are in your eyes
♪ Come on and come to me now
♪ Don't
♪ Be ashamed to cry
♪ Let me see you through
♪ 'Cause I've seen
the dark side, too ♪
♪ When the night falls on you
♪ You don't know what to do
♪ Nothing you confess
♪ Could make me love you less
♪ I'll stand by you
♪ I'll stand...
♪ By you
♪ Won't let nobody hurt you
♪ I'll stand by you
♪ So
♪ If you're mad, get mad
♪ Don't hold it all inside
♪ Come on and talk to me now
♪ And hey
♪ What you got to hide?
♪ I get angry, too
♪ Well, I'm a lot like you
♪ When you're standing
at the crossroads ♪
♪ And don't know
which path to choose ♪
♪ Let me come along
♪ 'Cause even if you're wrong ♪
♪ I'll stand by you
♪ Oh ♪ I'll stand by you ♪
♪ Won't let nobody hurt you ♪
♪ Nobody hurt you, no
♪ I'll stand by you ♪
♪ Take me in,
into your darkest hour ♪
♪ And I'll never desert you ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
♪ I'll stand by you ♪
♪ Yeah, ah-ah-ah-ah-ah-ah
♪ I'll stand... by you ♪
♪ Won't let nobody... hurt you
♪ Won't let nobody hurt you ♪
♪ No, no, no, no
♪ I'll stand by you ♪
♪ Take me in ♪
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ Into your darkest hour
♪ And I'll never desert you ♪
♪ I'll never
♪ Desert you...
♪ I'll stand by you ♪
♪ I'll stand... by you ♪
♪ I'll stand by you
♪ Won't let nobody hurt you ♪
♪ No, no, no
♪ I'll stand by you.
(song ends)
(school bell rings)
Sweet, gentle Porcelain,
I know you were instrumental
in raising the funds
for the tree in the memorial
garden in Finn's honor.
All I did was drive
to Home Depot
and buy a tree
for $20, but, yes.
Well, it looks like
we're gonna have to dip
into your West Village Halloween
Parade Assless Chap Fund
once again.
Tree is gone.
Someone's vandalized
the memorial.
(chain clanking)
(engine revving)
I don't understand! Why would
someone do something like that?
Who knows?
Grief can bring out
the irrational in all of us.
Sometimes it makes
people do very strange things.
Sometimes when people die,
we want to hold on
to what's left of them
to get us through
the hard times.
I'll take that $20
for a new tree, please.
I prefer exact change.
Thanks.
(school bell ringing)
KURT: I marked these boxes so it'd
be easier to separate things.
Thanks, honey.
You don't have to do this now.
It can wait.
There's no timetable.
CAROLE: No.
We should do it now, or...
I'm afraid I'll never do it.
(sighs heavily)
KURT:
Look.
It's the ball from the
first game we ever scored at.
You should keep this, Dad.
That was the weirdest
football game I ever been to.
Look, it's the faggy lamp
from my Marlene Dietrich
basement redecoration.
I think he kept it in here
to prove a point to Burt.
BURT:
You know, if it's, uh,
okay with everyone, I think
I'd like to keep that lamp.
No. It's not okay with me.
That thing is awful.
BURT:
I need a lamp
in my office at the shop.
I tore into him about this lamp.
You know, I was right,
in principle,
but, you know, come on.
The kid didn't have
a prejudiced bone in his body.
I knew what he meant when
he was calling it "faggy."
I wasn't teaching him
a lesson in tolerance,
I was teaching myself one,
and he was just unlucky enough
to be there for it.
CAROLE: Finn knew how you
felt about him, honey.
He kind of liked it
when you yelled at him.
Should've hugged him more,
you know?
No, it was always...
you know, we'd fist-bump
or we'd high-five, but...
I should've given him more hugs.
You know, the last
time I saw him,
he was so bummed out about
some test at school, and...
I just, you know...
told him
to get back at it, you know?
He was worth it.
(voice breaking): It was
the perfect time for a hug.
But for whatever reason,
I just...
I gave him a pat on the back...
and that's that.
Now he's gone.
KURT:
Oh, d-don't.
I need that.
I want it.
Seeing him come into the
hallway wearing this...
it was like Superman
had arrived.
(sniffles, chuckles):
God, his arms were long.
I always thought
that when I, uh...
(sniffles)
How do parents go on
when they lose a child?
You know, when I would see
that stuff on the news,
I'd shut it off, 'cause it was
just too horrible to think,
but I would always think:
how do they wake up every day?
I mean, h-h... (gasping)
how do they breathe, honey?
(muffled sob)
But you do wake up.
And for just a second,
you forget.
And then...
oh, you remember.
And it's like getting
that call again...
and again, every time.
You don't get to
stop waking up.
You have to keep on
being a parent,
even though you don't get
to have a child anymore.
(sobbing)
(continues sobbing)
What's with, uh,
the Banksy loser parade?
You're exhausting.
You seriously don't
recognize this Dumpster?
♪
Oh, yeah.
KURT: Soon as Finn joined
the Glee Club, being a loser,
an outcast and a misfit,
it... it all became okay.
Hey, give me that jacket.
Seriously, I'll pay you for it.
I'm sure you have a whole
room full of mementos.
I got nothing to
remember him by.
Well, you can't have this.
That jacket is reserved
for people who earned it.
I'm not gonna let you
bedazzle it with glitter
and turn it into some
Project Runway shawl.
So what are you gonna do,
beat me up and take it from me?
Throw me in a Dumpster?
You can't have it.
(sighs)
(Sam playing intro to James
Taylor's "Fire and Rain")
♪ Just yesterday morning
♪ They let me know
you were gone ♪
♪ Suzanne, the plans they made
♪ Put an end to you
♪ I walked out this morning
♪ And I wrote down this song
♪ I just can't remember
who to send it to ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ I've seen fire
and I've seen rain ♪
♪ I've seen sunny days
♪ That I thought
would never end ♪
♪ I've seen lonely times
♪ When I could not
find a friend ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
♪ But I always thought
♪ That I'd see you again
♪ Won't you look down
upon me, Jesus ♪
♪ You gotta help me
make a stand ♪
♪ You just gotta see me
through another day ♪
ARTIE & SAM (harmonizing):
♪ My body's aching
♪ And my time is at hand
♪ I won't make it
any other way ♪
♪ Oh, I've seen fire
♪ And I've seen rain
♪ I've seen sunny days
♪ That I thought
would never end ♪
♪ I've seen lonely times
♪ When I could not
find a friend ♪
♪ But I always thought
(slowing):
♪ That I'd see you again.
(song ends)
(school bell rings)
♪
Hi, Santana.
Shouldn't you be with
Tina in Glee Club?
I-I don't mean to pry...
it's just,
I had Tina mourning in song
with the Glee Club
until 10:45 at the earliest.
No, I had to get out of there.
Felt like my head
was gonna explode.
SANTANA:
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What the hell
do you think you're doing?
Principal Sylvester told us
the candles have to go.
She said she got a call
from the fire marshal.
You cannot let her do this.
Um, he's the janitor.
JANITOR:
New Santana Lopez
is right, Old Santana Lopez.
Under the tyrannical
jackboot of Sylvester regime,
I am powerless,
and I am too overcome
with Finn Hudson-related grief
to fight back.
Okay, this is...
this is insane.
SUE: Well, Donna,
one of us farted,
and I'm about 60% sure
it wasn't me.
You have no right
to take down that memorial.
Well, as a matter of fact,
I do, Sandbags. I allowed
that memorial to remain in the
hallway for over a week. Oh, please.
You wanted that memorial gone
because you're such
a coldhearted bitch.
What did you just call me?
A miserable,
self-centered bitch,
who has spent
every waking minute
of the past three years trying
to make our lives miserable.
I'm officially over it.
I don't care for your attitude.
Well,
I don't give a hot wet monkey's
ass what you care for.
You are not my principal.
See, I don't go here
anymore, Sue,
and that means
I can finally tell you
exactly what I think of you.
I have hated you
ever since the day I met you.
You are a horrible person
who never had a nice word
to say about Finn Hudson,
so don't you dare think
for a second
that he didn't hate you, too!
If I were you, I would choose my
next few words very carefully.
What are you gonna do?
You gonna expel me?
You get the hell
out of my office!
How about you make me get
the hell out of your office?
Donna, call the police.
Donna, you pick up that phone,
and I swear to God,
I will shove my foot so far...
That's assault!
No, this is assault!
(gasps)
(school bell rings)
Tina, I'm really glad that
you took the time
to come talk to me today.
I know a lot of young people
have trouble expressing
feelings of sadness.
I just don't know how
much longer I can do this.
Do what?
I just don't know how much
longer I can wear black.
I feel like this look is
so Tina two years ago.
And I spent so much time
transitioning away from goth,
and look at me... it's, like,
I'm back in that look.
Okay, yeah.
I'm just gonna see
what I... have
in my drawer here.
Okay. All right.
So, why don't you
have a look at these...
on your way out.
Okay?
Okay.
All right.
Hey, right on time
for your 1:30.
I'm happy some people are
finally coming to you for help.
Mm-hmm. But I don't think
I need grief counseling.
Have a seat.
(sighs) Come on.
(sighs)
Will, I was with you when
you found out that Finn died.
Okay? I stood right next
to you at the funeral.
And I couldn't help
but notice something.
What?
You haven't cried.
What are you saying, that...
that-that I don't feel anything?
No, that's
not what... Of course I
feel something, Emma.
I-I feel...
I feel more than I know
how to express. I...
I'm heartbroken.
To be honest,
I don't even know how
we're all supposed to move
forward, but in the meantime,
I have to make sure
that the people
around me are taken care of.
Okay. Okay.
Look, I-I... this... Listen to me.
Listen...
Listen to me; listen.
I love you, okay?
I know. Whatever you feel and
however you want to show it,
that's okay.
I just...
I think there's
gonna come a time
when you need to... let it
all out, and I want you to know
that I plan on being here
for you when you do.
I have to get back to class.
Okay.
(school bell ringing)
You're drunk.
You're beautiful.
You puke in my locker room,
you're cleaning it up.
Come on...
what's the big deal?
(frustrated sigh)
I get needing something to get
through the first few days,
but it's been a month.
You don't have to be scared
to have feelings.
That's crap!
Of course I do!
Why?
We're all having 'em!
Not like mine!
No one understands!
Understands what?
Tell me!
That if I start crying,
I don't think I'll ever stop!
(kicks locker)
(panting)
Finn would've kicked over
one of my chairs.
Yeah.
That was his specialty.
Sit down.
Come here.
(sobbing)
(crying):
I can't take it...
What chance do I have
of not being an idiot
and hurting people
without him around
to remind me who I really am?
You just got to do that
for yourself now...
and see yourself
how he saw you.
It's not good enough for me!
It's not like when he was alive.
(crying):
You got to make it good enough,
because it's all we got left.
And I'm telling
you this straight,
'cause that's how
you and I talk.
(sniffles)
He's dead...
and all we've got left is
his voice in our head.
(sobbing quietly)
I'm sorry, but it's time you...
you got to be your
own quarterback.
(sighs deeply)
(sighs)
Do you think we could...
retire his number?
Kurt has his letterman jacket.
Maybe... maybe we could
frame it or something,
and put it up in here.
Mm.
Other kids should
know who he was.
Years from now.
Yeah.
I can get that done.
But you got to promise
to put the tree back.
I didn't take the tree.
Fine, I took the tree.
Mm-hmm.
(sniffles)
It was a garbage tree, though.
It wasn't big enough.
They grow, you know.
(school bell ringing)
Okay, I know that Finn had
his doubts about God,
but I am convinced
that Squishyteets is up
in Heaven right now,
plopped down next to his new
best friend Fat Elvis,
helping themselves to a picnic
of baby back ribs
smothered in butterscotch
pudding and tater tot grease,
so, this is for you, Hudson.
(The Band Perry's
"If I Die Young" begins)
♪ If I die young,
bury me in satin ♪
♪ Lay me down
on a bed of roses ♪
♪ Sink me
in the river at dawn ♪
♪ Send me away
with the words of a love song ♪
♪ Uh-oh, uh-oh
♪ Lord, make me a rainbow
I'll shine down on my mother ♪
♪ She'll know
I'm safe with you ♪
♪ When she stands
under my colors ♪
♪ Oh, and life ain't always what
you think it ought to be, no ♪
♪ Ain't even gray,
but she buries her baby ♪
♪ The sharp knife
of a short life ♪
♪ Oh, well, I've had
♪ Just enough time
♪ Ooh, yeah
♪ So put on your best, boys,
and I'll wear my pearls ♪
♪ What I never did is done
♪ Oh, if I die young
♪ Bury me in satin
♪ Lay me down
on a bed of roses ♪
♪ Sink me in the river
at dawn ♪
♪ Send me away
with the words of a love song ♪
♪ Oh, oh...
(Santana cries)
(band stops playing)
(sobbing)
SANTANA:
No, no. No! No!
(screaming)
(footsteps running,
Santana sobbing, screaming)
KURT:
You okay?
You sang beautifully.
I couldn't do it.
There was only
one more chorus.
No, not the song.
I had this whole plan
to surprise everyone
and not be a bitch
for once in my life
and say all these
nice things about Finn,
and then, at the last minute,
I chickened out.
I even wrote them all down.
Would you read it to me?
No, I can't.
It's too embarrassing.
They're, like, really nice.
If there's one thing
I've learned from Finn dying,
it's that shame
is a wasted emotion.
I'm sure Finn had secrets,
too, but who cares now?
Do you really think,
one day, on your deathbed,
you're gonna think, "Oh, good,
no one knew I was kind?"
Okay.
"When we had sex,
Finn never stopped asking me
"if I was okay the whole time,
"and he meant it.
"One time, Becky Jackson left a
piece of chocolate birthday cake
"on my chair,
and when I sat on it,
"it looked like I
had pooped my pants,
"and, so, Finn walked behind me
until I could get out of school
"so no one saw
my chocolate butt
and thought that
I had messed myself."
Yeah, you would've never
lived that one down.
No.
He was a much better
person than I am.
That is true.
But Finn really
cared about you.
And I don't think he would've
done all those things
if he didn't think
you were decent, too.
(cries quietly)
Can you leave, please?
(sighs)
(Bruce Springsteen's
"No Surrender" begins)
♪ Well, we busted out
of class ♪
♪ Had to get away
from those fools ♪
♪ We learned more from
a three-minute record, baby ♪
♪ Than we ever learned
in school ♪
♪ Tonight I hear
the neighborhood drummer sound ♪
♪ I can feel my heart
begin to pound ♪
♪ You say you're tired
♪ And you just want
to close your eyes ♪
♪ And follow your dreams down
♪ Well, we made a promise
♪ We swore
we'd always remember ♪
♪ No retreat,
baby, no surrender ♪
♪ Well, now young faces
grow sad and old ♪
♪ And hearts of fire grow cold
♪ We swore blood brothers
against the wind ♪
♪ And I'm ready
to grow young again ♪
♪ And I hear your sister's voice
calling us home ♪
♪ Across the open yards
♪ Well, even we could cut
someplace of our own ♪
♪ With these drums
and these guitars ♪
♪ 'Cause we made a promise
♪ We swore
we'd always remember ♪
♪ No retreat,
baby, no surrender ♪
♪ Blood brothers
on a summer's night ♪
♪ With a vow to defend
♪ No retreat,
baby, no surrender ♪
♪ No retreat
♪ Baby, no surrender.
(song ends)
I love you guys.
Where is it, Puckerman?
It's just a tree.
I told Beiste I'd put it back.
No, not the tree.
Finn's jacket.
I went for a lie-down
in the nurse's office,
hung it up
on the coat rack by her door,
and when I woke up from
my grief siesta, it was gone.
I know you took it.
We all know you took it.
I didn't take a jacket.
If we were rounding up
the usual suspects, that would
pretty much just be you.
I didn't take Finn's jacket!
Enough!
Please!
No fighting this week.
(school bell ringing)
No me gusta. WILL: Santana?
Seriously, Puck,
you can keep it tonight,
but I need it back tomorrow.
All right?
It's Santana's now.
I swear I didn't swipe
the jacket, Mr. Shue.
I understand
wanting the jacket, Puck.
And I'm not saying
that you took it.
I didn't.
But if you did,
all I'm gonna say is
that all of us want some piece
of Finn to keep close to us.
(school bell ringing)
I owe you an apology.
Have a seat.
Okay, look, all I can say is
that I'm really...
Shut up.
You were absolutely right.
Everything you said,
you were right.
I was horrible to that kid,
and I'm utterly destroyed
that he died
thinking I didn't like him.
Well, maybe this, uh,
could be a lesson.
You know, maybe
you could start being nicer...
Oh, cut the crap, will you?
I don't care about that.
I don't care about people.
I care about him.
(sighs heavily)
He was such a good guy.
And I'll never get to tell him.
There's no lesson here,
there's no happy ending.
There's just nothing.
He's just gone.
(sighs)
He would have made
an excellent teacher.
I thought
I'd spend the next 30 years
teaching alongside him.
I thought I had all the time
in the world
(voice breaking):
to rail against him
and his dopey little Glee Club.
(sighs)
Oh, it's just so pointless.
All that potential.
(sighs)
Just...
This is sort of cheesy.
RACHEL:
No, it's beautiful.
I just had to see it.
(school bell ringing)
Nobody treat me
with kid gloves, okay?
I don't know
what to say, either.
(trembling breath)
(sniffles)
(choked-up):
I loved Finn, and...
(takes deep breath)
...he loved me,
and he loved all of you guys.
I know he did.
I like to sing in
the car and, um...
(crying): and before Finn,
I used to sing alone...
...and this was
the first song that I...
sang with him when we would...
drive around together, so...
this is for him.
(Adele's "Makes You Feel
My Love" begins)
♪ When the rain
♪ Is blowing in your face
♪ And the whole world
♪ Is on your case
♪ I could offer you
♪ A warm embrace
♪ To make you feel my love
♪ When the evening shadows
♪ And the stars appear
♪ And there's no one there
♪ To dry your tears
♪ I could hold you
♪ For a million years
♪ To make you feel my love
♪ I know you haven't
made your mind up yet ♪
♪ But I would
never do you wrong ♪
♪ I've known it
from the moment ♪
♪ That we met
♪ No doubt in my mind
♪ Where you belong
♪ I'd go hungry
♪ I'd go black and blue
♪ I'd go crawling
♪ Down the avenue
♪ No, there's nothing
♪ That I wouldn't do
♪ To make you feel my love
♪ Oh, the storms are raging
♪ On the rolling sea
♪ And on the highway of regret
♪ The winds of change
♪ Are blowing wild and free
♪ You ain't seen
nothing like me yet ♪
♪ I could make you happy
♪ Make your dreams come true
♪ Nothing that I wouldn't do
♪ Go to the ends
of the earth for you ♪
♪ To make you feel my love
♪ To make you feel my love.
(song ends)
(school bell rings)
(Will sighs)
(whistles softly)
That's a pretty hefty reward.
It's not a reward;
it's bait.
I'm gonna kick the crap out of
whoever brings that jacket back.
And I want it back
before I go home.
Home... here home?
New York.
That's my home now.
I'm not coming back here
for a while.
More than a while.
Maybe never.
You know, I used
to love coming here,
but now this just reminds me
of everything that I've lost.
I understand.
You should go.
Well, geez, Mr. Shue,
you don't have to rush me
out of the door.
(laughs) I'm a teacher.
It's supposed to make me happy
to see my kids grow up
and leave the nest.
Does it?
Well, I can say for a fact that
it certainly beats
the alternative.
♪
(softly):
Hey.
(sighs)
What...?
It's root beer.
Oh.
(chuckles)
Mmm.
So, what do you think?
50 years from now,
when this tree 30 feet tall
and the kids come
to make out under it,
will they know
who it was planted for?
Probably not.
You know what's tripping me out
is this line
between the two years.
It's his whole life.
Everything that happened
is in that line.
What are you gonna do
with your line now, Puckerman?
I'm gonna make a man of myself.
(sighs)
Figured if I don't have Finn,
I need an army to help me.
Are you serious? The army?
Air Force, actually.
Thought maybe I could be
a top gun.
I think they were actually
Naval aviators in that movie.
You know, if Finn was around,
I'd just keep letting him
point me in the right direction.
Now...
it's up to me
to figure it all out.
I'm proud of you.
You know?
Just don't get shot, okay?
Thanks, Coach.
(grunts affectionately)
(sighs)
Keep watering that tree.
You got it.
Have a good line.
(engine starts)
Hey, Mr. Shue.
Hey, Rachel.
I get flashbacks when you walk
in here and say that.
Good ones.
How are you doing?
Everyone keeps asking me that.
Well, from what I hear,
you've been a rock for everyone,
so I know that that means
that sometimes you don't get
to grieve yourself.
I'm okay.
I mean, I'm...
I'm really not okay,
but, uh, yeah,
I'm-I'm okay.
More importantly, how are you?
I have no idea.
(sighs)
I talk to him a lot.
I can still see his face
and can hear his voice
so clearly.
Do you think
that I'll ever forget it?
'Cause I'm afraid
that one day, I will.
What do you talk to him about?
Anything.
I mean, when we were dating,
it was, you know,
pretty much me talking
all the time
and him just pretending
to listen,
so it's not really
that different.
(chuckles)
I had it all planned out.
(crying)
I was gonna make it big
on Broadway
and maybe do
a Woody Allen movie.
And then when we were ready,
I would just...
come back,
and he'd be teaching here,
and I'd walk
through those doors,
and I would just say,
"I'm home."
And then we would live
happily ever after.
It's a good plan.
Did you tell him?
I didn't have to.
He knew.
And...
now what?
I don't know.
Something different.
Maybe something better.
I just... I don't think
that that's possible.
He was my person.
But thank you so much
for doing this.
I felt like I didn't know
if I would be able
to sing again,
but now I know that I can.
And I know that there have been
a lot of memorials for him,
but I had this made,
and I was hoping
that we could hang it in here.
(sighs)
Did he really say that?
(both chuckling)
He was smart, just, you know,
in an... in an untraditional
kind of way.
(chuckles)
Come on, let's... let's
hang it right over there.
(sighs)
♪
(Will sobbing)
(sobbing continues)
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com