[Snoring]
Ha ha ha!
[ Squawk]
[ Panting ]
[ Barking ]
Oh! Oh! Oh!
[ Yelping ]
Oh! Hey!
Watch yourself!
Say, what was that?
Eh... ha ha!
Oh.
For a minute,
I thought I saw
one of them...
flower things!
That's a relief.
I'd sure hate to
have to tell the queen.
Oh, well.
Have a rotten day.
# I'm a bad troll #
# A very bad troll #
# La la
la la la la ##
Waa! Ha ha!
[Footsteps ]
Hello, my pretties.
Hello. Hello. Hello.
Daddy's home.
Ha ha ha!
# Da da da ##
Llort!
Ow!
What is it?
What is
that awful smell?
Nothing. Just something
from the swamp, my dear.
That I wouldn't mind,
but this smells
like honeysuckle.
Shh. I brought
something for you.
Ta-da!
Fresh September morning dew
from the outside.
Dew just for you.
Hee hee hee!
You know, Violet,
what this garden needs
is a big rosy posy,
right there
in the middle.
And I'm just
the Sweet William--
I mean Stanley--
to do it.
Watch.
Ah, that's nice.
You're growing too high!
Please, stop.
Oh, please.
[ Rumbling ]
Would you
look at that?
[ Growling ]
Flower. Uh-oh!
Come with me!
You did this?
Right under
the queen's nose?
Ooh!
I hate flowers!
[ Gulp ]
And for your crime,
you are going before
the number-one flower hater
in the land.
Gnorga!
# In my kingdom #
# No flower shall grow #
# No face shall smile #
# No star shall glow #
# No heart shall care #
# Noword be true #
# No rule be fair #
# I promise you #
Ha ha ha!
# Touch the queen
and turn to stone#
#Touch the queen
and turn to stone #
# It feels delicious
to be so vicious #
# I'm Gnorga
the queen of mean #
# It's so delightful
to be so spiteful #
# I'm Gnorga
the queen of mean #
# If I choose
I destroy and demolish #
# Arrest and abolish
every troll I've known #
#Stand in my way
and you'll stand there forever #
# Because I'll turn you
into stone #
# I'm the queen of mean #
# I'm the meanest queen
you've ever seen #
#You should have no doubt
about my clout #
# I'm the queen of mean#
Waaa!
Ooh!
Ha ha ha!
# It's simply yummy
to be so crummy #
# I'm Gnorga
the queen of mean #
# I'm so grateful
to be so hateful #
# I'm Gnorga
the queen of mean #
#When I want
I will pillage and plunder #
# I'll bellow and thunder
Make you shake and moan #
# Get in my way
and I'll get you forever #
# Because I'll turn you
into stone #
# I'm the queen of mean #
# I'm the meanest queen
you've ever seen #
#You should have no doubt
about my clout #
# I'm the queen of mean #
# Absolutely the queen
the queen #
# I'm the queen of mean #
# I'm the meanest queen
you've ever seen #
#You should have no doubt
about my clout #
# I'm the queen of mean ##
Ha ha ha!
- Stone!
Be still!
Stanley, because you
have repeatedly...
- repeatedly--
- Disobeyed?
I am getting there, dear.
Disobeyed and, uh...
and violated...
unh... unh... the code
of proper troll behavior,
we have no choice but
to sentence you to, uh... to, uh--
Stone!
Ha ha ha!
Stone?
Turn him to stone.
Ha ha ha!
Be still!
Ahh!
With our number dwindling
yearly, dearly--
I mean dearie--
do we really want to
be turning him into,
you know, st--
He is kind, he is good,
he is gentle...
and he is giving
a bad name
to trolls everywhere!
Yes, I know, love lumps.
I quite agree.
I won't have him growing
any more of those things!
Flowers?
Stone him!
Why not make
an example of him?
I know a place-- rock and steel--
nothing grows.
Creatures more troll-like
than we are.
It will be worse
than stone.
It will be slow.
It will be painful.
Think what they'll say
about you in the newspapers.
Why, it's a shoo-in
for the tabloids.
Done!
Ah-ah-ah!
Ah ha ha ha!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Stop!
[ Grunting ]
Oh, ha ha ha!
Rock and steel.
Nothing grows.
Wh--
Oh!
Ohh!
Ahh.
[ Sighing ]
Wait a minute!
I think there's been
some mistake here.
Look at all
the green things--
grass, leaves, flowers.
What a place!
It's wonderful!
I'm going to
like it here!
[ Growl]
Aah!
[ Growl ]
Oh. Hello.
No! Aah!
[ Growl ]
[ Dogs Barking ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Barking ]
Oh!
Whoo! Whoo!
Oh ho ho! No!
Ah-ah-ah!
Aah!
Yum. Yum.
Ah-- Ah--
[ Ah-choo ]
[ Slurp ]
Ow!
Aah!
Ooh! Ah!
Hmm.
[ Honk Honk]
Yeeow!
Ah-ah-ahh!
Whoo-ho!
[ Quack]
Wa-hoo!
[ Ribbit ]
Ugh!
Oh!
Ah ha ha ha!
Stop!
Oh!
[ Crying ]
What a place.
It's worse than home.
I-I don't
like it here.
Not one bit.
All I ever wanted
was a little patch of green.
There.
There's my patch.
I'm safe in here,
and I'm never going out
of this cave...
ever again.
Hillary, have you seen
my briefcase?
In your hand, dear.
This trial certainly
seems to have you rattled.
Nobody's cooperating.
I'll have to work
a miracle to win it.
Plaid or striped?
Just a regular miracle
would do.
Then Dad and me are gonna
sail in my boat.
Then we're gonna
have ice cream,
and I'm gonna have
double chocolate.
Hey, Rosie!
Don't touch that!
Only me and Dad
get to go.
Go.
No, Rosie.
You stay here.
This is just
for me and Dad.
Ah-ha!
Ready to go, Dad?
- Finally.
- Great!
You're not coming.
Your father's off
to a meeting, honey.
But you promised
to take me to the park!
You know I have an important case
to prepare for.
The park will
have to come later.
It always
has to be later!
Why can't we
ever do what I want?
I want to do
what I want!
I'll see you tonight.
Your father works
very hard
to make our life nice,
children.
You have to learn
to appreciate that.
Mom, will you take us
to float my boat?
Oh, Gus. I have an open house
on Park Avenue today.
But Maria's here.
Yeah, cooking
and cleaning.
I'm late.
Now be a good boy, please.
And keep an eye on Rosie.
Good-bye, baby!
Aw, who needs them, anyhow?
## [ Humming ]
"Private. Keep out."
And stay out, Maria!
Hey, Rosie,
wanna go with me?
## [ Humming ]
[ Turns Off Vacuum ]
[ Bam ]
Ugh!
[ Turns On Vacuum ]
Beast.
[Tires Screeching]
Whoo!
Ha ha ha!
Rosie?
Rosie!
[ Squeals ]
Oh!
[ Giggling ]
Boat.
[ Motor Starts ]
Rosie!
Butterfly.
Butterfly!
[ Squealing ]
Ah! Oh!
Butterfly!
[ Panting ]
Hee hee hee!
[ Buzzing ]
[ Ribbit ]
Aah!
Ha ha ha!
Rosie?
Troll.
Rosie!
Rosie, get out
of the water!
Rosie!
Troll.
Oh!
[ Ribbit ]
[ Panting ]
Hang on, Rosie!
Hang on!
[ Ribbit ]
Coming, Rosie.
Rosie!
Rosie, where are you?
Ugh!
[ Giggling ]
Troll.
Uh...
that's right,
I am a troll.
You better believe it.
Um... I'm-I'm Stanley.
What's your name?
Hi.
Oh, uh, you don't--
you don't say much,
do you?
Troll.
No! Stanley!
Can you say Stanley?
Troll.
Forget it.
[ Sighs ]
Hey! I-I can--
I can grow things.
Do you wanna watch me?
Get a load of this.
Yeh!
Ha ha!
Flower.
Bug!
Eew!
Uh-oh.
[Whistle Blows ]
Ha! Ha ha ha!
Wa! Hee hee hee!
Hoo! Hoo! Yippee!
Troll.
Oh!
[ Giggling ]
I knew it!
I knew you'd like that!
Oh, we're a lot alike,
you and me.
My mommy read me stories about humans,
before she put me to bed,
but you are the first one
that I have ever met in person.
- Howcha do?
- Troll.
Yes, yes, oh, but I'm not
like other trolls.
I'm different.
I mean, I like
beautiful things,
Iike flowers.
Flower.
Yes. Flowers.
Oh, please,
tell me your name.
Rosie.
Oh! Rosie?
Did you he--
Rosie! Oh, yes!
I like that a lot.
Hee hee!
I like you a lot too.
And I'm so sorry about
the place being such a mess.
It doesn't have to be,
you know.
Oh, no. It could be
so beautiful.
Hee hee hee!
It could be cozy
for Rosie.
Cozy for Rosie.
Rosie, watch this.
# I like to
close my eyes #
# So my heart
can plainly see #
# Right through
the way things are #
# Clear to the way
they ought to be #
#To somewhere
that's safe and sunlit #
# And serene #
# Oh, and absolutely green #
Hee hee!
Hee hee hee!
Ho ho ho!
# Picture a perfect place #
# Where there is
no doom and gloom #
# Birds singing happy songs #
# And flowers
bursting into bloom #
# A somewhere
like nowhere else #
#You've ever seen #
#That's absolutely green #
#That's how
the world can be #
# If we just want it #
#Why isn't it that way
do you suppose #
# Maybe 'cause no one's
concentrating on it#
#Just give it
love and kindness #
# And see how green
it grows #
# Maybe it's just a dream #
# But I know
deep in my heart #
# If everyone believed#
# Believing is
the place to start #
# We could fill
everywhere with flowers #
# I f each of us
used all our powers #
# If we all cared
is what I really mean #
# We could all live
in a world #
#That's bright and shining #
# Oh, and absolutely green #
#We could all live
in a world #
#That's bright
and shining #
# And absolutely green ##
Uh-huh.
See?
Hee hee hee!
Ha ha ha!
I knew I could do it.
Hee hee hee!
Ugh!
I'm coming, Rosie!
Uh-oh! Oh!
Oh! Who's that?
I better hide.
Ooh! Ooh!
Uh!
Aah!
- Mm!
- Oh!
My boat!
Hee hee!
Rosie!
How did you
get down here?
You could have
killed yourself!.
My boat got broken
thanks to you!
Oh, no!
Shh!
Quiet!
Snuffy, don't!
I can't help it.
It's my...
hay fever.
Well, just
hold your breath!
Oh, here it comes.
[ Ah-choo ]
- Who's that?
- Troll.
Oh, ah, no.
Oh, uh, wait.
Troll.
Aah!
Oh, uh--
Troll, mine.
[ Stammering ]
Ha ha!
Hi.
Who are you?
Uh, I'm Stanley.
Troll!
I'm a troll.
And he's a good troll!
#Troll, troll
He's a troll #
#Troll, troll ##
Stop saying that.
He can't be a troll,
because there's
no such thing as trolls.
Uh-oh. Talking flowers.
This is weird.
Rosie, we better
go home now.
Go? You mean, leave?
You're gonna take
Rosie away from me?
You got it, spaceman.
- Don't, please!
- Get off my foot!
Waah!
Get away, you mutant!
Aw.
Waah!
Now look what
you've done!
Oh, gee!
No, don't.
Don't cry.
Oh, don't cry.
Rosie, stop.
Come on.
What can I do
to make you stop?
Buddle.
Buddle!
What is boddle?
[ Chirp Chirp ]
[Llort]
# La da da dee#
Llort, you idiot!
Hush up! Hush up!
Hush up!
# Dee da da da #
# Da dee do do ##
- Waah!
- What's that?
What's what, love lumps?
It sounds like...
- Waah!
- someone in pain.
I don't hear anything.
Waah! Waah!
Ha ha ho ho!
Shh! Shh!
Why, it's a baby crying.
[ Grr]
Waah!
Ooh! She sounds
so miserable!
You see,
Llort, lovey.
Life does have
its unexpected joys.
How I love to watch
a helpless creature suffer!
Ha ha ha ha!
[ Coughs ]
Ha ha ha!
Aah!
Stop attacking me!
Why do you
always attack me?
Time for beddy-bye.
Sit! Down!
Okay, now drink
your stupid bottle!
But then we go home!
Oh, "bottle."
Of course.
[ Sniff Sniff]
Come on, dolly.
Show us the old smile.
Hee hee hee!
[ Sniff Sniff]
Hey, this is serious.
Ahh, step aside, chumps.
I'll show yous
how to make the kid smile.
Hey, what
are you doing?
Hee hee! You'll see.
Hee hee!
Hey, I get it!
The old soft petal.
Come on! Follow me!
Oh, boy!
[ Clapping ]
Hee hee hee!
Hee hee!
Yeee!
Aah!
Ooh!
"Worse than death"?
"Slow and painful"?
Does that look
like misery to you?
Tell me. Does that
look terrible to you?
It looks nice,
very nice.
Don't you think so,
snooksie-poo?
Yes, I think so.
That's precisely
what's wrong...
you moron!
Punishment isn't
supposed to be nice.
It's supposed to
be punishing.
I should have
turned him to stone
Iike I wanted to
in the first place!
Perhaps you're
overreacting, love lumps.
It can't be as bad as--
as good as all that.
I know that place.
It's very-- Ooh!
Very-- Look!
What's happening to it?
Oh, well,
you have to wait.
Wait for you to wreck it
even more?
It looks stupid!
Oh! He's more troll-like
than Stanley!
He's rude!
He's smart-mouthed!
Ha ha ha!
I adore him!
And I'm going to send him
a little something
that will finish our Stanley
for now and forever!
Ooh!
Ha ha ha ha!
The boy will cry
a sea of tears.
The wind
will blow them well.
A thunderbolt
to shake their hearts
and drown them
in the spell!
Ha ha ha ha!
Waah!
Oh, come on.
It's not so bad.
I think it looks quite--
hee hee hee--
flor-adorable.
Waah!
[Gnorga ]
Ha ha ha!
Gnorga!
[ Coughing ]
What's happening?
It's Gnorga!
She's put
a curse on you!
That's right,
you happy sap!
We are finally
going to be rid of you
once and for all!
Ha ha ha ha!
No, don't!
Do you think maybe
you could stop now, huh?
Aah!
Rosie!
Rosie, hold on!
[ Coughing ]
Stanley!
Do something!
Uh! Uh!
Hmm!
Hey...
I'm not crying anymore.
I've stopped.
How'd that happen?
Why, I believe
you believed in saving
your sister so much
that for just
a moment there,
your--
your power was stronger
than Gnorga's.
It was?
Yeah. Oh, sure!
That was a good deed.
I believe there's no end
to what you can do
if you set
your mind to it.
I keep thinking when I find
my patch of green,
I'll invite every good troll
to come live with me.
They'll do good deeds,
and they'll have green thumbs.
Green thumb.
Just like me.
You sure like
to dream a lot.
Oh, sure.
You have to.
Anything that's real
starts with a dream.
Dreams are silly.
No! No, they're not!
Look, Gus.
See this boat?
This is no ordinary boat.
This is a dream boat.
And I'm gonna
show you how it works.
Look out there.
I-I don't see anything.
Hee hee hee!
Look again.
Where?
Ohh!
Oh!
Whoa, Stanley!
We're going to crash!
Oh!
Hee hee hee!
No way!
This is my dream,
and nobody gets hurt
in my dreams.
# Do you see it
through the trees #
Take a good look.
# Do you see
a magic place #
Oh, good.
Now look up.
# Do you feel
a tingly breeze #
Hoo hoo hoo!
# Blowing friendly
on your face #
Ha ha ha!
It's working very well.
Isn't this good?
Ha ha ha!
We're floating.
Oh, air is nice.
# Welcome to my world #
# A little world apart #
# A place my dreams
have made with wishes #
# From my heart #
# Welcome to my world#
# There's such a lovely view #
# If you believe in dreams #
# Then you will see it too #
# It's a gift
to be able to imagine #
#Then make your dreams
come true #
Look!
# It's a gift
of a very special kind#
# And I give
that gift to you#
Ha ha ha!
# Take it and begin#
# And let your eyes behold#
# A wonderland I've dreamed
more valuable than gold#
# Welcome to my world#
# A little world apart #
# A place my dreams
have made with wishes #
# From my heart #
# Welcome to my world##
Welcome.
Bienvenue.
I hope you'll
make yourself at home.
It's so nice
to have company.
Ha ha ha!
Welcome!
Welcome, one and all!
Ha ha ha!
How do you do that?
Oh, it's easy.
You got to
have a dream.
I haven't got
any dreams of my own.
Oh, sure you do.
Everyone has.
Here.
You take the wheel.
Me? You want me
to steer the boat?
Of course.
I want to
see your dream.
How?
How? It's very simple.
Ha ha!
Well, first, relax.
Now think of something
fun to do.
Okay, okay,
I'm thinking.
Good. Hold on
to that thought.
Ugh!
Yeah!
Hold on, Stanley!
Oh! Hey, hey, hey!
Hey, slow down!
Don’t you know dreams
are fragile things?
Errr!
There we go!
Full speed ahead!
Aah!
- Wow!
- Uh!
Ooh, wow!
Ooh, ow!
I hope you get some better thoughts
in your head than that.
That was more
like a nightmare.
[ Yawn ]
Don’t you think
we'd better
get home, Rosie?
Home.
Stanley.
Yeah?
Would you teach me
how to have
a green thumb?
Ha ha! Okay.
We could make flowers.
Right.
And blow them all
to smithereens.
[ Yawn ]
Wouldn't that be cool?
[ Snoring ]
"Gnorga and Llort--
laughingstock"?
"No authority"?
"Bad trolls turning good
at record pace"?
Have you seen this?
Seen what, sugar shins?
These blasted editorials!
They say our power's slipping.
We have no hold on our people.
Don't they know bad press
clears up my exquisite warts?
Maybe it's time
we told them we drowned
that pitiful little freak.
That is, once you make sure
we really did drown him.
Mmm!
Good night.
See you first thing
in the morning.
I told you to make sure
he's gone!
Ooh!
I don't see him,
llama legs.
I mean, look.
Not a hint.
Not a trace.
Not a clue.
[ Snoring ]
Oh!
What is it?
Uh, nothing. Nothing.
Nothing to worry your
pleasingly plump little head.
I need you
to tell me, Llort.
Did I or didn't I put
that wretched little creature
out of my misery?
Well, not-not
strictly speaking, bunny bum.
What?
- I said--
- I heard what you said.
What I want to know
is why!
Why didn't we do things
my way to begin with?
Do you know what
they're saying about us?
Finished! Washed up!
They're calling
for us to resign.
They're afraid
any troll anywhere
can start being good
without warning.
Think of it.
I can't think of it.
It's too dreadful. Too mortifying.
It can't happen.
I'll go there myself
and finish that happy
little mutant tonight!
[Whimpers ]
[Thunderclap]
No! No, my dear! No!
That place
is too dangerous!
Besides, it's green.
Wind, wind,
howl in the dark
and trash the place
called Central Park!
Wait! Wait for me!
Wait!
[ Gnorga ]
Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Ohh.
Rosie.
Rosie, wake up.
We have to go.
Come on. It's late.
We've got to go home.
Go.
Ohh... troll.
He'll be okay.
Come on. Shh!
Before he wakes up.
Mm!
[ Snoring ]
Troll, troll.
Troll, troll, troll.
[ Smack]
We have to get home
before Mom and Dad.
[ Snoring ]
Ugh!
Uh!
Come on.
[Owl Hooting]
Oh, wow.
What happened?
I don't like this.
Ohh.
It's okay, Rosie.
It's okay.
Come on.
We better go home now.
Yes. You said
it was big.
Yes. You told me
it was wide.
But you didn't say
it was bigger
than Troll world
and Gremlin land
and Goblinville
put together!
How in the name
of "Shartarb"
are we ever
going to find him?
Oh, I don't know,
cow ears.
It was your idea
to come here,
if you don't mind
me saying so.
I do mind
your saying so.
My feet hurt,
my warts are getting blisters...
and my corns
are getting bunions.
Oh, but wait.
Oh, shh!
What's this?
Troll boy
with the nasty temper?
Ha ha ha!
And look. That sweet,
adorable little baby.
Ugh! Ugh!
Horrible creature,
isn't she?
-[Chomp]
- Ow! Ow!
[ Snoring ]
# Hmm mmm mmm mmm #
# Hmm mmm mmm mmm mmm #
# Hmm mmm
Hmm mmm mmm mmm##
[Bird Cawing]
Heh heh heh!
[Bird Screeching]
Uh!
After them!
Aargh!
- Ha ha ha!
- Hang on, Rosie!
- Hang on!
-[Gnorga ] Ha ha ha!
Aah!
Ha ha ha ha!
Whoa!
Uh-oh!
Aargh!
Whoa!
- [ Gasps ]
- Ha ha ha ha!
Wait for me,
tootsy toes!
[ Gasps ]
Aargh!
Gotcha!
Ha ha ha ha!
Heh heh heh.
Aah!
[Thud]
I think
we lost them, Rosie.
Rosie?
Rosie!
What am I going to do?
Um... uh,
I'll get Stanley.
Stanley!
[ Yawning ]
Wait. What time is it?
Oh. It's nighttime.
[ Roars ]
All right,
tell you what.
Come back tomorrow
when the sun comes up,
and I'll...
discuss it with you.
Good night.
[ Yawning ]
[ Gnorga ]
Ha ha ha!
Oh, Stanley!
Wakey, wakey!
I've got
the little baby!
I've got the baby!
But-- Oh!
What-- Who--
Stanley!
[ Gnorga Laughs ]
Aah!
[ Gnorga ]
Stanley.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Gnorga!
Gnorga! Oh!
She's here!
She's got Rosie!
You've got to help
me get her back!
No, no, no,
I can't--
You're the only one
who can help.
You've got
the green thumb.
[ Gnorga ]
Stanley!
I've got the baby!
Uh! Easy!
Hoo hoo!
Stop being such
a scaredy-cat!
But what can I do?
What about
all your powers,
Mr. You've-got-
to-believe?
No, no, no.
My prestidigitation
is no match
for Gnorga's magic.
Sure, you're just
saying that
because you're
scared to fight her.
[ Gasp ]
I can't! Gnorga--
Oh, you don't know Gnorga.
She'll destroy me.
She'll marbleize me.
Well, I'm not scared.
I'd help if l could.
She'll turn me into stone.
I don't want to
be rockenized.
Gus! Don’t you understand?
In the troll world,
darkness always
triumphs over light.
Know what, Stanley?
You'll never have
a dream come true.
And you know why?
Because you’re
too scared to fight
for what you believe in!
You're a coward!
[ Gnorga ] Why did I listen
to you and send him here?
I should've sent him
to Goblinville.
They know how to deal with
a smiling, happy troll.
Come on.
- [ Growling ]
- Shh!
[ Barking ]
- Hush up!
- [ Whimpering ]
Hush up!
You're a booger.
Oh! Oooh!
Oooh! Oooh!
I'll turn you into stone.
Let me at her!
Wait! She's our bait.
I want her hurt!
No! We need her
to attract Stanley.
Stop attacking me.
Why do you always
attack me?
Aaah!
No!
That mutant little troll
has proven himself
to be monstrously
more trouble than he's worth.
I know.
I quite agree.
That's why we truly need
the little baby,
to bring him here
so we can finish him.
Come on, now,
take a deep breath.
Inhale.
Exhale.
[ Squealing ]
What's that?
- Inhale.
- [ Squeals ]
Exhale.
Will you hush up, Rosie?
[ Growling ]
[ Whimpering ]
[Rosie ]
Gus!
After them!
Let's get outta here!
[ Panting ]
Aah!
Uh!
Ooh!
[ Panting ]
Let me go, you ugly,
disgusting troll!
Ooh!
Gus!
You want to
act like a troll?
Be a troll!
Ha ha ha!
I'm not fooling anybody.
Oh.
And they're in trouble.
Trouble!
I have to go to them.
I'm going. I'm going!
What kind
of a good troll am I?
I'm going!
So what if Gnorga
finishes me.
I'm going!
I have to go.
[Gnorga]
Ha ha ha!
Oh ho ho!
I can't!
I'm not going.
Waah-aah!
[ Sobbing ]
Ha ha!
Oh, go away.
Ooh hoo!
I'm a coward.
[Thunderclap ]
Ha ha ha!
Oy dee dee dee
ahh ha ha!
Stop it!
Rosie!
No! No! Ow!
Be careful!
Aah!
No!
What's happening to me?
[ Snorts ]
Rosie!
[ Crying ]
Gus.
Rosie?
[ Giggling ]
Rosie! Stanley!
Stanley! Yes!
Gotcha!
Mm! Uh!
Gus!
- Well!
- Aah!
What do we have here?
Ha ha ha ha ha!
[Stanley]
Oh! Uh!
Aahhh!
Aah!
Uh!
[ Giggling ]
We beat Gnorga.
[ Kiss ]
You better believe it.
Stanley, you did it!
Oh, not yet he didn't.
Ha ha ha!
Touch him.
Touch him, you little troll.
Touch him!
Uh!
[ Gnorga ]
Aah ha ha ha ha ha!
It is done.
Aah! Oh!
Ooh! Oof!.
[ Thunderclap ]
Aaahhhh!
[ Sighs ]
[Alan ] I felt terrible
about having to run out.
He was so upset.
[ Hillary ]Apparently,
he recovered pretty quickly.
Maria said they were both
so quiet all afternoon,
she hardly knew
they were here.
That's a little strange.
I haven't seen hi m
suck his thumb in years.
Well, we both have been
terribly busy lately.
Maybe he's feeling
a little insecure.
Night-night, my babies.
Morning.
Hi, Dad.
Ah. Who's your friend?
Oh, your mom
said to tell you
breakfast is ready.
Still mad at me
for yesterday.
Well... what
about today, huh?
You know,
your mother and I
thought of a few fun
things we could do.
Dad, do you think
today maybe
we could do
what I want to do?
[ Radio ]
And today park officials
are counting the cost
of clearing up after a freak tornado
ripped through Central Park,
devastating the entire area.
[ Crying ]
Stanley.
[ Kiss ]
[ Hillary ]
Gussie! Let's go!
[ Sighs ]
Bye, Stanley.
[ Whistle ]
Stanley?
# I like to close my eyes #
# So my heart
can plainly see #
# Right through
the way things are #
# Clear to the way
they ought to be #
# To somewhere that's safe
and sunlit and serene #
# Oh, and absolutely green #
Hee hee hee hee!
Ooh hoo hoo hoo!
# Picture a perfect place #
# Where there is
no doom and gloom #
# Birds singing
happy songs #
# And flowers
bursting into bloom #
# A somewhere like nowhere else
you've ever seen #
# That's absolutely green #
# That's how the world
can be if we just want it #
# Why isn't it that way
do you suppose #
# Maybe 'cause no one's
concentrating on it #
#Just give it
love and kindness #
# See how green it grows #
# Maybe it's just a dream #
# But I know
deep in my heart #
# If everyone believed#
# Believing is
the place to start #
# We could fill everywhere
with flowers #
# If each of us
used all our powers #
# If we all cared
is what I really mean #
# We could all live in a world
that's bright and shining #
# Oh, and absolutely green #
# We could live in a world
that's bright and shining #
# And absolutely green ##
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
Gnorga, queen of posies!
[ Growl, Crunch ]
Aahhh!
Stop attacking me!
Why do you always
have to attack me?
Sit! Stay! Sit!