♪ [Waltz] ♪
♪ [Ends] ♪
Your Highness...
- [People Chattering]
Hyah!
[Woman Narrating]
There was a time, not very long ago,
when we lived in an enchanted world
of elegant palaces and grand parties.
The year was 1916
and my son Nicholas
was the Czar of lmperial Russia.
♪ [Dance] ♪
[Dancers Clap]
[Dancers Clap Twice]
Hello, darling.
We were celebrating
the 300th anniversary
- of our family's rule.
- Oh, Papa!
And, that night,
no star burned brighter
than that of our sweet Anastasia,
my youngest granddaughter.
She begged me not to return to Paris,
so I had a very special gift
made for her [Gasps]
to make the separation easier
for both of us.
For me?
Is it a jewellery box?
Dimitri. You belong in the kitchen.
- [Grunting]
Look.
♪ [Waltz] ♪
[Gasps]
It plays our lullaby.
You can play it at night
before you go to sleep
and pretend that it's me singing.
♪ [Continues] ♪
♪ On the wind ♪
♪ 'Cross the sea ♪
♪ Hear this song and remember ♪
♪ Soon you'll be home with me ♪
♪ Once upon a December ♪
♪ [Ends] ♪
- [Chuckling]
Read what it says.
"Together in Paris."
[Gasps]
Really? Oh, Grandmamma.
Mmm!
- [Laughing]
[Grandmother Narrating] But we would never
be together in Paris,
- for a dark shadow
- [Murmuring, Gasping]
- had descended upon the house
- [Glass Shatters]
of the Romanovs.
His name was Rasputin.
We thought he was a holy man,
but he was a fraud,
power-mad and dangerous.
How dare you return to the palace?
But I am your confidant.
Confidant? Hah!
You are a traitor. Get out!
You think you can banish the great Rasputin?
By the unholy powers vested in me,
- I banish you with a curse.
- [Guests Gasping]
- [Gasping]
- Mark my words.
You and your family will die
- within the fortnight.
- [Guests Gasping, Murmuring]
I will not rest until I see the end
of the Romanov line for ever!
[Guests Screaming, Shouting]
[Narrator] Consumed by his hatred
for Nicholas and his family,
Rasputin sold his soul
for the power to destroy them.
[Groans]
Go.
Fulfil your dark purpose
and seal the fate of the Czar and his family
once and for all.
[Narrator] From that moment on,
the spark of unhappiness in our country
was fanned into a flame
that would soon destroy our lives for ever.
[Gunshots]
- Help! Help!
- Hurry, children.
- My music box.
- Anastasia!
Come back! Come back!
- Anastasia...
- [Explosion]
Oh!
- [Grunts] Oy.
- Please, hurry! Come this way!
Out the servants' quarters.
- Hurry, Anastasia.
- Rasputin, she's getting away.
- My music box.
- Go! Go!
[Man] Comrades, in here!
Where are they, boy?
[Groans]
- Grandmamma...
- Keep up with me, darling.
- [Grunting, Shouting]
- [Screams]
- Rasputin!
- Let me go. Please!
You'll never escape me, child. Never!
[Laughing]
[Gasps]
[Shouting]
- Let me go!
Bartok!
- Master!
- [Gurgling]
- Uh-
- [Train Whistle Blows]
Anastasia, hurry. Hurry.
Oh!
- Grandmamma!
- Here, take my hand.
- Hold onto my hand.
- Don't let go!
- [Screams]
- Oh! Anastasia!
- [Grunts]
- Anastasia!
[Narrator] So many lives
were destroyed that night.
What had always been
was now gone for ever.
And my Anastasia, my beloved grandchild,
I never saw her again.
♪ [People Vocalizing] ♪
♪ [Upbeat] ♪
♪ Saint Petersburg is gloomy ♪
♪ Saint Petersburg is bleak ♪
♪ My underwear got frozen
standing here all week ♪
♪ Since the Revolution
our lives have been so grey ♪
♪ Thank goodness for the gossip
that gets us through the day Hey ♪
♪ Have you heard
there's a rumour in Saint Petersburg? ♪
what they're saying on the street? ♪
♪ Although the Czar did not survive, ♪
♪ One daughter may be still alive ♪
Oh?
♪ The Princess Anastasia ♪
♪ But please do not repeat ♪
♪ It's a rumour, a legend, a mystery ♪
♪ Something whispered in an alleyway
or through a crack ♪ - [Mutters]
♪ It's a rumour that's part of our history ♪
♪ They say her royal grandmamma
will pay a royal sum ♪
♪ To someone who can bring the princess back ♪
♪ [Whistling] ♪
- Vlad!
[Gasps] Dimitri!
[Muttering]
♪ A rouble for this painting ♪
♪ It's Romanov, I swear ♪
♪ Count Yusupov's pyjamas -
comrades, buy the pair ♪
♪ I got this from the palace,
it's lined with real fur ♪
♪ It could be worth a fortune
if it belonged to her ♪
Well, Dimitri, I got us a theatre.
Everything's going according to plan.
All we need is the girl.
Just think, Vlad, no more forging papers,
no more stolen goods.
We'll have three tickets out of here:
One for you,
one for me and one for Anastasia!
♪ It's the rumour, the legend, the mystery ♪
♪ It's the Princess Anastasia
who will help us fly ♪
♪ You and I, friend, will go down in history ♪
♪ We'll find a girl to play the part
and teach her what to say ♪
♪ Dress her up and take her to Paree ♪
♪ lmagine the reward
her dear old grandmamma will pay ♪
♪ Who else could pull it off but you and me?♪
♪ - We'll be rich
- We'll be rich ♪
♪ - We'll be out
- We'll be out ♪
♪ And Saint Petersburg
will have some more to talk about ♪
[Both Shouting, Laughing]
♪ Have you heard
there's a rumour in Saint Petersburg?♪
what they're saying on the street?♪
♪ Hey ♪
- [Chattering]
- ♪ Hey ♪
- [Chattering Continues]
♪ Have you heard
there's a rumour in Saint Petersburg?♪
♪ Have you heard?
Comrades, what do you suppose? ♪
♪ - A fascinating mystery
- The biggest con in history ♪
♪ The Princess Anastasia ♪
♪ Alive or dead? ♪
Who knows? Shh!
[Children Chattering]
[Door Opens]
[Woman] I got you a job in the fish factory.
You go down this path till you get to
the fork in the road.
- Go left-
- [Girl] Bye!
- Are you listening?
- Bye, everybody!
- [Kids Shouting]
- I'm listening, Comrade Phlegmenkoff.
You've been a thorn in my side
since you were brought here. - Hey.
- Acting like the Queen of Sheba
- Bye!
instead of the nameless
no-account you are. [Grunting]
- For the last ten years,
- [Sighs]
I've fed you,
I've clothed you, I've...
- I've kept a roof over-
- Kept a roof over my head.
[Gasps]
How is it you don't have a clue
who you were before you came to us,
but you can remember all that?
- I do have a clue to...
- Ach! I know.
"Together in Paris"!
So, you want to go to France
to find your family, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
- [Laughing]
Little Miss Anya,
it's time to take your place in life.
In life and in line.
And be grateful, too.
[Grunts] "Together in Paris"!
[Laughing]
Be grateful.
[Mimicking Phlegmenkoff's Laugh]
"Be grateful, Anya."
I am grateful. Grateful to get away!
"Go left" she says.
Well, I know what's to the left.
I'll be "Anya the orphan" for ever.
But if I go right, maybe I could find...
Whoever gave me this necklace
must have loved me.
This is crazy. Me? Go to Paris?
Send me a sign!
A hint!
Anything!
[Barking]
- Hey! Hey-hey-hey!
- [Barking Continues]
I don't have time
to play right now, OK?
I'm waiting for a sign.
You- Would you please leave me alo-
Stop! Give me that back!
Give- Give- Oh! Oh!
- [Grunts]
- [Whimpering]
Oh, great. A dog wants me
to go to Saint Petersburg.
[Barking, Whimpering]
- [Panting]
- [Gasps]
- Okay.
- [Barking]
I can take a hint.
[Whimpering]
[Barking, Whimpering]
[Wind Whistling]
[Barking]
♪ Heart, don't fail me now ♪
♪ Courage, don't desert me ♪
♪ Don't turn back ♪
♪ Now that we're here ♪
[Barking Continues]
♪ People always say ♪
♪ Life is full of choices ♪
♪ No one ever mentions fear ♪
♪ Or how the world can seem so vast ♪
♪ On a journey ♪
♪ To the past ♪
♪ Somewhere down this road ♪
♪ I know someone's waiting ♪
♪ Years of dreams just can't be wrong ♪
♪ Arms will open wide ♪
♪ I'll be safe and wanted ♪
♪ Finally home where I belong ♪
♪ Well, starting now ♪
♪ I'm learning fast ♪
♪ On this journey ♪
[Murmurs, Barks]
♪ To the past ♪
[Children Laughing]
[Woman] Oh, look!
Look at the beatiful puppy!
♪ Home, love, family ♪
- [Kids] Bye!
♪ There was once a time
I must have had them, too ♪
♪ Home, love, family ♪
♪ I will never be complete ♪
♪ Until I find you ♪
♪ One step at a time ♪
♪ One hope, then another ♪
♪ Who knows where this road may go? ♪
♪ Back to who I was ♪
♪ On to find my future ♪
♪ Things my heart still needs to know ♪
♪ Yes, let this be a sign ♪
♪ Let this road be mine ♪
♪ Let it lead me to my past ♪
♪ And bring me home ♪
♪ At last ♪
[Barking]
- One ticket to Paris, please.
- Exit visa.
- Exit visa?
- No exit visa, no ticket!
- [Both Gasp] Oh! Hmph
- [Growls]
Psst! See Dimitri. He can help.
- Where can I find him?
- At the old palace.
But you didn't hear it from me.
- Oh.
- Go.
- Go, go, go.
- Hmm, Dimitri.
Nice. Nice. Very nice.
- [Woman] And I look like princess.
- OK...
- I dance like a feather.
- Thank you. Thank you. Next, please.
[Breathy Sign]
[Husky, Sultry Voice]
Grandma, it's me.
Anastasia.
[Groans, Grumbles]
Oh, brother. [Whimpers]
That's it, Dimitri. Game over.
Our last kopeck gone
for this flea-infested theatre
and still no girl to pretend to be Anastasia.
We'll find her, Vlad.
She's here somewhere, right under our noses.
One look at this jewellery box, the Empress
will think we have the real Anastasia.
- I'm looking for...
- Before she catches on,
we'll be off spending the 10 million roubles.
[Whimpering]
Pooka!
Pooka, where are you?
[Grunting, Groans]
- Did you hear something?
- Mmm, no.
Hello?
Anybody home?
[Grunting, Whimpering]
[Growls, Barks]
[Blows]
Hmm.
- [Whimpering]
- ♪ [Music Box Tune] ♪
This place-
It's...
It's like a memory from a dream.
♪ Dancing bears ♪
♪ Painted wings ♪
♪ Things I almost remember ♪
♪ And a song ♪
♪ Someone sings ♪
♪ Once upon a December ♪
♪ Someone holds me safe and warm ♪
♪ Horses prance through a silver storm ♪
♪ Figures dancing gracefully ♪
♪ Across my memory ♪
♪ [Continues] ♪
♪ Someone holds me safe and warm ♪
♪ Horses prance through a silver storm ♪
♪ Figures dancing gracefully ♪
♪ Across my memory ♪
♪ Far away, long ago ♪
♪ Glowing dim as an ember ♪
♪ Things my heart used to know ♪
♪ Things it yearns to remember ♪
♪ And a song ♪
♪ Someone sings ♪
[Kiss]
♪ Once upon a December ♪
Hey!
What are you doin' in here?
- [Gasps]
- Hey!
- [Grunting]
- [Pooka Barking]
Hey!
[Growling, Barking]
Stop! Stop, stop, stop!
Hold on a minute. Hold on.
- [Panting]
Now, how did you get in here?
[Sighs]
[Sniffing, Growling]
- Excuse me, child-
- [Whispering] Vlad.
- Hmm?
- Do you see what I see?
- Hmm, no.
- [Pooka Barking]
- [Gasps] Yes! Yes!
- [Dimitri] A dog.
- Are you Dimitri?
- Cute.
Perhaps. That all depends
on who's looking for him. [Chuckles]
My name is Anya. I need travel papers.
They say you're the man to see,
even though I can't tell you who said that.
- Hmm. Hmm. - Hey, and wha...
Hey, why are you circling me?
- What, were you a vulture in another life?
- I'm sorry, "Enya."
- It's-It's  Anya.
- Anya.
- Anya. It's just that-
It's just that you look
an awful lot like- [Chucles]
Uh, never mind. Um, now, you...
said something about travel papers.
- Uh, yes. I'd like to go to Paris.
- [Vlad Laughing]
- You'd like to go to Paris?
- Mm-hmm.
- Who is this here? Oh! Oh, look!
- [Whimpering]
- Oh, he likes me!
- Nice dog. Uh-
Now, let me ask you something...
Anya, was it?
- There's a last name that goes with that?
- Well, actually...
This is gonna sound crazy.
I don't know my last name.
I was found wandering around
when I was eight years old.
And before that? Before you were eight?
I know it's strange, but I don't remember.
I have very few memories of my past.
Hm. That's perfect.
I do have one clue, however.
And that is Paris.
Paris?
Right. So, can- So,
can you two help me or not?
Hmm. Vlad, Vlad, tickets.
Huh?
Sure would like to. In fact, oddly enough,
we're going to Paris ourselves.
[Gasps] Uh, and I've got three-
Well, this one is-
But I've got three tickets here.
- Unfortunately, the third one is for her,
- Oh! Oh!
Anastasia.
- Oh.
- We are going to reunite
the Grand Duchess Anastasia
with her grandmother.
- You do kind of resemble her.
- The same blue eyes.
- The Romanov eyes.
- Nicholas' smile.
- Alexandra's chin.
- Oh, look.
She even has the grandmother's hands.
She's the same age, the same physical type.
Are you trying to tell me
you think that I am Anastasia?
I've seen thousands of girls
all over the country.
Not one of them looks as much like
the Grand Duchess as you.
- Look at the portrait.
- I knew you were crazy.
- But now I think you are both mad.
- Why?
- You don't remember what happened to you.
- No one knows what happened to her.
You're looking for family, in Paris.
And her only family is in Paris.
Have you ever thought about the possibility?
That I could be royalty?
- [Dimitri, Vlad] Mm-hmm.
- [Whimpers]
Well, it's kind of hard
to think of yourself as a duchess
- when you're sleeping on a damp floor.
- [Growling, Barks]
But, sure, every lonely girl
would hope she's a princess.
- And, somewhere, one little girl is.
- Hmm.
After all, the name "Anastasia"
means "she will rise again". [Scoffs]
Wish we could help, but the third ticket
is for the Grand Duchess Anastasia.
[Sighs] Good luck.
Why didn't you tell her
about our brilliant plan?
All she wants to do is go to Paris.
Why give away a third of the reward money?
I tell you, we're walking away too soon.
Not to worry. I got it all under control.
All right, walk a little slower.
Hmm.
- Hmm.
- [Whimpers]
Three, two, one...
- [Anya] Dimitri!
- Ah!
Right in the palm of our hand.
- Dimitri, wait!
- D-Did you call me?
If I don't remember who I am,
then who's to say I'm not
a princess or a duchess,
or whatever she is, right?
- Mm-hmm. Go on.
- Yeah, and if I'm not Anastasia,
the Empress will know right away.
- So it's just an honest mistake.
- [Dimitri] Sounds plausible.
But, if you are the princess,
then you'll finally know who you are
and have your family back.
You know- You know, he's right.
- Either way, it gets you to Paris.
- Right!
Ow!
[Groans]
[Dimitri] May I present
Her Royal Highness,
the Grand Duchess Anastasia.
- [Anastasia] Pooka, we are going to Paris.
- [Pooka Barks]
- [Dimitri] No, the dog stays. - What are
you talking about? The dog goes.
- No, the dog does not go.
- [Anastasia] I say he's going.
I'm allergic to dogs.
Anastasia?
You have just one problem there,
fellah. Anastasia's dead.
All the Romanovs are dead. They're dead.
Dead, dead, dead.
Am I right, my friend?
I mean, how could that be Ana- [Hisses]
[Screams, Whimpers]
Oh, come on.
Am I supposed to believe
that thing woke up after all these years
just because some guy
claims she's a Romanov? [Hissing]
Okay, Okay, I get the message.
Enough already with the glowing
and the smoke people.
[Signs]
If that thing's come back to life,
it must mean Anastasia's alive.
- [Dimitri] Just leave the dog.
- I am not leaving the dog.
- And that's her.
- [Vlad] We've got a train to catch.
Wow! Oh!
[Groans]
Mayday! Mayday!
Hey!
[Screaming]
Ooh! Yech!
[Groans] Ooh!
[Screams]
Ooh! Ooh!Ooh!
Hot It's hot!
[Groans]
Whoa, oh!
[Thud]
[Groans]
Oh, boy.
Ow! I tell you what... Ow!
Who dares intrude on my solitude?
Get out!
[Groans]
Bartok? Is that you?
Master? You're alive?
Yes. In a manner of speaking.
Whoa, that fell right out there, sir.
- Something's happened?
- Yeah.
- Whoopsie.
- I knew it.
I could feel the dark forces stirring.
I'm not surprised, because I saw her.
Anastasia.
Anastasia? Alive?
Uh, sir, your lips-
They're uh-
That Romanov brat!
Yeah, ain't that the kick in the head?
I guess a curse
just ain't what it used to be, huh, sir?
That's why I was stuck here in limbo.
My curse is unfulfilled.
[Groans]
[Moaning, Sobbong]
Look at me.
I am falling apart. [Sobs]
I'm a wreck!
Actually, considering how long
you've been dead,
- You look pretty good.
- Bah. [Sobbing]
- Sir, you do. You do.
- Really?
Sir, is this the face of a bat
who would lie to you?
Come on! For a minute there,
you had your old spark back.
If only I hadn't lost the gift
from the dark forces-
The key to my powers.
What? You mean this reliquary?
- [Gasps] Where did you get that?
- Oh, I found it.
- Give it to me!
- All right, all right. Don't get so grabby.
My old friend.
Together again.
[Chuckling]
Now my dark purpose will be fulfilled.
And the last of the Romanovs will die!
[Crack]
[Groans]
♪ In the dark of the night
I was tossing and turning ♪
- [Chattering] - ♪ And the nightmare
I had was as bad as can be ♪
♪ It scared me out of my wits ♪
♪ A corpse falling to bits ♪
♪ Then I opened my eyes
and the nightmare was me ♪
♪ I was once the most
mystical man in all Russia ♪
♪ When the royals betrayed me
they made a mistake ♪
♪ My curse made each of them pay ♪
♪ But one little girl got away ♪
♪ Little Anya beware, Rasputin's awake ♪
[Chorus]
♪ In the dark of the night, evil will find her ♪
♪ In the dark of the night, just before dawn ♪
[Groaning]
♪ Revenge will be sweet ♪
♪ When the curse is complete ♪
♪ - In the dark of the night
- She'll be gone! ♪
Hi, ladies. Listen, I...
♪ I can feel that my powers are slowly returning ♪
♪ Tie my sash,
add a dash of cologne for that smell ♪
[Groaning]
♪ As the pieces fall into place ♪
♪ I'll see her crawl into place ♪
♪ Do svidaniya, Anya, Your Grace ♪
♪ Farewell ♪
♪ - In the dark of the night, terror will strike her
- Terror's the least I can do! ♪
♪ In the dark of the night, evil will brew ♪
♪ Soon she will feel ♪
♪ That her nightmares are real ♪
♪ In the dark of the night ♪
♪ She'll be through! ♪
♪ In the dark of the night, evil will find her ♪
♪ Find her ♪
♪ In the dark of the night, terror comes through ♪
♪ - Doom her
- My dear, here's a sign ♪
♪ It's the end of the line ♪
♪ In the dark of the night ♪
♪ Come, my minions ♪
♪ Rise for your master ♪
♪ Let your evil shine ♪
♪ In the dark of the night ♪
♪ Find her now ♪
♪ Yes, fly ever faster ♪
♪ In the dark of the night
In the dark of the night ♪
♪ She'll be mine! ♪
[Train Chugging]
[Whistle Blows]
[Murmurs]
[Chucles]
[Clears Throat]
[Sharls]
Hmm. Oh, the mutt
gets the window seat.
[Yaps]
Stop fiddling with that. Sit up straight.
Remember, you're a grand duchess.
How do you know
what grand duchesses do or don't do?
- I make it my business to know.
- Oh.
Look, Anya, I'm just trying to help, all right?
- Hmm.
- Dimitri?
- Mm-hmm?
- Do you really think I'm royalty?
- You know I do.
- Then stop bossing me around.
She certainly has a mind of her own.
Yeah. I hate that in a woman.
[Whistle Blows]
[Clears Throat]
Look, I think we got off
on the wrong foot.
- Well, I think we did too.
- Okay.
- But I appreciate your apology.
- Apology?
Who said anything about an apology?
I was just saying that we...
Please, don't talk any more, okay?
It's only gonna upset me.
- Fine. I'll be quiet, if you will.
- All right, I'll be quiet.
- Fine.
- Think you'll miss it?
- Miss what, your talking?
No. Russia.
- Nope.
- But it was your home.
It was a place I once lived.
Then you plan on making Paris your home?
What is it with you and homes?
Well, for one thing,
it's something every normal person wants.
- For another thing, you...
- What?
- Just forget it.
- Fine.
Thank goodness it's you.
Please, remove him from my sight.
- What have you done to her?
- Me? It's her.
An unspoken attraction.
Attraction? That skinny little brat?
Have you lost your mind?
- Only asking a simple question.
- Attraction. Ridiculous.
Last month, the travelling papers were blue.
But now they are red.
Papers. Papers, please.
It's what I hate about this government.
- Everything's in red.
- Red?
I propose we move to the baggage car
before the guards come.
I propose we get off this train.
- [Barking]
- [Chittering]
[Barks]
- [Hisses]
- [Whimpers]
Hey.
Ow!
- [Groaning] - Oh, sorry.
I thought you were someone else.
Oh, it's you. Well, that's okay then.
- We've got to go.
- Where are we going?
I think you broke my nose.
[Signs]
Men are such babies.
[Yapping]
Ah! Yes. Yes. This will do nicely.
[Vlad] Ohh!
- She'll freeze in here.
- She can thaw in Paris.
- The baggage car?
- [Both Chuckling]
There wouldn't be  anything wrong with
our papers now would there, maestro?
Of course not, Your Grace.
It's just that I-
I hate to see you forced to mingle
with all those commoners.
- [Barking]
- [Chittering]
- [All Groan]
- [Dimitri] What was that?
I don't know.
But there goes the dining car.
- [Yapping]
- Get off of me.
- I'm trying.
- Ouch!
Ow!
- Uh, Dimitri.
- What?
I think someone has flambeed our engine.
Something's not right.
Wait here. I'll check it out.
[Groaning]
Anybody here?
- [Yells]
- We're going way too fast!
Nobody's driving this train.
We're gonna have to jump.
Did you say jump?
- After you.
- Fine. Then we'll uncouple the car.
[Groans]
Come on! I need a wrench, an axe, anything.
Here.
[Yapping]
[Grunding] Come on! There's gotta be
something in there better than this.
That'll work.
Go, go, go!
What did they teach you in the orphanage?
[Chittering]
The brakes are out!
Turn harder! [Groans]
Don't worry. We've got plenty of track.
We'll just coast to a stop.
- [All] Whoa!
- [Hissing]
[All Gasp]
You were saying?
I got an idea, Vlad. Gimme a hand with this.
Whoa!
Hand me the chain.
- Not you!
- Vlad's busy at the moment.
[Screeching]
No! No!
[Sharp Crack]
And to think that could have been you.
If we live through this,
remind me to thank you.
Here goes nothin'. Brace yourselves.
[Chain Clanking]
[All] Whoa!
Well, this is our stop.
[All Yelling]
[Screeching]
I hate trains.
Remind me never to get on the train again.
[Babbling]
Uh, wow.
Take it easy there. Sir, really,
you should watch your blood pressure.
My nephew, lzzie,
just keeled over one day, mid-mango.
[Muttering]
Stress- it's a killer, sir.
And he's a fruit bat.
No meat. No blood, even.
How could they let her escape?
You're right. It's very upsetting, sir.
Eh. I guess this reliquary's broken.
[Grunts]
You idiot!
[Growling]
All right now, sir.
Take it easy there. Just remember
what I said to you about stress.
- I sold my soul for this.
- [Groans]
My life- my very existence-
depends on it,
And you [Chuckles]
almost destroyed it.
I get it. I get it.
"You break it, you bought it."
See that you remember,
you miserable rodent! [Groaning]
Oh, sure. Blame the bat.
What the heck, we're easy targets.
What are you muttering about?
Anastasia, sir.
Just wishing I could do the job for you, sir.
I'd give her a "hah!"
Then a "hi-yah!"
And then a "whoo-ah!"
And I'd kick her, sir.
Oh, I have something else in mind.
Something more enticing.
Something really cruel.
[Screeching]
[Anastasia Groans]
Are we gonna walk to Paris?
[Dimitri]
We'll take a boat in Germany.
- Oh! Then we're walking to Germany?
- No, Your Grace, we're taking a bus.
A bus.
♪ [Vlad Humming] ♪
That's nice.
[Vlad] Sophie, my dear!
Vlady's on his way!
- Who's Sophie?
She's a tender little morsel.
A cup of hot chocolate
[Chuckling] Vlad-
after a long walk in the snow.
Vlad, ix-nay on the "Ophie-say."
She's a decadent pastry
filled with whipped cream and laughter.
- Is this a person or a cream puff?
- She is the Empress' ravishing first cousin.
But I thought
♪ [Scatting] ♪
we were going to see
the Empress herself.
Why are we going to see her cousin?
- Dimitri? - Well, nobody gets
near the Dowager Empress
without convincing Sophie first.
Oh, no. Not me. No.
Nobody told me I had to prove
I was the Grand Duchess.
- Look, I-
- Show up, yes. Look nice, fine.
- But lie?
- You don't know it's a lie. What if it's true?
- Hmm.
- Okay, so it's one more stop on the road
to finding out who you are.
I just thought this was something you had
to see through to the end, no mather what
Look at me, Dimitri. I am not exactly
grand duchess material here.
[Both Groan]
♪ [Humming] ♪
Tell me, child. What do you see?
I see a skinny little nobody
with no past and no future.
I see an engaging and fiery young woman,
who, on a number of occasion,
has shown a regal command
equal to any royal in the world.
And I have known my share of royalty.
You see, my dear,
I was a member of the lmperial Court.
So, are you ready to become
the Grand Duchess Anastasia?
- Hmm?
-What?
There is nothing left for you
back there, my dear.
Everything is in Paris.
Hmm.
Gentlemen, start your teaching.
I remember it well-
♪ You were born in a palace by the sea ♪
♪ A palace by the sea? ♪
- Could it be?
- Yes, that's right.
♪ You rode horseback
when you were only three. ♪
Horseback riding? Me?
♪ - And the horse
- He was white. ♪
♪ - You made faces and terrorised the cook
- Threw him in the brook ♪
♪ - Was I wild?
- Wrote the book. ♪
♪ But you'd behave
when your father gave that look ♪
♪ - Imagine how it was
- Your long-forgotten past ♪
♪ We've lots and lots to teach you
And the time is going fast ♪ [Barks]
All right. I'm ready.
♪ - Now shoulders back and stand up tall
- And do not walk, but try to float. ♪
♪ - I feel a little foolish. Am I floating?
- Like a little boat. ♪
♪ - You give a bow
- What happens now? ♪
♪ Your hand receives a kiss ♪
♪ Most of all, remember this ♪
♪ If I can learn to do it, you can learn to do it ♪
♪ - Something in you knows it
- [Together] There's nothing to it ♪
♪ Follow in my footsteps, shoe by shoe ♪
♪ You can learn to do it, too ♪
♪ - Now elbows in and sit up straight.
- And never slurp the stroganoff. ♪
♪ - I never cared for stroganoff.
- She said that like a Romanov. ♪
♪ - The samovar.
- The caviar. ♪
♪ Dessert and then good night? ♪
[Together]
♪ Not until you get this right ♪
♪ If I can learn to do it, you can learn to do it ♪
♪ Pull yourself together
[Together] and you'll pull through it ♪
♪ Tell yourself it's easy and it's true ♪
♪ You can learn to do it, too ♪
[Yells]
Next, we memorise the names of the royalty.
♪ Now here we have Kropotkin ♪
♪ - Shot Potemkin
- In the Botkin ♪
♪ And dear old Uncle Vanya loved his vodka ♪
- ♪ Got it, Anya? ♪
- No.
♪ - The Baron Pushkin ♪
- He was- Short
♪ - Count Anatoly ♪
- Had a- Wart
♪ - Count Sergei ♪
- Wore a feathered hat.
♪ I hear he's gotten very fat ♪
♪ And I recall his yellow cat ♪
♪ I don't believe we told her that ♪
[Horn Honks]
♪ If you can learn to do it, I can learn to do it ♪
♪ - Don't know how you knew it
- I simply knew it ♪
♪ Suddenly I feel like someone new ♪
[Vlad, Dimitri]
♪ Anya, you're a dream come true ♪
♪ - If I can learn to do it
- You can learn to do it ♪
♪ - You can learn to do it
- Pull yourself together ♪
♪ And you'll pull through it ♪
♪ - Tell yourself it's easy
- [All] And it's true ♪
♪ - You can learn to do it
- Nothing to it ♪
[Together]
♪ You can learn to do it, too ♪
[Foghorn Blowing]
Here. I bought you a dress.
[Giggles]
You bought me a tent.
[Whines]
- What are you lookin' for?
- The Russian Circus. I think it's still in here.
Come on. Just put it on.
[Groans]
Hmm.
Checkmate.
[Clears Throat]
Wonderful!
Marvellous!
Oh.
And now you are dressed for a ball.
And you will learn to dance for one as well.
Dimitri.
I'm- I'm not very good at it.
And-
One, two, three. One, two, three.
No, no. Anya, you don't lead.
Let him.
That, uh, dress is really beautiful.
- Do you think so?
- Yes.
I mean, it was nice on the hanger,
but it looks even better on you.
- You- You should wear it.
- I am wearing it.
Oh, right. Of course.
Of course you are.
I-I'm just trying to give you a, ih-
Compliment?
Of course. Yes.
♪ It's one, two, three and suddenly ♪
♪ I see it at a glance ♪
♪ She's radiant and confident
and born to take this chance ♪
♪ I taught her well, I planned it all ♪
♪ I just forgot romance ♪
♪ Vlad, how could you do this? ♪
♪ How will we get through this? ♪
♪ I never should have let them dance ♪
I'm feeling a little dizzy.
- Kind of light-headed?
- Yeah.
Me too.
Probably from spinning.
Maybe we should stop.
We have stopped.
- Anya, I-
- Yes?
[Pooka Growls, Barks]
You're doing fine.
- [Groaning] Are you all right?
- Fine. Fine.
Just riddled with envy. Look at him.
He can sleep through anything.
[Whining]
[Yawning]
Pretty jewellery box, isn't it?
Jewellery box?
Are you sure that's what it is?
What else could it be?
Well, something else.
Something... special.
Something to do with a secret.
[Laughs]
- Is that possible?
- Anything's possible.
- You taught Dimitri how to waltz,
didn't you? - [Laughs]
[Vlad Groans]
Sleep well, Your Majesty.
- [Bed Creaking]
- [Gasps]
[Choking]
- [Vlad Muttering]
- [Chuckles]
Sweet dreams, Pooka.
- [Gasps]
- There she is, master.
Aw. Sound asleep in her little bed.
And pleasant dreams to you,
Princess.
I'll get inside your mind,
where you can't escape me.
[Hissing]
[Yawning]
[Creaking]
- [Growls, Whimpers]
- [Door Closes]
[Thunderclap]
[Yapping]
[Whimpering, Barking]
[Groans]
[Thunder Rumbling]
Come on.
[Giggling]
[Chattering, Giggling]
[Squeals]
- [Giggles]
- [Thunerclap]
[Barking]
What? What, what,
what, what?
Pooka. Pooka, what?
[Barking]
[Thunderclap] Anya! Anya!
[Yapping]
[Groans]
Anya!
[Barking]
[Thunderclap]
Hello, sunshine.
Hello!
Jump in. Jump!
- Yeah!
- [Girls Squeal]
- [Thunderclap]
- [Groans]
Anya!
Anya! Stop!
Anya, no!
Yes, jump!
The Romanov curse!
- [Deep Voice] Jump!
- [Screams]
- Jump!
- [Screamong]
[Screamong]
[Groaning]
[Groans]
No.
Anya! Anya, Anya.
Wake up.
Wake up!
[Gasps]
[Panting]
- The Romanov curse.
- The Romanov what?
- Curse.
- What are you talking about?
I keep seeing faces-
So many faces.
- It was a nightmare.
- [Whimpers]
It's all right. You're safe now.
- [Thunderclap]
- No!
[Screaming]
Easy, master. Wow.
- [Creatures Twittering]
- This is no time to lose your head.
[Panting] You're right. [Groans]
I am calm. [Sighs]
I am... heartless.
I have no feelings whatsoever.
Sir?
I feel a sudden onset of clarity, Bartok.
I'll have to kill her myself in person.
- What, you mean... physically?
- You know what they say-
If you want something done right-
[Shrieking]
[Bartok] But that means going topside.
Exactly.
I have so many fond memories of Paris,
[Squeaking]
And killing the last of the Romanovs
with my own hands
- will be so delicious.
- [Squealing]
- [Groans]
- Well. Time to go.
- But you're dead. You're falling apart, sir.
How do you expect to get to Paris
in one piece?
I thought we'd take the train.
[Creatures Squealing]
Whoa!
[Woman] Mm. Ah, yes.
I remember so well.
Uncle Yashin was from Moscow.
Uncle Boris was from Odessa.
- And every spring...
- We'd take picnics by the shore on Sunday.
Haven't you anything better to do?
Oh, dear. You have to leave now. Yes.
[Sobbing]
Good-bye. [Sighs]
No more. No more.
Ah. Oh, I must say, I'm so sorry.
I thought that one surely was real.
Well, she was real. I mean, she was
human, of course, but not our real.
But we won't be fooled next time.
- No, I am going to think of really
hard questions. - [Meows]
No.
My heart can't take it any more.
I will see no more girls
claiming to be Anastasia.
[Dimitri] Where is Uncle Boris from?
[Anastasia]
What if Sophie doesn't recognise me?
She will. You're Anastasia.
It's just that-
- What?
Well, three days ago
I didn't have any past at all,
and now I'm trying to remember
an entire lifetime.
That's why you got me.
Now, where was Uncle Boris from?
Moscow?
Oui, monsieur?
[Gasps]
Oh!
[Squeals]
Sophie Stanislovskievna Somorkov-Smirnoff!
Vladimir Vanya Voinitsky Vasilovich!
Well, this is unexpected.
Oh, but look at me.
Where are my manners? [Barks]
Come in!
Come in, everyone. [Laughing]
[Pooka Barks]
I am palpitating with amazement
and shock and surprise-
[Barks]
All three.
[Vlad] May I present
Her lmperial Highness,
the Grand Duchess
Anastasia Nikolayevna.
Oh, my heavens!
She certainly does look like Anastasia.
But so did many of the others.
- Where were you born?
- [Anastasia] At the Peterhoff Palace.
Correct.
And how does Anastasia like her tea?
I don't like tea. Just hot water and lemon.
Good.
[Whining] Finally, you'll most likely
find this an impertinent question,
but indulge me.
How did you escape
during the siege of the palace?
There was a boy-
A boy who worked in the palace.
He opened a wall.
[Anastasia Chuckling]
I'm sorry. That's crazy.
Walls opening.
[Vlad] So, is she a Romanov?
Oh, well, she answered every question.
You hear that, child? You did it!
[Laughing]
- So, when do we go and see the Empress?
- I'm afraid you don't.
Oh? Come again, my pet.
The Empress simply won't allow it.
Now, Sophie, my bright diamond,
[Whispering]
surely you can think of some way
to arrange
a brief interview with the Dowager?
I refuse to budge until an
answer occurs to you. [Gigling]
Please.
Do you like the Russian Ballet?
I believe they're performing
in Paris tonight.
The Dowager Empress and I
love the Russian Ballet.
We never miss it.
We... did it!
We're going to see
the lmperial Highness tonight.
[Groans]
We're going to get the 10 million roubles.
- We're going to be- [Laughing]
- But. Vlad- Vlad.
- Vlad, she is the princess.
- Anya was extraordinary!
I almost believed her. And Sophie...
- [Vlad Laughs] - Sophie wants
to take us shopping for the ballet.
Shopping in Paris. Can you believe it?
♪ Lovers! ♪
♪ Ooh, la-la! ♪
[Laughing]
♪ Welcome, my friends, to Paree ♪
♪ Here, have a flower on me ♪
♪ Forget where you're from ♪
♪ You're in France - children, come ♪
♪ I'll show you that French joie de vivre ♪
♪ Paree holds the key to your heart ♪
♪ And all of Paree plays a part ♪
- Bonjour!
♪ - You'll stroll two-by-two
- Down what we call La Rue ♪
♪ And soon all Paree will be singing to you ♪
- Whoo!
- [Tohether] ♪ Ooh, la-la! ♪
♪ Ooh, la-la! Ooh, la-laaa! ♪
♪ Paree holds the key to I'amour ♪
[With German Accent]
♪ And not even Freud knows the cure ♪
♪ - There's love in the air
- And "zee" Folies Bergère ♪
♪ The French have it down to an art ♪
♪ Paree holds the key to your heart ♪
[Together] ♪ Ooh, la-la! ♪
♪ When you're feeling blue, come to Le Moulin ♪
♪ When your heart says "don't"
the French say "do" ♪
[Together] ♪ When you think you can't,
you'll find you cancan ♪
♪ Everyone can cancan ♪
♪ You can cancan, too ♪
[Women] Whee!
[Stammering]
- [Laughing]
- [Women] Whee! Whee!
- Whee!
- [Aplause]
♪ Paree holds the key to her past ♪
♪ Yes, Princess, I've found you at last ♪
♪ No more pretend ♪
♪ You'll be gone, that's the end ♪
[Cheers, Aplause]
♪ Paree holds the key to your heart ♪
♪ You'll be très jolie and so smart ♪
♪ - Come dance through the night
- And forget all your woes ♪
♪ - The city of light
- Where a rose is a rose ♪
♪ And one never knows what will start ♪
♪ Paree holds the key ♪
♪ To her ♪
[All]
♪ Heart ♪
♪ Ooh, la-la! Ooh, la-la! ♪
[Horns Honking]
We don't have anything to be nervous about.
- She's the princess.
- I know. I know. But...
No. No, you don't know.
I was the boy in the palace.
The one who opened the wall.
[Whispering]
She's the real thing, Vlad.
That means our Anya has found her family.
We have found the heir to the Russian throne.
- And you...
- Will walk out of her life for ever.
- But...
- Princesses don't marry kitchen boys.
I know, but...
We're going to go through with this
as if nothing has changed.
You've got to tell her.
[Anastasia] Tell me what?
Uh-How-
How beautiful you look.
Well, thank you.
Mm-mmm.
Ah, Sophie.
Monsieur.
♪ [Orchestra Tuning Up] ♪
[Conductor Taps Baton]
[Whispering]
Look. There she is.
♪ [Orchestra Plays Fanfare] ♪
Please, let her remember me.
♪ [Orchestra] ♪
♪ [Continues] ♪
[Shoring]
Everything's gonna be fine.
- ♪ [Ends] ♪
- [Aplause]
Come on. I guess it's time.
Relax. You're gonna be great.
- Oh.
- Hey! Hey, hey,hey.
Deep breath. Everything's gonna be fine.
Wait here forjust a moment.
I'll go in and announce you properly.
- Dimitri...
- Yes?
Look, we've been through a lot together.
Uh-huh.
- And I just wanted to...
- Yes?
Well-
Thank you, I guess.
Yes. Thank you, for everything.
- Anya, I...
- Yes?
- I'm-. I, uh-
I wanted to wish you
good luck, I guess.
- Oh.
- Uh-
Good luck.
Well, here goes.
Please inform Her Majesty,
the Dowager Empress,
- [Giggles]
- that I have found her granddaughter,
the Grand Duchess Anastasia.
She's waiting to see herjust outside.
I'm very sorry, young man,
but the Dowager Empress,
she will see no one.
Tell that impertinent young man
that I have seen enough
Grand Duchess Anastasias
to last me a lifetime.
- You'd better go.
- Please, let me just...
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I wish to live out the remainder
of my lonely life in peace.
Oh. I'll see you to the door.
Come, come now. Come to the door.
[Laughs]
Your Majesty, I intend you no harm.
My name is Dimitri.
I used to work at the palace.
Well, that's one I haven't heard, I must say.
Wait. Don't go. Please.
If you'll just hear me out...
I know what you're after. I've seen it before.
Men who train young women
in the royal ways.
- But if Your Highness will just listen...
- Haven't you been listening?
I've had enough.
I don't care how much
you have fashioned
this girl to look like her,
sound like her or act like her.
In the end, it never is her.
- This time it is her.
- Dimitri. I've heard of you.
You're that con man
from Saint Petersburg
- who was holding auditions to find
an Anastasia lookalike. - [Gasps]
But we've come all the way from Russia...
And others have come from Timbuktu.
No. It's not what you think.
How much pain will you inflict on an
old woman for money?
Remove him at once.
But she is Anastasia. I'm telling you.
She's the Grand Duchess.
If you'll only speak to her, you'll see.
- [Groans]
- [Door Slams]
- It was all a lie, wasn't it?
- No. No.
You used me?
I was just part of your con to get her money?
No. No, no, no.
It started out that way,
but everything's different now,
because you really are Anastasia.
- You are.
- Look, stop it!
From the very beginning, you lied!
- And I not only believed you, I actually-
- [Groans]
Anya, please!
When you spoke of the hidden door
of the wall opening and the boy-
- Listen to me. That was-
- No!
I don't want to hear about anything
that I said or remembered.
You just leave me alone!
Anya, please!
You have to know the truth!
Your Majesty.
- [Engine Starts]
- [Chauffeur Speaking Russian]
Ilya, slow down.
I'm not llya.
And I won't slow down-
- Not until you listen.
- [Gasps] You!
How dare you? Stop this car immediately.
Stop this car!
[Tires Squealing]
[Horn Honks]
You have to talk to her.
Just look at her. Please.
I won't be badgered by you a moment longer.
Do you recognise this?
[Gasps]
Where did you get this?
I know you've been hurt,
but it's just possible
she's been as lost and alone as you.
You'll stop at nothing, will you?
I'm probably about as stubborn as you are.
[Knocking]
Go away, Dimitri.
[Gasps] Oh.
I'm sorry.
I-I thought you were-
I know very well
who you thought I was.
Who exactly are you?
I was hoping you could tell me.
My dear, I'm old,
and I'm tired
of being conned and tricked.
I don't want to trick you.
And I suppose the money
doesn't interest you, either?
I just want to know who I am-
whether or not I belong to a family.
Your family.
You're a very good actress.
The best yet, in fact-
but... I've had enough.
- Peppermint?
- An oil for my hands.
Yes. Yeah.
And I spilled a bottle.
The carpet was soaked
and it forever smelled of peppermint.
Like you.
I used to lie there on that rug,
and how I missed you when you
went away.
When you came here, to Paris.
- What is that?
- This?
Well, I've always had it,
ever since before I can remember.
May I?
It was our secret.
My Anastasia's and mine.
[Gasps] The music box.
To- To sing me to sleep
when you were in Paris.
♪ Hear this song and remember ♪
[Together]
♪ Soon you'll be ♪
♪ Home with me ♪
♪ Once upon a December ♪
Oh, Anastasia!
My Anastasia.
- Oh!
[Kiss]
[Thunderclap]
[rasputin] Bartok, get me a comb.
Find some cologne. I want to look my best.
[Bartok] That might take some work, sir.
Then snap to it.
We're going to a party.
- A party in Paris?
- That's right.
Ooh, I could teach you
the latest dance step.
It starts with like a whoo,
and then you get really crazy
with the hips, sir.
It's fun.
We'll let the Grand Duchess Anastasia
have her moment.
- Who cares?
- And then we'll kill her.
Right. And then we'll-
Kill her?
Sir, what happened
to the party idea?
That's where we'll kill her. [Laughs]
Crush her at the height of her glory.
And we're back with the crushing.
Sir, I'm begging you. Please.
Please, forget the girl and get a life.
Oh, I'll get a life, Bartok.
Hers! [Thunderclap]
- [Laughing]
- [Thunderclap]
[Laughing]
I remember now how much I loved them.
They would not want us
to live in the past-
not now that we have
found each other.
- Hmm.
- Oh, look here.
The drawing you gave me.
Remember?
- [Gigles] Yes.
Olga made me so mad.
- She said it looked like
a pig riding a donkey. - [Laughs]
- She was right.
- In your laughter,
once again I hear my Nicky, your dear father.
[Gasps]
But you have the beauty of your mother,
Alexandra,
Empress of all Russia.
[No Audioble Diologue]
You sent for me, Your Grace?
10 million roubles, as promised,
with my gratitude.
I accept your gratitude, Your Highness.
ih, but I- I don't want the money.
What do you want, then?
Unfortunately, nothing you can give.
Young man,
where did you get that music box?
You were the boy, weren't you?
The servant boy who got us out.
You saved her life, and mine,
then you restored her to me.
Yet you want no reward?
Not any more.
Why the change of mind?
It was more a change of heart.
I must go.
Hello, Dimitri.
- Hello.
- Did you collect your reward?
My business is complete.
Uh, young man, you will bow
and address
the Princess as "Your Highness".
- No, that's not necessary.
- Please...
Your Highness. I'm glad you found
what you were looking for.
Yes, I'm glad you did, too.
Well, then. Good-bye, Your Highness.
Good-bye.
♪ [Scatting] ♪
[Whines]
[Growling]
- You look fabulous!
- [Barks]
Oh.
Do you mind? No, of course not.
You're a wonderful dog.
[Clears Throat]
Well, if you're ever in St Petersburg again,
look me up.
So long, Vlad.
Ah, my boy...
- You're making a mistake.
- Trust me-
This is the one thing I'm doing right.
[Whining]
So long, mutt.
I can't stay. I don't belong here.
[Whines]
♪ [Waltz] ♪
- He's not there.
- Oh, I know he's not- He-
- Who's not there, Grandmamma?
- A remarkable young man
who found a music box.
Well, he's probably too busy spending
his reward money as fast as he can.
Look at them dance.
You were born into this world
of glittering jewels and fine titles.
But I wonder if this is what you really want.
Of course. Of course it is.
I found what I was looking for.
I found out who I am.
I found you.
Yes, you did find me-
and you'll always have me.
But is it enough?
My darling,
- he didn't take the money.
- He didn't?
Knowing that you are alive,
seeing the woman you have become,
brings me joy I never thought
I could feel again.
[Kiss]
Whatever you choose,
we will always have each other.
Grandmamma, can't you tell me the-
[Pooka Barking]
- Pooka?
- [Barking]
- [Barking Continues]
- Pooka?
[Barking Continues]
Pooka.
[Train Whistle Blows]
[Chattering]
- Voila.
- Merci.
You're next.
[Gasps]
[Pooka Barking]
Pooka? Here boy.
- [Barking]
- [Gasps]
[Whining] There you are.
[Rasputin] Anastasia.
[Gasps]
[Growls]
Anastasia...
[Screams]
Anastasia.
[Growling]
Your lmperial Highness.
Look what ten years has done to us.
You, a beautiful young flower.
And me...
- A rotting corpse.
- That face.
Last seen at a party like this one.
- A curse.
- Followed by a tragic night on the ice.
Remember?
[Shouting]
- Rasputin!
- [Mimicking] Rasputin. [Laughs]
Destroyed by your despicable family!
But what goes around comes around
- And around and around and around
and around! - Stop!
- [Anastasia] Oh, no, stop it!
- You're on your own, sir.
This can only end in tears.
[Groans]
- I'm not afraid of you.
- I can fix that!
Care for a little swim under the ice?
Say your prayers, Anastasia!
[Screams]
- No one can save you!
- Wanna bet?
[Groans]
Dimitri...
- If we survive, remind me to thank you.
- Thank me later.
How enchanting.
Together again - for the last time!
- [Yells]
- [Rasputin] You'll get a kick out of this.
- No!
- Whoa!
[Roaring]
[Grunts] Whoa!
- Dimitri!
- [Yelling]
Watch out!
Do svidaniya, Your Highness.
Yeah!
Aah!
[Laughing]
Hold on!
Finally, the last Romanov death.
- [Laughs, Groans]
- [Growing]
[Screams]
[Snarling]
- [Laughs]
- No!
Anya!
[Screeching]
[Yelling]
Long live the Romanovs!
[Laughing]
[Anastasia] Right.
I couldn't have said it better myself.
[Groans]
[Pooka Barking]
[Gasps]
- [Shouts]
- [Growling]
Huh?
[Groans]
[Gasps] This is for Dimitri.
- Give it back.
- This is for my family.
- I'll tear you to pieces.
- And this is for you.
Do svidaniya.
[Groans]
[Screaming]
Oh, no.
[Whining]
Dimitri?
Oh. [Howls]
[Groans]
[Gasps]
- Ouch!
- Dimitri!
[Groaning] Let go. Let go.
- Sorry.
- Yeah. I know. I know.
All men are babies.
[Groans]
- I thought you were going to St Peters...
- I was.
- You didn't take the...
- I couldn't.
- Why?
- Because...
I...
[Pooka Barks]
They're waiting for you.
[Anastasia's Voice]
Dear Grandmamma, wish me luck.
We'll be together in Paris again soon.
A bientot.
They've eloped.
Isn't it romantic?
It's a perfect ending.
No. It's a perfect beginning.
♪ [Dance] ♪
♪ [Chorus Vocalizing] ♪
Oh!
[Laughs]
- Mm-mmm.
- Uh, hello. How-
[Laughing]
Mwah!
Wow!
I tell you what... Wow!
Ooh, It's-
Ooh, it, uh-
So long, everybody. [Laughs]
♪ We were strangers, ♪
♪ starting out on a journey ♪
♪ Never dreaming
what we'd have to go through ♪
♪ Now here we are,
and I'm suddenly standing, ♪
♪ at the beginning with you ♪
♪ No one told me
I was going to find you, ♪
♪ Unexpected
what you did to my heart, ♪
♪ When I had lost hope
you were there to remind me ♪
♪ This is the start ♪
♪ And life is a road
and I wanna to keep going ♪
♪ Love is a river
I wanna keep flowing ♪
♪ Life is a road
now and forever ♪
♪ wonderful journey ♪
♪ I'll be there when the world stops turning ♪
♪ I'll be there when the storm is through ♪
♪ In the end I wanna be standing ♪
♪ at the beginning with you ♪
♪ I knew there was somebody somewhere ♪
♪ like me alone in the dark ♪
♪ Now I know my dream will live on ♪
♪ I've been waiting so long ♪
♪ Nothing's gonna tear us apart ♪
♪ And life is a road
and I wanna to keep going ♪
♪ Love is a river
I wanna keep flowing ♪
♪ Life is a road
now and forever ♪
♪ wonderful journey ♪
♪ I'll be there when the world stops turning ♪
♪ I'll be there when the storm is through ♪
♪ In the end I wanna be standing ♪
♪ at the beginning ♪
♪ with you ♪
[Woman]
♪ Heart, don't fail me now ♪
♪ Courage, don't desert me ♪
♪ Don't turn back
now that we're here ♪
♪ People always say ♪
♪ Life is full of choices ♪
♪ No one ever mentions fear ♪
♪ Or how a road
can seem so long ♪
♪ How the world
can seem so vast ♪
♪ Courage, see me trough ♪
♪ Heart, I'm trusting you ♪
♪ On this journey ♪
♪ To the past ♪
♪ Home, love, family ♪
♪ There was once a time
I must've had them too ♪
♪ Home, love, family ♪
♪ I will never be complete
until I find you ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ One step at a time ♪
♪ One hope, then another ♪
♪ Who knows where
this road may go, oh ♪
♪ Back to who I was ♪
♪ On to find my future ♪
♪ Things my heart
still needs to know ♪
♪ Courage, see me through ♪
♪ Heart, I'm trusting you ♪
♪ To bring me home ♪
♪ At last ♪
♪ Hoo ♪
[Chorus]
♪ Courage, see me through ♪
♪ Heart, I'm trusting you ♪
♪ Hey, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Trust
Hey, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Hey, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Trust
Hey, yeah, yeah ♪
[Woman]
♪ Dancing bears ♪
♪ Painted wings ♪
♪ Things I almost remember ♪
♪ And a song ♪
♪ Someone sings ♪
♪ Once upon a December ♪
♪ Far away ♪
♪ Long ago ♪
♪ Glowing dim as an ember ♪
♪ Things my heart ♪
♪ Used to know ♪
♪ Once upon a December ♪
[Guitar Solo]
♪ Someone holds me ♪
♪ Safe and warm ♪
♪ Horses prance ♪
♪ Through a silver storm ♪
♪ Figures dancing ♪
♪ Gracefully ♪
♪ Across my memory ♪
♪ Far away ♪
♪ Long ago ♪
♪ Glowing dim as an ember ♪
♪ Things my heart ♪
♪ Used to know ♪
♪ Things it yearns to remember ♪
♪ And a song ♪
♪ Someone sings ♪
♪ Once upon ♪
♪ A December ♪