[music] [ Music Box: Waltz ]
[music] [ Orchestra: Overture,
Cole Porter Medley ]
[ Horns Honking In Distance ]
[ Ticking ]
[ Vehicles Passing ]
[music] [ Ends ]
[ Applause ]
[ Woman Scoffs ] Gentleman.
Some gentleman.
[ Man ] I wouldn't talk if I were you.
That's one thing I am not, thank God.
What?
You.
You, you big weasel. I'm not you.
Thank you. You have
such a way with words.
Don't.
What?
Touch the lights.
Oh, yes, I keep forgetting.
You love dark rooms.
Yeah?
Like a bat.
I'd rather be a bat than a duck.
Hmm. Thought I was a weasel.
You are a weasel and a duck.
Rather intriguing combination, I'd say.
What?
Never mind. You're too drunk
to follow anything intricate.
Oh, yeah? Where are you going?
Home.
To mother.
On the next train.
Oh, that's sweet.
All I do is just take a few drinks
to unwind from the show...
Unravel, you mean.
Come again.
No, I don't believe I will actually.
I'm rather bored with the whole thing.
You're bored.
Good night.
Why do you think I drink?
Good-bye.
Oh, what an exit.
Theatricality, my dear,
is your department.
Oh, wait a minute.
I gotta write that down someplace.
[ Murmurs ]
"Theatricality, my dear,
is your department."
Very clever.
Clever.
[ Glass Shatters ]
[music] With a million neon rainbows
burning below me [music]
[music] And a million blazing taxis
raising a roar;
[music] Here I... [ Off-key ] am [music]
[music] Above the town [music]
[music] In my pet
pailletted gown [music]
[music] Down in the depths [music]
[music] On the 90th floor [music]
Mmm!
[music] While the crowds at El Morocco
punish the parquet;
[music] And at 21, the couples
clamor for more [music]
More! More! More!
[music] I'm deserted
and depressed [music]
[music] In my regal eagle nest;
[music] Down in the depths [music]
[music] On the 90th floor [music]
[music] When the one
you thought you wanted [music]
[music] Wants ms mother [music]
[music] What's the use of swank
and cash in the bank galore? [music]
[music] Why, even the
janitor's wife [music]
[music] Has a perfectly
good love life [music]
[music] And here am I;
[music] Facing tomorrow [music]
[music] Alone in my sorrow [music]
[music] Down in the depths [music]
[music] On the 90th floor [music]
Oh, God.
[ Chiming Hour ]
[ Man ] All right. I'll
see you and raise you 40.
[ Man 2 ] That's too damn rich for me. I'm
out. [ Man 3 ] Aw, Willie, you're no sport.
[ Man 4 ] I'll see that.
And you're a sap.
So am I, I guess.
I'm in.
Now it's up to me. That's right,
Johnny boy. Cost you 40 to stay in.
I don't know. Don't tell
us you're shy suddenly.
Don't be a sore loser, Willie.
It's unbecoming.
I don't see what you're
so cheerful about. Shh!
This guy's a one-man crash.
Shush yourself.
I bet.
Yeah, you always do.
All right, here they are.
Tens and kings.
Two pair, ace high.
I could've beat that.
Yeah, so can I.
Three boys and two little girls.
Didn't I tell you I was a sap?
What do you got?
None of your business.
Well, Mr. Spanish?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Uh-oh. Here it comes.
Okay, save the apologies.
Let's see what you have.
Now don't be a sore loser.
Two of these.
My girls.
And three of these.
- [ Others Muttering ]
- My goodness.
I'm sorry.
I love this guy.
I think we'd better quit-
He's been sorry all night.
Before my wife wakes up
and shoots me.
I'm tired of being a masochist.
Gentlemen.
Hey, I know what you mean. Gentlemen, when my heart
is sick, I've got a remedy that does the trick.
You win.
[ All Laugh ]
No. Gentlemen.
Gentlemen.
Whenever you are blue,
I advise you to try my remedy too.
Just say...
[music] Tomorrow [music]
[music] Your trouble will be done
tomorrow [music]
[music] Your victory will be won
[music] We're all gonna have fun
'cause there ain't gonna be no sorrow;
[music] Tomorrow [music]
That's right. We won't
be playing you tomorrow.
[music] Yes, yes, tomorrow [music]
[music] It's all gonna be grand
tomorrow [music]
[music] You'll start leading the band
[music] We'll live in a new land [music]
I say this to myself in Venice,
and here I am.
You should've stayed in Venice.
See ya, Murray.
[music] Because there [music]
[music] Ain't gonna be no sorrow
tomorrow [music]
Ciao.
Ciao yourself.
[ Murmuring ]
[ Reading, indistinct ]
- Still low, Harry?
- [ Mutters ]
[music] Nobody wild about Harry? [music]
Ooh, ooh, ooh!
Ooh, domani.
Eh, domani.
[music] You're sure gonna meet [music]
[music] The one you'll adore [music]
God forbid.
I got enough troubles as it is.
[music] Your heart gonna beat
as never before [music]
It'll stop.
[music] No, it's all
gonna change [music]
[music] From darkness to dawn [music]
Mmm, Barney Google here.
[music] Ah! Why do you squeal
and feel so darn bitter? [music]
[music] You'll score
like a Yankee hitter;
The Dodgers are winning.
[ Mutters ] [ Scoffs ]
[music] Tomorrow,
the season will be spring [music]
the birds will all sing [music]
[music] Tomorrow,
Signor Cupid will be king [music]
[music] So there ain't
gonna be no sorrow [music]
[music] Tomorrow [music]
[ Sighs ]
No. Why borrow even
a small cup of sorrow?
Instead, get in your head,
mio caro.
[music] That there ain't gonna be
no sorrow tomorrow [music]
[music] No, no, there ain't gonna be
no sorrow [music]
[music] For you and me [music]
[music] Tomorrow [music]
Aah!
[ Woman ] What did you say? [ Man
] Quarter to 6:00, Miss Carter.
A quarter of 6:00?
In the morning.
It's still dark out.
Yes, ma'am, but it's lightenin' up.
I think you should
have your watch fixed.
I will, ma'am,
just as soon as I get one.
Good mornin'- I mean,
good night, Miss Carter.
Good night.
Quarter of 6:00.
Better not be quarter of 6:00.
I told that goon to get me back by
- Oh!
[ Sighs ]
These are going back.
I told Beth they pinch.
It's like wearing two vises.
Vise? Two vise.
So, where did she put that thing?
[ Keys Jangling ]
[ Doorbell Buzzing ]
Oh, no.
[ Sighs ]
It is quarter of 6:00.
I wonder,
which is the right life?
The simple or the nightlife?
[music] When, pray, should one rise?
[music]
[music] At sunset or at sunrise? [music]
[music] Which should be upper;
[music] My breakfast or my supper?
[music]
[music] Which is the right life? [music]
[music] Which? [music]
What?
No. "Which."
[music] If the wood nymph left the park,
would Park Avenue excite her? [music]
[music] Would the glowworm trade her spark
for the latest Dunhill lighter? [music]
[music] Here's a question
I would pose [music]
[music] Tell me which
the sweeter smell makes [music]
[music] The aroma of the rose [music]
[music] Or the perfume
that Chanel makes? [music]
Or this letter the hotel sent?
[music] Oh [music]
[music] Which is the right life? [music]
[music] The simple or the nightlife?
[music]
I don't know.
[ Water Splashing ]
This says
we are being thrown out,
so somethin' is wrong.
[music] When, pray, should one rise?
[music]
[music] At sunset or at sunrise? [music]
Well, when you figure it out,
call me, huh?
[music] Which should be the upper;
[music] My breakfast or my supper?
[music]
[music] Which is the right life? [music]
[ Yawns ]
[music] Which-[music]
[ Gasps ]
Beth!
What time is it, Rodney?
6:00, sir.
6300?
6300.
Hmm.
I'm sick of 6:00.
Sir?
Why isn't it 7:00
or even 8:00?
Well, it was just 5:00
recently, sir,
and 6:00 does precede 7:00
and 8:00.
I'm sure there's a logic
to that somewhere,
but it's just too tiring
to think about.
Yes, sir.
[music] After hunting all over
for pleasure [music]
[music] With some measure
of success [music]
Are you singing to me, sir? No.
I was just singing to myself.
Yes, sir. Go right ahead, sir.
[music] I've decided the pace
known as rapid [music]
[music] Leads to vapid
nothingness [music]
[music] And Fm;
[music] Tired of betting, tired of sporting,
tired of flirting, tired of courting [music]
[music] Tired of racing, tired of
yachting, tired of loafing [music]
[music] Tired of rotting [music]
[ Sharp Inhale ]
[music] Tired of dining, tired of wining
Tired of tea-ing [music]
[music] Tired of being tired [music]
[music] fired, '(wed [music]
[music] Oh [music]
[music] Won't somebody care [music]
[music] For a poor young millionaire?
[music]
Mr. Pritchard.
Don't stop, Rod.
I just need a little air.
Sir, wouldn't the window suffice?
Please don't slow down.
If you knew what blues meant,
you'd find me amusement.
Well, I've tried.
I've tried.
Step on it, Rod.
God knows I've tried.
[music] I've had every thrill [music]
[music] From a Rolls-Royce
to a Ford [music]
[music] And there's no concealing
the fact I'm feeling [music]
[music] Bored, bored [music]
[music] Bored [music]
Haven't seen you in a long time.
Such a child.
What a lovely little tie.
Is it a boy or girl?
A girl? You should dress
her differently. Harold.
Yeah. Such a doll.
Look at her eyes.
Yeah, a little doll.
Harold.
Give me the children.
Harold! Oh.
Oh, Harold, turn that off.
Oh, would that I could, ma'am.
Oh, it's the sun.
The sun it is.
Give me the sun, Mother.
Aren't we looking pretty today?
Thank you.
I need a refill and a cab.
Ah, some refreshment
and a conveyance. Yes.
You're in my way.
You wanna get killed?
Ooh, there's one. Taxi.
You're sure you wouldn't like
to get back in now, sir?
Oh, I think I look
rather striking out here.
What?
Striking.
Yes, I know, but-What? Uh-oh.
Taxi!
[ Tires Screeching ]
Gracious, you're heavy.
I'm awfully sorry.
What the hell were you doing,
anyway, hanging onto that taxi?
Are you all right, Miss O'Kelly?
Oh, it sobered me up anyhow.
Mr. Pritchard, are you hurt?
No. I landed on something soft.
Hmm. I like you. Thank you. Would
you like to have a drink on that?
Sir, I'm afraid the car isn't so fit.
Oh, really?
[ Coughing ]
What's the matter?
I don't smoke.
She doesn't smoke.
I knew that.
Now, who's this?
Rodney James.
He used to drive for me.
Very funny.
Hello, Rodney.
A pleasure.
He's very formal.
Yes. He tries to compensate for me.
What's your name?
Kitty O'Kelly.
I don't believe that.
Well, I know what you mean.
But the real one's
Kathy Krumm with a "K."
How would that look in lights?
[ Together ]
Crummy with a
[ Both Laughing ]
What would you be doing
in lights anyway?
I'm a singer.
Oh.
What do you do?
Nothing. I'm an heir.
What?
Well, that's not a taxi.
Nope.
That's your car.
Yep.
Look what I did to it. That's all right.
I got a couple of others.
You do?
Mm-hmm.
What kind? Just like this one.
I can't tell 'em apart.
I like you more and more.
Thank you.
Is that why you call this one
MOP III?
No, actually, that's me.
You're the third MOP?
Yeah.
You ever get bored?
Never.
Rodney.
Sir!
[ Clears Throat ]
Call a cab.
[music] [ Bugle On P.A.: Call To Post ]
Excuse us.
Hurry up! It's starting.
I hope we miss it.
Oh, will you stop badgering me?
I'm not badgering you.
We're lost.
I'm making sense.
Oh, where do we Beth, bet?
What'd you have in mind, honey?
[ Together ] "Beth, bet"? What?
Beat it, Morris.
You ain't cute.
Oh, yeah? Well, dames don't belong
down here no way. Come, snooks.
Aw, go suck an egg.
I can't see a thing.
I wish you'd wear your glasses.
Where are we going?
Straight ahead.
Oh!
Bettin' our last $300 is no way to
make ends meet. I always win at games.
They probably won't take our bet anyway.
They'd better.
They don't know us. Unless you'd
rather sleep in the park tonight.
They have to know you.
That's ridiculous.
[ Track Announcer On P.A. ]
The horses are approaching the gate.
Stand here.
Is this the line?
You don't know nothin' about betting
or racing-Oh, stop crabbing!
Crab, crab, crab.
I'm not crabbing.
Tell them to hurry up.
No.
Hmm!
[ Gruffly ] Yes?
Yes.
[ Giggles ]
I'm in an awful hurry.
May I get ahead of you?
For you, anything.
Thank you.
Except this.
Except what?
Yes? I'm betting
also on this race.
I don't like to miss my chance.
I have lucky feeling today.
You're Italian. Mmm.
Venetian.
Every Italian I've ever met is rude,
inconsiderate and selfish. Brooke.
Perhaps because they are not
used to women who are spoiled.
Yeah, in Italy, we don't have.
Elizabeth, call the police.
They don't come around where there's
betting, honey. It ain't legal.
[ Man ] Hey, Spanish. They're
at the gate. What'll it be?
1,000. Ladies' Day to win.
I hope you lose.
Spanish. 1,000.
Grazie. Ciao.
[ Track Announcer ] The flag is up.
What did he say?
What are you girls doing here?
We were drawn by your magnetism.
Uh-huh. Now don't be rude
to the man, Elizabeth.
Which one, sir, do you think will win?
I ain't a seer, lady.
What? He says he ain't a seer.
And he certainly ain't no "sir."
Mmm, tough cookie, huh?
You wanna start somethin'?
How about Cot-ton Ball?
Cotton Ball. That's a nice name.
Pays 20-to-1.
I'll take it.
Put that away. You want
to get us all locked up?
It's real.
Put that away!
Look. $300.
No cash. No cash.
Look, kid, I can't take your bet nohow.
I don't know ya.
I'm Brooke Carter. Oh, nice to meet ya.
So long.
Beth.
[ Groans ]
You better take her bet, wise guy,
if you know what's good for you.
Yeah?
Yeah.
This is... Sleep Out Louie's dame.
Carter?
That's right.
Carter. 300. Cotton Ball.
You wanna put it on his nose?
Yeah, yeah.
What?
Are you sure you don't
wanna try Ladies' Day, honey?
Valentino looked awful positive.
You mean positively awful.
[ Bell Rings ]
That's it, girls.
[ Track Announcer ]
They're off and running!
Who is Sleep Out Louie?
Beats me.
- At the start, it's Chuck-a-luck. Blue Boy in second.
- [ Shouting, Cheering ]
Jumper is third.
Ladies' Day is drawing up.
Pumpkin Pie and Texas Moon.
It's Chuck-a-luck with the lead.
Blue Boy moving up to second.
They're going into the first turn.
It's Chuck-a-luck in front by a length.
Blue Boy is second.
Jumper is third.
Ladies' Day moving up to fourth.
Pumpkin Pie, Texas Moon
and, at the rear, it's Cotton Ball.
[ Mimicking ] Oh, that Cotton Ball.
That's a nice name.
You bet on Cotton Ball?
We certain-We certainly did,
and he's going to win.
[ Mocking Laugh ]
Chuck-a-luck in front by two lengths.
Blue Boy is second.
And Ladies' Day is now
moving up fast on the inside.
Pumpkin Pie, and here comes Cotton Ball.
Where? Where?
Right there.
Going into the far turn,
it's Chuck-a-luck in front.
We hate you. Come on, Cotton Ball!
Move it!
And Ladies' Day is moving up
very fast on the outside.
Turning into the stretch,
it's Chuck-a-luck and Ladies' Day.
They're neck and neck.
Come on, Chuck-amen!
No, it's Ladies' Day.
I'm sure.
It's Chuck-a-luck and Ladies' Day!
And Ladies' Day moves ahead.
It's Ladies' Day by a head!
The winner!
Chuck-a-luck was second.
Pumpkin Pie was fourth.
Jumper was fifth.
Blue Boy in sixth.
And here comes Cotton Ball.
Oh, look at him.
Well, good-bye, ladies.
Tomorrow, everything
will be better.
[ Mocking Laugh ]
[ Track Announcer
Continues, indistinct ]
Well, at least we know
who Sleep Out Louie is.
Who?
Nobody.
Mmm.
Come on, snooks.
We have just enough change
for the subway.
Never been on the subway.
Oh, you'll love it.
[ Track Announcer ]
Well, folks, there's Cotton Ball.
Guess he was hungry.
Come on, cheer up.
Something will come up.
Maybe we'll hear from your mother.
Fat chance.
Yeah, well, I keep telling you you
gotta be more polite to folks. Hmm.
That guy was probably
some rich Italian count or something.
Would've been a lot smarter than bettin'
on Cotton Ball, being nice to him.
That's a revolting thought.
Yeah?
Yeah.
- [ Horn Honks ]
- Well, listen...
Buongiorno!
[ Scoffing ]
Okay, watch me.
You are hitching hike?
Hmm?
Hitching hike.
Oh, of course. We always
hitching hike after we lose.
Sort of a penance.
[ Chuckling ] Ah.
And what do strong, handsome
Venetians do when they win?
Whatever the ladies desire.
[ Singsongy ]
The subway. The subway.
Well, how about a little hitch
for two sore losers?
No, just one.
I gotta see a man about a dog.
Oh.
Beth.
You know, snooks,
three on a match and all that.
Yeah, it will be my pleasure
to drive you.
[ Mumbling ]
You ain't kiddin'.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Door Closes ]
[music] At words poetic,
I'm so pathetic;
[music] That I always
have found it best [music]
Hmm?
[music] Instead of getting them
off my chest [music]
[music] To let 'em rest
unexpressed [music]
You mustn't do that.
[music] I hate parading
my serenading [music]
[music] And I'll probably miss a bar;
That was good.
[music] But if this ditty
is not so pretty;
[music] At least it'll tell you [music]
[music] How great you are [music]
You're the top.
[music] You're a Waldorf salad [music]
[music] You're the top [music]
[music] You're a Berlin ballad [music]
[music] You're a baby grand
of a lady and a gent [music]
[music] You're an old Dutch master
You're Mrs. Astor;
[music] You're Pepsodent [music]
[ Laughs ]
I've never been so bad.
[music] You're romance [music]
[music] You're the steppes
of Russia [music]
[music] You're the pants [music]
Pants?
[ Laughs ]
[music] On a Roxy usher;
[music] I'm a lazy lout that is just
about to stop [music] Oh, don't stop.
[music] But if, baby, I'm the bottom,
you're the top [music]
Oh, thank you.
[music] Your words poetic
are not pathetic; No?
[music] On the other hand,
boy, you shine [music] Oh.
[music] And I can feel after
every line [music] Yeah?
[music] A thrill divine [music]
[music] Down my spine [music]
[music] Now, gifted humans
like Vincent Youmans [music]
[music] Might think that your song is
bad [music] Oh, what does he know?
[music] But for a person
who's just rehearsin' [music]
[music] Well, I gotta say
this, my lad [music]
You're the top.
[music] You're an Arrow collar;
[music] You're the top [music]
[ Clears Throat ]
[music] You're a Coolidge dollar;
[music] You're the nimble tread
of the feet of Fred Astaire [music]
That's nice.
[music] You're an O'Neill drama
You're Whistler's mama [music]
[music] You're Camembert [music]
Camembert.
[music] You're a rose [music]
[music] You're Infemo's Dante [music]
[ Giggles ]
[music] You're the nose [music]
The nose?
The nose.
[music] On the great Durante [music]
Oh, yeah.
[music] I'm just in the way;
[music] As the French would say,
De "trop" [music]
[music] But if, baby, I'm the bottom,
you're the top [music]
[ Both Laughing ]
[music] [ Kathy Humming ]
You're the top.
How can you sing?
I'm dizzy.
[music] You're a dancing belly;
[music] You're the top [music]
[music] You're a hot tamale [music]
[music] You're an angel [music]
[music] You're simply too,
too, too diveen [music]
[music] You're a Botticelli [music]
[music] You're Keats [music]
[music] You're Shelley [music]
[music] You're Ovaltine [music]
Aw.
[music] You're a boon [music]
[music] You're the darn
at Boulder [music]
[music] You're the moon [music]
Really?
[music] Over Mae West's shoulder [music]
[music] I'm a nominee [music]
[music] Of the G.O.P. [music]
[music] Or GOP;
[ Together ] [music] But if,
baby, I'm the bottom [music]
[music] You're the top [music]
Mopsie!
You Okay?
I don't get enough exercise.
You know that?
No?
No.
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Johnny ]
[music] You're the top [music]
[music] You're the Colosseum [music]
You know the Colosseum?
[ Brooke ] Mm-hmm.
[music] You're the top [music]
[music] You're the Louvre museum [music]
[music] You're a melody
from a symphony by Strauss [music]
[music] You're a Bendel bonnet,
a Shakespeare sonnet [music]
[music] You're Mickey Mouse [music]
[music] You're the Nile [music]
[music] You're the Tower of Pisa [music]
[music] You're the smile
on the Mona Lisa [music]
[music] I'm a worthless check,
a total wreck, a flop [music]
[music] But if, baby,
I'm the bottom [music]
[music] You're the top [music]
You sing.
Oh, yes.
You finished?
Tonight, we go to El Morocco.
My mother's always had
a weakness for Latins.
And you?
I haven't had that weakness.
No, no?
My mother's in South America.
And your father?
My father isn't in South America.
Ah, your mother and your father...
You remember the crash?
Oh, yes.
I come to America
to make success.
And the day
I come from the boat, crash.
Well, you're doing all right.
Yes. Today, I'm very rich.
How rich?
Oh.
That rich?
Your father in the crash...
crash?
Phfft!
So, what you do?
You have no money.
That was the silly part
of the whole thing.
Daddy thought we were broke,
but he just didn't know Mother.
He didn't know your mother?
Not too well.
I see.
[ Deep Breath ]
She had about a million dollars
hidden around the house. My goodness.
[ Imitating Mae West ] Goodness
had nothing to do with it.
Gary Cooper. [ Laughs ] Yeah.
So what happened to your mother?
She went down to South America.
And she left you no money.
Ah. Oh, a little, and she
sends more every so often.
But lately, it hasn't been so often.
In fact, we haven't heard from her
in three months...
except for one postcard from Rio
that just said, "Ole! Love, Mother."
But then you must
need some money.
No, I don't.
Oh, you don't?
But my hotel does.
Your hotels need money.
Well, they must because they
keep asking me all the time.
Well, this is terrible.
That's just what I tell them.
I fix now this problem for you.
Oh, will you?
Of course. I'm Venetian.
Well, you're more than that.
Yes.
I'm Communist.
Well, be that as it may...
[music] You're the top [music]
[music] You're Mahatma Gandhi [music]
[music] You're... Napoleon brandy;
Oh, Napoleon.
[music] Yeah, you're the purple light
of a summer night in Spain [music]
Italy. Scusi.
Shh!
[music] You're the National Gallery
You're Garbo's salary [music]
[music] You're... [music]
Yeah?
[music] Cellophane [music]
Oh.
[music] You're sublime [music]
[music] You're a turkey dinner;
[music] You're the time of
that Derby winner [music] No.
[ Together ] [music] I'm a toy balloon
that is fated soon to pop [music]
[music] But if, baby,
I'm the bottom [music]
[music] You're the top [music]
[ Vehicle Horn Honking ]
[music] [ Both Holding Note ]
[ Vehicles Passing ]
[ Horns Honking ]
[ Man ] Curtain's going up!
Curtain is going up!
Curtain's going up!
The curtain is going up!
[ Horns Continue Honking ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[music] [ Orchestra: Overture ]
[music] [ Continues ]
Thank you. Would you mind terribly
checking this with our other things?
I'll do it for you, handsome.
Take the night off.
Anytime you say, kiddo.
Excuse me.
Um...
Thank you.
Excuse me.
[ Sighs ]
Thank you.
Oh, my, look at that.
Look at what?
What's the matter?
Nothing really.
I'm afraid that one of you
is in one of our seats.
Nonsense. There's two seats.
One for each of you.
Yes, but the ones I bought
were together. See?
Six and seven.
You're in seven.
What's wrong with that one?
That's nine.
You're being very literal. It's
not for me. It's for Rodney.
He cries at shows.
Sometimes I have to hold his hand.
Or I become uncontrollable.
He becomes uncontrollable.
Well, I wouldn't want
to break anything up.
Shove over, Spagnoli.
Thank you.
Hmm!
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Oh, fine. Now I've got
King Kong in front of me.
Huh? Ah, yes.
Look what you've done.
What?
King Kong's wife.
Oh. Oh, dear.
Can you see the stage?
Not at all.
You have taken the only seat
from which anything is visible.
I hope you enjoy the show.
Allow me. Shall we?
What's the matter? It's an old children's
game. It's called musical chairs.
Huh? We're switching again, junior,
'cause you got such terrific: seats.
This gentleman's gonna switch
with that-gentleman. Excuse me.
[music] [ Orchestra: Intro ]
[music] Now, before this modern idea
had burst;
[music] About the women
and children first;
[music] The men had much more charm
than they have today [music]
[music] And if only one
of that type survived [music]
[music] The very moment
that he arrived [music]
[music] I know I'd fall
in a great big way;
[music] I can't imagine
being bad [music]
[music] With any Arrow collar ad [music]
[music] Nor could I take
the slightest joy [music]
[music] In waking up a college boy;
[music] I've no desire
to be alone [music]
[music] With Rudy Vallee's
megaphone [music]
[music] So when I'm
saying my prayers [music]
[music] I say [music]
[music] Find me [music]
[music] A primitive man [music]
[music] Built on [music]
[music] A primitive plan [music]
[music] Someone [music]
[music] With vigor and vim [music]
[music] I don't mean the kind
that belongs to a club [music]
[music] But the kind that has a club
that belongs to him [music]
[music] I could be [music]
[music] The personal slave [music]
[music] Oi someone [music]
[music] Just out of a cave [music]
[music] The only man
who will ever win me [music]
[music] Has gotta wake up
the gypsy in me [music]
[music] Find me a primitive man [music]
[music] Find me [music]
[music] A primitive man [music]
[ Cavemen Grunting ]
[music] [ Cancan ]
Kathy Krumm.
Shh. She's not so bad.
No, Skeezix.
That's Kathy Krumm.
You know her? Sure. We went
to school together. P.S. 122.
You went to P.S. 122?
Shh.
[ Grunting ]
[ Shouting, Jabbering ]
[ Exclaims ]
[ Sharp Whistle ]
[music] Trouve moi [music]
[music] Un homme primitif [music]
[ Murmuring ]
[music] Trouve moi [music]
[music] Un garcon naif [music]
Ah!
[ Muttering ]
Hey!
[ Tarzan Yell ]
[music] Trouve moi
un homme primitif
Follow me.
This way. This way.
Hello. Hello.
How'd you like the show?
Sensational. Sensational.
Sisters.
Mm-hmm.
Hi, gorgeous.
Hello there.
Oh, boy. An American Indian.
Hey.
[ Brooke ] Congratulations.
I don't know this girl.
You don't know this girl?
I've never seen her.
Hi, Mopsie.
You don't know these girls.
Well!
Oh, thank you.
[ Laughing ]
Scusi.
[ Squeals ]
Excuse me. 'You-[ Laughs ]
[ Groans ]
Oh.
[ Laughing ]
[ Mock Laughing ]
Shh.
[ Thumps ] [ Kathy ] Who is it?
Mopsie! Was I good?
Oh! Thank you.
[ Laughing ]
I have another surprise for you.
You do?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, he's very cute.
No, not him.
Behind you.
Kathy Krumm,
you're a nasty girl.
Brookski!
P.S...
1-2-2!
[ Together ]
1-2-2! And...
[music] [ Humming ]
[music] Hurrah for the
orange and blue [music]
[music] To 1-2-2
we will ever be true [music]
[music] She gives us the knowledge
to send us to college [music]
[music] Hurrah for the
orange and blue [music]
[ Shrieking ]
Come in here!
[ Both Chattering, Laughing ]
[ Kathy ] Look at you!
You look absolutely gorgeous!
[music][ Up-tempo ]
[ Kathy ] What about the time that Mr.
Petrovich-[ Brooke ] Don't you dare.
Made a pass at you in the gym-Stop.
It was the locker room.
After that game? That game
was in the locker room.
I can't stand it!
[ Giggling 1
I haven't thought about that.
Neither have I.
But isn't he the one that
started calling you Brookski?
You're right.
I'd forgotten all about him.
Ooh, was he mean.
[ Both Giggling ]
Mr. Spanish.
Yeah?
I've been thinking. You remind me of
someone I'm really quite fond of.
Yes? Who?
Me.
Si. Mike and I,
they look alike.
Yeah, except you look better.
Oh, no. I prefer you.
Oh, you're too kind. Would you
care to dance? That's a good idea.
Do you mind if I lead?
My pleasure.
Listen to Mutt and Jeff.
We can't talk for two minutes...
Two hours.
And a half.
Not counting the car ride.
It's been years and years.
I thought you didn't smoke.
I don't.
Lots of terrible things have happened.
What about that time in biology?
Would you yield for a question?
[ Together ]
We'll consider it.
About public: school. I can't picture
Brookie there. [ Others ] Brookski!
Neither could the school.
Mother thought I was getting spoiled.
So she took me out of Miss Hopkins's.
And into 1-2-2.
[music] Hurrah for the orange and blue [music]
[ Johnny, Mike ] And then what happened?
Nothing. Mother was right.
I was spoiled.
After one year, boing-
back I went to Miss Hopkins's.
What's it mean, boing?
She got kicked out.
My mom couldn't afford it, so we
didn't see each other much after that.
Why don't you guys
go take a walk or something?
We did that.
Twice.
Then go tie your tie.
You too.
Sir, you're not in fashion.
Thank you very much
for pointing that out.
You're quite welcome.
It's the fashion, George.
I know, but Mildred
is so out of touch.
I am not.
She is not.
What are you doing, lady?
Hands off of my husband.
It's the latest fashion.
[ All Muttering ]
I think we'd better dance
before they throw us out.
Yeah. Okay, spaghetti.
Let's go.
[music] [ Slow Tempo ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Johnny Chattering ]
Canals. And it's so nice.
[music] [ Up-tempo ] [music] If you're
ever in a jam, here I am [music]
Yeah. You've got it.
[music] If you ever need a pal,
I'm your gal [music]
[music] If you ever feel so happy;
[music] You land in jail,
I'm your bail [music]
[ Together ] [music] It's
friendship, friendship [music]
[music] Just the perfect
blendship [music]
[music] When other friendships
have been forgot [music]
[music] Ours will still be hot;
[music] Lah-dle-ah-dle-ah-dle [music]
Dig, dig, dig.
Whee!
[music] If you ever lose your way,
come to "K" [music]
I'm getting tired of this.
[music] If you're ever in a flop,
call for MOP [music]
Oh, MOP.
[music] By the other hand [music]
[music] If you ever take a boat
and get lost at sea [music] Yes?
What?
[music] Write to me [music]
[music] It's friendship,
friendship [music]
[music] Just the perfect
blendship [music]
[music] When other friendships
have been forgit [music]
[music] Ours will still be it [music]
[music] Lah-dle-ah-dle-ah-dle [music]
Chuck, chuck, chuck.
Oh, that's cute.
Thank you.
[ Together ]
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, and...
Hey, you wanna spend
Sunday on the Sound?
Oh, would you, Brooke?
He's got a terrific house.
Well, I'd have to get some clothes.
Me too.
And Beth.
Lead off, Mr. Spanish.
Yeah!
[music] If you're ever down a well,
ring my bell [music]
Choc-chem!
[music] If you ever catch on fire,
send a wire [music]
I Will, I Will. Yeah?
[music] If you ever lose your teeth and
you're out to dine, borrow mine [music]
[music] It's friendship,
friendship [music]
[music] Just the perfect
blendship [music]
[music] When other friendships
have ceased to gel [music]
[music] Ours will still be swell [music]
[music] Lah-dle-ah-dle-ah-dle [music]
Hep, hep, hep.
[ Fingers Snap ]
Whee!
[ Honking ]
[ Beth ]
I'm coming! I'm coming!
I'm coming. Well, hurry up.
We've been waiting all night.
Oh, Brooke, it is late.
It is not.
This will make it earlier, Beth.
I'm Mike Pritchard.
How do you do?
Well, I don't mind if I-Where did you
find him? He goes with Kathy here.
Remember my old friend Kathy?
I told you about her.
Oh, that little girl from public: school.
Well, I grew, if you don't mind.
You got good taste too. He's
just someone I ran into.
I like your friend.
And she's single too.
Oh, really?
Thanks a lot.
Any more at home like you?
Mercifully not.
You're just jealous. Well, what
do they call you, big boy?
Rodney James.
Rod.
That, I'm afraid, is the diminutive.
[ Engine Starts ]
Well, I bet you ain't.
[ Others Laughing ]
[ Backfiring, Gears Grinding ]
[ Laughter Continues ]
[music] [ Singing Operatic
Aria In Italian ]
[ Kathy Laughing ]
Get in here, John.
[music] Bravo [music]
You missed three rounds, John.
Four. Four. Four.
Oh, that's right, Mertle.
Guzzle it, you old drunk.
I must say that bird
drinks like a fish.
Thank you.
Broke, you drink too?
Brooke.
Brook.
No. Brooke.
Si. Bruke.
[ Chuckling ]
No wonder you never
invited me to your place.
Oh, dear.
[ Engine Starts ]
[music] If they ever
black your eyes [music]
[music] Put me wise [music]
Yeah.
[music] If they ever
cook your goose [music]
[music] Turn me loose [music]
[music] If they ever put a bullet through
your brain, I'll complain [music]
[music] It's friendship,
friendship [music]
[music] Just the perfect
blendship [music]
[music] When other friendships
go up in smoke [music]
[music] Ours will still be oke [music]
[music] Lah-dle-ah-dle-ah-dle [music]
Cluck, cluck, cluck.
[ Laughing, Cheering ]
Smell, smell, smell!
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
No. I'm driving.
Oh, come on.
Oh, come on, Rod. You've only had one.
Yeah, Rod.
That is not my name.
I am simply not a "Rod."
Thank heaven.
Open wide.
Whoo.
[music] If you ever lose your mind,
I'll be kind [music]
Isn't he sweet? [ Brooke ] Yes.
[music] If you ever lose your shirt,
I'd be hurt [music]
There's a switch.
[music] If you're ever in a mill and get
sawed in half, I won't laugh [music]
[music] It's friendship,
friendship [music]
[music] Just the perfect
blendship [music]
[music] When other friendships
have been forgate [music]
[music] Ours will still be great;
[music] Lah-dle-ah-dle-ah-dle [music]
Goo, goo, goo.
Bravo!
[music] If they ever hang you, pard,
send a card [music]
[ Mike Laughing ]
[music] If they ever cut your throat,
write a note [music]
You have my word.
[music] If they ever make
a cannibal stew of you [music]
Yeah?
[music] Invite me too [music]
[music] Oh, it's friendship,
friendship [music]
[music] Just the perfect
blendship [music]
[music] When other friendships
are up the crick [music]
[music] Ours will still be slick [music]
[music] Lah-dle-ah-dle-ah-dle [music]
Zip, zip, zip.
Woof, woof, woof.
Quack, quack, quack.
Tweet, tweet, tweet.
Peck, peck, peck.
Push, push, push.
Hip, hip, hip.
Put, put, put.
Give, give, give.
Take, take, take.
[ Others Vocalizing, Laughing ]
Rod.
Rodney.
Right. [ Mouthing
Words ] [ Gasps ]
[ Vocalizing, Chattering Continue ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Muffled Groan ]
[ Loud Slam ]
[ Door Opens ]
Ah, Rodney.
Is she safe?
Sir?
Did she get home safe? I
thought she was with you, sir.
Who?
Miss Carter.
No Miss Carter.
Little Annie Orphan.
You mean the figure
in the comic?
Of course. She has been trying to return
to her Daddy Warbucks for three weeks.
He is not her real daddy
because she is orphan.
She has no mama, no daddy.
She has no eyes either.
Yeah. It's a symbol.
Ah. Well, sir, I haven't
had a look yet.
Why don't you look for yourself?
Oh, grazie, grazie. Is there
anything else you'd like?
Oh, no. Grazie.
Thank you. It's enough.
Whatever you say, sir.
Leaping lizards!
Sir?
Leaping lizards.
She always says "Leaping lizards."
How eloquent.
See, ma, she no home.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Yeah, tomorrow.
I shall say a small prayer.
Thank you!
You are very gentle.
Thank you, sir.
[music] [ Singing, indistinct ]
[ Loud Clatter ]
[ Sizzles ]
[ Clears Throat ]
[music] [ Humming, Singing ]
[ Sighs ]
Leaping lizards.
What?
Oh, never mind.
Don't just stand there.
You look like a nervous turtle.
Another reptile.
Huh?
How does one tell, I wonder,
when turtles are nervous?
Well, they stay in their shells,
Rodney ol' James.
Well, that is not the case
with this turtle. No, huh?
No, he was simply amazed that anyone who
could swill so much liquor of an evening...
could possibly arise
so early in the morning.
I love the way you talk.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Coffee's hot.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Those for Miss Carter?
Yep.
An eccentric breakfast,
I dare say.
Oh, she don't eat 'em.
She don't-uh, doesn't?
Nope.
Well, what does she do with them?
She puts 'em on her face.
I see. Silly of me to ask.
I made some fresh orange juice
in the icebox, if you want it.
No, thank you.
I don't believe I'll eat
or drink for several days.
What do you all do around here
to pass the time?
[ Cucumber Crunches ]
Oh, many things.
Like?
Well, there are several
splendid horses in the stable.
A large pool, a tennis court,
a skeet range.
Mr. Pritchard also plays poker,
football...
Oh, I love football.
All that contact.
Madam, please,
keep your distance.
I was just gonna get
some orange juice for Miss Brooke.
I'm sorry.
You're an old grouch.
That's true.
You can put the coffee down now.
[ Loud Slam ]
Isn't there anything you like to do?
Yes, there is.
What?
Sleep.
I bet you mean sleep too.
Yes, I do.
[ Sighs ]
[music] But are you fond
of riding, dear? [music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[music] Yes, I'm fond of riding, dear;
[music] But in the morning, no;
No?
No.
[music] Well, are you good
at shooting, dear? [music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[music] Yes, I'm good
at shooting, dear [music]
[music] But in the morning, no;
[music] When the dawn's early light
comes to crucify my night [music]
[ Loudly ] [music] That's
the time when I'm in low;
[music] Are you fond of
wrestling, dear? [music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[music] Yes, I'm fond
of wrestling, dear;
[music] But in the morning, no [music]
No, no?
[music] No, no, no, no, no;
[ Exhales ]
Have you got everything?
Yes.
Shall we go amongst 'em?
I think we had better.
[music] Can you do the crawl, my dear?
[music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[ Sighs ]
[music] I can do the crawl, my dear;
[music] But in the morning, no;
[music] When I, as Gunga Din,
bring his bromo seltzer in [music]
[music] That's the time when
I'm in low; [ Whimpers ]
[music] Do you use
the breaststroke, dear'? [music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[music] Yes, I use
the breaststroke, dear [music]
[music] But in the morning,
no, no [music] No, no?
[music] No, no, no, no, no;
[ Mike ] Rod, is that you?
Yes, sir.
What are you yelling about?
Just seeing if you're up, sir.
Have you got my fizzy?
Right here, sir.
What shall I do
with Miss O'Kelly's coffee?
She's gone for a walk
or something equally bizarre.
I'll drink it.
Yes, sir.
Morning, Beth.
Hi.
Bye.
[music] Are you fond of poker, dear?
[music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[music] Yes, I'm fond of poker, dear;
[music] But in the morning, no;
[ Brooke ] Beth? Yeah.
Do you have it all?
Yeah.
Thanks.
[music] Can you fill an
inside straight? [music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[music] I've filled plenty
inside straights [music]
[music] But in the morning,
no, no [music] No, no?
[music] No, no, no, no, no [music]
[ Loud Slam ]
What are you gonna do?
Meditate.
Can I watch?
No. Go away.
Okay. But, Rod...
Rodney?
Yes.
I'll see you in the afternoon.
[ Objects Clattering Loudly ]
Ooh-ooh.
[music] [ Humming ]
[ Door Opens ]
[music] [ Vocalizing ]
Buongiorno.
Hiya.
Brooke is up?
I think she's down.
Is bad?
I'd say it's a four-cucumber day.
That's bad.
It ain't good.
Well, I try.
Well, "boner fortuner."
Oh.
Brooke.
It's me-Johnny.
[ Brooke ]
No kidding.
Brooke, you are angry.
Brooke, I'm sorry
I didn't tell you the truth.
But it's only a little lie.
I become very rich very soon.
Maybe tomorrow.
Okay, okay.
I'll see you later.
Let me wake up now.
Yeah, I go.
Brooke.
What?
Little Annie Orphan no home yet.
Brooke? Did you hear
about Little Annie?
Leaping lizards.
Yeah.
I see you later, Mia Cara.
[music] Is it in marble;
[music] Or is it in clay? [music]
[music] Is what I thought
a new Rolls [music]
[ Mutters In Italian ]
[music] A used Chevrolet? [music]
[music] Is it a sapphire [music]
[music] Or simply a charm? [music]
[music] Is it real fire [music]
Yeah.
[music] Or just a false alarm? [music]
[music] Is it today's thrill;
[music] Or really romance? [music]
[music] Is it a kiss on the lips [music]
[music] Or just a kick in the pants?
[music]
[music] Is it the gay 906$ [music]
[music] Cavorting above? [music]
[music] Or is it [music]
[music] At long last [music]
Love?
Talking to yourself?
Uh, yeah, a little.
Nice day.
Belissima.
Oh, that's Italian. Ah,
for the day and for you.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, I think I'll go get
a cruller or something.
[ Laughs ]
Ciao.
Yeah. Auf Wiedersehen.
Ah, Kathy.
Hmm?
Little Annie Orphan no home yet.
No, huh?
What about Dick Tracy?
Oh, still the same.
Is bad.
Sure is.
Yeah.
[ Deep Breath ]
Well.
[music] [ Humming ]
[music] Is it the rainbow;
[music] Or just a mirage? [music]
[music] Will it be
tender and sweet [music]
[music] Or merely massage? [music]
[music] Is it a brainstorm [music]
[music] In one of its quirks? [music]
[music] Or is it the best;
[music] The crest [music]
[music] The works'? [music]
[music] Is it for all time [music]
[music] Or Simply a lark? [music]
[music] Is it the Lido I see;
[music] Or only Asbury Park? [music]
[music] Should I say thumbs down [music]
[music] And give it a shove? [music]
[music] Or is it at long last [music]
Love?
[ Mike ]
Talking to yourself?
I was just thinking
about... things.
Anyone I know?
No.
Well, don't go away.
I'm just gonna...
Okay.
Be right down.
[music] Is it an earthquake [music]
[music] Or simply a shock? [music]
[music] Is it the good
turtle soup [music]
[music] Or merely the mock? [music]
[music] Is it a cocktail [music]
[music] This feeling of joy? [music]
[music] Or is what I feel [music]
[music] The real McCoy? [music]
[music] Have I the right hunch [music]
[music] Or have I the wrong? [music]
[music] Will it be Bach I shall hear
or just a Cole Porter song? [music]
[music] Is it a fancy love [music]
[music] We're thinking of? [music]
[music] Or is it at long [music]
[music] Last [music]
Love?
[ Screams ]
Oh! Hoo-hoo!
Rodney!
Rodney?
[ Screaming ]
Oh, I'm sorry.
I've got alcohol in my eyes.
Well, that's an original way to drink.
No. Shaving alcohol.
You shouldn't drink that at all. [
Chuckles ] I wasn't drinking it.
Could we continue this
conversation later? Gladly.
Thank you. Could I ask you
one question before I go?
No.
What's that all over your face?
Smallpox.
Thank you.
Why don't you go shave?
I Will.
[ Grunting, Chuckling ]
[music] Is it a breakdown [music]
[music] Or is it a break? [music]
[music] Dee, Dee, Dee, Dee [music]
[music] Is it a real porterhouse [music]
[music]Or only a steak [music]
[music] What can account for [music]
[music] These strange pitter-pats?
[music]
[music] Could this be the dream [music]
[music] The cream, the cats'? [music]
[music] Is it to rescue [music]
[music] Or is it to wreck? [music]
[music] Is it an ache in the heart;
[music] Or just a pain in the neck?
[music]
[music] Is it the ivy you touch [music]
[music] With a glove? [music]
[music] Or is it at long [music]
[music] Last [music]
Love?
I wonder what'll happen.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Squeals ]
Hey!
[ Screams ]
No!
[ Whimpers ]
Get yourself a scotch, Alfred.
Huh?
That's okay. That's Mabel.
My mother.
[ Kathy Laughs ]
Touchdown!
I win.
Mother, you're always spoiling it.
[ Grunting ]
I said no tackling.
We're not gonna have any tack...
I hate this game.
I've always hated this game.
Really, Kitty.
You're getting awfully butch.
I don't know what came over me. Not
to mention this other young lady.
Hi. I'm Brooke. I'm broken.
My back is broken.
I'm sorry!
He's always complaining.
Michael, if you're going to play
with pros, you have to be prepared.
Yes, Mother.
Now, who's this?
I'm Johnny Spanish.
I bet you are.
No, Mabel. That's his name.
I love it!
Now cut that out.
He goes with her.
Lucky me!
Oh, well, if that's your type.
You can have him, Mrs. Pritchard,
but he's all show.
Oh, yes.
Call me Mabel, dear. I don't like
to be reminded of my husband.
Sure.
Tea, Mrs. P.?
Perfect timing, Rodney.
Where would you like it?
Well, where am I now? I'd say you
were in the middle of the backyard.
Well, I think I'll have my tea
in the middle of the backyard.
Very good, madam. See how she
makes decisions? Just like that.
Who's your playmate?
Oh, that's Elizabeth.
Now, please, madam,
don't encourage her.
I'm his shadow.
You see what I mean.
Oh, now, Rodney.
You're blushing.
That's a first.
Is he blushing?
I've seen him blush before.
He's blushing.
You can spare us
the sordid details, Michael.
Could we change the subject?
Well, Rodney, you and
Elizabeth run off and play.
We can manage the tea.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, couldn't I stay?
We're never alone.
[ Laughing ]
I know what you mean, dear.
Madam, that is unfair.
Well, Rodney, let's face it.
You are no pushover.
Oh, hear, hear.
Well, all right. Stay.
Have a drink.
Thank you.
[ Thuds ]
Rodney, you're such a tiger.
I see you still haven't
shaved that silly thing off.
Do we have to talk about it now?
Don't you like his mustache?
She hates it. He only grew
it to look like Rodney.
Well, he's my idol.
He's mine too.
Oh, go away!
[ Laughing ]
I see I'm still the only one
currently unattached.
You'll all have to come to the club dance
with me tonight, help me pick someone out.
Absolutely out of the question.
[music] [ Slow Tempo ]
Michael.
Hi, Mabel.
Hello, handsome.
Hello, madam.
[ Sighs ]
Your mother looks
beautiful tonight. Yes.
Who's that stick
she's dancing with?
Captain Craig.
I don't know what he's captain of.
That's what they've always called him.
Maybe it's his first name.
I knew a guy called Sergeant once.
Possible.
[ Shoe Shuffling, Tapping ]
They don't like
tip-tap.
They don't like anything.
I think if a bomb fell right outside, they'd
just give you that look and go right on dancing.
Oh, of course.
Didn't you know?
Yes? [music] When you're
out in smart society;
[music] And you suddenly
get bad news [music]
[music] You mustn't show anxiety [music]
No?
[music] And proceed to sing
the blues [music] Hmm.
[music] For example,
tell me something sad [music]
[music] Something awful
Something grave [music]
[music] And I'll show you how
a Racquet Club lad would behave [music]
Okay.
[music] Have you heard
the coast of Maine [music]
[music] Just got hit
by a hurricane? [music]
[music] Well, did you evah? [music]
[music] What a swell party
this is [music] [ Laughs ]
Perfect! [music] Have you
heard that Uncle Newt;
[music] Forgot to open
his parachute? [music]
[music] Well, did you ever;
[music] What a swell party
this is [music] Precisely!
[music] It's great, it's grand [music]
[music] It's wonderland [music]
[music] It's tops, it's first;
[music] It's DuPont, it's Hearst;
[music] What soup
What-a fish [music]
[music] That meat
What a dish [music]
[music] What salad
What cheese [music]
Yes? [music] Pardon me One
moment, please [music]
[music] Have you heard
that poor, dear Blanche [music]
[music] Got run down
by an avalanche? [music]
[music] Well, did you ever? [music]
[music] What a swell
party this is [music]
[music] Have you heard Mrs. Cass had three
beers and then ate the glass? [music]
[ Gasps ] [ Muffled ] [music]
Well, did you ever? [music]
Hmm. [music] What a swell
party this is [music]
Any bets?
Just go ahead.
[music] Have you heard
it's in the stars [music]
[music] Next July
we collide with Mars? [music]
Well, did you evah!
What a swell party this is.
[music] Have you heard
that poor old Ted [music]
[music] Just turned up
in an oyster bed? [music]
Well, did you evah!
[music] What a swell party
this is [music]
[music] What daiquiris [music]
[music] What sherry, please [music]
[music] What Burgundy [music]
[music] What great Pommery [music]
[ Coughs ]
What brandy. Wow!
What whiskey.
And how!
[music] What gm and what beer [music]
[music] Will you sober up, my dear?
[music]
[music] Have you heard
Professor Munch [music]
[music] Ate his wife
and divorced his lunch? [music]
[music] Well, did you evah? [music]
[music] What a swell party
this is [music]
Help!
Coraggio!
Would you, old man?
Of course.
[music] Have you heard
that Mimsie Starr [music]
[music] Just got pinched
in the Astor Bar [music]
Well!
[ Muttering ]
Swell party.
Michael, what are you doing?
[music] Have you heard
that Captain Craig [music]
[music] Breeds termites
in his wooden leg? [music]
Michael Oliver Pritchard!
[music] What a swell
party this is [music]
[music] It's fun, it's fine [music]
[music] It's too divine [music]
[music] It's smooth, it's smart [music]
[music] It's Rodgers, it's Hart;
[music] What debs [music]
[music] What stage, [music]
[music] What gossip [music]
[music] What gags [music]
[music] What feathers [music]
[music] What fuss [music]
[music] Just between
the flour oi us [music]
Michael, you are incorrigible!
[music] Lilly Lane has
lousy luck [music]
[music] She was there
when the lightning struck [music]
Well, did you ever!
What a swell party this is.
Bye, Mom.
Bye, Mabel.
[ Sighs ]
[music] Mrs. Smith
in her new Hup [music]
[music] Crossed the bridge
when the bridge was up [music]
Well, did you ever!
What a swell party this is.
I believe I need a drink.
Hey, Spanish.
They're deserting us.
I see. Let's go. I'm with you, John.
Excuse us.
[music] It's fun, it's fresh [music]
[music] It's post depresh [music]
[music] It's Shangri-la [music]
[music] It's Harper's Bazaar [music]
[music] Oh, what domes
Que! Chic [music]
[music] Those pearls, they're
the peak [music] Oh!
[music] What glamor and
what cheer [music]
[music] This will simply
slay you, dear [music]
[music] Kitty isn't paying calls [music]
[music] She slipped over
Niagara Falls [music]
[music] Well, did you ever? [music]
[music] What a swell
party this is [music]
Yeah?
Yeah.
[music] And Johnny's
rather scatterbrained [music]
[music] He dove in
when the pool was drained [music]
[music] Well, did you ever? [music]
[music] What a swell
party this is [music]
[music] [ Ends ]
[ Scattered Applause Continues ]
Is that thing itchy?
What thing?
The thing on your lip.
Oh.
No.
Not at all?
Well, when it's growin' in.
Mm-hmm.
A little.
Kiss me, you fool.
On. Right.
[ Mabel ]
Michael? Brooke!
Did you hear something?
No.
I hate to tell you
what I think it was.
Then don't.
All right.
Brooke? Michael!
I don't hear a thing.
Well, I do.
It's your mother.
Oh.
Well.
Yes, Mabel.
Where are you?
Oh.
Hi.
We were just looking for Kitty and John.
What a coincidence.
Oh, have you seen them?
Yes. They just left.
They left?
Right.
Where'd they go?
Back to the city.
Gee. They didn't
want to disturb you.
Oh, they didn't?
No.
But we weren't doing
anything... special.
Were we?
I can't think of anything.
Mmm. Kitty has
a matinee tomorrow,
and Mr. Spagnoli indicated there was
a rather heavy card game scheduled.
Oh.
I see.
Well, you may take the car.
The captain's going to show me his
lighthouse. See you in a day or so.
Good night.
Good night, Mom.
Good night, Mabel.
[music] [ Big Band On
Radio: "You're the Top"]
[music] [ Whistling Along ]
[music] [ Whistling Continues ]
Could you please turn the station?
Can you find another station?
All right.
Take it easy.
[ Switching Radio Stations ]
But why so gloomy are we?
The night is beautiful.
You are beautiful.
I'm beautiful.
You ain't bad.
[ Speaks Italian ]
Huh?
I have idea.
Oh, I bet you do.
I'm no Boob McNutt.
And I'm no Dumb Dora.
Si. You know,
I prefer Blondie .7
Oh, I know.
Oh, no! No.
What's your idea?
They make us unhappy?
We make them unhappy.
How do we do that? They make us jealous?
We make them jealous.
Give them some of their own
medicine, you mean. Of course!
We are seen everywhere.
We hold hands. We kiss.
We-
Uh-huh.
What do you think?
I think this is
a very original pass.
No, it's not a pass.
No.No, no.
Si. It's just sort
of a show we put on?
Doesn't mean anything?
No.
[ Clears Throat ]
Do we rehearse?
If you like.
Hmm.
This show could be a hit.
[music] You're such
a Ne plus ultra creature [music]
What was that?
French.
[music] That if I had your photo [music]
[music] I couldn't pick
my favorite feature [music]
[music] I like you so in Toto [music]
Latin.
Oh, thank you.
[music] In every way,
from every angle [music]
[music] You're the bangle
I long to dangle [music]
Very convincing.
I'll say that much for you.
[music] Or from basement to roof [music]
[music] From Wagner opera
to opera bouffe [music]
Go on. I love it.
I love it!
[music] From alpha to omega [music]
What?
[music] '(All 'CZ!' [music]
Oh.
Yeah.
[music] From alpha to omega [music]
I thought you said "alfalfa."
[music] You were made for me [music]
"From alpha to alfalfa."
You are nice.
You know that?
[music] From left hooks
by Dempsey [music]
[music] To Braddock's uppercuts [music]
[music] From Jericho to Kokomo [music]
[music] Not to mention
from soup to nuts [music]
Is this part of the show?
[ Laughing ]
[music] From Journal
until Mirror [music]
I'm not so good on that turf.
[music] From coast to coast [music]
Oh, I don't know about that.
[music] From Juliet to Norma Shearer;
[music] You're what I like
the most;
Yeah?
Yeah.
[music] And from morning
until evening [music]
[music] Will you stun yourself
with wine? [music]
Certainly.
[music] Till from alpha to omega [music]
[music] You are mine [music]
[music] [ Holds Note ]
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Brooke ]
Here we are!
Yeah.
Here we are.
Will you be needing
anything else, sir?
No. Ta-ta!
Hmm.
No, you can go to bed, Rod.
[ Clears Throat ]
Good night, Rod.
Good night.
Never gets that right,
and he never will.
I don't know why
he keeps trying to do it.
Once a week we have it, and I have
to pick it up and dust it off,
put it on the shelf.
[ Bottles Clinking ]
Ridiculous actually.
[ Yelps ]
Guess who!
The bride of Frankenstein.
Oh, how'd you know?
I have a sixth sense.
Gracious.
I got dressed just for you.
Undressed, you mean.
Oh, now,
don't be vulgar, Rodney.
Where do you think you're going?
With you.
I'm simply going
to park the car.
I love parking.
I don't know.
I feel a little guilty.
So I've noticed.
[music] You could have
a great career [music]
Hmm?
And you should.
Only one thing stops you, dear.
Too much money.
You're too good.
If you want a future, darling,
why don't you...
get a past?
[music] 'Cause that fatal moment's
coming [music]
[music] At last;
[music] We're all alone [music]
Want a drink?
[music] No chaperone [music]
[music] Can get our number [music]
[music] The world's in slumber;
[music] Let's [music]
[music] Misbehave [music]
[ Chuckles ]
[music] There's something wild [music]
[music] About you, child [music]
[music] That's so contagious [music]
[music] Let's be outrageous [music]
[music] And misbehave [music]
[ Sighs, Clears Throat ]
[music] When Adam won Eve's hand,
he wouldn't stand [music]
[music] For teasin' [music]
[music] He didn't care about;
[music] Those apples
out of season [music]
Oh.
Mmm.
[music] They say that spring [music]
[music] Means just one thing [music]
[music] To little lovebirds [music]
[music] We're not above birds [music]
[ Moaning ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
[music] I feel a sudden urge
to sing [music]
Huh?
[music] The kind of ditty
that invokes the spring [music]
[music] So control
your desire to curse [music]
[music] While I crucify
the verse [music]
[music] This verse you've started
seems to me [music]
Yeah?
[music] The Tin-Pantithesis
of melody [music]
[ Scoffs ]
So spare me, please, the pain.
Just skip the damn thing
and sing the refrain.
[music] [ Note ]
[music] Mi-mi-mi-mi [music]
[music] [ Second Note ]
[music] No, no, no, no;
[music] [ Third Note ]
[music] Do-re-[music]
[music] Take it away [music]
[music] The night is young [music]
[music] And the skies are clear [music]
[music] So if you want
to go walking, dear;
[music] It's delightful [music]
[music] It's delicious [music]
[ Groans ]
[music] It's de-lovely [music]
[music] I understand
the reason why [music]
[music] You're sentimental
'Cause so am I;
Are we?
[music] It's delightful [music]
[music] It's delicious [music]
[music] It's de-lovely [music]
[music] You can tell at a glance [music]
[music] What a swell night
this is for romance [music]
[music] You can hear
dear Mother Nature [music]
[music] Murmuring low;
[music] "Let yourself go" [music]
[music] So please, be sweet,
my chickadee [music]
[music] And when I kiss you,
just say to me [music]
[music] It's delightful? [music]
Mm-hmm.
[music] It's delicious [music]
[music] It's delectable? [music]
[music] It's delirious [music]
[music] It's dilemma [music]
[music] It's de-limit [music]
[music] It's deluxe [music]
[music] It's de-lovely [music]
[ Screams, Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
Come on!
Where are we going?
Take a dip!
Take a dip?
In the pool.
How exciting.
Hey. Katerina.
[ Giggling 1
Ah! [ Laughing ] Katerina!
Oh.
[ Mutters ]
Winded?
Oh.
[ Panting ]
What are you doing?
I dance.
I didn't know you could dance.
Yeah.
You see?
I don't think I can do that.
Try it.
Watch out.
Bene.
See?
Yeah. Of course bene.
The night is young.
You are young.
Grazie.
[music] From cotton plowed under;
[music] [ Vocalizing ]
[music] Ba-Ba-Ba-bam [music]
[music] From Benzedrine
to Ovaltine [music]
[music] Not to mention
from go to stop [music]
That's my house.
Ah, that's your...
[music] From corn muffins
to Triscuit [music]
[music] From fat;
[music] To thin [music]
[music] From Zev
to the young Seabiscuit [music]
[music] I'll bet on you to win [music]
[music] And will you beat me
and maltreat me [music]
[music] And bend
my Spanish spine? [music]
[music] Certainly;
[music] From alpha to omega [music]
[ Both Giggling ]
Last one in's a rotten chicken!
Whoo!
I'm a rotten chicken.
Whoa.
[ Chuckling, Whimpers ]
[music] The knot is... [music]
Ah, swell.
[music] So we take a few hours off to eat
the wedding cake [music] It was your idea.
[music] It's delightful [music]
Oh!
[music] It's deli-[music]
[music] It's de-lovely [music]
[ Both Laughing ]
[music] It feels so fine
to be a bride [music]
How's the groom? [music] Well,
he's slightly fried [music]
[music] It's delightful
It's delicious [music]
It's-I can't swim.
Oh!
[music] To the pop of champagne [music]
[music] Off we hop
in our plush little plane [music]
[music] Till the bright light
from the darkness [music]
[music] Cozily calls [music]
[music] Niagara Falls;
[music] All's well, my love
Our day's complete [music]
[music] And what a beautiful
bridal suite [music]
[music] It's de-reamy [music]
[music] It's de-rowsy [music]
[music] It's de-reverie [music]
[music] It's de-rhapsody;
[music] It's de-regal [music]
[music] It's de-royal [music]
[music] It's de-Ritz [music]
[music] It's [music]
[music] It's de-lovely [music]
[ Mike, Brooke Chattering ]
Madam, please.
This is my room!
Oh, tell it to the marines.
The marines?
I love your p.j.'s.
You'll have to excuse me.
I was just... doing the books.
[music] Are you good
at figures, dear? [music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[music] Yes, I'm good
at figures, dear;
[music] But in the morning, no;
[music] Do you do
double entry, dear? [music]
[music] Kindly tell me if so [music]
[music] I do double entry, dear;
[music] But in the morning, no, no;
[music] Yes, yes [music]
[music] No, no [music]
[music] Yes, yes;
[music] No, no, no, no, no;
[ Elizabeth ] Yes. [ Rodney ] Mmm.
[music] We're on the crest
We have no cares [music]
[music] We're just a couple
of honey bears [music]
[music] It's delightful
It's delicious [music]
[music] It's de-lovely [music]
[music] All's as right as can be [music]
[music] Till one night
at my window I see [music]
[music] An absurd bird with a bundle
hung on his nose;
Get baby clothes.
[music] These eyes of mine
are filled with joy;
[music] The nurse appears
and cries, "It's a boy!" [music]
[music] He's appalling [music]
[music] He's appealing [music]
[music] He's a polliwog [music]
[music] He's a paragon [music]
[music] He's a Popeye. [music] [music]
He's a panic. He's a pip. [music]
It's getting late!
[music] And while I wait,
my poor heart aches on [music]
[music] Why keep the brakes on'? [music]
Let's misbehave?
[music] I feel quite sure
un peu diamour [music]
[music] Would be attractive [music]
[music] While we're still active [music]
[music] Let's misbehave [music]
[music] You know my
heart 'vs true [music]
[music] When you say you
for me care [music]
[music] Somebody's sure to tell [music]
[music] But what the hell [music]
[music] Do we care? [music]
[music] They say that bears
have love affairs [music]
And even camels.
Mm-hmm.
[music] We're merely mammals [music]
[music] [ Humming ]
[ Crowd Chattering ]
[ Cheering ]
There you go, Frank.
Yay!
Did you see that?
Of course I saw it.
[ Sighs ]
Didn't take them very long, did it?
Nope. First pitch.
How do you know she pitched?
Huh?
He might have done the pitching.
Remember Casanova? He was Italian too.
Ollie, what are you
talking about?
What do you mean what am I talking about? I'm
talking about our two friends over there.
Giving the ball game
some pretty stiff competition.
Well, good for them.
What's wrong with that?
Johnny's a swell guy,
and she's a peach.
I just wish they weren't
so angry at us.
You mean you knew that was going on?
Nope. But I'm glad.
You are?
Mm-hmm.
Makes me not feel so bad
about stealing her boyfriend.
You're strong, you know that?
Mm-hmm.
All gone.
Hey, that's a good idea.
We'll let them see us.
What?
You're jealous? Oh, don't be absurd.
Me jealous?
You are!
I am not.
You thought she'd be
pining away for you.
I certainly didn't have
any such thought.
Now just be quiet
and watch the ball game.
Hey, Ollie. That reminds me.
What?
Did you hear about the horse that could
pitch and field as good as Babe Ruth?
A horse?
It's a joke.
Oh, that's funny.
It's not finished yet.
Oh.
This horse could pitch
and field, you see,
so the manager
asked his trainer...
He said, "Can he bat?"
Oh, that's very funny.
It's not over yet. It's the
longest joke I've ever heard.
If you'd be quiet, I could finish it.
Well, go on. Finish it.
All right.
The manager says,
"Can he bat?"
And the trainer answers, "Whoever
heard of a horse that can bat?"
Yeah? Go on.
Oh, forget it.
[ Crowd Cheering ]
Kill him! Kill him!
Hit him on the head! Kill him!
Yes! Go!
Kill him! Kill him!
What?
[ Bell Clangs ]
[music] [ Movie Soundtrack:
Suspenseful ] [ Stairs Creaking ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Movie: Thunderclap ]
I'll be right back.
All right, Ollie.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
[ Movie: Thunderclap ]
[ Shouting, indistinct ]
[ Blow Lands ]
Oh!
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Blow Lands ]
[ Movie: Explosions ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
'Saw
[ Giggling ]
You-
Ah, yes.
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Excuse me.
[ Thunder Continues ]
Johnny, what happened to you?
Our show is a very big success.
It is?
Oh, very big.
I think we close tonight.
Oh.
[ Movie: Dog Barking ]
[ Laughing ]
Johnny Spanish-wonderful chap.
And he's in love with you.
That's what he told me.
Mm-hmm.
And Kitty and I-Well, she makes
me laugh. [ Mock Laughing ]
Anyway, Johnny and I-Well, we
decided to make it up between us.
I hope you're
very happy together.
No, seriously.
He's got a big poker game or something
over in Staten Island tonight,
and this time he's positive
his ship is gonna come in.
Mm-hmm. Like the Titanic.
And he's gonna call you tomorrow.
Hmph.
He doesn't hold anything
against us.
As a matter of fact, he feels...
Why don't you just come out
and say what you mean?
Well,
as Dorothy Parker once said
to her boyfriend...
[music] Fare thee well [music]
Mm-hmm.
As Columbus announced
when he knew he was bounced...
[music] It was swell, Isabelle
Swell [music]
Yeah, but... [music] As Abelard
said to Heloise [music]
[music] Don't forget to drop a line
to me, please [music]
You mean-[music] As Juliet
cried in her Romeo's ear;
[music] "Romeo, why not face
the fact, my dear?" [music]
Sure.
[music] It was just one
of those things [music]
[music] Just one of those
crazy flings [music] Mm-hmm.
[music] One of those bells
that now and then ring [music]
Just... one of those things.
That's right.
[music] It was just
one of those nights [music]
[music] Just one of those
fabulous flights [music]
[music] A trip to the moon
on gossamer wings [music]
[music] Just one of those things [music]
Taxi!
[music] If we'd thought a bit
about the end of it [music]
Take me home. [music] When we
started painting the town [music]
[music] We'd have been aware
that our love affair [music]
[music] Was [music]
Too hot...
not to cool down.
[music] So good-bye, dear,
and amen [music]
[music] Here's hoping
we meet now and then [music]
[music] It was great fun [music]
[music] But it was just one [music]
[music] Oi those 'Mugs [music]
I wonder which is which.
Excuse me?
No, I won't.
Now, really, Elizabeth. I don't see why you continue
to blame me for the actions of my employer.
After all,
it's none of our affair.
You watch your words, junior,
unless you want a fat lip.
I didn't mean-I know what you meant.
You know what he meant, don't ya?
[ Squawks ]
Don't exert yourself, Mertle.
She's probably hungry. I'll take
care of my bird. Thanks a lot.
All right.
[ Sighs ]
[ Clears Throat ]
Just drive, curly.
Just drive.
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
Right through there, boys.
Hello.
Are you here? It's Johnny. No!
That's what I thought.
She says she's not here.
No kiddin'.
Brooke, he says he's won
a half-a-million-dollar pot!
"Congralutations."
She says, "Congralutations."
He wants to know
if you want to help him spend it.
I'm not here.
[ Glass Clatters ]
She's not here.
Okay. Sorry, Johnny.
Good-bye.
Okay. The show's over, boys.
Beat it.
You look like you ain't et in a week.
Ain't ya hungry?
Huh?
Did you see the paper?
Your pal bought
a new horse for Kitty,
but Rod says she's not
answering her phone neither.
[ Whining, Shouts ]
Yeah, I thought you'd like it.
Well, I got a reaction anyway.
I'm glad to see you ain't blind yet.
Order more champagne.
Oh, come on, honey!
Ain't you had enough?
No guy is worth this.
What guy?
I'm just an "alhocolic."
All right.
[ Bottle Clatters ]
Well, I'll order some more up for you,
but first I gotta wash up a little...
and feed Mertle.
She's starving.
I'll be right back.
Take your time.
[ Mutters ]
Newspapers.
People buying horses.
[ Muttering ]
It's disgusting.
Silliest thing I ever heard.
Newspapers are-
[ Muttering ]
Oh.
[music] My story is much too sad
to be told [music]
[music] But practically
everything [music]
[music] Leaves me totally cold [music]
[music] The only
exception I know [music]
[music] Is the case [music]
[music] When I'm out on
a quiet spree [music]
[music] Fighting vainly
the old ennui [music]
[music] And I suddenly
turn and see [music]
[music] Your fabulous [music]
[music] Face [music]
[music] I get no kick
from champagne [music]
[music] Mere alcohol
doesn't thrill me at all [music]
[music] So tell me,
why should it be true [music]
[music] That I get a kick
out of you? [music]
[music] Some get a kick
from cocaine [music]
[music] I'm sure that if
I took even one sniff [music]
[music] That would bore me
terrifically too [music]
[music] Yet I get a
kick out of you [music]
[music] I get a kick
every time I see you [music]
[music] Standing there before me [music]
[music] I get a kick
though it's clear to me [music]
[music] You obviously don't [music]
[music] Adore me [music]
[music] I get no kick in a plane;
[music] Flying too high
with some guy in the sky [music]
[music] Is my idea [music]
[music] Of nothing to do [music]
[music] Yet I get a kick [music]
[music] Out of you [music]
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
[ Buzzing Continues ]
I'm coming!
Hold your horses!
What?
Telegram for Miss Carter, madam.
I'm a "miss" too, wise guy.
Oh. No slur intended.
Oh. No tip neither.
Beth, you could have
given him a dime.
Snooks, we ain't got a...
I can't see very well,
but isn't your mouth hanging open?
[ Teeth Click ]
Honey, it is a miracle.
Listen.
"Dear Brooke,"
"Have today wired your bank
one million unsullied American dollars."
"Will write soon.
Love, your sullied mother."
What the hell
does "sullied" mean?
That's British for "Ole."
Oh.
Come on. Get up.
Why?
'Cause we are going to
that old "400" dance tonight.
We are not!
Yes, we are.
I'm tired of you mopin' around.
I haven't got anything to wear!
You've got
a million dollars, dummy.
What's a million dollars
without love?
It ain't hay, Snooks.
[ Squawks ]
[ Car Horns Honking ]
Come on, children. Come on.
[ Children Shouting ]
Tony will be-
Could you please help?
Come on, Alexander.
We'll go home soon.
Mommy!
No!
[ Honking Continues ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
This is very cute.
Miss?
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Oh, do you want this?
You got it.
Excuse me, miss.
Could you come over here, miss?
[ Continues, indistinct ]
[ Horns Honking ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
[ Vehicles Passing ]
Brooke, you've gone bananas.
It ain't hay, Snooks.
[ Squawks ]
[ Chattering ]
Brookski?
Kathy!
[ Both Whining, Wailing ]
[ Crying Continues ]
I'm so sorry.
I ruined everything.
Oh, no, no. It's not your fault.
We can't blame a soul.
I can think of
a couple of heels.
You don't hate me?
Are you kidding?
P.S...
1-2-2!
[ Crying ]
Oh, come on, you two.
Cut it out.
Trouble is, nobody ever learned you
the facts of life. Shove over.
[music] When Mummy
in her sixteenth year [music]
[music] Was dreaming of romance
a lot [music]
[music] She thought
that she was Guinevere [music]
[music] And every boy
Sir Lancelot [music]
Sir Lancelot.
Guinevere.
Come on in.
This is free.
[music] But now that Mummy's
more mature [music]
[music] And knows her way about [music]
[music] She don't believe
in "Vive l'amour" [music]
[music] For Mummy's found out;
[music] Most gentlemen
don't like love [music]
[music] They just like to
kick it around [music]
[music] Most gentlemen
can't take love [music]
[music] 'Cause most gentlemen
can't be profound [music]
[music] As Madam Sappho [music]
[music] In some sonnet said [music]
[music] A slap and a tickle
is all that the fickle male [music]
[music] Ever has in his head [music]
[music] Most gentlemen
don't like love [music]
[music] They just like to
kick it around [music]
[music] So just remember;
What?
[music] When you get that glance [music]
What is this?
[music] A romp and a quickie [music]
Oh!
[music] Is all little
Dickie means [music]
[music] When he mentions romance [music]
That's right.
[ All Grunt ]
Take that!
And that!
[ Grunts ]
[music] In every land, children [music]
What?
[music] They're all the same [music]
Yes.
[music] A pounce in the clover [music]
[music] Then when it's over [music]
[music] "So long and
what is your name?" [music]
Follow me!
Up. One, two, three, four
five, six, seven, eight.
[music] Most gentlemen
don't like love [music]
[music] They just like to-[music]
[music] Most gentlemen [music]
[music] Can't be profound [music]
[music] So if your boyfriend
some fine night should say;
[music] He'll love you forever;
[music] Part from you never [music]
[music] Just push mm
out oi the hay [music]
[ Women ]
Yeah!
[music] 'Cause most gentlemen
don't like love [music]
[music] We've been in love [music]
[music] And we know what
we're talking about;
[music] Oh, to our woe [music]
[music] We have found out;
Let's hear it!
[ All ]
[music] They just like to slap it;
[music] They just like
to squeeze it [music]
[music] They just like to
bounce it around [music]
[music] They just like to [music]
[music] Kick it around [music]
[ Screaming, Chattering ]
Hey, Brooke. Let's go for a walk.
Yeah, okay.
Beth, you'll see about the stuff?
Oh, sure. You two go ahead.
[ Chattering ]
Hello?
Get me Murray Hill 4-1599, please.
Charge it to Brooke Carter.
Hello, Rod?
Now listen very carefully,
meathead.
[ Barking ]
Ridiculous.
I feel better already.
I mean, let's just go back.
And we're gonna dance with
a different sucker every dance.
And flirt with them all.
Make 'em all suffer.
Yeah.
He can't even speak English.
I know.
He reads the funny papers.
Gambles like a fool.
I know.
He snores.
He loves me.
I know.
[ Sighs ]
[ Children Shouting ]
Well, he's completely irresponsible.
I know.
And terribly lazy.
He drinks much too much.
I know.
He snores.
He loves me.
I know.
Isn't it silly?
[music] The gods who nurse this universe
think little of mortals' cares [music]
[music] They sit in crowds
on exclusive clouds [music]
[music] And laugh
at our love affairs [music]
[music] I might have had
a real romance [music]
[music] If they'd given me
a chance [music]
[music] I love him [music]
[music] But he didn't love me [music]
[music] I wanted him [music]
[music] But he didn't want me [music]
[music] Then the gods
had a spree [music]
[music] And indulged in
another whim [music]
[music] Now he loves me [music]
[music] But I don't love him [music]
[music] I told this tale
with its weary wail [music]
[music] To several devoted wives [music]
Really?
[music] They said, "You're young
You have simply sung" [music]
[music] "The story of
all our lives" [music]
[music] So maybe
there are couples here [music]
[music] Who have had
the same career [music]
[music] You loved him [music]
[music] But he didn't love you [music]
[music] You wanted mm [music]
[music] But he didn't want you [music]
[music] Then the gods
saw you two [music]
[music] And indulged in
another whim [music]
[music] Now he loves you [music]
[music] But you don't love him [music]
[music] [ Big Band: "Friendship" ]
There they are.
Come on.
You two go ahead.
Hmm? Oh.
Of course.
Beat it, junior.
Yes, sir.
Well, it took you long enough.
Are those other two bozos here?
Of course.
What are you doin'
in the mornin'?
What did you have in mind?
[ Laughing ]
[music] From being merely
a necessary luxury;
[music] And someone sympathetic
to have about; Mm-hmm.
[music] Why, now you're nearly
a luxurious necessity [music]
[music] I couldn't imagine
ever living without [music]
Oh, yeah?
[music] I suppose I could somehow
struggle through [music] Mm-hmm.
[music] But I hate to picture myself
without you [music]
Flummery.
It's all flummery.
[music] Picture Henry Ford
without a car;
[music] Picture heaven's firmament
without a star [music]
[music] Picture Fritzy Kreisler
without a fiddle [music] Tsk, tsk.,
[music] Picture poor Philadelphia
without a Biddle [music]
[music] Picture Central Park
without a sailor [music]
[music] Picture Mr. Lord
minus Mr. Taylor;
[music] Mix them all together
and what do you got? [music]
[music] Just a picture of me
without you [music]
[ Sighing ]
[music] Picture Ogden Nash
without a rhyme [music]
[music] Picture Mr. Bulova
without the time [music]
[music] Picture Staten Island
without a ferry [music]
[music] Picture little George Washington
without a cherry [music]
[music] Picture brother Cain
without his Abel [music]
[music] Picture Pritchard here
minus Mother Mabel [music]
[music] Mix them all together
and what have you got? [music]
[ Men ] Yes? [music] Just a
picture of you without me [music]
[ Together ]
Oh, no.
[music] Picture Paul Revere [music]
[ Mike, Johnny ]
[music] Without a horse [music]
[music] Picture love
in Hollywood [music]
[music] Without divorce [music]
Yeah.
[music] Picture Barbara Hutton
without a nickel [music]
[music] Picture poor Mr. Heinz, my dear,
without a pickle [music]
[ Laughs ] [music] Picture a good
cigar without Havana [music]
[music] Picture Huey Long
less Louisiana [music]
[ All ] [music] Mix them all together
and what have you got? [music]
[music] Just a picture of me
without-[music]
[music] You without [music]
[music] Me without [music]
[music] You without me [music]
[music] Me [music]
[music] Just a picture of me
without you [music]
[ Applauding ]
[ Laughing ]
Change partners!
[music] [ Band: Intro ]
[music] [ Waltz ]
She is lovely, no?
She is lovely, yes.
I think she is more lovelier now
than ever I see her.
Yep.
Isn't she beautiful?
She sure is.
I think she's more beautiful now
than I've ever seen her.
Mm-hmm.
[music] [ Music Box ]
[music] [ Slows ]
[music] I Stops 1
[music] [ Orchestra: Medley ]
[music] [ Ends ]