[ People chattering ]
[ Girl ]
Merry christmas!
[ Woman #1 ]
Oh, happy holidays!
[ Woman #2 ]
Happy holidays!
[ Man ]
Happy hanukkah.
[ Chattering continues ]
[ Woman #3 ]
Happy christmas to you too!
Hurry, gladys.
I'm coming.
Wow!
Cool trains.
[ Whistle tooting ]
Mm-hmm!
[ Blows nose ]
Excuse me!
[ Grunting, gasping ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Crash ]
[ Woman ]
Are you are all right?
Hey!
Close the lid!
What are you doin'?
You're lettin'
the heat out!
You're draggin' it.
I got it.
You're draggin' it!
I got it!
Whoa! Hyah!
[ Quacking ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Chuckling ]
[ Kissing ]
♪Deck The Halls
With boughs of holly ♪
♪Fa-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la ♪
♪'Tis The Season
To be jolly ♪
Hi, guys! How are you?
Merry christmas to you!
[ Bell ringing ]
Merry christmas
to ya!
[ Shouting, chattering ]
Ho-ho-ho-ho!
Why, if I live to be 102,
I'll never forget the year
that the muppets
almost missed christmas.
An icy storm blew in,
and I--
hey, buddy. What are you doin'?
We're tryin' to make
a movie over here.
Why, I'm joe snow,
your affable,
good-natured narrator.
[ Chuckling ]
Snowman narrator?
We don't have
no snowman narrator.
Now get out of the shot,
you burl ives wannabe.
What, no snowman narrator?
Well, that's
a big mistake.
I'm part of
the whole holiday
collective consciousness.
I'll have my attorneys see you--
frog, slush and snow cohen.
♪ [ Piano ]
♪Hey, Jingle Bells ♪
♪Jingle Bells ♪
Yeah!
♪Jingle All The Way ♪
♪Oh, What Fun
It is to ride ♪
♪In A One-horse Open Sleigh ♪
♪Hey, Jingle Bells
Jingle bells ♪
[ Muttering ]
♪Jingle All The Way ♪
[ Laughing ]
Yeah!
♪ [ Continues ]
♪ [ Humming ]
Gonzo, I sold my collection
of rare cheese...
To buy you
this crystal petri dish
for your mold collection.
Oh.
Um, gee, rizzo,
I sold my mold collection...
To buy you this
diamond-tipped
cheese slicer.
Did you save the receipt?
♪And A-making Spirits
Bright ♪
Yeah! Ha-ha!
♪What Fun It Is
To ride and sing ♪
[ Squeaks ]
♪A Sleighing Song
Tonight ♪
Beakie, you sold
your periodic table
of the elements...
Autographed
by stephen hawking...
To buy me this stand
for my electron microscope?
Meep.
Oh, but I sold
my electron microscope...
To buy you these rare
mutagenic elements.
Oh! Oh!
But don't open it.
Ohh!
[ Whimpering ]
[ Gasps echoing ]
♪A Sleighing Song
Tonight ♪
♪Oh, Jingle Bells
Jingle bells ♪
♪Jingle All The Way ♪
Johnny, my best friend
in the whole wide world,
I sold my moped to buy you
this solid gold record player.
Well, thanks, sal.
♪Oh, What Fun
It is to ride ♪
♪In A One-horse
Open sleigh ♪
Big jerk.
♪ [ Scatting ]
Hey, there he is.
Hey, come on,
sing a song with me, baby.
I don't feel like
singing right now.
What?
Yeah, he doesn't feel like
singing with you. Right, kermit,
my new best friend in the world?
Oh, kermie. Mistletoe.
Here we go, rowlf.
♪Sleighing Song Tonight ♪
Leave me alone.
Oh!
Where's
your holiday spirit?
Piggy.
Just one christmas kiss,
hmm?
Piggy!
Would you please
leave me alone!
[ Gasps ]
♪ [ Stops ]
[ Grunting ]
Well--
kermit, what's wrong?
Yeah, your gloomy behavior
would make us wonder
if something bad has happened.
[ Gulps ]
We-- we lost everything.
- huh?
- wow, you're good.
I didn't know
you could read people
like that.
It's a gift.
Like my gold record player.
I'm sorry I convinced
you all to work so hard
and believe in this dream.
It was all for nothing.
- [ All groaning ]
- we lost the money.
We lost the theater.
We've lost everything.
But it'll work out all right,
right, uncle kermit?
I mean,
we'll just all pull together
and everything'll be okay.
Right?
Yeah!
Yeah.
Not this time.
[ Sighs ]
Everybody!
♪Jingle Bells, Jingle Bells ♪
[ All grumbling ]
[ Sighs ]
Kermit!
Help me, I'm stuck!
I can't help you.
I'll ruin your life.
[ Sighs ]
[ Groans ]
Hmm.
Mmm.
[ Shivering ]
How could this happen?
Someone
has got to do something!
Oh, dear.
♪ [ Whistling ]
Oh, glenn, hi.
Um, kermit the frog
has got a real "problemo."
So, you're gonna wanna
send someone down there...
So they can, um, dish out
a little yuletide justice.
Oh, sorry, dan, no can do.
Daniel.
I- I prefer daniel.
Uh, this is a major crisis.
Dan. Danny.
Daniel.
We have strict guidelines...
That define what is
and isn't an emergency.
I can't just dispatch a field
agent without a thorough review
from the subcommittee.
Come on.
You know that.
[ Laughs ]
Listen,
feliz navidad, amigo.
Huh?
♪ [ Whistling ]
[ Daniel ]
Fine.
If you're not gonna do your job,
well, I'm gonna do it for you.
I'm taking kermit's case
t-to the boss.
No, you're not.
Whoa.
H-hey.
Right, you're just gonna
walk into the boss's office
without an appointment.
That's the kind of attitude
that's gonna keep you
in a cubicle, mister.
I don't care.
Kermit deserves justice.
- he's goin' for it!
- no, he's not.
He's gonna do it.
I bet he's gonna do it.
Troublemaker.
[ All chattering ]
[ Glenn ]
What's next?
We're all gonna wear color?
Wait.
Oh.
He's not gonna.
Nope. Nope.
No.
It's called fronting off.
The young folks
told me about this.
He did it.
♪ [ Chorus Vocalizing ]
Career suicide.
[ Deep voice booming ]
Who dares disturb my peace?
[ Yelps ]
[ Echoes ]
[ Normal voice ]
Don't you just love
the big voice? It's so scary.
Aah!
[ Gasps ]
What, too big?
No.
A jurassic butterfly.
Whoa, that's cool.
You can really see the beauty
of the compound bug eye.
I think it's too big.
Danny from accounting,
right?
Uh, yeah.
Dani-el.
Daniel.
"Danny-l."
Well, danny-l,
do we have an appointment?
No.
But this is an emergency.
It's about kermit the frog.
Listen, I don't worry about him.
He always does the right thing.
Yeah, well, I'm afraid that
if you don't help him, he may
never do the right thing again.
- what?
- can you please just take a
look at his case, your honor?
Uh, your excellency.
Your bossiness.
I really can't.
I have this appointment
with the archangels.
You know, we're talkin' about
armageddon. We're tryin' to get
streisand for the post party.
You don't know
how much this means to me.
I will never ask
for anything again.
[ Exhales ]
All right, look.
If you can convince me
that kermit needs my help,
I'll send my best agent.
Oh, thank you so much.
But if you can't convince me
that kermit needs my help,
you'll have to transfer
all of my albums to mp3 files.
Well, you have, like,
every album ever recorded.
Ever.
Yeah.
Plus imports.
So you better be right
about kermit.
Have a seat.
What channel?
8-5-7-3-2-9-6,
and then press pound.
Which one is pound? Is
that the tic-tac-toe thing
or the squiggly bug thing?
Tic-tac-toe.
Oh, you do it.
Oh.
Okay.
[ Beeping ]
Uh, I should probably
rewind it a little.
Yeah.
[ AUDIO: Rewinding ]
You know?
And that's why I have
this funny collar!
That's a great story,
kermit.
Aw, thanks.
You're funny.
Aw.
Listen, kermit, I wanna talk
about your big holiday show
that's coming up.
- tell everybody about that.
- yeah, yeah, well, listen,
I'd be happy to.
It's going to be a lot of fun,
and we could really
use the support right now.
Listen, kermit,
I love the muppets.
So I for one will be there
front and center...
At your christmas eve
performance,
and I urge everybody watching
to come to the show too.
- thank you. That's great.
- all right, ladies and
gentlemen, kermit the frog.
Get your tickets now
for the muppet christmas show
starting christmas eve.
Thank you, kermit.
Thank you, carson.
Thank you! Thanks, everybody!
See ya at the show!
That went well, kermit.
All that free publicity
should definitely
sell a lot of tickets.
I sure hope so.
Oh! I'd better
go work on my act.
Oh, that's true.
I've seen it, yes.
Oh, sure. Sure.
Ooh! Who is this
little carson daly?
What?
He is so now, he's so today.
[ Gonzo ]
I know.
- he's so cute!
- excuse me, but who are you?
Bonjour.
Je m'appelle luc fromage.
What?
But I am not stinky
like the cheese.
No, no, it-it's
a different sort
of smell.
While you were out doing
all your promotional stuff,
yeah?
I hired luc to help us
with the big musical number.
Oh. Hmm.
He worked
with cirque du soleil.
Just a littl.
Un peu.
And he speaks french.
I took your little
"12 days of christmas"...
Yeah?
And I made them
into this--
this great--
vehicle.
Vehicle.
[ Imitates horn ]
Whoo-whoo!
Into the journey
of the soul.
But not this soul
or this sole.
Well, no, no, no.
The deep place.
The deep soul.
Very deep.
Well, I can't wait
to see it.
"Cirque du so lame"?
I don't think we want the word
"lame" in the title.
It is not lame.
You are lame. It is lamé.
Lamé?
Lamé, like
the shiny fabric.
Yeah, oh, okay, okay, lamé.
Right.
Yeesh.
Un, deux, trois!
Let the magic begin!
♪ [ Orchestra ]
[ Whispers ]
Yeah!
[ Gonzo ] yeah.
Ohhhhh, wah!
♪ [ Humming ]
Whoo! Whoo!
- whoo!
- [ Groans ]
It speaks
to your essence, no?
No!
You're gonna love
the five golden rings.
The wh--
gonzo to scooter.
Gonzo to scooter.
Bring home the bacon, over.
10-4.
Bacon down, bacon down.
- roger.
- would you hurry up?
- [ Grunting ]
- don't make me Miss my cue.
The ham is jammed.
Repeat. The ham is jammed.
- [ Grunting ]
[ Yelling ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Yelling continues ]
Hang on!
[ Yelling ]
[ Fromage ]
I love the chaos!
- I love the chaos!
- [ Groans ]
- [ Yelling continues ]
Oh, my nose.
Oh!
[ Sighs ]
♪ [ Ends ]
Yes! Yes!
Bravo! Bravo!
Mwah! Mwah! Mwah!
Luc,
you're a genius!
Oh! Yes!
Bravo!
Yes!
So, what do ya think,
kermit?
Uh, eh-eh-eh-eh, well,
it's-- it's not really
what I was hoping for.
What?
Are you blind?
Are you blind
in your little
froggy eyes?
W-well, look, luc,
I-i-i appreciate all
the work you've put in here.
It's just that
our christmas show
is days away...
And, well, I don't even know
what this is.
This is a metaphor
for the winter solstice.
The dark side
of christmas!
[ Groans ]
Pathos and the dark side
of christmas?
[ Gonzo ] it's a metaphor.
No, luc, w-we want our show to
focus on the joy of christmas.
You would.
You're a little frog.
[ Spits ]
I quit!
[ Stammers ]
Whoa.
Now what?
That was our big opening number.
What'll we replace it with?
I don't know,
but we better come up
with something quick.
[ Cackling ]
Oh! Geez!
I'll do
my boomerang fish.
I throw them away,
and they come back to me.
[ Boomerang slicing
through air ]
[ Both yell ]
[ Laughing ]
Gee, lew, I don't know.
It's kind of lacking
in a christmas theme.
Okay. Rita! Murray!
Where are you?
We got pizza here!
Who wants pizza?
Pizza? Count me in.
Hey, johnny,
check out rizzo's nose.
What's that?
It's so shiny,
you could even say
it glows.
[ All grumbling ]
[ Laughing ]
Check this one out.
Hey, nosetradamoose.
Can you predict the future
with that thing?
Knock it off, will ya?
I got feelings too, you know.
Yeah, just not
in your nose.
[ Laughing ]
Let's see-- shiny nose,
laughing and calling names.
I've got it!
Meet the new star
of the christmas show,
frosty the snow rat!
Uh, gee, gonzo, I thought
you would have gone for
rizzo the red-nosed rat deer.
Oh, sure, if you wanna
go for the obvious.
♪ [ Scatting ]
Ha-ha-ha!
This business
is in business, okay?
Oh, yeah?
I got the health permit.
I got the fire permit,
the permit to operate
a topless nightclub.
What? What?
All the
contracts--
- wait a minute. A permit for
a topless nightclub?
- better safe than sorry, okay?
Good point.
So, "kermin,"
I will need a ticket
to Miami, okay?
A-a ticket to Miami?
Why?
Ah, well, I have been invited
to shake my bonbons...
At ricky martin's
south beach christmas party,
okay?
[ Gonzo ] cool.
Ha-ha!
♪ [ Vocalizing ]
Uh, well, I-- I don't know
what to tell ya, pepe,
but, um, we're flat broke.
[ Woman ]
Oh, hello!
Hello, "muffins"!
[ Kermit ]
Uh, hello?
[ Gonzo ] hi.
[ Pepe ]
Hola.
Hi!
Rachel bitterman, new owner of
bitterman bank and development.
Oh. Well, where's
Mr. Bitterman?
- dead.
- [ Gasps ]
Dead?
O-oh, my goodness.
I-i'm sorry.
Is there anything
we can do for you?
Yes, as a matter of fact,
there is.
You can pay me the considerable
debt you owe me, in full,
by midnight of the 24th,
or vacate this theater.
Uh, but-but-but the 24th
is christmas eve.
Yes.
It also happens to be
the due date
for payment on the theater.
It's funny how one day can mean
so many different things.
But-but we had a deal
with Mr. Bitterman.
You see, he said we could
extend the contract and pay him
after the whole week of shows.
Oh. Yeah.
That's right.
Mm-hmm.
Too bad you don't have
anything in writing.
Contracts.
What are ya gonna do?
But-but-but christmas eve--
that only gives us time
to do one show.
And how is that
my problem?
Oh!
It isn't.
Well,
uh, m-ms. Bitterman,
we've worked so hard.
Owning this theater
is our dream.
Working for a dream.
That's beautiful.
My employees
work for a salary.
Salaries?
I-is this like monies?
Yes, pumpkin.
And if you ever feel like
working for monies
instead of stardust,
you just let me know.
Okay, so, if you need
boxes for the move,
you could check the back
of the liquor store.
Well, we're gonna
get you that money.
Yeah, when pigs fly.
[ Shrieking ]
Get the rope!
Whoa-whoa-whoa!
[ Shouting ]
[ Crashing ]
For the record,
I consider
that flying pig...
To be a coincidence
and not a sign from god.
Eh, ma'am? Ma'am?
I want to work for monies
instead of stardust, okay?
You said to let you know.
Oh.
But what
about our dream, pepe?
"Kermin," I must think of
ricky martin and his dream
to salsa with pepe.
And she's hot.
[ Bitterman ]
Welcome...
To bitterman bank
and development.
Gracias.
Starbucks run?
Sí, sí.
Do you know, I like my coffee
like I like my women. A latte!
Oh! Oh!
[ Laughing ]
Hmm.
[ Pepe ]
Do you know, I was talking
to my fabulous--
[ Sighs ]
Wow.
See what I'm
talking about?
Yeah.
Cup of joe sounds good
right about now.
How do you have coffee
in a bush?
Shrub.
It's a shrub.
When you write the laws
of the universe, you know
where all the loopholes are.
Hence, I created
a coffee shrub.
Anyway--
[ Scoffs ]
I can't believe
what bitterman did.
It's-- it's so immoral.
It's just--
it's unfair.
It's immoral, it's unfair.
Why do you care about
kermit's credit problems?
Just, please, keep watching.
I-i promise
you'll want to help kermit.
All right,
I'll keep watching.
You're just lucky spongebob
isn't on right now.
I love spongebob.
Do I care?
Christmas is ruined.
What are we going to do?
It would take a miracle
to save the theater!
♪ [ Harp ]
Huh?
Oops, sorry.
Like, I was totally
just tuning up my harp.
Well, you know-- you know, guys,
l-let's not assume the worst.
I-i mean, maybe we'll be okay.
[ Sighs ]
[ Beaker ]
Mee-mee-mee-mee-mee.
Excuse me.
Dr. Honeydew?
Oh, yes?
Could you figure out a way to
raise enough money with one show
to pay ms. Bitterman?
Let's work it out.
Beaker, would you boot up
the old window operating system?
Mee-mo.
Ooh! Mm-hmm.
Aha.
Now, if we let "x"...
Equal the value
of our debt...
And "y" the value
of seating capacity,
it appears
maximum attendance...
Will result in "y"
Being greater than "x."
Mmm? Uh--
oh. Oh.
Yes, beaker?
Mee-mee-mo-mo-mee-mee-mind.
Yes, I think you have
a beautiful mind too.
[ Shrieking ]
So we'll have enough money
to pay off bitterman
bank and development?
Yes. Wait. No.
Uh, yes-- no!
- beakie, do you have
my wax pencil?
- [ Shrieking continues ]
Oh, there it is.
Uh, yes, as long as
we add 1,900 seats.
But-but-but that's
impossible.
Or we don't pay anyone
till new year's.
- well, th-that's not so bad.
- of next year.
[ Dr. Honeydew ]
Beakie?
What it boils down to,
everybody is, uh,
we sort of
have to defer our wages.
- huh?
- [ Gasps ]
For a period
of, um, about a year.
[ All gasping ]
What?
[ Gibberish ]
How will I afford
my propecia?
[ Scooter ]
That's not a toupee?
Look, everybody, I know
it seems like we've already
given everything we can, but...
If we don't give a little more,
we could lose the whole theater.
Our home.
So, what do you say?
[ Case thuds ]
- piggy?
- oh.
Wh-wh-where--
where are you going?
Oh, kermie, I would love to
stay and work for free,
but a Hollywood doctor show
needs a hip young star...
With her finger on the pulse
of today's urban youth.
And, well, naturally,
they called moi.
[ Groans ]
Typical.
I'm sorry.
Well--
all right, peeps,
let's bounce!
Piggy! Piggy, we need
a star for our show too!
- piggy?
- [ Murmuring ]
Okay, fine.
We'll just do our show
without her.
- without her?
- [ Mock swedish ]
[ All murmuring ]
[ Muppet ]
Huh!
- I don't see how
we can do without piggy.
- I'm sorry, guys, it's--
well, I hate to be
materialistic,
but, like, how are we
supposed to have christmas
without any money?
- yeah!
- mee-mee-mee-mee-mee!
[ Mock swedish ]
The words on my coffee mug
are right.
"It is hard to soar with eagles
when you work with turkeys."
Turkeys?
Turkeys? What is that
supposed to mean?
Guys! Guys!
Look at us.
Fighting and being selfish
when kermit has
done so much for us.
We should be ashamed
of ourselves.
[ Murmuring ]
Well--
fozzie's right.
Kermit, I defer my paycheck.
- count me in.
- thanks, scooter.
We're in!
Ya!
- I'm in.
- I'm in too!
- [ Mock swedish ]
- I'm really in.
- all right!
We'll show ms. Bitterman!
When we pull together,
we can do anything. Right?
- yeah!
- [ All shouting in agreement ]
- even if we go broke
doing it!
- huh?
- uh-- uh, gonzo?
- hmm?
You're not helping.
Oh. Sorry.
[ Pepe ]
This little fishy
went to the market,
and, uh,
this little fishy
needs a kiss.
[ Kiss ]
And, uh, this little fishy
looks like my cousin manolo.
Look, pepe. I want you--
oh, I want you
too, okay?
Do not... interrupt me.
I want you to tell me
everything you know about the
muppets' financial situation.
You tell me, bitter, baby.
I give you all the papers
right there, okay?
All the papers?
Sí.
You mean, this is the only copy
of the contract between
the muppets and bitterman bank?
Sí. i needed it to get
all the permits, oka?
[ Groans ]
Hey!
[ Grunting ]
Maybe you should go
with the french tips.
Forget the nails.
[ Groans ]
Listen, pee-pee--
pepe.
Sorry.
Do they know you have
the only copy of the contract?
Ah, well, I cannot answer
this question...
Until we talk about
my christmas bonus, okay?
I love your spirit.
Well--
listen to me,
my little king prawn king.
You answer
this question,
and I'll give you
your christmas bonus.
[ Moans ]
Then tell me.
[ Blows ]
Tell me.
[ Laughing ]
Tell me!
No, they don't know
I have it, okay?
Peel me! I'm yours!
Yes!
File this!
[ Gasping, laughing ]
Rough and sexy, okay.
[ Laughs ]
But tell me, bitterbuns,
why are you so excited about
the muppet theater anyways?
Oh, for heaven sakes,
it's not about the theater.
No, it's about real estate,
it's about making money,
not losing it.
It's about something
like this.
- I call it club dot.
- [ Gasps ]
Ooh! Nice!
[ Cackling ]
[ Gasps ]
Ooh, does it come
with action figures?
No, it doesn't come
with action figures.
It's a scale model
of a trendy nightclub!
Oh, you're
so brilliant.
But, uh, how will the peoples
fit inside? It's so tinies.
I mean, really tinies.
Come.
I'll-- I'll show you.
Huh?
♪Dee-dee-dee ♪
[ Groans ]
I think your club dot is going
to need bigger doors, okay.
♪A-la-la-la-la-la
This is not what I
taught you ♪
♪And It's Really Bad ♪
[ Whooping ]
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop it!
I don't know when I've seen
dancing so... Wonderful.
Yeah?
[ Laughing ]
So, how's it going
here, howard?
Oh, kermit!
Things could not-- mwah--
be-- mwah-- better--
mwah-- period.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, is it possible
to give 110%?
Because that's what I'm
getting from these girls.
Well, great.
Well, listen.
Keep up the good work, huh?
Okay, okay.
Love that tushy.
[ Giggles ]
[ Laughing ]
Okay, you clodhoppers.
Let's go.
Five, six, seven, eight.
♪La-la-- ♪
♪Ra-rumph
Rumph-ba-ba-bum
rumph-ba-bum ♪
Drummer boy!
Ah. That was, uh--
[ Clears throat ] loud.
Uh, everybody
take five, huh?
Gee, I don't know.
It seems like the show's
still missing something.
I know!
I'll do my boomerang fish!
Thank you, lew.
Thank you. Mm-hmm.
No, thanks.
Sorry, gretchen.
Oh.
I don't know.
What do you think, fozzie?
What does the show need?
Gosh, kermit.
Maybe what the show needs...
Is somebody who'll make people
feel like they got
their money's worth.
- mmm.
- you know, somebody
with star power.
Yeah?
I know, uncle kermit.
You should call
your famous friends.
You're right, robin.
To the star phone!
Right, right.
Listen. We are all big fans.
I watch you every morning.
We were wondering if you'd come
out and star in our christmas
show at the muppet theater.
I don't know, kermit,
I was planning on spending
the holidays with my loved ones.
Well, good golly,
Miss molly.
You are such a big star, it
would be an honor if you would
come out and be in our show.
Let me remind you
about the last time
I worked with a frog.
We fell madly in love.
So naturally,
I have a key made
to his apartment.
I break in and reorganize
his closets while he's at work
as a little favor.
And how am I rewarded
for going to all this trouble?
The frog
stops calling me!
Remember that?
Hey there, madonna.
Want a free muppet t-shirt?
Courtney, can you juggle?
Uh, thanks, Mr. Connery.
Uh, I understand,
Mr. Schwarzenegger.
Hello, Mr. Rogers?
Hello, angelina?
Oh, hi there, britney.
Hello, nicole?
Um, gee, I could sure do
with a little star power
around here, uh, triumph.
Um, is there any way
you could help me out?
Muppet movies
are always the best.
You mean that?
For me to poop on!
[ Laughing ]
Right, right.
You got me again.
Uh, uh, bye-bye.
- hey, guys, he's comin'.
- [ Chattering ]
Sorry, everybody.
No luck finding a star.
[ Groaning ]
Oh, well.
Sure you can't find anyone
now, but just watch.
The day after christmas--
hmm?
All these stars will
be marked down 40%.
Yeah, but don't give up, guys.
You know, may--
I'm sure someone
will come through.
Someone like, um--
- oh, I don't know.
Just somebody.
- hmm? Hmm?
You know,
somebody will, uh--
yeah?
Like, uh--
uh-- all right, all right.
I'll go get her.
Yes!
All right!
Do we have a rhythm?
Can't find a pulse.
Quick, the paddles!
Let's go.
Clear!
[ Steady beep ]
Nothing.
All righty.
Let's call it.
Time of death, 8:27 AM.
Oh. I-i think
I'm feeling better.
The shocky things worked!
I'm alive!
No, you're dead.
No, I'm alive!
No, you're dead!
I'm alive!
- it's a miracle.
- cut. Cut!
- [ buzzing ]
- what do you think
you're doing?
- it's called acting, sweetie.
- you're an extra.
You're supposed to be
a dead body.
Look, I didn't quit
the legitimate theater to play
some lump under a dumb sheet.
I was thinking my character
could start dating JD.,
then become a nurse
with attitude.
You'd have to go.
Guess again, puerca.
Oh. All right.
Uh-- oh, I know!
I'll be the cute janitor.
Yes, yes, the cute janitor
who works her way up
to head of hospital.
We just have to lose
frankenstein over there.
- [ Growls ]
- excuse me. Pardon me.
Kermie? Wha--
piggy, our show
really needs you.
We really need a star.
Would you please, please
consider coming back?
Oh, kermie.
I'm afraid
I'm must see tv now.
Scrubs needs me.
Yeah. Miss piggy?
Yes, billy?
You're fired.
I'm sorry.
What did he say?
I think he said you're fired.
- gone.
- canned.
- shalom.
- fired? Fired?
You wouldn't know talent
if it hit you in the eye!
Uh-oh.
And it's about to too!
Okay, guys.
I'll take it from here.
Sorry about that, Mr. Lawrence.
Piggy, let's go, okay?
Fine. I quit! I'm a real
theater actress anyhow,
not some spoiled tv showoffs.
Just a little boost,
guys.
Oh, you got it.
Thank you. Thanks.
Thank you, guys.
Naturally, kermie,
as your star, I have
the following demands.
Yeah.
A fresh fruit plate.
Nothing frozen.
[ Grunting ]
Ah, pepe.
My heart is hot...
Like a black car
left in the sun
on a summer's day.
I must have you now.
[ Gasps ]
Oh, rachel.
Oh, pepe!
Mmm.
[ Man ]
So, rachel.
[ Rachel ]
Call me ms. Bitterman.
Okay, ms. Bitterman.
- ms. Bitterman,
I'm just not exactly clear--
- [ Pepe ] huh?
Another mans?
I will crush him
like a plankton, okay.
So, um,
what will you do...
If the muppets
come up with the money
before the deadline?
Come,
my sweet potato brain.
The answer is here.
If the others are as stupid
as that backstabbing shrimp,
they'll never notice that
I've changed the contract...
From midnight to 6:00 PM.
[ Chuckling ]
Right.
Changed the contract.
I don't get it.
Look, the old contract,
the deadline was midnight.
The new contract,
the deadline is 6:00 PM.
At 6:01, I foreclose
on the muppet theater,
gut it and put up
a trendy nightclub...
Where I can sell
overpriced drinks...
To pierced and tattooed
rave monkeys.
[ Laughing ]
Rave monkeys.
Come, einstein.
Let's go decorate my tree.
Right.
Decorate your tree.
[ Groaning ]
And tomorrow you can oil
that chair for me.
Right. Oil your chair.
You know, not everything
is an innuendo.
Innuendo.
[ Grunts, panting ]
What have I done?
I must warn kermit.
Mmm.
[ Grunts ]
Ay.
[ Thuds ]
[ Chattering ]
- [ Statler ]
Yeah. Okay. Here's your one.
- the muppets?
- uh-huh. Got it right here.
Yeah. Thanks.
- two tickets, please.
Get on in there.
Okay, here ya go.
Mr. Kermit! Mr. Kermit!
Oh. Ooh!
I have excellent news.
Oh, yeah?
We have sold enough tickets
to cover our debt.
Oh, good!
Hey, everybody,
gather round!
Oh, boy. Uh, listen, everybody.
Before we go out there,
I just want to thank you all
for sticking together.
Because of all your
hard work and dedication,
we've made enough money
to save the theater!
[ Cheering ]
Let's go out there
and have a great show, huh?
Nice work, guys.
And because
I love you all...
Like cousins I no longer
keep in touch with,
tonight I dedicate
my performance to vous.
Give us a kiss
for good luck, kermie.
Uh, well, I--
fifteen seconds
to curtain, boss.
Got a show starting!
I'll take a rain check, piggy.
Thank you, scooter.
What?
Sure. Anytime.
Places, everybody!
Places, places.
Scooter!
- where you headed, sister?
- kermit, kermit!
I must warn you, okay?
Oh, dios mío.
Gee, pepe, shouldn't you be
in Florida with ricky martin?
No, no, no, no. Listen, because
the words I'm about to say
are very important, okay?
Okay. I'm listening.
You listening?
I'm listening.
You are sure? Because
this is very big, okay.
Pepe, the show's
about to start!
Left, right, left, right,
left, right, left, right!
Okay.
First of all,
she cheats on me
with another man.
Oh, good grief.
Okay. And then the dollhouse.
You know the dollhouse?
- yeah, yeah.
- it's not a dollhouse!
It's a nightclub!
Really? Hmm.
Imagine that.
And ms. Bitterman,
while very sexy, is dishonest.
Left, right, left, right!
She changed the c--
k-kermit!
[ Squeals ]
Great.
Left, right, left, right.
Oh, boy.
Now let's see. Um--
cue the intro!
Boss?
You are the intro.
What? Oh, good grief!
[ Man announcing ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
kermit the frog!
[ Cheering ]
Ha-ha!
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Ah. Oh, boy.
Thank you very much, ladies
and gentlemen, and welcome to
the muppet christmas show.
[ Scattered applause ]
Now at this time,
we'd like to ask you...
To please turn off
all cell phones and pagers.
[ Phones beeping ]
[ Beeping continues ]
- I think it's off.
- [ Beeps ]
[ Beeps twice ]
Okay. Thank you. Now--
- [ Beeping ]
- [ Kermit groans ]
Merry christmas, everyone!
It's showtime!
[ Applauding ]
♪There Was A Frog ♪
♪A Very Strange
Enchanted frog ♪
♪And He Came To France Where
The ladies cancan dance ♪
[ Whooping ]
♪To The Moulin Scrooge
Where our story starts
for you ♪
[ Pepe ]
Wait, donner.
Stop, schnitzel.
[ Grunts, panting ]
Kermit.
Whoa! Aha.
Kermit, please,
I must--
my, my.
It sure is a nice christmas here
in paris in the year 1900.
I'm sure I'll find
the inspiration I need
to write about love...
Here in this fancy
red windmill.
Ooh, but first,
I think I'll try this
funny green root beer.
Ooh.
Ahh.
Hi! I'm the green fairy.
Well, what are you
doing in my drink?
The backstroke. Ah!
And now, get ready...
For a magnificent, opulent,
stupendous, tremendous,
gargantuan
spectacular spectacular!
- [ Shouting ]
- get ready for moulin scrooge!
♪ [ Pop ]
♪ [ Clucking Rhythmically ]
♪ [ Quacking Rhythmically ]
[ Pepe ]
Kermit! Kermit!
It's very important.
[ Gasps ]
Unbelievable, okay?
Oof!
Aah!
When the beautiful saltine,
the sparkling zirconia diamond,
saw this stranger,
she knew what she wanted
for christmas,
and it was green.
[ Whimpers ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
presenting the star of our show,
the beautiful, stunning,
exotic, voluptuous saltine!
- saltine!
- [ Crowd gasps ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Coughing continues ]
Whoa!
Bonsoir, mes amis.
[ Exhales ]
Come and get me, boys.
[ Laughing ]
♪Santa Baby ♪
♪Slip A Sable
Under the tree ♪
♪For Me ♪
♪I've Been
An awful good girl ♪
♪Santa Baby ♪
♪And Hurry Down
The chimney tonight ♪
Let's pick it up a little!
♪Come And Trim
My christmas tree ♪
♪With Some Decorations
Bought at tiffany's ♪
♪I Really Do
Believe in you ♪
♪Let's See If You
Believe in me too ♪
Kermit, I--
what?
- uh--
- [ Pepe chuckles ]
Uh, doobie-do?
[ Grunts ]
♪Jingle Bells, Jingle Bells
Jingle all the way ♪
What?
♪When You Come
To moulin scrooge, you stay
you've gotta pay, yeah ♪
♪ [ Clucking Rhythmically ]
[ Miss piggy ]
Where'd you come from?
Hey, this is my big number!
♪So If You're Feeling Plucky ♪
♪Our Chickens Are Just Ducky
At the moulin scrooge ♪
[ Miss piggy ]
Coming through!
Move it! Move it!
♪It's Christmas Every Day
As long as you can pay ♪
Out of the way!
♪And-- ♪
Stop!
Will everybody stop
singing different songs!
I can't remember which one
I'm supposed to sing!
- [ Angry grunting ]
- excuse me, excuse me.
"Santa baby,"
From "be-do-be-do."
Ah.
Oh, yeah. Right.
♪Be-do-be-do
Santa baby ♪
♪Forgot To Mention
One little thing ♪
♪A Ring ♪
♪I Don't Mean
On the phone ♪
♪Santa Baby
So hurry down
the chimney tonight ♪
♪Hurry Down
The chimney tonight ♪
♪Hurry Tonight ♪
♪ [ Piano ]
♪ [ Ends ]
I'll be waiting up
for you.
[ Giggling ]
Uh, thank you.
There is one present
you can give moi.
Well, what is it,
beautiful saltine?
Vous, froggy.
Hmm?
Vous.
Voulez-vous coucher
avec moi?
Say wha--
♪ [ Ends ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Chickens clucking ]
Boy, that went great.
Kermit, the theater is
in great danger, okay?
Huh?
The contract says--
Ay, i'm exhausted, okay.
Oh, boy.
Kermie, quickly.
What were your 10 favorite
things about my performance?
[ Stammering ]
Well, it's really hard to
narrow it down to just 10.
Oh, kermie!
Yeah, really. Mmm. Hmm?
Try! Start with number 10
and work backward
to your favorite.
Don't you have to change
for your next number?
Oh! My next number!
Oh, yes!
I'm wonderful
in that too.
Of course.
Ay.
Now, pepe,
what is going on?
Okay. You are listening?
Because this is
very important, okay?
Pepe, I'm listening.
Okay, okay.
[ Exhales ]
You must get the monies
to bitterman by 6:00,
not midnight, okay.
Otherwise, we will all
be on the streets, okay.
Wait a second. That's not
what the contract says.
Oh, mira, mira.
Look, look.
What?
- do you see--
- whoa! Hey, wait a second.
She changed
the contract, okay?
You see?
You can see right here.
She's very, very tricky,
okay, kermit.
Wait a minute.
That-- that can't be.
Oh, it does be.
And it's almost 6:00, okay.
[ Gasps ]
"Kermin," unless we do something
fast, ms. Bitterman's going
to take the theater, okay.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
But the joke's on her
'cause we've got the money.
[ Gasp ]
Oh.
Ha-ha!
- yeah, and I'm gonna
take it to her right now.
- okay.
Pastel m&m's?
I said no pastel m&m's!
Kermie, you said you'd treat me
like a star if I came back.
- hmph! How could you?
- but, piggy, it's just a--
comin' through.
[ Chicken clucks ]
Kermit, 6:00.
I gotta get to the bank.
Sí, sí.
Kermit. Maybe I should
go to the bank for you.
No, no.
Fozzie, but what about
your monologue?
You've been working
so hard on it.
This is more important.
Hmm?
And, uh, besides,
it's kind of crazy here.
Sí, sí, sí.
I will fill in
for fozzie, okay.
See, I'm very funny.
Very funny.
Waka waka, okay.
Ah! Not bad!
Gracias, gracias.
Now, are you sure
you're okay missing
your stand-up spot?
Kermit, you have done
so much for us.
Let me do this for you.
Okay, fozzie,
you've got the job.
But now, remember,
this is a very important
job to us.
Kermit!
You can count on me.
Uh, uh, fozzie!
Yeah?
Uh, the money?
Oh! Oh, oh.
Right, right, right, right.
The money. Yes, of course.
Ayayay.
Boy, hope that was
the right thing to do.
Where's fozzie? He's on.
This is me, okay.
[ Announcer ] the comedy
stylings of fozzie bear!
Right, right.
♪ [ Band ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing continues ]
Eh, thank you, thank you.
[ Laughing ]
Okay. [ Clears throat ]
Waka waka, okay.
[ Clears throat ]
What are santa's three favorite
gardening tools, okay?
Hoe, hoe and hoe, okay?
♪ [ DRUM: Rim Shot ]
Hoe, hoe and hoe.
♪ [ Rim Shot ]
This what santa says, okay.
Gardening tools!
Hoe, hoe, hoe!
Hey, the shrimp's
floundering!
[ Laughing ]
You shut up, okay.
[ Audience laughing ]
- he told us to clam up.
- oh, what's he wanna do?
"Mussel" us?
[ Laughing ]
Don't get me steamed, okay.
Steamed shrimp.
Whoa, pass
the cocktail sauce!
Oh, yeah!
[ Laughing ]
That's it!
I'm coming up there!
Whoa, I'm shakin'.
♪ [ Band ]
You're always shakin'.
[ Audience laughing ]
I'm going to the bank.
Gosh, I sure hope they have
a little bear's room there.
[ Australian accent ]
Excuse me, mate!
Wh-wh-what?
Watch your step.
This street is teemin'
with wild crocodiles.
Ah-- there aren't
any crocodiles here.
Are you tellin' me
how to do my job?
No, no, no, no.
It's just that this is a city,
and there aren't any swamps.
Crikey!
You're a bear!
Oh! I'm gonna have to
tranquilize him,
'cause bears get a tad cranky
when they get a bit stressed.
Huh?
[ Screaming ]
Crikey! There he goes!
[ Shouts, panting ]
He's getting away!
Watch out, folks!
Stand back! Come on!
I think he went this way.
Watch out!
There he goes.
[ Panting ]
What? What?
[ Screams ]
He's right there.
These darts are really potent,
so I've gotta get a clean shot.
[ Gasping ]
[ Chuckling ]
Meanwhile, everybody
waited nervously...
For fozzie to get
to the bank.
[ Grunts ]
Well, what's happening?
Wh-what's going on?
Everything
is melding together.
[ Voice slowing down ]
Crikey.
I think I'm going to--
I am.
[ Thuds ]
[ Screams ]
There he goes!
[ Panting ]
What's this? Hmm.
[ Spraying ]
Ow! Ooh. Ow! Hot!
Ow! Hot! Ow, my eyes!
[ Screams ] oh! Ow!
[ Spitting ]
[ Panting ]
Where did he go?
Where'd he go?
[ Exhales ]
Merry christmas!
Ho, ho, ho.
[ Panting ]
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Oh!
Oh!
Oh, you poor thing.
Are you okay?
[ Panting ]
Where's bitterman bank?
Bitterman bank.
Look at you.
You're soaking wet
and freezing.
Here, you take my coat.
[ Girl ]
Look! It's him!
What?
That green guy
who stole christmas...
And ruined
all our wishes!
I'm nancy nut-what
from whatville, you see,
and you've made me
and uncle nicky quite angry.
He'll make sure you don't
steal christmas again...
By making you feel
some serious pain.
Let's get him!
And, uh--
I can't rhyme.
Can't we just go
beat him up?
Yeah, let's go get
that sick green pup!
[ Screams ]
[ Panting ]
Ow! Ooh! Ow!
[ Man ]
Hey.
[ Man #2 ]
Hey, that's a bear!
A bear?
[ All shouting ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Fozzie ]
Hey, where you going?
[ Whimpering ]
Hey!
Anyone here seen that guy
that stole christmas?
He went that way!
Come on! Get him!
There he goes!
He's green,
he's mean, and--
hey!
[ Whimpering ]
Thank you.
Stop, you!
Come back here!
[ Exhales ]
[ Shouts, panting ]
Hello! Hello!
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Screams ]
Where's ms. Bitterman's office?
- what?
- uh, where's ms. Bitterman's
office?
I need to deposit this money.
Well, if I was a bear,
I suppose
I'd deposit my honey in
an old tree somewhere.
No, not honey! Money!
- what?
- money!
I need to give
ms. Bitterman her money!
Oh, ms. Bitterman's
laundry.
Oh, no.
Her offices are
on the 13th floor.
What--
I let her know
you're coming.
- thank you.
- gesundheit.
[ Panting ]
Where's the buttons?
No buttons!
Ah!
[ British accent ]
Oh, what a beautiful
nightclub.
[ Phone ringing ]
What do you want?
[ Normal voice ]
I mean, what do you want?
What? No! Stop him.
No, not stockings.
Stop h--
do not-- never mind.
[ Beeping ]
[ Bell dings ]
Wa-ha-ha!
[ Gasps, gulps ]
Uh-oh.
[ Screams, whimpering ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Blowing, sucking ]
[ Shouting ]
- [ Crackling ]
- ow! Ow! Ooh! Ow! Ow!
Ooh! Ooh!
Ah! Ah! Ah! Ah!
[ Screaming ]
Oh!
Yes!
No!
[ Sighs ]
Oh.
[ Screaming ]
[ Crackling ]
Owie!
[ Grunting ]
So, looks like
the christmas spirit...
Is with the good guys
for a change.
[ Grunts ]
We know the truth
about the contract.
There's nothing in here.
Ha! You mean, nothing
but a pile of cash.
Ahh!
- [ Beeps ]
- no!
[ Panting ]
Now, if you don't mind,
if you could take
your sad self...
Away from here.
You smell
like a burnt couch.
[ Blows ]
[ Gasping ]
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, no.
Yes!
♪ [ Piano ]
[ Honking ]
Chug! Chug! Chug! Chug!
Chug! Chug! Chug!
Nog! Nog!
[ Belches ]
Oh, hey, rizzo.
Listen, you did a great job.
Your nose was a real
bright spot.
Yeah, lucky break.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Belches ]
♪ [ Humming ]
[ Scooter ] great. And
you guys have been dancing
together for a long time?
Yeah. Yeah.
Wait! Hey, girls.
Come back.
My uncle used to
own the theater.
Hey, hey, scooter?
Hmm? Yeah, boss?
Uh, have you
seen fozzie?
No, not since he left.
Hmm. I think I better
go look for him.
And Miss the party?
I'm sure he'll be fine.
Yeah, you're probably right,
but I'd feel better
if I knew for certain.
Hmm.
[ Laughter ]
[ Sighs ]
Fozzie? What happened?
Please tell me
you deposited the money.
Oh, kermit. I--
[ Sighs ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh, fozzie, no.
Oh.
[ Frog ]
Go ahead. Try it. Yeah.
Just put your tongue on it.
[ Little frog ]
Really?
Yeah. Just lick it.
You sure it won't stick?
Of course. Yeah.
No, no. Of course not.
I dare ya.
I double dare ya.
I triple-frog dare ya.
Oh! Hey.
Now you gotta do it.
Yeah.
Oh.
See, it--
[ Gasps ]
[ All laughing ]
Well, good luck
with it.
I'm stuck!
Guess I was wrong.
I'm stuck! Guys, don't leave me.
I'm stuck!
Think, fozzie. Think.
I'm trying.
I'm trying, kermit.
[ Thuds ]
- what happened to you
after you left the theater?
- well,
first the crazy australian
tried to shoot me
with his blowgun.
Then I got painted green,
so people thought
I stole christmas.
Then I ran through
a steam bath and got burnt
by a bunch of lasers.
Fozzie, there's no time
for your stories.
This is serious.
Now, was it ever
out of your hands?
No.
[ Sighs ]
Oh, wait.
Maybe for a second
when I bumped into
santa and his army.
Fozzie, do you realize
that if we don't
find this money,
we'll have lost everything
we've worked for?
Just keep looking.
[ Whimpers ]
Does it help
that I feel really badly?
[ Sighs ]
[ Whimpers ]
Okay. So here are
your holiday bonuses.
Merry christmas.
[ Woman ]
Thank you, ms. Bitterman.
Merry christmas.
Kermit.
Hey!
You gave me
the greatest present of all.
Your theater.
Ms. Bitterman,
you changed the contract.
You can't prove that.
I can't believe you'd do this
on christmas eve.
Huh. By now
I thought you would have
realized I'm the bad guy.
Ms. Bitterman,
why can't you understand
what this theater means to us?
It's our dream.
Your dream?
Mm-hmm.
Please. I mean,
you can't eat a dream.
You can't sell
watered down drinks
from a dream.
You can't be the queen
of a polynesian tribe
in a dream.
Oh, wait. Yes, you can.
Forget that last one.
The point is...
I believe in money,
not dreams.
A life without dreams?
That-that-that's terrible.
You just don't get it,
do you?
Dreams ruin lives.
And in your case,
they ruined the lives
of your friends too.
Uh--
[ Sighs ]
[ Whimpers ]
Hey, kermit.
Don't let it spoil
your holiday.
Remember, this is the most
wonderful time of the year.
Hmm.
♪'Tis The Season
To be jolly ♪
♪Fa-la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la ♪
This is not good.
This is not good at all.
Somebody's gotta
do something
about that bitterman.
That's what I've been
trying to say.
I mean, look what she's put
this poor frog through.
I'm sorry I convinced you all
to work so hard
and believe in this dream.
It was all for nothing.
We lost the money.
We lost the theater.
We've lost everything.
I mean, send someone
down there to dole out
some justice.
Uh, could you send someone
down there to dole out
some justice, please?
Let me think about it.
[ Wind whistling ]
[ Sighs ]
"Thank you, kermit,
from the children of the world.
'For the lovers,
the dreamers and you.'"
Dreams.
Bitterman's right.
I ruined everyone's life
with my ridiculous dreams.
[ Sighs ]
Hmm.
[ Shivers ]
You can't tell me
that this is what
you wanted to happen.
It isn't.
Hello, fritz?
We've got a problem on earth.
Can you prepare the transport
for a field agent?
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, great. Great.
Should I get glenn on the horn?
No.
Wha--
me?
N-no. I-i'm the wrong guy.
I'm gonna go get glenn.
Oh! What--
what'd you do
with my clothes?
My glasses?
I look like an ice-cream man
from hello, dolly!
What-- what's this?
and implementation of
divine intervention on earth."
"Regulatory guide
to the design
I should probably tell you
I'm a very slow reader.
Okay. Fine.
"Performing miracles
for dummies," huh?
I'm sorry.
I'm the wrong guy for the job.
See, I'm a numbers guy.
People are too unpredictable.
Danny-l,
you are the right guy.
You have a real
understanding
of right and wrong...
And an innate sense
of justice.
You'll be fine.
Now, get down there before
he turns into a frogsicle.
Go.
[ Snaps fingers ]
[ Screams ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Groans ]
Kermit! Oh!
Oh, dear boss.
I'm too late!
See? I've already
blown my mission.
[ Screams ]
Come on, kermit.
[ Blowing ]
Hang in there, buddy.
[ Whirring ]
[ Kermit shuddering ]
[ Gasps ]
Who are you?
Why are you breathing on me?
You're alive!
Now I can save you.
Yeah, well, do me a favor
and don't bother.
Nobody can save me.
I think I can.
You see, my name is daniel.
Yeah.
And I've been sent from above
in the name of justice
to right a wrong...
And help you get
the theater back.
You? You look like
some kind of an ice-cream man
from hello, dolly!
Well, normally
I'm an accountant.
Well, normally I'd love to sit
and listen to this, but I've
got other things on my mind.
Good-bye.
No. You don't understand.
I know that bitterman
changed the contract.
How do you know that?
Oh, wait a second.
You don't run one of those
muppet internet fan sites,
do you?
No. No, no. I'm a friend,
and I'm here to help.
Yeah. Mmm.
I'm sure if we put
our heads together,
we could come up with a plan.
Sure. Whatever.
What would the boss do?
Hey! We'll call the press.
Alert the media!
Start a frenzy.
No way, pal.
Bitterman owns the paper,
she owns the tv stations
and three-quarters
of the internet.
- how could one person
own so much?
- corporate synergy.
It's out of control.
♪ [ Nbc Chimes ]
Now could you please
just leave me alone? Please!
Actually, I'm not allowed to.
[ Groans ]
Besides, you should not
be alone right now.
You're not yourself.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kermit the frog
would not walk out on his
friends on christmas eve.
Walk out? What do you know
about my friends, huh?
I'll tell you what I know.
My friends would be better off
without me. That's what I know!
What? That is not true.
It is true!
In fact,
I've ruined their lives,
and I wish I'd never been born!
[ Gasps ]
No.
Y-you did not just say that.
You did not just say that!
I did just say it.
I said I wish
I'd never been born!
- what am I supposed to do now?
- I wish I'd never been born.
There. I said it again. I wish
I'd never been b-o-r-n, born!
I wish I'd never been born.
Chapter 12, paragraph two.
"If the subject
tells the field agent...
That he had wished
he'd never been born"--
psst! Psst!
Come close.
I wish I'd never been born!
"Then the field agent
is required to adjust
the world accordingly."
Yeah, do whatever you like,
because, did I mention,
I wish I had never been born!
Okay. Calm down, daniel.
I wish I'd never been born.
What are you doing?
I saw this in
a training video once.
What?
[ Groans ]
[ Thunderclap ]
Welcome to the world
in which
you were never born.
[ Gasping ]
H-how did--
[ Screams ]
Not ready is he.
There is no try.
Only do.
Hmm!
Oops. Wrong world. Sorry.
Dan, how did you--
[ Groaning ]
Oh! What's the matter
with you?
[ Thunderclap ]
I'm sorry.
I-- I had to do that.
I'm just following procedure
as outlined in the manual.
[ Woman on PA. ]
Bitterman plaza is now closing
for christmas eve.
Welcome to the other world--
the world in which
you were never born.
[ Kermit ]
Wh-- what happened
to the park?
[ Daniel ]
Ms. Bitterman bulldozed it
and built this mall.
[ Kermit ]
But how did--
what did--
wait a second.
Are you some kind
of a magician?
No. But I am
a part-time balloon
animal artist.
- [ Gasps ]
- you see, I take the balloons,
and you twist them into--
I have no time
for that now, kermit.
This is a serious mission.
[ Whimpers ]
I will guide you
through a mysterious world.
The journey will shock you.
Hey.
Leave me alone!
I'm goin' home to pack
and say good-bye to my friends.
Now the joke's over.
[ Whimpers ]
Number one.
Hmm?
You don't have a home.
W--
number two, you don't
have any friends,
because you haven't
been born.
But--
number three,
I don't joke.
I've been told
I'm not funny.
Oh, really?
That gag with the snow
in my face was hilarious.
Gonzo?
I'm new at this.
Oh, sir.
Sir, if you could just
spare a second here.
I'm-i'm gonzo,
and this is
amy the dancing brick.
Gonzo, thank goodness.
Hey. Why aren't you
at the party?
[ Gonzo ]
Look, buddy. I'm trying
to work here. Great.
What?
That was my only customer
today. Thanks a lot.
What?
Thank you.
Kermit.
Now why don't you
just run along.
- I don't get it. Gonzo?
- you're a bad luck guy for me.
[ Groans ]
I'm sorry, amy.
I don't understand.
I mean, gonzo acted
like he didn't know me.
Yeah, because
that was the gonzo
from the kermit-less world.
[ Whimpers ]
Hey, isn't that
your friend rizzo on tv?
I'm afraid to look.
What?
Rizzo on fear factor? how?
Hey, dawn,
for your next stunt,
you're gonna have to
face off against a filthy,
disease-ridden rat.
- Hey.
- Are you ready?
And if you pass this test,
you will then have to eat
the disgusting rat.
Wh-what?
Here we go.
That was not in my contract.
Three,
two, one.
No. No. No, no, no!
Go!
Hiya.
[ Screams ]
[ Kermit ]
What a disgusting show.
How can nbc
live with themselves?
It's worse than it seems.
[ Rizzo ]
Somebody get me outta here!
For some reason,
your not being born
has altered the world,
so 90% of network tv
is reality shows.
- Go ahead. Eat the rat.
First bite's the hardest part.
- [ both scream ]
- [ rizzo ]
No!
- Tastes just like chicken.
Oh, poor rizzo.
I can't watch this.
No!
This is a nightmare.
[ Both scream ]
You weren't there to keep
your friends together, so--
please don't eat me!
♪ [ Irish Folk ]
Hey. Do you hear music?
Is that the band? Oh.
♪ [ Continues ]
Okay. Let me see
my spesh, fluffy.
Wait a second.
You guys are the mayhem band.
You're not riverdancers.
Out of the way,
before you get stomped.
And besides,
what are you doing
out of the kitchen?
Shouldn't you be
on some number two plate
special or something?
What are you talking about?
Over there, short stack.
[ Whimpers ]
Dochopper's?
Are you a dancer?
♪ [ Ends ]
[ Kermit ]
Oh, no. It can't be.
[ Whimpers ]
Oh, dear.
I'm sorry, kermit.
Kermit?
[ Horns honking ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Daniel ]
Yep. The muppet theater.
Do you wanna see how
that turned out without ya?
♪ [ Rock ]
Oh, Dr. Honeydew.
Dr. Honeydew.
Please tell me you know me.
Please tell me this is still
the muppet theater.
Muppet theater?
Can't you read, lizard?
This is dot.
♪ [ Rock Continues ]
What the--
[ Whimpers ]
[ Groans ]
♪ [ Electronic Dance ]
Wha--
oh.
[ Whimpering ]
Oh, no.
This is a nightmare.
Now do you believe that
you haven't been born yet?
I'm starting to.
[ Man ]
Hey, ms. Bitterman.
Here you go, dear.
Oh, thank you, johnny.
All right.
Hey, listen, boss. By the way,
these two deadbeats over here--
they stopped buyin' drinks
for the girls about an hour ago.
Is that true?
We've been buyin' all night.
Yeah, we're goin' broke.
Yeah.
They're lyin'.
I think it's time
for you two to hit the road.
[ Both ]
Whoa!
[ Crashes ]
[ Laughing ]
How about another?
You better believe it.
- ms. Bitterman?
- yes?
We're all out of mineral water.
Then find some empty bottles
and fill it with tap water.
But-- oh!
[ Crash ]
Ms. Bitterman,
not only have you ruined
the muppet theater,
you've also ruined
the muppets.
Thank you.
Customer feedback
is very important to us.
I will certainly
consider your input.
[ Snaps fingers ]
Uh, wait a second.
Mee-mee-mee-mee.
Mee. Mee-mee-mee-mee.
Beaker, you're all swollen.
Uh, uh, could we
talk about this?
[ Screams ]
[ Shouts ]
[ Low voice ]
Meep-meep.
I managed to get
my hand stamped.
Lick your hand,
and we'll try to get back in.
You guys okay?
There you go.
Fozzie?
Yeah?
You probably don't
recognize me, do ya?
No. But this is christmas eve,
and it looks like
you could use a hand.
Hmm. Hmm. Your kindness
means a lot to me right now.
Yeah, well,
always help a stranger!
Ah, bye!
Ah!
[ Laughing ]
[ Kermit ]
Well,
he's acting
a little strange, but,
gee, it's good to know
fozzie turned out
basically okay.
Yeah. If being
a pickpocket is okay.
Wha--
he-- he-he took my wallet.
Unbelievable.
And you don't even have
pockets. Even more unbelievable.
Yeah, but...
How could things
be this bad without me?
I guess someone like you
makes a big difference
in a lot of lives.
Hmm.
But... I'm just one frog.
You know what?
I think there's someone else
you should see.
Piggy.
Hmm.
She lives in this sty?
Yeah.
Apartment 217.
Here.
Hmm?
You better take these.
[ Miss piggy ]
Who is it?
Um, uh, my name is kermit.
Uh, uh, kermit the frog.
[ Chains clinking ]
Who?
[ Gasps ]
Uh, someone you used to know.
[ Sighs ]
Yes, uh, of course.
It's all coming back to me now.
Um, wait right there.
[ Miss piggy ]
Oh. Oh. Out of my way.
[ Toilet flushes ]
[ Cat screeches ]
Oh, sorry.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Clattering ]
[ Crash ]
[ Cat screeching ]
[ Chuckles ]
Piggy?
Korwin?
It's been so long
since we met at, uh--
oh, you brought candy! Oh!
Oh, oh! Let's see
what's in here. Oh, oh!
Mmm! Mmm! Oh. Mmm.
Creamy good!
Oh. Mmm! Oh, fruit center.
Oh, oh! Nuts! Oh!
[ Chomping ]
Mmm!
[ Kermit ]
Piggy, uh, merry christmas.
Oh! Mmm.
I can see
you really like cats.
Doesn't everyone?
Hmm?
So, uh--
make yourself comfortable.
Have a seat--
somewhere.
Thank you.
Um, you, uh--
[ Cats meows ]
You look, uh, good.
So, uh,
what are you up to?
Oh. Actually, I do
quite a lot of acting.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Of course,
I do most of it
from here now.
[ Rings ]
[ Cats meowing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
Your, uh-- your phone.
All right, already.
Excuse me.
Uh, sure.
[ Grumbles ]
[ Jamaican accent ]
Hello, darling.
N-nice kitty.
Miss piggy knows
the answers you seek.
Miss piggy's for
entertainment purposes only.
You must be 18 or older.
2.99 a minute.
Local tolls may apply.
Piggy, what are you doing?
You're not jamaican.
Yeah, well,
I'm not psychic either.
[ Jamaican accent ]
Now, as I was sayin'--
[ Line clicks ]
Hello? Hello? Oh, great!
You just
lost me a gig.
Yeah, yeah--
but, piggy, that's not
real acting. That's deceiving
people for money.
Oh, no.
You're not a cop, are you?
'Cause if you are,
you have to tell me.
No. No, no. No.
I'm just a friend.
Look. What do you say
you and I go out for a nice
christmas dinner, huh?
But-but-but
what about my babies?
I mean, I still have to wrap
Mr. Meow-meow's present.
[ Cat ]
Meow-meow.
Besides, I look terrible.
Oh, piggy. Are you crazy?
You always look beautiful.
You've got more beauty
and talent than...
Any supermodel
or movie star I know.
It's true I once had dreams
of going to Hollywood
and becoming a big star.
But they were just dreams.
Silly dreams.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sobs ]
[ Sniffles ]
Oh.
Oh, piggy.
I think you should
leave now.
What?
Big day tomorrow.
[ Chuckles ]
Lots to do.
Yeah, but--
clean, decorate,
bake the christmas cry.
- pie.
- [ Cat meows ]
What? I'm not pathetic.
No.
I still have
my phone acting.
It's just the kitties and I
want you to leave now.
Y-y-yes, piggy.
I heard you.
Leave! Did you hear me?
But-but-but
it's just that--
scram! Vamoose!
But, piggy--
I said out!
Piggy.
Hi-yah!
Oh!
[ Groans ]
And take
your chocolates too!
Huh?
[ Door closes ]
[ Door opens ]
On second thought,
I'll take these.
[ Door closes ]
[ Piggy wailing ]
[ Kermit ]
Daniel?
Hmm. Daniel?
Daniel, where are you?
[ Panting ]
Daniel!
Daniel, where are you?
I want my life back, please!
[ Panting, gasps ]
Daniel?
♪ [ Guitar Strums ]
♪I Feel So Small And Useless ♪
♪Ambiguous And Clueless ♪
♪I Just Can't Seem
To get anything right ♪
♪I Feel So Invisible Tonight ♪
♪All The Plastic Santas ♪
♪Doin' Hula Dances ♪
♪Remind Me
That I don't belong ♪
♪All The Fake Snow Falling ♪
♪And My Friends Not Calling ♪
♪Leave Me Nothing
But this song ♪
♪On The Most Miserable
Christmas ♪
♪Of My Life ♪
♪The Most Miserable
Horrible, obnoxious ♪
♪Intolerable Christmas ♪
Hey. Don't give up.
You just haven't found
the right audience.
[ Groans ]
I'm so tired of scrounging.
♪ [ Ballad ]
I've had my chance.
♪If Only I Could Go Back ♪
♪And Take Another Crack At ♪
♪All The Things
I've left undone ♪
♪I'd Do Them Right ♪
♪If I Had My Friends
And family here tonight ♪
♪I'd Have The Most
Wonderful christmas ♪
♪Of My Life ♪
♪Everyone Matters ♪
♪Even The Smallest
Of the smallest ♪
♪Can Make The Biggest
Dreams come true ♪
♪Everyone Matters ♪
♪For Worse Or For Better ♪
♪We Can Change
The world around us ♪
♪With Everything We Do ♪
♪Even You ♪
♪Even Me ♪
♪You And Me ♪
Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
[ Grunts ]
Thanks, pal.
What was your name?
Uh, kermit.
Kermit.
Mm-hmm.
Well, have a great
christmas, kermit.
Thanks.
I'll see you around
the mall sometime.
Right.
[ Sighs ]
So long, gonzo.
Merry christmas.
Huh.
Kermit,
I'm-i'm-i'm sorry...
I couldn't help you
save the theater.
I guess I--
I wasn't much help at all.
You know, the theater's
just a building.
I mean, I just
want to get my life back.
All I care about is
being with my friends again.
What's wrong?
Kermit, I don't know
how to tell you this, but...
I don't know how to
get your life back.
Wh-wh-what do you mean?
Are you saying I'm stuck
this way, here, like this?
Well, you see,
I've never done this before.
Yeah, but I can't leave
my friends like this.
There must be something
in your book or something.
You see, it really doesn't
go into a lot of detail
on the subject.
No, but-but--
I wish I'd never said
"I wish I'd never been born."
I-- I wish
I'd never said that.
How could I have said that?
I could have just said
"kermit, you're having
a bad day" maybe,
or "kermit, maybe
things aren't quite
goin' your way."
But no, no! I had to say
"I wish I'd never been born!"
How selfish!
[ Phone rings ]
It's ridiculously selfish.
I'm stuck here in this reality
along with all my friends!
Hello?
Oh, I don't believe this.
Yes?
How am I ever gonna get back?
Oh, what a ridiculous
thing to do.
Yes?
I give up.
I can?
That's great!
How could this happen?
Oh. Well, that's a little weird.
[ Indistinct ]
Okay. Thank you.
I don't believe this.
Kermit. Kermit.
[ Sobbing ]
I can send you back.
I appreciate your help,
daniel, but there's--
what? You-- you can?
Yeah.
Well th-that's terrific!
That's great!
Uh, uh, but, um,
it's a little strange.
Listen. Whatever it takes.
Just do it.
I'm ready. Just do it.
Okay.
Yeah? Yeah?
[ Hawks, spits ]
Oh! That's disgusting.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Gasps ]
The park. It's back!
I'm back! And--
and I've got spit in my eye,
but I don't even care.
You did it, daniel! Yay!
I guess I did.
Yes. Thank you,
thank you, thank you!
Well, don't thank me.
Just, please, go be
with your friends.
Right!
I'll go be with my friends!
Hey, daniel.
Is there anything
I could do for you?
Well, as a matter of fact,
if you found my visit helpful--
mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
You could, uh,
tell my boss by filling out
this customer survey.
Ah--
it will really help
when I come up for review.
Daniel, you've done more
than you could ever know.
Thanks.
Aw, come here you.
[ Laughs ]
[ Groaning ]
Daniel.
Daniel, not quite so tight.
Not quite so tight.
Yeah. Yeah.
Sorry. I'm just really happy.
No, it's okay, really.
Yeah. Thanks.
Bye-bye!
Bye.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Uh, kermit--
[ Laughing ]
Whoo-hoo!
I'll mail it to ya.
Thank you, daniel! Thank you!
Whoopee!
[ Laughs ]
I'm back!
[ Laughing ]
Boy, this is great!
Thank you, daniel!
[ Laughing, gasps ]
Yahoo!
Merry christmas, everyone.
I'm back!
- huh?
Look at the--
oh, I'm back! I'm back!
This is wonderful!
Merry christmas!
Looks like somebody's
been drinkin' a little
too much eggnog.
[ Laughs ]
The only thing I drank...
Was a shot of reality
and a big glass of appreciation!
[ Laughing maniacally ]
An appreciation of everything,
from gonzo's nose...
To piggy's beauty.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, rowlf, it's really you!
Hey, kermit.
Hey, piggy. Wow. Hey.
You still got that mistletoe?
Huh?
I'm not talking to vous.
Aw, come on.
You don't need mistletoe
when you're green.
What?
Ah!
- [ Screams ]
- whoa.
[ Miss piggy ]
What are you doing?
Yeah, he's drunk all right.
Kissin' a pig on
the chops like that?
[ Kisses ]
Mwah!
[ Laughs ]
Beauregard!
[ Panting ]
Did you see that?
Yeah.
Kermie kissed me!
He kissed me! Oh! Oh!
My dreams just came true.
Oh!
[ Laughs ]
[ Miss piggy ]
Don't worry. My fall was
cushioned by kermit's love.
Yeah, I hope kermit's love
can fix my tuba.
No problem, eugene. You bet.
And merry christmas, eugene.
Merry christmas.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
Fozzie?
Any second now,
I know you'll remember
how I let you down.
I understand if you never
wanna speak to me again.
Aw.
[ Sighs ]
I feel so useless.
Oh, fozzie,
are you kidding?
Our friendship
is a lot more important
than any old theater.
Really?
Really.
Thank you, kermit!
Thank you!
You bet.
But why are you so happy?
We just lost everything.
I'll tell you why
I'm happy, folks.
Because tonight I realized
that it's not that horrible
that we lost the theater.
Well, that's good,
because we lost it.
Yeah, yeah,
but, you see, guys,
what really matters is--
money!
That's right. I said money.
Let's face it, frog.
Money talks.
Oh, let's hear what
it has to say, shall we?
Uh, could everybody please
pack up and get out,
so ms. Bitterman
can gut this place?
Ms. Bitterman, this theater
is not yours yet.
[ All ]
Yeah!
Yeah! So get out,
or I'll throw you out.
Oh!
This little piggy's
feeling brave.
And this little piggy's
going to kick
your skinny banking butt!
Oh-- skinny.
Thank you.
It's too bad I can't
say the same for you,
Miss porky.
[ Gasps ]
Porky?
Oh, here it comes.
Oh! Oh! That does it.
Hi-yah!
- [ All ]
Oh!
- hmph!
Oh, you did not just do that.
[ Muppet ]
Uh-oh.
[ Screaming ]
[ Shouting ]
Ay! Ay! Ay! Ay-yah!
Oh, I see.
[ Muppets murmuring ]
So you want
a piece of me?
[ Shouts ]
[ Muppet ]
Whoa. Go, piggy.
Piggy, come on!
I see you are very agile
for a plus-size pig.
[ Miss piggy grunting ]
[ All gasping ]
Oh, my goodness!
And you will be
very unattractive
with a plus-size lip.
I'll give you
five bucks on the pig.
Oh, make that 10. [ Laughs ]
[ Kermit ]
Don't take that.
Get her, piggy!
[ Bitterman grunting ]
[ Singsongy ]
Ha-ha, ha-ha-ha!
- ow!
- ooh!
[ Waldorf ]
That's not good.
[ Statler ] that had to hurt.
[ All ]
Oh! Oh, my. Oh, my.
[ Whimpers ]
Kermie!
Now listen.
Everyone calm down.
Violence won't solve anything.
And ms. Bitterman
may take our theater,
but she can never touch
the muppet theater
in our hearts.
Yes!
That's right.
Well, that's fortunate,
because I don't want
the theater in your hearts.
I want the theater
that exists in reality.
Now if you all
wouldn't mind, clear out!
♪ [ Scatting ]
Look, everyone! Look!
I got some good news, okay?
Unless, of course,
you're a sexy banker lady.
Then it sucks, okay?
Oh, I'm really worried.
Pee-pee's--
pepe.
Pepe.
Pee-pee's got some bad news.
What, are we out of
toenail polish?
No.
I took the monies
you paid me...
And filed for
a special permit
with the city, okay?
The muppet theater is now
an official historical
landmark, okay?
- historical landmark?
- wow!
Historical landmark?
So are we!
[ Laughing ]
The theater can never
be torn down or changed.
It will always remain
the muppet theater, okay?
- no matter who owns it.
- that's amazing!
Yeah!
Ah!
Read it and weep, okay?
Seriously,
if you could start weeping,
we'd all appreciate
seeing this, okay?
Wow, pepe.
That was brave and selfless.
Sí, sí, sí. it was.
But, uh, when you can
help friends...
And get revenge on enemies,
isn't that what christmas
is all about, okay?
[ Chuckling ]
I can't believe this!
How am I gonna make money
off this junky building now?
This is the worst
christmas ever.
Or is it the best christmas
ever? Why, with an infusion
of cash from you,
we could add seats
to the balcony--
mee-mee-mee!
Advertise--
and then put on some really
spankin' profitable shows.
[ Makes sizzling noise ]
No!
[ Gasps ]
I hate you "muffins"!
Good lord.
No!
[ Piggy ]
Ooh, ooh, ooh.
No kidding.
I was frightened.
♪ [ Humming ]
Out of my way!
Oh, and a merry humbug
to you there, grumpy.
Stupid muffins!
This is absolutely
ridiculous!
Hey, uh--
hey. We're all singin'
christmas carols outside,
and it's snowin', and--
it's real pretty.
Wanna come?
[ All ]
Yeah!
[ Fozzie ]
Come on. Come on. Let's go.
Christmas carols.
Come on.
♪We Wish You
A merry christmas ♪
♪And A Happy New Year ♪
♪Good Tidings We Bring
To you and your kin ♪
♪Good Tidings For Christmas ♪
♪And A Happy New Year ♪
[ Whirs ]
[ Gasps ]
Heavens.
This is our best year ever.
Whoa. Merry christmas.
[ Chuckling ]
Someone up there
is looking out for us.
Amazing.
I failed on my mission
to get justice for kermit, yet
everything managed to work out.
Do you think maybe
kermit never needed...
Revenge or justice,
or even the theater?
Yeah.
But what did he need?
What do you think
he needed?
I asked you first.
Yes, but I'm the boss.
Yeah, but I don't know
the answer.
People just really
need to know
what matters in life,
and you opened kermit's eyes
and showed him
what he already had.
People don't need
my intervention.
If people don't need
your intervention, then...
How come the salvation army
ended up with all the money,
the muppets got to
keep their theater,
and bitterman ended up with
nothing except her own greed?
Danny-l, I work
in mysterious ways.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, on behalf of
the muppets, thank you.
♪Everyone Matters ♪
♪Even The Weakest
Of the meekest ♪
♪Can Change The Course
Of history ♪
♪Everyone Matters ♪
[ Kermit ]
♪We're In This Together ♪
♪The World Would Be
So different ♪
♪If There Never Was A Me ♪
♪Even You ♪
[ Miss piggy ]
♪Even Me ♪
[ Kermit ]
♪You And Me ♪