(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(ENTHRALLING MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL HUMMING)
(SINGING) Look down, look down
Don't look 'em in the eye
Look down, look down
You're here until you die
The sun is strong
It's hot as hell below!
Look down, look down
There's 20 years to go
I've done no wrong
Sweet Jesus, hear my prayer!
Look down, look down
Sweet Jesus doesn't care
I know she'll wait
I know that she'll be true
Look down, look down
They've all forgotten you
When I get free
You won't see me
Here for dust!
Look down, look down
Don't look 'em in the eye
How long, dear Lord
Before you let me die?
Look down, look down
You'll always be a slave
You're standing in your grave
Now bring me prisoner 24601
Your time is up
and your parole's begun
You know what that means...
Yes! It means I'm free!
No! It means you get
your yellow ticket of leave
-You are a thief
-I stole a loaf of bread
-You robbed a house
-I broke a window pane
My sister's child was close to death
And we were starving
You will starve again
Unless you learn the meaning of the law
I know the meaning of those 19 years
A slave of the law
Five years for what you did
The rest because you tried to run
Yes, 24601
My name is Jean Valjean!
And I'm Javert!
Do not forget my name
Do not forget me, 24601
Look down, look down
You'll always be a slave
You're standing in your grave
(ALL HUMMING)
Freedom is mine
The earth is still
I feel the wind
I breathe again
And the sky clears
The world is waking
Drink from the pool
How clean the taste!
Never forget the years, the waste
Nor forgive them for what they've done
They are the guilty, every one!
The day begins
and now let's see
What this new world
will do for me!
You'll have to go!
I'll pay you off for the day
Collect your bits and pieces there
and be on your way
You have given me half
what the other men get
This handful of tin
wouldn't buy my sweat!
You broke the law!
It's there for people to see
Why should you get the same
as honest men like me?
And now I know how freedom feels
The jailer always at your heels!
It is the law!
This piece of paper in my hand
It makes me cursed throughout the land
It is the law!
Like a cur
I walk the street
The dirt beneath their feet
Come in, sir, for you are weary
And the night is cold out there
Though our lives are very humble
What we have, we have to share
There is wine here to revive you
There is bread to make you strong
There's a bed to rest till morning
Rest from pain, and rest from wrong
He let me eat my fill
I had the lion's share
The silver in my hand
cost twice what I had earned
In all those 19 years
A lifetime of despair!
And yet he trusted me
The old fool trusted me
He'd done his bit of good
I played the grateful serf
and thanked him like I should
But when the house was still
I got up in the night
Took the silver
Took my
flight!
-Tell his reverence your story!
-Let us see if he's impressed!
-You were lodging here last night
-You were the honest bishop's guest
And then, out of Christian goodness
when he learned about your plight
You maintain he made a present
of this silver
That is right!
But my friend, you left so early!
Surely something slipped your mind
You forgot I gave these also
Would you leave the best behind?
So, messieurs, you may release him
for this man has spoken true
I commend you for your duty
Now God's blessing go with you
But remember this, my brother
See in this some higher plan
You must use this precious silver
to become an honest man
By the witness of the martyrs
By the passion and the blood
God has raised you out of darkness
I have bought your soul
for God!
What have I done?
Sweet Jesus, what have I done?
Become a thief in the night!
Become a dog on the run!
And have I fallen so far
And is the hour so late
That nothing remains
but the cries of my hate?
The cries in the dark that nobody hears!
Here where I stand
at the turning of the years?
If there's another way to go
I missed it 20 long years ago
My life was a war that could never be won
They gave me a number
and murdered Valjean
When they chained me and left me for dead
Just for stealing a mouthful of bread!
Yet why did I allow this man
to touch my soul and teach me love?
He treated me like any other
He gave me his trust
He called me brother
My life he claims for God above
Can such things be?
For I had come to hate the world
This world that always hated me!
Take an eye for an eye!
Turn your heart into stone!
This is all I have lived for!
This is all I have known!
One word from him and I'd be back
beneath the lash, upon the rack
Instead he offers me my freedom!
I feel my shame inside me like a knife
He told me that I have a soul
How does he know?
What spirit comes to move my life?
Is there another way to go?
I am reaching, but I fall
and the night is closing in
As I stare into the void
to the whirlpool of my sin
I'll escape now from that world
From the world of Jean Valjean
Jean Valjean is nothing now!
Another story must begin!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SINGING) At the end of the day
you're another day older
And that's all you can say
for the life of the poor
It's a struggle! It's a war!
And there's nothing that anyone's giving
One more day standing about
What is it for?
One day less to be living!
At the end of the day
you're another day colder
And the shirt on your back
doesn't keep out the chill
And the righteous hurry past
They don't hear the little ones crying
And the winter is coming on fast
Ready to kill
One day nearer to dying!
At the end of the day
there's another day dawning
And the sun in the morning
is waiting to rise!
And the waves crash on the sand
Like a storm that'll break any second
There's a hunger in the land
There's a reckoning still to be reckoned
And there's gonna be hell to pay!
At the end of the day!
FOREMAN: At the end of the day
you get nothing for nothing!
Sitting flat on your bum
doesn't buy any bread!
-There are children back at home
-And the children have got to be fed
-And you're lucky to be in a job
-And in a bed!
(FOREMAN SHOUTS)
And we're counting our blessings!
Have you seen
how the foreman is fuming today
With his terrible breath
and his wandering hands?
It's because little Fantine
won't give him his way
Take a look at his trousers
you'll see where he stands!
And the boss, he never knows
that the foreman is always on heat
WOMAN: If Fantine doesn't look out
Watch how she goes
She'll be out on the street!
At the end of the day it's another day over
With enough in your pocket
to last for a week
Pay the landlord, pay the shop
Keep on grafting as long as you're able
Keep on grafting till you drop
Or it's back to the crumbs off the table
Well, you've got to pay your way
At the end of the day!
And what have we here
little innocent sister?
Come on, Fantine, let's have all the news!
Dear Fantine, you must send us more money
Your child needs a doctor
There's no time to lose
Give that letter to me
It is none of your business
With a husband at home
and a bit on the side!
Is there anyone here
who can swear before God
She has nothing to fear?
She has nothing to hide?
What is this fighting all about?
Will someone tear these two apart?
This is a factory, not a circus
Now, come on, ladies, settle down!
I run a business of repute
I am the mayor of this town
I look to you to sort this out
and be as patient as you can
Now someone say how this began!
At the end of the day
she's the one who began it!
There's a kid that she's hiding
in some little town
There's a man she has to pay
You can guess how she picks up the extra
You can bet she's earning her keep
sleeping around!
And the boss wouldn't like it!
Yes, it's true there's a child
and the child is my daughter
And her father abandoned us
leaving us flat
Now she lives
with an innkeeper man and his wife
And I pay for the child
What's the matter with that?
At the end of the day
she'll be nothing but trouble
And there's trouble for all
when there's trouble for one!
While we're earning our daily bread
she's the one with her hands in the butter
You must send the slut away
or we're all gonna end in the gutter
And it's us who'll have to pay
At the end of the day!
I might have known the bitch could bite!
I might have known the cat had claws!
I might have guessed your little secret!
Ah, yes! The virtuous Fantine
Who keeps herself so pure and clean
You'd be the cause, I had no doubt
of any trouble hereabout
You play a virgin in the light
but need no urging in the night!
She's been laughing at you
while she's having her men!
She'll be nothing but trouble
again and again!
-You must sack her today!
-Sack the girl today!
Right, my girl
On your way!
There was a time when men were kind
When their voices were soft
and their words inviting
There was a time when love was blind
and the world was a song
and the song was exciting!
There was a time
Then it all went wrong
I dreamed a dream in time gone by
when hope was high and life worth living
I dreamed that love would never die
I dreamed that God would be forgiving
Then I was young and unafraid
And dreams were made and used
and wasted
There was no ransom to be paid
No song unsung, no wine untasted
But the tigers come at night
with their voices soft as thunder
As they tear your hope apart
As they turn your dream
to shame
He slept a summer by my side
He filled my days with endless wonder
He took my childhood in his stride
But he was gone when autumn came
And still I dream he'll come to me!
That we will live the years together
But there are dreams that cannot be
And there are storms we cannot weather
I had a dream my life would be
so different from this hell I'm living
So different now from what it seemed!
Now life has killed the dream
I dreamed
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SINGING) I smell women!
Smell 'em in the air!
Think I'll drop me anchor
in that harbor over there!
Lovely ladies!
Smell 'em through the smoke!
Seven months at sea
can make you hungry for a poke
Even stokers need a little stoke!
Lovely ladies waiting for a bite!
Waiting for the customers
who only come at night
Lovely ladies ready for a call
Standing up or lying down or any way at all
Bargain prices up against the wall!
Come here, my dear
Let's see this trinket you wear
This bagatelle
Madame, I'll sell it to you!
-I'll give you four
-That wouldn't pay for the chain
I'll give you five, you're far too eager to sell
It's up to you
-It's all I have!
-That's not my fault
-Please, make it 10!
-No more than five
My dear, we all must stay alive!
Lovely ladies waiting in the dark
Ready for a thick one
or a quick one in the park
Long time, short time, anytime, my dear!
Cost a little extra
if you want to take all year
Quick and cheap is underneath the pier!
What pretty hair!
What pretty locks you've got there
What luck you've got
It's worth a centime, my dear!
-I'll take the lot!
-Don't touch me! Leave me alone!
Let's make a price
I'll give you all of 10 francs
-Just think of that!
-It pays a debt
-Just think of that
-What can I do? It pays a debt
Ten francs may save my poor Cosette
Gimme the dirt
Who's that bit over there?
A bit of skirt
She's the one sold her hair
She's got a kid
Sends her all that she can
I might've known
there is always some man
Lovely lady, come along and join us!
Lovely lady!
Come on, dearie, why all the fuss?
You're no grander than the rest of us
Life has dropped you
at the bottom of the heap
Join your sisters
Make money in your sleep!
WHORE 1 : That's right, dearie
Let 'im have the lot
WHORE 2: That's right, dearie
Show 'im what you've got
Old men, young men, take 'em as they come!
Harbor rats and alley cats
and every kind of scum!
Poor men, rich men, leaders of the land
See them with their trousers off
They're never quite as grand!
All it takes is money in your hand!
Lovely ladies going for a song
Got a lot of callers
but they never stay for long
Come on, Captain, you can wear your shoes
Don't it make a change
to have a girl who can't refuse?
Easy money
Lying on a bed
Just as well they never see
the hate that's in your head!
Don't they know they're making love
to one already dead?
Here's something new
I think I'll give it a try
Come closer, you!
I like to see what I buy
The usual price
for just one slice of your pie
I don't want you!
No! No, monsieur, let me go!
Is this a trick? I won't pay more!
No, not at all
You've got some nerve, you ugly slut!
You've got some gall!
It's the same with a tart
as it is with a grocer
The customer sees what he gets in advance
It's not for the whore
to say yes sir or no sir
It's not for the harlot
to pick or to choose
Or to lead me a dance
I'll kill you, you bastard, try any of that!
Even a whore who has gone to the bad
won't be had by a rat!
By Christ, you'll pay for what you've done!
This rat will make you bleed, you'll see!
I guarantee, I'll make you suffer!
For this disturbance of the peace
For this insult to life and property!
I beg you, don't report me, sir
I'll do whatever you may want
Make your excuse to the police!
Tell me quickly what's the story
Who saw what, and why, and where?
Let him give a full description
Let him answer to Javert!
In this nest of whores and vipers
Let one speak who saw it all
Who laid hands on this good man here?
What's the substance of this brawl?
Javert, would you believe it?
I was crossing from the park
When this prostitute attacked me
You can see she left her mark!
She will answer for her actions
When you make a full report
You may rest assured, monsieur
That she will answer to the court
There's a child who sorely needs me
Please, monsieur, she's but that high
Holy God, is there no mercy?
If I go to jail she'll die!
I have heard such protestations
every day for 20 years
Let's have no more explanations
Save your breath and save your tears
Honest work, just reward
That's the way to please the Lord
A moment of your time, Javert
I do believe this woman's tale
But, Monsieur Mayor
You've done your duty, let her be
She needs a doctor not a jail
-But, Monsieur Mayor
-Can this be?
Where will she end
This child without a friend?
I've seen your face before
Show me some way to help you
How have you come to grief
In such a place as this
Monsieur, don't mock me now, I pray
It's hard enough I've lost my pride
You let your foreman send me away
Yes, you were there and turned aside
I never did no wrong
Is it true, what I've done...
My daughter's close to dying
... to an innocent soul?
-If there's a God above...
-Had I only known then
...he'd let me die instead
In his name my task has just begun
I will see it done
But, Monsieur Mayor!
Take her to the hospital
I will see it done!
Can this be true?
I don't believe what I see!
A man your age
To be as strong as you are!
A memory stirs
You make me think of a man
from years ago
A man who broke his parole
He disappeared
Forgive me, sir!
I would not dare
Say what you must
Don't leave it there
I have only known one other
who can do what you have done
He's a convict from the chain gang
He's been 10 years on the run
But he couldn't run forever
We have found his hideaway
And he's just been re-arrested
And he comes to court today
Well, of course, he now denies it
You'd expect that of a con
But he couldn't run forever
No, not even Jean Valjean!
You say this man denies it all
And gives no sign of understanding
or repentance
You say this man is going to trial
And that he's sure to be returned
to serve his sentence
Come to that, can you be sure
that I am not your man?
I have known the thief for ages
Tracked him down through thick and thin
And to make the matter certain
There's the brand upon his skin
He will bend
He will break
This time there is no mistake!
He thought that man was me
without a second glance
This stranger he has found
This man could be my chance
Why should I save his hide?
Why should I right this wrong?
When I have come so far
and struggled for so long?
If I speak, I am condemned
If I stay silent
I am damned!
I am the master of hundreds of workers
They all look to me
Can I abandon them?
How will they live
If I am not free?
If I speak, they are condemned
If I stay silent, I am damned
Who am I?
Can I condemn this man to slavery?
Pretend I do not feel his agony?
This innocent who wears my face
Who goes to judgement in my place
Who am I?
Can I conceal myself for evermore?
Pretend I'm not the man I was before?
And must my name until I die
Be no more than an alibi?
Must I lie?
How can I ever face my fellow men?
How can I ever face myself again?
My soul belongs to God, I know
I made that bargain long ago
He gave me hope when hope was gone
He gave me strength to journey on
Who am I?
I'm Jean Valjean!
And so, Javert, you see it's true
This man bears no more guilt than you
Who am I?
24601!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SINGING) Cosette, it's turned so cold
Cosette, it's past your bed time
You've played the day away
And soon it will be night
Come to me
Cosette, the light is fading
Don't you hear the winter wind is crying?
There's a darkness
which comes without a warning
But I will sing you lullabies
and wake you in the morning
Oh, Fantine, our time is running out
But, Fantine, I swear this on my life
Look, monsieur, where all the children play!
Be at peace!
Be at peace ever more
-My Cosette...
-Shall live in my protection
-Take her now!
-Your child will want for nothing
Good monsieur
You come from God in heaven
And none will ever harm Cosette
as long as I am living
Take my hand
The night grows ever colder
Then I will keep you warm
Take my child
I give her to your keeping
Take shelter from the storm
For God's sake
please stay till I am sleeping
And tell Cosette I love her
and I'll see her when I wake
Valjean, at last
We see each other plain!
Monsieur Ie Mayor
You'll wear a different chain!
Before you say another word, Javert
Before you chain me up like a slave again
Listen to me! There is something I must do
This woman leaves behind a suffering child
There is none but me who can intercede
In mercy's name, three days are all I need
Then I'll return, I pledge my word
Then I'll return
You must think me mad!
I've hunted you across the years
Men like you can never change
A man such as you
-Believe of me what you will
-Men like me can never change
-There is a duty that I'm sworn to do
-Men like you can never change
-You know nothing of my life
-No, 24601!
-All I did was steal some bread
-My duty is to the law
-You know nothing of the world
-You have no rights!
-You would sooner see me dead
-Come with me, 24601!
-But not before I see this justice done!
-Now the wheel has turned around
Jean Valjean is nothing now
-I am warning you, Javert
-Dare you talk to me of crime
-I'm the stronger man by far!
-And the price you had to pay
-There is power in me yet!
-Every man is born in sin
-My race is not yet run!
-Every man must choose his way
-I am warning you, Javert
-You know nothing of Javert!
-There is nothing I won't dare!
-I was born inside a jail
-If I have to kill you here
-I was born with scum like you
-I'll do what must be done
-I am from the gutter, too
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
And this I swear to you tonight
There is no place for you to hide
Your child will live within my care
Wherever you may hide away
And I will raise her to the light
I swear to you
I will be there
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) There is a castle on a cloud
I like to go there in my sleep
Aren't any floors for me to sweep
Not in my castle on a cloud
There is a lady all in white
Holds me and sings a lullaby
She's nice to see
and she's soft to touch
She says
"Cosette, I love you very much"
I know a place where no one's lost
I know a place where no one cries
Crying at all is not allowed
Not in my castle on a cloud
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Now look who's here!
The little madam herself
Pretending once again
She's been so awfully good!
Better not let me catch you slacking
Better not catch my eye
Ten rotten francs your mother sends me
What's that going to buy?
Now, take that pail
My little mademoiselle
And go and draw some water from the well
We should never have taken you in
in the first place
How stupid the things we do
Like mother, like daughter
The scum of the street!
Still there, Cosette?
Your tears will do you no good
I told you fetch some water
from the well in the wood
Please do not send me out alone
Not in the darkness on my own
(ANGRILY) Enough of that
(SOFTLY) or I'll forget to be nice!
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
You heard me ask for something
And I never ask twice
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
My band of soaks
My den of dissolutes
My dirty jokes
My always pissed as newts
My sons of whores
Spend their lives in my inn
Homing pigeons homing in
They fly through my doors
And their money's as good as yours
Welcome, monsieur!
Sit yourself down
And meet the best innkeeper in town
As for the rest
All of them crooks
Rooking the guests
and cooking the books
Seldom do you see
Honest men like me!
A gent of good intent
Who's content to be
Master of the House!
Doling out the charm
Ready with a handshake
and an open palm
Tells a saucy tale
Creates a little stir
Customers appreciate a bon-viveur
Glad to do a friend a favor!
Doesn't cost me to be nice
But nothing gets you nothing
Everything has got a little price!
Master of the House!
Keeper of the zoo!
Ready to relieve them
of a sou or two
Watering the wine
Making up the weight
Picking up their knick-knacks
When they can't see straight
Everybody loves a landlord
Everybody's bosom friend!
I do whatever pleases
Jesus! Won't I bleed 'em in the end!
(LAUGHS)
Master of the House!
Quick to catch yer eye!
Never wants a passer-by
to pass him by!
Servant to the poor
Butler to the great
Comforter, philosopher and life-long mate!
Everybody's boon companion!
Everybody's chaperone!
But lock up your valises
Jesus! Won't I skin you to the bone!
Enter, monsieur
Lay down yer load
Unlace yer boots
Rest from the road
This weighs a ton!
Travel's a curse
But here we strive
to lighten your purse
Here the goose is cooked!
Here the fat is fried!
And nothing's overlooked till I'm satisfied
Food beyond compare!
Food beyond belief!
Mix it in a mincer and pretend it's beef
Kidney of a horse
Liver of a cat
Filling up the sausages with this and that!
Residents are more than welcome!
Bridal suite is occupied!
Reasonable charges
Plus some little extras on the side!
Here we go
Charge them for the lice
Extra for the mice
Two percent for looking
in the mirror twice
Here a little slice
There a little cut
Three per cent for sleeping
with the window shut!
When it comes to fixing prices
There are lots of tricks he knows!
How it all increases!
All them bits and pieces!
Jesus! It's amazing how it grows!
Master of the House!
Quick to catch yer eye!
Never wants a passer-by
to pass him by!
Servant to the poor
Butler to the great
Comforter, philosopher and life-long mate!
Everybody's boon companion
Gives them everything he's got
Dirty bunch of geezers
Jesus! What a sorry little lot!
I used to dream
that I would meet a prince
But, God almighty, have you seen
what's happened since?
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
"Master of the House"
isn't worth my spit!
Comforter, philosopher, and life-long shit!
Cunning little brain
Regular Voltaire!
Thinks he's quite a lover
But there's not much there
What a cruel trick of nature
Landed me with such a louse!
God knows how I've lasted
living with this bastard in the house!
-Master of the House!
-Master and a half!
-Comforter, philosopher!
-Don't make me laugh!
Servant to the poor
Butler to the great
Hypocrite, and toady, and inebriate
Everybody bless the landlord!
Everybody bless his spouse!
Everybody raise a glass!
(ALL WHOOPING)
Raise it up the master's arse!
(ALL LAUGH)
Everybody raise a glass
to the Master of the House!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(CHEERING)
(SINGING)
I found her wandering in the woods
This is her child
I found her trembling in the shadows
And I am here to help Cosette
And I will settle any debt
you may think proper
I will pay what I must pay
to take Cosette away
What to do?
What to say?
Shall you carry our treasure away?
What a gem!
What a pearl!
Beyond rubies is our little girl!
How can we speak of debt?
Let's not haggle for darling Colette!
-(SOFTLY) Cosette!
-Cosette!
Dear Fantine, gone to rest
Have we done for her child what is best?
Shared our bread, haven't we?
Shared each bone
We treated her like she's one of our own!
Like our own, monsieur!
Your feelings do you credit, sir
I will ease the parting blow
Let us not talk of bargains
or bones or greed
Now, may I say we are agreed?
That would quite fit the bill
if she hadn't so often been ill
Little dear, cost us dear!
Medicines are expensive, monsieur
Not that we'd begrudge a sou
It's no more than we Christians must do!
One thing more
One small doubt!
There are treacherous people about!
No offense!
Please reflect
Your intentions may not be correct
No more words!
Here's your price
1, 500 for your sacrifice
Come, Cosette, say goodbye!
Let us seek out some friendlier sky
Thank you both for Cosette
It won't take you too long to forget
(INDISTINCT)
Look down and see the beggars at your feet!
Look down and show
some mercy if you can!
Look down and see
the sweepings of the street!
Look down, look down
upon your fellow man!
How do you do?
My name's Gavroche!
These are my people
Here's my patch
Not much to look at
Nothing posh
Nothing that you'd call up to scratch
This is my school, my high society!
Here in the slums of Saint Michel
We live on crumbs of humble piety
Tough on the teeth, but what the hell!
Think you're poor?
Think you're free?
Follow me! Follow me!
Look down and show
some mercy if you can!
Look down, look down
upon your fellow man!
What you think yer at?
Hanging round me pitch
If you're new around here, girl
You've got a lot to learn
Listen, you old bat
Crazy bloody witch
Least I give my customers
some pleasure in return
I know what you give
You give them all the pox
You spread around your poison
till they end up in a box
Leave the poor old cow
Move it, Madeleine
She used to be no better
till the clap got to her brain
When's it gonna end?
When we gonna live?
-Something's gotta happen now
-MAN: Or something's gonna give
It'll come, it'll come, it'll come
Where are the leaders of the land?
Where are the swells who run this show?
Only one man, and that's Lamarque
speaks for these people here below
See our children fed!
Help us in our shame!
Something for a crust of bread
in holy Jesus' name!
In the Lord's holy name
In his name, in his name, in his name
Lamarque is ill and fading fast
Won't last a week out, so they say
With all the anger in the land
How long before the judgement day?
Before we cut the fat ones down to size?
Before the barricades arise?
Watch out for old Thnardier!
All of his family's on the make
Once ran a hash-house down the way
Bit of a swine and no mistake
He's got a gang
The bleeding layabout
Even his daughter does her share
That's ponine, she knows her way about
Only a kid, but hard to scare!
Do we care?
Not a cuss!
Long live us!
Look down and show
some mercy if you can!
Look down, look down
upon your fellow man!
Here's the old boy!
Stay on the job and watch out for the law!
-Stay out of this!
-But, ponine...
You'll be in trouble here!
It's not your concern, you'll be in the clear
-Who is that man?
-Leave me alone!
Why is he here?
Hey, ponine!
I didn't see you there, forgive me
Please, monsieur, come this way
Here's a child what ain't eaten today
Save a life
Spare a sou!
God rewards all the good that you do
Wait a bit!
Know that face!
Ain't the world a remarkable place?
Men like me don't forget
You're the bastard who borrowed Cosette!
What is this?
Are you mad?
No, monsieur, you don't know what you do!
You know me, you know me!
I'm a con, just like you
It's the police! Disappear!
Run for it!
It's Javert!
Another brawl in the square!
Another stink in the air!
Was there a witness to this?
Well, let him speak to Javert!
Monsieur, the streets are not safe
But let these vermin beware
We'll see that justice is done!
Look upon this fine collection
crawled from underneath a stone
This swarm of worms and maggots
could have picked you to the bone!
I know this man over here
I know his name and his trade
And on your witness, monsieur
I'll see him suitably paid
But where's the gentleman gone?
And why on earth did he run?
You will have a job to catch him!
He's the one you should arrest!
No more bourgeois when you scratch him
than that brand upon his chest!
Could it be he's some old jailbird
that the tide now washes in?
Heard my name and started running
Had the brand upon his skin
And the girl who stood beside him
When I turned they both had gone
Could he be the man I've hunted?
Could it be he's Jean Valjean?
(CLEARS THROAT)
In the absence of a victim
Dear Inspector, may I go?
And remember when you've nicked him
It was me wot told you so!
Let the old man keep on running
I will run him off his feet!
Everyone about your business
Clear this garbage off the street!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
There, out in the darkness
A fugitive running
Fallen from God
Fallen from grace
God, be my witness!
I never shall yield
till we come face to face
Till we come face to face
He knows his way in the dark
Mine is the way of the Lord
Those who follow the path
of the righteous
shall have their reward
And if they fall, as Lucifer fell
The flame!
The sword!
Stars in your multitudes!
Scarce to be counted
Filling the darkness
With order and light
You are the sentinels
Silent and sure
Keeping watch in the night
You know your place in the sky
You hold your course and your aim!
And each in your season
returns and returns
And is always the same
And if you fall, as Lucifer fell
You fall in flames!
And so it must be
For so it is written
On the doorway to Paradise
That those who falter and those who fall
Must pay the price!
Lord, let me find him
that I may see him safe behind bars!
I will never rest till then!
This I swear!
This I swear by the stars!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SINGING)
That inspector thinks he's something
But it's me who runs this town!
And my theatre never closes
and the curtain's never down!
Trust Gavroche! Have no fear!
You can always find me here!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) Enjolras!
At Notre Dame the sections are prepared!
At Rue du Bac they're straining at the leash!
Students, workers, everyone!
There's a river on the run!
Like the flowing of the tide
Paris coming to our side!
The time is near
So near it's stirring the blood in their veins
And yet beware!
Don't let the wine go to your brains
For the army we fight is a dangerous foe
With the men and the arms
that we never can match
It is easy to sit here and swat them like flies
But the National Guard
will be harder to catch
We need a sign to rally the people
To call them to arms
To bring them in line
-Marius, you're late
-JOLY: What's wrong today?
You look as if you've seen a ghost!
Some wine, and say what's going on!
A ghost you say? A ghost may-be
She was just like a ghost to me!
One minute there, then she was gone!
I am agog!
I am aghast!
Is Marius in love at last?
I have never heard him "ooh" and "ah"
(LAUGHS)
You talk of battles to be won
And here he comes like Don Juan
It is better than an opera
Thank you!
It is time for us all
to decide who we are
Do we fight for the right
to a night at the opera now?
Have you asked of yourselves
what's the price you might pay?
Is this simply a game
for rich young boys to play?
The colors of the world
are changing day by day
Red, the blood of angry men!
Black, the dark of ages past!
Red, a world about to dawn!
Black, the night that ends at last!
Had you been there tonight
you might know how it feels
To be struck to the bone
in a moment of breathless delight
Had you been there tonight
you might also have known
How the world may be changed
with just one burst of light
And what was right seems wrong
And what was wrong seems right!
-Red!
-I feel my soul on fire!
-GRANTAIRE: Black!
-My world if she's not there!
-Red!
-The color of desire!
-Black!
-The color of despair!
Marius, you're no longer a child
I do not doubt you mean it well
But now there is a higher call!
Who cares about your lonely soul?
We strive towards a larger goal
Our little lives don't count at all!
Red, the blood of angry men!
Black, the dark of ages past!
Red, a world about to dawn!
Black, the night that ends at last!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SINGING) Well, Courfeyrac!
Do we have all the guns?
Feuilly, Combeferre!
Our time is running short!
Grantaire, put the bottle down!
Do we have the guns we need?
Give me brandy on my breath
and I'll breathe them all to death!
Listen, everybody!
General Lamarque is dead!
Lamarque is dead
Lamarque, his death is the hour of fate
The people's man
His death is the sign we await!
On his funeral day
They will honor his name
With the light of rebellion
ablaze in their eyes
From their candles of grief
we will kindle our flame
On the tomb of Lamarque
shall our barricade rise!
The time is here!
Let us welcome it gladly
with courage and cheer!
Let us take to the streets
with no doubt in our hearts
But a jubilant shout!
They will come one and all!
They will come when we call!
Do you hear the people sing?
Singing the song of angry men?
It is the music of a people
who will not be slaves again!
When the beating of your heart
echoes the beating of the drums
There is a life about to start
when tomorrow comes!
Will you join in our crusade?
Who will be strong and stand with me?
Beyond the barricade
is there a world you long to see?
Then join in the fight
that will give you the right to be free!
Do you hear the people sing?
Singing the song of angry men?
It is the music of a people
who will not be slaves again!
When the beating of your heart
echoes the beating of the drums!
There is a life about to start
when tomorrow comes!
Will you give all you can give
so that our banner may advance?
Some will fall and some will live
Will you stand up and take your chance?
The blood of the martyrs
will water the meadows of France!
Do you hear the people sing?
Singing the song of angry men?
It is the music of a people
who will not be slaves again!
When the beating of your heart
echoes the beating of the drums
There is a life about to start
when tomorrow comes
(MEN SHOUTING)
How strange, this feeling
that my life's begun at last
This change!
Can people really fall in love so fast?
What's the matter with you, Cosette?
Have you been too much on your own?
So many things unclear
So many things unknown
In my life
There are so many questions and answers
that somehow seem wrong
In my life
There are times when I catch in the silence
the sigh of a far away song
And it sings of a world that I long to see
Out of reach, just a whisper away
Waiting for me!
Does he know I'm alive?
Do I know if he's real?
Did he see what I see?
Does he feel what I feel?
In my life
I'm no longer alone
now the love in my life is so near
Find me now!
Find me here!
Dear Cosette
You're such a lonely child
How pensive
How sad you seem to me
Believe me, were it within my power
I'd fill each passing hour
How quiet it must be, I can see
With only me for company
There's so little I know
that I'm longing to know
Of the child that I was
in a time long ago
There's so little you say
of the life you have known
Why you keep to yourself
Why we're always alone
So dark, so dark and deep
The secrets that you keep
In my life
I'm no longer a child
and I yearn for the truth that you know
Of the years, years ago!
You will learn!
Truth is given by God to us all
in our time, in our turn!
In my life
She has burst like the music of angels
The light of the sun!
And my life seems to stop
as if something is over
And something has scarcely begun!
ponine, you're the friend
who has brought me here
Thanks to you, I am one with the Gods
and heaven is near!
And I soar through a world
that is new, that is free!
Every word that he says is a dagger in me!
In my life
There's been no one like him anywhere
Anywhere, where he is
If he asked, I'd be his!
In my life
There is someone who touches my life
Waiting near!
Waiting here!
A heart full of love!
A heart full of song!
I'm doing everything all wrong!
Oh, God, for shame!
I do not even know your name
Dear mademoiselle
Won't you say?
Will you tell?
A heart full of love!
No fear, no regret!
My name is Marius Pontmercy
And mine's Cosette
Cosette! I don't know what to say
Then make no sound
I am lost!
I am found!
A heart full of light!
A night bright as day!
And you must never go away
Cosette, Cosette!
This is a chain we'll never break
Do I dream?
-I'm awake
-A heart full of love!
-He was never mine to lose
-A heart full of you!
-Why regret what could not be?
-A single look and then I knew!
-I knew it, too!
-These are words he'll never say
-Not to me
-From today...
Not to me! Not for me
Every day
-For it isn't a dream
-PONINE: His heart full of love
-Not a dream
-He will never
-After all!
-Feel this way
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) This is his lair!
I've seen the old fox around
He keeps himself to himself
He's staying close to the ground
I smell profit here!
Ten years ago
He came and paid for Cosette
I let her go for a song
It's time we settled the debt
This'll cost him dear!
What do I care who you should rob?
Gimme my share! Finish the job!
You shut your mouth!
You'll get what's yours!
CLAQUESOUS: What have we here?
Who is this hussy?
It's your brat ponine!
Don't you know your own kid?
Why's she hanging about you?
ponine, get on home!
You're not needed in this
We're enough here without you
I know this house, I tell you!
There's nothing here for you!
Just the old man and the girl
They live ordinary lives
Don't interfere! You've got some gall!
Take care, young miss
You've got a lot to say!
-She's going soft!
-Happens to all!
Go home, 'Ponine!
Go home, you're in the way!
I'm gonna scream
I'm gonna warn them here!
One little scream
and you'll regret it for a year!
(SCREAMING)
Make for the sewers! Get underground!
Leave her to me! Don't wait around!
You wait my girl! You'll rue this night!
I'll make you scream!
You'll scream alright!
It was your cry sent them away
Once more 'Ponine, saving the day!
Dearest Cosette
My friend 'Ponine
Brought me to you
Showed me the way!
Someone is near!
Let's not be seen!
Somebody's here!
My God, Cosette!
I heard a cry in the dark
I heard the shout of angry voices
in the street
That was my cry you heard, Papa
I was afraid of what they'd do
They ran away when they heard my cry
Cosette, my child
What will become of you?
Three men I saw beyond the wall
Three men in shadow moving fast!
This is a warning to us all!
These are the shadows of the past!
Must be Javert
He's found my cover at last
I've got to get Cosette away
before they return!
We must get away from
shadows that will never let us be
Tomorrow to Calais
And then a ship across the sea
Hurry, Cosette!
Prepare to leave and say no more
Tomorrow we'll away!
Hurry, Cosette!
It's time to close another door
And live another day!
One day more!
Another day, another destiny
This never-ending road to Calvary
These men who seem to know my crime
will surely come a second time
-One day more!
-I did not live until today
How can I live when we are parted?
One day more!
Tomorrow you'll be worlds away
And yet with you my world has started!
One more day all on my own
Will we ever meet again?
One more day with him not caring
I was born to be with you!
What a life I might have known
And I swear I will be true!
But he never saw me there!
One more day before the storm!
Do I follow where she goes?
At the barricades of freedom!
MARIUS: Shall I join my brothers there?
ENJOLRAS: When our ranks begin to form
Do I stay, and do I dare?
Will you take your place with me?
ALL: The time is now! The day is here!
One day more!
One more day to revolution
We will nip it in the bud
We'll be ready for these schoolboys
They will wet themselves with blood!
One day more!
Watch 'em run amuck
Catch 'em as they fall
Never know your luck
when there's a free-for-all
Here a little dip
There a little touch
Most of them are goners
So they won't miss much!
One day to a new beginning!
Raise the flag of freedom high!
Every man will be a king!
There's a new world for the winning!
There's a new world to be won!
Do you hear the people sing?
My place is here! I fight with you!
One day more!
I did not live until today
-I will follow where they go
-One more day on my own
I will learn their little secrets
I will know the things they know
One day more!
-One more day to revolution
-Tomorrow you'll be worlds away
Never know your luck
When there's a free-for-all
We'll be ready for these schoolboys
Tomorrow we'll be far away
Tomorrow is the judgement day
Tomorrow we'll discover
what our God in heaven has in store
One more dawn!
One more day!
One day more!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Here upon these stones
we will build our barricade
In the heart of the city
we claim as our own
Each man to his duty
and don't be afraid!
Wait! I will need a report
on the strength of the foe
I can find out the truth!
I know their ways
Fought their wars
Served my time
In the days of my youth
Hey, little boy, what's this I see?
God, ponine, the things you do!
I know this is no place for me
Still I would rather be with you!
Get out before the trouble starts!
Get out, 'Ponine, you might get shot!
I got you worried now, I have!
That shows you like me quite a lot
There is a way that you can help
You are the answer to a prayer!
Please take this letter to Cosette
and pray to God that she's still there!
Little you know!
Little you care!
I have a letter, monsieur
It's addressed to your daughter Cosette
It's from a boy at the barricade, sir
In the Rue de Valette
Give me that letter here, my boy
He said to give it to Cosette
You have my word that
my daughter will know
what this letter contains
Tell the young man
she will read it tomorrow
and here's for your pains
Go careful now
Stay out of sight
There's danger in the streets tonight
Dearest Cosette
You have entered my soul
and soon you will be gone
Can it be only a day since we met
and the world was reborn?
If I should fall in the battle to come
let this be my goodbye
Now that I know that
you love me as well
it is harder to die
I pray that God will bring me home
to be with you
Pray for your Marius
He prays for you
And now I'm all alone again
Nowhere to turn, no one to go to
Without a home, without a friend
Without a face to say hello to
And now the night is near
Now I can make believe he's here
Sometimes I walk alone at night
when everybody else is sleeping
I think of him and then I'm happy
with the company I'm keeping
The city goes to bed
and I can live inside
my head!
On my own
Pretending he's beside me
All alone I walk with him till morning
Without him, I feel his arms around me
And when I lose my way
I close my eyes
and he has found me
In the rain
the pavement shines like silver
All the lights are misty in the river
In the darkness
the trees are full of starlight
And all I see is him and me
forever and forever!
And I know it's only in my mind
That I'm talking to myself
and not to him
And although I know that he is blind
Still I say there's a way for us
I love him, but when the night is over
He is gone
The river's just a river
Without him
the world around me changes
The trees are bare and everywhere
the streets are full of strangers
I love him, but every day I'm learning
All my life, I've only been pretending
Without me, his world will go on turning
A world that's full of happiness
that I have never known
I love him
But only
on my own
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
ALL: (SINGING) Now we pledge ourselves
to hold this barricade!
Let them come in their legions
and they will be met
Have faith in yourselves
and do not be afraid
Let's give 'em a screwing
they'll never forget!
This is where it begins
And if I should die in the fight to be free
Where the fighting is hardest
there will I be
Let them come if they dare
We'll be there!
He's back!
Listen, my friends
I have done as I said
I have been to their lines
I have counted each man
I will tell what I can
Better be warned
They have armies to spare
and our danger is real
We will need all our cunning
to bring them to heel!
Have faith!
If you know what their movements are
we'll spoil their game
There are ways that our people can fight
We shall overcome their power!
I overheard their plans
There will be no attack tonight
They intend to starve us out
before they start a proper fight
Concentrate their force
Hit us from the right
Liar!
(SINGING) Good evening, dear Inspector
Lovely evening, my dear!
I know this man, my friends
His name's Inspector Javert!
So don't believe a word he says
'cause none of it's true
This only goes to show
what little people can do!
Bravo, little Gavroche!
You're the top of the class!
So what are we going to do
with this snake in the grass?
Tie this man
and take him to the tavern in there!
The people will decide your fate
Inspector Javert!
Shoot me now or shoot me later
Every schoolboy to his sport!
Death to each and every traitor!
I renounce your people's court!
Take this man
Bring him through
There is work we have to do
There's a boy climbing the barricade!
Good God! What are you doing?
'Ponine! Have you no fear?
Have you seen my beloved?
Why have you come back here?
Took the letter, like you said
I met her father at the door
He said he would give it
I don't think I can stand any more
ponine, what's wrong?
There's something wet upon your hair
ponine, you're hurt!
You need some help!
Oh, God, it's everywhere!
Don't you fret, Monsieur Marius
I don't feel any pain
A little fall of rain
can hardly hurt me now
You're here
That's all I need to know
And you will keep me safe
And you will keep me close
And rain will make the flowers grow
But you will live 'Ponine
Dear God above!
If I could close your wounds
with words of love
Just hold me now, and let it be
Shelter me
Comfort me
You will live 100 years
if I could show you how
I won't desert you now
The rain can't hurt me now
This rain will wash away what's past
And you will keep me safe
And you will keep me close
I'll sleep in your embrace at last
The rain that brings you here
is heaven blessed!
The skies begin to clear
and I'm at rest
A breath away from where you are
I've come home from so far
-So don't you fret, Monsieur Marius
-Hush-a-bye, dear ponine
-I don't feel any pain
-You won't feel any pain
-A little fall of rain
-Can hardly hurt me now
-Can hardly hurt you now
(GASPING)
I'm here!
That's all I need to know
-And you will keep me safe
-I will stay with you...
-And you will keep me close
-...till you are sleeping
-And rain...
-... will make the flowers...
...grow
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) She is the first to fall
The first of us to fall upon this barricade
Her name was ponine!
Her life was cold and dark
yet she was unafraid!
We fight here in her name
She will not die in vain
She will not be betrayed
JOLY: (SINGING)
Here comes a man in uniform!
What brings you to this place?
I come here as a volunteer!
Approach, and show your face!
You wear an army uniform!
That's why they let me through!
JOLY: You've got some years
behind you, sir!
There's much that I can do
You see that prisoner over there?
A volunteer like you!
A spy who calls himself Javert!
GRANTAIRE: He's going to get it, too!
MAN: They're getting ready to attack!
Take this, and use it well!
But if you shoot us in the back
You'll never live to tell
MAN: Platoon of sappers
advancing towards the barricade!
Troops behind them! Fifty men or more!
Hold!
Fire!
(GUNSHOTS)
(SINGING) Look how they turn and run!
And so the war was won!
They will be back again
Make an attack again
For your presence of mind
For the deed you have done
I will thank you, monsieur
when our battle is won
Give me no thanks, monsieur
There's something you can do
If it is in my power
Give me the spy Javert!
Let me take care of him!
The law is inside out
The world is upside down!
Do what you have to do!
The man belongs to you!
The enemy may be regrouping!
Hold yourself in readiness!
Come, my friends
Back to your positions
The night is falling fast!
We meet again
You've hungered for this all your life
Take your revenge
How right you should kill with a knife!
You talk too much
Your life is safe in my hands
-Don't understand
-Get out of here
-Valjean, take care! I'm warning you
-Clear out of here!
Once a thief, forever a thief
What you want, you always steal!
You would trade your life for mine
Yes, Valjean, you want a deal!
Shoot me now for all I care
If you let me go, beware!
You'll still answer to Javert!
You are wrong
and always have been wrong
I'm a man no worse than any man
You are free
and there are no conditions
No bargains or petitions
There's nothing that I blame you for
You've done your duty
Nothing more
If I come out of this alive
You'll find me at number 55 Rue Plumet
No doubt our paths will cross again!
Go!
(GUNSHOT)
(SINGING) Courfeyrac, you take the watch
They won't attack until it's light
Everybody keep the faith
For certain as the eagle flies
we are not alone
The people too must rise
Marius! Rest.
(SINGING) Drink with me
to days gone by!
Sing with me
the songs we knew!
Here's to pretty girls
who went to our heads!
Here's to witty girls
who went to our beds!
Here's to them
and here's to you!
Drink with me
to days gone by!
Can it be you fear to die?
Will the world remember you
when you fall?
Can it be your death
means nothing at all?
Is your life just one more lie?
Drink with me
to days gone by!
To the life
that used to be!
At the shrine of friendship
never say die
Let the wine of friendship
never run dry
Here's to you!
And here's to me!
Do I care if I should die
now she goes across the sea?
Life without Cosette
means nothing at all
Would you weep, Cosette
should Marius fall?
Will you weep
Cosette
for me?
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) God on high
Hear my prayer
In my need
you have always been there
He is young
He's afraid
Let him rest
heaven blessed
Bring him home!
Bring him home
He's like the son I might have known
if God had granted me a son
The summers die one by one
How soon they fly on and on
And I am old
and will be gone
Bring him peace
Bring him joy
He is young
He is only a boy
You can take!
You can give!
Let him be
Let him live!
If I die
Iet me die!
Let him live
Bring him home
Bring him home!
Bring him
home!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SINGING) You at the barricade listen to this!
The people of Paris sleep in their beds!
You have no chance
No chance at all!
Why throw your lives away?
Let us die facing our foes!
Make them bleed while we can!
Make them pay through the nose!
Make them pay for every man!
Let others rise
to take our place
until the earth is free!
Here's a hint of gold
Stuck into a tooth
Pardon me, monsieur
You won't be needing it no more!
Shouldn't be too hard to sell
Add it to the pile!
Add it to the stock!
Here among the sewer rats
A breath away from hell
You get accustomed to the smell
Well, someone's got to
clean 'em up, my friends
Before the little harvest
disappears into the mud
Someone's got to collect
their odds and ends
When the gutters run with blood
It's a world where the dog eats the dog
Where they kill for the bones in the street
And God in his heaven
you don't interfere
'Cos he's dead as the stiffs at me feet!
I raise my eyes to see the heavens
And only the moon looks down!
The harvest moon shines down!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) It's you, Javert
I knew you wouldn't wait too long
The faithful servant
at his post once more!
This man's done no wrong
and he needs a doctor's care!
I warned you I would not give in!
I won't be swayed!
Another hour yet
and then I'm yours
And all our debts are paid!
The man of mercy comes again
and talks of justice!
Come, time is running short
Look down, Javert!
He's standing in his grave!
Take him, Valjean
Before I change my mind!
I will be waiting, 24601!
Who is this man?
What sort of devil is he?
To have me caught in a trap
and choose to let me go free?
It was his hour at last
to put a seal on my fate!
Wipe out the past
and wash me clean off the slate!
All it would take
was a flick of his knife!
Vengeance was his
and he gave me back my life!
Damned if I live in the debt of a thief!
Damned if I yield
at the end of the chase!
I am the law, and the law is not mocked!
I'll spit his pity right back in his face!
There is nothing on earth that we share!
It is either Valjean or Javert!
How can I now allow this man
to hold dominion over me?
This desperate man whom I have hunted
He gave me my life!
He gave me freedom!
I should have perished by his hand
It was his right
It was my right to die as well
Instead, I live, but live in hell
And my thoughts fly apart
Can this man be believed?
Shall his sins be forgiven?
Shall his crimes be reprieved?
And must I now begin to doubt
who never doubted all these years?
My heart is stone and still it trembles
The world I have known
is lost in shadow
Is he from heaven or from hell?
And does he know
that, granting me my life today
this man has killed me even so?
I am reaching, but I fall
And the stars are black and cold
As I stare into the void
of a world that cannot hold
I'll escape now from that world
From the world of Jean Valjean
There is nowhere I can turn
There is no way to go on
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) Did you see them
going off to fight?
Children of the barricade
that didn't last the night?
They were school boys
Never held a gun
Fighting for a new world
that would rise up like the sun
Where's that new world
now the fighting's done?
-Who will wake them?
-No one ever will
No one ever told them
that a summer day can kill
Same old story
What's the use of tears?
What's the use of praying
if there's nobody who hears?
Turning, turning
Turning, turning, turning
through the years
Minutes into hours
and the hours into years
Nothing changes, nothing ever can
Rounding round the roundabout
and back where you began
Round and round
and back where you began!
There's a grief that can't be spoken
There's a pain goes on and on
Empty chairs at empty tables
Now my friends are dead and gone
Here they talked of revolution
Here it was they lit the flame
Here they sang about tomorrow
And tomorrow never came
From the table in the corner
They could see a world reborn
And they rose with voices ringing
And I can hear them now!
The very words that they had sung
became their last communion
On the lonely barricade at dawn
Oh, my friends, my friends, forgive me
That I live and you are gone
There's a grief that can't be spoken
There's a pain goes on and on
Phantom faces at the window!
Phantom shadows on the floor!
Empty chairs at empty tables
Where my friends will meet no more
Oh, my friends, my friends, don't ask me
What your sacrifice was for
Empty chairs at empty tables
Where my friends will meet
no more
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) Every day, you walk
with stronger step
You walk with longer step
The worst is over
Every day, I wonder, every day
who it was brought me here
from the barricade
Don't think about it, Marius!
With all the years ahead of us
I will never go away
and we will be together every day
Every day
we'll remember that night
and the vow that we made
A heart full of love
She was never mine to keep
A night full of you
-She is youthful, she is free
-The words are old, but always true
Cosette, Cosette!
-Love is the garden of the young
-I saw you waiting and I knew
Waiting for you
-Let it be!
-At your feet!
-At your call!
-And it wasn't a dream
-A heart full of love
-Not a dream...
-This I give you...
-...after all
-... this day
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) Monsieur, this is a day
I never can forget
Is gratitude enough
for giving me Cosette?
Your home shall be with us
and not a day shall pass
But we will prove our love
to you, whom we shall call
a father to us both
a father to us all
Not another word, my son!
There's something now that must be done
There lived a man
whose name was Jean Valjean
He stole some bread
to save his sister's son
For 19 winters served his time
In sweat he washed away his crime!
Years ago
he broke parole
and lived a life apart
How could he tell Cosette
and break her heart?
It's for Cosette this must be faced
If he is caught, she is disgraced
The time has come to journey on
and from this day he must be gone!
Who am I?
You're Jean Valjean!
What can I do to turn you from this?
Monsieur, you cannot leave
Whatever I tell my beloved Cosette
she will never believe
Make her believe
I have gone on a journey a long way away
Tell her my heart was too full for farewells
It is better this way
Promise me, monsieur
Cosette will never know
I give my word
What I have spoken, why I must go!
For the sake of Cosette, it must be so
CHORUS: (SINGING) Ring out the bells
upon this day of days!
May all the angels
of the Lord above
In jubilation sing their songs of praise
And crown this blessed time
with peace and love!
The Baron and Baroness de Thnard
wish to pay their respects to the groom!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
I forget where we met
Was it not at the Chateau Lafarge?
Where the Duke did that puke
down the Duchess's decolletage?
No, Baron de Thnard
The circles I move in are humbler by far
Go away, Thnardier
Do you think I don't know who you are?
He's not fooled!
Told you so!
Show monsieur
what you've come here to show
Tell the boy what you know!
Pity to disturb you at a feast like this
But 500 francs
surely wouldn't come amiss
In God's name, say what you have to say!
But first you pay!
What I saw, clear as light
Jean Valjean in the sewers that night
Had this corpse on his back
hanging there like a bloody great sack
I was there, never fear!
Even found me this fine souvenir!
I know this! This was mine!
This is surely some heavenly sign!
One thing more, mark this well
It was the night that the barricade fell!
Then it's true! Then I'm right!
Jean Valjean was my savior that night!
As for you, take this, too!
God forgive us the things that we do!
Come, my love, come, Cosette
This day's blessings are not over yet!
(LAUGHING)
Ain't it a laugh?
Ain't it a treat?
Hob-nobbin' here
among the elite?
(VOCALIZING)
Here comes a prince
There goes a Jew
This one's a queer
But what can you do?
Paris at my feet!
Paris in the dust!
And here's me, breaking bread
with the upper crust
Beggar at the feast!
Master of the dance!
Life is easy pickings
if you grab your chance
Everywhere you go
law-abiding folk
doing what is decent
but they're mostly broke!
Singing to the Lord on Sundays
praying for the gifts he'll send
But we're the ones who take it
We're the ones who make it in the end!
Watch the buggers dance!
Watch them till they drop!
Keep your wits about you
And you stand on top!
Masters of the land!
Always get our share!
Clear away the barricades
and we're still there!
We know where the wind is blowing
Money is the stuff we smell
And when we're rich as Croesus
Jesus! Won't we see you all in hell?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(SINGING) Alone I wait in the shadows
I count the hours till I can sleep
I dreamed a dream Cosette stood by
It made her weep to know I die
Alone at the end of the day
Upon this wedding night I pray
Take these children, my Lord
to thy embrace
And show them grace
God on high
Hear my prayer
Take me now
to thy care
Where you are
Let me be
Take me now!
Take me there!
Bring me home!
Monsieur, I bless your name
I am ready, Fantine
Monsieur, lay down your burden
At the end of my days
-You raised my child in love
-She's the best of my life
And you will be with God
Papa, papa, I do not understand!
Are you alright?
They said you'd gone away!
Cosette, my child! Am I forgiven now?
Thank God, thank God
I lived to see this day!
It's you who must forgive
a thoughtless fool!
a thankless man!
It's thanks to you that I am living
and again I lay down my life
at your feet
Cosette, your father is a saint!
When they wounded me
he took me from the barricade
Carried like a babe
and brought me home to you!
Now you are here
again beside me
Now I can die in peace
for now my life is blessed
You will live, papa, you're going to live!
It's too soon
too soon to say goodbye!
Yes, Cosette, forbid me now to die!
I'll obey
I will try
On this page
I write my last confession
Read it well
when I, at last, am sleeping
It's the story
of those who always loved you
Your mother gave her life for you
then gave you to my keeping
Come with me
where chains will never bind you
All your grief
at last, at last, behind you
Lord in heaven
Look down on him in mercy
Forgive me all my trespasses
and take me to your glory!
Take my hand
I lead you to salvation
Take my love
For love is everlasting
And remember
the truth that once was spoken
To love another person
is to see the face of God
CHOIR: Do you hear the people sing
lost in the valley of the night?
It is the music of a people
who are climbing to the light
For the wretched of the earth
there is a flame that never dies
Even the darkest night will end
and the sun will rise
They will live again in freedom
in the garden of the Lord
They will walk behind the plough-share
They will put away the sword
The chain will be broken
and all men will have their reward
Will you join in our crusade?
Who will be strong and stand with me?
Somewhere beyond the barricade
is there a world you long to see?
Do you hear the people sing?
Say, do you hear the distant drums?
It is the future that they bring
when tomorrow comes!
Will you join in our crusade?
Who will be strong and stand with me?
Somewhere beyond the barricade
is there a world you long to see?
Do you hear the people sing?
Say, do you hear the distant drums?
It is the future that they bring
when tomorrow comes
(ALL VOCALIZING)
Tomorrow comes!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING LOUDLY)
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SINGING) God on high
Hear my prayer
In my need
you have always been there
He is young
He's afraid
Let him rest
heaven blessed
Bring him home!
Bring him home
He's like the son I might have known
if God had granted me a son
The summers die one by one
How soon they fly on and on
And I am old
and will be gone
Bring him peace
Bring him joy
He is young
He is only a boy
You can take!
You can give!
Let him be
Let him live!
If I die
Iet me die!
Let him live
Bring him home
Bring him
home!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(SINGING) One day more!
Another day, another destiny
This never-ending road to Calvary
These men who seem to know my crime
will surely come a second time
-One day more!
-I did not live until today
How can I live when we are parted?
One day more!
Tomorrow you'll be worlds away
And yet with you my world has started!
One more day all on my own
Will we ever meet again?
One more day with him not caring
I was born to be with you!
What a life I might have known
And I swear I will be true!
But he never saw me there!
One more day before the storm!
Do I follow where she goes?
At the barricades of freedom!
Shall I join my brothers there?
When our ranks begin to form
Do I stay, and do I dare?
Will you take your place with me?
ALL: The time is now! The day is here!
One day more!
One day more to revolution
We will nip it in the bud
We'll be ready for these schoolboys
They will wet themselves with blood!
One day more!
Watch 'em run amuck
Catch 'em as they fall
Never know your luck
when there's a free-for-all
Here a little dip
There a little touch
Most of them are goners
So they won't miss much!
One day to a new beginning!
Raise the flag of freedom high!
Every man will be a king!
There's a new world for the winning!
There's a new world to be won!
Do you hear the people sing?
My place is here! I fight with you!
One day more!
I did not live until today
One more day on my own
How can I live when we are parted?
One day more!
Tomorrow you'll be worlds away!
Never know your luck
When there's a free-for-all
And yet with you my world has started
Tomorrow we'll be far away
Tomorrow is the judgement day
Tomorrow we'll discover
what our God in heaven has in store
One more dawn!
One more day!
One day more!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Well, Les Miserables is 25 years young!
What a remarkable evening.
This is going to be one of
the greatest nights of my life.
We are all very lucky to be here in front of
such an incredible, stellar, amazing cast.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
I realized, over the last few days,
seeing the original cast here,
the two wonderful London
companies at the moment,
and our extraordinary cast tonight,
that I've not only shared
Les Miserables with them,
I've shared most of
my professional life with them.
And everyone, including the choir,
the ensemble, everyone,
they're all the stars of the West End
that have kept the British
musical theatre thriving.
And they're here
for the same reason I'm here
and the same reason you're here.
We love Les Miserables. There's something
extraordinary about this musical.
And ever since it opened,
25 years ago, at the Barbican
it is you, the public, that have grasped it
and embraced it in the most personal way.
And that's how we all feel.
I watched the second act backstage.
It was as electrifying
as it was for you outside,
just because the embrace between us,
and seeing everybody
just love this material so much,
and love their fellow performers,
is something I have never
encountered in the theatre,
and I never will for the rest of my life.
The inspiration, of course,
belongs to Victor Hugo,
and Victor Hugo inspired two Frenchmen,
they had to be French, of course,
Alain Boublil and Claude-Michel Schonberg,
to write the show,
with the wonderful, uplifting words
of Herbert Kretzmer.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the authors of Les Miserables.
(ALL CHEERING)
Just a few words
on such an emotional evening,
in front of such a huge and warm crowd.
I must remember that 32 years ago
I was asking myself one question.
Would Les Miserables make
a good subject for a musical?
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
And I was unconscious enough
to think it was,
and Claude-Michel
crazy enough to agree with me.
So tonight is a celebration of
obviously the genius of Victor Hugo,
of nearly 40 years of collaboration and
friendship between Claude-Michel and me,
(ALL APPLAUDING)
and 27 years of collaboration and
friendship with Cameron Mackintosh.
It's also the celebration of incredible talents
that we met through Cameron.
Namely they are the people
who have helped him to reshape our work.
They are James Fenton,
Trevor Nunn, John Caird,
and master lyricist Herbert Kretzmer.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
Well, it's an evening...
It's hard to speak, but...
An evening which I will remember
for all my life, obviously.
Seeing this company of companies
perform this night, this incredible evening,
and the 1985 evening, with whom
we share so many fond memories,
is something that we'II carry with us
for the rest of our lives.
I want to thank you, Cameron,
again, for making us
such an incredible and overwhelming
birthday present.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
It's an incredible evening for us.
We are privileged to attend such a concert.
But I am wondering
what we are doing here, really,
because, generally, when you have
a tribute for a show like that
it means that the authors,
they are dead for a long time.
(ALL LAUGHING)
And we are still here.
And they are not very happy
every day, those two gents
and Laurence, the director of the show,
that we are here
because we are always looking
what they are doing with our baby.
But anyway, as Alain said,
it's 40 years of brothership
between me and Alain,
27 years of friendship
and collaboration with Cameron.
Sometimes it's easy,
sometimes it's very tough,
but it's always a lot of fun.
And I wish that it will last a very long time.
Thank you very much, everyone.
Thank you!
(ALL CHEERING)
I've just realized
that I'II be nearly 90 for the
50th anniversary. What shall I do?
I intend to be here, though.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Now, in 2002,
it was Victor Hugo's bicentennial,
and we decided that
we would do a school's edition,
so that under-19-year-olds
could perform the show.
They've been extraordinary doing it.
Hundreds and thousands of students
and tens of thousands
of productions have done it.
And now, here, just a few of them
are going to be here
to take part in our celebration
as we come to an end tonight.
They are the future.
They will be doing Les Miserables
when tomorrow comes.
(SINGING) Do you hear the people sing
lost in the valley of the night?
It is the music of a people
who are climbing to the light
For the wretched of the earth
there is a flame that never dies
Even the darkest night will end
and the sun will rise
They will live again in freedom
in the garden of the Lord
They will walk behind the plough-share
They will put away the sword
The chain will be broken
and all men will have their reward
Will you join in our crusade?
Who will be strong and stand with me?
Somewhere beyond the barricade
is there a world you long to see?
Do you hear the people sing?
Say, do you hear the distant drums?
It is the future that they bring
when tomorrow comes!
Will you join in our crusade?
Who will be strong and stand with me?
Somewhere beyond the barricade
is there a world you long to see?
Do you hear the people sing?
Say, do you hear the distant drums?
It is the future that they bring
when tomorrow comes
(ALL VOCALIZING)
Tomorrow comes!
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)