[Tape recorder: STARTS]
♪ Trying hard to find out
where my baby is tonight ♪
♪ If she is not at home
I wouldn't go ♪
[Tape recorder: STOPS]
[Song: Crazy On You by Heart]
♪ If we still have time,
we might still get by ♪
♪ Every time I think about it,
I wanna cry ♪
[Doorbell: RINGING]
[Woman:]  Hi,
hello Ben.
What can I do
for you?
[Ben:]  Hi,
is Lily in?
[Woman:]  Oh, sorry
she is at dancing.
She be home
soon though.
Do you want to come in?
[Ben:]  Nah,
it's OK.
Could you give her this
from me?
[Woman:]  Of course,
what is it?
[Ben:]
It's a mixtape.
Some my dad's
old music.
She likes that,
I think.
I was doing it anyway,
so I did her a copy.
Will you tell her
I came around?
[Woman:]  Yeah
I be sure do.
[Song: I Wonder Where My Baby
Is Tonight by The Kinks]
♪ Well I wonder where my baby
is tonight ♪
♪ I wonder where my baby is tonight ♪
♪ I wonder where my baby is gone ♪
♪ hope she will do no wrong ♪
♪ looking for my baby,
she is not around ♪
♪ I wonder where my baby is tonight ♪
♪ I wonder what on Earth
my baby is doing ♪
♪ If she is not at home there is
trouble brewing ♪
♪ If she really loves me, ♪
♪ she will believe in what I say ♪
♪ I hope that everything
is gonna be all right ♪
♪ Well I wonder where my baby
is tonight ♪
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
E N J O Y   this   SRT   SUBTITLE   R e l e a s e
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1499280
Mixtape (2009) English for hearing-impaired.srt
FPS: 25.000
With special thanks to: "Owen, Eric & William"
who also subtitled the 15 min long sequel:
Disco (2010) English for hearing-impaired.srt
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
We want more subtitles right NOW!
1) ALL DVD's to be subtitled.
2) ALL VIDEO GAMES to be subtitled.
3) ALL videos/DVD's used in lessons at school to be subtitled.
4) More pre-recorded & live subtitles on TV.
____           __            ___   __              ___        __               __
/     /   _   /    )  _   _ (_     /  _)        _  (_      _   /  _)        _   / _   _
(     /)  (-   /(_ /  (-  ( /  /     /(_)  () (/ _)   /   () /    /(_)  () (/ _)   (__)  /  () (/  /)
- Bringing you free subtitles       /                  Online  /  Since 1993    - /
-  |Africa| |Asia| |Australia| |Europe| |North America| |South America|   -  /
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+                          A big Thank You to EVERYBODY                            +
+        involved in making [closed capture] srt files and supporting us       +
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+