[ Orchestra:Fanfare]
[ Continues ]
[ All ]
Day of days
Wonderful day of love
Beauteous day
-[ Thunder Rumbling ]
-  Let the sun rise above
Glorious day
Making the sun appear
Beauty reigns
Over this day of days
Day of days
Wonderful day oflove
[ Thunder Continues Rumbling ]
Beauteous day
Let the sun rise above
Glorious day
Making the sun appear
Beauty reigns
Over this day
Of days
Papa!
[ Bell Clanging ]
Now that's the third time
she's run away from me
It's disgraceful
It's unbelievable
Why do you give me
nothing but trouble?
As soon as you're born,
your mother runs away
You're going to be married,
and your bride runs away
It's nothing but run, run, run!
- If only it hadn't rained
- What has the rain got to do with it?
In the sunlight, in the moonlight,
nothing could stop her
- But other women run away too
- But after the wedding
That's different
That's all right
Why didn't she wait that long?
Any decent girl would have waited that long
Ah, but not she
She is different
- Ohh - [ Groans ]
- She is wonderful Ohh!
Oh, why did it have to rain?
[ Guests Murmuring, Chattering ]
Your Grace, the guests are getting very excited
They want their presents back
What? Oh, no
The presents will not be returned
The Liebenheims
have never returned anything
Your Grace, may I suggest
perhaps a few words of explanation?
Very well Very well
Go and explain it to them
[ Murmuring, Chattering ]
- Shh!
- [ Murmuring, Chattering Ceases ]
[ Clears Throat ]
Uh, ladies and gentlemen
you are all here today
to attend the wedding
of two charming,
delightful people
And now you're surprised
to see me standing here alone
To tell you the truth,
I'm surprised myself
[ Murmuring, Chattering ]
No, no, no, no Please
You -You must not despair
I promise you
this wedding will take place
[ All ]
Ahh!
N-N-Not today, but, uh, someday
[ All ]
Ohh!
No, no, no, no
You must not doubt me I will find her
I will find her even if I have to
search the whole world
And I will bring her back
Nothing can stop me
I will bring her back
even if I have to drag her
I have a nasty temper
though I keep it in control
For, after all
I really am a simple-hearted soul
He's a simp, he's a simp
He's a simple-hearted soul
But when my seeds of kindliness
have failed to bear me fruit
I then become, I must confess
a nasty-tempered brute
He's a nas, he's a nas
He's a nasty-tempered brute
And now I've stood enough
I have to treat her rough
And show her I am capable
of caveman stuff
She'll love me and like it
When I start the strike
it will not be tenderly
[ All ]
What a man!
I'll win her, the sinner
By Harry, we'll marry
And she'll propose to me
[ All ]
Gorgeous, isn't he?
My papa tells me
I have charms galore
[ All ]
Ahh!
And I have never had
complaints before
We'll sail away soon
and on our honeymoon
-  She'll love me
- She'll love him and like it!
-  She'll love it
- Love him! Like it! Love him! Like it!
[ All ]
She'll love it!
Countess, please
[ Sighs ]
Whew The narrowest escape
I ever had
Five more minutes,
and I'd have been married
[ Shivers ]
I even had the wedding gown on
But fortunately it didn't fit
And suddenly I realized
it was fate
The dressmaker had saved the day
Oh, think what I owe
that dressmaker Mmm!
I owe him for the dress too!
- But, Countess -
- Oh, I know I know what you're going to say
I owe everybody
And here was my chance
Here was a chance to marry a man
who had everything a woman desires
He's rich, he's wealthy
and he has nothing but money
And how we could use it
And how!
Come in
Are you the lady who jumped
on this train after we had started?
Yes, and I shall complain about it
Trains don't go until I get on them
Oh! [ Chuckling ] Oh, pardon me
I've just come from a wedding
It isn't any of your business
where I've come from
Pardon me, madame
May I take the liberty of asking
where you are going?
I don't know
I haven't the slightest idea
Can't you make a suggestion?
Well, we go to Vienna
- Mmm
- Monte Carlo?
- Yes, madame
Two tickets for Monte Carlo
Yes, madame
Monte Carlo
Monte Carlo!
Bertha, how much money
have we left?
- Only 1 0,000 francs
- That's enough
With this 1 0,000 francs I'll win my freedom,
my happiness at the green tables
Let's see The first day
I'll win, uh, 50,000 francs
- But, Countess -
- No, no, no, no That's enough for the first day
But on the second day I'll take
the 50,000 francs and win 1 00,000
And on the third day 1 50,000
And then 300,000
And then I'll start!
I'll smash the bank
And that means millions Millions!
Listen, here's a puzzle
And believe me, it's hot
She comes from a wedding
She has nothing on
She's left her husband behind
She has no ticket
She has no idea where she wants to go
And she goes to Monte Carlo
How old is her husband?
Too old!
-[ Train Whistle Blowing ]
- [ Laughing ]
[ Orchestra ]
[ Continues ]
-  Blow, whistle
- [ Whistle Blows ]
Blow away
Blow away the past
-  Go, engines
- [ Whistle Blows ]
Anywhere
I don't care how far
On, on, from darkness into dawn
From rain into the rainbow
Fly with me
Gone, gone
All my grief and woe
What matter where I go
If I am free
[ Bell Clangs ]
Beyond the blue horizon
Waits a beautiful day
Good-bye to things
That bore me
Joy is waiting for me
I see a blue horizon
My life has only begun
Beyond the blue horizon
Lies a rising
Sun
[ Chorus ]
Beyond the blue horizon
Waits a beautiful day
Good-bye to things
That bore me
Joy is waiting for me
I see a blue
-  Horizon
- [ Chorus ]  Blue horizon
My life has only begun
Beyond the blue horizon
Lies a rising
Sun
[ Engine Chugging Rhythmically ]
[ Whistle Blows Twice]
[ Bell Clanging ]
[ Patrons Chattering ]
[ Croupier]
Twenty-nine! Black! Odd!
[ Chattering Continues ]
If I only had your luck
Tell me, how do you do it?
Nothing to it
I have a system that can't miss
If I happen to be standing
beside a brunette, I bet on red
If I'm standing next to a redhead,
I bet on black
But suppose you're standing next to a blonde
What do you do then?
[ Chuckles ]
I ask her where she lives
There's your blonde
Well, why don't you
go and speak to her?
- Don't tell me you're afraid
- I am
And for the first time
I don't know what's the matter with me
But I must have some excuse
If only she'd dropped something,
I - I could pick it up
If she only had a little dog,
I could get him to bite me
I've got it
You shall introduce me
- But I don't know her either
- That's the whole idea
You go up and speak to her,
she's very insulted
then I come up
and slap you in the face twice
Oh, no Oh, no
All right, then Once Go
[ Slap ]
Go and introduce yourself
Fifty francs, please, madame
Merci, madame
She is superstitious
[ Chuckles, Clears Throat ]
Uh, don't strike, madame
If you want any luck,
you must stroke - stroke caressingly
Naturally, not my back, madame
No luck to that
But the back of my head -
Stroke my hair and see what happens
Magic, madame
From then on, magic
Everything you touch will turn to gold
Millions at your fingertips
What? You don't want to?
All right, madame
But I warn you -
fail to do this, and you'll have no luck
You'll lose everything
You'll come out a beggar
But don't blame me when it's too late
Armand, if she wins now -
[ Giggles ] the rest'll be easy
- Bye-bye, old boy! [ Chuckles ]
- Good luck!
[ Croupier Speaks French ]
-[ Roulette Ball Drops ]
-[ Croupier Continues In French ]
- Who is she?
- She lives in the Palace Hotel
Think her name is Countess Mara
[ Croupier Speaking French ]
[ Roulette Ball Rolling ]
-[ Croupier] Sixteen!
- [ Murmuring, Chattering ]
[ Croupier Continues In French ]
[ Roulette Ball Rolling ]
She shall win She must win
She must win She must win
She shall win She mu -
[ Chuckles ]
- [ Croupier] Sixteen!
- [ Murmuring, Chattering ]
[ Croupier Continues In French ]
All on 1 6, please
[ Croupier Speaking French ]
[ Roulette Ball Rolling ]
[ Roulette Ball Drops ]
- [ Croupier] Sixteen!
- [ Murmuring, Chattering ]
[ Croupier Speaking French ]
- All on 1 6 again, please
- [ Croupier Continues In French ]
[ Roulette Ball Rolling ]
-[ Roulette Ball Drops ]
-[ Croupier] Sixteen!
[ Murmuring, Chattering ]
[ Croupier Continues In French ]
All on 1 6!
- [ Murmuring, Chattering Continues ]
- [ Croupier Continues In French ]
[ Roulette Ball Rolling ]
Hello? Hello?
Palais de Danse?
This is Count Rudolph Farriere speaking
I want a private dining room for two
[ Croupier]
Twenty-nine! Black! Odd!
[ Murmuring, Chattering ]
[ Croupier Continues In French ]
[ Muttering ]
Eleven - Four- Five -
[ Muttering Continues ]
Five hundred thousand -
Eleven and nine and four-
[ Muttering ]
makes two million
six hundred
and thirty thousand francs
That is up until
the 1 5th of September
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, 1 0, 1 1 -
Nine, 1 0, 1 1 -
Four, eight, six, 1 1
five, six, 1 1 -
Five million -
Good evening, Countess
You engaged the servants,
didn't you?
Yes, Countess, I did
Two valets, a chauffeur, a footman,
a hairdresser and an extry maid
That's good
And tomorrow they promised us
the other five rooms
We will have the entire floor
That's very good
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
" Dear Countess, please pardon me
for sending these flowers so late
but I had to get
the little flower girl out of bed first''
Such impudence!
- Good night
- Good night, Countess
[ Phone Rings ]
Hello?
[ Rudolph ]
Can't you go to sleep either, Countess?
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Rudolph Vocalizing ]
[ Continues ]
-  [ Orchestra ]
-  Pardon me, madame, if I
Seem a trifle bold
But my little story
Must be told
You are very rude
Who you are I do not know
But no true gentleman
Would annoy a lady so
Give me a moment, please
A moment, please
One word, one smile
One thrill
Fill me with ecstasy
And speak to me
You should, you must
You will
I never knew
That one like you
Could bring me to
My knees
Lift me
And let me rise
To paradise
For just a moment
Please
Give me a moment, please
A moment, please
One word, one smile
One thrill
Fill me with ecstasy
And speak to me
You should, you must
-  You will
- [ Receiver Settles Onto Cradle]
I never knew
That one like you
Could bring me
To my knees
Lift me and let me rise
To paradise
[ Humming ]
[ Ends ]
I tell you, she doesn't
even know you're alive
Certainly she does
I've written her every day this week
Yes, and nothing doing
I don't understand it
I've tried everything
No one could be fresher than I was
I don't know what to do next
[ Rerson Whistling ]
[ Whistling Continues ]
Give me a moment, please
A moment, please
A word, a smile, a -
[ Chuckling ]
You, uh -You know this lady too?
Do I know her?
[ Chuckles ]
She's, uh, the Countess Mara,
isn't she?
Quite right Countess Mara
Lives at the Palace Hotel
Third floor Rooms 300-3 25
Entrance: 306
- Where do you live, may I ask?
- At the Palace Hotel, of course
Uh, formerly I lived
at the Grand Hotel
but she insisted
that I move to the Palace
Well, you know what one will do
to please a woman
[ Both Laughing ]
Especially when she's so beautiful
Beautiful?
That hardly describes her
You have no idea how she looks How could
you tell,just seeing her on the street?
- Of course
- [ Both Chuckling ]
How does a woman look in the morning?
That's the time to tell
You should see her
in her negligee
Her neck and her shoulders -
[ Gasps ]
And that lovely blonde hair
But there's only one drawback-
she has no money
- What do you mean?
- She has no money at all
Well, one can't live on fresh air
You've said enough!
Do you know what you are?
Oh, no, I'm not, I assure you
For pity's sake, speak low
I'll do whatever you want
Only be quiet Otherwise, I'll lose my position
Your position?
Who are you?
I'm a hairdresser
The personal hairdresser of Countess Mara
- Her hairdresser?
- Yes, sir
[ Laughs ]
Well! This is getting interesting
Now you won't do
anything against me?
On the contrary
I'm delighted to meet you
- We must see a lot of each other
- Yes
We -We have mutual interests
[ Laughs ]
- We, uh -We must exchange ideas
- Yes, of course
- We -We must become friends
- Oh, yes
But there What am I saying?
[ Laughs ]
- We are friends!
- Yes, of course we are!
- Friends [ Chuckling ]
- Armand
I want you to meet
a very great friend of mine
- How do you do?
Yes
[ Laughing ]
- Who is he?
- [ Chuckles ]
- You don't know who he is?
- No
He is her hairdresser
[ Chuckles ]
and I -
[ Giggles ]
I am his very best friend
[ All Laughing ]
Allow me to introduce myself
My name is Count Rudolph Farriere
I'm delighted to meet you
My name is, uh -
Just call me Paul
[ Laughs ]
Just call him Paul
[ All Laughing ]
Paul?
Here's a lucky devil
and I surely envy him
For his store
of inside information
He is in his glory
when a lady wants a trim
Work to me is like a recreation
[ All ]
Oh, boy, what an occupation
Why waste away your youth
Searching for the naked truth
Why attend a college
Get your knowledge
Trimmin' the women
Ha!
Who needs a lot of Greek
To caress a lady's cheek
Couldn't you contrive it
while in private
Trimmin' the women
Now, if you care for beauties
-  Be a beauty specialist
- [ Chuckles ]
He caresses ladies' tresses
And they never resist
But why ply another trade
Barbers pet and yet get paid
You could make a sort of
indoor sport of
[ All ]
Trimmin' the women
[ Chuckles ]
Come here
[ Chattering ]
Why try to figure out
What this world is all about
Never mind the great books
Fill your date books
[ All ]
Trimmin' the women
Shy guys and those who feel
That they have no sex appeal
Get a lot of chances
for romances
[ All ]
Trimmin' the women
No hairdresser ever
Has to lead a double life
Now, he can pet a cute brunette
And still be true to his wife
But why sigh and yearn so much
For the skin you love to touch
Satisfy the craving
finger-waving
[ All ]
Trimmin' the women
Ahh!
[ Laughing ]
I've just heard a puzzle!
It's a hot one
She jumps on the train
She comes from the wedding
The husband is not with her
She is not dressed
She has no ticket
She doesn't know where she wants to go
And she goes to Monte Carlo!
How old is the hus -
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
- Oh, you are the new hairdresser?
- Brand-new, mademoiselle
You may come in
Try and keep me out
I hope the countess will like you
Paul has told me everything about her
I know exactly what to do
That isn't what counts The thing for you
to know is what you mustn't do
Don't ever try to tell her stories
Don't mention gambling
Don't talk about money in any way
In fact, don't talk at all
I understand
And remember,
the countess is very strict about this -
never flirt with chambermaids
- I never do
- Quite right
But to avoid any future misunderstandings -
[ Giggles ]
I am not a chambermaid
[ Both Chuckling ]
Still, I - [ Clears Throat ]
I never do
Now I will announce you to the countess
Bring her in
I am ready
How do you do?
- How long have you been a hairdresser?
- Oh, a long time, madame
I have served many, many ladies
- Where did you work?
- At home
I mean, uh, the - the ladies
always came to my house
Oh, yes Yes, of course Yes
- Uh, naturally, there'll be no more of that
- I realize that
You are in my employ now
and you will devote yourself entirely to me
Only to you, Countess
- And I hope it will not be a job for a day
- That depends entirely upon you
Then I'm sure it will be at least, uh -
[ Chuckles ] a week
Who knows?
Maybe for months
Maybe for years
Uh, who knows?
- By the way, what's your name?
- Rudolph
- Rudolph?
- Yes Rudolph
Rudy!
I don't like that name
I don't ever want to hear it again
Oh, but don't worry
It's not your fault
Let's see
I shall call you, um Paul
Just call me Paul
Rudolph!
Yes, Countess?
Didn't I tell you your name was Paul?
If you ever answer again to Rudolph, I'll -
[ Rhone Rings ]
Hello? Yes? Who?
Who do you wish to speak to?
Rudolph?
Paul For you
Thank you, madame
Pardon me, please
Hello, this is
Paul
Paul!
[ Chuckles ]
No Paul
R-U-D-O-L-P-H
Paul!
Yes! Paul is here too
What we want to know is,
how are things going?
What?
You are not alone
[ Laughs ]
He's not alone!
You can't speak?
Oh, I understand
Yes, well, I'll ask questions
and you just answer
Yes
[ Chuckles ]
Yes Yes!
No
[ Chuckles ]
Well, I hope so
[ Laughing ]
Good-bye
See you tonight
My servants
don't receive phone calls here
- Please remember that
- Quite right, Countess
And please don't ever make engagements
without asking me first
And you will not have
this evening off
You will stay right here
Thank you very much, Countess
You're making yourself
much too prominent
[ Crashing, Thudding ]
-[ Man ] Bags
- Yes All right Yes
Excuse me, madame
My baggage has just arrived
Well, don't unpack yet
I'm not at all sure I'm going to keep you
So far you've done nothing
but make me nervous
Now I'd like to see
what else you can do
Cut my hair
Haircut à la Marotte
The countess said " à la Marotte''?
Yes, yes À la Marotte
À la Marotte
Oh! [ Chuckles ]
Of course
How silly of me
À la Marotte
[ Laughing ]
[ Both Chuckling ]
[ Rudolph Continues Chuckling ]
And that's what you call a haircut?
Are you insane?
Yes, madame! Oh, Countess,
please forgive me, but I can't do it!
To cut that beautiful, lovely hair
would be nothing but cold-blooded murder
- You're discharged!
- Oh, please, give me one more chance!
I'll do anything!
Countess, please forgive me!
- I'll do anything you say I promise -
- I want you to leave this house
Rudolph!
Raul
[ Groaning ]
Ohh
[ Whirring ]
I don't ever want to see you again
I want you to leave
just as soon as you've finished
- Please, Countess
- Immediately
- And I'm not going to change my mind
- Give me one more chance
Please, please, Countess
Please, please stop bothering me!
Oh, I'm so nervous I could scream
- Oh, I have a headache
- Headache?
Oh, yes
And it's all your fault
No, no No, don't do that
Don't do that No
No, no, no, no! No!
No No No
Ohh Ohh
Ohh!
Oh, that feels good
Oh, that feels even better
[ Moans ]
Oh
You must have electricity
in your hands
Oh, I never felt like this before
Gorgeous!
Of course you'll stay
Thank you, madame
And whatever I call you -
Paul, Rudolph, or Rudy-
whenever I call you
please come
Countess, even when
you don't call me, I'll come
Madame, you inspire me now
Just try and fire me now
This is something new to me
It's hard to understand
I don't know what you do to me
Whatever it is
It's grand
Since we met today
I feel that I'm in wonderland
I can't explain
The way I feel
Whatever it is
It's grand
I've never known
a more delightful
Headache remedy
It's just as good
for broken hearts
And housemaid's knee
If my head should ache tonight
I'll need a helping hand
It may be wrong
It may be right
[ Giggles ]
[ Both ]
Whatever it is
It's grand
[ Typing ]
Honorable Countess
if your account with us
is not settled by tomorrow night -
Countess Mara, Palace Hotel
Dear Countess
we are sorry to inform you--
[ Typing ]
Rudolph! Have you gone
completely out of your mind?
No! Nothing like that
I just happened to mention
I was a good driver
and the next day
the chauffeur was fired
- And what do you think of this?
- What?
Yesterday I served her breakfast
and instantly
two lackeys were out of a job
In other words, I'm driving her car,
dressing her hair
waiting on her
Just wait till she fires her maid
No, sir!
It's an insult, sir!
Not a chance!
You can't bribe me!
And if you ever ask for the lady's address
again, I shall call the police!
Good-bye
See you later
Get out of my way!
Countess, you wanted to see me
about something very important
Rudolph, I'll have to discharge you
Sorry
But I'm not going
And it won't be so easy
to get rid of me either
Why, I - I never expected this I -
I've given up everything for you
The little business of my own I -
I've lost all the ladies I used to work for
My whole life
has been arranged to suit you
and now, for no good reason at all,
you want to kick me out
I know I know
Everything you say is true, but -
Well, I -
I simply can't afford
to keep you any longer
[ Doorbell Buzzes ]
Will you please open the door?
- What do you want?
- I want to speak to Countess Mara
Lots of people want that
[ Doorbell Buzzing ]
- What's the big idea?
- Please, sir Won't you listen?
Get out I don't want to waste time
mucking about with you
Your Grace What are you doing?
Please come in, Your Grace
Your Grace will excuse this?
He is a new man
He has no idea who Your Grace is
You'll get to know me
Rlease, Your Grace
Yes
[ Laughing ]
Helene
Do you know who that is?
That's her fiancé
Duke Otto von Liebenheim
[ Chuckles ]
Looks dumb, doesn't he?
[ Giggles ]
Do you know why?
Because he is dumb
Otto, I left you three times
because I wanted to be fair with you
But sometimes if one is in trouble enough,
the best intentions go up in smoke
Especially if one has all kinds of bills
no money,
and the hotel invites you to get out
No place to go
Well, in a moment like that,
one's not very responsible
One's liable to get
the most terrible idea
All right Marry me
Otto, if I were to promise to do so now,
it would be only for your money
And you dare tell me that
right to my face?
Yes I do
Oh, you are so different!
Where is there another woman
in the world
who would marry a man
only for his money and tell him so?
Splendid
You're beautiful
I'm rich
You buy, and I pay
You tell me everything
and I'll forgive you
It will be the happiest marriage
in the world
You're really very nice
I wish I could love you
You'll love me and like it
I'm wealthy but healthy
-  And I'll be true to you
-  What a man
My income is nearly
a million pounds yearly
But we could struggle through
if I cared for you
I'll build you castles, dear
beyond compare
I fear you're building castles
in the air
-  Imagine our thrills
-  Ah, but when you see the bills
-  I'll love you
-  And like it
I'll love it
[ Whistling ]
She'll love me and like it
[ Vocalizing ]
Good man
You shall stay with us
Rudolph
I think I'll be able
to keep you after all
Countess
I - I'd like to tell you a secret, but -
but I'm afraid you might fire me
- What is it?
- Well
it's not so easy to explain, but I -
- but I'm not -
- You're not what?
I'm not poor
As a matter of fact,
I have quite a nice little fortune
Now, if you would allow me,
I'd only be too delighted -
How dare you insult me
How dare you
Oh, please
Please don't send me away
You've misunderstood me
I only wanted to offer you some advice
Now, we're in Monte Carlo, aren't we?
Very well Now here's what I mean:
I didn't make this fortune dressing hair
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, no
- It was inherited
- Inherited?
I mean, uh -
I inherited, uh
from my father-
[ Chuckles ]
all my luck at gambling
I was not so fortunate
I never won in my life
Countess, won't you let me play for you?
Just once?
- No, no, no, no
- I have a system that can't fail
Don't tell me
I don't want to hear about it
- What is it?
- [ Chuckles ] I'll tell you
If I stand beside a brunette,
I bet on red
If I stand beside a redhead,
I bet on black
But what if you stand beside a blonde?
[ Laughs ]
Well, when I stand beside a blonde,
then it makes no difference at all
Red or black, black or red,
nothing can stop me I always win
All right
- We'll go and play tonight
- Yes
But -
But how can I go to the casino
with my hairdresser?
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, Countess Please don't worry
No one at the casino
knows I'm a hairdresser
My clothes are upstairs
and when the countess goes out
with me tonight
everyone will think
that I am the count
- Go and get dressed
- Yes, my countess
- [ Knocks ]
- Come in
I don't need you anymore
You don't look like a count
So much better
My last thousand francs
My happiness will be at stake, Rudolph
My whole future is in your hands
Because I feel the urgency
Of your supreme emergency
Madame, I cannot
and I will not fail
Come good or evil
take my all
On you alone
I stake my all
And let my castles either rise
Or fall
Forever
Always, in all ways
Rely upon me
Should any doubt come
Wait for the outcome hopefully
Always, in all ways
Whatever may be
I will rely on just you
And trust you
Sometimes, in small ways
We may not agree
But we will weather
hardship together
Wait and see
We'll have a happy ending
If you will keep depending
Always, in all ways
On me
Your sympathetic attitude
Has won my deepest gratitude
I hope we may not
have to say good-bye
If you should have to go away
I'll follow as a stowaway
Someday I may be able to
Repay
Your kindness
Always, in all ways
Rely upon me
Should any doubt come
Wait for the outcome hopefully
Always, in all ways
Whatever may be
I will rely on just you
And trust you
Sometimes, in small ways
We may not agree
But we will weather
hardship together
Wait and see
We'll have a happy ending
-  If I will keep
-  If you will keep
Depending
Always
In all ways
On
-  You
-  Me
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Man Speaking French ]
[ French ]
Eleven Black Odd
[ Laughing ]
I lost again
Bad luck in this game
Good luck with her
Oh
[ Man Speaking French ]
[ Clock Chiming ]
-  [ Trumpet: " Always In All Ways'' ]
- [ Chiming Continues ]
[ Chiming ]
[ Sousaphone: " Always In All Ways'' ]
Would the countess like anything to eat?
No, thanks
We've dined
The countess has lost
one of her buckles
Must have lost it
when we were dancing
But the countess
wanted to play tonight
Oh, yes
That's what we wanted to do
But Duke Otto was there, so, of course,
that made it impossible for us to stay
Well, we had to do something
So, we went out and
looked around
Bertha, you've no idea
how beautiful Monte Carlo is
The park- simply divine
And the promenade -
like a walk in the clouds
And as far as you could see,
not a soul
And so we sat down close
Very close
Uh, you see, I felt so cold
Yes, there's a very strong
sea breeze tonight
Yes Quite right Quite right
A very strong sea breeze
And when the countess felt so cold?
Well, uh, finally I became so -
I became so chilly
I didn't want to take any chances
What's the use of catching a cold?
And so I told him,
"Rudolph, we mustn't wait any longer
You go back to the casino alone
and play for me''
And so he went
And now I'm waiting for him
to come back
Oh, I wish he were here
[ Knocks ]
I don't need you anymore
Come in
200,000 francs
How dare you
That will be all for tonight
Give me a moment, please
A moment, please
One word
One smile
One thrill
Let me enfold your charms
Within my arms
You should
You must
You will
I never knew
That one like you
Could bring me to
My knees
Lift me and let me rise
To paradise
For just
A moment
Please
No more
I implore
Leave me till
Tomorrow
Always, in all ways
Until you agree
I will continue
Striving to win you
Wait and see
We'll have
A happy ending
If you will keep
Depending
Always
In all ways
On
Me
[ Chiming ]
[ Flute: " Always In All Ways'' ]
[ Chiming Continues ]
[ Chiming Ends ]
[ Knocks ]
[ Sighs ]
Come in
[ Door Handle Rattles ]
[ Sighs ]
Oh, where -
Oh!
Oh, the key
just a moment, please
[ Murmurs ]
[ Groans ]
This lock must be out of order
I'll tell Rudolph
Rudolph? Why Rudolph?
He's so good at so many things
He'll fix it
I found it last night on the floor
The countess must have put it on the table,
and the sea breeze must have blown it off
- [ Chuckles ]
- It's all right It's all right
The countess will pay Rudolph now,
won't you?
- Mm-hmm
- He hasn't been paid since he's been here
And he works so hard
He even works overtime
And now that we can afford
a chauffeur and a lackey again
I think we ought to hire them
And, Countess, really, if I were you
I wouldn't let my hairdresser
do anything else
but dress my hair
- Good morning
- Morning
Fix my hair, please
[ Chuckles ]
Well, I -
I thought this morning
would be different to this
I expected to tell you something
very important
- I'm not curious
- Something about myself
Something that -
that ought to concern you
I told you to fix my hair
- Helene -
- Please
Of course I appreciate
what you've done for me
I never was in such a situation before,
and you got me out of it
Please don't think I'm not grateful
Naturally you must know that
Why, last night I was actually
carried away by it
And now, uh, let's forget it
Just a minute
I don't understand
Do you mean that I'm to forget that -
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, no Not a chance
I couldn't forget it
And I won't forget it
If that's the case,
I'll have to return the money
Here
Now I want you to leave at once
So you can send me away like that
just as if nothing had happened
Well, that's pretty good
Do you know what I thought last night?
I thought you loved me
Can you beat that?
One often does things at night
one regrets the next morning
Yes And maybe ashamed of too, hmm?
Please Now, won't you
try to understand?
After all, there is
a little difference between us
The only difference between us is that
you're a woman, and I'm a man That's all
Oh, I'm afraid not
I happen to be a countess
Yes, and I'm a -
I'm a hairdresser
All right I am a hairdresser
Yes, that's me, and what of it?
Now I'll tell you something else
I fell in love with you because
I thought you were the perfect woman
Now I know you're only a conceited
countess and not much of a woman
And to me you're not a man at all
What's this?
I'm not a man?
No, not in my opinion
[ Laughs ]
Well, we'll see about that
All right
Now I'm not a man
- Come here!
- Open the door, and leave the room
Move another step,
and I'll call for help
Let go of me
Take your hand away
You brute
I'll scream so everybody will hear me
Oh That's what you get
for being nice to your servants
Good-bye
And now, madame,
forget all about this
as you will, no doubt,
by nightfall
I have already forgotten it
[ Rings ]
Madame Renee's Beauty Parlor
A hairdresser named Rudolph?
No, not with us I'm sorry
[ Chattering ]
[ Rings ]
United Hair Service
Who? Rudolph?
No There's no one here
by that name
What? He also answers
to the name of Rudy?
No
Well, I'm sorry, madame, but, uh -
- No I -
- [ Mouthing Words ]
Just one moment, please
Hello?
Are you looking for
a hairdresser called Rudolph?
Mm-hmm Tell me
What does he look like?
Oh, he looks marvelous
[ Chuckles ]
I see
What? Oh, you want your hair dressed
to go to the opera tonight
Yeah, well, I'm sorry I don't know him
I'll send you another hairdresser
What?
[ Chuckles ]
You don't want anybody else
[ Chuckles ] Oh, but, madame,
we have lots of good men here
Hmm?
[ Chuckles ]
There's no one like him?
Oh, madame, that's just
your personal opinion
Yes
Well, if nobody else will do,
I'm afraid you'll never get to the opera
Good-bye
Helene, it's 8:00
The opera will begin
Helene, the opera has begun
Will you please stop
making me nervous?
You know I can't go
until my hair is dressed
But, darling, you look
so beautiful the way it is
Nonsense And that shows how much
you know about women
All day long I've worn myself out
trying to find Rudolph
- Other men would appreciate that!
- B-B-But, darling -
Will you please do me a favor?
Go to the opera I'll join you
I promise I'll do everything I can
to find Rudolph
And when you do find him -
Oh, when I do find him
I'll never let him out of my sight
How dare you leave
without asking Countess Mara
If it happens again, I'll fire you
just a minute
Is he your hairdresser or mine?
Oh, go to - go to the opera
Immediately!
[ Chuckles Nervously ]
Very well, darling
I'm too nervous
She's very nervous
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Take your time
Rudolph
Rudy
[ Thuds ]
Do you know that I've been
looking for you all day?
So they told me
- And do you know why?
- Madame wants to go to the opera
No I don't want to go to the opera
No? Then there was no need
for me to have come
- Oh, yes, there was
- Madame, I'm here for one reason only:
strictly business
- So -
- Madame
what you have done to me
shall never be forgotten
But business is business
I had made up my mind
never to enter this room again
But when I heard you were
going to the opera, I said to myself
" Rudolph, here's your chance -
one you can't afford to lose''
Madame, as a hairdresser
I have the greatest interest
that you see this opera tonight
What do you mean?
I'll dress your hair
as I've never dressed it before
You'll be so beautiful,
you won't know yourself
And when you sit in the box with
His Grace, Duke Otto von Liebenheim
all Monte Carlo will look at you
All the ladies will envy you and say,
"Who is this great artist
" who can make a woman
look as beautiful as that?
We must find him''
And they will
I'll see to that
You mean I'll be an advertisement for you?
Yes, madame
- So that all the ladies will come to you?
- Yes, madame
- The blondes?
- Yes
- The brunettes?
- And the redheads?
- Yes, madame
Oh, no!
[ Sobbing ]
This is the way I'm going to the opera
Yes, and I'll show myself everywhere
In the balcony, in the orchestra,
on the staircase, in the lobby
And when anybody asks me who did it,
I'll tell them you did it
[ Sobbing ]
I'm going to ruin you
[ Orchestra ]
[ Woman ]
I love but you alone
I am forever your own
No matter what betide
No one can divide us
[ Horn Honks ]
Desist, Lady Mary
Do you know
this man is not a nobleman
-  He is a hairdresser
- [ Crowd Gasps ]
A common barber
[ Chorus ]  A barber, a barber, a barber
I am a mere hairdresser
I confess
But if I am
Do you love me
The less
[ Applause]
- Hello, darling
- Hello
[ Applause Continues ]
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Applause Ends ]
- Have I missed very much?
- Oh, no, no Only the first and second act
- I'm glad your hairdresser-
- Please don't mention him
I don't want to hear another word
about hair or hairdressers
What's the opera about?
I asked you what the opera was about
It's - It's all about a - a hairdresser
Well, I - I can't help it
I-I didn't write it
- Do you want to go somewhere else?
- No
What's the matter with this hairdresser?
Oh It's a silly story,
only possible with music
Imagine a lady falling in love
with a hairdresser
That's possible even without music
Things like that happen every day
I should say so
Tell me, uh, d-did - did she marry him?
Oh, no She had no idea
he was a hairdresser
- She's only just found it out
- Then, uh, what did she do?
- What could she do?
- She threw him out, of course
She'll regret it
Such stupidity
Oh, yes She'll discover her mistake
But then, of course, it'll be too late
It's always too late then
Think of a woman falling in love
with a man, then throwing him out
Well, there's no good end to that
Shall I tell you how it ends?
She'll marry a duke
It serves her right
[ Stick Thumps ]
[ Orchestra Resumes ]
- Is that the woman?
- Yes
I don't like her
She isn't even pretty
And look at the way she's dressed
[ Chuckles ]
And this woman has the nerve
to throw a man out
She's crazy
Lady Mary, tell me
Should he come back to you
what would you do?
What would you do?
The same as before
I'd drive him away
[ Clapping ]
[ Mouthing Words ]
[ Trumpet Fanfare]
Good sires and ladies
Prepare to make apologies
For a grievous mistake
The man we knew
as the barber Beaucaire
Is not a barber
And not Beaucaire
He is a prince
A prince of France
-  He is a prince
-  The barber is a prince
He is a prince
[ All Singing At Once]
-  He is a prince
He is a nobleman
-  The barber is a nobleman
-  He is a prince, He is a prince, a nobleman
- The barber is a nobleman
- He is a prince, He is a prince, a nobleman
- He is a prince
- The barber is a prince
- He is a nobleman
He is a prince
I have the most awful suspicion
Tell me, on your word of honor,
are you a hairdresser?
[ Chuckles ]
No
- Who are you?
- Allow me to introduce myself
My name is Count Rudolph -
- Farriere
- Yes, madame
Oh Oh
[ Chuckles ]
- I feel just as foolish -
- Yes, madame
I mean, I - I mean, I feel just as foolish
as the woman in the play
Yes, madame
- Count Farriere
- Yes, madame?
Rudolph, can you -
can you ever-
Your Highness, can you forgive me
There is nothing to forgive
Being a lady of propriety
You just obeyed
the dictates of society
But this I know
You never really
Loved me
So, fare thee well
My lady
Fair
[ Sobbing ]
Poor woman
[ Applause]
I don't like that ending
I like happy endings
[ Whistle Blowing Rhythmically ]
Beyond the blue horizon
Waits a beautiful day
The sky will smile upon me
While I know you love me
I see a new horizon
Our life has only begun
Beyond the blue horizon
Lies the rising sun
[ Whistle Blows Rhythmically ]