Telegram for Mr. Ellery.
Pardon me.
They call up at the last
minute and want tickets.
How can they do this?
Telegram, Mr. Ellery.
Give me.
I gotta take care of
the back of the stage.
Hello.
Telephone, Mr. Ellery,
Atlantic City.
The boss may be sick,
but he's not too sick
to keep us on the jump.
I got it. I got it. Hello,
hello. Yes, Mr. Carroll.
Yes, everything's all right.
Listen, will you
stop worrying?
Listen, Mr. Carroll,
your health is
worth more than that.
Well, listen, Mr. Carroll,
will you do me a favor?
Will you take your
arteries and go to bed
and forget about
the whole thing?
Yeah, yeah.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
Here. Put that...
They want you backstage,
Mr. Ellery.
Lander and Ware
haven't shown up yet.
haven't shown up. What am
I supposed to do here?
Go on and give
their performances?
Long distance,
Atlantic City calling.
You cut them off.
Listen, tell them I've died.
I can't be disturbed.
Telegram for Mr. Ellery.
All right.
Don't knock me down.
(CHATTERING)
Lieutenant Murdock,
of the Homicide Squad.
MAN: Well, what's the matter?
MURDOCK: I want my tickets.
I'm sorry, Commissioner.
There's nothing for you.
What?
I'm sorry.
Where's Jack Ellery?
He's just gone backstage.
MURDOCK: Hey!
Hey, you.
Where're those tickets
you were going
to leave for me?
Gee, Bill,
I forgot all about them.
Yeah?
Well, remember them now.
I'm going to hustle
over to the Astor
to pick up Ethel.
Oh, listen, I couldn't
get a couple of tickets
for the White House.
Would you like to stand?
What?
With me all laid
out like a funeral
and a dame on my hands?
What are you beefing about?
I got a show on my hands.
Say, that's nothing.
I got Ethel on mine.
I promised her.
Well, unpromise her.
Judas H. Priest!
Here you're bellyaching
about a couple of tickets
and I got a star
and leading lady here
that haven't shown up yet.
You can't get
away with this.
I promised Ethel.
Well, tell her
you can't show up.
What's the matter,
you afraid of that fluff?
What? Me?
Me afraid of a dame?
Hey, I'll tell a dame
anything I want to
and push her in the mush
if she lets out a peep!
(SCOFFS) Well, what
do you want from me?
Go ahead and...
Hey, a swell pal
you've turned out to be.
When you were
a cheap reporter
butting in around the
Police Headquarters,
did I ever give you
the runaround?
Oh, go away, will you?
You bother me.
I'm a busy man here.
All right.
That washes us up.
Just try and ask me
for a favor sometime.
Go away.
You're breaking my heart.
Out! Out! Out! Out!
Out, you!
Take it on the lam.
You take it.
Out! Get out, you big
mallet-head! Outside!
What kind of a place is this?
Opening night.
Get in there and
get your clothes off.
Oh, people are
so inconsiderate.
Oh, Mr. Ellery.
Not now, not now.
(GIGGLES)
That was grand.
I love the way
you sing that, Eric.
Thank you, dear.
But let's rush, darling.
We've got to get
to the theater.
No, no, not yet, Ann darling.
You must play it once more.
I must try my new
lyrics once more.
Come, just once.
Come on. Be a good girl.
There.
(SINGING)
In some secluded rendezvous
That overlooks the avenue
With someone sharing
a delightful chat
Of this and that
(MOUTHING)
And cocktails for two
As we enjoy a cigarette
To some exquisite chansonette
Two hands are
sure to slyly meet
Beneath a serviette
With cocktails for two
Oh, I adore
you, darling.
And I adore you, too,
but you'd better be careful.
You'll sing it
to me some night
like that onstage.
Well, I wouldn't care.
(SINGING)
With intoxicating kisses
For the principal ingredient
Most any afternoon at five
We'll be so glad
we're both alive
Then maybe fortune
will complete her plan
That all began with
cocktails for two
There you are.
(BOTH LAUGH)
(CLOCK CHIMING)
There's the clock.
We must go to the theater.
Come along, dear.
This is the happiest
night of my life, Eric,
and nothing,
nothing can spoil it.
Nothing, Ann dear,
nothing.
But there's one thing
I must tell you.
No, no, no, there's only
one thing you can tell
me tonight, darling.
Come along.
(CAR APPROACHING)
Oh, Judas H. Priest.
Listen, this is opening night.
Will you get inside here?
You're in here making
taxicab hocus-pocus.
Oh, this isn't hocus-pocus.
This is orange blossoms.
You mean you're
going to get married
and all that stuff?
We're going over
to Jersey and wake up
a minister after the show.
Oh, gee, ain't
that marvelous.
Can you imagine
buying all that
from a minister for $10?
And what a break
for the show.
Crooners make it real.
Say, listen, I'll have it
on the front page
of every morning
newspaper in the city.
Oh, but say, listen,
in the meantime,
would you mind coming
inside and getting busy,
please, just for me?
Shall we?
Let's.
Oh, grand.
Hey, listen, Lona,
have you got
a date for tonight?
LONA: I don't know yet.
Hey, listen,
you two can't get
married tonight.
Why not?
Well, wait till Sunday night.
We'll get a better
break in the Monday
morning newspapers.
ERIC: I'm sorry, Jack,
but we don't wait.
We take off tonight
and I bet we find you
crawling out of the
minister's nightshirt
with a couple of
newsreel cameramen.
They want you
out front, Mr. Ellery.
Oh, that Carroll's
blood pressure's going
up by long distance.
Good evening, Norma.
Hello, Norma.
Oh, Mr. Lander.
I hope you're a wonderful
success tonight
and that nothing...
I mean that everything...
Thanks, Norma,
I hope you like me.
Like you. Gosh.
I beg your pardon.
Oh!
Well, how long did it take you
to get a bottle of champagne?
Or maybe I'm wrong
and you're
the star of this opera
and I'm the hired girl.
I'm sorry, Miss Rita.
I stopped to
hear some gossip.
Gossip.
Dirt? Spill it.
Mr. Lander and Miss Ware
are gonna get married.
Married? Why, he can't...
Why not? He's gotta
get married sometime.
He can't always
play around.
Married.
And to that little...
After what I've been to him.
Oh, yeah?
Well, after what
I've done for him.
Why, I brought him
into this show.
You brought him in?
You and who else?
Just me.
Carroll saw me
in an act with him
and brought him along.
Listen, baby, blues
singers like you are
thicker on Broadway
than brunettes in Africa.
It was Lander
Carroll wanted.
He just brought you along
to hold his hat for him.
Is that the truth
you're telling me,
you broken-down clown,
or are you trying to ride me?
I wouldn't joke about a
thing like that, Miss Rita.
Isn't it just
beautiful and
romantic?
(SQUEALS)
WOMAN 1: Well,
get off the table.
How can I work
with you sitting on there?
I got dirt.
She's got dirt.
All Carroll's
children got dirt.
Dish it. Dirt's
no good cold.
It's Ross, and
is she burning.
Lander and Ware
are telling it to
the minister tonight.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
WOMAN 2: Honest?
WOMAN 3: You mean they're
going to get married
with a license and
a ring and what not?
What a funny thing to do.
It dates them,
like coffee.
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
(HUMMING)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Come in.
Good evening, Mr. Lander.
Good evening.
Oh, isn't it splendid?
They've been
turning people away
for half an hour.
Well, that's grand.
Here's your coat.
Thank you, dear.
Eric, Rita Ross,
she is very angry.
Now, don't worry, darling.
Oh, but this means so much,
this Broadway opening.
Wouldn't it be wise perhaps
to make up with her
just for a little while?
Oh, I know Rita.
She'll put on an act, perhaps
throw a tantrum or two,
but she'll survive.
Oh, I hope you're right.
Well, of course I'm right.
Nobody as happy as
I am could be wrong.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Five minutes to
overture, Mr. Lander.
Oh, and you are not
even made up, Eric.
I'll go.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Come in.
Just a gag, I guess.
That ain't no gag.
Don't be silly.
Number coming up,
Miss Ware.
ANN: Thank you.
(SCREAMS)
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
Ann, are you hurt?
I don't think so.
What's going on here?
Somebody tried to
drop a spotlight on me.
Oh, go on.
You got opening night nerves.
Anything wrong?
I thought I heard
a scream.
Come on, come on,
snap out of it, Ware.
Don't yell at her
like that, Jack.
Nobody's going
to hurt her.
It's just probably
some clumsy electrician
up there with
a hand full of thumbs.
And awhile ago
somebody smashed
my mirror.
JACK: What?
MAID: Yes, sir, Mr. Ellery.
Come on, I'll show you.
Are you all right, dear?
I guess so.
Of course you are.
Oh, I was so frightened.
No, you're not.
You must be.
Come on, you'll
be all right now.
You'll be all right now.
(CRYING)
I suppose it's a little
wedding gift from Rita?
Rita could pull the
theater down on us,
and we'd still climb
out and go over to
Jersey and get married.
And any accidents
that happen after tonight
happen to Mr. And Mrs. Lander.
You bet.
Oh, the door blew shut.
Gee, this theater's
as drafty as Times Square.
Listen, hear that?
That's the overture.
You're in the opening
number. Come on.
I'll be all right.
Go on then, dear.
Go on.
MAN: Hurry up. Hurry up.
JACK: Judas H. Priest!
Will you come on
and get on the stage
just for me, please?
This is opening night.
I'm only trying
to put on a show.
Come on, girls.
Go ahead, get on
the stage, will you?
MAN: Mildred LaRue.
All right now,
honey-bunch,
hop to it, and give.
(GASPS)
Oh, will somebody go up
there and tell those dumb
clucks to be careful?
Careful, my eye.
This rope has been cut.
Cut?
Oh, honey, don't
let that upset you.
Now, just go out there
and slay them, huh?
Consider them slayed.
Atta girl.
(SINGING) Ladies and gentlemen
We are pleased
to present again
With Mr. Carroll's permission
The latest edition
of the Vanities
As we display this grand array
of feminine charm and grace
We can see the
same old question
staring you in the face
Each year we hatch
another batch
of personalities
Eyes and lips
and hips and ankles
dimpled arms and knees
An endless supply
of loveliness that
never seems to cease
To you it's all a
mystery that can't
be solved by police
Lovely, languorous ladies
from each corner of the globe
Hello, honey, this is
Jack Ellery, backstage.
Listen, give me
the 47th Street
Police Station
right away, will you?
The last thing she said
over the phone was,
"You were going to
take me to the opening
of the Vanities.
"Now you want to shove
me off on a cheap
picture show. Nuts!"
Nuts? To you?
Yeah, nuts to me.
That's what my friend
Jack Ellery did for me.
(PHONE RINGING)
Washed me out
with a swell number
just as I was getting
places with her.
Imagine her saying
nuts to you.
(MEN LAUGHING)
OFFICER: Yeah.
Oh, is this funny.
It's your pal, Jack Ellery,
at the Vanities calling.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Says he's having
trouble backstage,
wants a couple of men.
Tell him okay. Hang up.
Okay.
I'll take that call,
and will I take that call.
Broke me up with
Ethel, did he?
Maybe I can do
some breaking, too.
Come on, boys.
ALL: Okay.
OFFICER: Sure, let's fix
ourselves up for the winter.
Oh, boy, the Vanities.
Hey, you stay here.
Maybe somebody
will go silly tonight
and want a cop.
Come on.
Oh, nuts!
(SINGING)
Where do they come from
And where do they go?
These glorious,
glorified creatures
Did they pose for billboards
or photographers?
Were they cigarette girls
or stenographers?
Did they hail from
Bridgeport or Kalamazoo?
How I wish I knew
Why am I puzzled
and when will I know?
Where do they come from
And where do they always go?
And where do they go?
These glorious,
glorified creatures?
Will they settle down
to happy marriages?
Playing bridge and
pushing baby carriages?
Or will they all wind up
as Hollywood queens?
On the movie screens?
Why am I puzzled
and when will I know?
Where do they come from
And where do they always go?
(MEN SINGING) We know
They come from the East
From dashing,
crashing mobs
Who hurry to their jobs
upon a subway strap
The busy, dizzy places
on the Eastern map
Now you see they
come from the East.
(MEN SINGING) No
They come from the West
From great open spaces
The figures and faces
are certainly best
(WHOOPING)
Just where they come from
By this time you know
Now I will show you
Exactly where they all go
(MEN SINGING) Lovely one
Your sweet exquisite
loveliness
Is ever haunting me
My lovely one
Your voice will
still be echoing
Through all the years to be
I can't forget
The beauty of your silhouette
Against the setting sun
Though we're apart
Within my heart
There lives an image
of my lovely one
Where do they come from?
And where do they go?
These glorious,
glorified creatures
Will they settle down
to happy marriages?
Playing bridge and
pushing baby carriages?
Or will they all wind up
as Hollywood queens
Mr. Lander.
There's a button loose
there on your coat.
The woman, she's in your
dressing room, waiting.
Well, have you had
any luck?
I don't know this lady.
Oh, that's quite all right.
You can talk,
but please hurry.
I got the things she stole
and you were right.
It was Rita Ross?
Well, there's the stuff,
and it was in her apartment.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
ERIC: Good.
Anything missing?
I don't know yet,
and I don't care.
I've got what I wanted.
So you're sure
you've got this
Rita Ross stopped?
What makes you doubt it?
Oh, I was just
looking through some
papers in her desk
and apparently she's written
the Vienna Police Department.
Here's their answer.
You read it?
No.
I just closed my eyes,
picked it up and
brought it along.
You read it, you spy.
You read it.
If you tell a single
word to anybody, I'll...
ERIC: Please.
HELENE: I warn you.
Please, darling.
Please be calm.
Oh, Eric, I told you
not to let strangers
meddle in your
private affairs.
Now, this...
Listen, lady, I mind
my own business.
Though I can see why
you might be interested
in this Viennese opera
singer of 30 years ago.
She won't say
anything about them.
Now they both know,
Rita Ross and this woman.
Listen, dear,
I'm not worried about her.
I'm going to see
Rita right now.
But Eric, you're on
the stage in just a minute.
This will only
take a minute.
HELENE:
I want to talk to you.
You're not paying me.
I've got some things to say
and you're going to listen.
Norma, will you
get me something?
Get you what,
Mr. Lander?
Just tell me,
anything at all.
Anything at all,
so long as it takes
those tiny ears of
yours out of here.
Go on.
You stole a photograph
out of my apartment.
I wouldn't say stole.
I just happened to be
looking through some stuff.
You weren't keeping it
under cover, were you?
What did you take it for?
It just seemed to be
a good idea at the time.
The dame in that photograph
must have been quite a bother
to the boys in
Vienna 30 years ago.
Why did you take it?
Elsie Singer,
and in grand opera, too.
Why did you write
to the Vienna police?
Nothing will come of that
if you don't get out of step.
I didn't tell them
that Helene Smith,
the wardrobe woman,
was Elsie Singer.
Rita, for 30 years
a woman makes amends,
suffers to keep
herself and her child,
and now...
You look a lot
like your mother
around the eyes.
Yes, she is my mother.
And she killed
a guy in Vienna.
He was a dirty rotten...
But he was a big shot
and the Vienna police
are still looking
for the woman
that killed him,
for Elsie Singer.
Don't all those
years of drudgery
and sacrifice
mean anything to you?
How are you and Ann
Ware getting along?
I hear you're
going to marry her.
Yes, tonight,
after the show.
Fine.
And when you read
about your wedding
on the front page,
right next to it
you'll find a piece
about a Mrs. Helene Smith
being pinched for murder!
You won't do that.
You like living too well.
Do that to my
mother and I'll...
You threaten me!
That's good!
Remember, you tell
that story to anybody
and I'll see that
you never tell anybody
anything again!
Judas H. Priest! The third
number's gonna be over!
Will you get on that
stage and break it up?
I've never been
treated this way
in my 57 years
in show business.
(MAN SINGING) Your love
song is my seventh heaven
Each note of my
heart beats rhythms new
What's gone wrong, Helene?
What do you want to
argue with her now for?
Wait till the show's over.
You'll have plenty of time.
Get on down there.
Don't worry about Rita,
my dear.
MAN: Mildred LaRue.
Eric, another minute
and they'll be off.
Okay, Jack.
What are you keeping
from me, Helene?
Rita Ross,
she knows about Vienna.
She does, does she?
Well, I'll talk to her.
No, I'll handle her.
You'll do nothing
of the sort.
Oh, you've been
very sweet and helpful,
but this is something
I've got to take
care of myself.
Whether you like it or not,
I intend to help,
and at any cost.
Homer.
MAN: Mildred LaRue.
Here's your wig.
Oh, Mr. Ellery.
Oh, not now, baby.
But...
Get on the stage.
Not now, dear.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Eric. Eric, come here.
Why don't you smile
for the customers?
Say, you ought to be
grinning from ear to ear.
You're marrying
this beautiful girl.
Say, I'm going to have
every newspaper man in
town at the wedding.
I'm afraid not, Jack.
What?
We'll have to
postpone the wedding
for a few days.
Why?
Oh, there's your cue.
Come on, get on the stage.
Watch out for that piano.
Get up there.
(SINGING) Today was so
depressing and so long
You were gone,
I was blue
Tonight I feel like
bursting into song
A song for you
Night winds are sighing
There's music in the sea
The whole world has joined
In a lover's rhapsody
What are the wild
waves saying to me?
Live and love tonight
Ripples of moonlight
illuminate the shore
Like beacons of romance
I never saw before
What are they all
conveying to me?
Live and love tonight
Sweetheart,
I've lived this moment
In all my dreams
All my life
I've waited for this moment
And now if we delay
Our moment may slip away
In my embraces
You haven't said a word
But I listened closely
And this is what I heard
Your heart beats cry
In rhythm with mine
Live and love tonight
Did you really mean
that we're not going
to be married tonight?
Yes, dear.
Something has come up.
Don't ask questions now.
Everything's going
to work out fine.
But if there's any trouble,
shouldn't I know?
(SINGING) Sweetheart,
I've lived this moment
In all my dreams,
all my life
(SINGING) I've waited
for this moment
And now,
if we delay, our moment...
Mr. Ellery.
What?
There's some
comedians out
there with flat feet.
They say they're cops
and that you sent for them.
Oh, yeah, yeah. Yeah,
couple of friends of mine.
I couldn't get them tickets,
so I'm going to let them
see the show from here.
It's okay. Send them in.
(BOTH SINGING)
Your heart beats cry
in rhythm with mine
Live and love tonight
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Oh, old crockhead,
so it's you.
Yeah, me.
I send to the Police
Station for a copper
and look what I get.
I thought this was
your night off.
So it is,
but I'd give up anything
to do an old pal a favor,
especially after all
the trouble you went to
about those tickets.
Oh, now listen, Bill.
You know I...
You can't square yourself!
What are we here
for, somebody
disturbing your peace?
Not mine,
somebody else's.
It seems that
somebody around here's
dropping sand bags
on the leading lady's dome
and trying to cut her up
with broken glass.
Say, boy, go back
to your bootleg.
This legal stuff ain't
agreeing with you.
Listen, mallet-head,
we got comedians
in this show
that get paid
to be funny.
Hey,
what do you want me to do,
make a pinch for false...
Judas H. Priest,
30,000 cops in New York,
and I've got to pick out
a big flat-footed
Romeo like you.
Why don't you take
your lamps off those dames
and do
a little police work?
This is police work.
Them babies look like
they got clues or something.
Oh, be serious,
will you, Bill?
Somebody around here's
committing merry mayhem,
maybe murder.
Why don't you kind
of peek around, huh?
Sure, I'll peek around.
Now, there's
a baby over there
that looks suspicious
and ought to be followed.
(LAUGHS) Don't get too
close to her or she'll
mistake you for King Kong.
Oh, Mr. Ellery.
Oh, not now.
Go away. Not now.
Oh, but...
(GIGGLES)
(SINGING)
Soothe me with your caress
Sweet Marijuana, Marijuana
Help me in my distress
Sweet Marijuana, please do
You alone can bring
my lover back to me
Even though I know
it's all a fantasy
And then, put me to sleep
Sweet Marijuana, Marijuana
You alone can bring
my lover back to me
Even though I know
it's all a fantasy
And then put me to sleep
Sweet Marijuana, Marijuana
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Get back here.
Come on, you big mallet-head!
First thing you know,
you'll be out
in the audience.
(SCREAMS)
What's that?
Don't you know?
Blood.
JACK: Hey, what's
the matter up there?
It's blood.
You're crazy.
That's paint.
WOMAN: There's
a woman up there!
MAN: There's nobody up there.
There is!
Quiet. Quiet.
There's a show
going on out front!
Hey, cork this place up.
And, Ben, you stay with me.
Okay, Boss.
How do you get up there,
or would you know?
Yeah, I know.
Probably some dame up there
got dizzy and fainted.
It's all right.
Come on with me, Bill.
JACK: Come on, come on!
Get this show going,
will you?
Get out on the stage.
If you guys want $5
short in your pay envelope,
just keep...
MAN: Mildred LaRue!
This is a great
spot for a girl
to pick out to
sleep out a drunk.
What is this?
What is it?
Listen, they got good cops
over there in Jersey.
What's her act?
You don't know?
Maybe she's one of
the Flying Ginsbergs.
Well, come on,
pick her up.
Are you going to
stay down there
and get married to her?
Yeah, she is dead.
What? Judas H. Priest!
Who is she, Jack?
Well, I can't see her face.
Wait a minute.
Mustn't touch
until the medical
officer says so.
MURDOCK: Now, who is she?
JACK: I never saw her before.
What do you mean?
Don't you know
everybody in your show?
Yeah,
I know everybody in the show
and that's the answer.
She ain't in the show.
Uh-oh.
No mouth burns.
Funny place to
pick for a bump off.
Yeah.
A million buildings
here in New York.
365 nights in a year,
but this dame's got
to pick this night
and this building
to commit suicide.
It isn't suicide.
It's murder.
What?
You mean somebody
chased her up here
and shoved that
stuff down her throat?
No, somebody pushed
this into her heart.
Well, I've finished.
You can take her away now.
MAN: Yes, sir.
Murder,
and my opening night!
What do you do in
a case like this,
give the people
their money back?
Oh, hey, Bill,
you're not gonna
close the show?
Oh, no, I'm going
to parade the body
and give 10 cents
a head to see it.
Listen, Bill, you
can't do that.
Don't you understand?
The boss is sick
in Atlantic City
and this is my big chance.
Asking me for
a favor now,
aren't you?
Yes, Bill, I am asking
you for a favor.
Listen. Please don't
close the show.
Nothing doing.
Pull your show.
Listen, if it wasn't for
me, you'd still be
pounding those pavements.
Wasn't it my paper
that went to bat for you
when the commissioner
broke Drake and McGinley?
Yeah, and tonight
you penciled me
out of my dame.
Go and make
your announcement.
The party's over.
Oh, listen,
I'll get you 50 dames,
but don't break me, will you?
Who owns this doodad?
I wouldn't know.
Sure, you wouldn't know.
Know anybody
around here who would?
Well, the wardrobe
woman might.
Well, let's go and
see the wardrobe woman.
Okay.
But first call off your show.
What are you going to do?
Go down there and
make an announcement,
I suppose?
"Will the killer
please step forward?"
Listen, Bill, let
the killer think, see,
that nobody's wise
and then you can
stand down there
and watch who's who.
MURDOCK: Nothing doing.
Can you imagine if
you went down below,
there see,
with the report in one hand
and the killer in the other?
Why, you'd come out
of the Police
Station a captain.
Just imagine that,
Captain Murdock.
Don't that just
roll off your tongue?
Captain Murdock.
Why, say, those two
words go together
like bacon and eggs.
Sure.
Maybe I'll
investigate this murder
to music for awhile.
Now you're talking, Bill.
Come on down here,
you can watch
everything from here.
Come on.
Why, what's wrong?
It's all right, darling,
I think she's just fainted!
You run along upstairs.
Run along.
JACK: Now, come on, come on,
get back everybody, will you?
Go on, get back,
will you?
Listen, boys and girls,
will you listen to me?
There's nothing
wrong here.
This lady just went
upstairs and got dizzy
and fainted. See?
So now, make your changes
for the second act.
And if you don't,
I'm going to rehearse you
all day Sunday
and then fire you.
Now go on,
move along now.
(CHATTERING)
MAN: Eight minutes.
Eight minutes change.
Come on, you only have
eight minutes for your change.
Down the stairs!
Come on,
down to the dressing room.
(CHATTERING)
You can't come in here.
There are girls.
We can go anywhere.
You the wardrobe woman?
Yes.
Well, do you recognize that?
Who's been wearing it?
Rita Ross.
That's all.
Well, Venus, where
have you been?
That...
There was a girl fainted.
Well, what of it?
Are you working for her?
I'm sorry.
Oh, go away!
Say, Rita, come here
a minute, will you?
There's a fellow out
here that used to go
to school with you.
There's a catch
in it somewhere.
I never went to school.
MAN: Come on, girls,
snap into it!
Rita,
this is Lieutenant Murdock
from Police Headquarters.
What have I done,
parked in front
of a fire plug?
You ever seen this before?
I wouldn't be surprised.
Yours?
Could be.
I don't care if it
could or it couldn't.
Is it?
I usually wear one like
that with this costume.
So what?
So, this.
Is she dead?
Yes.
Somebody pushed this
pin through her heart.
Oh, how horrible.
Do you know this dame?
No.
No. Pardon me for asking.
Of course you don't.
There's a hundred people
back of the stage here
and nobody's ever
seen her before.
I saw her.
Well, why didn't you say so?
You asked me
if I knew her.
I don't.
I see a thousand people
a day I don't know!
Go on, go on.
Where did you see her?
About a half an hour ago,
coming out of
the wardrobe room.
Wardrobe. Wardrobe.
Wardrobe. Oh, Ben.
Get the wardrobe woman.
Right.
And?
Mrs. Smith and that girl
had some kind of a row.
Oh, they did, did they?
Yes.
Mrs. Smith has
a duplicate of that pin.
Or did.
Where's your pin?
Right here.
Okay.
Here's the wardrobe
woman, Bill.
Mrs. Smith, have you
any more of these toys?
Things like that are always
carried in duplicate.
Well, turn it up.
It's gone.
Oh, it's gone, eh?
Yes, I looked,
after you asked for it.
Yeah, I had an idea.
A little birdie peeped
that you might
not find it there.
OFFICER: Hey, you
can't go in there.
HOMER: Take your hands
off of me, menial!
Who are you, and why
are you addressing this
lady like that?
I'm Police,
Lieutenant Murdock.
And who are you?
Mr. Boothby.
He's with the show.
The man with the
flying trapeze?
Sir, I have played with
Modjeska and Mantell!
Ah! That's their
grudge, not mine.
Now, keep out of here.
I don't care who you are.
I demand that you
cease the absurdity
of questioning
this fine woman.
Listen, Hamlet,
ever hear of a little thing
like interfering
with justice?
Justice?
"Oh, Justice, what stupidities
are committed in thy name!"
Scram out of here or
I'll have you committed.
Please, Homer.
Come on, Romeo.
I'm quite all right.
HOMER: Take your hands off me!
HOMER: I was never so
insulted in all my life!
(SIGHS) Now, then.
Why did you kill that dame?
I didn't.
I never saw her before.
(LAUGHS)
Is this the woman you heard
having a row with this dame?
Yes, and a hot one.
It's a lie!
It's the truth,
and I'll take my
oath on it in court!
Well, you had a row with her,
the pin is missing.
Now what does that add up?
I guess that's
all you want of me.
I've got to change
for the last act.
Maybe there won't
be any last act.
I'll be seeing you.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Let me see.
Yeah! Why did you kill her?
One of the boys
found this not far
from the body.
A private dick, hey?
You got a guy in this troupe
by the name of Lander?
He's the...
He's the leading man.
Ben, lead the leading
man of this troupe
of trained seals here,
will you?
Okay.
But Mr. Lander
couldn't have had anything
to do with this
terrible business!
Ain't that sweet of you!
Say, Bill, here's Lander,
but listen, he's got to
go on for the opening
of the second act.
Are you Lander?
Yes.
Do you know this woman?
Do my ears deceive me,
or am I at last
hearing a "yes"?
Who is she?
Her name's Sadie Evans.
She was a private detective.
Uh-huh.
Now we're climbing!
Say, listen, Bill,
my intermission's half over.
Now, what was your
business with her,
Lander?
Some things were stolen
from my apartment
and I hired her
to recover them.
Well, why didn't
you notify the police?
Notify the police!
He wanted to get
his stuff back!
Now, those stolen things,
what were they?
Purely a private matter.
Well, there ain't
no private matters
when I'm prying
into a murder case!
Now, come on, cough up.
My private affairs haven't
any connection with the
death of this woman.
Have a heart, will you?
Another minute and
he'll be too late
for the opening
of the second act.
Now quit stalling.
Stalling!
Everybody don't want
their private affairs spilled
all over the carpet.
Hey, this is
a murder investigation.
Yeah?
How'd you like to go out
and blab to everybody
about you and Ruby
sliding down
that fire escape?
What do you think
this is, a blackout?
(LAUGHS)
All right, well,
we'll put aside
the private affairs
for a minute. See?
Now then,
did you see this girl
talking to this
woman Mrs. Smith?
Uh-uh. I see!
Going to make sure
about telling
the same story, eh?
Lady, you better walk,
while I talk to
this man Lander alone.
Gee, Bill,
he's gotta sing!
Well, let him sing to me.
Now, come on,
lad, let's play Truth.
Either you or
Mrs. Smith is lying,
but I don't know
who's lying for who,
but it won't be long now.
Listen!
Will you listen to me?
This place is sealed
as tight as a drum.
Why ruin my show and
spoil this guy's chances?
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
RITA: Ellery! Jack Ellery!
Jack Ellery! Ellery!
Come on, come on, you dames.
On the stage! Come on.
Get away from that door!
JACK: Get down there!
What're you yelling about?
JACK: Go on,
get down there!
That!
Someone threw that at me!
A token of affection,
I take it!
Now, you wouldn't
know who that
belonged to, would you?
No, I...
I haven't the slightest idea.
Mr. Policeman,
that's half of
this woman's scissors!
Where's the other half?
I... I don't know.
You sure are the most
not knowingest woman
I've ever run into.
She killed that
girl and she just
tried to kill me.
What are you doing,
waiting for her
to drive past a red light
so you can arrest her?
You keep your mouth shut!
Don't you tell me
what to do!
Rita, don't start
an argument.
Come on, get on the
stage, will you?
Lieutenant, either
Mrs. Smith killed that
woman, or Mr. Lander did.
Look me up
after this number,
and I'll blow the lid
off the whole business.
(BIDDING FAREWELL)
I'll see you in the chair!
MURDOCK: How long does
the next number take, Jack?
JACK: About four minutes.
Well, I don't mind
watching the girls
for four minutes,
considering I'm going
to arrest a murderer
right after.
(SINGING)
I need you, my inspiration
For I'm faced with defeat
Without you,
this new creation
never can be complete
The whole world
would hear my masterpiece
If you would appear
Where are you?
(SINGING) My lover, I'm here
Love me
And floods of melody
will pour from your soul
Play on
For I can see immortal
fame as your goal
Someday the finest orchestra
will play my rhapsody
Someday I'll see my
dream turn into reality
All right, Boothby,
there's your cue.
Okay, lights!
Darling, you were grand!
So were you, darling.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYS)
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(UPBEAT JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) There's rhythm
down in Martinique Isle
That has any
minuet beat a mile
for low-down quality
And they call it
the ebony rhapsody
Instead of playing
music like you do
They supply a little
classical voodoo
They keep swinging
that thing while singing
the ebony rhapsody
It's got those licks,
it's got those tricks
That Mr. Liszt would
never recognize
It's got that beat,
that tropic heat
They shake until they make
the old thermometer rise
Oh, Lawdy, yes,
they have bandanas
They go to market
singing dirty hosannas
Swayin' to that
ebony rhapsody!
Give me that
prop machine gun.
Careful, Mr. Boothby.
The safety's off.
There you are!
Where's my drink?
Miss Rita, really
you oughtn't to...
Don't you tell me what to do,
you moonfaced...
Cut it out!
What are you trying
to do to the girl?
Nothing of what I'm
going to do to you
after this number!
Now you get out of here!
You're fired!
What happened?
Rita!
She says after this number,
she'll wreck Eric and me!
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(WOMEN SINGING) Fare thee well
Till I can be beside you
Once again, my love, my love
Fare thee well
And may the angels guide you
until then, my love
Get Dr. Saunders, quick!
I'll get him, boss!
Step aside there, girls!
Now listen.
Now wait a minute!
Now listen to me, everybody!
We've had a little
trouble here, see,
but everything's
gonna be all right.
So take it in your
stride like real
troupers, will you?
There's over 2,000
people out front
that've paid a lot of money
to come and see this show,
and they're entitled
to everything
we can give 'em,
don't you understand?
So kind of settle down
and give 'em the works,
will you?
Make your changes now.
(PERFORMERS CHATTERING)
Yes, she's dead all right.
Dead!
Yeah, she was going
to blow the lid off,
and now she's dead.
Does that add up
anything?
Listen, it might
add up to making
you look ridiculous
if you're not careful.
Yeah? Well, it's simple.
Mrs. Smith or Lander did it.
Lander wouldn't
do that, I know!
Yeah, you know!
She had to be shut up,
and somebody
shut her up pretty.
And it was your
wardrobe woman
or your tenor.
Wait a minute.
It could have been
the machine gun.
Did you ever stop to figure
that somebody could
have stuck a bullet
in there with those blanks?
Listen, sap!
How could one
bullet out of 300
hit a certain dame
just where it'd croak her?
No, no, no.
It was Mrs. Smith or
Lander did the trick!
Ben, get that Mrs. Smith.
And where did
that guy Lander go?
He went upstairs
about a minute ago.
Oh! Yes!
Mr. Lander! Lander!
Hey, Brownie, go get
Rita Ross' understudy
right away.
What's wrong with her?
She can't finish the show.
Go and get her,
will you? Go on!
I'm sorry, Mr. Ellery!
Haven't I got enough worries
without... Go away!
It's... It's you.
Are you looking for
something, Mr. Lander?
Are you looking
for someone?
Yes, where's Lander?
I don't know.
Are you sure there's nothing
I can do for you, Mr. Lander?
Something maybe
you'd like to know?
ERIC: That's nice of you,
Norma, but...
Something maybe
about Vienna?
Norma! Do you know?
Yeah, I know.
You know the letter
she got from
the Viennese police?
Yeah.
Then tell me!
Did she answer that letter?
Yeah, tonight, after
she'd talked to you.
Then it's...
Then it's all too late!
No, it isn't.
She thinks
it's in the mail.
Norma! I owe you
everything for that!
MAID: What's the
matter with you, man?
Don't you know
enough to knock before
you come busting
into a lady's room?
What's going on here?
Why, nothing.
What's this you're burning?
That? A note I was
going to leave for Rita,
but she'll be
here in a moment.
She will, will she?
Yes, she's got to change.
Well, she ain't
going to be here,
and her next change
will be in a wooden kimono.
What do you mean?
You're putting on
a good act, Lander.
She's dead!
Dead?
Yeah, and you know it.
But how should I know it?
You don't think I...
I did think,
but since catching you here,
I'm past thinking.
Come on.
I'm sorry, Mr. Ellery.
I've been looking
all over for you.
Where'd you find that?
I found it back of that flat.
Somebody threw it there.
Lander was standing there.
He could have tossed it.
Mrs. Smith.
Maybe Boothby.
Listen, don't say anything
to anybody about this, hear?
But won't I get
into trouble?
Don't say a word.
Shut up!
Oh! Mr. Ellery!
What do you...
Not now, not now!
Oh!
(GIGGLES)
But ain't you
going to turn that over
to the copper, Mr. Ellery?
Not till I find out
who it belongs to.
It's a cinch
it ain't Lander's.
It might be Mrs. Smith's,
it might be Boothby's.
But anyway,
I ain't going to give it
to that big flatfoot until...
Until the show's
over, anyway.
But do you think I'll...
Listen, go away.
You bother me!
Please!
You sent for me?
Yeah.
You know, I thought
you killed Rita Ross,
but I know now he did it.
He killed Rita Ross?
Is she dead?
Very.
You don't seem to be
upset much, do you?
She deserved to be killed,
but he didn't do it.
Uh-oh.
She deserved
to be killed?
It's stupid to think
that Eric... Mr. Lander...
Eric? Eric?
Say, what is it
between you two?
Why, not a thing.
Why, she just
mothers everybody.
Yeah, maybe she's
been mothering
the private detective.
It's a crime to get
a sweet old lady
all muddled up
the way you're doing!
Yeah, but it was the
blade from that sweet
old lady's scissors
that missed that
Ross dame's head.
And you, Mr. Lander,
was in the room with me.
And you, you sweet old lady,
just where were you
when the blade
from those scissors
was thrown?
Why, anybody could have thrown
that scissors blade.
Sure, anybody could
have thrown 'em.
Now, look here.
You had a row with
the private detective,
and Ross overheard you.
The blade from your scissors
was thrown at the dame.
I don't think she did it.
Now shut up, will you?
Now, the Ross dame
said she would spill
something about you
that would send
you to the chair,
and then the Ross
dame gets killed.
Why don't you
take me downtown
and leave her alone?
No, laddie, I ain't
gonna take you downtown,
but you've been
a great help to me.
Now go on, go out
and roll your hoop.
Right now this
old lady's my meat.
Oh, you!
Please, Eric, go!
Ben! Take this
Prince Charming outside,
will you?
Come on, come on, get out!
I'll have plenty
to say to you later!
Mr. Lander, your
number is on right away.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Say, Eric! I want to
see you a minute alone.
ANN: What's up?
Go on, Ann, exit.
This doesn't affect you.
It affects me if
it affects Eric.
Go on, Jack, she knows
everything now. What is it?
Well, listen, about Rita.
Did you...
Of course he didn't.
Did you bring
a gun in here tonight?
A gun? Certainly not.
Are you telling me
the truth?
Well, of course I am, Jack.
Okay. Then we'll
find out who did it.
In the meantime, get on
there and do your number.
Go ahead, kid.
Hurry, darling.
I'll be in time.
Don't worry!
(SINGING) Oh, what delight
to be given the right
To be carefree
and gay once again
No longer slinking,
respectable drinking
Like civilized ladies and men
No longer need we miss
A charming scene like this
In some secluded rendezvous
That overlooks the avenue
With someone sharing
a delightful chat
Of this and that
And cocktails for two
As we enjoy a cigarette
To some exquisite chansonette
Two hands are
sure to slyly meet
Beneath a serviette
With cocktails for two
My head may go reeling
But my heart will be obedient
With intoxicating kisses
As the principal ingredient
Most any afternoon at 5.; oo
We'll be so glad
we're both alive
Then maybe fortune
will complete her plan
That all began
With cocktails for two!
Find out anything yet, Doc?
Shot in the back.
It looks like a
small caliber gun.
A small caliber gun?
Why are you so anxious
to keep Lander out of this?
Had he anything
to do with this
mysterious business
you killed Rita for?
Judas H. Priest!
Now I suppose she did it!
It's a good thing
General Grant's got
an alibi.
Yes, and I suppose
you knew she didn't?
Sure, I know.
You know!
Why, she just confessed!
Confessed?
Yeah, why, sure,
I knew she or Lander did it,
so I played 'em up
against each other.
Yeah.
You killed Rita?
MURDOCK: You knew!
Smart Broadway guy!
Well, how'd you kill her?
Well, what does it matter?
It doesn't.
Look, and we've no
time for you now, Jack.
Listen, do one thing.
Tell me something.
You stabbed Rita with one
half of that scissors blade,
didn't you?
Is that what Dr.
Saunders says?
Quiet, quiet!
Well, that cinches it!
Answer me, Mrs. Smith.
You killed Rita with
that scissors blade,
didn't you? Didn't you?
Yes.
Yeah. What does
that add up to?
Well, it just adds up to
a washout, mallet-head!
Yeah!
Dr. Saunders in there
has just found
that Rita was shot
with a small
caliber revolver.
Yeah! Yeah!
Are you kidding?
Why should I kid you?
And I suppose you're going
to lock up Mrs. Smith here,
because she stabbed
Rita with a.32 revolver
at 16 paces!
Hey, go and rivet some panties
on your cuties out there.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Wise guy!
You always thinking
Smith and Lander did it.
What about this
guy Boothby out here?
No, no!
Anybody with half
an eye could see...
No, no!
...that he's in
love with the old dame.
Yes, yes.
He was handling
that phony machine gun!
All right. He might
have been handling
something else at
the same time, huh?
Ben!
Go and bring Boothby here.
Okay.
You're killing me!
Say,
I found
something out there
that might interest a good,
smart detective.
Of course, there's no use
my taking it up with you.
What is it?
Well, here, mallet-head.
I picked it up on the stage.
Can you make it out?
Uh-huh.
Yeah. Yeah. That's right.
Yeah, thanks.
It's Lander's gun.
What?
That's what the Bureau says.
Permit issued to
Eric Lander, actor,
54 West 54th Street.
I knew it! Come on, Ben!
Where's Lander?
He's up making a change.
How can I help when
I don't know a thing?
Every man for himself.
So that's it?
I'm sorry, Jack,
but there it is.
Oh! Gee, Eric, won't
you listen a moment?
Say, what are you doing here?
Nothing.
Hey, where's
that gun of yours?
I don't know anything
about that gun!
Yes, you do!
No, I don't.
Somebody stole it
out of my apartment.
Why don't you try
something new?
Didn't you steal it
yourself and bring it
down here
to bump off Rita Ross?
It was stolen.
That's all I know.
You got him.
Yeah. Give me that paper!
Whose handwriting is this?
It's no use, Bill.
I... I've been trying.
He... He won't talk
till after the show.
All right, Mr. Ellery.
He won't talk,
but you will!
Now come on, kick in.
You know something.
It'd mostly be
over your head!
Quit your stalling.
Now where's that gun?
Did he tell you where it was,
or have you got it?
Search me!
Well, that's an idea.
Come on, Ben.
Take it easy, will you?
I got you!
I thought I recognized
your handwriting!
So my old pal holds
out murder evidence!
Sorry, Jack, but this
puts the finger on you.
Now where's that gun?
Gonna be tough,
are you?
No, I ain't going to be tough,
and I'll play ball with you.
This show's got eight
minutes to run, see?
Now if you want that gun,
you're gonna let
me finish my show,
or don't you wanna do that?
I don't do no trading
in murder cases.
Yeah? Maybe you
won't have a case
if you take Lander
along with you.
If you haven't got that gun,
well, you got no evidence,
don't you understand that?
And that'll just leave
you a copper with a
remarkable dumbness!
Hey, you got a big house
here, Jack, tonight,
but there's a bigger
house up the river.
Yeah, I know that,
and if I flop with this show,
I just as well go on
up there and stay there,
you understand,
for the rest of my life.
And let me tell
you something!
If you want that gun,
you're gonna wait
eight minutes, see,
and that's flat and final!
All right, I'll let
you finish the show.
Now you're talking!
Wait a minute.
Stick 'em out.
Bill, you can't do that!
Come on, stick 'em out!
In case you try
to make a getaway.
That's a lovely dirty trick!
Yeah, you did me
a dirty trick, too.
And you'll be lucky
if you don't go down
for a long stretch
while your boyfriend's
sitting it out on
the hot seat.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
MAN: Mr. Lander,
the finale's on.
But how can I sing?
JACK: Come on,
do the best you can.
Do it for me, will you?
Roy, can't you
find Mr. Lander?
ROY: I'll try, Miss Ware.
ANN: Hurry, darling.
The number's half over!
I'm sorry, dear,
but I can't help it.
Eric, what is it?
Nothing, dear,
nothing at all.
Put your hands over, please.
That's us.
(SINGING) Sweetheart,
I've lived this moment
In all my dreams,
all my life
(SINGING)
I've waited for this moment
And now if we delay
our moment may slip away
In my embraces,
you haven't said a word
But I listened closely
and this is what I heard
(BOTH SINGING)
Your heart beats cry
in rhythm with mine
Live and love tonight
Well, old mallet-head,
this is the finale!
Looks like my show's
a big success.
Yeah.
Sorry you stuck your
nose in it, fellow,
but I gotta do
my duty, you know.
That's okay, pal.
Being's you been
such a nice boy,
well, I'm going to
give you that gun. Here.
Hey!
Where'd you have it parked?
(SHUSHING)
Don't tell nobody.
No!
(CHUCKLES)
You'd never've found it!
Well, it's a break for you,
you found it again yourself!
Yeah?
Yeah!
(ALL SINGING)
In some secluded rendezvous
That overlooks the avenue
With someone
sharing a delightful chat
Of this and that
And cocktails for two
As we enjoy a cigarette
To some exquisite chansonette
Two hands are
sure to slyly meet
Beneath a serviette
With cocktails for two
My head may go reeling
But my heart will be obedient
With intoxicating kisses
For the principal ingredient
Most any afternoon at 5.; oo
We'll be so glad
we're both alive
Then maybe fortune
will complete her plan
That all began
With cocktails for two!
Oh, what a delight
to be given the right
to be carefree
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Come on, little songbird!
No!
If it's okay to you,
I'll go up and
change my clothes.
As you are, young fellow.
I'm going with you.
I'm afraid
there isn't any room
in the bus, miss.
Eric!
Don't worry, darling.
Everything will be all right.
Come on, come on.
I'm cutting in here.
Come on.
No, you can't
take him away!
Norma!
Scram, lady, scram!
But he didn't do it!
Judas H... Something!
I've never seen so many judges
and juries before in my life!
I tell you
he didn't kill her!
Kill her! Which her?
Why, he killed two
of them and played
a part in the Vanities
in the same night.
That's pretty good!
Now, go on, scram,
lady, scram!
I'm gonna take him to
a place where he can
get a bit of rest.
I saw it done!
You saw what done?
Nothing.
I mean, Rita Ross.
She's been furious all week,
account of Miss Ware
getting the lead in the show.
And when she heard
Mr. Lander was going
to marry Miss Ware,
she just went wild!
I saw her sneak out
of her dressing room.
(MIRROR SHATTERING)
At first I thought
she only wanted
to queer Miss Ware's
performance.
And then I saw her
go upstairs,
and then I heard
the lamp crash,
and I knew she did it.
I'm asking you what you saw,
not what you know!
I suppose you saw her
cut the sandbag?
No, I didn't
know about that.
But she was away
from her dressing room
a long time,
and when she came back...
It was a bottle of acid.
I couldn't think what
she'd be doing with it,
so I followed her.
There was another woman
following her, too,
a woman I'd
never seen before.
Down on the stage,
Miss Ware was singing
with Mr. Lander.
Rita took out the acid,
and that woman saw
she was going to throw it
down on 'em.
Suddenly Rita's arm flew up.
I couldn't see
just what happened.
And then the woman fell.
So you can't arrest
Mr. Lander for that!
Sounds straight.
Nobody knew anything
about the acid.
But why didn't you tell me
Rita Ross murdered her?
I didn't know it then.
I saw the cops carrying
her into the stage
manager's office,
and Mr. Ellery said
she'd fainted.
I'd have told, all right.
Rita deserved to
go to the chair.
She was rotten
to everybody.
I'm glad she's dead!
Yeah. So you stabbed
her with the other
half of the scissors?
That?
She threw that at herself
just to make trouble
for Mrs. Smith.
She hated Mrs. Smith.
Yeah, so what?
Your story sounded on
the square, but now
you're all mixed up.
It sounds phony.
Come on, Lander,
I'll pick you out
a nice airy cell.
No, you can't take him!
I thought so!
You saw Rita Ross murdered.
You were there.
No, I...
You know who shot her!
Yes. Yes, I was there.
I'll tell.
But Mr. Lander didn't do it.
He was good to her.
Why, he got her into
this show, and he
was fine to me.
Why, he wouldn't let her
fire me lots of times,
and he stood up for me
when she beat me,
and made her stop it,
like he did tonight.
She hit me,
right in front of everybody.
I hated her
like I never hated
a human being before!
I got her gun.
I knew where she had it.
I wasn't going to kill her.
I was just going
to make her keep her
hands off me
if she'd come at me again.
I watched her
dancing and smiling,
and I thought
how black and mean
she was inside.
And then the music got wilder.
Everything was
whirling on the stage.
She was herself then,
just a she-devil
without a heart or a soul!
She had no right to live!
She deserved to be killed!
And then I saw
Mr. Boothby grab
the machine gun
and spray
the dancers with it.
I could feel every
shot crashing into
my brain
till I didn't know
what I was doing!
I prayed for him
to turn it on her,
with the bullets
tearing her to pieces.
And then I let her have it.
I killed her!
But you shot her
with Lander's revolver!
Mr. Lander's? Oh, no!
No! It was Rita's.
I saw it at her house.
I saw it at the theater.
Why, she must have stolen
Mr. Lander's revolver!
Tell me,
what was she going
to spill about him?
Why, she...
I never could find out.
She'd faked up
something or other.
Anything to break
off his marriage.
But it isn't going
to be broken off now,
is it, Mr. Lander?
No, Norma, thanks to you.
So it was the gun
you were trying to
get back, Lander?
You hadn't the nerve
to tell that new
sweetheart of yours
that Rita Ross
was running loose
in your flat.
Well, I hope
you don't have too
much explaining to do.
All right, Ben,
he's in the clear.
And you came clean,
old girl, and if I can
give you a break, I will.
And as soon as I've
changed my clothes,
I'm going out to find
the best attorney
in New York.
We're coming with him,
and all you have to do
is tell him
what you told us.
Thank you very much.
Bless you!
All right, Ben.
Come on.
You go ahead, honey.
Everything's going
to be all right.
Don't worry.
Well, do you
want me now, Bill?
What do I want you for?
All right, forget about it.
I'm sorry we tangled.
Forget about it, fellow,
forget about it!
Say, Bill,
tell me something.
How'd you like the show?
Hey, do you want
my honest opinion?
Yeah.
You big mallet-headed
lamebrain,
what do you know
about a show?
You've been hanging out
in that Police Station...
Mr. Ellery.
Oh, dear. All right, Nancy.
Now, what have you
been trying to tell me?
Mr. Ellery, what I
wanted to tell you was
that Rita Ross has
been stealing things.
What?
Yes, Mr. Ellery.
I saw her sneak
into the wardrobe
and steal a hat pin.
Judas H... Something.
There you are!
Why didn't you
listen to her?
Why didn't you listen
to her, mallet-head?
She wasn't talking to me.
She was talking
to you, brainless.
What a smart dick you are!
Why, take one look at a girl
and you can tell she's
got a clue or something!
Mr. Ellery!
What is it that I had?
Never mind, honey.
You still have it.
Say, how about
a little supper,
you and me?
Wait a minute.
Nancy's coming
with me tonight.
What?
Yeah.
And you promised me 50 dames
if I let the show run!
Yeah, I promised you 50 dames,
but she's 51 on the team.
You scum, you!
You wash me up with Ethel
and now you bust up
my night off, and well...
Well, just try
and ask me for
a favor sometime.
Yes, I'll ask you
for a favor!
I'll ask you for
a favor right now!
Shut up! Shut up!
Get out of the building,
you're bothering me!
Take that big
mallet-head of yours
and get out of here, please!
Cops hanging around a theater
give it a bad name. Go away!
You are beginning
to smell up the place!
(LAUGHS)
Well, Nancy,
what shall we do?
Oh! Mr. Ellery!
Uh-oh. Come on,
let's do it.