BOYS [SINGING]:
Hark the herald angels sing
Glory to the newborn king
Peace on Earth and mercy mild
God and sinners reconciled
Joyful all the nations...
There will be no peace on Earth
with all that blooming noise going on.
- Here you are, boys.
BOYS [IN UNISON]: Thanks, guv'nor.
BOY 1:
Come on.
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
BOY 2: All right, come on, hurry up.
BOY 3: All right, all right.
BOY 1:
Come on, this house here.
[SINGING]
Hark the herald angels sing
Glory to the newborn king
Peace on Earth and mercy mild
God and sinners reconciled
Joyful all ye nations rise
Join the triumph of the skies
With the angelic host proclaim
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Christ is born in Bethlehem
Infernal, horrible caterwauling.
Hark the herald angels sing
Glory to the newborn king
Why can't they leave a man
in peace?
Get on with your work, Cratchit.
Hark the herald angels sing
Glory to...
BOYS: Merry Christmas.
- Get away from me, you scavengers.
Blimey. Who's he?
That's Father Christmas.
A plague on Father Christmas.
And he sends his best
to you too, guv'nor.
[BOYS LAUGHING]
BOY 4: Regards, Father Christmas.
- Humbug.
Insolent young ruffians.
Coming here
with their Christmas nonsense.
Beware, Cratchit.
You have a dangerous
sense of humor.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Hell fire and damnation.
Don't they know
that I'm trying to run a business here?
Uncle Ebenezer,
I cannot tell you what a joy it is
to see your happy, smiling face.
- Hmm, it's you.
- A Merry Christmas, Uncle Ebenezer.
God save you.
God save me from Christmas.
It's a lot of humbug.
Christmas a humbug? Come now,
I'm sure you don't mean that.
And I'm sure that I do mean that.
Merry Christmas indeed.
What reason have you got
to be merry? You're poor enough.
to be miserable? You're rich enough.
There is no such thing as rich enough.
Only poor enough.
Don't be so dismal, Uncle Ebenezer.
What else can I be
when I live in a world
full of fools babbling Merry Christmas
at one another?
What's Christmas
but a time for finding yourself
a year older and not a day richer?
There's nothing merry in that.
If I could work my will, nephew,
every idiot who goes about
with Merry Christmas on his lips
should be boiled with his own pudding
and buried with a stake
of holly through his heart.
Oh, God forbid, uncle.
You keep Christmas in your way
and let me keep it in mine.
But you don't keep it.
Then let me... Get off my ledger.
You'll ruin my binding.
Then let me leave it alone, sir.
And be good enough to leave me alone
during business hours.
Seven o'clock on Christmas eve?
That's not business hours.
That's drudgery for the sake of it.
And an insult to all men of good will.
- Hear, hear.
- Thank you, Bob Cratchit.
Another word from you, Cratchit,
and you will celebrate Christmas
by losing your position.
Yes, sir.
Sorry, Mr. Scrooge.
You're quite a powerful speaker, sir.
I wonder you don't go into politics.
You're fool enough.
[CHUCKLES]
Come now.
Don't be angry.
Dine with me wife and me tomorrow.
As though
you hadn't got enough problems,
you went and got yourself married.
Now why in God's name
did you ever do that?
Because I fell in love with the lady.
If there's one thing in the world
more nauseating
than a Merry Christmas,
it's the hypocrisy of a happy marriage
with some idiot lovesick female.
Good afternoon, sir.
My offer stands.
You are always welcome, uncle.
Just like Christmas itself.
I said good afternoon.
Merry Christmas, uncle.
You too, Bob Cratchit. And your family.
Thank you, sir.
And to your good lady.
Oh, and uncle, happy New Year.
Good afternoon.
[CLOCK CHIMING]
Excuse me, sir.
But, well, it's 7:00, sir.
Correct, Cratchit.
Well, I don't wish to be impertinent,
Mr. Scrooge,
but, uh, would it be too much trouble
for me to have my, uh, wages, sir?
The trouble with you, Cratchit,
is that all you think of is pleasure.
Pleasure and squandering money.
You'll, uh...
You'll be wanting the whole day off
tomorrow, I suppose.
- If it's convenient, sir.
- No, sir.
It is not convenient.
And it is not fair.
Yet if I stopped your wages for it,
you'd think yourself ill-used no doubt.
And yet you don't think me ill used
when I pay a day's wages for no work.
Well, it is Christmas day,
Mr. Scrooge.
And it is only once a year, sir.
A poor excuse for picking a man's
pocket every 25th of December.
I don't pay good money for you
to be forever on holiday.
I appreciate your kindness,
Mr. Scrooge.
That's my weakness.
I'm a martyr to my own generosity.
I give you one Christmas day off
and you expect them all.
Very well, take the day.
Thank you, sir.
But be here all the earlier
the next morning.
Yes, sir. I will, sir.
Thank you very much.
Oh, and, uh, Merry Christmas,
Mr. Scrooge.
Be gone from here and take your
infernal Merry Christmas with you.
I beg your pardon, sir.
No offense, sir.
There's another one.
Fifteen shillings a week.
A wife and five children.
Still talks of a Merry Christmas.
[MERCHANT SHOUTING
AND CROWD MURMURING]
Boo. Kathy, my dear.
Tim. Oh.
Oh, you're both frozen.
I'm sorry I'm late.
But Mr. Scrooge and I had a lot
of last-minute business to attend to.
Well, my loves,
which one do you like best, eh?
I like that dolly in the corner.
I like all of them.
Ha, ha. Good boy.
And why not one in particular?
Well, you said
I can't have none of them,
so I might as well like them all.
Tim, you are a philosopher
and a gentleman.
And I've got 15 shillings in my pocket.
BOTH:
Fifteen shillings?
Fifteen shillings.
Which says that the Cratchit family
are gonna have as good a Christmas
as the lord mayor of London himself.
Oh, I do like that dolly in the corner.
[SINGING] Christmas children
Peep into Christmas windows
See a world as pretty as a dream
Christmas trees and toys
Christmas hopes and joys
Christmas puddings
Rich with Christmas cream
[LAUGHING]
Christmas presents shine
In the Christmas windows
Christmas boxes
Tied with pretty bows
Wonder what's inside
What delights they hide
But 'til Christmas morning
No one knows
You with five children, Bob.
Five for a shilling.
Thank you, John.
[SINGING]
Won't it be exciting if it snows?
I suppose that children everywhere
Will say a Christmas prayer
'Til Santa brings
Their Christmas things
There, my loves. I've bought you
the finest bird in the shop.
Well, for one and ten pence
ha' penny.
[SINGING] Christmas children
Live in a Christmas daydream
Waiting for the magic to unfold
Wondrous things to eat
Every Christmas treat
Rich or not
The Christmas pot of gold
Hypnotizes children young and old
[MERCHANT SHOUTING
INDISTINCTLY]
Quite right, Mr. Cratchit.
With your lot to feed,
apples at six a penny are the best bet.
I'd rather have the dolly in the corner.
I'd rather have the oranges.
And 1846 is the best vintage
in 20 years.
At that price it should be.
- Your change, sir.
- Thank you, Mr. Bissett.
- And a happy Christmas to you.
BISSETT: Happy Christmas to you, sir.
This will make the finest quality punch,
Mr. C.
And only tuppence a pint.
Christmas punch,
it's a Cratchit specialty.
[KIDS LAUGH]
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Four pence for a Christmas pudding.
Scandalous.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
JOHN: It's Papa.
- Where is he?
Here we are, my loves.
Look what we've brought for you.
And about time too, Bob Cratchit.
We were beginning to think
you'd all gone away for Christmas.
[SINGING] Christmas children
Hunger for Christmas morning
Thank you.
Christmas day's a wonder to behold
Young ones' dreams come true
Not so young ones too
I believe that story we've been told
You're not the only ones
who have been busy.
Come and see
what we've been up to.
Christmas is for children
Young and old
MAN 1: Uh, good evening.
MAN 2: Good evening, sir.
Have we the pleasure of addressing
Mr. Scrooge or Mr. Marley?
It's no pleasure to me, sir,
to be addressed by either of you.
And Mr. Marley has been dead
these seven years.
Seven years ago
this very night he died.
We've no doubt his liberality
is well represented
by his surviving partner.
[MAN 1 CHUCKLES]
Uh, Mr. Scrooge.
Uh, sir, at this festive season
of the year, sir,
it is more than usually desirable, uh,
that we should make
some slight provision
for the poor and the destitute.
Excellent. Then I suggest you do so.
You miss our point, sir.
The poor suffer greatly
at the present time.
Many thousands
are in want of common necessaries.
- Are there no prisons?
- Oh, indeed there are, sir.
That's something
there's no shortage of.
And the workhouses,
are they still in operation?
They are, sir.
I wish I could say they were not.
I'm very glad to hear it.
For a moment I was afraid
that something had occurred
to stop them in their useful purpose.
MAN 1:
Oh, but, sir.
A few of us
are endeavoring to raise a fund
to buy the poor some meat and drink
and means of warmth.
We choose this time, sir,
because it is a time when want
is keenly felt and abundance rejoices.
- What may we put you down for, sir?
- Nothing, sir.
MAN 1:
Ah, you wish to be anonymous.
I wish to be left alone, sir.
That is what I wish.
I don't make myself merry
at Christmas
and I cannot afford
to make idle people merry.
I have been forced to support
the establishments I have mentioned
through taxation.
And God knows
they cost more than they are worth.
Those who are badly off
must go there.
Many would rather die than go there.
If they would rather die
then they had better do it
and decrease the surplus population.
Good night, gentlemen.
Humbug.
Poppycock. Balderdash. Bah.
[SINGING]
Scavengers and sycophants
And flatterers and fools
Pharisees and parasites
And hypocrites and ghouls
Calculating swindlers
Prevaricating frauds
Perpetrating evil
As they roam the earth in hordes.
Feeding on their fellow men
Reaping rich rewards
Contaminating everything they see
Corrupting honest men
Like me
[SHOUTING AND MURMURING]
I hate people
People are despicable creatures.
Loathsome, inexplicable creatures
Good for nothing, kickable creatures
I hate people
I abhor them
When I see the indolent classes
Sitting on their indolent arses
Gulping ale from indolent glasses
I hate people
I detest them
I deplore them
MERCHANT 1:
Knives, scissors or razors to grind.
SCROOGE [SINGING]:
Fools who have no money spend it
Get in debt then try to end it
Beg me on their knees befriend them
Knowing I have cash to lend them
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Softhearted me
Hard-working me
Clean-living, thrifty
And kind as can be
Situations like this
Are of interest to me
It's Mr. Scrooge.
MERCHANT 1:
Knives, scissors or razors to grind.
Two pounds, 5 shillings, ladies.
Due before Christmas.
That means today.
But you see, Mr. Scrooge, sir,
we've been giving more credit
than usual.
That's your business, madam.
Mine is to collect
2 pounds, 5 shillings now.
We sell things for children, sir.
At this time of the year
people can't afford to pay.
Neither can I afford it, madam.
However, I will allow you
an extra week's credit.
BOTH:
Oh, thank you, Mr. Scrooge.
Which will only cost you
a further 12 shillings.
Twelve. Oh, but, Mr. Scrooge.
But we scarcely make
that much in a week.
If you would prefer me to confiscate
your store and its contents,
which is my legal right, I will do so.
- But we will pay, sir.
- We will pay, sir.
You'll both sign this.
MERCHANT 1:
Knives, scissors or razors to grind.
- And you can give me a pair of these.
WOMAN 1: Certainly, Mr. Scrooge.
Oh, look, there's that lovable
Father Christmas again.
MOTHER: Merry Christmas, sir.
A penny for the baby, sir.
[SCROOGE GRUMBLES]
MERCHANT 2:
Lavender. Sweet lavender.
[SINGING]
I hate people
I loathe people
I despise and abominate people
Move over.
Life is full of cretinous wretches
Earning what
Their sweatiness fetches
Empty minds
Whose pettiness stretches
Further than I can see
Little wonder
I hate people
And I don't care if they hate me
[ALL BOOING]
[KIDS LAUGHING]
Not now, Mr. Scrooge, please.
Two pounds 7 and 6, Miller.
And now is as good a time as any.
[IN SQUEAKY VOICE]
Stop it, stop it.
- But I'm performing.
- You're always performing.
- Where's my money?
- Tomorrow for sure, Mr. Scrooge.
After the Christmas morning show.
It's my best day of the year.
Tomorrow it will be 2 pounds 10
or I confiscate your puppets.
All right, Mr. Scrooge.
Two pounds 10.
[IN SQUEAKY VOICE]
Oh, what a pity. What a pity.
BOYS [SINGING]:
Father Christmas, Father Christmas
He's the meanest man
In the whole wide world
You can feel it
- He's a miser
- He's a skinflint
SCROOGE:
Bah.
He's a stingy lout
Leave your stocking out
For your Christmas gift
And he'll steal it
It's a shame he's a villain
What a game for a villain
To play on Christmas day
Hark the herald angels sing
Glory to the...
Thank you, guv'nor.
Father Christmas
Will be just as mean
As he's ever been
And I'm here to say
We should all send Father Christmas
Get out of here.
On his Merry Christmas way
Come on.
[BOYS CHATTERING]
[WHISTLES]
PHILLIP:
Wait for me.
Father Christmas
He's the rottenest man
In the universe
There's no one worse, you can tell it
- He's a rascal
- He's a bandit
- Scum.
- Come along.
He's a crafty one
Leave your door undone
He'll go in your house
And sell it
MAN:
Here's your money, sir. Pray count it.
You waste breath, sir.
No one has ever short-changed me.
[BOYS CHEER]
It's a crime
It's a scandal
What a game for a vandal to play
On Christmas day
SCROOGE:
Beat it.
TOM: Merry Christmas, sir.
Merry Christmas.
[CHUCKLES]
MERCHANT 2:
Lavender. Sweet lavender.
Sweet lavender.
Hot broth, Mr. Scrooge,
a small token of Christmas esteem
with the compliments of Tom Jenkins.
No.
And there'll be a free can of broth, sir,
every night for the coming year
in gratitude for your infinite kindness
in giving me another two weeks to pay.
One week.
- Ten days?
- One week.
- And put a lid on that stuff.
I'll take it home.
[SINGING]
If you distrust Father Christmas
It's as well to know
That we told you so
Because I'm here to say
We should all send Father Christmas
SCROOGE:
Beat it.
- Father Christmas
On his Merry Christmas way
[DOG BARKING NEARBY]
Scrooge.
Marley?
Humbug.
[BELLS JINGLING]
Merry Christmas, guv'nor.
Merry Christmas.
[WIND HOWLING]
MARLEY:
Scrooge.
It's humbug still.
I'll not believe it.
[FAINT LAUGHTER]
[BELL RINGING]
[CLOCKS CHIMING]
[RINGING AND CHIMING
INTENSIFIES]
[RINGING AND CHIMING STOPS]
Huh.
[CHAINS CLANGING NEARBY]
[GRUMBLES]
MARLEY:
Scrooge.
How now.
What do you want with me?
MARLEY:
Much.
Who are you?
In life, I was your partner,
Jacob Marley.
Can you sit down?
Of course I can sit down.
SCROOGE:
Do so then.
[SCROOGE SCOFFS]
You don't believe in me, do you?
No, I don't.
Why do you doubt
the evidence of your own eyes?
Because I've had a slight
stomach disorder.
It's undoubtedly affected my vision.
You're an hallucination.
Probably brought on
by an undigested bit of beef
or a blob of mustard,
or a crumb of cheese or an old potato.
Yes, that's what you are.
You are an old potato.
You do not exist, Jacob Marley.
It's humbug I tell you.
It's a lot of...
[WAILS]
No! I beseech you!
Stop!
Now do you believe in me?
I believe in you absolutely.
But why do you walk the earth?
Why do you come to persecute me?
And what is that great chain
you wear?
I wear the chain I forged in life.
I made it link by link
and yard by yard while on Earth.
And now I'll never be rid of it
any more than you
will ever be rid of yours.
Mine?
It was as heavy and long
as this seven Christmases ago.
It's a terrible ponderous chain
you are making, Scrooge.
Tell me more, Marley,
but speak comfort to me.
- I have none to give.
- None?
Comfort comes from other sources,
Ebenezer Scrooge.
And is given by other ministers than I
to other kinds of men than you.
When I lived, my spirit, like yours,
never walked beyond the narrow limits
of our counting house.
But you were always
a good man of business.
Mankind should be our business,
Ebenezer.
But we seldom attend to it,
as you shall see.
Marley!
[SCROOGE WHIMPERING]
Marley. Marley.
[SINGING] See the phantoms
Filling the sky around you
They astound you I can tell
These inhabitants of hell
Poor wretches
Whom the hand of heaven ignores
Beware
Lest their dreadful fate be yours
It was a dream.
[CHUCKLES]
Yes, that's what it was. A dream.
It's not a dream, Ebenezer.
For pity's sake, Marley.
Leave me in peace.
It was for pity's sake I came here.
Pity for you.
I leave you with just the tiniest chance
of escaping my fate.
You were always
a good friend to me, Jacob. Thank you.
You will be visited by three ghosts.
I... I think I'd rather not.
The first will appear tonight
when the bell tolls 1.
Couldn't I take them all at once,
and get it over with, Jacob?
The second at 2:00.
And the third when the bell tolls 3.
- I must go now.
- Marley, wait.
I'm doomed to wander
through the world
in everlasting repentance.
Remember
what has passed between us.
Farewell, Scrooge.
Three ghosts? Ha.
Three humbugs.
[GROANS]
[CLOCK CHIMING]
Half past 10?
Quarter to 11?
One o'clock?
[CLOCK BELL CHIMES]
Who are you?
I am the spirit
whose coming was foretold to you.
- You don't look like a ghost.
- Thank you.
May I enquire more precisely
who or what you are?
I am the Ghost of Christmas Past.
- Long past?
- No, your past.
- What business brings you here?
- Your welfare.
To be woken by a ghost
at 1:00 in the morning
is hardly conducive to my welfare.
Your redemption, then.
Rise and walk with me.
Where are we going?
We are going to look
at your childhood.
KIDS [SINGING]:
Sing a song of gladness and cheer
For the time of Christmas is here
Look around about you and see
What a world of wonder
This world can be
Sing a Christmas carol
Like the children do
Enjoy the beauty
All the joy and beauty
That a Merry Christmas
Can bring to you
Do you remember these children?
Of course. All of them.
London bridge is falling down
My fair lady
For the time of Christmas is here
Sing a song of sixpence
A pocket full of rye
Look around about you and see
Here we go round the mulberry bush
On a cold and frosty morning
Look, there's my little sister.
- Fran. Fran.
- Sing a Christmas carol
Fran!
Why doesn't she wave back?
She cannot see you.
These are but shadows
of the things that have been.
That a Merry Christmas
Can bring to you
I could never join
in those Christmas parties.
The school is not quite empty, is it?
A solitary boy neglected by his family
is left there still.
Poor boy.
I wish...
- What is it?
- Ugh, nothing, nothing.
What is it you wish?
There were some boys
singing a Christmas carol
outside my door last night.
I should have given them something,
that's all.
Let us look at another Christmas.
Ebby. Dear, dear brother.
- I've come to bring you home.
- Home with you, Fran?
Father is so much kinder
than he used to be.
He sent me in a coach
to bring you home, Ebby.
We're to be together
all Christmas long.
Go and fetch your things.
Always a delicate creature
whom a breath might have withered.
But she had a large heart.
She had. I'll not deny it.
She died a woman
and I believe had children.
One child.
Your nephew.
Yes.
There is a Christmas
that you really enjoyed.
Why, it's old Fezziwig alive again.
I was his apprentice.
Yo-ho, Ebenezer. Yo-ho, Dick.
Hi-de-ho and chirrup.
No more work today, me boys.
Hi-de-hi, it's Christmas Eve, Dick.
It's Christmas, Ebenezer.
Now come on, clear everything away
before a man can say Jack Robinson.
And make some room here
before Mrs. Fezziwig
and my daughters arrive
with the punchbowl.
SCROOGE: My word,
I am a good-looking chap. Ha.
And strong too.
I used to carry sacks around all day.
And that other fellow.
I remember him. Dick Wilkins.
Nice young fellow.
Very attached to me he was.
Dear, oh, dear.
[SHOUTING AND LAUGHING]
VIOLINIST:
Hey!
FEZZIWIG:
Mrs. Fezziwig.
[LAUGHS]
Me very dear friends.
There will now be happiness
and contentment in this room,
the like of which none of us
has ever seen before.
Begin.
[ALL CHEER]
[SINGING] Of all the days
In all the year that I'm familiar with
There's only one that's really fun
ALL: December the 25th
- Correct
Ask anyone called Robinson
Or Brown or Jones or Smith
Their favorite day and they will say
ALL: December the 25th
- Correct
December the 25th, my dears
December the 25th
The dearest day in all the year
- December the 25th
- Correct
December the 25th
FEZZIWIG:
Mrs. Fezziwig.
- December the 25th
- Correct
At times we're glad to see the back
Of all our kin and kith
But there's a date we celebrate
ALL: December the 25th
- Correct
At times our friends may seem
To be devoid of wit and pith
But all of us are humorous
ALL: December the 25th
- Correct
December the 25th, my dears
December the 25th
The dearest day in all the year
[ALL LAUGHING]
Why didn't you join the dance?
Because I couldn't do it.
[GHOST TSKS]
December the 25th, my dears
December the 25th
The dearest day in all the year
- December the 25th
- Correct.
If there's a day in history
That's more than any myth
Beyond a doubt, one day stands out
ALL: December the 25th
- Correct
I don't hear any arguments
So may I say forthwith
- I wish that every day could be
ALL: December the 25th
FEZZIWIG:
Hey.
Go on.
[ALL CHEER]
Now, go on, go on. Go on.
Oh, me?
[LAUGHING]
What a marvelous man.
What's so marvelous?
He's merely spent a few pounds
of your mortal money,
three or four perhaps.
What is that to be deserving
of so much praise?
You don't understand.
He has the power
to make us happy or unhappy,
to make our work
a pleasure or a burden.
It's nothing to do with money.
December the 25th, my dears
December the 25th
The dearest day in all the year
December the 25th, my dears
[FEZZIWIG LAUGHS]
Isabel.
Fezziwig's daughter.
You were going to marry her,
weren't you?
Yes.
[SINGING]
You, you were new to me
You, you were spring
You, you were true to me
You, you were everything
[SINGING] They say happiness
Is a thing you can't see
A thing you can't touch, I disagree
FEZZIWIG:
Hi-de-ho.
- Here we are.
- Yoo-hoo. Yoo-hoo.
Happiness is standing beside me
I can see him, he can see me
Happiness is whatever
You want it to be
Happiness is a high hill
Will I find it? Yes, I will
Happiness is a tall tree
Can I climb it?
Watch and see
They say happiness
Is the folly of fools
Pity poor me, one of the fools
Happiness is smiling upon me
Walking my way, sharing my day
Happiness is whatever
You want it to be
Happiness is a bright star
Are we happy? Yes, we are
Happiness is a clear sky
Give me wings and let me fly
Let me fly
[HORSE NEIGHS]
For happiness
Is whatever you want it to be
SCROOGE [SINGING]:
You, you were good for me
You were my day
Did all you could for me
I let you go away
I did love her, you know.
- Did you?
- Oh, yes, I loved her.
Then why did you let her go?
I've never been quite sure.
Then let us go and see.
- Ebenezer?
- Yeah?
I've come to say goodbye.
I am going away, Ebenezer.
You will not see me again.
But you were gonna marry me.
No.
You have found another love
to replace me.
She's much more desirable
than I am.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
This lady here.
How shall I ever
understand this world?
There is nothing
on which it is so hard as poverty
and yet, there is nothing it condemns
with such severity
as the pursuit of wealth.
You fear the world too much,
Ebenezer.
All your nobler dreams that I loved
I've seen die off one by one
until only the desire for gain is left.
I'm not changed towards you, am I?
Yes, you are.
Your promise to me was made when
you were poor and content to be so.
- You were someone else then.
- I was a boy.
You see?
Your own feelings tell you
that you are not what you were.
I see that all too clearly.
And so I can release you.
Have I ever asked to be released?
In words, no.
But in a changed nature, yes.
In everything that made my love
of value to you, yes.
If you met me today,
you would not love me.
- I would, I do.
- Shh.
- I still do.
- I'm trying to listen.
Isabel, I find it impossible to discuss
personal affairs during business hours.
Now, please.
ISABEL:
You see?
If you weigh me by gain,
I weigh very little.
And so I am not enough for you.
And I release you with a full heart
for the love of him you once were.
Say something, you fool.
Say something.
You may, for a little while,
have pain in this, but it will pass.
And you will dismiss the recollection
of it gladly as an unprofitable dream
from which it happened
well that you awoke.
OLD SCROOGE:
Don't go, it's a mistake. Don't go.
Be happy in the life you have chosen.
OLD SCROOGE:
Isabel.
Isabel?
[DOOR CLOSES]
You fool.
[SINGING]
You fool
I let you go away
And now I can see
Now you're a dream gone by
Oh, how could there be
Such a fool as I?
I who must travel on
What hope for me?
Dream where my past has gone
Live with a memory
You, my only hope
You, my only love
You, you
You
Spirit, remove me from this place.
I can bear it no more.
[CLOCK TICKING]
[SOBBING]
Stupid old fool.
Getting yourself all upset
over nothing.
It's all in your imagination.
[CLOCK CHIMING]
The first at 1, the second at 2.
I'm ready for you, wherever you are.
Nothing.
[LAUGHTER]
GHOST:
Ebenezer Scrooge.
Come here, Scrooge.
I'm waiting for you.
Or shall I come in there and get you?
I'm coming.
I'm coming, I'm coming.
GHOST:
Welcome, Scrooge.
Is it too bright for you?
Come over here, you weird little man.
I am the Spirit of Christmas Present.
Now look upon me.
You have never seen
the like of me before.
Never.
Yet, how many of my brothers
have you rejected
in your miserable lifetime?
I have never met any
of your brothers, sir.
You have never looked for them.
Well, how many of them are there?
What year is this?
1860.
Then I have 1, 859 brothers.
Each year at this time,
one of us visits this puny little planet
to spread some happiness,
and to remove as many as we can
of the causes of human misery.
Which is why I have come to see you,
Ebenezer Scrooge.
[SCROOGE YELLS]
You're a funny-looking little creature.
I must admit, I found it hard to believe
you'd be as horrible
as my brothers said you'd be.
But now that I look at you, I can see
they were understating the truth.
Let me assure you that I am a man
of the highest principles
and the most generous spirit.
Generous spirit? You?
You don't know the meaning
of the phrase.
But you're about to find out.
Now, drink this.
- What is it?
- Taste it.
SCROOGE:
Mm.
Do you like it?
It's wonderful.
I've never tasted anything like it.
Of course you haven't.
- What is it?
- The milk of human kindness.
There are more good things
in this life, Scrooge,
than you can possibly imagine.
I'm sure there are.
Can I have some more?
[SINGING] Ebenezer Scrooge
The sins of man are huge
A never-ending symphony
Of villainy and infamy
Duplicity, deceit and subterfuge
And no one's worse
Than Ebenezer Scrooge
Though man's a handy candidate
For hell
I must admit, life sometimes
Has its brighter side as well
I like life, life likes me
Life and I fairly fully agree
Life is fine, life is good
Especially mine
Which is just as it should be
I like pouring the wine and why not?
Life's a pleasure that I deny not
I like life here and now
Life and I made a mutual vow
Till I die, life and I
We'll both try to be better somehow
And if life were a woman
She would be my wife
- Why?
Because I like life
That's all very well for you,
but not for me.
I hate life.
Nonsense, man. Why?
Because life hates me, that's why.
Scrooge, you're an even bigger fool
than I took you for.
I've never heard
such a lot of self-pitying drivel.
You don't even know how to live.
Now you listen to me.
I like life
Well, go on.
[SINGING]
I like life
That's better.
[SINGING]
Life likes me
Good, good.
I make life a perpetual spree
A perpetual spree
Eating food
Drinking wine
Thinking who'd like the privilege
To dine me
I like drinking the drink I'm drinking
That's better, Scrooge.
I like thinking the thoughts
I'm thinking
I like songs, I like dance
I hear music and I'm in a trance
- Tra-la-la
- Oom-pa-pa
Chances are we shall get up
And prance
[SCROOGE LAUGHS]
Where there's music and laughter
Happiness is rife
- Why?
Because I like life
[SCROOGE LAUGHING
HYSTERICALLY]
BOTH [SINGING]:
Where there's music and laughter
Happiness is rife
Why? Because I like life
See how much we like life
[GHOST GRUNTS]
[GHOST CHUCKLING
AND SCROOGE GRUNTING]
What happened? What's happened?
What the devil am I doing in a pile
of snow in the middle of the night?
That's what I'd like to know.
Where are we?
Now, Scrooge,
over there lies the lavish home
of Robert Cratchit, esquire, who owes
both the opulence of his surroundings
and the magnificence
of his Christmas celebrations
to the high principles
and generous spirit of his employer.
Here. I want to look in the window.
It will cost you nothing, which I'm sure
will be good news for you.
Will they be able to see me?
No, which I feel sure
will be good news for them.
I could do with
another of them drinks.
Later.
For the time being, I think it better
you see things as they really are.
Oh, nectar. Pure nectar.
And at only tuppence a pint,
you can't really grumble.
What a tragedy it is that Her Majesty
and His Worship the Lord Mayor
couldn't be with us tonight.
They don't know what they're missing.
Now you try that, my love.
Mm. Bob Cratchit, you're a genius.
JOY:
The stuffing's ready, father.
The marriage of roast goose and sage
and onion stuffing  la Cratchit
is one of the culinary miracles
of our day.
[MRS. CRATCHIT CHUCKLES]
And a living legend throughout the
length and breadth of Camden Town.
Now, the only remaining problem,
my dear,
is whether to put the stuffing
inside the goose
or the goose inside the stuffing.
[KIDS LAUGH]
But since the ultimate intention
is to put them both inside ourselves,
I don't suppose it very much matters.
And here they are, the one and only
carol-singing Cratchits.
Newly returned
from their triumphant musical tour.
How did you do, Tiny Tim?
- Ten pence ha'penny.
- Ooh. Well done.
Another fantastic coup
by young Timothy Cratchit.
The financial wizard.
At only 7 years of age,
the youngest millionaire
in the vast Cratchit empire.
Ladies and gentlemen, if I may steal
a moment of your valuable time,
I would ask you to drink a toast
to the sparkling good health
of the two gentlemen
whose industry and generosity
have provided
our sumptuous Christmas repast.
- Master Timothy Cratchit.
MRS. CRATCHIT: Tim.
And Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
MRS. CRATCHIT: What are you
trying to do, ruin our Christmas?
But his money paid for the goose,
my dear.
No, your money paid for the goose,
But he paid me the money.
Because you earned it, my love.
Fifteen shillings a week
at three pence an hour.
And not a penny rise in eight years.
Believe me, you earned it.
Oh, Mr. Scrooge assures me
that times are hard.
He's right. For you they are.
But not for himself.
Well, nonetheless, he is the founder
of our feast and we shall drink to him.
Quite right.
You, listen to this.
The founder of our feast indeed.
I wish I had him here.
I'd give him a piece of my mind
to feast upon.
He'd have indigestion for a month.
CRATCHIT: Ethel, my dear,
the children. It's Christmas.
It needs to be Christmas, Bob,
to drink to a rotten, hard,
stingy old miser like Scrooge.
- But, Ethel...
- You know he is, Bob.
Nobody knows it better than you,
my poor love.
To Christmas, my dear.
Children,
we shall drink to your father,
for all the love and happiness
he gives us.
And to Tiny Tim
for the health we wish him.
And for the sake of your father,
I'll even drink to that old miser,
Mr. Scrooge.
Long life to him and to us all.
A Merry Christmas to us all.
Merry Christmas.
CRATCHIT:
God bless us.
God bless us, everyone.
As I said to the Lord Mayor,
if Her Most Gracious Majesty
is feeling bored, I said,
you wheel her over to Camden town,
I said.
A glass of Bob Cratchit's hot punch
and a song from Tiny Tim
and we'll have her back
on her regal feet in no time.
[KIDS LAUGH]
Well, there's your punch.
Now where's our song, my Tiny Tim?
KIDS: Tiny Tim.
- Come on, Tim.
- Song, song now.
[SINGING] On a beautiful day
That I dream about
In a world I would love to see
Is a beautiful place
Where the sun comes out
And it shines in the sky for me
On this beautiful winter's morning
If my wish could come true somehow
Then the beautiful day
That I dream about
Would be here and now
On this beautiful winter's morning
If my wish could come true somehow
Then the beautiful day
That I dream about
Would be here
And now
[ALL CLAPPING]
CRATCHIT:
Good boy.
MRS. CRATCHIT:
Well done, Tiny Tim, well done.
GHOST:
What an unpleasant child.
You know, Scrooge, there are
few things more nauseating to see
than a happy family
enjoying themselves at Christmas.
Do you not agree?
I think Bob Cratchit's
really rather fond of me.
Ho-ho-ho. And so is his wife.
Couldn't you tell?
She doesn't really know me.
That is one of the few things
wherein fate has blessed her.
And, uh, what will become
of Tiny Tim?
What's this?
Concern over a sick child?
Have you taken leave
of your senses?
Don't mock me, spirit.
Is the child very sick?
Not that it's of any great importance
to me whether he is or not, but is he?
Well, of course he's sick.
You mean he's seriously ill?
Will he live? Well, will he?
What does it matter to you,
Ebenezer Scrooge?
If he's going to die,
then he'd better do it
and decrease the surplus population.
We have one more call to make.
Ladies and gentlemen,
will you please honor me
with your undivided attention?
The time has come
that I know you all look forward to
in this house every Christmas Eve,
when I ask you to drink
to the good health
and long life
of my celebrated Uncle Ebenezer.
[DISCONTENTED CLAMOR]
Sounds to me as
if he knows I'm here.
Of course he doesn't.
He can't see you.
Harry, I've visited you every Christmas
for the past five years,
and to this day I can never understand
this extraordinary ritual
of toasting the health
of your old Uncle Ebenezer.
I mean, everybody knows
he's the most miserable old skinflint
that ever walked God's earth.
- Who's he?
- Oh, just a friend.
My dear Tom, it's very simple.
He is indeed
the most despicable old miser,
worse than you
could ever possibly imagine.
[ALL LAUGH]
- You find this amusing?
- Believe it or not, he likes you.
HARRY:
You see, I look at it this way:
If I can wish
a Merry Christmas to him,
who is beyond dispute
the most obnoxious
and parsimonious
of all living creatures...
ALL:
Hear.
HARRY: Then I know in my heart
that I am truly a man of goodwill.
- Scoundrel.
- Wait, there's more to come.
And besides, I like old Scrooge.
- What did I tell you?
HARRY: Truly I do.
I can't help feeling
that hidden somewhere deep inside
that loathsome old carcass of his
there's a different man fighting
to get out.
Be careful, he may be worse
than the one you know.
HARRY:
Oh, God forbid, Tom.
Anyway, that's the reason I ask him
to come here every Christmas.
In the forlorn hope that one day
he might pick up enough goodwill
to raise his clerk's wages
by five shillings a week.
MAN:
Hear, hear.
HARRY:
God knows it's high time he did.
He's playing
with other people's money.
HARRY'S WIFE:
All right, Harry, that's enough.
I refuse to have Christmas haunted
by Uncle Ebenezer.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
We'll have some dancing
and some music.
Then we'll play some
splendid party games.
There's a charming new game
called The Minister's Cat.
It's very funny.
You'll all end up getting
very angry when you lose.
And as for you, nephew,
if you were in my will, I'd disinherit you.
Scrooge. Come over here.
You need some more of this.
Hmph. Raise my clerk's wages.
[PIANO MUSIC PLAYING]
Mm. Mm.
[SCROOGE CHUCKLES]
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
[CLAPPING]
I know that tune.
I used to sing it when I was a lad.
KEN:
The minister's cat is a lonely cat
GRAHAM:
The minister's cat is a languid cat
GORDON:
The minister's cat is a lordly cat
MARY:
The minister's cat is a lazy cat
GUY:
The minister's cat is a ludicrous cat
HARRY'S WIFE:
The minister's cat is a lascivious cat
JAMES:
The minister's cat is a...
- Too late, you're out.
- Oh, no.
He's out, he's out.
He's out.
You see, they get furious
when they lose. It's lovely.
He's out, next M. Come on, M, M, M.
Now M.
The minister's cat is a marvelous cat
The minister's cat
is a marmalade cat
- Marmalade.
- The minister's cat is a miserable cat
- Miserable.
- The minister's cat is a merciful cat
- Merciful.
- The minister's cat is a... Uh...
Merry, say merry.
[ALL LAUGHING]
- Oh, damn it.
- I told you to say merry.
Why are you so stupid?
He's always been stupid.
- Stop yawning when I'm talking to you.
- What next?
- N, N.
- N.
- The minister's cat is a naughty cat
- Quickly, quickly.
- The minister's cat is a noble cat
- Noble cat.
- The minister's cat is a nebulous cat
- Nebulous.
- The minister's cat is a...
- Nasty cat.
- Oh, no, no.
- Oh, no, no, I'm not out.
- I was just about to say nasty.
- You fool, it's too late.
You could have said neglectful,
nervous, nauseating.
You're out, you're out, you're out.
The minister's cat is an orange cat
- The minister's cat is an old cat
- Yes.
SCROOGE: Look, I was
rather good at it but I... But I didn't...
Oh, thank you, my boy.
What a wonderful evening.
That Minister's Cat game, splendid.
I thought I was rather good at it.
Good night, good night. Thank you.
I can honestly say that I haven't
enjoyed a Christmas as much as this
since I was a young apprentice
at old Fezziwig's
so, so many years ago.
Yes.
What Christmases we used to have
in those days.
Fantastic they were.
He had this daughter.
Reminded me a little bit
of your mother, she did.
Her name was Isabel.
Oh.
Oh, Isabel.
WOMAN [SINGING]:
They say happiness
Is the folly of fools
Pity poor me, one of the fools
- Happiness
- Happiness...
Was standing beside me.
I could see her
She could see me
Happiness is whatever
You want it to be
Yes, Scrooge.
I have brought you home.
You're not going?
My time upon this little planet
is very brief.
I must leave you now.
But we still have so much to talk about,
haven't we?
There is never enough time to do or
say all the things that we would wish.
The thing is to try to do as much
as you can in the time that you have.
- Yes, but...
- Remember, Scrooge, time is short.
And suddenly,
you're not there anymore.
SCROOGE:
No, wait. Don't go.
Don't leave me.
Where are you?
Why is it so dark?
I can't see.
I can't see, I can't see.
I can't see, I can't...
[PANTING]
Oh, my God. What am I doing here?
Oh, I'm in bed.
That's what I'm doing here.
This is where I'm supposed to be
in the middle of the night.
Was I dreaming again?
I must have been.
That giant.
[CLOCK CHIMING NEARBY]
I must be mad. There are no giants.
[CLOCK BELL CHIMES]
There are no ghosts.
[GASPS]
Am I in the presence of the Ghost
of Christmas Yet To Come?
And you are to show me
shadows of the things
that will happen in the time before?
Is that so, spirit?
Ghost of the Future, I fear you more
than any apparition I have seen.
But as I know your purpose
is to do me good,
and as I hope to be another man
from what I was,
I am prepared to bear you company.
Will you speak to me?
The night is waning fast
and I know that time is precious to me.
Lead on, spirit. Lead on.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
There you are, me friends.
Shining as bright
as the happy thoughts
the mere mention of the name
Scrooge brings to our minds.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are gathered here today because
we are united by a common bond.
ALL:
Yeah!
Namely our feelings of gratitude
to Mr. Ebenezer Scrooge.
[CROWD CHEERS]
TOM: I don't think any of us
can ever hope to find the words
to describe the true depth
of our feelings towards him.
[CHEERING AND CHATTERING]
Is this the future?
All right, my friends, all right.
I understand your excitement.
That's Tom Jenkins,
the hot soup man.
TOM: We are all overjoyed...
- He owes me 6 pounds.
I must say he looks uncommonly
happy for someone so deep in debt.
All these people owe me money.
They love me and I never knew.
Kindly hold down your emotions,
if you please.
- Now, we are all deeply moved.
ALL: Yes.
And those of us what has been in debt
to Mr. S over all these years
will never forget
what a rare and beautiful thing
he has just done for us all.
- Right?
ALL: Right.
Three cheers for Mr. Scrooge.
- Hip, hip, hooray!
ALL: Hooray!
What did I do? What did I do?
Whatever it was,
it has made them truly happy,
and I am the cause.
My friends, I thank you
from the bottom of my heart.
I shall remember this moment
until my dying day.
[CROWD CHEERS]
ALL [SINGING]:
For he's a jolly good fellow
And so say all of us
[CROWD CHEERS]
May I say in all humility
[ALL CHEER]
I have labored unceasingly
all my life.
[ALL CHEER]
To be worthy of this
moving demonstration
of your feelings towards me.
[ALL CHEER]
Ladies and gentlemen,
on behalf of all the people
who have assembled here
- I would merely like to mention if I may
ALL: You may.
[SINGING]
That our unanimous attitude
Is one of lasting gratitude
For what our friend
Has done for us today
[ALL LAUGH]
And therefore
I would simply like to say
ALL:
You may.
Thank you very much
That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me
I may sound double Dutch
But my delight is such
I feel as if a losing war
Has been won for me
And if I had a flag
I'd hang me flag out
To add a sort of final victory touch
But since I left me flag at home
I'll simply have to say
Thank you very, very, very, much
[ALL LAUGHING]
Thank you very much
That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me
It sounds a bit bizarre
But things the way they are
I feel as if another life's
Begun for me
And if I had a cannon I would fire it
To add a sort of celebration touch
But since I left me cannon at home
I'll simply have to say
Thank you very, very, very much
For he's a jolly good fellow
And so say all of us
Thank you very much
That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me
It isn't every day
Good fortune comes me way
I never thought
The future would be fun for me
- And if I...
- Hey.
You've woken my baby.
Will you keep quiet?
Beg your pardon, lady.
[SINGING QUIETLY]
And if I had a bugle I would blow it
Shh.
[SINGING LOUDER] To add
A sort of how's your father touch
But since I left my bugle at home
I'll simply have to say
Thank you very, very, very much
No, no, dear friends.
It is I who should thank you.
- Thank you very much
Thank you very much
That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me
The future looks all right
In fact it looks so bright
I feel as if they're polishing
The sun for me
- And if I had a drum I'd have to...
- If I had a drum I'd have to bang it
To add a sort of
Humpty Dumpty touch
But since I left me drummer at home
I'll simply have to say...
The color hurts my eyes.
I mustn't show weak eyes
to your father when he gets home.
- It must be near his time.
- Past it.
But I think he's walked
a little slower these last few evenings.
MRS. CRATCHIT: I've known him
walk with Tiny Tim on his shoulder
very fast indeed.
But he was light to carry
for it was no trouble, no trouble.
Where is Tiny Tim?
Take me to him.
TINY TIM [SINGING FAINTLY]:
On this beautiful winter's morning
If my wish could come true somehow
Then the beautiful day
That I dream about
Would be here
And now
I must go now, my little fellow.
I promised your mother
I'd help her with the Christmas dinner.
I'll come and see you again
tomorrow.
Same time.
All right?
[SOBBING]
Oh, Tim.
Poor Tiny Tim.
Spirit, you've shown me
a Christmas yet to come
that mingles great happiness
with great sadness.
But what is to become of me?
No, no. Please, I beg you.
I've seen the error of my ways.
I will repent.
Truly, I will repent!
[SCREAMING]
Help! Help!
Help, help!
[RUMBLING]
[SNIFFS]
[MUTTERS]
[GRUNTS]
[SIZZLES]
VOICE:
Ah.
So there you are.
Marley.
Where am I?
I should have thought it was obvious.
I heard you were coming down today,
so I thought I'd come to greet you.
Show you to your quarters.
[SCREAMING NEARBY]
Nobody else wanted to.
[SCROOGE WHIMPERING]
That's very civil of you, Marley.
- I am dead, aren't I?
- As a coffin nail.
[CLANKING]
- I'd rather hoped I'd end up in heaven.
- Did you indeed?
You may find your office here
rather small, but not, I trust, unfamiliar.
Office?
Your activities in life
were so pleasing to Lucifer,
that he has appointed you
to be his personal clerk.
A singular honor.
You will be to him, so to speak,
what Bob Cratchit was to you.
That's not fair. Aah! It's...
- It's...
- Diabolical.
I must confess
I find it not altogether unamusing.
Here we are, my dear Ebenezer.
[BELL RINGS]
Your office.
It's freezing cold in here.
Lucifer turned the heat off.
He thought it might make you drowsy.
You'll be the only man in hell
who's chilly.
Watch out for the rats.
They nibble things.
Rats?
[WHIMPERING]
MARLEY:
Oh.
I almost forgot.
I knew there was something.
They apologize that your
[CLANKING NEARBY]
Chain wasn't ready for your arrival.
It's so big,
they had to take on extra devils
at the foundry to finish it.
It's even bigger
than I thought it would be.
Oh.
[SNICKERS]
Here it is now.
Don't let them do this to me, Marley.
I beg you.
That's quite a chain, isn't it?
Help me. Help me.
Bah, humbug.
Merry Christmas.
Don't leave me, Marley.
Help!
Help, help!
Help, help, help!
Help!
[GASPING]
Where am I?
I'm in my own room.
I'm not in hell at all.
I haven't got any chains.
Perhaps it didn't happen after all.
Perhaps it did.
But I'm alive.
I'm alive.
I've got a chance to change
and I will not be the man I was.
I'll begin again.
I will build my life.
I will live to know
that I've fulfilled my life.
I'll begin today.
Throw away the past,
and the future I build
will be something that will last.
I will take the time I have left to live
and I will give it all
that I have left to give.
[SINGING]
I will live my days for my fellow men
And I'll live in praise
Of that moment when
I was able to begin again
I will start anew
I will make amends
And I'll make quite certain
That the story ends
On a note of hope
On a strong amen
And I'll thank the world
And remember when
I was able to
Begin again
[LAUGHING]
I don't know what to do.
Yes, begin again.
I'm as light as a feather.
I'm as happy as an angel.
I'm as giddy as a drunken man.
A Merry Christmas, everybody.
Oh, Jacob Marley, wherever you are,
you shall see a change in me, Jacob.
I swear it.
[LAUGHING AND YELLING]
Boy. Boy, boy, what day is it?
- Today?
- Today.
Why, Christmas day, of course.
It's Christmas day.
I haven't missed it.
The spirits have done it all
in one night.
Well, they can do what they like,
you see.
Of course they can.
Of course they can. Ha, ha.
- Hello, my fine young fellow.
- Hello.
Do you know the butcher's
in the next street but one?
I should hope so.
What a remarkable boy.
An intelligent boy.
Do you happen to know
if they've sold the prize turkey
that was hanging up in the window?
Not the big one, the enormous one.
What, you mean the one
as big as me?
Ha, ha. What a wonderful boy.
So witty. It's a pleasure to talk to him.
- Yes, that's the one.
- It's still there.
It is? Go and buy it.
- What's that?
- Here's two sovereigns.
Go and wake up the butcher
and tell him to open his shop.
Meet me there in ten minutes.
Be holding that turkey
and I'll give you a half a crown.
Go on, run. Run, run.
Run, run.
Oh, what a lovely boy.
I think I'm gonna like children.
Now, that's what I call a turkey.
It's twice the size of Tiny Tim.
Come on, dear boy.
Let's go and open the toy shop.
Thank you. Merry Christmas.
And I'll have that and some of those.
And the hobby horse,
and then some flutes and...
And some trumpets.
And that doll.
- And some bows and arrows.
- Bow and arrows.
Yes and... Oh, yes, and I...
- I must have a cricket bat.
- Ha, ha.
And these, and these.
And a horse and a spinning top.
And a piano.
And... And all those dolls.
- All of them?
- Yes.
I like that one.
Oh, and this beautiful coach.
- And several kites and the horse.
- Yes, yes.
- And these boats.
- Yes.
And some of these.
Oh!
I'll have that.
Now, how much is all this?
- Oh. Uh... Oh.
- Well, never mind.
Here are some sovereigns
and you can keep the change.
Oh, thank you, Mr. Scrooge.
And I shall require
the services of several small boys
to help to transport these
delightful objects to their destination.
And each boy shall receive
a half a crown.
Half a crown, yes, Mr. Scrooge.
Mr. Scrooge, what has happened?
What happened is perfectly simple,
Pringle.
I've discovered that I like life.
[KIDS LAUGHING]
[SINGING]
I like life
Life likes me
Life and I fairly fully agree
Life is fine
Life is good
Especially mine
Which is just as it should be
I like pouring the wine and why not?
Life's a pleasure that I deny not
I like life, here and now
Life and I made a mutual vow
Till I die, life and I
We'll both try to be better somehow
And if life were a woman
She would be my wife
[KIDS LAUGH]
Why?
Because I like life
[KIDS CHEER]
SCROOGE:
Oh, look, a slide.
No, let me. Let me, let me.
[YELLS THEN GRUNTS]
[ALL LAUGHING]
[SINGING]
I like life
Life likes me
I'll make life a perpetual spree
Eating food, drinking wine
Thinking who'll have the privilege
To dine me
I like living the life of pleasure
Pausing only to take my leisure
I like songs, I like dance
I hear music and I'm in a trance
[PLAYING PLEASANT MELODY]
Tra-la-la, oom-pa-pa
Chances are I shall get up and prance
[SCROOGE HUMMING]
Where's there's music and laughter
Happiness is rife
KIDS: Why?
- Why?
Because I like life
Uncle Ebenezer.
Oh, Merry Christmas to you,
my dear nephew.
And to your enchanting wife.
We were just on our way
to your house with some presents.
These are for you.
From an old fool who deeply regrets
the Christmases gone by
that he might have shared with you,
and...
This is for you, my dear.
A sort of belated wedding present.
Oh, Uncle Ebenezer, thank you.
Christmas lunch is sharp at 3.
May we expect you?
You may.
I'll be there. Oh, you are a pretty girl.
[ALL SINGING]
I like songs, I like dance
I hear music and I'm in a trance
Tra-la-la, oom-pa-pa
Chances are
I shall get up and prance
Where there's music and laughter
Happiness is rife
Why?
Because I like life
Father Christmas
He's the greatest man
In the whole wide world
And he knows it
Every Christmas, Father Christmas
Puts a great big sack
On his dear old back
Because he loves us all
And he knows it
And he goes for a sleigh ride
If it snows, then he may ride all night
But that's all right
[LAUGHING]
KIDS:
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
SCROOGE:
Hey, hey, hey.
KIDS: In the morning
SCROOGE: In the morning
KIDS: Christmas morning
SCROOGE: Christmas morning
If you lift your eyes
There's a big surprise
On your bed you'll see
There's a gift from Father Christmas
From Father Christmas
- That's how Christmas ought to be
- Ha, ha. Hey!
Merry Christmas.
A Merry Christmas to you, sir,
from Father Christmas himself.
MRS. CRATCHIT:
Oh, dear.
Don't worry about your goose,
Mrs. Cratchit.
You can use it as stuffing for this.
Now, where are the other presents?
This dolly is for you, my dear.
And this one is for you.
And this pretty little dolly is for you.
It's the dolly in the corner.
[SCROOGE CHUCKLES]
- And those are for you, my boy.
- Thank you.
And these, Bob Cratchit,
are for you and your good lady.
I must leave you now.
As you can imagine,
it's a very busy day for me.
And I have many more calls to make.
Ah! I almost forgot.
[KIDS CHATTERING]
This is for you.
You didn't steal it, did you?
Ha, ha. No, I didn't steal it.
It's a present for you to keep.
A Merry Christmas, Tiny Tim.
You still don't recognize me,
do you, Bob Cratchit?
Yes. Uh, no.
- You're Father Christmas?
- No.
[SHRIEKS]
It's Mr. Scrooge. He's gone mad.
It's all right, my dear.
There's nothing to be frightened of.
No, I haven't gone mad.
And on Monday
when your salary will be doubled...
Doubled? He has gone mad.
- We'll sit together and discuss
how I can help your family.
To start with, we'll find the right
doctors to get Tiny Tim well.
And we will get him well,
you know, Bob.
Yes, I believe you.
I'll believe anything.
And may this be the merriest
Christmas of all our lives.
[CHEERING]
Tom Jenkins, Tom Jenkins.
About that 6 pounds you owe me.
You agreed to give me
a few more days, I just need...
You can keep it.
It's my Christmas present to you.
God bless you this Christmas day,
Mr. Scrooge.
Thank you very much.
[SINGING]
Thank you very much
That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me
It sounds a bit bizarre
But things the way they are
I feel as if another life's begun for me
And that goes for anyone else
who owes me money, you can keep it.
As of this day,
all my debts are ended.
[ALL SINGING] And if I had a drum
I'd have to bang it
To add a sort of
Humpty Dumpty touch
But since I left my drummer at home
I'll simply have to say
Thank you very, very, very much
PUPPETS [SINGING]:
Thank you very much
That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me
It isn't every day
Good fortune comes my way
I never thought
The future would be fun for me
And if I had a bugle I would blow it
To add a sort of
How's your father touch
But since I left my bugle at home
I'll simply have to say
Gentlemen, Merry Christmas.
ALL:
Merry Christmas, Mr. Scrooge.
Come to my office
on Monday morning
and I will give you a hundred guineas
for your most worthy cause.
And the same every Christmas.
Thank you very, very much,
Mr. Scrooge.
[ALL SINGING]
Thank you very, very, very much
Thank you very much
That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me
The future looks all right
In fact it looks so bright
I feel as if they're polishing
The sun for me
- Sing a Christmas carol
Sing a Christmas carol
Like the children do
And if I had a cannon I would fire it
To add a sort of celebration touch
And enjoy the beauty
All the joy and beauty
That a Merry Christmas...
And since I left my cannon at home
- I'll simply have to say
- Christmas is here
Thank you very, very, very much
Thank you very much
That's the nicest thing
That anyone's ever done for me
I may sound double Dutch
But my delight is such
I feel as if a losing war
- Has been won for me
- Come along, boys.
And if I had a flag
I'd hang me flag out
To add a sort of final victory touch
But since I left me flag at home
I'll simply have to say
[PANTING]
Thank you very much
Thank you very, very, very much
Merry Christmas.
[HUMMING]
CHUCKLES]
[LAUGHING]
Hello.
I don't know whether you can hear me,
old Jacob Marley.
And I don't know whether or not
I imagined the things I saw.
But between the pair of us we...
We finally made a Merry Christmas,
didn't we?
I have to leave you now.
Must go and get ready.
I'm going to have Christmas dinner
with my family.