23.976 English-SDH
subrip from NTSC-6.01GB © 09-09-2016
The Land Before Time XIV
Journey of the Brave (2016)
NARRATOR: Long, long ago,
in the Land Before Time,
great beasts ruled
the world.
These mighty beasts
were the dinosaurs.
Yes, it was
a place of wonder,
but also filled
with danger...
(ROARS)
...where survival
was uncertain
and families were sometimes
torn apart.
(CROAKS)
Which is how the young
Longneck named Littlefoot
came to live with
his grandmother,
grandfather,
and his close friends
in the beautiful
Great Valley.
The perils of the world had
claimed his mother and
separated him from his father.
Then,
a miraculous day came.
Littlefoot and his father,
Bron, were reunited.
During the time
they were apart,
Bron had become
the leader of a large
migrating herd.
This meant he couldn't
stay with Littlefoot in
the Great Valley.
Bron wanted his son
to join him,
and Littlefoot wanted
to be with his father,
but he also didn't want
to leave his home.
So Littlefoot made the
tough decision to stay
with his grandfather,
grandmother
and friends.
Now each year,
when the Season of New Growth
follows the Cold Time,
and the warm sunshine
falls softly
on the Great Valley,
Littlefoot looks forward
to a visit from his father,
leading the great herd
on their yearly migration.
It's a reunion he dreams
about all year long.
And it will be
happening today.
(GASPS)
Today's the day!
(GROWLS)
(ROARING)
(RUBY GIGGLING)
(GIGGLING)
You can't find me!
(ROARING)
(GIGGLES)
Come on, Littlefoot,
we're playing hide
from the Sharptooth!
Come and play!
Can't, Ruby!
My dad's coming today!
Mr. Threehorn,
is Cera around?
She's gone
to the swimming hole.
What's the hurry?
Today's the day
my dad comes back!
(SINGING) Hey, hey, hey
Today's the day
My dad's coming home
from far away
We'll race and we'll run
and we'll laugh and play
I feel so happy
that I gotta say
Hey, hey, hey
Today is the day
Yep, yep, yep
The time is near
Our brothers and sisters
will soon be here
I will teach them to swim
and to be your friend
(GASPS)
You will teach them
to stay away
from your rear end.
Yeah.
Hey, hey, hey
Today is the day
PETRIE: Hey, guys!
It spring! It spring
And me feel
like flying
In spring no one be
grumpy or grouch
(CROAKS)
When me up in the air
and skying
Oh! Hey! Oh! Wait! Ohh!
Whoa!
(SPLASHES)
Ouch.
You just barely missed
the hatchlings, Petrie!
Oh, Petrie real sorry.
They're not born yet,
they can't hear you.
No listen to her.
Ahh!
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Hey, guys,
you know what day
today is?
I do!
Hey, hey, hey
Today's the day
When I'm gonna
blow that rock away
I'll hit it so hard
it'll break in two
You'll be amazed
at what I can do
Hey, hey, hey
Okay. Get ready!
(GRUNTS)
(THUDS)
What did I tell you?
I moved the rock
We are very, very glad
Me fly so high
I'm gonna see
my dad
It the flying-est
Swimming-est
Happiest
Spring-iest
ALL: Day
Today's the day!
DUCKY: Today is the day!
CERA: Hey, hey
LITTLEFOOT:
Today's the day
ALL: Today's the day!
(SPIKE SIGHS)
(ALL LAUGH)
(CRACKING)
(GASPING)
The eggs.
(CRACKING)
Ohh!
(CHIRPING)
(CHUCKLES)
Hello, little guy.
Hey.
(LAUGHING)
He got you, Petrie!
He sure do.
(ALL LAUGH)
(CHIRPING)
So cute.
I am Ducky,
your sister.
(CHIRPING)
And this is Spike,
your adopteded brother.
(MOANS PLEASANTLY)
And me Petrie,
your adopteded brother's...
Uh...
Me just Petrie.
(LAUGHS)
(CHIRPING)
(LOUD FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Grandpa! Grandma!
Look, it's the hatchlings!
(MOANS)
Ah. What a special today
this is.
Today! I forgot.
Today's the day my dad comes back!
Great!
Special day!
We are so happy for you,
yes, we are.
Can we go watch
for him?
(LAUGHS) I thought
you might want to.
Come, Littlefoot.
Now, Grandpa,
keep an eye on the ice.
It's still slippery.
We will, Grandma.
Come on.
We're lucky to live
in such bounty, Littlefoot.
Not many of our kind do.
There they are!
My dad's herd!
You're right, Littlefoot.
But where's my dad?
I don't see him.
That is strange.
Bron is always
at the head of the herd.
I'm sure there's nothing
to worry about.
WILD ARMS: Help!
Help!
Who's that?
We'd better
take a look.
(SCREAMING)
Help!
Oh, I'm safe.
Am I really here?
Somebody pinch me,
please.
No! Not you!
No. Not you. (LAUGHS)
I'll pinch myself.
Ow! Ouch.
Why did I do that?
And you are?
I, uh... Well, everybody
calls me Wild Arms,
though I never really
figured out why.
Oh. (LAUGHS)
That makes so much
sense now!
What happened,
Wild Arms?
Aw, I mean
what didn't happen?
The earth shook
and spit liquid fire.
And the heat...
Like you've never
seen before!
But, it's too upsetting
to talk about.
But if you must know,
it all started
with a horrible boom!
The Fire Mountain
exploded.
It just blew its top.
Fire everywhere
you looked.
There was no escape.
And the Longnecks, oh,
they were hit the hardest.
Let me tell you,
their leader was brave.
He wouldn't leave
any of us behind,
even though
he was in danger.
I only escaped thanks
to my superior
grace and agility.
The leader is
my dad.
Who?
Bron.
Oh, yes, yes,
that's him!
Bron!
What a brave Longneck
he was.
Ooh.
Er... Is.
Uh, is!
'Cause he's still is...
He still is... I'm sure.
What happened
to him?
I don't know.
I lost sight of him
at the Fire Mountain.
He's in trouble?
Grandpa, we have
to help him.
Littlefoot...
Will you take us
back there?
You know the way.
So, you want me
to take you
across the earthbreak,
through the Land of the
Feather-Head Sharptooth,
along the moving water
back to the same
Fire Mountain that I just
escaped from?
How foolish
do you think I look?
Let me put it
another way.
The answer is no!
Please. That's my dad.
He needs our help.
He's right, Littlefoot.
We can't do it.
But...
You'll go, won't you?
I'm sorry, Littlefoot.
It's too dangerous now.
We must wait for the mountain
to stop spitting rocks.
Bron wouldn't want us
to get hurt.
But my dad needs us now!
Your father is very
strong and wise.
He's lived through
many earthshakes.
I'm sure he's on his way
here right now.
Where are you, Dad?
CERA: There you are.
We couldn't
find you anywhere.
We all worry about you.
We are sorry
about your father.
Yes, we are.
Yes, we sorry.
Thanks.
I think he's in trouble.
He needs me.
What can you do?
I'm going
to the Fire Mountain.
I'm going to help him.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, that funny,
Petrie thought you say
you going to Fire Mountain.
I... I did say that.
I'm going.
No seem funny now.
What are you talking about?
You don't even know
how to get there.
Wild Arms said how.
Across the earthbreak,
through the Land of the
Feather-Head Sharpteeth
and along the moving
water to the Fire Mountain.
If you think
we're going to the
Fire Mountain...
I don't.
He's my father.
I'm going alone.
(SQUAWKING)
(GASPS)
(ROARING IN DISTANCE)
(TWIG SNAPS)
(RUSTLING)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
Guys?
(ALL GASP)
PETRIE: Oh!
Littlefoot,
you scare us.
You scared me.
What are you doing
out here?
You cannot find
your dad all by yourself.
You cannot.
Littlefoot need us.
(MOANS)
Uh-uh. It's too dangerous.
I can't let you come.
You can't stop us.
(LITTLEFOOT GASPS)
Oh, looking down
make Petrie dizzy.
(THUD)
(ROARING IN DISTANCE)
(NERVOUSLY)
What do we do now?
Wild Arms said we have
to cross the earthbreak.
Did he say how?
No.
We don't have
to go across!
We can follow it
to the Long Valley.
(WIND HOWLING)
That will bring us
to the Fire Mountain.
Well, even
if the Long Valley
does go there,
that will take longer.
We've gotta cross now!
(SCOFFS)
Let me know
when you find a way.
LITTLEFOOT: I know!
If we can knock
this tree down,
we can use it to cross.
Hmm.
(STRAINING)
(TREE TRUNK CREAKING)
(STRAINING CONTINUES)
(GROANS)
I know it will reach
if we could just...
(STRAINING)
CERA: Look out!
(GASPS)
(THUDS)
(GRUNTS)
(TREE CREAKING)
Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
Cera did it!
(CLAPPING) Yes, she did!
Thanks, Ducky.
Well, if we're
gonna go, let's go!
DUCKY: Now what?
I guess we go there.
But that's the Land
of the Feather-Head
Sharpteeth.
It look scary.
It will be okay.
Everything looks
scary to you.
My nest not scary.
My... My tree
not scary.
(DISTANT ROARING)
(GULPS) That scary.
We'll never
make it through!
The Sharpteeth will
smell us coming.
I think we should go back
and try the Long Valley.
Petrie like any way
that's not that way.
But this way's the fastest.
If we go around,
we may be too late
to help my dad.
If we get eaten,
we won't help him either.
What do you think, Spike?
Spike?
(WIND HOWLING)
CERA: Where's Spike?
Oh! Sharptooth
ate Spike!
I think Spike is
doing the eating.
(YELLING) Spike!
Spike?
He can't have gone far.
Where are you?
Spike?
Do you see him, Petrie?
No.
Spike!
(GASPS)
Looks like he went
this way.
(FLIES BUZZING)
Ew!
Ugh. Petrie smell
something not good.
That's stinkweed.
Yep, yep, yep.
(SPIKE CHOMPING)
(CHUCKLES)
LITTLEFOOT: There you are.
Spike, we don't have
time for this.
My dad needs me.
No more food stops. Okay?
Why did you eat
stinkweed, of all things?
Ducky...
(BURPS)
(SINGING)
Spike, you are my friend
My very special friend
(MOANS)
And we all like you
very much
We know that you are happy
when you fill up your tummy
But what you are eating now
is not so yummy
(MOANS)
No, no, no!
It is hot and stinky
Stinky and hot
It may feel good
inside your hungry spot
But when you are
eating things
that taste all mucky
You will be smelling
very yuck-yuck-yucky
So you should not
eat what is hot
And stinky
(SNIFFS)
Wait a minute.
Spike, you just gave
me an idea!
(GRUNTS)
Maybe there's a way to go
through the Sharptooth Land
and be safe.
That's impossible!
But what if we cover
our smell with stinkweed?
They'll smell that
instead of us!
You sure it work?
Would you go near Spike,
smelling like that?
Petrie would not go near
Petrie smelling like that!
Let's see
if this will work
I think this plan
can work
Yeah, because you're
always right
(SCOFFS)
If we're not lucky
and a Sharptooth meets us
He think we stinkweed
and won't want to eats us
Because we
ALL: Hot and stinky
Stinky and hot
We'll walk right past him
and we won't get caught
He will not see us
with his big red eyes-es
'Cause we be wearing
gooey green disguises
No, he will not
If we be hot
ALL: And stinky
Your turn.
ALL: You've got to
got to be
Hot and stinky
Stinky and hot
You can all be goofy,
but I will not
But that nasty Sharptooth
will smell you
if you let it
I don't like stinkweed
and I say forget it
BOTH: No, you cannot
ALL: You've got to,
got to, got to
Got to, got to, got to,
got to be
Hot and stinky
Hey, stop that!
ALL: Hot and stinky
Ew!
Stinky and hot
Now we all stinky
and hot
(LAUGHING)
(BURPS)
(GROANS)
Okay, everybody,
stay together.
Here we go.
CERA: I hope you know
what you're doing.
LITTLEFOOT: Me, too.
(GASPS)
(ROARING)
(WHISPERS)
Get back, everyone.
(FOOTSTEPS POUNDING)
(ROARING)
(GROWLING)
(SOFTLY) Seems like
the stinkweed's working.
Quiet, now.
Yes, Petrie be
very quiet,
quieter than quiet,
so quiet nobody hear me.
(GROWLING)
Petrie.
What?
Oh, yes. Quiet.
(SNIFFING)
(GASPS)
(SQUEAKING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
How much further,
Littlefoot?
I don't know!
It's hot.
And I'm stinky!
I don't like being
hot and stinky!
No one likes that.
No, no, no.
Look! Water!
(ALL EXCLAIM)
CERA: Yeah!
DUCKY: Water!
(ALL LAUGHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
Um, guys,
maybe we should go soon.
I'm not ready. My belly's
only half full,
which means it's half empty.
(GROANS)
(MOANS)
Spike.
No eating the stinkweed.
We need to keep stinking.
(STRUGGLING)
Spike, let go.
Ahhh!
(SPLASHING)
(CHUCKLES)
Littlefoot go for swim.
I want to swim.
No, Cera!
Me, too.
(BOTH GIGGLE)
(LAUGHING)
(SNIFFING)
(ROARS)
(SNIFFS)
(GIGGLING)
Um, guys, the stinkweed...
Stinkweed!
It's washing off!
(ROARING)
(SHUDDERS)
(ROARS)
(BOTH SNIFFING)
(SHIVERING)
(GROWLING)
(ALL GASPING)
(GROANS)
(GROWLING)
Run!
(ROARS)
Come on! Come on!
Whoa!
(ALL PANTING)
(ROARING)
(ALL WHIMPERING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(CRASHING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
(STRAINING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(CRASHING)
ALL: Whoa!
This way!
(ALL STRAINING)
Come on! Come on!
(STRAINING CONTINUES)
ALL: Whoa!
(ALL GASP)
We're trapped!
We should have gone
my way!
Cera, I'm trying
to think.
(HUFFS)
LITTLEFOOT: Hey!
You all get
behind those rocks.
Spike, Cera, grab
each end of that vine.
When I tell you,
pull it tight. Okay?
ALL: Mmm-hmm.
Here it come!
(ROARING)
Oh, no! This it!
(GULPS)
(GROWLS)
(ROARS)
Over here, big guy.
Right here.
(ROARING)
Now!
(GROANING)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
(ROARS)
(ALL CHEERING)
(ROARING)
(ROARS)
(ALL GASP)
DUCKY: The other one
is coming!
Let him come.
(STRAINING)
(CRASHING)
(GROANING)
(ALL CHEERING)
(GROANS)
CERA: Bye-bye!
(SIGHS) We are
all in one piece.
(CHUCKLES)
Better than million
little pieces.
(RUMBLING)
It's the Fire Mountain,
like Wild Arms said.
We just have to reach
the moving water
and we'll be fine.
Fine? What do
you mean, fine?
We are nowhere
near fine.
(GROANS)
Huh?
(GASPS)
DUCKY: Look, guys.
Spike found a way down.
LITTLEFOOT: Thanks, Spike!
(HOWLING)
Well, hello there,
Ruby and Chomper.
What can we do
for you?
Is Littlefoot here?
Did you look at Cera's?
We've looked for him
everywhere, and everywhere
we've looked, he isn't.
I don't like
the sound of this.
(ROARING IN DISTANCE)
(WHINING)
(EXHALES) Petrie glad
we leaving Land
of Feather-Head Sharpteeth.
Until we have
to go back home.
Oh.
Petrie stomach feel
funny again.
(YAWNS)
(THUDS)
(SNORING)
(SNORING CONTINUES)
Come on, Spike.
We have to keep going.
Spike is tired-ed,
Littlefoot.
Ducky, can you help
move him?
(SNORING CONTINUES)
Okay, Spike,
let's keep going.
(STRAINING)
(YAWNS)
(SNORING RESUMES)
Ducky.
(YAWNS)
Nothing makes me tired
like almost getting
eaten by Sharpteeth.
(YAWNS)
Petrie so sorry.
We find your
dad tomorrow.
(ALL SNORING)
Littlefoot isn't here,
and Cera should be
home by now, too.
I haven't seen
Petrie either.
Oh, dear. I assumed
Spike and Ducky were
still out playing.
I suspect
the young ones
have gone looking
for Littlefoot's father.
Cera, too?
(STOMPS)
What was she thinking?
We have to find
them right away.
I saw Littlefoot
listening closely
to what Wild Arms said.
I would guess he went
the way he described.
Thankfully,
there's some light
from the night circle.
We'll leave now.
I'll ask Wild Arms
to guide us.
(SOFTLY)
We should go, too!
(SOFTLY) Yes, but let's
not let them know
we're going, too.
(WIND HOWLING)
(ROARING IN DISTANCE)
(SHUDDERS)
(WHIMPERING)
(ROARING CONTINUES)
Okay, guys.
Ah... (CHUCKLES)
I'm sure you can find
the Fire Mountain
without me.
I mean I'd love
to come,
but, uh, I got a thing
to do, and it's called
"live."
We need all the help
we can get, Wild Arms,
with these little ones
out here all by themselves.
Of all the wild stunts
these young ones have pulled,
this is the worst.
We'll find them,
Mr. Threehorn.
We've got to.
(ALL SNORING)
(SIGHS)
Through there
is the Land of the
Feather-Head Sharpteeth.
Right, Mr. Wild Arms?
You mean the land
of certain death?
Yes, that is it.
Okay?
Or we can
just be sensible
and go back now.
I vote sensible.
Who's with me?
I mean, come on. How do
we even know if the little
ones came this way?
Well, what do
you think, Chomper?
Chomper?
I believe we have
some followers.
Chomper?
Ruby?
CHOMPER: I don't know
what you mean.
We're not here.
It's okay.
Come on out.
Hello, everybody,
everybody, hello.
Hi.
(SCREAMS) Sharptooth!
Run! Save yourself!
(SHUDDERING)
(CHUCKLES) No need
for panic, Mr. Wild Arms.
Chomper here is a friend.
Uh, have you taken
a good look at his teeth?
(CHUCKLES) It's all right,
Mr. Wild Arms.
Chomper only eats bugs.
We don't need
another Sharptooth
when we're walking into
a whole land of Sharpteeth.
Oh, finally someone
who's sensible!
Up top!
Okay.
Four more eyes are four
more chances to find them.
Please?
(SIGHS)
Well,
guess we can't just send
you two back on your own.
BOTH: Yay!
(BOTH CHEERING)
Hey, Mr. Wild Arms.
(EXHALES)
(LAUGHS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Would you mind,
Mr. Threehorn?
I knew I'd end up
carrying him
sooner or later.
(WILD ARMS GROANING)
Chomper, can you smell
if Littlefoot and the others
went this way?
Uh-huh.
(SNIFFING)
Littlefoot. Cera.
I smell them all.
Come on,
through here.
(SNIFFING)
CERA: You said we'd find
the moving water by now.
It should be
around the bend.
That's what you said
two bends ago!
(STOMACH GROWLING)
(GASPS)
Sharpteeth!
Do not worry, Petrie,
that is just Spike's belly.
Oh. (SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
We're all hungry!
And thirsty!
I have an idea.
I'm going to go up there
and look around.
You all wait here.
Hmm.
LITTLEFOOT: I see it!
The Fire Mountain.
And there,
the moving water
leads right to it.
But how come
we can't find it?
(GASPS)
Can I see,
Littlefoot?
Um, uh...
(GASPS)
Spike?
I don't know
if you should
come up here.
Oh!
Petrie want
to see, too.
CERA: Hey,
wait for me.
Um...
I think this ledge
is too small
to hold all of us.
I want to see
for myself.
Cera...
(SIGHS)
We're nowhere near
the moving water.
It should be around...
"Around the bend."
I don't think you know
where we're going.
We should have gone
my way!
(THUDDING)
(ALL GASP)
(CRACKING)
Oops.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED STRAINING)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
Nice going,
Littlefoot!
Me? I told you
not to come up there!
None of this
would have happened
if we went through
the Long Valley,
like I said.
If we went on instead
of stopping last night
I'd be with my dad!
You wouldn't be
anywhere without me.
You? You're just
slowing me down.
You all are.
(ALL GASPING)
I'd be better off
alone.
You want to be alone,
that's fine!
Fine!
I'm gonna find
the Long Valley.
I know where
that will lead.
You coming with me?
(GROANS SADLY)
Good.
We're better off
without him.
(SINGING) Who needs friends
to slow you down
Wasting our time
with too much talking
Who needs friends
to grumble and frown
(SQUEAKING)
When we should
just keep walking
I'm just fine
On my own
(GASPS)
I will be better
off alone
Who needs friends
who get you lost
And don't wanna listen
when you tell them
That you know
the best way to go
And you're just trying
to help them
Might as well
Talk to this stone
Ow!
I'm sure
I'm better off alone
And who needs friends
Who needs friends
To boss me around
BOTH: That's really
hard to swallow
Can't she see?
Can't he see?
It's so clear to me
BOTH: I should lead...
And she should follow?
And he should follow?
BOTH: My mistake
I should have known
I would be
better off alone
I'm sure
I'm better off alone
We're so much
better off alone
I guess
I'm better off alone
(WIND WHOOSHING)
Huh?
It's too soon to be dark.
(GASPS)
Oh, no!
Sand cloud!
Cera? Guys?
(GROANS)
Petrie feel bad.
(MOANS IN AGREEMENT)
Spike, too.
Me, three.
I miss Littlefoot.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
Petrie hate wind!
(YELLS)
(GASPS) Petrie!
Help!
Hurry, Spike.
Hurry.
(GASPS)
Guys?
(GASPING)
Sand cloud!
(GASPS)
ETTA: Don't tell me
you're thinking about
going back out there.
That's a sand cloud,
case you didn't notice.
My friends
are out there!
Well, then you'd best hope
they find some shelter
like you.
You don't understand.
They're only out here
because of me.
Well, getting yourself killed
is not a way I ever heard
of showing you care.
Nothing you can do
but wait out the storm.
(GROWLING)
Mmm.
Nope, not dead.
You still got time
to grow up and learn
to listen.
(SIGHS)
(GROANS)
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SPLUTTERING)
Ducky?
Spike?
Petrie?
(GASPS)
Who's there?
(BOTH GASPING)
(BOTH SIGHING)
(SIGHS) Spike.
What are you doing
sneaking up on me?
Where's Ducky?
(BOTH GASPING)
(SPLUTTERING)
Here I am.
Good.
What about Petrie?
The wind tooked him away.
Oh, great!
I guess we'll have
to look for him.
What about Littlefoot?
He's probably
far off by now.
I'll bet
he missed the storm.
I do not know.
Well, I do.
Let's go find Petrie.
The storm covereded
everything with sand.
Which way?
(MOANS IN AGREEMENT)
Um, that way.
I do not think
that's right.
No, no, no.
Well, I say it is.
Come on.
Petrie! Petrie!
Where is he?
(SHIVERING)
Ducky?
Spike?
Anybody?
(SHOUTING)
Anybody at all?
(GASPS)
(WHIMPERS)
Littlefoot! Cera!
(SCREAMING) Help!
(WHIMPERS)
Nice diggers.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
(WHIMPERS)
No!
(GRUNTS)
No eat Petrie!
ALL: More.
(GULPING) More?
More?
ALL: More. More. More.
(ALL CHEERING)
Hello.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
Me Petrie.
ALL: Petrie!
Petrie! Petrie!
Whatcha doin', hon?
I'm gonna go help
my friends.
Aren't you nice.
You know, I had a cousin
who was nice like that.
She put her head
in the mouth of a Sharptooth
just to help a friend.
Course, she's not
around anymore, 'cause...
Well, she put her head
in the mouth of a Sharptooth.
(LAUGHS)
Oh! I'm Etta, by the way.
What's your name?
Littlefoot.
Sorry.
Nice to meet you,
Fiddlefoot.
You don't mind me saying,
you look more like
a Littlefoot.
That's what
I'm gonna call you.
Nice to meet you,
Etta.
Look, Etta!
Daylight!
(RUMBLING)
What?
Earthshake!
Whoa!
Etta!
(CRASHING)
(BOTH GASP)
(SIGHS)
That was a close one.
The opening.
We gotta move this.
(BOTH STRAINING)
Looks like we're good
and stuck.
(SIGHS)
CERA: Petrie!
Petrie!
(MOANS)
Hmm.
Are you sure this
is the right way?
Look! Footprints!
Now we're
getting somewhere!
Hmm.
But that's
Spike's footprint.
And yours.
Oh, you just led us
in a circle.
Oh.
Well, maybe
I meant to do that.
(GASPS)
(STUTTERING)
What's going on?
Hey! Get away!
Big dinner
for leader!
(GASPS)
Get leader!
ALL: Leader!
Leader! Leader!
(STAMMERING)
I'm not afraid of
your silly old leader.
Here come leader!
(BOTH GASP)
Petrie!
We found you!
Huh?
(MOANS EXCITEDLY)
(SIGHING)
Petrie so glad
to see you.
You?
You can't be
their leader!
ALL: (CHANTING)
Petrie! Petrie! Petrie!
(CHUCKLES)
Me think me can.
You don't even know
how to be a leader.
Oh, it no hard.
Watch.
ALL: (CHANTING) Leader!
Leader! Leader!
Huh?
I wish Littlefoot
could see this.
No find yet?
(MOANS SADLY)
He's probably
at the Fire Mountain
by now.
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
We should find
the Long Valley.
What do you think
we should do?
I just told you.
I mean Petrie.
Who cares
what Petrie thinks?
ALL: (CHANTING) Petrie!
Petrie! Petrie!
They care.
Well?
Petrie think...
Well,
Petrie think, um...
We're waiting!
Uh,
being leader hard.
(SIGHS)
But Petrie
miss Littlefoot.
(MOANS IN AGREEMENT)
Us, too.
Yep, yep, yep.
Well, how are you
supposed to find him?
We don't even know
where we are!
So we are lost.
(GULPS)
No, no, we're not.
I mean, not really.
Okay, we are lost.
And I miss him, too.
Let's go find him.
Petrie must go
and find friend.
ALL: No! No! No!
No be sad.
Um...
Petrie order no be sad.
Petrie always
remember you.
And you.
And back there, all you.
ALL: Petrie! Petrie!
Petrie!
(RUSTLING)
ALL: Oh!
(LAUGHING)
Leader! Leader! Leader!
(CHEERING) Yay!
(SPIKE GROANS)
(LITTLEFOOT GRUNTING)
Littlefoot, leave it be.
Honey, no one can
break through that.
Cera could.
But she's not here.
(SIGHS) It's hopeless.
Come on, Littlefoot,
cheer up.
I had a sister once
used to say,
"Just when things get darkest,"
"that's when you look for the light."
Unless, of course,
it's too dark to find it.
You don't understand.
My friends only
came out here to help
me find my dad.
And now I can't save him.
Well, what...
What happened to your dad?
He got trapped
by an earthshake when
the Fire Mountain blew up.
That's what
Wild Arms said.
Wild Arms?
Oh, heck,
I know a Wild Arms.
Moves like this?
Yes, that's him!
He travels
with my dad's herd.
They all made it out okay,
except my dad.
Oh, my.
Is your father's name Bron?
Yeah, it is!
Oh, honey, I was there,
at Fire Mountain.
What happened?
Please tell me.
Okay.
But you may not like it.
The Fire Mountain
was shaking and rumbling.
Trouble was coming
and everybody knew it.
There was only one longneck
who knew what to do
and that was your dad.
He ordered the herd
to head down the mountain
as fast as they could.
But the Fire Mountain
didn't wait for them
to get down.
(EXPLODING)
Ow!
I barely made
it out myself.
Someone fell.
I think it was Wild Arms.
Your father went back
and saved him.
And that's when
it happened.
There was an explosion.
Your father got separated
from the others.
Well, honey,
that's the last
I saw of him.
That's my dad.
He wouldn't leave
anyone behind.
Even though it meant
risking his life.
I guess that's what
you do for your herd.
And your friends.
I never should have
left them.
Now, Littlefoot,
don't give up.
Get off your tail
and we're gonna get
out of this cave.
How?
(SINGING) When you're stuck
in a hole and you
don't know where to go
When it's too dark
for you to tell
Your tail from your toe
You wonder which way
is wrong
And which road is right?
The best thing
for you to do is just
Look for the light
One little spark
A little bit of hope
to lead you out of the dark
Somewhere deep
inside of you,
it's shining so bright
All you gotta do is look
You gotta look
for the light
If there's a wall,
sometimes you bump it
A big old rock,
you have to jump it
Maybe you're tired
Maybe you're scared
(GASPS)
But the only thing
you have to be
Is be prepared
To look for the light
And open your eyes
You never know when
you're gonna find a surprise
Some things
may tickle you
(GIGGLING)
Others may bite
So, listen to my sister,
mister
Come on and
look for the light
Get up and
Come on and
look for the light
Well, that's what my
sister used to say,
but you can't exactly
go by her.
She ran into a tree once
and been a little funny
in the head ever since.
Hey, Etta!
Maybe that's a way out!
(SIGHS)
It's just light
shining off the water.
Oh, I'm sorry,
Littlefoot.
(SIGHS)
That's okay.
Let's keep
looking for the light.
That's the spirit!
It's water, Etta!
Heard ya the first time,
but we're looking
for a way out.
Like I was saying
about my sister...
Etta, if water's
coming in the cave,
you know
what that means?
It's wet?
No. It means
it has to be
going out, too!
If it wasn't,
the cave would be
filled with water.
Oh, I didn't think
of that.
If water can find
a way out,
maybe we can, too!
I like the way you think,
Littlefoot!
She had a lot of sayings,
my sister. Like...
You know,
"Don't use your tail to sniff the trail."
(LAUGHING)
Oh, that got me
every time.
(MUMBLING)
Littlefoot!
(MOANS EXCITEDLY)
Hmm!
Oh! Look!
Littlefoot's footprints!
He must be close,
yes, yes, yes!
Nice going, Spike!
That was hard to see
with all these
Sharptooth footprints around.
Sharptooth?
(GROWLING)
(ALL GASPING)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
CERA: This way!
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(SHUDDERING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
(GASPS) Look, Etta.
It's the moving water!
My friends and I
were looking for it.
Oh, my.
It's under the ground!
That's why we couldn't
find it before.
I bet if we
follow this water,
it will lead right
to the Fire Mountain.
Now all we have to do
is find my friends.
Hmm. But how?
They could be anywhere.
(INDISTINCT VOICES)
That's funny.
It's like I can hear them.
(INDISTINCT VOICES)
Etta,
can you get up there?
Hmm.
My wing got a
little singed.
But I can try.
(HUMMING)
Hmm.
Now what?
Poke through!
Okay.
(THUDDING)
(SHUDDERING)
ETTA: Yoo-hoo.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(LAUGHS)
Sorry to startle you,
but I wonder if I can have
just a moment of your time.
Are you by any chance
friends with Littlefoot?
We are!
He says you should
come with me.
What's a Bigbeak
doing underground?
Well, that's an
interesting story and I'd
love to tell all of you that.
But first,
maybe we should get you
away from that Sharptooth.
(GROWLING)
Honey, would you mind
giving that rock just
a little shove?
You got it!
(STRAINING) Go!
(ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Whoa!
(STRAINING)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(SIGHS)
Littlefoot!
Hi, everyone!
Oh, Petrie miss you!
Spike and me, too!
(SOFT CHUCKLE)
I'm so happy
we're all together.
I... I should have
never left you.
Yeah, well,
maybe we all
shouldn't have left.
I'm sorry, Littlefoot.
Me, too.
Etta,
these are my friends.
(LAUGHS)
I can sure see that!
Hey, look what me
and Etta found.
It's the moving water!
It went under the ground.
That's why we couldn't
find it before.
I think this will take us
right to the Fire Mountain.
I mean...
If you still want
to go with me.
I will go with you,
Littlefoot.
(MOANS IN AGREEMENT)
Petrie, too.
Hey, hey, hey!
Count me in.
Well, what are
we waiting for?
Let's go!
Jump!
Whoo-hoo!
(LAUGHS)
The water's great!
(SCREAMS)
(YELLS)
(LAUGHING)
Look out below!
ALL: Ooh! Ah!
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ALL GIGGLING)
Look! Light!
We're coming out!
Petrie see only sky.
(GASPS)
CERA:
Oh, what does
that mean?
(GASPS) Falling water!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Whoa!
(LAUGHING)
(GIGGLING)
Ooh! That was the best!
I want to do
that again!
(MOANS IN AGREEMENT)
Anybody know
where we are?
ETTA: Yep.
I'm afraid I do.
(ALL GASP)
(EXHALES)
Petrie like
the water more.
What now?
Etta, where did you say
you saw my dad?
Just over that ridge,
that's where
your father fell.
Littlefoot,
you might not like
what you see.
(GASPS)
Littlefoot?
Dad!
(ALL PANTING)
(STUTTERING)
What are you doing here?
We came to get you.
Thank you, all of you.
But my leg is stuck.
There's nothing
you can do.
(SNIFFING)
They came this way.
Sharptooth!
(SCREAMS)
(YELLING) Sharptooth!
Nobody make a sound!
Everybody needs
to be very, very...
(SOFTLY)
Quiet, Wild Arms.
(ROARING)
This way.
(SHUDDERING)
(WHIMPERS)
(WHIMPERING)
I wanna go home.
(SHUSHING)
Oh, no... Why...
(ROARS)
He's gone.
(SHIVERING)
You hear that?
He's gone!
(CLEARS THROAT)
He's gone.
Isn't that great?
There has to be
something we can do!
(WHIMPERS)
Me so sorry.
Etta, please
take them home.
I am not going!
(EXPLODES)
(ALL GASPING)
Littlefoot,
your dad's right.
You didn't give up
on your herd.
I'm not giving up
on you!
We want to help, too.
ETTA: Uh-huh!
(MOANS IN AGREEMENT)
Cera, do you think you can
move that big rock?
That one? It's huge!
I know.
But you can do it.
Look out,
I'm coming through!
Guys, Etta,
we're going
to need a tree.
Get that one.
ETTA: Okay.
SPIKE: Mmm-hmm!
What can Petrie do?
Go up high.
Let us know when
the flowing fire starts
coming for us.
Petrie will!
Huh?
Hang on!
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
(GROWLING)
(STRAINING)
Cera, you can do it!
Get ready!
You're going down!
(STRAINING)
Yeah!
Whoa!
(GASPS)
Yeah!
Dad.
Littlefoot.
(BOTH STRAINING)
Okay,
put the end in here!
(STRAINING)
Everyone get ready!
When I say,
"Push down!"
Hurry!
Ready, set, push!
(ALL STRAINING)
(GRUNTING)
Dad, now!
Hey!
Petrie think you
should hurry!
Go! Go! Go!
(ALL GASPING)
(BRON GRUNTS)
(ALL CHEERING)
MR. THREEHORN: Cera!
Dad!
(GIGGLING)
Thank goodness.
(MOANING HAPPILY)
What are you doing
way out here?
We came to save you.
Oh, we thank you
but no need saving.
This time we do saving.
ETTA: Wild Arms!
What are you doing
back here?
Well, Etta, I volunteered
to lead the rescue.
That's what
I'm doing here.
(CHUCKLES)
You volunteered?
Really?
Well, uh...
(CHUCKLES) Yeah?
(LAUGHING)
Grandpa!
I see you
found your father.
He did.
We all did.
(ALL AGREEING)
You've got quite
a group of friends.
You remind me
of someone I know.
Come, everyone.
Let's all go home.
Finally someone
who's sensible!
Let's get
out of here.
(LAUGHING)
NARRATOR:
Littlefoot had
found his father.
And he found
something else, too.
Something he
wasn't looking for.
The realization that
he and his friends
would always be together
till the end
of their days
in the Land Before Time.
(ALL LAUGHING)
PETRIE: Ooh, you'll be
very stinky.