(ROOSTER CROWS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Luisa.
Luisa, are you
coming down soon?
"Kiss number 60."
"The kiss upon the eyes."
"The eyelid kiss
is said to produce"
"A unique sensation
of an unworldly nature,"
"Running from
the base of the spine
to the knees."
BELLOMY: Luisa.
What you been
doing up there, dear?
Studying.
Well, that's good.
What's that for?
Number 26.
Kissing a parent.
Where are you going?
Town.
Before you go,
would you do
your dad a favor
And come over here a second,
let me see how this fits?
I always look
like a sick turkey.
Ah.
(GROANS)
The neckline is too high.
Be careful...
Where did you get that?
That's your
mother's necklace.
I found it in a box of
old letters.
You gave it to her,
didn't you?
I can't believe you were
ever that romantic.
Ha!
Did you stand
outside her window
And serenade her
with love songs too?
Mmm.
(GARGLING)
I guess not.
There are other things
in the world
As important as
love songs, you know.
Like what?
Like work songs,
that's like what.
Like hymns, anthems, marches.
Dirges.
Never mind.
(SIGHS)
Papa, I've got to take wing.
Be careful,
it's duck season.
I don't suppose your wings
Are going to
carry you anywhere
near that carnival, are they?
What carnival?
Luisa.
You look nice in the necklace.
(HAMMERING)
Hi, Mr. Hucklebee.
(MOUTHING WORDS)
Luisa?
How many times,
since they moved in,
Have I told you not to talk
to that idiot next door?
Couple of hundred.
A couple of
hundred times you told me
not to talk to his son either.
Good for me.
And no carnival.
* I'd like to swim
In a clear blue stream
* Where the water is icy cold
* Then go to town
In a golden gown
* And have my fortune told
* Just once, just once
* Just once before I am old
* I'd like to be not evil
* But a little worldly wise
* To be the kind of
girl designed
* To be kissed upon the eyes
* I'd like to dance till 2:00
* Or sometimes dance till dawn
* Or if the band
could stand it
* Just go on and on and on
* Just once, just once
* Before the chance is gone
* I'd like to waste
a week or two
* And never do a chore
* To wear my hair unfastened
* So it billows to the floor
* To do the things
I've dreamed about
* But never done before
* Perhaps I'm bad
or wild or mad
* With lots of grief in store
* But I want much more
Than keepin' house
* Much more, much more,
* Much more!
Where you going?
Uh, got to make sure
the hogs get fed.
You're all dressed up.
Got a date with one of them?
I just got to go
the store first
to get the feed.
All right, and pick me up
some of that cough syrup
That puts me right
to sleep, will you?
I got to get back to work.
(EXCLAIMS)
That's one hammer
I'll never see again.
BELLOMY: Oh, yes, you will.
Keep your crud
on your own side!
You keep your face
and your damn bricks
out of my side!
Or you'll be
wearing brick earmuffs.
Thief!
Murderer!
Lunkhead!
Fuzz bucket!
He's out of his
mind with love,
that son of mine.
Nothing sets
the heart a flutter,
like a good old fashion feud.
What do you think will happen
when they meet on that
road to the carnival?
I don't know.
But they'll never
suspect we planned it.
That son of mine,
he's fantastic.
My daughter is fantastic too.
Just think if they knew
that we wanted them wed.
A pre-arranged marriage?
They'd rather be dead.
Children.
Lovers.
Fantasticks.
Geese.
How cruel ever we are.
How crafty to know
To manipulate children,
you merely say
No.
* Oh!
* Dog's got to bark,
a mule's got to bray
* Soldiers must fight
and preachers must pray
* And children, I guess,
must get their own way
* The minute that you say no
* Why did the kids
pour jam on the cat?
* Raspberry jam
all over the cat?
* Why should the kids
do something like that
* When all that
we said was no?
* Why did the kids
put beans in their ears?
* No one can hear
with beans in their ears
* After a while
the reason appears
* They did it
'cause we said no
* Your daughter
brings a young man in
* Says "Do you like him, Pa?"
* Just tell her,
"He's a fool"
* And then,
you've got a son-in-law
* You've got a son-in-law!
* Sure as the June
comes right after May!
* Sure as the night
comes right after day!
* You can be sure
the devil's to pay
* The minute that you say no
* No!
* Make sure you never say...
Kids.
Won't it be nice,
when our kids are married
So they can drive
each other crazy,
instead of us?
Right. They're nearly there.
There just one thing missing
for our hero and heroine,
a climax.
You watch what you say,
you are talking
about my daughter.
And speaking in
theatrical terms
We have to find some way
to end the feud
Without them knowing
we made the whole thing up.
Well, how do you
propose we do that?
That's the problem.
Wait a minute.
You see?
Whenever you got a problem
The United States
Postal Service
comes to the rescue.
Yeah, they run
a tight shift.
Let's go, Bellomy.
Let's have a talk
with this fellow...
Are you crazy?
We can't go to the carnival,
the kids will see us,
They'll think
we're looking for them.
Instant heat.
I seem to remember
that's good for
romance. Isn't it?
Uh-huh. Uh-ah!
Fuel to the fire.
"Specialists in
dreams come true."
"Family feud settled."
What are we waiting for?
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
Romeo, Romeo!
Wherefore art thou, Romeo?
MATT: But soft.
What light through
yonder window breaks?
It is the east,
and Juliet is the sun.
Arise, fair sun,
and kill the envious moon.
What if someone sees us?
Come on.
Our fathers.
I don't care
about our fathers.
about the wall.
I don't care about
anything but you.
* If we were in
Verona long ago
* And just like the story,
our true love forbidden
* I would study swordplay
and I'd stand
and fight them all
* Anyone who would come
between us
* Would have to deal with me
* I'd stand and face them all
* As one by one they'd fall
* You'd fight them all
* They'd start to fall
BOTH:
* Love conquers all!
* Love!
* I am love!
* You are love!
* Better far than a metaphor
can ever, ever be
* Love!
* I am love!
* You are love!
* My mystery...
* His mystery...
* Of love
* You are Polaris,
the one trustworthy star
* You are!
* I am!
* You are September,
A special mystery
* To me!
* To he!
* You are sunlight! Moonlight!
Mountains! Valleys!
* The microscopic
inside of a leaf!
* My joy!
* Yes, I am his joy!
* My grief!
* Yes, I am his grief!
* My star!
* Yes, I am his star!
* My leaf!
* Yes, I am his leaf!
* Oh. Love!
* I am love!
* You are love!
* Better far than a metaphor
can ever, ever be
* Love!
* I am love!
* You are love!
* My mystery
* His mystery
* Of love
* Love
Do you speak English?
Oh, my God.
What is it?
It's my father.
Must be this one.
MATT: My father too.
They're not
supposed to be here.
Neither are we.
We'll meet tonight,
by the big tree.
In the moonlight.
In moonlight.
It's a century
till moonlight.
I'll never wash
this hand again.
What the devil...
At your service.
Wait, you the famous
El Gallo?
El Gallo.
Oh, yeah. See, we got your
advertisement in the mail
And we got ourselves
a little problem.
A love problem.
You two have a love problem?
And you seek sympathy
from our little
band of outcasts.
What would you two be willing
to do in front of an audience?
No, wait a minute...
We are not
talking about us.
We're talking
about our kids.
Who happen to be
a boy and a girl.
Less challenging.
Follow me.
Although we are not
yet fully prepared
The official opening
of the entire carnival,
I think we can proceed
with our business here.
One moment,
I'll check my files.
I'm sorry,
what did you say
your names were?
Hucklebee.
Bellomy.
I do beg your pardon,
this is "N" through "Z."
Yes, there we are,
"A" through "M."
Oh!
How did you do that?
It wasn't easy
it took months to
set up these files.
Oh my...
(WHISPERING) Quiet.
I'm beginning to
get a picture.
You said you had
a daughter?
Yes.
I see a girl.
Is her name Luisa?
Is that your
daughter's name.
Yes.
That's her. Oh, look.
She is standing
next to a young man
who must be, who must be...
Quick, before
the image fades.
Matt.
That's it.
You're amazing.
They seem to be
happy enough.
What about the feud?
Of course that's there,
I said "seem."
Obviously your children
are feeling
a great deal of torment.
Uncanny.
And you've come to me
for some kind of magic, eh?
You're in luck.
Ooh!
Frankly, we came to you
to find out
how to end this feud.
Many paths lead
to the summit.
Follow me.
You know,
we kind of thought
it'd be a good idea
If my mild-mannered son
was turned into
a rip-roaring hero.
Really?
Well, yes, that would be
The first thought of
a common rural mind.
And by an amazing coincidence,
it's also mine.
Ah! Boy, are we lucky.
Of course to have a hero,
you must first have a villain.
That makes sense. But who?
Let's think, the young lady
knows both of you,
so that wouldn't work.
What about you?
Me?
Oh, I couldn't
do it, for free.
But for a small donation
to my favorite charity...
Yeah.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
Would $60 be
an insult?
Yes, but I'm used to abuse.
Oh, yes. I see it,
I start to
kidnap his daughter,
Your son runs in to save her.
Then a battle.
I allow the boy to defeat me,
your son becomes a hero,
The parents relent,
the feud is over forever.
She melts into his arms.
How much for such a drama?
That, senor, depends.
Depends on what?
On what else.
The quality of the rape.
Rape? No!
No rape!
Oh, very well then,
the abduction.
The rape, the chase,
the kidnapping.
Call it what you will,
from the Latin rapere.
Meaning "to seize."
* Abductions, abductions,
Theatrical abductions
* Complete with
maidens in distress
And fabulous productions
* The sort of thing you see
Upon the operatic stage
* Two lovers are meeting
Their happiness is fleeting
* All at once a bandit man
Is standing there repeating!
* Surrender and so forth
* Give us the girl!
And so forth
* In short they are surrounded
by a gang of angry men
* I see it, I see it
A gang of angry men
* Heaven
I can assure you
this is heaven
* For six,
young love is out of seven
* This is a dream of ecstasy
* How can we deny them
such a dream of ecstasy?
* Sounds a bit expensive
I would like to know the fee
* The people are cheering,
I'm standing center leering
* I wear a cape
and steer a snare
That's really quite endearing
* I enter and so forth
I grab the girl and so forth
* I ravish her and start to
carry her into the night
* The hero, he sees her,
he grabs the girl
and frees her
* He tries to tweak me
by the nose
* Which certainly
should please her
* We argue and so forth
We draw our
swords and so forth
* We shout "En garde!"
And fight until
I stagger and I die
* They're fighting, exciting,
El Gallo starts to die
* The parents relenting,
resolve the scene presenting
* A prefect picture of content
With both of them consenting
* To marriage and so forth
To end the feud and so forth
* They swear to
tear the world apart
And live in harmony
* The lovers are kissing
The parents reminiscing
* The scene is
one of utter bliss
* With not a cliche missing
* There's laughter
and so forth
* A happy dance and so forth
* Then all at once
A harpist and
a piano start to play
* I hear it
* He hears it
* How beautifully they play
* Drama
* A stormy night
* What he's offering is drama
* A bloody fight
* In my life's faded cyclorama
* What a sight
* He tries to shed
a little light
* It's so exciting when
you shed a little light
* Really
* The lovers kiss
* I must admit
that this is thrilling
* Oh, such happiness
* And it can happen
if I'm willing
* How can it miss?
* Just make sure
the price is right
* So why be pikers?
Just make sure
the price is right
* Why should we be pikers?
* Just make sure
the price is right
* Abductions, abductions
Theatrical abductions
* Complete with
maidens in distress
And fabulous productions
* With moonlight, and so forth
A happy end and so forth
* And it all depends on one
* It all depends
* It all...
* Depends on what you pay
* Pay!
* Olay!
First class it is.
Now, let's see.
What else should we use?
Do you want Jo-Jo
the Chicken Lady?
I don't think so.
I know, the Bavarian baby.
I've got one who
is very talented,
he can swallow a sword.
If you throw in $4 extra
he cleans up after himself.
What about that act?
Which?
"Shakespearian company,
direct from London."
"Theatre Royal, Drury Lane."
No. No, you don't want that.
Now, instead...
I think Shakespeare
is a great idea.
After all, my son
thinks he is Romeo.
My daughter would be
a perfect Juliet.
Really, gentlemen,
I assure you
it's not a good idea.
Now, for a first
class abduction...
Let me see.
BELLOMY: But Shakespeare,
that's real class.
I was in a Shakespeare
play once.
HUCKLEBEE: Really?
Uh-huh.
My daughter would
like Shakespeare.
So would my son.
Likes that
I am the Pantomim whatever.
And with Shakespeare,
it's sure to be
done in good taste.
Sir, the players have arrived.
Thank you.
But your services
will not be necessary.
Now or ever.
Back in the trunk.
These men are from London?
Straight from
Theatre Royal, Drury Lane?
Absolutely, one long,
straight ride.
Down.
Don't see us as we are.
Gentlemen, please.
Remove ten pounds of
road dust from these
aged wrinkled cheeks.
See make-up caked in
glowing powder pink.
Imagine a beard, full-blown
and glowing like
the whiskers of a bear.
Imagine hair in a box,
I have all colors.
Please, I beg of you,
imagine hair.
And not these clothes,
dear God, no, no.
Not rags like
every beggar has.
But see me in a doublet.
Mortimer, fetch the doublet.
Thank you.
EL GALLO: Gentlemen,
if you insist
on Shakespeare,
My advice is,
don't over-rehearse.
Say a cue, you'll see,
I'll know it. Go on, try me.
Friends, Romans,
countrymen.
Is what?
Friends, Romans, countrymen.
No, no, no.
Don't tell me,
I'll get it.
You'll see.
Oh, yes, of course, of course.
Why, that's easy.
Why didn't you pick
a hard one?
Now, here, watch this.
Friends, Romans, countrymen.
Screw your courage
To that sticking place.
And be not sick.
And pale with reef.
For thou are handmaidens.
But far more fair than she.
Is.
How was that?
Do you think
he can do it?
The chicken lady is cheaper
and you get to keep the eggs.
I got faith in the bard,
let's sign him on.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Allow me to
introduce myself.
I am Henry Albertson.
BELLOMY: And who is that?
HENRY: That's Mortimer.
He has been with me
all his life.
He does death scenes.
Would you like to see one?
He's an expert.
Mortimer,
die for the gentlemen.
(CHOKING)
(GROANS)
And that's the short version.
The Indian is
out of the question.
Besides,
I think he is dead.
Oh. Too bad, 'cause
they're a team.
Inseparable.
So what could we
use instead?
How about Siamese twins.
Two for the price of one.
Nah, we're gonna
stick with Shakespeare.
Yeah. It'll be
a lifelong memory
for the children.
Lifelong memory it is.
Still not sure about
the Indian.
Gentlemen, we must hurry.
We have an abduction to stage.
This very night.
Here, you two had
better go home
and rehearse your parts.
Parts? We're not actors.
This is too much
to memorize.
Not actors, you say.
Very well then.
We'll do the abridged version.
* Abductions, abductions
Theatrical abductions
* Complete with
maidens in distress
And fabulous...
That's my part.
* With moonlight and so forth
* And happy
ending and so forth
* And it all depends on
* What you
* Pay
That's my part.
Hello.
I should have put on
something warmer.
I didn't expect it
to be so cold.
Feel my hand,
it's trembling.
Oh. Oh, well, here.
I don't need this.
No, you'll freeze.
No, no, really. Please.
I'm fine.
I'm not cold at all.
You're gonna wear it?
Yeah. You just said
you weren't cold, right?
Oh, I'm...
(THUNDERCLAP)
It's all right.
I'm scared, Matt.
I'll take care
of you, Luisa.
I promise,
I'll protect you.
I love you, Matt.
I want there to be
a happy ending.
I promise that there will be.
(THUNDERCLAP)
Feel that?
What?
My hand.
It's trembling too.
* Hear how the wind
begins to whisper
* See how the leaves go
streaming by
* Smell how the velvet rain
is falling,
* Out where the fields are
warm and dry
* Now is the time
to run inside and stay
to find a hideaway
* Where we can stay
MATT:
* Soon it's gonna rain
I can see it
I can tell
* Soon it's gonna rain
What are we gonna do?
* We'll find
four limbs of a tree
* We'll build
four walls and a floor
* We'll bind it
over with leaves
* And duck inside to stay
* Then we'll let it rain
* We'll not feel it
* Ran pell-mell
* And we'll not complain
* If it never stops at all
* We'll live and love
* Within our own four walls
How was it?
It was wonderful.
* We'll find
four limbs of a tree
* We'll build
four walls and a floor
* We'll bind it
over with leaves
* And run inside to stay
* When it's gonna rain
* Come run inside to stay
* For soon it's gonna rain
* I can see it
I can feel it
* Run inside
* And then we'll let it rain
* Then we'll let it rain
* We'll not feel it
* Rain pell-mell
* And we'll not complain
* Happy ending
* If it never stops at all...
* Then we'll let it rain
* Why complain
We'll live and love
* Within our walls
* Happily we'll live and love
No cares at all
* Within our castle
* Walls
(SCREAMING)
That's it. Go get him, son.
En garde!
(LUISA SCREAMING)
Not bad for a boy.
Matt!
Matt! Matt!
For Harry, England,
and St. George.
I'm unharmed.
Help!
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(YELLING)
(SCREAMING)
Oh, no.
Shakespeare stuff is great!
You there.
In the black cape.
Let her go.
What?
I said, let her go.
If that's what you want...
(SCREAMS)
Yee-haw!
Hold on, darling.
I've got you.
And who do you think has you?
(LUISA SCREAMING)
He's gone.
He's gone!
Yes.
Luisa.
Son!
Daughter?
Hey.
Papa, he saved me.
Well, in that case...
Neighbor.
Friend.
I always knew
there would be
a happy ending.
(ALL VOCALIZING)
* Love! You are love!
* Better far than a metaphor
can ever, ever be
* Love! You are love!
* My mystery of love!
* Love... Love... Love...
* Love...
* Love!
Luisa.
Ask your dad
if you can stay up
and watch the sunrise.
You ask him.
(BOTH WHISPERING)
(HUMMING)
LUISA: It's strange,
isn't it?
Meeting close up
without having to
hide from our fathers.
Here I am.
In the flesh.
Those days are over.
Yes, I see.
Luisa, what's the matter.
I don't want it
to be like this.
Like all the other
people that we know
sitting on a porch swing,
Fumbling for
a timid little kiss.
You like me better
through a crack in the wall?
No!
But you have to be
my hero.
I do?
Yes. You have to be.
You're right.
That moon
Is ours.
We own it.
I will not let it wane.
Stop moon.
Wane not.
I command thee.
Wax.
That's it.
That's the man I love.
Come.
Come into my arms
and here, take this,
This burning kiss
to wear upon your lips.
What?
Did you gargle
with something.
Yes, salt water.
Salt water.
It kills the germs.
This plum is
too ripe.
Sorry.
Please don't watch me
while I'm eating.
Sorry.
* Take away
the golden moonbeam
* Take away the tinsel sky
* What at night seems
oh so scenic
* May be cynic by and by
* Take away the painted sunset
* Take away the blue lagoon
* What at night seems
oh so scenic
* May be cynic much too soon
* Take away the sense of drama
* Take away the puppet play
* What at night seems
oh so scenic
* May be cynic by today
* Take away
the secret meetings
the chance to fight
* What at night seems
oh so scenic
* May be cynic in the light
ALL:
* So take it away
and paint it up right!
and decorate it!
* So take it away,
that sun is too bright!
* I say that
it really is a pity
It used to be so pretty
* Take away
the golden moonbeam
* Take away the tinted sunset
LUISA:
* Take away the tinsel sky
* What at night
seems oh so scenic
(OVERLAPPING)
* Take away the sense of drama
* May be cynic by and by
* Take away
the secret meetings
the chance to fight
* May be cynic much too soon
* What at night seems
oh so scenic
* May be cynic in the light
ALL:
* By today
* Much too soon
* By and by
This plum is too ripe!
ALL:
* Sorry
Tell you one thing,
Staying up all night
isn't what it's
cracked up to be.
Well, it might've been
if you hadn't
Sat around yawning
the whole time.
Sorry.
But I had an exhausting
battle, remember?
And what about me?
What did I have?
You're not the only ones
who didn't get any
sleep around here.
Damn swing creaking all night,
and you two bickering.
Why don't you put
some oil in that thing?
Why don't ya
paint your house?
What? What'd he say?
It's an eyesore.
Ruins the whole
neighborhood.
Neighborhood?
There ain't no
neighborhood around here!
Slopping the pigs
right in front of the house.
While we're at it,
I just assumed everybody
Didn't walk through
my corn field singing.
What are you two
fighting about?
This is our argument.
What? What'd she say?
She said,
"This is our argument!"
Well, knock it off,
for crying out loud.
If we thought you
were gonna act like this,
we never would've...
I just think that
maybe a "thank you"
might have been in order.
Never would've what?
(EXHALES)
We never would've let
you stay out all night!
Your father and I,
we treat you like adults.
And you turn around
and you act like
a couple of spoilt kids.
Now, I want you two
to kiss and make up.
This should be
a beautiful moment.
An act of heroism
took place last night.
Come on.
No expense was spared.
Bellomy.
Nice going, Bellomy.
Two hundred and fifty
smackers down the drain.
This is just great.
MATT: Wait a minute.
You two paid for us?
All my heroics
were make believe?
What would you call
a man who would stoop
As low as to do
something like this?
A father.
Matt, where are you going?
I got a score to settle.
Wait, I'm coming with you.
Luisa.
Matt, wait,
I'm coming with you.
No refunds.
Even with a receipt.
Somebody
get me a sword.
(GROANS)
En garde!
Up a bit with the wrists.
A foot back more.
Never take your eyes
from your opponent!
Quickly!
Aim for the entrails.
Good. Encore.
You have great enthusiasm,
But as in all things,
experience counts
for everything.
(GRUNTING)
It's impolite
to attack a man
Once he's in his
space of shaving.
Oh, I forgot.
You don't shave.
(GRUNTING)
I'm available for lessons.
Matt!
This isn't much fun
when you're not being paid.
Matt?
You... You...
Villain.
Don't do that.
You'll hurt your hand.
Nice boy.
Wait.
What?
What did you say?
I didn't say anything.
Then what
were you thinking?
I wasn't
thinking anything.
Yes you were. Well,
what are you thinking now?
Well...
Go on say it.
I just wanted to tell you,
I think you were right.
Right?
Not to pick up
the sword again.
Not to fight with him.
What I mean is...
Maybe you're not ready yet.
To be a hero.
No?
Well, maybe
I can be the villain.
He seems to have
all the good scenes.
With you anyway.
"You'll hurt your hand."
(SCOFFS) What a line.
I don't need you.
I don't need any of this.
I'm gonna go out
into the big world
And make a pile of money
and surround myself
with beautiful women
Who appreciate me.
See if I care.
(SOBBING)
* Beyond that road
lies a shining world
* Beyond that
road lies despair
* Beyond that road
Lies a world that's gleaming
* People who are scheming
* Beauty!
EL GALLO:
* Hunger!
* Glory!
* Sorrow!
* Never a pain or care
* He's liable to find
* A couple of surprises there
* For, I can see it!
* Shining somewhere!
* Bright lights somewhere
Invite me to come there
* And learn!
And I'm ready!
* I can hear it!
* Sirens singing!
* Inside my ear
I hear them all singing
* Come learn!
* Who knows, maybe
All the visions I can see
* May be waiting
just for me to say
* I can see it!
* Say
* Shining somewhere!
* Say!
* Take me there and
make me a part of it!
* Make
* Make me see
those shining
sights inside of me!
* Make him feel it!
* Make me feel
those lights inside
* I know it's so
I know that it really may be!
* Just what
I always waited for!
* This is what
my life's created for!
* Let me learn!
Hello, big boy.
Welcome to the Casbah.
Getting kinda dizzy.
That perfume!
It's Alexia de L'Amour.
Drink that.
What is it?
A little something
from the Caliph.
Two parts rhino horn,
one part mandrake,
one part ginseng.
Absinthe and a little
sprinkling of cojonas.
What's that?
Don't ask.
* I'd like to swim
in a clear blue stream
* Where the water is icy cold
* Then go to town
In a golden gown
* And have my fortune told
Just once.
Just once before you're old.
It's my bandit.
Your bandit, yes.
What are you doing
up there in that tree?
Growing ripe.
Don't grow too
ripe or you'll fall.
Very wise.
What do you see from up there?
Everything.
Do you see Matt?
Do you care?
No, I just wondered.
Can I climb up
there beside you?
You can if you can.
You know,
there's always my way.
Put a ladder in the back.
Is it fun to be a bandit?
It has its moments, yes.
I think it must be fun.
So...
How do you do it?
Do you ride into town
pretending to be a carnival
And then steal things
when people aren't looking?
That's one way to go.
And what do you steal?
Whatever's most valuable.
Whatever's treasured most.
That's more like it.
You see this ribbon?
That's where you
gave me a bruise.
Take me with you.
Show me your world.
What is it that you want?
That's just it.
I don't know what I want.
I want things
I've only heard about
Or dreamed.
I want to see places
I've never seen before.
I want to do things
I've never ever done.
You and I.
Us. Together.
Yes.
Dancing forever and forever.
* Round and round,
'Neath a magic spell
* Velvet gown, pink lapel
* Life is a colorful carousel
* Reckless and terribly gay!
* I'm ready anytime
* If you'll take me,
I'm ready to go!
* So show the way to me
* I will try to be
* Ready to go
* I seem to see Venice
We're on a lagoon
* A gondolier's crooning
a gondola tune
* The air makes your hair
Billow blue in the moon!
* I could swoon!
* You're so blue
in the moon! *
Oh, look.
Carnival in Venice.
Something I've
always wanted to see.
What's this?
A mask.
But it doesn't
have any expression.
Exactly.
As long as you wear this mask
your feelings will
never betray you.
No matter what happens,
with the mask,
you'll be able to laugh
And dance through it all.
That boy looks familiar.
Of course.
He's a country bumpkin,
they all look the same.
And they all wind up
the same way.
They're stealing his wallet.
Put on the mask,
then it's amusing.
Oh, yes, I see,
they're just having fun.
Bene! Bene!
(GRUNTS)
EL GALLO: Mustn't
cover the necklace.
Luisa.
It's much too beautiful.
* We'll just dance!
* We'll kick up our heels
to music and dance!
* Until my head
reels with music
* Just like
a lovely real romance
Luisa!
* All we'll do is daily dance
* All we'll do is just dance
* All we'll do is just...
Luisa!
Really? I'm exhausted.
You can't be.
The evening's just started.
* I seem to see Athens,
it's terribly chic
* Atop the Acropolis,
it's terribly Greek
* There's Venus,
Adonis, and us
Cheek to cheek
* Oh, how chic!
* To be Greek
cheek to cheek! *
(COUGHS)
Oh, look.
A Greek temple.
And they're having
some sort of contest.
Maybe it's the Olympics!
Yes! It's Greek wrestling.
Yes.
That boy...
They're gonna kill him.
Now remember,
if it is unpleasant.
Yes, of course, the mask.
Oh, I see, It's a game.
I just love classic sports.
You look lovely.
* We'll just dance!
* We'll kick up our heels
to music and dance!
* Until my head
reels with music
* Just like
a lovely real romance
Luisa!
* All we'll do is daily dance
* All we'll do is just dance
Luisa.
All we'll do is just... *
Phew!
Couldn't we just
sit this one out?
Ridiculous.
When there's music
to be danced to?
Play, gypsies.
* We'll be in Benghazi
or maybe Bombay
* I understand
India is terribly gay
* The natives assemble
on feast day and play
* With their snakes?
* What a racket it makes!
(HISSING)
I think
I'm going to love India.
Such a big population,
and I adore crowds.
Oh, look, there's a fakir.
Hi, fakir.
See, he's there
with his assistants.
They all know Yogi
and they're just
all loads of fun.
(GROANING)
There's a young one.
They're putting him
down on some nails.
If he fails, he'll be
cut to bits by those nails.
(WHIMPERING)
I don't want to see this.
You're probably right,
it may be someone you know.
LUISA: (LAUGHS)
I see, he's just faking.
He's a fake fakir.
Fake.
(SCREAMING)
I hate fakes.
* We'll just dance!
* We'll kick up our heels
to music and dance!
* Until my head
reels with music
* Just like
a lovely real romance
* All we'll do
is daily dance
* I can see
the friendly natives!
* All we'll do is just dance
* All we'll do is just
All we'll do is just
* All we'll do
* is just
* dance
(THUNDER CRACKING)
I'm suddenly afraid.
Of what?
I don't know.
Something.
Maybe you should go home.
All my life I've waited
for something
magical to happen.
Now at last,
with you, it will.
Or what if it's
all just illusions?
Sleight of hand.
This for example.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
The glamorous sideshows.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It's all scenery.
Smoke
And mirrors.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Well, what do you think now?
I think you're wonderful.
But don't you understand
it was only a trick?
And when you're
dealing with tricks,
What you see isn't
always what you get.
I'm warning you to be careful.
I know you are.
But I trust you.
I know that you'll
make it all right.
Oh, very well then.
You better go pack
some things so that
we can run away together.
After all, you can't
run away and stay at home
at the same time.
Well, who cares
if we never see this
one goat town again.
We can drop by
in five or six years
To see if your father
is still alive.
What?
The world
Is waiting.
I wonder if Matt...
Matt?
Never mind.
All right, go.
Get ready.
See if you can borrow
a little money
while you're about it.
Kiss me first.
No matter what happens,
I'll never,
ever forget that kiss.
A unique sensation
of an unworldly nature
Running from the base of
the spine to the knees.
(LAUGHS)
Wait.
Give me a trinket
to pledge that
you'll come back.
That necklace.
It was my mother's.
Good. It will
service your pledge.
I will leave you
my mother's necklace
Because it is
my favorite thing.
Guard it.
And I'll go pack.
I won't be long.
You're really
taking me with you?
Would I lie?
I won't be long.
You will be here?
I promise.
All right, move it out.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Ah, the prodigal son
comes out from his trip
around the world.
Allow me to say,
you look much wiser
but less well groomed.
Leave me alone.
Fine, I'm in a bit of
a rush, anyway.
Where did you get that?
Oh, this?
It's just a souvenir.
It's Luisa's.
You stole it.
Please, she gave it to me.
Not that it's any
business of yours.
Now, as I said.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
All right. Move it out.
El Gallo.
El Gallo!
El Gallo?
(SOBBING)
EL GALLO:
There is a curious paradox
that no one can explain.
Who understands the secret
of the reaping of the grain.
Who understands
why spring is born
out of winter's laboring pain.
Or why we all must die a bit
before we grow again.
Matt.
What happened?
You look awful.
It isn't worth tears,
Luisa, please.
Did you find the money
and the beautiful women.
I can't remember, I...
I was drugged
or hypnotized
or something.
There was this
funny light and mirrors.
I know.
And there was this music.
Strange music and people
Turning and spinning and...
Wearing masks.
I remember crying out.
But no one came
to help you.
I'm sorry, Matt.
No, I...
It's all right.
I deserved it.
I've been foolish.
I have, too.
Believe me,
more than you.
* When the moon was young
* When the month was May
* When the stage was hung
for my holiday
* I saw shining lights
* But I never knew
* They were you
They were you
* When the dance was done
* When I went my way
* When I tried to find
rainbows far away
* All the lovely lights
* Seemed to fade from view
* They were you
They were you
BOTH:
* Without you near me
* I can't see
* When you're near me
* Wonderful things come to be
* Every secret prayer
* Every fancy free
* Everything I dared
for both you and me
* All my wildest dreams
* Multiplied by two
* They were you
I missed you, Matt.
I missed you, too.
Here, maybe I can
stop your bleeding.
You already have.
You've been hurt too.
Look, it's beginning to snow.
I know.
Here.
Take my coat.
Both.
There's room there
for both.
* Love! You are love!
* You are love!
* Better far than a metaphor
can ever, ever be
* Love!
* You are love!
* My mystery
* Of Love!
BELLOMY:
Look, they've come back.
HUCKLEBEE:
It's a miracle.
They're home.
Matt!
Luisa.
EL GALLO:
* Try to remember
the kind of September
* When life was slow
and oh, so mellow
* Try to remember
the kind of September
* When grass was green
and grain was yellow
* Try to remember
the kind of September
* When you were
a tender and callow fellow
* Try to remember,
and if you remember
* Then follow
* Deep in December,
it's nice to remember
* Although you know
the snow will follow
* Deep in December,
it's nice to remember
* Without a hurt
the heart is hollow
* Deep in December,
it's nice to remember
* The fire of September
that made us mellow
* Deep in December,
our hearts should remember
* And follow