[ORCHESTRA PLAYlNG]
[CROWD APPLAUDlNG]
[SlNGlNG]
With a laugh and a dance
Mine's a life to entrance
Not a thought, not a care
With a heart debonair
I am free as the sea
Like the lark who at dawn
Bids the darkness begone
Do I sing merrily
With a laugh and a dance
Mine's a life to entrance
For I know naught but glee
And the word that I bring
And the theme that I sing
Is the song of a heart that's free
Oh, then let music ring
While sweet voices sing
Pleasure is mine
Echoes repeating, measures entreating
Song of a heart light and free
Laughing all the day
Chaffing cares away
Hear my roundelay
Heigh-o
Not a thought, not a care
With a heart debonair
I am free as the sea
Like the lark who at dawn
Bids the darkness begone
Do I sing merrily
With a laugh and a dance
Mine's a life to entrance
For I know naught but glee
And the word that I bring
And the theme that I sing
Is the song of a heart
That's free!
[MOUTHS]
Come on. Hurry up.
Better play the short version, Papa.
Mama's in a hurry.
''The Light Cavalry Overture.''
[ORCHESTRA PLAYlNG]
Patti, get your valise. We'll have to rush
or we're going to miss the boat.
l wanna miss the boat.
Mother, why do we always have to go
to Kissamee-in-the-Catskills;
-l hate Kissamee-in-the-Catskills.
-Oh, nonsense. Last year you loved it.
-Last year l was a child.
-You're still a child...
...even if you sit up half the night
lengthening your dresses.
But l was 1 7 last week.
You may treat me like a baby,
but inside l'm a woman.
Now, Patti, l want no trouble
with you this summer.
You're not interested in boys
and l want you to stay that way.
When you're 1 8,
we'll have a little talk--
Eighteen ;
Mother, that's almost a whole year away.
How will l ever get through the summer;
-l'm gonna be a misfit all summer long.
-That's enough.
Finish your packing
and change your clothes.
And l don't want to hear one other word
about Kissamee-in-the-Catskills.
Remind me to shorten that dress.
MELBA: Mr. Hibbs is here
with the carriage, Mama.
BOTH: Hi, Mr. Hibbs. Hi, Nettie. Hi, Hettie.
HlBBS: Hi.
Come on up for the baggages, Mr. Hibbs.
KATHERlNE: Oh, boys, close your valise.
RlCKY: We can't. They're too full.
-Have Melba sit on it.
-You gotta sit on our valise.
-Why;
-Because you got the biggest sitter.
Besides, Mama said.
A female woman
is supposed to have hips.
RlCKY:
Sit harder, Melba.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYlNG]
Put on your hats and coats.
RlCKY: Do l have to sit
on Patti's lap this year, Mama;
McCORMlCK:
Can l take Delilah along;
Oh, he was supposed to play the short
version. Yes, you do. No, you can't.
Only sissies sit on girls' laps.
[KNOCKlNG]
Come in, Mr. Hibbs.
-Who's going to give Delilah her bath ;
-Maggie will be stopping by every morning.
You ought to have allowed
more time this year.
Nettie and Hettie
ain't what they used to be.
But Delilah doesn't like Maggie.
-Why can't Patti sit on my lap ;
-Folks never leave enough time.
Can l take Delilah as far as the boat;
She's never seen the Hudson River.
All right. Mr. Hibbs can bring her back.
Mother, really.
You'd think we were Gypsies.
-That's it.
-Don't be silly.
[CROWD APPLAUDlNG]
lt is. Come on, children.
Be sure you have everything, now.
Take Father's coat,
bring Delilah and we're off.
Off for two glorious weeks
at Kissamee-in-the-Catskills.
[PEOPLE CHATTERlNG]
Young man, l'm not paying you
1 0 cents a day to gawk into a well.
-l wasn't gawking. There's a frog in there.
-Shh!
[FROG CRO AKlNG]
Fish it out after dark.
Carry the Schuster's bags in.
They're still on the front stoop.
Papa, the surrey's gonna be here
any minute.
-What's the surrey got to do with it;
-Papa, the Robinsons will be on it.
Oh, Robinsons or no Robinsons,
get up here and carry these bags in.
Welcome home. Mrs. Robinson,
you're looking as young as your daughters.
-Hello, Mr. Robinson.
-Hello, Finlay. lt's hot.
Billy. Billy Finlay.
Gosh, he's grown a foot.
Hello, Patti.
-Gosh, you look wonderful.
-So do you, Billy.
-Can l help you; Can l take your bag;
-Thank you.
-Here's mine.
-What's the matter; Your arm broken ;
-l suppose we have our same old rooms;
-No, better ones. You're up in 23 this year.
-Old Mrs. Hochstatter finally died.
-ln our bed;
No, in Hoboken.
Patti, how about a walk before supper;
l mean, after supper.
l mean, how about a walk;
-l have an engagement, Billy.
-Already;
-Oh.
-What's wrong with his pants;
Gee, can l help it if my father
won't let me have longies for another year;
Poor boy. Parents are so trying.
Patti, how about walking to the post office
with me tomorrow, maybe;
Sorry, l'm not expecting any mail, Billy.
Golly, last summer she was fun.
What's got into her, anyway;
Old age. She thinks she's 1 8
and she knows you're only 1 6.
Well, can l help it; Besides, l look older.
l know. And l don't mind a bit.
Be sure to scrub out this basin, girls.
And remember,
there are other people in the world.
Don't stay in the bathroom forever.
-Yes, Mom.
HORATlO: Katie!
Who put this feather snake in my suitcase;
My new jacket's covered with whiskers.
Now, Horatio, don't get excited.
-Must be the molting season.
-Yes. Well, l won't have it.
[KNOCKlNG]
Come in.
[DOOR OPENS]
-Valerie.
-Patti.
-Oh!
-l just heard you got in.
A whole year and how you've changed.
Why, you're pretty.
Melba hasn't changed a bit.
-We followed your tour in the papers.
-Oh, that.
After one's been on the stage
since one was 6...
...why, one tour is just like another.
But with John Barrymore.
Let me touch you.
Well, yes, he was rather nice.
Did you have a scene with him;
Well, no, not exactly.
You see, l die in the prologue.
-Someone in the audience shoot you;
-Melba.
Patti, l've got oodles to tell you...
...but it's all going to have to keep
until big ears with hair bows aren't around.
Melba, dear, why don't you go and see
what we're going to have for dinner;
l already know.
Sauerkraut and pig's knuckles.
Patti, Mother's still playing whist.
Be a sport and tighten me up, will you;
About 1 8 inches.
PATTl: lt's beautiful.
-lt's the La Belle Mode for Young Misses.
PATTl: ls that all right;
-A little tighter, dear.
-l can still take a deep breath.
PATTl: All right.
They wear the same in the loony house
only they call them straitjackets.
They do give you such a
wonderful feeling, don't they;
Yes, wonderful.
How would you know;
Melba, would you ask Mr. Finlay
what night we take our baths;
l already know. Thursday, 7 a.m.
We have Saturday night.
But then, of course,
we have a more expensive room.
-Are there any new people here this year;
-Not a soul.
Talk about the man shortage. Why, l may
have to ask one of your brothers for a date.
-Oh, is it that desperate;
-lt's indescribable.
Of course, it's not so awful for you.
You're not eligible for the older set.
Well, l'm almost 1 8.
-Yeah, in 1 1 months.
-Will you please go downstairs;
Oh, Patti, darling,
l know just how you feel.
That old unwritten law.
Seventeen just can't go with 1 8.
lt doesn't seem fair.
But when you're in the older set,
why, then you'll understand.
lf you ask me, some people
are just afraid of competition.
Melba, dear, why don't you go downstairs
and help Billy Finlay set the tables;
Think l will.
l have the most wond--
[HORN HONKlNG]
[PEOPLE CHATTERlNG]
lsn't he dashing;
PATTl:
Who do you suppose he is;
He must be related
to that Mrs. Armendez from Cuba.
Well, l guess l'd better be running along.
l mustn't keep my mother waiting.
Thanks for lacing me, darling.
[DOOR CLOSES]
What are you gonna wear;
Oh, l don't know.
What are the Cuban colors;
Three blue stripes on white
with a red triangle.
But you're too skinny for stripes.
You don't look good in red.
More water, Patti;
-No, thank you.
-l'd love some.
Melba, that makes five.
The dam will go any minute.
Mama said a bad word.
Go swimming with me tomorrow, Patti;
l really can't say, Billy.
-Next day;
-l'll have to let you know.
l can go both days.
What are they staring at;
My new dress.
Right this way, Senor Armendez.
Thank you.
KATHERlNE:
Patti, close your mouth.
Oh.
[CHUCKLES]
That mustache does nothing for you.
KATHERlNE: Wipe you lip, dear.
-Oh.
Careful, you'll blow crumbs in Papa's lap.
Oh, Papa, l'm sorry.
Oh, now it's ashes.
What's the matter with that girl;
lt's that new Cuban.
Ouch! That's my sore ankle.
Now, Papa, ashes are good for moths.
Well, l don't like moths.
Why should l be good to them;
What new Cuban ;
Papa, please. He's right behind you.
Hm; Oh, so that's it, eh ;
What's so extraordinary about him;
You'd think he had two heads.
[HORATlO CHUCKLES]
l was much more attractive
when l was his age, wasn't l;
Yes, Papa, much.
-May l please be excused;
-You haven't touched your tapioca.
-l'll eat it.
Quiet, children. Very well, Patti.
-Thank you.
-Elbows off the table, dear.
Oh, l'm sorry--
-Oh, Patti. Gee, l'm sorry.
-Oh, gosh, tapioca.
With raisins.
Oh!
-Oh, no, dear.
-Get back to the kitchen, young man.
A regrettable accident, regrettable.
lt won't happen again, l assure you.
Poor child.
ALL [SlNGlNG] :
Like the roses need their fragrance
Like a sweetheart needs a kiss
A kiss
Like the summer needs the sunshine
Like a laddie needs a miss
A miss
Like a broken heart needs gladness
Like the flowers need the dew
Need the dew
Like a baby needs its mother
That's how I need you
How I need you
[VOlCE CRACKS]
[BO YS GRO AN]
What did you expect, Caruso;
[BO YS CHATTERlNG]
[PLAYlNG OFF-KEY]
[SlNGlNG]
That's how I need you
Patti.
ls your head all right;
You sure dented my tray.
-He isn't in here, is he;
-With us kids;
Hey, Patti, come on.
Let's have ''The Oceana Roll.''
Yeah, Patti, sing ''The Oceana Roll.''
-Yeah, come on, Patti.
-Come on, Patti.
[ALL CHEERlNG]
[SlNGlNG]
Billy McCoy was a musical boy
On the cruiser Alabama
He was there at the piano
Like a fish down in the sea
Oh, when he rattled off some harmony
Every night upon the ocean
He would get that raggy notion
Start that syncopated motion lovingly
No one could sleep
Way out there on the deep
When Billy cut loose out at sea
Each fish and worm
Begins to twist and squirm
The ship starts in to dip
And does a corkscrew turn
Just see that smoke so black
Sneak from that old smokestack
It's floatin' right to heaven
And it won't come back
Now here and there
You'll see a stool and chair
A-slippin' round the cabin
Shoutin' ''I don't care!''
And then the hammock starts a-swingin'
And the bell begins a-ringin'
While we're sittin' at that piano
There on the Alabama
Playin' the Oceana Roll
ALL [SlNGlNG] : Each fish and worm
Begins to twist and squirm
The ship starts in to dip
And does a corkscrew turn
Just see that smoke so black
Sneak from that old smokestack
It's floatin' right to heaven
And it won't came back
Now here and there
You'll see a stool and chair
A-slippin' round the cabin
Shoutin' ''I don't care!''
And then the hammock starts a-swingin'
And the bell begins a-ringin'
While we're sittin' at that piano
There on the Alabama
Playin' the Oceana Roll
Every time he sits down
At the piano stool
People start a-shoutin'
''You're a playin' fool''
'Cause he is the master of the razzmatazz
He's known to everyone as Mr. Jazz
When he gets a-goin'
With a real hot break
Even Davy Jones
Begins to shim and shake
Oh, brother, you'll declare
Hey, he's a bear
What a lot of music he can make
-So listen here
-And lend an ear
So listen here and lend an ear
And lend an ear
Slippin' round the cabin
Shoutin' ''I don't care!''
And then the hammock starts a-swingin'
And the bell begins a-ringin'
While we're sittin' at that piano
There on the Alabama
Playin' the Oceana Roll
[ALL CHEERlNG]
l'll see you all later.
VALERlE: Patti.
-Thank you.
Oh, Val, wasn't it awful
what happened in the dining room;
Oh, you poor dear.
What a dreadful impression to make.
l can never look him in the face again.
But l suppose l'll have to when l apologize.
lf l were you,
l'd keep out of his way for a while.
He was quite upset.
-You've met him;
-Well, naturally.
He asked to be presented to me.
-Oh, Val, what's he like;
-Oh, very adult.
Beautiful manners. A gentleman.
Oh, a gentleman.
l've never met one.
Patti, l've got wonderful news for you.
Eddie Gavin doesn't have a girl this year.
l believe he's available.
Oh, him. He's always available.
Well, l wouldn't be too hasty
if l were you.
You know, a clever woman
can always mold a man.
No, thank you. He's moldy enough.
Oh, dear.
-Senor Armendez.
-Excuse me a moment, please.
[PLAYER PlANO PLAYlNG]
Miss Robinson ; l've been looking for you.
-For me;
-Everywhere. But you had vanished.
l wanted to return your fan and
to reassure you about the little accident.
Oh, but it wasn't an accident.
-You mean you did it on purpose;
-Oh, no, l mean it was all my fault.
-l stooped when l shouldn't have stooped.
-Oh, no. lt was my fault.
-l bent when l shouldn't have bent.
-No, mine.
-l stooped when l--
-Nonsense, mine. l bent.
-Stooped.
-Bent.
-No, please. lt's forgotten, yes;
-Oh, well, thank you very much.
Oh, but l did spoil your jacket
and your dessert.
You know,
Mr. Finlay only allows one helping.
Well, l'll tell you a secret.
l detest tapioca.
Me too.
l'd much rather have one
of your American ice-cream sodas.
Well, there's an ice-cream parlor
in the village.
-Oh ;
-Yes. You just go down this road...
...turn left at the knife--
l mean, at the fork.
And then you turn right--
l mean left.
Well, maybe you'd better
show me the way, huh ;
Shall we take a little stroll;
-Now;
-Yes.
-The two of us;
-Unless you'd like to ask someone else.
-Oh, no.
-Well, fine, fine.
-We will toast our meeting with a soda.
-Strawberry.
Well, hello, you two.
l didn't know you had met.
-Oh, we're old friends.
-We're going to have a soda.
-Strawberry.
-l'd love one.
-Would you like to join us;
-l'd adore to.
Heavenly night for a stroll.
-Patti, isn't it rather late for you;
-l don't know what you mean.
Oh, Patti. Hello, Valerie.
Good evening, Mr. Armendez.
-Good evening.
-Bad news, darling. Time for bed.
But, Mama, l'm not tired.
Nevertheless, you need your rest.
Growing girls, you know.
Come along, dear.
Now, isn't that just like a mother;
l'm so sorry.
We'll do it some other time.
That's a promise.
Good night, senorita. Buenas nochas.
Good night.
My, don't they make a nice couple;
He asked me first.
Oh, now, Patti,
don't you go getting ideas.
He's much too old for you.
You've got plenty of time.
Not on a two-weeks vacation, l haven't.
[CHlLDREN LAUGHlNG]
Don't run and watch out
for the poison ivy.
-What's it look like;
-A shiny green leaf with three forks.
Anybody knows that.
-Like this;
-McCormick, drop that.
Mac's gonna get poison ivy.
lf l do, l'll give it to you.
That's enough.
l forbid either one of you to get it.
Oh, Patti. Hurry along, dear.
Children.
Be sure you stay on the children's side
and don't get out where it's deep.
-Now run along.
RlCKY: Okay.
Take a squint at the potato sack.
Where did you get that suit;
[lMlTATES SEAL BARKlNG]
[ALL LAUGHlNG]
Why don't you watch
where you're going;
Castle-buster.
l'm sorry, Mac.
l'll help you build another.
What's the matter;
Look at me.
Yeah, pretty awful.
lf l were you,
l wouldn't let anybody see me.
Hi, Patti. Don't go away.
l'll be right back.
Hello, Melba.
On second thought, Patti, an older woman
like you ought to be with the grownups.
Why don't you stand up for your rights
and go on back there;
Oh, quick. Cover me with sand.
Bury me or something.
MELBA:
Come on, Mac.
McCORMlCK:
What's the matter; ls she dead;
-She will be if he sees her.
-Hurry.
Hurry up.
-Havana must be simply beautiful.
-Mm-hm.
Not that.
-Hello, children. What are you playing, huh ;
McCORMlCK: Funeral.
Yeah, we just buried a dead fish.
-ls that Morro Castle;
-No, Robinson's Castle.
-Oh, are you Patti Robinson's brother;
RlCKY: Yeah.
Where does she hide herself, huh ;
-Oh, under pails, boxes, most anything.
-Ha, ha. Well, when you find her...
...tell her that the strawberry sodas
are wonderful, will you;
Come along, Demi. Horrible child.
Oh, no. l think she's very amusing.
They're a very charming family.
Did you hear that;
l'm horrible, the family's charming,
the sodas are wonderful.
-Shall we take a dip ;
-lf you'll promise to protect me.
Why, Valerie, you disappoint me.
l had hoped to find you independent,
self-reliant.
All the qualities l admire
in American women.
Oh.
Well....
Hey, look.
Lady Godiva.
Hey, Melba, where's Patti;
l haven't the faintest idea.
Billy, wait for me.
PATTl:
Help, Melba. Melba, Mac.
Oh, please, kids.
Come get me out of here. Melba!
-Patti, where are you;
PATTl: Here, Papa, l'm down here.
-Down where;
PATTl: Oh, hurry, Papa. Under a pail.
-Come on, Papa, hurry. Please, hurry.
-Pail; What...;
PATTl:
Please, l can't stand it any longer.
Help, help, help, Papa.
Get me out of here, please!
What are you doing there;
You come out of there this minute.
-You could be drowned.
-l wanna drown.
And when l do, l hope my bathing suit
washes up at Mama's feet.
What's the matter with your bathing suit;
Has it got a hole;
Oh, Papa, everything.
All the other girls are dressed
like young ladies.
And l'm kept like an orphan, an infant.
The way Mama treats me,
you'd think l'm in diapers.
Patti, l'm sure your mama knows
what's good for you.
ls it good for me to be a laughingstock,
an object of ridicule, a potato sack;
Oh, my dear child,
it can't be as bad as that--
Oh, my, yes, yes, it can.
Oh, you poor little thing.
Here, put this on.
Cover yourself up.
And l'll be right back.
Thank you, Papa.
Katie, l wanna talk to you.
Look, the lifeguard's
teaching me to swim.
Yes, so l notice. l'll finish the lesson,
thank you very much.
A pleasure, sir.
Katie, you've got to buy Patti
a bathing suit.
She has a bathing suit.
-Look out.
-Hold my chin up.
Call that a bathing suit;
That's a potato sack.
My daughter is not a potato.
KATHERlNE:
Your daughter;
lf l remember correctly,
l had a little something to do with that.
Now, Katie-- Look out, Katie.
What do you want her to do,
go around flaunting herself like Valerie;
Great heavens, no, but l--
l suppose l ought to put her hair up,
pull in her waist.
-Pad her hips.
-Look out, look out.
The first thing you know, some silly man
will come along and want to marry her.
-ls that what you want;
-Good heavens, no,
She's just a child, she's a baby, she's....
Katie, you're a smart woman.
You know what's best for our girl.
l'm gonna leave Patti entirely to you.
But look here, Katie.
Couldn't you possibly find
a bathing suit for her...
...that's maybe a little bit in between ;
That's a girl, Katie.
Say, you're doing fine.
Come on around here now.
That's the stuff.
ALL [SlNGlNG] :
Aba daba, daba, daba, daba, daba, daba
Means ''Monk, I love but you''
Aba daba, dab in monkey talk
Means ''Chimp, I love you too ''
Then the big baboon one night in June
He married them and very soon
They went upon
Their aba daba honeymoon
Way down in the Congoland
Lived a happy chimpanzee
She loved a monkey with the long tail
Lordy, how she loved him
Each night he would find her there
Swinging in the coconut tree
And the monkey gay at the break of day
Loved to hear his chimpie say:
''Aba daba, daba, daba, daba, daba, daba ''
Said the chimpie to the monk
Said the monkey to the chimp
All night long they'd chatter away
All day long they were happy and gay
Swinging and singing
In their honky-tonky way
Aba daba, daba, daba, daba, daba, daba
Means ''Monk, I love but you''
Baba daba, dab in monkey talk
Means ''Chimp, I love you too ''
Then the big baboon one night in June
He married them and very soon
They went upon
Their aba daba honeymoon
''Aba daba, daba, daba, daba, daba, daba ''
Said chimpie to the monk
Said monkey to the chimp
All night long they'd chatter away
All day long they were happy and gay
Swinging and singing
In their honky-tonky way
Aba daba, daba, daba, daba, daba, daba
Means ''Monk, I love but you''
Baba, daba, dab in monkey talk
Means ''Chimp, I love you too ''
And the big baboon one night in June
He married them and very soon
They went upon
Their aba daba honeymoon
[CROWD LAUGHlNG]
And the big baboon one night in June
He married them and very soon
They went upon their aba daba honey
CHORUS: Aba daba, aba daba
Aba daba honeymoon
ALL:
A honeymoon
[CROWD LAUGHlNG
AND CHATTERlNG]
Billy, Mrs. Schlessinger
wants a hot-water bag.
On a night like this;
Don't argue, fill it.
MELBA:
l'll hold the bag.
Hello, Val.
Why, Patti, what are you doing here
all by your lonesome;
-Waiting for someone.
-Billy;
Oh, well, l should hope not. Demi.
Oh ; Do you have a date with him;
Well, not exactly.
But last night, when l couldn't go
for a walk with him, he said another time.
-And this is another time so....
-Oh.
You know, Patti, if you want to
intrigue a sophisticated man like Demi...
...you're just going to have to learn
to project your personality.
-l'm afraid l haven't much to project.
-But of course you have.
Why, you're full of latent fire.
All you have to do is fan it a little bit.
Adopt a more alluring manner.
Act more worldly,
more mysterious, like, uh....
Like Theda Bara.
Oh, but, Val, Theda Bara was born
in the shadow of the sphinx...
...and l was born across the street
from McSweeney's Livery Stable.
Theda Bara is the perfect model for you.
Now, when you get Demi
exactly where you want him...
...appeal to his protective instinct.
Act helpless.
You know, if there's one thing
foreign men adore, it's a clinging vine.
Oh, but, Val, Theda Bara's too exotic, l--
But, Patti, it's so simple.
All you have to do is think of Egypt,
the Nile and the pyramids....
-You really think it would help ;
-Absolutely.
Gosh, Val. Thanks a lot.
Don't mention it, darling.
l'm always glad to help.
Theda Bara;
DEMl:
What did you say;
PATTl:
Yes, Demi, there are two Patti Robinsons.
One is gay, carefree, debonair.
[PATTl AND DEMl LAUGHlNG]
The other is deep, mysterious.
The real me.
The me l keep hidden from the world.
-l'm an iceberg.
-l beg your pardon ;
Oh, not that l'm cold, mind you...
...but only one-fifth of me
appears above the surface.
lmagine that.
Well, do you suppose the other four-fifths
might care to go for a canoe ride;
Oh, golly, that'd--
Well, that might be rather nice...
...if you promise not to rock the boat.
The other four-fifths of me can't swim.
Oh, well, then l don't know.
They tell me the lake is pretty deep.
Oh, but l wouldn't be afraid with you.
lf anything happened--
Well, if anything happened...
...l'd fling my arms around your neck
like a clinging vine and l'd cling.
l'd cling, cling, like a....
Like a clinging vine.
-Patti, l'd love to take you canoeing, but--
-Did somebody mention canoeing;
Demi just asked me for a canoe ride.
-Unfortunately, she doesn't swim.
-Oh, dear.
And the Robinsons would never forgive you
if anything happened to their little girl.
Shall we;
All right. l'm sorry, Patti.
When you learn to swim, hm;
-Let's go, Valerie.
-Mm-hm.
-Of all the gooses.
-Geeses.
Letting that vamp walk off with him.
And what was the idea of telling him
you couldn't swim;
lt wasn't my idea, it was Val--
Oh!
Sometimes l wonder
what Billy sees in you.
CHORUS [SlNGlNG] :
By the light
Of the silv'ry moon
I want to spoon
To my honey I'll croon love's tune
MEN: Honey moon
WOMEN: Honey moon
CHORUS:
Keep a-shining in June
Your silv'ry beams
Will bring love's dreams
We'll be cuddling soon
By the silv'ry moon
Mama and Papa;
Gee willikens.
[SlNGlNG]
By the light
Of the silv'ry moon
-I want to spoon
-To my honey I'll croon love's tune
-Honey moon
-Won't you listen, Honey moon;
-Keep a-shining in June
-Your silv'ry beams will bring love's dreams
-Beams will bring love's dreams
-We'll be cuddling soon
Cuddling soon
-By the silv'ry moon
By the light
Of the silv'ry moon
I wanna spoon
To my honey I'll croon love's tune
Honey moon
Keep a-shining in June
Your silv'ry beams
Will bring love's dreams
We'll be cuddling soon
By the silv'ry moon
Oh, my dear.
Oh, my dear Patti,
you sing like a nightingale.
Oh, l could listen forever.
-Do you really like me;
-Oh, Patti, can't you see;
To me, you are perfect.
Oh, but, Demi, you're so much older.
Everybody says so.
Don't listen to them.
ln my country, age is unimportant.
Girls marry very young.
Oh. You're not asking me to marry you;
Not yet, but who knows;
Who knows; That isn't very definite.
Oh, my darling.
lsn't it enough for you to know that
you're the one woman l've been seeking;
So beautiful, so alluring,
so full of latent fire.
l feel exactly the same way
about you, Demi.
-But we must be honest with each other.
-Of course.
There's something l must tell you.
lt wouldn't be fair to go on
until you know the whole truth about me.
-You have a past, huh ;
-Oh, no, no.
lt's right now. Oh, l--
l'm so ashamed.
l don't know how l can say it.
lt's something over which
l have no control.
You--
You're not addicted to drink;
No, only sodas. Strawberry.
My darling, whatever it is,
l will understand.
l will forgive and forget.
Querida, may l kiss you;
lf you like.
-Demi, what is it;
-No corset.
Oh, Demi. Demi l tried to tell you.
lt'll only be 1 1 months, please wait.
-What you ask is impossible.
-Oh, Demi.
Demi, don't leave me.
Please, don't leave me.
Demi, don't leave me. Please, Demi.
Demi, please come back to me.
-Patti, what is it; What's the matter;
-Please, Demi....
Huh ; Oh!
She can't swim.
l'll save you, keep calm.
Don't lose your head.
-Don't touch me, don't touch--
-Stop struggling.
-Stop.
-Let go. Go away.
-But you can't swim, you'll drown.
-l don't care.
DEMl: She's hysterical.
-Hold her, l'll hit her with the paddle. Oh!
Oh, oh! Demi, Demi, Demi.
Oh, Demi, Demi.
l'm so sorry, did l hurt you;
-That's all right. Where is she;
-Oh, Demi.
-Patti!
-Demi. Oh, Demi.
Oh, oh, oh!
Oh!
DEMl:
Patti, Patti, come back here.
Patti, come back here.
Patti, where are you;
Patti; Patti;
[PATTl SNEEZES]
[HORSE WHlNNlES]
You may as well come out.
l will wait.
Now, what do you mean
telling me you couldn't swim;
l was scared out of a year's growth.
You deserve a good, sound spanking,
you know that;
l'm sorry. Honest.
l was only trying to....
A girl's not supposed to be independent,
able to swim, things like that.
-Who says so;
-Valerie.
Oh, she does, does she;
Men don't like it, do they;
Well, that depends.
Some don't and some do.
Before you catch cold,
you've got to get this dress off.
Now;
As soon as you get back to the hotel.
[HORSE WHlNNlES]
Just borrowing it, amigo, all right;
You're not angry anymore;
-We'll talk about that in the morning.
-What time;
Come along,
l don't want you to catch the influenza.
Come on. Hurry up.
[SNEEZES]
-Hello, Papa.
-Mr. Robi--
Ten minutes after 1 0,
a fine time to be bringing a girl home.
-What happened;
-Patti fell in the lake.
-He frightened me.
-You frightened her; ls this a joke;
No, Papa. He was serious.
-Where did you get that blanket;
-When he chased me into the barn.
-Her dress was soaking wet and l--
-He wanted me to take it off--
What;! Young man,
you ought to be ashamed of yourself.
Throwing my little girl into the lake,
chasing her into a barn.
Bringing her home in a horse blanket.
Control yourself.
You'll wake up half the hotel.
-l'll wake up the other half of the hotel.
-l was trying to tell your husband--
And l mistook this man for a gentleman.
A fella that plays jokes,
chases little girls into barns.
-Oh, Papa, he's gone.
-l'll speak to your consul about this.
Beast.
You can't do that to my girl.
Put them up, you rounder.
[SPEAKS lN SPANlSH]
When are you gonna light the fuse,
Mr. Finlay;
Tomorrow evening, boys.
-Here you are.
-Thanks.
This is going to be the biggest,
most elaborate pyrotechnical display...
...in the entire Catskills.
Oh, Billy, make sure all the Roman candles
and skyrockets are pointing north...
...then come inside
and change the flypaper.
-What are pyrotechnicals;
-Shh!
Those things we got
hidden under the bed.
McCORMlCK:
Oh.
All right, Katie. One, two, three, inhale.
There. Every summer
it gets a little more difficult.
Oh, not that you're gaining weight,
my dear. lt's that l'm losing muscle.
[KNOCKlNG]
-Horatio, the children.
-lt's all right.
l imagine by now they suspect
we're rather fond of each other. Come in.
Hello, Patti. What's the matter;
Why aren't you dressed for the dance;
What dance; Oh, that.
Well, l'm not going. l'd much rather
stay here and take care of Mac and Ricky.
Melba can do that. She should be at
the party with the rest of the young people.
That Armendez fellow is taking Valerie
and she refuses to go with anyone else.
Oh. What's the matter with Billy;
Oh, Papa. Billy, he's just a child.
How would l look walking in
with a child who's still in knickers;
More sensible than you would
with a grown man.
l think you're taking this too seriously.
You'll have a lot of beaus
before you find the right one.
-Have a lot of girls before you met Mama;
-Who me; Of course.
-That's not what Mama says.
-Well, of course....
Your mama didn't know
anything about that.
There was one in particular,
a stylish little redhead.
She had big brown eyes.
She had a turned-up nose.
She had-- Oh, she was a pip.
-What was her name;
-Who; Oh, Beulah.
Beulah was crazy about me.
She kept giving me presents all the time.
Crocheted neckties.
She gave me a hand-painted shaving mug
with forget-me-nots on it.
Painted it herself, you know.
That was her perfume.
Every time l smell forget-me-nots,
it brings me back to Beulah.
PATTl: Oh, what happened to her;
-Beulah ;
She married another man.
A millionaire, mind you.
l thought my life would end.
But here l am.
Still going strong, eh, Mama;
-My, yes.
-And it'll be the same with you, my dear.
After a couple of weeks,
you'll forget this foreign fella.
-lsn't that so, dear;
-Oh, yes.
Just as you forgot all about
that stylish little redhead.
Come say good night to the boys.
The Stresemanns are waiting.
Oh, no, no, no, Katie.
Not the chicken feathers again.
Oh, Horatio. They're very fashionable.
Yes, well l only hope
we don't run into a rooster.
KATHERlNE:
Boys, stop that.
-Hey, hold on.
-Time for you to quiet down.
Why have they got
their sister's nightdresses on ;
The girls have outgrown them,
but they're still perfectly good.
There's no reason
why they should go to waste.
Besides, nobody's ever
going to see them.
Time for you to settle down now.
Night, dear. Night, darling.
-Patti's going to sit with you.
-Well, good night, girls. l mean, boys.
Night.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SPEAKlNG lN SPANlSH]
The blanket belongs to the horse.
[KNOCKlNG]
Now, you boys stop it.
Remember what Mama said.
Hi, Patti. Look, cut myself.
-Doing what;
-Shaving, of course.
Oh.
How about changing your mind
and coming to the dance with me;
-Billy, l already--
-But l got long pants.
l borrowed them from Adolph Glick,
the undertaker's son.
His father's got all sizes.
Please, Patti. Be a sport.
Very well then, Billy.
But only under one condition.
That you promise to dance
every dance with me.
Gee, Patti,
l didn't know you felt that way.
My feeling for you is purely
maternal, Billy. lt's just that....
Well, for certain reasons, l can't
let anyone else put his arms around me.
Well, that's jake with me.
You get dressed
and l'll go pick up the pants.
-Well, where are they;
-Down the old Moravian cemetery...
...behind Ezekial,
beloved husband of Arabella.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYlNG]
PATTl:
Billy.
Well, it's about time. What kept you;
lt's these pants.
l think they're made for bigger remains.
-Well, let me see.
-Well, l dassn't.
-Billy!
-Well, l told you.
Well, don't just stand there. Pull them up.
l think l need suspenders.
Don't you know anything
about men's pants;
My father has some.
Wait for me, l'll be right back.
DEMl:
Well, Valerie, l should imagine...
...you'd find the theatrical profession
quite fascinating.
Of course a career
is all very well and good...
...but what a woman really longs for
is a home and babies.
Don't you just adore babies;
Well, l don't know, l never had any.
VALERlE: Well, l was talking to my mother
only yesterday...
...and l told her
that if the right man came along...
...l'd give up my career in an instant.
Oh, l'd be very sure it was the right man
before l made such an important decision.
Oh, but l am sure.
Well, what l mean is when it's
the right thing, you know it at once.
Love is like that, Demi, darling.
DEMl:
Yes, l guess it is. Ahem.
Shall we dance;
[SONG ENDS]
[CROWD APPLAUDlNG]
-Billy! What are you doing in those pants;
-Looking for suspenders.
You deliberately disobeyed me.
Take them off. l'll see you in your room.
Father, be reasonable. Patti's waiting.
Get out of those pants.
[BOTH GASP]
Billy, how dare you;
You ought to be ashamed.
What for; His legs are beautiful.
[ORCHESTRA PLAYlNG]
[CROWD CHATTERlNG]
What a perfect couple.
Wouldn't they have beautiful children ;
That depends upon whom they marry.
Gee, it's sure a scorcher.
Maybe if you didn't wear celluloid,
you know.
See any nice stray skirts around;
l'd like a turkey trot,
but they all got gobblers. Ha, ha, ha!
You have my deepest sympathy.
Patti.
l find you in the strangest places.
Now, what are you doing under this canoe;
-Waiting for suspenders.
-Su-- You wear suspenders;
Oh, no. Not me.
My friend.
You know,
l've never met anyone quite like you.
-You're an amazing young woman.
-Woman ;
An amazing young lady, then,
if you object to being called a woman.
Oh, no. No, l don't.
Um, may l have this dance;
Oh, no. No, l've got to go home.
But you said
you were waiting for your friend.
Well, he wouldn't like it.
He's very possessive.
So am l.
Oh. Please don't hold me close.
l'm subject to fainting spells.
Oh ; Very well. Arm's length.
[PATTl HUMMlNG]
Do you hesitate;
Well, l try not to.
No, l mean in the waltz. The dip step.
Oh, yes, l can be very dippy.
[SONG ENDS]
[CROWD APPLAUDlNG]
You're not having
one of your fainting spells, are you;
Oh, Patti.
The dance is supposed to end that way.
Didn't you know;
Ladies and gentlemen,
form your circles for the polka.
lt's all right, Patti.
This dance ends quite differently.
lmagine coming to a dance half-dressed.
Gee, who;
No fooling;
Ain't cut your pinfeathers yet, eh ;
[LAUGHS]
l always knew l hated you, Eddie Gavin,
and now l know why.
Why don't you go back to your dolls;
Does your mother know you're out,
little girl;
No one asked you to dance with me.
Aw, don't be a crybaby.
-Why, look, there's Patti.
-What;
Well, what did l tell you;
She's having a wonderful time.
-But does she have to wear them;
-Certainly.
A man your age ought to know better.
Everybody's accusing you
of robbing the cradle.
Oh, hello, dear. Have some punch.
That's the....
Why, Patti, what's the matter;
Oh, Papa....
[SOBS]
Here.
Golly, what happened;
PATTl:
l wanna die.
Gee, what did Billy do;
lt's all his fault.
He should've worn suspenders.
[KNOCKlNG ON DOOR]
Patti!
Patti, dear, no, no, no. What happened;
She wants to die.
No. Now, there, there. Don't cry so hard.
Oh, Papa, l wanna go home.
My reputation in the Catskills is ruined.
Yes. Now, well, Papa's here now.
You tell Papa all about it.
-Well....
-What happened;
First he lost his pants.
-Who;
-Billy.
Then he kissed me.
Billy;
Then he put his arms around me.
-Who;
-Demi Armendez.
What; That rounder again ;
Then the most awful thing happened.
Oh, Papa, l'm so ashamed.
What did that man do;
lt wasn't what l wanted.
lt's what you and Mama wanted.
l'm the only girl almost 1 8 who doesn't--
Doesn't what;
Who doesn't own a pair of corsets.
l warned her to be careful.
So that's all.
All;
Papa, l won't be laughed at. l won't.
l can never show my face
among decent people again.
Well, now, honey,
it's a very pretty little face.
Everybody knows my secret.
l'm a marked woman now.
[KNOCKlNG ON DOOR]
Oh, there's your mama. Come in, Katie.
You! What are you doing here;
l'm terribly sorry about what happened.
ls there anything l can do;
HORATlO:
You've done enough.
l demand to know what your
intentions are toward my daughter.
lntentions; l have no intentions,
Mr. Robinson.
She's just a child.
Child; Oh, no!
Here we go again.
l never wanna see him again.
-There, you hear that; Now go away.
-The shouting, you'll have to stop.
l pay my board.
l'll shout whenever l want to.
FlNLAY: But l can't have you
disturbing the guests at this hour.
-After all, they pay their rent too.
-Libertine!
FlNLAY: Your screaming and shouting
is keeping them awake.
Please have consideration for them.
lf you were a man,
you'd meet me on the lawn.
lf you were a man, l would.
-This is a family hotel.
-This is a family matter.
l'll trouble you
to keep your nose out of it.
-Katie.
-Papa, what happened;
-Why did you leave the dance;
-l wanna talk to you.
Alone!
What is it; Where's my little girl;
You're always trying to keep her a little girl.
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
The mess you got
my daughter into.
l--; Just a minute, Horatio.
Let's start at the beginning.
All right. First he lost his pants.
-Who;
-Billy.
-Then he kissed her.
-Billy;
-No. Then he put his arm around her.
-Who;
That Cuban fella.
-And that isn't all.
-Oh, no. My poor baby.
lsn't a baby anymore.
Everybody's laughing...
...because you won't let her
wear one of those figure-pinchers.
-Oh, that's ridiculous.
-l won't have my daughter a laughingstock.
lt's time l took charge
of the welfare of this family.
My girls are dressed like babies.
My boys are dressed like girls.
l don't think you know anything
about bringing up my children.
-Oh, you don't;
-No.
l suppose that little redhead
could've done better.
-What little redhead;
-So there was more than one.
-Now, wait a minute. You're being foolish.
-lt came out finally, didn't it;
All these years you've been pretending
there was no one else.
No, no, Katie,
there was never anybody but you.
l was second choice. You only married me
because Beulah wouldn't have you.
Now, Katie, l made all that up.
l was sitting there.
l winked at you. You saw me.
For a girl who doesn't exist,
you described her perfectly.
Well, she doesn't exist.
-l know who it was too.
-Who;
That little barmaid who used to work
Schultz's beer garden.
Schultz's beer garden ;
Katie, you're out of your mind.
First l'm not a fit mother,
now l'm out of my mind.
l didn't say you were out of your--
-l refuse to stay and be insulted further.
-Well, where are you going;
l'll undress in the bathroom.
You can't. This isn't our night.
[PATTl GRO ANS]
[PATTl SOBBlNG]
For gosh sake, Patti, stop blubbering
and let's get some sleep.
PATTl:
l'll never sleep again. Never.
You're gonna be awful tired
by the time you're 30.
Oh, Patti dear, don't cry so.
No man is worth it.
You don't understand.
My reputation's ruined.
Oh, it isn't as bad as you think.
Nothing is so terrible
it can't be lived down and forgotten.
Mama, l wanna go home.
Now, running away
never solved anything.
These things seem so tragic at your age.
But in a few years, you'll look back
and laugh at the whole thing.
Laugh ; How can a mother say
such a thing to her daughter;
Oh, believe me, darling,
when l was 1 7, l felt just the same way.
Only with me, it was bustles.
l thought l couldn't live without one,
but l did.
But that's different. Bustles were silly.
Now, that's only in the point of view.
Ten years from now,
you'll probably think corsets were silly.
How am l gonna get through
those 1 0 years;
With you sniffling and Mom lecturing,
how am l gonna get through the night;
RlCKY:
Ah!
[CRO AKlNG]
[FlRECRACKERS POPPlNG]
[BO YS CHEERlNG]
Help! Help! Let's go!
Where--; Where is somebody;
[FlRECRACKERS BOOMlNG]
Help!
There you are.
Well, it's been a grand and glorious 3rd.
BlLLY:
Hello, Patti. Feeling better;
PATTl: l haven't been sick.
l do wish you'd stop following me.
BlLLY:
l'm not. l'm following the hedge.
Patti, it's not healthy
for you to be a hermit.
You ought to get out more
among your friends.
-l have no friends.
-You have me.
l know what you're going through, Patti.
We're in the same boat.
With me it's knickers and with you it's--
Some parents ought to be locked up.
lt's not only that, Billy.
The other night, my parents
had their first quarrel and it was over me.
Why, they're not even sleeping
in the same room.
Yeah, l guess one room is kind of small
when two people aren't speaking.
You know;
When l served dinner last night,
your mother asked me...
...to ask your father
to ask your brother to pass the gravy.
lt's all because
Mama won't let me grow up.
She won't let the way l look outside
catch up with the way l feel inside.
Parents know so little about us.
What we think, how we feel, our problems.
They know nothing about our world.
They don't seem to want to.
They've forgotten they were ever in it.
Whether we're happy or not
doesn't seem to matter.
PATTl: As long as we do
what they think we should do.
Somebody our age ought to tell
people their age about people our age.
l know it.
Patti, help me out tonight at the show.
Do our old number with me.
Gosh, Billy.
l'd like to, but l'm never going to
appear in public again until l own--
Golly, l wish l had the money
to buy you a pair of--
Billy....
That's a very nice thought, though.
Thank you.
[HORATlO GRUNTS]
lt's Papa!
-Did you hurt yourself, Papa;
-Of course l hurt myself.
Children, l wanna ask you something.
-We didn't do it, Papa.
-Didn't do what;
-Whatever it was.
Children...
...are you happy;
Am l a good father
or do you think l should be locked up ;
Let me into your world.
Let me do something for you.
ls there anything you need;
l need some worms to go fishing.
Worms; Oh, yes. Here's a dime.
Buy yourself a shovel.
-l'd like a white rabbit.
-You shall have two white rabbits.
No, wait a minute. On a second thought,
perhaps one would be better.
Melba, is there anything
l can get for you;
No, Papa.
What l want, l think l can get for myself.
-Gee, he must have fallen on his head.
-Yeah.
[CHORUS SlNGlNG]
[SlNGlNG]
I have a true and noble lover
He is my sweetheart all my own
His like on earth who shall discover
His heart is mine
And mine alone
We pledged our troth each to the other
And for our happiness I pray
Our lives belong to one another
Oh, happy, happy wedding day
Come, come, I love you only
My heart is true
Come, come, my life is lonely
I long for you
Come, come, naught can efface you
My arms are aching now to embrace you
Thou art divine
Come, come
I love you only
Come
Hero mine
Come, hero mine
CHORUS [SlNGlNG] :
Come, come, naught can efface you
My arms are aching now to embrace you
Thou art divine
-Come, come
-I love you only
-Come, hero
-Sweetheart
-Mine
[KNOCKlNG ON DOOR]
-Melba;
HORATlO: No, darling, it's Papa.
Well, darling, have you changed your mind
about going to the show tonight;
How can l in my condition ;
l don't know. l'd like to see you go.
Oh, l can't. Nothing can induce me.
Nothing;
Well, perhaps one thing,
but that's impossible.
My dear child,
with Papa, nothing is impossible.
You lace them up on a bedpost,
you know.
Oh, and you know that black dress
of your mama's;
Now, you get Miss Zilly
to fix that up to fit you.
Oh, Papa. Oh, Papa.
You're the most wonderful papa
in the world.
-Thanks, dear.
-Oh, golly.
[SlNGlNG] Young Johnny Jones
He had a cute little boat
Bet your life
And all the girlies
He would take for a float
Uh-huh
He had girlies on the shore
Sweet little peaches by the score
Ho, ho, ho, ho
But Johnny was a wisenheimer, you know
-Why, his steady girl was Flo
-That's me
And every Sunday afternoon
She'd jump in his boat and they'd spoon
And then he'd row, row, row
Way up the river
He would row, row, row
A hug he'd give her
Then held kiss her now and then
She would tell him when
He'd fool around and fool around
And then they'd kiss again
And then he'd row, row, row
A little further
He would row
Oh, how he'd row
-Then he'd drop both his oars
-Take a few more encores
And then he'd row, row, row
Then he'd drop both his oars
Take a few more encores
And then he'd row, row, row
Oh, honey, you were wonderful.
-l got three bows.
-l know you did.
lf l'd known you were here,
l would've done the number with you.
Oh, well, thanks, Billy,
but Mr. Finlay asked me to sing.
All right, Eddie. You're on.
Well, if you'll excuse me,
l guess l'll go get dressed.
Mr. Finlay.
What's Patti doing backstage;
FlNLAY: l'm putting her on for a song
after Jane Schimpf's birdcalls.
VALERlE: l won't have it. Everything goes
wrong when that troublemaker's around.
You know, l have my professional
reputation to think about.
As the star of this show...
-...l will not appear on the same bill.
FlNLAY: l just asked her to fill a spot.
VALERlE: This theater is not big enough
for the two of us.
Now, which one of us goes;
l guess that's me.
FlNLAY: Oh, Miss Robinson, l--
-lt's all right, Mr. Finlay.
l'll go. Thank you for being so kind.
Mr. Finlay,
it's not my artistic temperament.
lt's just that Patti's
a plain, old-fashioned jinx.
[AUDlENCE LAUGHlNG]
Mother; Mr. Finlay!
-What is it; What happened;
-My dancing shoes, they're gone.
-Hurry up. You follow Eddie Gavin.
-l'm not a barefoot dancer.
-Someone's taken my darling's shoes.
-Where are your street shoes;
l didn't bring any,
and l can't do this in bedroom slippers.
Some miserable sneak stole my shoes.
Now, who wa--;
Billy Finlay.
-Who, me;
-Yes, you. You did it for Patti.
My son is an honest boy.
Why, he wouldn't think of--
Where are they;
Oh, Billy Finlay.
How dare you!
-l wear a size 4 triple-A.
-Yes.
-Well, they were here a minute ago.
-l refuse to submit to these indignities.
l won't go on.
l won't go on and that's final.
You can give the people
all their money back.
Come, Mother.
l've had enough of amateur theatricals.
Who wants their money back;
Anybody can do her number.
My sister, for instance.
-Yeah, but she doesn't know it.
-l beg to differ.
She peeked in the window
all during rehearsals.
She did; Well, where is she;
l don't know.
You might try the drugstore.
Here we are.
Here's a nice strawberry soda.
l guess there's nothing left for me to do
but become a missionary.
Well, you wouldn't wanna do that
on an empty stomach.
Try this.
Oh, good evening, Mrs. Penford.
-Hello, Billy.
-Patti, the show's in trouble.
My father wants you to take
Valerie's place. She walked out.
She did;
How would l know her number;
Well, you peeked in the window
during rehearsals.
Oh.
No, Billy. lt's out of the question.
lf you don't,
we'll have to give the money back.
lt was supposed to go to the
Preservation of Wildlife in the Catskills.
lt was;
Think of all those poor little beavers
and possums, skunks and....
You're right, Billy.
l mustn't let personal feelings stand
in the way of our four-footed friends.
-Come on.
-Gee, l hope l peeked enough.
-You did.
PATTl: Thanks for the soda.
There goes one
of my satisfied customers.
Only this afternoon, her father
bought her one of these corsets. Oh.
She's undoubtedly suffering
from curvature of the spine.
WOMAN: Oh.
-The corset will correct it.
But you mustn't bend over in them
or they lock.
-Like so:
-Really;
DEMl:
Patti, are you ready;
You are going to dance with me,
aren't you;
Please, l need you.
Oh, Patti, can't you ever forgive me
for what l did;
Whatever it was.
lf you don't,
l'll drown myself in the lake.
Oh, Patti.
FlNLAY:
Senor Armendez, Miss Robinson, you're on.
So that's where they went.
What are you doing after the show;
Why, there's Patti.
And that's my best dress.
Tell Mama it was.
-lt was.
-You can straighten up now, Patti.
-l can't.
You can't.
What; You can't;
Smile, Patti. Smile.
Smile, smile.
Oh, she's laced them up too tight.
What she got, lockjaw;
-Stand back. Give her air, will you;
-What is it;
Frozen muscles. Very interesting.
-lt's that straitjacket.
-What have you done to my child;
-Your child is no longer a child.
-l'll take charge of this.
-Carry her to the dressing room.
-Here, give her to me.
lmagine, one kiss
causing such complete paralysis.
Mind your own business.
You buy that man some pants.
Just set her down here
on the couch, please.
On my side, please.
Thank you. Now everyone out.
-Yes, everybody out. Everybody.
-You too, Papa.
Me too; Okay, all right.
-Hurry, Mama.
-Oh, Patti, honey.
Darling, a surgical corset!
Your father ought to have
his head examined.
-There.
-Oh!
Oh, Mama, how would he know;
ln other words,
l should have picked it out.
You're a woman, Mother.
KATHERlNE:
And so are you, my baby.
Tomorrow we'll get you
a La Belle Mode corset.
We will;
Unless you'd rather have
a whalebone wasp waist.
-Oh, Mother.
-But as for my new dress....
Oh, l didn't hurt it, honest.
You wear it much better than l ever did.
l think you better keep it.
Besides, don't tell Papa,
but l can't get into it anymore.
Oh, Mama.
l'd like permission to call on your daughter
when we get back to the city.
What for;
-Well, to get to know her better.
-Seems to me you know her well enough.
All this kissing, bending.
lt is customary in my country
to ask permission to call...
...when a man's intentions are serious.
You may call, Demi.
We'll be very happy to see you.
-Look, this man's trying--
-l know.
-But this is my daughter.
-Papa.
Don't you think it's about time
you two stopped acting like children ;
Why, the way you're behaving,
the kids aren't getting any sleep.
KATHERlNE:
Patti.
Oh, Mama.
Well, look at that.
l walked the floor with her...
...brought her through sickness,
helped her with her homework...
...and worried and worried
about her happiness.
And now what do l do;
l walk into a church,
and when the preacher asks:
''Who gives this woman to this man ;''
l stand up like a fool and say, ''l do.''
Papa, my father was no fool.
SubRip - diamarg