(THUNDER CRASHING)
BINDER: Please.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
If he makes it
to the river, he's won.
We cannot allow that
to happen, Mr. Lopaki.
(GROANS)
You're firing too close!
(GRUNTING)
(FINGERNAILS SCRAPING)
Brandy?
It's like a drug, isn't it?
To bring a man down.
Was it worth it?
Every nickel.
Good.
(RINGING)
Yes?
(STAMMERING) Hi, I'm looking
for Douglas Binder.
You a friend
of Mr. Binder's?
No, I...
I'm his daughter.
MARIE: Doug was a nice man.
He had manners.
He didn't tell you where
he was moving, did he?
He owed some rent, honey.
I told him he could wait to pay
me till he got back on his feet.
He wasn't in
an accident, was he?
Oh no, he lost his job
with the oil tool company.
When Doug moved out,
he left this box.
He told me I could hold it till
he could make up his back rent.
Do you have any idea
where he might be now?
You might try checking down
in Our Lady of Charity.
ELIJAH: Marine, huh?
Recon.
I was in the service
for a while myself.
Really?
Yeah.
Do you know him?
He comes here sometimes.
Nice guy, too.
If I see him, I'll tell
him you're looking.
Do you happen to know
where he lives?
(STAMMERING)
I'm afraid your daddy...
Well, he was like the
rest of us, out of doors.
You know?
WAITRESS:
How is that gumbo, Chance?
A tragedy.
The coffee was
tolerable, though.
It ain't free, neither.
Yeah, I know.
Leave your wallet
in your tuxedo?
I play that one on you before?
Yeah. For the gumbo.
That's right.
NATASHA: Hi.
Do you have any change?
Thank you.
NATASHA: Hi, Marie.
Yes, I was wondering if my father
came to pick up his mail yet.
He hasn't? No, that's fine.
Thank you. Bye-bye.
Hello, pretty lady.
Leave me the hell alone.
We'll take the wallet.
How about a little
extra, honey?
(GROANS)
CHANCE: You having fun?
MAN: Why don't you do
yourself a favor, boy?
I think the favor
is gonna be done for you.
(WHIMPERING)
It's okay.
I said, get lost!
Now, take your pig stick
and your boyfriend
and find a bus to catch.
Oh, this guy's funny.
(MEN CHUCKLING)
Come on. Let's go!
MAN: Let's go!
Come on!
(CRACKING)
(SCREAMING)
You know, it's a shame. This used
to be such a nice part of town.
Next time be more careful
when you show your wallet.
(STRIKERS CHANTING)
Without cops, the city stops!
MAN: Come on, let's hurry now!
Come on.
Will the strike end soon?
Here you go.
(STRIKERS CHANTING)
Happy birthday to me.
Excuse me.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I need to fill out
a missing person report.
Look, I just pulled
a double shift.
Why don't you
catch me tomorrow.
Okay. Why don't
you catch me now.
What is the name
of the missing individual?
Douglas Charles Binder.
Relationship
of reporting party?
Daughter.
Okay. You got a picture?
Mmm-hmm.
Got something
a little more recent?
No, I don't.
See, my parents were
divorced 20 years ago.
You got an address?
I think my father was homeless.
I didn't even know myself
until I just came down here.
Look, I'm not sure what
you want me to do here.
I want you to take my report.
Well, generally, in order
to be considered missing,
you need somewhere
to be missing from.
Fine.
Look, if you're too busy
to do your job, Detective,
then I'll find somebody
who isn't so busy.
Look“.
You want to find your father, take
my advice, canvass the missions,
ask at the shelters,
but get somebody who knows
the city to show you around,
or I'll be filling out
one of these on you.
Hey, you're welcome.
All right, pipe down
and listen up.
We got 12 positions this
morning, Able Seaman or better.
When I call your name, come into
the office, show your papers,
and you'll get your ship.
Here we go. First man,
Gombas, Luigi. Able Seaman.
Right here.
Walker, Steven.
Second Engineer.
Hi.
They told me at the cafe
that you might be down here.
I need to talk to you
about something.
I don't think this
is a good time now.
Walters, Nichols D. Able Seaman.
Yeah.
How'd you like to work for me?
I'll pay you $100 a day.
For doing what?
For$100, does it really matter?
Actually, it does. Yeah.
It does.
Look, I really need you
to help me find someone.
Gill, Bill. Cook.
You know this city, you obviously
can take care of yourself.
Boudreaux, C.
Able Seaman.
I would like
to help you, darling.
Looks like I'm gonna
be out of town.
Way out of town.
Sorry.
Chance. Thought you got blackballed
about that thing with Captain McDonald.
That was a big
misunderstanding, you know.
(CHUCKUNG) Right.
Broke his damn jaw
is what I heard.
You make sure
I said a big "hello."
Wait a minute.
Johnson says I was reinstated.
With the company.
Not with the union.
You owe some dues here, boy.
217 bucks.
I'll pay that off
on this cruise.
No. Nobody ships out if they're
in arrears, you know that.
How am I gonna pay my dues
if I can't get the job?
I don't make the rules, mate.
Look, your ride doesn't sail
till the end of the week.
If I can get the money,
then what?
Then I'll let you ship out.
I'll get the money.
MAN: Keep going.
Take it back.
Yeah, bring it.
Bring it, bring it,
bring it. Okay, down.
So, this guy you're looking for,
he owes you money or something?
He's my father.
Okay, I changed my mind.
I'll help you for two days,
you'll pay me $217.
It's a deal.
You can drive.
I don't have
a driver's license, ma'am.
NATASHA:
So, what's your name?
Chance Boudreaux.
What's your name?
It's Nat.
Nat?
Your parents name you
for a bug?
No, actually,
it's short for Natasha.
Natasha.
What kind of a name is Chance?
Well, my mama took one.
So, how did you lose your papa?
My parents, they got divorced
when I was seven and my father...
Well, he moved away.
NATASHA: We started to write and he
even called me a couple of times.
Three weeks ago
the letters just stopped.
CHANCE: I've got a friend
here who can help us.
You check the line,
I'll look around inside.
Hey, you don't have a bottle
of hot sauce on ya, do ya?
Elijah. What's happening?
Wednesday meat loaf.
I mean, they said
it was meat loaf.
I thought you were
gonna get a ship.
I lost my boarding pass.
I've got something to show you.
You two know each other?
We met yesterday.
Have you seen my father?
I saw the next best thing.
I was at Plaza D'ltalia yesterday, and
I saw this sleeping bag in a cart.
It was a tiger stripe, like the kind
they used to issue to recon guys.
Your daddy had one
just like it.
Thanks, Charlie.
You bet.
Don't be offended.
He passed them out for money.
Yeah, I've had to do it myself.
Here. Barracks Street.
Both sides this time,
Grandpa. Next! Get!
Here. Decatur.
Lower half.
Well, if it ain't
my good friend Boudreaux.
I thought you was
gonna catch a ship.
Maybe I'll stick around
to run for mayor.
We're looking for someone
who worked for you.
The man's name
is Douglas Binder.
I never heard of him.
I think he knew you.
Did he work for you, sir?
Maybe he did, maybe he didn't.
I'm not too good with names.
NATASHA: I have a photograph.
What Mr. Poe is trying to say is
he's not too good with faces.
Right?
VAN CLEAF: Hello, Randal.
I didn't know you had company.
We were just leaving.
NATASHA: You know,
we should go back up there.
CHANCE: Not now.
Not together.
Poe knows something about
my father, obviously.
Look, if you don't want to go back
up there, I'll just go back myself.
Hey. If you want to find your daddy,
you're gonna have to work smarter,
not harder.
Yeah.
Natasha Binder?
What's the problem?
Miss Binder, I'm afraid
I have some bad news.
They found your father's body.
I'm sorry.
They made a positive I.D.
How did it happen?
There was a fire last night in an
abandoned building in the Ninth Ward.
The fire department discovered your
father's body in one of the rooms.
I need to see him.
Your daddy was burned
pretty badly.
The identificatian
had to be made from
dental charts in your
father's service record.
What's your involvement here?
I was helping her
find her daddy.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SNORING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SCREAMS)
Wakey, wakey, you fat fuck!
(GROANS)
(EXCLAIMING)
Oh, God! Mr. Fouchon,
what are you doing here?
Don't talk, Randal. Listen.
Don't worry about Randal.
(RANDAL EXCLAIMS)
He's all ears.
When Mr. Van Cleaf came upon
your visitors yesterday,
you neglected to tell him that they were
inquiring about one of our volunteers.
That was nothing,
Mr. Fouchon.
Oh, it was something, Randal.
(SCREAMING)
This man we hunted last night.
Why don't you tell us
his real name?
You fuck.
Binder. Binder.
Douglas Binder.
That is not the one
we selected, is it?
I couldn't get the guy
you asked for.
Look, you said you wanted a combat
veteran, so I sent you Binder.
He has more medals.
He had a family.
Now they're asking questions.
Please. Please. I said I was sorry.
I said...
I said I was sorry.
Careless is what
you are, Randal.
Careless and stupid,
and now you're sorry, too.
He said he was alone.
I didn't know he had
any relatives, honest.
You made a mistake?
Is that what you're saying?
Yeah.
And I see you're anxious
to make up for it, aren't you?
Right. Yes, sir.
We've got another client and he's
about to select a new playmate.
(GROANS)
Next time, send us
the one we ask for.
RANDAL: I will,
Mr. Fouchon, I swear.
I think we understand
each other.
Yes? No?
Yes.
Yeah.
Randal.
I come back here,
I cut me a steak.
You did your best.
No, I came too late.
I mean, Jesus, he was living
out of a shopping cart.
God damn it. Why didn't
he just tell me?
Why didn't he ask for my help?
I've been there myself
on the street.
It's hard.
It's hard to put your hand out.
I just kept thinking if I could
just tell him that I loved him.
And because
he loved you so much,
he didn't want
to pull you into it.
Our friend, Mr. Boudreaux.
Silver Star.
Marine Force Recon.
VAN CLEAF: He joined the Merchant
Service after he got out.
His captain
was smuggling opium.
When Boudreaux found out,
he threw the man overboard.
He's been looking
for work ever since.
He's obviously not someone
we should underestimate.
He was raised in the
bayous by his uncle.
I think Mr. Boudreaux would
make a very interesting quarry.
Maybe I should pay him a visit.
No, no, no, no.
Send a couple of lads down there to
have a chat with him, would you?
Yeah.
Bingo.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
Some friendly advice, Boudreaux.
Get the fuck outta Dodge!
Do it today! And tell that
bitch girlfriend of yours
to point her titties north
and step on the gas!
(GROANING)
It's always nice to see you.
You seem to have a real talent,
Mr. Boudreaux, for attracting violence.
Does that make me a bad person?
What did you arrest me for? Getting
beat up without a license?
Thank you for calling me.
Oh, my God, you look awful.
Darling, you hurt my feelings.
What we have here
is a charge sheet.
Willfully crossing a police barrier,
that's considered criminal trespass.
Yes, that officer was nice
enough to mention that to me.
What were you
doing at the house?
The dog tag
you find in that fire?
They always come in twos.
So I went back to that place
to look for the other one.
Your daddy,
he didn't die in the fire.
He was murdered.
There's no evidence of that.
There is now.
That hole in that tag was made
by something sharp and hard.
And I'll bet my rent money it was made
when Binder was still wearing it.
Now, why would somebody go through all
this trouble to kill a homeless man?
Do you believe us now?
Look, honey, the wheels
turn slow around here.
Real slow.
But they do turn.
I'll order a new autopsy.
This'll help.
You should see a doctor.
I hate them doctors.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC
BEING PLAYED ON PIANO)
(PHONE RINGING)
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
Shit!
What?
Not now.
So, you in Nam?
Yeah, a long time ago.
It seems to me a man with
your obvious experience
should be pulling down
a lot more money.
You're gonna pay me 100 bucks
to fill out a form?
I'll pay you a lot more than
that if you got the experience.
What kind of experience?
Well, maybe you
ain't interested.
No.
I'll fill out the application.
You got any family? Anybody
to worry about you?
Friends?
Anything like that?
No, I got nobody.
You'll deposit $500,000 in our account
in a bank in the Cayman Islands.
Do not refer to our agreement by telex
or in conversations on the phone.
You'll be provided
with a guide, trackers
and the weapon of your choice.
Naturally, we'll dispose
of the body
and provide you with an
out-of-town, air-tight alibi.
Don't worry, Mr. Zenan, all you
have to do is point and shoot.
(APPLAUDING)
VAN CLEAF: Mr. Zenan
has made his selection.
A black man named Roper.
Used to be in Special Forces.
Excellent
I don't see any problem
with your choice.
It has always been the privilege
of the few to hunt the many.
Soldiers, policemen,
fighter pilots.
Men who kill for the government
do so with impunity.
Now all we do is offer
the same opportunity
for private citizens
such as yourself.
These opponents,
they're volunteers?
More or less.
The same government that's made
murder their sole preserve,
they train our targets.
We pride ourselves on only
hunting combat veterans,
men who have
the necessary skills
to make our hunts more interesting.
What about the police?
I'm sure that they would be
interested if they were to find out.
Dr. Morton here assists us with the
formality of police autopsies.
It's no accident
that we're in New Orleans.
Last year we conducted hunts
in Rio de Janeiro at Carnival,
Yugoslavia during the late
unpleasantness. Oh, yeah.
You see, there's always some unhappy
little corner of the planet
where we can ply our trade.
All right,
Mr. Fouchon.
You have a client.
Well, thank you
for visiting, Mr. Zenan.
Dr. Morton will
show you to the car.
My bank will arrange the transfer
of funds within the hour.
Excellent
When do we go out?
We'll contact you when the necessary
arrangements have been made.
Chance.
What you doing here?
Secret mission.
Mmm.
Rub me, baby. Come on.
Oh, yeah, baby.
Hello, Poe.
What the fuck?
(GROANS)
You miss me?
Christ, not again.
Looks like you're short an ear, so
you better listen very carefully.
Now, are you paying attention?
(GROANING)
Who sent those apes after me?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
(GROANING)
Two million people
in this city.
Who's gonna miss a fat slob
like you, Poe? Van Cleaf!
His name was Van Cleaf.
Good boy. Where is he?
I don't know where he lives!
He ain't even American!
Look, he'll kill me
if I don't do what he says!
Please, you gotta believe that!
Tell your boyfriend, Van Cleaf,
I'm gonna find out
who killed Douglas Binder.
If you understand me,
just grunt.
(GRUNTS)
Again.
Did you get my memo?
Binder, Douglas C.
I want you to take another
look at the post-mortem.
That memo contains evidence that might
make Binder's death a homicide.
Now, you can act on it,
Doctor, or you can file it,
but if I have to get a court
order for a formal inquest,
I will.
(COUGHING)
You should do something
about that cough.
Don't you ever knock?
We have a problem.
A big problem.
They want me to redo
the autopsy on Binder.
Who is it that's asking?
A detective named Mitchell.
Binder's family's
breathing down her neck.
Can we buy her?
No.
I guess we've overstayed
our welcome.
Tonight is our last hunt
in New Orleans.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Open it.
(GUN FIRES)
What a funny little man.
A change of scenery's what we need.
Something less tropical.
Rolling hills, castles.
Eastern Europe. We can
work there for years.
Where's Poe?
Mr. Poe couldn't make it.
He's got an ear infection.
Look, he said he'd have
some work for me.
That may still
be a possibility.
We got a little game we'd
like you to play with us.
This money belt
has $10,000 in it.
It's all yours if you
want it, every penny.
What do I have to do?
The rules of the game
are very simple.
All you have to do is get to the river.
Ten miles through the city.
You and the money belt make it to
the river, you're $10,000 richer.
Bullshit.
Maybe you like being
the object of pity,
begging for quarters,
sleeping in the rain,
listening to half an hour of fire
and brimstone for a bowl of soup.
Man, fuck you.
You could change
everything tonight.
Think of what $10,000
could buy you.
You could get new clothes,
clean yourself up,
look men in the eyes when you
pass them on the street.
This money could make you a man again,
instead of the shadow of your former self.
I get to the river,
I get the cash.
Every nickel.
And if I don't make it?
You're a sports fan, Roper.
Figure it out.
You've got a five minute head start.
Don't waste it.
This is New Orleans,
Mr. Zenan, not Beirut.
(PANTING)
After you, sir.
Mr. Zenan,
take it off "safe."
(PANTING)
(AUTOMATIC GUNFIRE)
(GROANING)
Finish him.
I don't want him.
He's wounded.
Finish him.
I can't do that. I hit him.
I shot him.
Let go. Hey!
Listen, don't make me look bad
in front of my dogs.
You know why you're here?
You paid us half a million dollars
to find out if you're alive or dead.
Now finish him.
Finish him!
God, why didn't he go fishing?
(GROANS)
(GROANING)
Now you understand why we
insist on payment up front.
Here.
Set the dogs on him,
won't you, Pik?
I don't wanna
be out here all night.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Help me! Please!
(MOANING)
Help me!
Please! Help me!
MAN: Go on, get a job!
Please!
Please! Watch it! Damn!
Watch yourself.
Help me. Help me!
Help me. Please.
ELIJAH: Hey, look!
Come on, man!
Hey, just call the police
here or something!
Help me!
Come on. Let me in!
No, we're closed!
Let me in!
Hey, buddy! Come on!
Brother, get out of here. Come on, get out.
Help me, man!
Help me! I ain't got
no change, man!
(GUN FIRING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
He was passing out flyers
for Randal Poe.
Let's pay him a visit.
Randal, Randal, Randal.
You were gonna leave
without saying goodbye?
My mama got sick in Biloxi.
I was gonna call you,
Mr. Van Cleaf.
Of course you were, Randal.
Of course you were.
I know you didn't mean
to hurt my feelings.
Hmm?
(SOBBING)
(WHINES)
(EXCLAIMS)
(CHUCKUNG)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Looks like we missed the party.
Get down!
(GUNS FIRING)
(GROANS)
Stay down!
(GROANING)
Go, go, go!
(GROANS)
(CRACKING)
(CRYING)
Let's go. We can't
just leave her here!
FOUCHON: Keep him in the Quarter.
Stay on his ass.
She's dead. Come on.
Grab the bar!
(GRUNTS)
Yeah!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Ladies first.
What?
(NATASHA EXCLAIMING)
it appears we'll have one
last hunt after all, Pik.
The train went by maybe two,
two and a half hours ago.
This could be dangerous.
We're on his turf now.
Thank you, gentlemen, for making
yourselves available on such short notice.
We are stalking
an exceptional opponent.
Truly a world-class trophy.
The price for participating
in this little excursion
is $750,000 each.
Should one of you be lucky
enough to bring him down,
I'll consider that hunter's
account paid in full.
Shouldn't we be worried about
alligators or something?
If it makes you
feel better, yeah.
CHANCE:
Come on, keep going.
It's still a long way
to Uncle Douvee's place.
NATASHA: At least they won't
be able to find us out here.
Yes, they will, if they have a
tracker as good as Uncle Douvee.
All they have to do is to
check along the rail road.
I'm just guessing we
have a couple of hours.
Okay.
Maybe less.
Come on. Let's go.
(PANTING) Isn't there
a trail or something?
This is the trail.
You're really enjoying
yourself, aren't you, Chance?
If it's tough for us,
it's tough for them.
You trust me?
Of course I trust you.
Close your eyes.
Why do you want me to trust
you with my eyes closed?
Close your eyes.
(RATTLING)
(HISSING)
Is it dead?
Not hardly.
What are you doing?
I'm leaving a surprise
for my friends.
(SCREAMS)
(HISSING)
(SCREAMING)
Son of a bitch!
(HISSING)
(GROANING)
I'll fuck you,
then I'll eat you!
If you would die quieter
and pick up the pace,
Boudreaux would have less time
for these little surprises.
Jerome!
Would you be so kind?
And do watch your step,
won't you? Let's go.
(EXCLAIMING)
(LAUGHING)
Sometime I amaze myself, me!
Good whiskey make jack
rabbit slap the bear!
(CHANCE WHISTLING
RHYTHMICALLY)
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(CONTINUES WHISTLING)
Chance?
Yeah!
Chance!
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
You come to see
your Uncle Douvee.
(QUESTIONING IN FRENCH)
Natasha, my Uncle Douvee.
(GREETING IN FRENCH)
We'll fix him up good.
Put bandage on it, no hurt.
Be strong, my boy.
Douvee, I've got some
people after me.
I know.
I can smell them.
You've still got a .30-06, the one
I gave you for your birthday?
No. A gator ate it.
But, uh,
I've still got your shotgun.
So tell me, this man
what chase after you,
he mad at you
for business or pleasure?
Both.
Uh-huh.
I'm going to take Elvira south,
then to Bayou La Fouche,
Mardi Gras graveyard.
If you can talk her
into it, go ahead.
You be careful.
Don't worry about me.
I love the company.
Be careful. Without
you, I'm hunting them.
He's gonna be all right.
Oui. Come.
We go.
(MACHINE-GUN FIRING)
Here, drink.
But do not spill.
It kills the grass.
The place is clean.
He just left.
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(SCREAMING)
(MEN SCREAMING)
Get the fuck down!
(SHOUTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Hold it!
Boudreaux is the target
we're after.
You are a fucking buffalo!
Move!
Boudreaux went this way, maybe 10,
15 minutes ago. He's on a horse.
He's trying to lead us
away from his friends.
Get in the fucking trucks.
Move! Fucking move!
Will you move? Move!
They're fucking
brain-dead.
Get the helicopter.
Find Boudreaux.
We'll set up an ambush
this side of Bayou La Fouche.
I can take him from the air.
Any pinhead can take
him from the air.
I wanna take him
from the ground!
I can take him from the air.
Be a professional, Pik.
You're making a mistake.
Make sure he gets there, Pik.
That's him.
(GROANING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Hey, pigeon.
Avril Pybus has a store
two miles this way.
You go to a telephone,
call the sheriff.
You know, chere, I think you
should call the sheriff.
VAN CLEAF: It appears your trophy
is ripping us a new orifice.
Let me review the tactical
situation for you, gentlemen.
Boudreaux is wounded.
He's been pursued and harried
across miles of open country.
Now he's cornered
and outnumbered 20 to 1.
He's an annoying
little fucking insect,
and I want him
stepped on, hard.
You're not angry
with me, are you, Pik?
(CHUCKLES)
I don't get angry.
I'm a professional.
Let's move!
(RHYTHMIC WHISTLING)
This is not good.
If we walk away now, we can
be in Mexico in five hours.
What the fuck is the
matter with you, Pik?
Hunting drunks in
alleys made you soft?
(SHOUTING)
God, that son of a bitch
is good!
Goddamn it, I'm gonna blow
his goddamn head off!
What are you looking at,
you sons of bitches?
This is what you paid for!
Get him!
Seal off this place.
The son of a bitch is dying.
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(GROANS)
Sorry about the shirt.
Ah, give it a rest, pal.
Now what do you want to do?
Now,
now we put arrow into everyone
what's not Chance, huh?
Come.
You fucking bitch!
(GROANING)
Now, now look what you do.
Give me this gun. I take
care of all these bad guys.
Give me this gun!
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
NATASHA: Chance!
I told you to go for help.
But we help.
We're here to help.
All these men try to kill you.
Boudreaux, Boudreaux, Boudreaux.
I've been looking
all over for you.
You've been looking
in the wrong places.
That's good,
'cause I know you wouldn't
want to hurt my feelings.
(EXHALES)
(GROANS)
Can you get UP?
I cannot dance,
but I can get up.
(MOANING)
(GROANS)
(SHOUTS)
(RHYTHMIC WHISTLING)
(GRUNTS)
You lucky son of a bitch!
You want some more of that?
CHANCE: Yeah!
(ECHOING) How does it
feel to be hunted?
(GROANING)
You tell me!
CHANCE: You should
know better.
There isn't a country in the world
I haven't fired a bullet in.
(SHOUTS)
You can't kill me!
You can't kill me.
I'm on every battlefield.
There's no winner here!
I don't see one.
You're looking at him!
Come on, you son of a bitch!
Take your best shot!
Chance!
NATASHA: Chance.
Chance.
DOUVEE: My boy!
(NATASHA SC REAMS)
(GROANS)
(NATASHA CRYING)
Just shoot him!
(GROANS)
You won't do that,
will you Mr. Boudreaux?
NATASHA: Chance!
Please!
FOUCHON: If he shoots me,
he'll kill you.
He's picked the wrong
tool for the job.
Put the weapon down
or I'll run her through!
(YELPS)
You see, Miss Binder,
you I can understand,
it was a matter of family.
You had nothing in common
with those people.
What made you want to
complicate my life like this?
Poor people get bored, too.
Oh!
Come here.
No, please!
Load me.
(SHOUTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Hunting season is over.
(LAUGHS)
(EXCLAIMS)
Douvee! Douvee!
What is this noise?
I was dreaming.
Chere, I think about you.
I tell this turkey,
he no kill this eagle.
Some headache I got here.
Oh!
Ooh!
Oh, my God.
What?
I think I hurt pretty bad.
Now this,
this real catastrophe!
This real bad.
Yeah, real bad.
(LAUGHING)