[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Whoa!
BOY 1: Come on, man.
BOY 2: Got you.
EARL: Hey.
- Heh.
EARL: You want my money, you best start
throwing some elbow into that, boy.
Dollar-fifty.
That's two bits shy a car wash.
A $1.50 each.
No, ha, ha, man.
No, you must have got me confused
with some other idiot.
Hell, the rain's doing
half the work for you.
[BOYS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
[CAR APPROACHING]
WILCOX:
Well, lookie here.
- Bobby Earl, the cultured pearl.
- What's up, Gomer?
You boys wanna take a break?
Bobby Earl, we gotta talk.
[BOYS LAUGHING]
- I said quit!
- Talk about what?
Take a ride.
- A ride.
- Please?
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
Yeah, this is Wilcox. I need a tech team
down at Ferguson's place.
Do a makeover on a--
What kind of car is that anyway? Ow!
Leave him be,
you cracker son of a bitch!
- I ought to lock you up!
EARL: Grandma, go inside.
- Why can't you leave him be?
- I'm all right, Grandma.
Listen. Hey. It's all right. It's all right.
All right? I'll be back before supper.
BOY:
Grandma, why are they taking Bobby Earl?
[GRUNTING]
Now, give me that head! That's it!
Let's shake up that cage a little bit, son!
You're not getting that meat
tenderized enough?
Now, you sit down
and let's see what else we got to start with.
- Look here, Bobby Earl. Unh!
- Ugh.
- Get the fuck up.
Now, I'm gonna ask you nicely, son.
Did you fuck her before
or after you filleted her?
- Ha-ha-ha.
- Huh?
Country-ass motherfucker.
Oh, "asshole," is it? "Asshole"?
- I'll show you fucking--
- Unh!
[GRUNTING]
[DOOR OPENS]
ARMSTRONG:
"At the first official electrocution in 1890...
...the victim had the electrodes removed
from his head after 15 seconds.
Suddenly he opened his eyes
and began gasping for air...
...apparently unaware
that he was supposed to be dead.
The warden and all present
completely lost their wits...
...before calling for the current
to be turned back on.
Witnesses describe a blue flame
playing about the base of the spine.
This time the electricity flowed
for four minutes.
Over the years,
other witnesses to electrocutions...
...have described the prisoner
catching fire...
...the electricity so powerful...
...that the eyeballs pop out
onto the cheeks...
...a sound like bacon frying.
And during the autopsy, the liver is so hot
that it can't be touched by human hands.
Despite its best efforts,
this justice system has killed...
...at least 23 innocent men...
...and sentences blacks who kill whites...
...seven times more
than whites who kill blacks."
Eh, 1890...
...to the 1990s.
Over a hundred years of progress.
[ALL LAUGHING]
You paint a grim picture indeed,
professor.
I wish you had been as vivid
describing the victims.
They were people who suffered
far more cruel and unusual punishment...
...than any our penal system
could even imagine.
- No, no. I refuse to believe--
- Let me finish.
- Very well.
I submit to you, the issue is revenge.
[APPLAUSE]
An eye for an eye,
a tooth for a tooth, if you will.
No, I refuse to believe
in any god or government...
...which is willing to trade
torture for torture...
...or death for death.
In closing, professor...
...if your wife or child
were murdered...
...how do you think you'd feel
about that last statement of yours?
How would I feel? Heh.
Very much the same as yourself.
But I would not want
their deaths avenged...
...by a system as cruel
and capricious as this.
[APPLAUSE]
- Ha, ha. Well, you changed my mind.
- Well, I thought I had you.
- They're gonna kill my boy.
- Excuse me?
My grandson. They got him down south
in a Florida prison on death row...
- ...for something he didn't do.
- Paul, heh. Good luck.
I'll see you in Washington.
Look, I'm sorry. I no longer practice law.
He said to me,
"Go up to Cambridge, Massachusetts.
Find Mr. Paul Armstrong...
...and give him this."
Well, thank you. I'll, uh--
I'll read it and get back to you.
No, you read it now.
MAN:
Come on.
- Come far?
- Ochopee, Florida.
Mm. This is a long way.
"Victim was white. I am black.
Held without food or water."
Beaten?
By Mr. Tanny Brown, the black-hatingest
police in Everglade County.
Mm. "Murder one.
Death penalty."
That white judge, he was 87 years old.
He called Bobby Earl an animal,
ought to be take out and shot.
Listen, it's 25 years since I practiced law.
He said, if you turn me down...
...I was to go to Princeton, New Jersey
and find Mr. Harry Gilyard.
- He's a good man.
- But he said to come to you first.
I'm sorry, I can't.
Eh, I....
Where can I drive you?
Where are you staying?
I ain't staying nowhere.
There a 2 a.m. bus leaving for Princeton
from the Trailways station.
I can get there by myself.
Thank you for your time.
No, no, you keep it.
It's got your name on it.
ALL [CHANTING]:
Sick in bed
Momma called the doctor
And the doctor said
Ding dong
Let's get the rhythm of the head
Daddy!
GIRL:
Mr. Armstrong, Mr. Armstrong.
[ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Wonderful, wonderful.
[GIRLS CONTINUE CHATTERING]
Carry on dancing.
There you go.
Where's your mommy?
GIRLS [CHANTING]:
Sick in bed
Momma called the doctor
And the doctor said
Let's the the rhythm of the head
Ding dong
- Oh, hi.
- What happened to you?
Oh, um....
I was working in juvenile detention center
this morning with this kid, Carlos.
He was in for dealing.
Usual rap sheet:
misdemeanors, history of drug use.
- Mm-hm.
- Half-hour in, I ask about his mother.
And, bam, he goes berserk.
I'm on my back seeing stars.
Another day at the office.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, well, then an hour later,
I'm standing in front of the judge...
...trying to convince her he's perfect
for the Crossroads program instead of jail.
How did you explain the eye?
Oh, I told her my husband
was a wife beater.
Well, thank you very much.
Why don't you go back
to being a lawyer?
It is safer.
Yeah, for who? Me or the bad guys?
Can we have some more popcorn,
please.
- Yeah, Daddy will bring it out.
- Thank you.
LAURIE:
Paul, how did the debate go?
Eh, little old lady showed up tonight.
Tells me her grandson's on death row
down in Florida.
He's a black kid. Went to Cornell.
- Can I see it?
- Mm.
Back to the salt mines.
[GIRLS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
- Oh, no. Oh, no, no.
- Paul, I--
He needs a lawyer...
...not a teacher. And I need a drink.
Paul, did you really read this?
I mean, maybe this one
is worth checking out.
Why don't you check it out?
Everglade County was your neck of woods.
KATIE:
Mom, can we sleep outside tonight?
No way.
I'd sooner go to hell
than into another courtroom.
You know, I think this
would be really good for you.
Put you in the real world.
Why is every fucking thing the real world
except teaching? Hmm?
[GIRLS LAUGHING]
That's the real world?
A guy's on death row. He's asking you
to put your money where your mouth is.
Paul, all I'm saying is that...
...every once in a while
you gotta get a little bloody.
It's good for the soul.
Yeah.
PHIL: Oh, I see them.
LIBBY: There they are.
Grandma.
- Hi, Grandma.
- Ha, ha.
PHIL: Hey, Laurie.
LAURIE: Dad.
What's that on your face?
Hi, sweetness.
Welcome.
KATIE: Hi, Grandpa.
LAURIE: Mom.
It's not a bad paper as papers go...
...but of course that's not
saying a hell of a lot.
Delores, sweetheart. Ha-ha-ha.
Hey, Mr. Phil.
It's been a long time. Ha, ha.
- This is Paul Armstrong. My son-in-law.
- Delores.
Delores Rodriguez,
keeper of archives, news-trivia expert.
Buried three husbands.
Were it not for Libby,
I could well be photo op number four.
And how is Libby's health these days?
It's very good.
Pity.
Business.
Paul needs to see what you've got
on the Joanie Shriver murder trial.
- That poor kid from Ochopee?
- Mm-hm.
Watch your back in here.
[DELORES HUMMING]
So far, we are online back to 1985.
Everything before that
is still on microfiche.
I can dig around the back
and see what else I can find.
How long will that take?
Oh, that depends, sweetheart. You'll be
amazed at what I can do with a little help.
[ALARM BUZZES]
ROGERS:
Mr. Armstrong.
Sergeant Rogers?
Raise your arms, please.
[WAND HUMMING]
Tape recorder.
There you go.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[ALARM BUZZES]
Your first time, Mr. Armstrong?
[LAUGHS]
[PRISONERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Give this to my sister. My man.
She take care of my kids, man.
They don't let me make phone calls.
[PRISONERS CONTINUE
SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN:
Come on, talk to me, baby.
Hey. Hey. Sweet thing.
Hey, come here, honey. I'll talk to you....
ROGERS:
Buzz when you want out.
If you're unable to buzz,
don't worry about it.
EARL:
Sweet Jesus.
The old girl said
you was gonna be coming up in here.
And I said, "No.
No, Grandma, he too busy a man...
...to come all the way from Harvard
just to give me his time."
But praise God...
...here you is.
Please.
Now, if I really talked with
that kind of verbal buck-and-shuffle...
...I'd be free today.
What's your game?
[SCOFFS]
Sir, it's no game. It's....
It's a funny thing about
small-town Florida people, professor.
Like crabs in a bucket, black or white.
One tries to climb out and the others
hop on his back and pull him back down.
Souls of Black Folk, Du Bois.
I've read it.
- All right?
- I'm impressed.
Good.
Well, I've always been
that climb-out crab.
See, my mother OD'd on heroin
when I was 13 up in Newark.
And it was Grandma that came
and got me and brought me here.
I was high school valedictorian.
Got a full scholarship
to Cornell University...
...but they never treated me
like nothing but an outsider.
So how do you like Grandma, huh?
She's something else,
coming up on that bus like that.
Yes, she's a very determined lady.
But why did you send her up to see me?
Because, Mr. Armstrong,
you are from a small town, like me.
Fife, Scotland. First in your family
to attend a university.
Magna from Cambridge. Columbia Law.
Youngest assistant DA, 1960-69.
Joined Jackson, Boll & Manheim, 1970.
1980 to the present...
...Harvard professor of law...
...author of Process and Law,
and six books since.
- Okay, okay.
- All of which I've read.
Enough.
Let's start.
- Joanie Shriver.
- The victim.
Eleven years old. White girl.
Snatched from the front of the Ochopee
Elementary School, March 4, 1986.
Found a day later,
raped and cut up in the Glades.
A teacher ID'd the car as looking
somewhat like mine.
And Officer Tanny Brown
come and lock me up.
- I read the transcript.
- Well, let me tell you this:
Down here, if the chief head-banger
takes a dislike to you...
...your ass is his.
See, Tanny's a nigga
who likes being a big fish--
He's black?
Oh, yes.
[CHUCKLES]
Yes, sir. See, this is the new South.
Now, they've got black cops
to torment your black ass.
It's called affirmative action.
Ah, hmm.
Tell me about your confession.
[GRUNTS]
My confession? I was slapped.
I was punched.
Beaten with a phone book.
Made to piss myself, kicked.
And then Officer Tanny Brown walked in.
WILCOX:
Hey, Tanny, no, wait.
TANNY: Come on, now, J.T., I need you
to back me up on this one here.
Pretty Robert Earl.
I want to ask you....
- Last time.
- It's like I told you. It's like I told you.
I don't know this girl.
I have no reason to lie to you.
- Hey.
- Come on, Robbie Earl, talk to me.
Come on, stop. Stop fucking arou--
What did you say to her?
How'd you get her in the car?
- Mm--
- Say, "Ah." "Ah."
[GROANING]
[GUN CLICKS AND EARL GASPS]
TANNY:
Talk to me, Bobby Earl.
Talk to me.
[EARL GROANING]
I hate pretty motherfuckers like you.
Listen, I don't know no Joanie Shriver.
Come on, you pretty motherfucker,
talk to me.
Ain't so pretty now, are you?
[GUN CLICKS AND EARL GASPS]
[CRYING]
EARL:
They had me in there at least 22 hours.
No food, no water, no sleep.
No bathroom.
--at which point you drove her
to an isolated section of the Everglades...
...approximately two and a half miles
southeast of her home.
Yes.
And did you drive her to that location...
...with the full intent to kidnap, rape...
...sodomize and kill her?
Speak into the microphone, Robert Earl.
[WHISPERS]
Yes.
[RECORDER CLICKS]
You feel much better now, don't you?
You a strange fruit, Robert Earl.
Strange fruit, indeed.
EARL: I would've confessed to anything
and they just spoon-fed me to the row.
It's your word against theirs.
I didn't do it.
DOLIVEAU:
She's a pretty thing.
You wouldn't have known
when they brought her in.
He was a very angry boy,
that Bobby Earl.
Parts of her chest and abdomen
were so badly damaged...
...hard to tell how many times
she'd been stabbed.
The cuts were...
...long, sort of shallow at each end,
deep in the middle.
The nature of the wounds
curved upward.
- Kind of in a half-moon shape.
- Like a scimitar?
Yeah. But miniature.
I'd say six inches from hilt to tip.
Let me ask you, your autopsy report
states that the girl was raped.
But there's no record of any semen here.
Well, there wasn't any.
- There wasn't?
- No. No, she was penetrated.
If there was no semen, how did you
establish the O-positive blood?
Yeah, we got that
from the teeth and gums.
Hmm.
And you said here that
you examined Bobby Earl's hand...
...and you found cuts that could be
attributed to teeth marks.
That's right.
But you never matched
the dental plate to the cuts.
Well, I didn't need to,
once he confessed.
Did you know he was beaten for 22 hours
before he gave his confession?
So he says.
So the cuts on his hand
could have been from the beating. No?
Oh, how convenient.
WILCOX:
Armstrong?
- Yes.
- I'm Detective Wilcox.
Spoke on the phone about hooking up
with Tanny Brown?
- Yes. J.T. Wilcox.
- That's right.
Tanny said he'd hook up with you
this afternoon if you're still around.
Anything I can do?
Well, if you have time later, thank you.
Looks like you got a busy afternoon
lined up, Mr. Armstrong.
Some people to see, yes.
You ever been here before?
- No.
- Come on. It's a nice little town.
So how's old Bobby Earl doing?
Oh, he's, uh, holding it together.
Ha-ha-ha. "Holding it together."
JIMMY: Hey, J.T.
- Hey, Jimmy.
Yeah, I'd expect he would be
holding it together.
Cold-hearted son of a bitch.
Stayed right frosty to the end.
Get that vehicle back in the street, Charlie.
That's the last time I'm telling you.
CHARLIE:
Sorry, J.T.
Then he just started spitting it out,
like a goddamn machine.
Scared me to death.
Scared you to death?
[LAUGHS]
What did old Bobby Earl tell you?
About the bare-assed light bulb
at 4 in the morning?
I beat on him with a rubber hose?
How about a phone book?
[CHUCKLING]
White pages or yellow pages?
Mr. Armstrong?
Now, you listen to me.
Do you think if I'd gotten physical
with old Bobby Earl...
...he wouldn't be wearing my anger
all over him at that arraignment?
What do you think, professor?
I'm impressed.
You have a nice day now.
Harvard University. Do tell.
I'm a graduate of Florida State myself.
Bobby Earl Ferguson.
Change of venue, denied.
Motion to suppress a confession,
denied.
Objection to an all-white jury, overruled.
Noted for the record.
I said, "You'll have to plead guilty,
take a 25-year hit.
You'll have some life left
when you come out."
He says, "But, sir, I didn't do it."
So he made you go to trial, hmm?
Tell me. This, uh, matching
blood statement by Dr. Doliveau...
- ...why didn't you challenge it?
- Yes.
Even us backwoods
Florida State Law School alumni know...
...that an O-positive match
doesn't mean anything...
...unless you get genetic screening
or an enzyme-base analysis.
You just narrowed it down
to about 40 million suspects.
How did this testimony
survive cross-examination?
About half the people in the courtroom
were on a first-name basis with that woman.
She's known around here
as a very fine physician.
And a doctor is a god. You know that.
Pathetic.
Jury didn't care.
I'm gonna tell you something, worst thing
in that courtroom was Bobby Earl himself.
He sat there, day after day,
looking guilty as hell.
It's not a popularity contest.
I find that a naive statement, counselor.
Is that what you teach your law students
up there? "The truth will prevail"?
When's the last time you tried a case?
It's been 25 years.
Does that make you feel better?
Ha, ha. Hell.
Hang dog, show dog,
I don't think it'd make any difference...
...if Bobby Earl was
a 6'4" golden-haired Caucasian...
...who just quarterbacked Florida State
past Miami, 62-0 in the Cotton Bowl.
That jury is not gonna disregard
the boy's own words.
His confession was coerced.
Now, why didn't you bring in an expert
to analyze his voice on the tape?
I tried, sir. Truly, I tried.
I know my job, Mr. Armstrong.
But what you're not hearing is the fact...
...that people in this town were sick
with grief over that poor little girl.
And they wanted their revenge.
The end.
Mr. McNair.
Many thanks for your time.
Mr. Armstrong, no matter what
you may think of me as a lawyer...
...I defended that boy pro bono...
...because I believe everybody
has a right to legal counsel.
I paid for it dearly. I've lost half my business
because I defended that son of a bitch.
And he got the chair.
Can you imagine what it'd be like for me
around here if I'd gotten him acquitted?
[PEOPLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
CONKLIN: We always have a teacher
out here at 3:00...
...make sure the boys don't horseplay
or the girls while away the afternoon...
...gossiping and giggling on the corner.
Horseplay. Gossip. Sweet.
That day it was about 10 after 3.
Most everyone was gone.
And I saw her by the banyan tree.
She walked past the car, then turned...
...like someone in the car had called her.
She walked back...
...and before she got in she--
Oh, God.
I go to bed with this every night.
Her waving.
The car was parked under that tree?
Right like that there.
Well, that far away?
Hmm.
When did the police show you
the car for identification?
The police? No, they didn't.
They just showed me a photo.
- A photo?
- Mm-hm.
Really?
- From what angle?
- Angle?
Mm, uh, front, rear, side?
Side.
But you couldn't see the side from here.
Not if it was in that position.
It seemed like the car to me.
I was solid to myself when I said it.
- I understand.
- No, you don't!
You're tearing open a wound,
coming here. You know that?
I'm only trying to get at what happened.
And I am sorry for your grief.
Many thanks for your time.
Miss Conklin, may I ask you
one last question?
What color is that car?
- Midnight blue.
Not dark blue? Black?
Midnight blue.
How can you be so sure?
Because that's Tanny Brown's car.
Everyone knows that.
Thank you.
[GIRLS CHANTING INDISTINCTLY]
GIRLS:
One, two, three, four, five.
Come on in.
Tanny Brown.
- Paul Armstrong.
- Yeah.
So you're trying to get Robert Earl
off the row, huh?
No.
I'm just trying to get some information.
- Information?
- Mm-hm.
Well, fair enough.
Let's see if we can get you
some information.
Ah. Now...
...the girl got into the car
right here where we are.
I know.
You might wanna fasten
your seat belt now.
All right, now you, uh....
You watch carefully.
Robert Earl made this right here...
...heading towards the girl's house.
Nothing for her to get excited about.
See that second house there
with the blue trim?
That's hers.
She'd have wanted to go that way,
but he took her this way.
We think that's where he popped her.
Yeah, he's a pretty son of a bitch,
Robert Earl, but he's mean.
He's real mean.
[GASPING]
Scream! Scream!
[LAUGHING]
- I can't breathe.
TANNY: Come on.
Oh, come on, big man like you.
You can scream louder than that.
- Come on.
- Stop!
[GRUNTING]
What the fuck
was all that nonsense about?
Heh. Trying to get you some information.
That is what you've came down here for,
isn't it?
Now, you be careful.
You're way beyond your perimeters.
You take a look around you, Mr. Armstrong.
You take a look at where you are.
You smack dab in the middle of hell.
Didn't take you but five minutes
to get here...
...and there ain't nobody
that can hear you scream for help...
...let alone an 11-year-old girl.
Starting to get the picture, huh?
Starting to see it
with Joanie Shriver's eyes?
- I get the point.
- You get the point, huh?
They come through here.
He was probably carrying her.
Weren't any defensive wounds
on her hands.
We figure he knocked her out cold
in that car...
...back there at the intersection
near her house.
Did his killing
while she was unconscious.
Otherwise, we'd have seen stab wounds
on her hands...
...or some of his skin
up underneath her nails.
Anyway, this is it.
This is the kill spot here.
They told us at the coroner's office...
...that the rape was pre-mortem,
some of the cuts too.
But damn if he didn't do a lot of damage
to her after she was dead.
It's like he just went stone crazy.
He pushed her body in the water
down here...
...and tried to cover her up
with some brush.
Want you to meet Joanie Shriver,
Mr. Armstrong.
Go on. Take a look.
[PHONE RINGS]
- Hello.
- Katie?
Daddy! I'll go get Mommy.
No, no, don't get Mommy just yet.
Listen.
I've been thinking about you all day today,
sweetheart.
- And I love you very much.
- I love you too, Daddy.
- Can you come back to Miami tonight?
- No.
No, I can't come back tonight.
So I want you to sleep with Mommy.
- Daddy, I'm too old for that.
- It's not for you, it's for her.
Do it for me.
Okay, I'll do it for you.
- Good girl.
- I love you.
I love you too.
[GRUNTS
[HORN HONKING]
Damn.
They just hate long stories
about how you messed up their vehicles.
Heh. I hope you took out
that insurance option.
Hey, I like them lightning bolts, though.
Hell, you might not even wanna
paint this over.
I know I wouldn't.
[PHONE RINGING]
What do we gotta do
to get rid of you, Mr. Armstrong?
Convince me that Bobby Earl
deserves to die.
Under the circumstances,
that's not possible.
So I'm not gonna waste my time trying.
But, uh, I do have a question for you.
Are you aware that Robert Earl
was picked up on kidnap charges...
...in Dade County a year prior to his arrest
for Joanie Shriver's murder?
Case went all the way to trial.
You aware of that?
Yeah, I bet Mr. Victim
forgot to tell you about that.
And what was the result?
Prosecution's case collapsed, uh,
on a technicality, I believe.
Acquitted or thrown out of court?
Look, Armstrong...
...I knew Robert Earl was bad news
first time I ever laid eyes on him.
Used to see him hanging around the school
when I'd pick up my girls.
Hanging around with his pretty-boy looks
and his college-boy words.
And he just felt wrong.
Wasn't just me that felt that way.
Every man in this department.
- Everybody in town.
- I still don't hear any evidence.
We didn't need any.
- We had a confession.
- If that's a confession...
...my ass is a banjo.
Damn arrogant Yankee son of a bitch!
- He did it, goddamn it!
- Whoa! Come on, J.T. Leave him alone.
- Damn it, that man is an asshole!
- J.T., just calm the hell down.
Agh!
You tell me that man never laid a hand
on Bobby Earl Ferguson in 22 hours?
- He slapped him once or twice.
- Which was it?
Once, twice or what?
Look, Armstrong, you and I both know
it wasn't a textbook confession, all right?
But it was enough
to convict and close the case.
This is a case that hangs together
by the thinnest of threads.
You come down here, you start picking
at them threads, it's liable to fall apart.
I don't wanna see that happen.
I tell you something else.
I want to see Robert Earl go to the chair
for what he did.
Yeah.
Tell me, what is your policy on taking guns
into the interrogation room?
Very simple: We don't.
May I see your left ankle?
Please?
TANNY:
You, uh--? You looking for this?
I checked it with the duty sergeant.
You didn't take it out?
Point it at Bobby Earl?
No, sir.
You didn't stick it in his mouth
and play some Russian roulette?
No, sir.
Then how did I know
where to look for it?
EARL:
You're back. Let's get started.
Why didn't you tell me
about your run-ins?
What run-ins?
All those times Tanny Brown tried
to bust me down?
Come on.
Tanny Brown had nothing to do
with your arrest in Dade County.
- Dade County?
- Yeah.
The charge was kidnapping.
That was bullshit.
That was bullshit. I took some
white girl for a ride in my car.
It was just a ride.
In fact, she asked me for that ride.
When it came out the arresting cracker
happened to be a boyfriend...
...the judge should've
just thrown it out of court.
My life was different after that.
How?
How was your life different after that,
if the case was thrown out?
They took away my scholarship.
Let me tell you what a scholarship is
for someone like me.
It's a trade-off, pure and simple.
I get a free ride, they get a better image.
The minute I walked into court,
I couldn't live up to my end of the bargain.
That's all the justification they needed.
It's the same way Tanny Brown
felt justified looking for me when--
Wait. Wait. Wait a minute.
I don't follow you.
Imagine....
Imagine a man, a very bad man...
...driving a car heading south,
driving off the turnpike into Ochopee.
He stops, takes a siesta under
a banyan tree just outside a schoolyard.
Then he spots a little girl.
Pretty little girl.
And he talks her into his car
because he's friendly when he needs to be.
And then he does it.
Right there in the Glades.
He drives on and never gives it
another thought.
Yes. Go on.
That very bad man
moves on down the line.
A waitress in the Keys...
...two tourists in Lakeland,
a prostitute in Tampa, and finally...
...he gets sloppy.
Big-time sloppy.
That's murder one.
That's the row. Death row.
- He's here?
- Yes.
And what does he find
when he gets here?
A neighbor on the row
who's in for killing a little girl.
Yeah, a little blond girl
down in Ochopee.
All cut up and thrown in the swamps.
And he says:
"Well, boy, I know you didn't do it,
because I did."
Then he starts laughing.
And he says,
"You must be the sorriest fuck in this unit."
I can hear him, professor,
I can hear him every night.
MAN:
Bobby Earl!
Agh, Bobby Earl! Ha, ha!
Why won't you talk to me?
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Shut up, you crazy fuck!
Shut up!
It's like a death sentence
on top of a death sentence.
He calls me his last victim.
Who is he?
Blair Sullivan.
[HUMMING]
MAN 1: How are you? What can I do?
MAN 2: I made a reservation....
Yeah, you really had me going.
I was starting to think to myself,
"Maybe the man is onto something. Maybe."
What are you talking about?
Funny thing is, you almost pulled it off,
brother, you almost got away with it.
Got away with what?
Your wife, slick.
"Prentiss," that is her maiden name,
isn't it?
Yes. Was.
Was before she married you.
Laurie Prentiss, assistant DA.
What about her?
She was the prosecutor on Robert Earl's
kidnap trial in Dade. Ring any bells?
What you think, man?
Small-town police
don't do their homework?
Don't know how to access information?
I don't understand exactly
what kind of hidden agenda...
...you've got stuffed up your sleeve...
...but I'm telling you...
...you stay the hell out of my town.
I'd been plea bargaining everything
that came across my desk for six months.
I just wanted to show
the good old boys how good I was.
I was hot for it.
Thought I had the case locked tight.
My star witness, the arresting officer.
He said when he came up on the car,
he found Bobby Earl on top of her...
...in the back seat
and she was screaming bloody murder.
Two seconds
into the cross-examination...
...the defense attorney
produces a prom photo...
...with my star witness
in a tuxedo with the victim.
Son of a bitch admits
they were high school sweethearts.
I didn't wanna go out without a fight...
...so I got the judge to grant me
a 24-hour recess so I could regroup.
I came back with nothing,
he threw the case out.
Why the hell didn't you tell me?
I did. I told you when I met you.
- I told you--
- Bullshit.
You should've told me the night
you read the letter.
- I didn't-- I--
- Why not?
I didn't know if it would influence you.
That you might not take the case
and you might not help this kid.
He paid dearly with everything else
that happened to him.
Why? Because he lost a scholarship
and spent an extra night in prison?
No, Paul. lt was more than that.
Later, I found out that they beat him
real bad that night.
He ended up in the hospital.
Listen to me. It was my fault.
I want you to help him get his life back.
I want you to make it right for him.
No, Laurie, you want me
to make it right for you.
You're right.
But how does what I'm telling you
change his situation on death row?
Okay.
DELORES: They called it "The Pilgrimage
of Death." He sold a lot of papers.
The guy started out
with his landlady in New Orleans...
...a prostitute in Mobile
and a sailor in Pensacola.
And then he got real busy.
A body every 100 miles.
Pensacola, when was that?
Ohh....
Late April, early May.
You know, it was incredible.
APBs in three states,
FBI flyers all over the place...
...and nobody spots him.
GUARD: Painting and writing letters
to the families of his victims...
...that's all the son of a bitch does.
Yeah, we got a whole other theme park
for Mr. Sullivan.
[PRISONERS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN: Hey, are you here to see me, man?
GUARD: Hey.
MAN:
I'm innocent. I'm innocent.
[MAN SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[PRISONERS CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
GUARD:
All right.
He's all yours.
They don't like me very much.
Really?
- Why is that?
- Mm.
Creative differences.
Hmm.
Uh, tape recorder. May I?
Mm, be my guest.
You have quite an art gallery back there.
Thank you.
Idle hands are the devil's workshop.
Hmm.
Do you believe in Jesus?
Yes. Yes, I do.
That's good. That's very good.
I done killed so many
goddamn people...
...I can't keep up with my correspondence,
but my question is this:
Do you think any one of those people
rolled out of bed...
...on the morning of their last day thinking,
"Today's my day to die"?
You got to take Jesus into your heart
right away, because you never know.
Even if you don't have a condition,
you might have a situation.
- You a killer too?
- Me?
- No.
- You never been in a war?
- Korea? Vietnam?
Never did a little hit-and-run
with the BMW?
Never told the wifey to get an abortion?
Or that piece of chicken you got on the
side, "Here's $300, get it taken care of."
No.
Because you got that look.
You got ice in your eyes.
I can tell.
Well, you're wrong.
Am I now?
Mr. Armstrong...
...let's see whom we're talking to here.
Are you married?
Yes.
Kids?
- No.
- Liar.
House or an apartment?
- I have a house.
- Alarms on the windows?
- No.
- Dogs?
- You have trouble sleeping?
- No.
- Liar.
You afraid to die?
- I don't give it much thought.
- Liar!
That's three lies.
Same as Peter did to Jesus
before the cock crowed.
You should be ashamed of yourself,
lying to a condemned man.
Well, don't my lies tell you
as much about me as my truths?
Okay.
Heh. Oh.
Would you do me a favor?
Mail this for me.
Thank you.
So, what do you want to talk to
an old bad guy like me for?
Ochopee.
Nice town.
What happened there?
You been talking to my old neighbor,
Bobby Earl. Excitable boy.
Did you kill Joanie Shriver?
Did I?
There been so many.
Did you kill Joanie Shriver?
Hell, Armstrong, you're starting to get all
frantic and excited, just like Bobby Earl did.
- Did you?
- You're the visitor I've had in two years...
...since those behavioral-science
boys come to see me.
Wanted to know about my childhood.
Did my folks beat me,
abuse me, sex me up?
I tried telling them there ain't no formula
for people like me.
What we're dealing with here
is just a predisposition for an appetite.
You know, good parents, bad parents....
Ain't no cause and effect.
It's just an appetite.
Fuck you.
Let me tell you a few things, Armstrong.
One, I am filled with power.
You may think I'm an impotent prisoner,
handcuffed...
...locked in a cell each night and day,
but I am filled with a strength...
...that reaches way beyond
these bars, sir!
I can touch anyone I want to!
Just as easy
as dialing the telephone!
There's no one beyond my reach!
You hear me? No one!
Did you kill her?
I ain't gonna tell you
if killed that little girl or not.
Even if I did, how would you know
to believe me?
Killing is easy for me.
How hard do you think lying is?
Yeah. Go to hell.
Oh, I will. No doubt about that.
But say I could help
you find something?
Something important.
Something interesting. Real important.
Like what?
[MIMICS SWOOSHING]
[GRUNTING]
Where is it?
- Not far from where they found her.
- Where?
- They just didn't read the signs.
- What signs?
- You know your Bible?
- My Bible?
Ecclesiastes 11:1.
You can't miss it
if you can just read the signs.
- What signs?
- "Seek, and ye shall find."
[ALARM BUZZING]
[HUMMING]
- Do you have a Bible here?
- That's one thing we got plenty of.
The Gideons love us.
- How'd it go?
- Well, I wouldn't like him as a neighbor.
- He asked me to mail this.
- Not again. Goddamn him.
Wilkinsons. Sick bastard.
These give me nightmares.
I never let them out. Can't even read them.
LENA:
Hey, Roz, what's up, baby?
Oh, you saw Tyrone?
Please. He is not telling you the truth.
You know he's lying.
Because I saw him with her last night.
Anyway, girl, someone is here
so I'll speak to you later. All right, then.
[R&B MUSIC PLAYING QUIETLY
ON RADIO]
- Hi.
LENA: Hi.
- Does Tanny Brown live here?
- He's at a soccer practice with my brother.
- Hi. I'm Lena.
- Hi.
- You must be Mr. Armstrong.
- Yeah? How do you know?
Well, everyone knows you're the guy
my father was complaining about.
He'll be back in a few minutes.
Would you care for some iced tea?
- That would be very nice.
- All right, then. Come in.
You're the only one for me
And I'm proud
[MUSIC STOPS]
LENA:
You know, I'm gonna study law too.
I graduated first in my high school class.
Well, good for you.
LENA: I'm thinking about going
to the University of Virginia.
They have a great school
and my mom lives in Newport News.
That's Joanie and me.
Daddy used to call us his girls.
I remember how we used to talk
about opening up a pet shop together.
I miss her.
There isn't a day that goes by
that I still don't talk to her.
TANNY:
Talk to who?
- Reese, I want you to wash up for supper.
- But, Daddy--
Go wash up for supper.
Lena, is supper ready?
LENA: Yes, Daddy.
- Mm-hm. Take Mr. Armstrong's glass.
He was just leaving.
- Get the hell out of my house, man.
- You should never have been in charge.
- I'll have you locked up.
- Too close to the victim.
You got no right
interrogating my children.
- You got no right coming here...
- All right.
...telling me how to do my job!
How many times did she have dinner in
this house, sleep over with your daughter?
That is-- Look, I got an office.
You want something here?
What you come around here for?
I thought you might be interested
in recovering the knife.
The knife. So now all of a sudden,
you're Sherlock Holmes, huh?
You're obviously not.
[HISSING]
Any luck?
"Cast thy bread upon the waters,
for thou shalt find it after many days."
Ecclesiastes 11:1.
Blair Sullivan's directions.
Blair Sullivan, huh?
"And if the tree fall toward the south
or toward the north...
...in the place where the tree falleth,
there it shall be."
Oh, yeah, you're really
onto something now, Armstrong.
Really onto something.
Look here...
...how you come to Blair Sullivan
on this thing?
Well, it's a long story.
Well, take a look around you.
Look where you at.
- You see where you are?
ARMSTRONG: Yes.
"Seek and ye shall find."
[TANNY LAUGHING]
Man, Sullivan must have bust a gut
the minute he seen you coming.
Talking about the Bible. Ha-ha-ha.
Look, we must've had
50, 60 volunteers...
...poking, digging and dragging
through all you see here...
...trying to find that knife.
And we know this place.
What's this?
That's a culvert. They run under the roads.
Keep them from washing away.
[SNARLS]
- What was that?
- Well, that's the local wildlife.
You know, there's a couple hundred
of them here, if you want to keep looking.
Do people live in a place like that?
Hell, no. That's an old poacher's shack,
what they call a hunting blind.
It's like a base camp for gator hunters.
Do, uh-- Do the skinning there,
rest up in the evening.
It's kind of a nighttime thing.
[HORN HONKING]
Oh, what the hell is he doing now?
- What now?
- Look at this: one, one, one.
- What about it?
- Sullivan said we have to read the signs.
Eleven-one. Chapter eleven, verse one.
You're a real hard case, Armstrong.
You know that?
You're fishing, Armstrong.
There's nothing out here.
You're fishing.
The man's an idiot.
Armstrong.
Goddamn it.
Hey. How about this?
North, south. South, north.
That's a tree, no?
You wanna make your point?
Step down here, please, will you?
Well, I've just about run out
of patience with you, Armstrong.
- Just step down.
- I hope this is good, whatever it is.
Would you mind picking that up?
Is something wrong
with your hands all of a sudden?
No, but, uh, if it is the murder weapon...
...technically it's better to be discovered
by an officer of the law.
Mm. I see.
That way we won't jeopardize
my legal position.
Thank you, professor.
Goddamn.
Goddamn you, Armstrong.
You got a lot of explaining to do.
Sullivan...
...all but admitted that he killed the girl...
...without anyone sticking a gun
in his mouth.
Fuck Blair Sullivan and fuck you too.
No. Rejoice.
For a great injustice
is about to be undone!
Yes!
[SQUAWKING]
[GROWLING]
What was Sullivan driving?
Three cars.
- All stolen.
- What was he driving when he hit Florida?
- Green Monarch.
- Damn.
We need a Ford Granada.
I see your Monarch...
...I raise you Bobby Earl's...
...Granada.
ARMSTRONG:
They're almost identical.
WARDEN:
I'm no friend of capital punishment...
...but at least the letters will stop.
WOMAN:
More of Sullivan's correspondence.
That's the lot?
So far.
Warden.
WARDEN:
"Dear Mr. and Mrs. Shriver...
...I've been wrong
not to write to you before this...
...but I've been real busy
getting ready to die.
I just wanted you to know what a real...
...sweet piece of business
your little baby was.
Doing her was like carving up...
...a ripe melon...
...like picking ripe cherries
on a summer morning...
...like plowing a scented field,
and plow her I did.
Although, I don't imagine anything's
gonna come of that particular crop...
...come harvest time, do you?"
It's signed, "Your friend Blair Sullivan."
Now...
...he doesn't specifically say
in this letter...
...that he killed Joanie Shriver.
Does he?
No.
He said what I read.
That being with her was
"like carving up a ripe melon."
Nothing further.
Bobby Earl, Bobby Earl.
How does it feel being free?
- Uh, I'd like to thank--
- Your attorney.
My attorney, Mr. Lyle Morgan.
My grandma for never giving up hope,
and Professor Paul Armstrong.
If it weren't for him,
I wouldn't be standing here today.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
MAN: Bobby Earl.
WOMAN: Bobby Earl.
MAN:
Do you have any plans to leave the city?
WOMAN:
Where will you reside?
MAN:
Bobby Earl.
- How are you?
LAURIE: I'm very happy for you.
I'm happy for both of us.
- Professor.
ARMSTRONG: Bobby Earl.
EARL:
Thank you so much.
ARMSTRONG:
Before we go back...
...we'd like you to come for drinks Friday.
Oh, I'd love to, but I can't.
I made other plans.
But we'll meet again. I promise you.
MAN: One more shot. Got a second?
LAURIE: Congratulations.
- You have a safe trip.
MAN: Bobby Earl.
[REPORTERS CHATTERING]
Hey there, Mr. Ferguson.
Congratulations.
Got them all fooled, don't you?
Judge, even that know-nothing
Harvard fool, huh?
But not me.
No, sir. Not Tanny Brown.
I'm gonna be all over you
like white on rice, boy. You hear?
- Come on.
- Miss Evangeline.
[BAND PLAYING
"I ONLY HAVE EYES FOR YOU"]
ARMSTRONG [SINGING]:
They all disappear
[HUMMING]
[MUMBLING LYRICS]
[LAURIE LAUGHING]
Oh, I love you.
LYLE:
The firm's been much more successful...
...than I ever dreamed it would be
when I started it.
- So, Lyle, are you single at all?
- I've been married for eight years.
Oh, good. It's time for you to fool around.
PHIL:
All right. Champagne, anyone?
- Yeah. Yes, I'd love some. Thank you, Phil.
- Thank you, Phil.
LIBBY: You ought to stay on a few days
and we'll make it a real vacation.
No, we gotta get back. I'm behind
on my caseload. Paul, you've got classes.
- Yep.
- Paul, I think you missed your true calling.
You should've been a detective.
No, thanks. I'm quite happy
to get out of the real world.
- Ha-ha-ha.
PHIL: Here we go. A little refreshment.
[PHONE RINGING]
Katie. Katie. Sweetie, get the phone.
Hello, hello. Hello.
I would like--
I would like to propose a toast.
To innocence revealed.
To death denied.
To the triumph of truth over appearance.
- Hear, hear.
Telephone for you, Daddy.
- Don't finish it.
DELORES: What are you doing after?
What am I doing after the party?
I have an appointment.
I'm afraid, in fact,
I'm gonna have to leave now.
- Hello.
SULLIVAN: Well, well, well.
- Congratulations, professor.
- Sullivan?
How'd you get this number?
I've got all your numbers.
It's been a big week for you.
Been a big week for me too.
Sure you know the governor
signed my death warrant.
Hell, I got less time than it takes
to play a round of golf.
Anyways...
...my letter done sewed it up tight
for you.
We thought that might do the trick.
We?
- Who's "we"?
- I'll tell you when you get here.
Things worked out kind of perfect
for you, didn't it?
Maybe a little too perfect.
- You got a pen?
- Yes.
13 Tula Way.
Winterglade.
My folks' place.
I want you to call on them.
I want you to say goodbye for me.
Tell them I love them...
...and that they are in my prayers...
...and then you come to me.
You do that for me
and I'll tell you who "we" is.
You best run, Armstrong.
[THE ORIOLES' "CRYING IN THE CHAPEL"
PLAYING QUIETLY ON RADIO]
[DOORBELL RINGING]
Hello?
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Anyone home?
MAN [ON RADIO]:
Ha-ha-ha. Takes me back to my youth.
Now, I wanna remind you all
of next Sunday's fish fry.
[FLOOR CREAKING]
And now, from the bounty of the Lord...
..."Amazing Grace"
on Everglade Christian Radio.
CHOIR [SINGING]:
Amazing Grace
How sweet the sound
[FLY BUZZING]
That saved a wretch like me
I once was lost
But now I'm found
Was blind
[MUSIC STOPS]
SULLIVAN:
"So the dead which he slew at his death...
...were more than they
which he slew in his life."
Judges 16:30.
I told you I had power.
Not this time, Armstrong.
So tell me...
...what did you see?
What did you hear?
Well, give me all the details.
Spare me nothing. Come on.
Come on, man, I want everything.
- Come on.
- No.
When you called me to say:
"We thought the letter
would do the trick"...
...who did you mean by "we"?
Come, on.
Tell me what you saw down there.
Tell me about my folks.
That was the deal.
No.
Okay. Why not? Okay.
By "we," I meant me
and the shining boy of the hour.
See, I pushed the buttons
to make you do the dance...
...to spring our boy...
...who, in turn, did the deed.
- "Did the deed"?
- You know what I'm talking about.
I had some unfinished business
out there.
I gave Bobby Earl life...
...so he could give me death.
Joanie Shriver?
I never had the pleasure of making
that sweet little girl's acquaintance.
Bobby Earl coached me a little bit
on the details.
All I had to do to take his crime
was tell you where the knife was...
...and write that letter.
You should see your face, Armstrong.
Ha, ha.
What the hell's going on up there?
- Why me?
- We needed us a legitimizer.
Who'd believe us?
We're just psychopaths.
- But why me?
- You were Bobby Earl's con.
- He had his reasons.
- Reasons?
- It's my turn now.
- What fucking reasons?
No, it's my turn now! Come on.
How did my folks look? Hmm?
How did they smell?
Tell me everything.
Come on. Spare me nothing.
Hmm?
They said they forgive you
and they'll remember you in their prayers.
- No.
- Yeah.
I'm sure you're lying, cocksucker! No!
You inhuman bastard!
You cannot cheat me of this!
I'm screwed! Come on!
We played you like a tune!
It ain't over yet!
You got the trials of Job ahead of you!
The trials of Job!
The sin is pride, you motherfucker...
...and the messenger is revenge!
[DOOR SLAMS]
SULLIVAN [ON RECORDER]:
We played you like a tune!
It ain't over yet! You got to--
Tanny.
[SOBBING]
No!
[GROWLING]
TANNY: I told you how fragile this was.
- You're right.
- I said you were right.
- You know where I am?
I'm sitting at the Sullivan house
and I wanna tell you...
...it's a good thing for you
I just I put Wilcox on his tail.
PRIEST: "ln the name of the father, son...
- Shut up.
PRIEST: ...and the Holy Spirit--"
Shut up!
"As governor of the state of Florida...."
I have a confession from Sullivan
on tape and it is evidence.
TANNY:
Armstrong, you're a goddamn fool.
First you had evidence this way,
now you got evidence that way.
His confession don't mean shit
unless he testifies in court.
Don't lecture me about confessions,
not after the way you got Bobby Earl's.
"--to cause the sentence of death
to be executed on Blair Sullivan."
[WHIMPERING]
TANNY:
Armstrong, you keep Sullivan alive.
ALL:
Our father, who art in heaven...
...hallowed be thy name.
[PHONE RINGING]
Thy kingdom come. Thy will be done
on earth, as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses.
Paul.
Katie, are you packed?
- Where are you, J.T.?
- I'm right on top of him, Tanny.
- Collins and 50th.
TANNY: The Eden Roc.
I want you to stay on his tail. Don't jump
that rabbit until I give you the green light.
Ten-four.
[RINGING]
[TAPE RECORDER WHIRRING]
SULLIVAN [ON RECORDING]: You were
Bobby Earl's con. And he had his reasons.
ARMSTRONG: Reason? What reasons?
SULLIVAN: It's my turn now.
No, it's my turn now!
I'm sorry, there's no answer.
What about messages?
Did she leave anything for me?
WOMAN:
Just one moment, sir.
SULLIVAN: We played you like a tune!
It ain't over yet!
You got the trials of Job ahead, mister!
The trials of Job! The sin is pride....
WOMAN:
Sorry, sir, no messages.
SULLIVAN:
--and the messenger is revenge!
Laurie.
On, no, I left him. Angus.
- Who?
- The teddy bear Daddy gave me. I left him.
- We already gave the key back.
- But we can't just leave him.
[SIGHS]
Come on, we'll find a maid.
Maybe she'll let us back in the room
if you ask her nicely.
Don't let anyone touch that luggage.
All right?
- Yes, sir.
- I'll be right back.
I gotta call Mom and Dad.
- Did I get the laundry?
- Yeah, I think so.
Good.
KATIE:
The maid wouldn't take Angus, would she?
I don't think so.
You gotta take better care of your stuff.
KATIE:
I know. I'm sorry.
[LINE RINGING]
Laurie! Laurie!
We'll go in your car.
Now get those keys out.
- Mommy.
- Hey, hey. You better lock it up, girl.
Now, get the keys out. All right?
We're gonna have ourselves a little ride.
Come on, Wilcox,
pick up the damn phone.
[PHONE RINGING]
- Just get in.
- Leave her here.
Move your hand or I'll cut her head off.
Get in there.
Hurry up.
Let's go. Let's go. Hurry up.
Come on, pick it up.
- Sweetie, come in, quick.
EARL: Get in the car.
KATIE:
Mommy, where's Daddy?
TANNY:
Armstrong.
That's Laurie's car.
I think Bobby Earl has them.
Where the hell is Wilcox?
[GRUNTING]
Mommy, where are we going?
It's a surprise.
Stop touching her.
Look, I'm way out of my jurisdiction here.
I need to call for backup.
All right.
[HORNS HONKING]
Why are you doing this?
He saved your life.
Bitch, that don't make up
for what you did to me, does it?
- Let her go. She didn't do anything to you.
- No.
- She's a part of you.
- Let her go.
She's a tiny version of you.
She'll grow up and be a hero like Mommy.
- It's okay.
- Shut up!
Get down. Get down,
in case he sees you.
[HORN HONKING]
Damn.
- Pull over. Pull over to the left!
- Where? I can't.
To the left! I'll kill her!
ARMSTRONG:
They're going against the traffic.
EARL:
Bitch, drive!
[HORNS HONKING]
- Take it! Punch it! Punch the gas! Punch it!
- No!
Punch it! Punch it!
Bitch, you better drive! Punch it!
Punch it or I'll kill her! I'll take her now!
[LAURIE & KATIE SCREAMING]
[EARL LAUGHING]
TANNY:
Oh, shit.
[PHONE RINGING]
Professor? Listen up.
- Daddy?
- Katie.
I got me a double date here, professor?
Remember Joanie Shriver?
Well, that's nothing compared
to what I'm gonna do to your little girl here.
Mom.
[RATTLING]
ARMSTRONG: Look, there's the car.
TANNY: It's about the only place he'd be.
Keep your eyes open, Armstrong.
We're in his backyard now.
Now, we need to split up.
I'm gonna go around back, all right?
Now, look here...
...you squeeze one off if you have to.
Don't try to hit nothing.
Just point and squeeze.
[BIRD SQUAWKS]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
- Where is he?
LAURIE: Hurry.
Get it off my mouth. He's out there.
Hurry.
He's out there somewhere.
Get Katie out of here. Hurry, quick.
Everything's going to be all right.
LAURIE: He's out there.
I don't know if he's gonna come back.
[BIRD SQUAWKING]
ARMSTRONG:
Fucking knot.
[GUN SHOT]
LAURIE:
That was close. Paul. Paul.
EARL: Welcome to the party, professor.
- Unh!
LAURIE:
Stop it!
EARL:
Give me Tanny's gun.
He couldn't stand to see me free,
living the good life, so I killed the fucker.
Let them go. You have me now.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, it's not you that I want, professor.
Is it, Laurie?
It's not you I've been waiting for
and thinking about the last eight years.
- But she dropped her case against you.
- Not soon enough.
You, little lady,
had me held for just one night...
...so you could make a name
for yourself off of me. Sullivan was right.
The sin is pride.
- I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
- I had no idea they were gonna hurt you.
- Hurt me?
Do you want to see
what those fuckers did to me?
- No.
- They cut me.
They castrated me. You feel that?
- You had me--
- Aah!
EARL: Did you think those fuckers
would give a shit about justice?
[LAURIE YELLS]
Sit your ass down.
Like that knife, Paul?
That's what put me on the row and eight
years later, that's what made me free.
Please, let Katie go.
She's just a little girl.
I'm saving Katie for dessert.
Now I'm going to do me
these two lovely ladies of yours.
- Aah! No! Paul!
- Easy!
- And then I'm gonna disappear.
- No.
Now, what I need to know from you is
how do you want to die, first or last?
And Blair Sullivan?
Watch your fucking hands.
What about him, Bobby Earl?
Don't fuck with me, Armstrong.
Sullivan is dead.
No. The governor gave him
a stay of execution.
You're a desperate man, Armstrong.
I brought him the news.
- What fucking news?
- That his parents were still alive and well.
SULLIVAN [ON RECORDER]:
No, it's my turn now!
How did my folks look? Hmm?
How did they smell?
ARMSTRONG: They said they forgive you
and will remember you in their prayers.
- You're a fucking liar!
- Sullivan's gonna testify against you.
SULLIVAN: You inhuman bastard!
- Liar!
[ALL SCREAMING]
SULLIVAN:
We played you like a tune!
It ain't over yet! You got the trials
of Job ahead of you!
The trials of Job!
[ALL GRUNTING]
Paul!
TANNY:
Get your ass out of the water, Armstrong.
[SNARLING]
KATIE:
Daddy!
[GROANING]
[COUGHING]
[HUMMING]
You all right there, Armstrong?
Well, I'm in better shape than you are.
I loved Joanie Shriver
like she was my own.
What about you?
Are you going to be okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Least we'll be able to sleep at night.
Well....
We'll see.
[CRYING]
[English - US - SDH]