Hello, Is this Randy Bates?
Who wants to know?
This is Crazy Carl Cummings.
KZTS all-hits radio station.
Pride of the nation at 98.9.
We've got a surprise for you just about
as big as Barry Manilow's beak,
Are you sitting down?
Better yet, are you laying down?
Are you on a waterbed, all comfy?
Are you horizontal, Randy boy?
No, I'm sitting up,
but I think I can handle it.
Do you like country music?
I used to like Roy Acuff.
Roy Acuff? Would you take Dolly Parton
in a pinch?
I may be Crazy Carl, but I would.
But you won it.
An evening with Dolly Parton.
The evening begins with a pre-show dinner
for you and Miss Parton...
at the Hawaii Kai Room
of the Sheraton Barstow.
A backstage pass for you for Dolly's
big show at the Barstow War Memorial...
and then, a little dessert
at Massimino's Cafe.
And who knows whether
the evening will end there?
Because, Dolly, she's a powerful woman.
She's been on the road a long, long time.
All right.
- What's your favorite radio station?
- KZTS.
I can't hear you.
We'll pick you up at 6:00
in a long black limousine, baby.
Yeah, all right.
Dolly Parton? You turned a hard-core felon
into a trembling teenager.
What kind of indictment
did this guy skip out on?
Two counts of atrocious assault.
He found his wife in bed with a roadie
from ZZ Top and took a tire iron to both.
You must be awful tired,
you had a long drive to get here.
That's my job,
track them and snatch them.
I can't believe this guy is sitting there
expecting a limousine.
Good evening, sir. Congratulations.
Goddamn, I never won anything before.
Allow me.
I am ready to party hard.
I'm Tom Nowak. I've been empowered
by the State of California...
to return you to Sacramento
where you're due to stand trial.
You son of a bitch!
What's your favorite radio station, Randy?
K-Suck, you dork!
Once we catch them, we never gloat.
Thank you, gents.
What kind of music do you like?
I sure as hell don't want to hear
no Roy Acuff, I'll tell you that.
Matter of fact...
I'd like to hear something
that sounds about as mean as I feel.
Why don't you just let me
pick it for you, then?
A Crazy Carl Cummings special.
John Capshaw from Sacramento,
He's got a good start,
and Rampage is a tough one to ride,
It looks like he'll get big money
out of this rodeo,
Capshaw has gone down,
and the rodeo clowns move in,
Here's what clowns are all about,,,
as the bull takes it out on the barrel,
Thanks, partner.
Nice ride, cowboy.
Tom, how are you doing?
Say, my favorite bloodhound.
I just did John Capshaw and I could
sure use the cash now, if you got it.
- You did Capshaw?
- How?
I'll tell you later. You got the money?
We're just ordering. Sit down.
You got to eat, for Christ's sake.
I'll have the Chief Justice Warren Burger,
well done.
Extra fries.
One Warren, burn it.
Have you got the money?
I got to visit someone.
You got to visit somebody?
Isn't that funny?
I never thought of Tommy Nowak
as the kind of guy who pays a social call.
Have you got the money?
All right.
Thanks.
Tell us how you did Capshaw.
He tricked the poor bastard.
That's what he did.
He snuck up
when the dude was half unconscious.
- Who are you?
- I'm Capshaw's lawyer, okay?
I'll tell you this...
there's a pretty thin line between
what you do and what some outlaws do.
Maybe a thin line, but it ain't invisible.
- Afternoon, Miss McGuinn.
- Afternoon, Mr. Barton.
When you going to take some sun?
You're about the palest thing
in the whole damn camp.
One of these days, Mr. Barton.
Remember when I gave you
our rent money on the first of the month...
- right on time?
- Remember?
It's a golden day in my book of memories.
First time since you and your husband
came here...
when you actually paid when it was due.
Can I have it back?
You're a really nice person, Mr. Barton.
Isn't he?
Hi, honey.
What's up?
- What's that?
- Leave that alone.
That's baby food money, Roy.
Not for shotguns, not for Wild Turkey.
Not so you can get wasted
on some kind of horse tranquilizer.
You're with me on that, right?
Do you hear, boys?
This is baby food money.
$120.
Would you help me with the baby?
Say, hey, Roy.
- We finally got it knocked, baby.
- Knocked?
Like that Amway franchise in the desert?
Or the oil field work in Alaska?
Or how about our famous
chinchilla farm, remember?
Make cash fast by raising chinchillas
for their pelts...
unless you leave the cage door open
and they run away.
I know I screwed up a lot of things...
but honest, we're on Dream Street now.
Come on.
How'd you make this money?
We didn't make it.
Some friends of ours did.
- It's counterfeit?
- State of the art, baby.
This is the big time.
Listen to me.
You do six months for selling hot VCRs,
I'm still here when you get out.
I waited for you.
But I didn't count on these prison buddies.
Please, for the baby's sake,
get rid of these psychos.
They scare me.
Psychos? These guys?
Let me keep the money here a few days.
I'll find a good hiding place for it.
I know I screwed up
some things in the past...
but this is idiot-proof.
Doesn't it seem just a little strange
that this woman...
who has no previous record at all...
is the only person being indicted
for possession of counterfeit money?
Your Honor, she was the only one home
at the time of the raid.
And she refuses to tell us
anything about the crime.
One could hardly blame
the woman, Mr. Hastings...
when she's got a Folsom Prison
class reunion...
going on right behind her.
If Your Honor pleases, these gentlemen
have come to post bond for the defendant.
We believe that the counterfeit money
we found in that trailer...
is just the tip of the iceberg.
There are other moneys...
and other crimes involved.
So we ask the court...
to set the bond with these facts in mind.
The court sets bail at $25,000.
We can cover that action, baby.
Your Honor, Mrs. McGuinn
prefers to seek bail...
from a recognized bail bondsman.
What do you got for me, Buddy?
I told you. I got Little Walter Drucker.
The schmuck who gave me
this defective microwave for collateral.
He is sitting downtown
at the Golden Bear Motel...
waiting to be plucked
like an apple on a tree.
Why don't you let
one of the kids handle him?
There's no fun
in the Walter Druckers of the world.
Fun?
Mr. Bring-them-back-alive
wants a big fun-fix.
If I may quote
the immortal Olivia Newton-John:
"Have you never been mellow?"
I know what you can do.
You can fill out mileage reports.
Justify all the money
I am giving you for gasoline.
Will you do that for me?
I asked you a question.
And I didn't give you an answer.
So, you can do Walter Drucker.
"Hell, no. That's no fun."
You could fill out mileage eports.
"Hell, no. That's too much like a real job."
You can jump on Mary Ellen Chesbro:
The beautiful court stenographer who's
been mooning over you for two years.
"Hell, no. She might get her hooks in me."
Come on, Tommy!
Do Walter Drucker.
For once in your life, be reasonable.
I tried that once. I didn't like it.
How's that baby?
I had to leave her with my sister
over in Nevada.
Sure was sorry to hear about the arrest.
Are they gonna take the baby away?
I mean, after they find you guilty and all?
I don't know, Mr. Barton.
Sure is a fine machine.
Every boy's dream. A pink Cadillac.
You know what Elvis said.
Roy never drove this thing.
Never even had the top down.
And you ask me
why I never get any sun on my face.
I don't mean to interfere...
in your marriage...
but it's dangerous
messing around with a man's vehicles.
You're right about that, Mr. Barton.
Very right.
Come back here, damn it!
What are you going to do now?
Or you can explain it to Alex.
He'll pass judgment.
Yeah, okay.
But I'm worn out.
Don't you have any speed?
Diet pills? What the hell am I supposed
to do with supermarket diet pills?
You can gobble the whole box
as far as I'm concerned.
I'm not gonna waste good crystal
on you now.
Maybe if you find Lou Ann.
Hell of an escape, Lou Ann.
You are about the palest thing.
Obviously a hardened criminal,
I can tell by the Kewpie bow lips.
Who cares about her lips? She walked out
on a bond of $25,000. She's a fugitive.
You want her or not?
For me it's all the same.
I want her. You got a priors on her?
Her old man has all the priors,
but I didn't post bond for the old man.
Did they run together by any chance?
Actually, you might have competition
from the hubby.
She's more scared of him
than she is of the law.
Why's that?
He's involved with that gang of ex-cons,
you know, the Birthright.
Birthright?
No, Buddy. I want you to understand me.
Watch the rhythmic movement
of my lips as I tell you...
- I'm not going to take this assignment.
- Come on, I need you.
Do you know what I was saying
to somebody yesterday?
I swear I said, "Tommy Nowak...
"he can track down a shadow
in the middle of the night."
I happen to track fugitives, Buddy.
I don't go around aftr whacked-out
ex-cons that carry automatic weapons.
But I bet those guys
from the Birthright are saying:
"Let's waste this broad
before she turns state's evidence."
I mean, it probably
is the first time in your life...
that you can serve the cause of justice.
Yeah.
What? I happen to love our legal system.
As long as it keeps you
in diamonds and Sonys.
You're saving her by catching her.
So, where are you going to start looking?
It says here she's got a sister
that lives out near Reno.
- Reno?
- Might as well start there.
But watch the mileage, would you?
Stay clear of the Birthright!
Speed and wine!
Give me some of that stuff.
I want that stuff that killed Hank Williams,
I just don't want quite that much.
What are you yelling for, Roy?
Do you think you've earned the right
to have a good time?
No.
What's your problem, Roy?
No problem, Alex.
Tell me.
I don't...
I don't like...
"I don't like seeing Lou Ann out there
in Silhouette City."
I always know
what you're thinking, don't I?
Yeah.
Go ahead. Take it down.
Go ahead.
Stop!
Turn around.
Do you trust me?
Yes, sir.
Go stand in your wife's picture.
Now, here's the point.
I need at least a dozen more
full automatic weapons...
to start building the arsenal of my dreams.
The arsenal of our dreams.
Yeah.
But our weapons budget,
our communications budget...
just about our whole budget
is driving around in the desert...
with your wife.
Now, are you man enough
to go get it back?
- Yes, sir, I am.
- Good.
I thought so.
Waycross, why don't you go help him out?
- What should I do about...
- The female?
Use your best judgment.
Look at this gorgeous girl.
If this cash was genuine, I'd have
your Harvard education all paid for.
$253,000.
That'd just about do it.
This sure does look real.
Why don't you cut loose this one time?
Take this play money into Reno
and give yourself a weekend on the town.
What are you talking about?
I just got here.
Lou Ann, honey, you're a fugitive.
We figured, if anybody comes after you,
this might be their first stop.
It's best we scater for a while
until this thing blows over.
We'll take the baby to my folks' house.
She'll be safe there.
You just go on in to Reno.
Have yourself a good time.
And get some sun while you're at it.
Bye, baby. I love you. Yes.
- Everything's gonna be all right.
- We'll see you in a couple of days.
Bye.
Bye, honey. I love you. Don't forget me.
You seen a blonde in a pink Cadillac?
Only in my dreams.
Pack them.
Aren't you gonna treat yourself
to some new clothes?
We mustn't let our babies
get more glamorous than us.
Maybe just one dress.
Ring these up.
I'm going to show her to ladies' wear.
- And the shoe department.
- Good.
I'll go! Give me the dice while I'm hot.
Let's go again.
Coming up. Eight!
- Okay, give me the dice.
- Your skin is soft.
Fellow, leave the lady alone.
Leave me alone while I'm holding the dice.
Give me those dice. Okay!
You can't do it.
I'm going to double it!
Seven, out.
Oh, no. I lost.
Your skin...
it is so soft. Like Velveeta.
You know Velveeta?
Yeah. You think my skin
looks like processed cheese.
May I see you for a moment?
Right this way. Thank you.
Sit down over here, Mrs. McGuinn.
Somebody got you some nice threads,
didn't they?
Recognize this woman?
She looks familiar.
Like someone who never really
got a break.
Someone who might go crazy for a day.
I wouldn't judge her.
You're a cop?
Not exactly.
What do you mean, not exactly?
Who the hell are you?
I'm a skip tracer.
I work for the bail bondsman
who put up your bond.
Why didn't you have your husband
and his friends put up the money?
If you're taking me back, let's get going.
I can't take much more
of this Elvis tribute.
If you don't mind me saying,
you look dressed to kill tonight.
I'm dressed to torture, killing's too good.
Could you hold that a second?
My purse!
You creep! Just give me back my...
Thanks.
I got a warrant for that woman.
Here's fine.
Didn't think anyone
could run that fast in heels.
Tina Turner taught me.
Look, mister, I got an 8-month-old baby...
I don't even want to hear about it.
I'm just a delivery boy.
Where are the handcuffs?
Yo're not gonna handcuff me? Aren't you
into the whole bondage part of the job?
Lady, I don't even like starch in my collars.
You wouldn't take bail money
from the Birthright...
but you managed to spend some
of that counterfeit cash around town.
It's not so complicated.
I had the whole thing figured out.
It's for my daughter.
I was going to take a little bit
of the make-believe money...
and win a lot of the real money...
at the tables.
It's dumb.
It sounds like
one of my husband's great ideas.
He sounds really swift.
How'd you get tied up with him
in the first place?
Believe it or not, Roy was the coolest boy
in San Bernardino...
about 40,000 Heinekens ago.
He said I was marrying James Dean.
I ended up with an amphetamine junkie.
You don't know how many women I talk to
who tell the same story.
Look...
I have $250,000
of very high-quality counterfeit cash...
Forget it. I wouldn't take it if it was real.
Shut up and listen to me.
I didn't mean it that way.
- You didn't?
- I didn't mean it that way.
I thought that if I gave the money
to the cops, they might go easy on me.
We could go back and pick it up.
Helping you with your legal case
is absolutely none of my business.
My job is just to follow you, find you...
and Federal Express you back home.
The three F's?
I could use a little help.
This is so wrong.
Stand aside.
It makes a really good hiding place.
It kind of reminds you of going
to the drive-in movie, doesn't it?
Parking in the woods...
listening to the crickets off in the distance.
- The howling of the wolves...
- Will you shut up?
The baying of the dogs.
You just have to play
that little-girl-lost routine, don't you?
"I'm just a fugitive felon.
"That doesn't mean I'm not feminine.
"I just need a strong man to help me.
"I guess that makes me
like a Cosmo fugitive."
Buddy. Look, I asked you for a favor.
You said okay.
You don't have to go making fun of me.
I'm through taking shit from men.
That's one thing we have in common.
Because I'm through
taking shit from men, too.
It's a little late
to try to head out to Sacramento now.
Come on in. Make yourself comfortable.
Those are gone.
Put your sack down. Take a load off.
Buddy? It's me, in Reno.
I haven't found her yt.
I've got the scent, though.
I'll probably find her tomorrow
or the next day.
Will you forget about the mileage?
I'm tired of talking about mileage.
I'll call you in the morning
no matter what happens.
Why did you lie?
It just seemed easier
than explaining things.
Would you care for something
from our complimentary mini-bar?
Yeah.
I forgot that's the way it is
with these joints.
They get you half in the bag,
and you forget how to play the game.
Maybe one Cuervo. Just a short one.
We'll keep the drapes open,
so it won't get too dark in here.
What's the matter? Are you nervous?
Are your palms all sweaty?
Can you help me with my zipper?
Thanks.
Going somewhere?
I was just getting a glass of water.
I have a little gas.
Feel good?
Thank you.
Look at these little jellies.
No, it's mine.
It's mine. That's for the bill.
That's for you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I'm a big tipper.
- Let's look at some of this play dough.
- No.
I have had no trouble
spending any of that money.
- I can see why. It's real.
- It can't be.
It's real.
- How do you know?
- I just know.
I think these guys
must have come across...
high-grade counterfeit money. They've
been exchanging it for the real stuff.
The money in your trailer
was probably the last of the fake stuff.
This is Grade A, U.S. Government green.
You mean...
I've been running around...
with $250,000...
in real money?
Yep.
Birthright money?
Oh, God.
What's going to happen to me?
What's going to happen to my baby?
I've got a job to do.
We better hit the road.
America for Americans!
Did you get the female?
What about the money?
You two have put me
on a very low-budget level.
Now, I tried to have some pamphlets
made up cheaply.
Waycross, why don't you come up here
and take a look at this?
"Niggers," blah, blah, blah...
"Spics, gooks taking our jobs."
Blah, blah, blah.
"Conspiracy of the Jews."
- It's not very good.
- Why don't you tell everyone why?
Well, first of all, the printing stinks.
I mean, "niggers" is all blurred...
and now and here you got "Jews"
runnng off into the margin.
You got that right.
- You think that's funny?
- I mean...
Imagine...
trying to recruit new members
with amateurish crap like this.
There's no way, Alex.
You are going to Silhouette City.
All right!
He's a warrior.
Good.
Now I feel some unity.
Now I feel some power.
Not just a bunch of small-time car thieves,
penny ante codeine junkies...
wife beaters,
drifters without a clue in this world...
but warriors.
Ready to seize everything
that's been denied them.
Why don't you go back
to that sister's house and wait?
I guarantee you, within five days
we will have all our money back.
And we will deal with the female.
You see that? That's God.
God caused that flat tire.
He doesn't want you to take me back.
- God's into blowing tires now?
- Yes.
I'm just asking for two more days.
We can go to my sister's house
and I can see my baby again.
Don't you know
I've already gone clinically insane?
Taking you back here to get the money,
interfering with your case.
Ever since I met you,
I've been breaking the law.
What the hell is the law anyway?
The same people who make the law,
break the law every day.
I am not talking about their law,
I am talking about my law.
Fine!
Then follow your own law.
What do you mean the trail went cold?
Tom, you're too good,
I'm having serious trouble with this.
Wait, don't hang up. All right.
Since you've driven all the way to Reno,
Nevada, you might as well do Jack Bass.
We got a tip that he's been
hanging around Harrah's lately.
Yeah.
Okay.
Wait, Tom.
Do you know what
cherchez la femme means?
It's French for dig up the broad,
already. Okay?
I've always admired your way
with a Continental phrase.
I've got a new case. A real mean dude.
What the hell am I going to do with you?
Take me along. Maybe I can help.
Oh, God. Give me a break.
Too much raw dude for you, babe?
I can dig it.
If my life were a movie,
there'd be a sign on it saying:
"Caution: Some scenes too intense
for younger viewers."
Okay.
Let's say this act of yours works
and you catch this Bass character.
- We catch this bastard, doll face.
- Yeah.
We catch him. What did he do, anyhow?
He stabbed a dealer down in Vegas.
Imagined he was cheating him,
and went crazy with a 10-inch blade.
Where are we gonna try and catch him?
I hear he's been hanging around Harrah's
the last few nights.
What'll you do when you catch him?
I'm gonna apprehend him.
Turn him over to the local authorities.
Without getting to know
anything about him.
Nothing about his personal life.
I don't want to know about his brother,
his mother, his sister...
I don't want to know
about the family pets...
the pet parakeet, the dog, the cat.
I don't want to know diddly-shit.
Wait for my signal.
And remember your line.
Hello, Jack. I'm Miss Reno Casino.
This is where you want to be. Big jackpot.
Big payoffs.
Come on in and try your luck.
This is where you want to be.
If you feel lucky,
this is where you want to play...
because the action never stops.
Come on in.
What do you think?
Looks like a penis, only smaller.
If you're feeling lucky,
this is the place to be.
Because the action never stops.
If you're hungry, step right up,
come in and try one of our restaurants.
This is it, folks. This is the place
you want to be. Big payoffs.
Here he is, Mr. Hassleback.
Our one-millionth customer.
What a fine specimen of a man he is, too.
Yes, Mr. Lucky One Million.
Sorry we don't have
a brass band for you, Mr...
- Jack Bass.
No brass for Mr. Bass.