[ Artillery Firing,
Targets Being Hit ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Mumbling ]
[ Yoda Narrating ]
LIKE FIRE ACROSS THE GALAXY,
THE CLONE WAR SPREAD.
[ Yoda Narrating ]
IN LEAGUE WITH
THE WICKED COUNT DOOKU,
MORE AND MORE PLANETS SLIP.
[ Yoda Narrating ]
AGAINST THIS THREAT
UPON THE JEDI KNIGHTS...
FALLS THE DUTY
TO LEAD THE NEWLY FORMED
ARMY OF THE REPUBLIC.
AND AS THE HEAT OF WAR GROWS,
SO TOO GROWS THE PROWESS...
OF ONE MOST GIFTED STUDENT
OF THE FORCE.
THE BANKING CLAN
HAS HIDDEN HUGE FACTORIES
ON MUUNILIST,
BUILDING HUGE DROID ARMIES
AND MASSIVE WARSHIPS.
- WE MUST ACT QUICKLY.
- I AGREE.
BUT WHO TO SEND?
MASTER WINDU STILL FIGHTS
ON DANTOOINE.
LEAD THE ASSAULT
MASTER OBI-WAN CAN.
MY ARMY
IS READY, CHANCELLOR.
WE CAN LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
YES, AND YOUNG SKYWALKER
AS WELL.
I SUGGEST THAT WE GIVE HIM
SPECIAL COMMAND
OF YOUR SPACE FORCES.
HIS EXCEPTIONAL SKILL
WILL BE QUITE USEFUL.
CHANCELLOR, I FEEL
THAT PADAWAN ANAKIN...
IS NOT YET READY
FOR SUCH RESPONSIBILITY.
TRUE. WITH HIS MASTER
A PADAWAN'S PLACE IS.
BUT UNDENIABLY STRONG
HE HAS BECOME. PERHAPS--
THEN IT IS DECIDED.
[ Thinking ] I DOUBT
EVEN MASTER QUI-GON COULD HAVE
PREPARED A JEDI FOR THIS.
[ Beeping ]
ARC TROOPERS, YOU HAVE BEEN
SELECTED FOR THIS TASK BECAUSE
YOU ARE THE BEST, THE ELITE.
YOU ALL KNOW WHAT TO DO.
THE SUCCESS OF YOUR MISSION
IS OUR KEY TO A SWIFT VICTORY.
WHEN YOU GET INTO POSITION,
SEND WORD, AS PLANNED,
THEN I WILL JOIN YOU.
MASTER, I KNOW
YOU DON'T THINK I'M READY
FOR A COMMAND OF MY OWN,
BUT I AM THE BEST PILOT
IN THE ORDER.
CHANCELLOR PALPATINE KNOWS IT.
I DON'T KNOW WHY YOU CAN'T--
PADAWAN, YOUR SKILLS
HAVE NEVER BEEN IN QUESTION.
IT IS YOUR MATURITY.
I'VE ARGUED THIS BEFORE.
BUT THE DECISION HAS BEEN MADE.
MAY THE FORCE BE WITH YOU,
COMMANDER.
ALL SQUADRONS TO ME.
ARC TROOPERS, DEPLOY!
YES, SIR.
EVASIVE ACTION!
[ Explosions ]
ROGER, ROGER.
[ Camera Lens Whirs ]
[ Chittering ]
- [ Gun Cocked ]
-[ Vehicle Approaching ]
[ Wavering Sound ]
GENERAL KENOBI,
TARGET SIGHTED.
VERY GOOD, SERGEANT.
PROCEED WITH THE NEXT PHASE.
[ Yoda Narrating ]
TROUBLED IS THE PLANET
MON CALAMARI.
ITS RACES HAVE DIVIDED.
THE DROID ARMY OF
THE QUARREN ISOLATION LEAGUE...
MOVES AGAINST
THE CALAMARI COUNCIL.
ALONE, THE CALAMARI
ARE NO MATCH.
INTERVENE WE MUST.
MASTER FISTO,
IN THESE MATTERS,
TRUST YOUR INSIGHT WE DO.
MAY THE FORCE BE WITH YOU.
[ Blowing On Conch Shell ]
[ Explosion ]
[ Distant Explosions ]
THOSE GUNS ARE DESTROYING
OUR FORWARD POSITIONS.
THE REPUBLIC
IS BREAKING THROUGH.
[ Rumbling ]
[ Rumbling Stops ]
SIR, OUR CANNON
AT THE BASE OF THE TOWER
HAS BEEN DESTROYED.
THEIR RANGE IS GREATER
THAN WE THOUGHT.
IT MUST BE THEIR ARTILLERY.
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
I DON'T KNOW WHY DOOKU
SENT YOU HERE IF ALL YOU'RE
GOING TO DO IS STAND AROU--
[ Chokes ]
I MEAN,
WHENEVER YOU'RE READY.
[ Growls ]
[ Roars ]
- [ Screeches ]
- [ Roars ]
[ Speaking Foreign Language ]
INDEED.
[ Roars ]
[ Speaking Foreign Language ]
[ Clanging,
Commotion Continues ]
IMPRESSIVE.
YOU MASK YOUR PRESENCE WELL.
FLAWLESS TIMING.
PERFECT CONTROL.
YOU HAVE GREAT SKILL
OF INFILTRATION.
MY HOST WOULD APPLAUD
YOUR ABILITIES
POSTHUMOUSLY.
HOWEVER,
I AM NOT LOOKING
FOR A SPY.
[ Roars ]
[ Growls ]
YOU ARE MORE POWERFUL
THAN I HAD SENSED.
THE DARK SIDE
IS STRONG IN ME.
FOR I AM SITH.
[ Laughs ]
A BOLD CLAIM.
BUT YOU ARE NOT SITH.
YOU WEAR THE TRAPPINGS
OF THE SITH,
YOU FIGHT LIKE THE SITH,
BUT THIS CAN BE
IMITATED, HOWEVER.
YOU LACK A VITAL QUALITY
FOUND IN ALL SITH.
SITH HAVE NO FEAR.
AND I SENSE MUCH FEAR
IN YOU.
YOU ARE A FOOLISH OLD MAN
WHO KNOWS NOTHING
OF THE DARK SIDE.
[ Laughs ]
INDEED.
[ Wind Whistling ]
TRULY IF YOU WERE SITH,
WOULD THIS CONTEST
BE NOT OVER?
[ Yells ]
IT WOULD NOT BE SO EASY
TO DEFEAT A SITH.
SO FINISH IT.
WE HAVE OTHER PLANS.
HAVE YOU BEEN
WATCHING, MASTER?
I HAVE INDEED,
LORD TYRANUS.
THE CHILD'S SKILL
WITH A LIGHTSABER
ARE MOST IMPRESSIVE.
YOU HAVE FOUND
A PROMISING DISCIPLE,
MY APPRENTICE.
SHE SHALL SERVE US WELL.
I AM HONORED.
LET ME INTRODUCE
MY MASTER,
THE TRUE LORD
OF THE SITH,
DARTH SIDIOUS.
WHAT IS YOUR BIDDING?
A JEDI NAMED
ANAKIN SKYWALKER.
YOU WILL FIND HIM FOR US
AND ELIMINATE HIM.
JEDI. THEIR ORDER
IS A FADING LIGHT
IN THE DARK.
CORRUPT AND ARROGANT.
THEY MUST BE PUNISHED.
THE JEDI SHALL FALL!
CONSIDER THIS A GIFT.
SHE WILL BE
MORE THAN A MATCH
FOR YOUNG SKYWALKER.
IT MATTERS NOT.
SHE IS MERELY AN INSTRUMENT...
TO BRING FORTH
THE ERADICATION OF THE JEDI.
GENERAL KENOBI,
OUR CANNONS ARE BEING DESTROYED.
[ Camera Lens Whirs ]
MOUNT UP.
YES, SIR.
[ Laughing ]
GENERAL KENOBI,
WE ARE IN POSITION.
I'M ON MY WAY.
WE'RE SET, GENERAL.
VERY WELL.
LET'S END THIS BATTLE,
COMMANDER.
[ Artillery Fire ]
-[ Sergeant ] GENERAL.
- MERCY, I BEG YOU.
I AM MERELY A BANKER.
THAT IS ENTIRELY UP TO YOU
AND YOUR UNCONDITIONAL
SURRENDER.
[ Creature Approaching ]
CONTROL ROOM SECURE, GENERAL.
ONE CAN NEVER BE
TOO SURE, COMMANDER.
[ Roars ]
[ Groans ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
GENERAL,
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
I'M FINE.
SEEMS I'VE CREATED
QUITE THE MESS NOW.
HAVEN'T I?
YES, SIR.
[ Whimpering ]
[ Obi-Wan ]
NOW, WHERE WERE WE?
AH, YES.
I BELIEVE
YOU WERE SURRENDERING.
[ Troopers Marching ]
[ Beeping ]
WE LOST GOLD LEADER.
COMMANDER,
ENEMY REINFORCEMENTS
COMING IN .35.
[ Anakin ]
CLEAR OUT, GOLD 2,
I'M COMING IN.
R4, SWITCH ALL POWER
TO FORWARD SHIELDS.
[ Beeping ]
- [ Beeping ]
- I KNOW. I KNOW.
RED LEADER,
FIRE ALL YOUR MISSILES
ACROSS THE BOW OF CRUISER 8.
BUT, COMMANDER,
THERE'S NOTHING OUT THERE.
-NO TARGETS.
- DO IT NOW, TROOPER!
[ Beeping ]
COMMANDER SKYWALKER,
ALMOST ALL THE GUN PLATFORMS
ARE DESTROYED AND ONLY--
WAIT. WHAT'S THAT?
COMMANDER, WE JUST LOST
BLUE SQUADRON.
A ROGUE FIGHTER HAS--
I SEE IT.
MOP UP
THE FIGHTERS AS PLANNED.
THIS ONE'S MINE.
[ Beeping ]
GOT YOU.
I HAVE YOU NOW.
- [ Beeping ]
- INCREASE POWER
TO THE THRUSTERS, R4.
THIS IS NO DROID PILOT.
[ Beeping ]
COME ON.
WHAT WAS THAT?
I DON'T KNOW, GENERAL.
THAT'S NOT ONE OF OURS.
NO, GENERAL.
THAT WAS ANAKIN.
YES, GENERAL.
- ANAKIN!
- IT'S UNDER CONTROL, MASTER.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO BE IN SPACE,
LEADING OUR FORCES.
IT'S UNDER CONTROL.
UNDER CONTROL?
I DON'T THINK SO.
YOUR PLACE IS
WITH YOUR SQUADRONS,
YOUNG ONE, NOT--
NOT CHASING ONE SHIP
THROUGH THE CITY STREETS.
MASTER, THIS IS
NO DROID PILOT.
AND THE FORCE IS WITH HIM.
I CAN'T LET HIM GET AWAY.
ANAKIN, I'M ALSO SENSING
SOMETHING STRANGE.
BUT YOU MUST
LET THAT SHIP GO.
IT'S BAITING YOU.
- [ Beeping ]
- JUMPING INTO HYPERSPACE?
YOU HAVE HIS COORDINATES?
[ R4 Beeping ]
THEN PLUG THEM IN.
HE'S NOT LOSING US.
[ Obi-Wan ] ANAKIN.
MASTER, THE BATTLE UP HERE
IS MORE THAN WON.
I CAN HANDLE THIS.
DO NOT FOLLOW THAT SHIP.
ANAKIN, DO YOU HEAR ME?
DO NOT FOLLOW THAT SHIP!
THAT IS AN ORDER! ANAKIN!
SORRY, SIR.
YOUR SIGNAL IS BREAKING UP.
PADAWAN, IF YOU--
YOU HAVE THE COORDINATES?
YES, GENERAL.
TAKE A SQUAD
AND FOLLOW HIM.
I'VE GOT A BAD FEELING
ABOUT THIS.
[ Explosions ]
[ Spaceship Approaching ]
FIRE AT WILL.
ROGER, ROGER.
RECHARGE ACCELERATORS.
- FIRE.
- ROGER, ROGER.
[ Alarm Blaring ]
INTERNAL EXPLOSIONS
ALL OVER.
WE ARE LOSING CONTROL.
WHAT?
[ Electronic Twittering ]
THE CRYSTAL IS
THE HEART OF THE BLADE.
THE HEART IS
THE CRYSTAL OF THE JEDI.
THE JEDI IS THE CRYSTAL
OF THE FORCE.
THE FORCE IS THE BLADE
OF THE HEART.
ALL ARE INTERTWINED.
THE CRYSTAL,
THE BLADE,
THE JEDI.
YOU ARE ONE.
YOU HAVE TAUGHT ME WELL,
MASTER LUMINARA.
REMEMBER ALWAYS,
THE CRYSTAL IS
THE HEART OF THE BLADE.
BARRISS OFFEE,
YOUR TRAINING
IS COMPLETE.
SOMETHING TRESPASSES
ON SACRED GROUND.
THE TEMPLE IS BREACHED.
[ Beeping ]
[ Electronic Twitter ]
I SENSE A PRESENCE,
YET SEE NOTHING.
THEY ARE HERE.
[ Rapid Beeping ]
HMM.
TO ILUM WE MUST GO.
ABSOLUTELY NOT.
YOU CANNOT RISK
THE SENATOR'S LIFE LIKE THIS.
MILADY, I MUST PROTEST.
HMM. VERY LITTLE TIME
THERE IS, SENATOR.
OUR ONLY HOPE
TO RESCUE JEDI.
TO ILUM WE MUST GO NOW.
THIS IS NOT A RESCUE SHIP.
MAY I REMIND OUR MASTER JEDI
WE HAVE A MORE PRESSING MISSION?
A SLIGHT DETOUR.
JEOPARDIZE THE MISSION...
IT WILL NOT.
A SLIGHT DETOUR.
JEOPARDIZE THE MISSION
IT WILL NOT.
BE PUT IN DANGER
THE SENATOR WILL NOT.
SAVE THE LIVES OF JEDI
WE MUST.
MASTER YODA,
I AM CONVINCED.
I WILL NOT REQUIRE
MY CAPTAIN'S FURTHER...
PERSUASION.
HUH?
HMM.
CAPTAIN. MAKE BEST
POSSIBLE SPEED TO ILUM.
YES, MILADY.
ILUM? THAT PLANET IS ON
THE OTHER SIDE OF THE SYSTEM.
[ Beeping ]
A SLIGHT DETOUR?
WELL, ACTUALLY, I DON'T HAVE
A MORE IMPORTANT PLACE TO BE.
STAY ON THE SHIP YOU MUST.
MUCH DANGER I SENSE.
MASTER YODA, I CAN'T
LET YOU GO OFF TO ATTEMPT
A RESCUE MISSION ALONE.
YET ALONE I MUST BE
FOR THE RESCUE TO SUCCEED.
CALL YOU I WILL
IF ASSISTANCE I REQUIRE.
[ Electronic Twittering ]
I HAVE A BAD FEELING
ABOUT THIS.
MASTER YODA HAS BEEN GONE
FAR TOO LONG.
I SHOULD HAVE NEVER
LET HIM GO ALONE.
HE'S A JEDI MASTER, MILADY.
HE'S QUITE CAPABLE OF HANDLING
WHATEVER MAY BE OUT THERE.
MASTER YODA DID ASSURE YOU
HE WOULD CONTACT YOU
IF HE REQUIRED HELP.
[ Beeping ]
TRAVELING ALONE IN A BLIZZARD
ON AN UNCHARTED PLANET
IS COMMONPLACE FOR A JEDI,
BUT NOT A SENATOR, HMM.
MISS PADMEÉÉ IS SAFER
WHERE SHE IS.
[ Beeping ]
3PO IS RIGHT, R2.
I'LL RUN A DIAGNOSTIC
ON THE COMMUNICATION ARRAY.
THIS WEATHER
HAS BEEN GIVING US
SOME LOW-BAND INTERFERENCE.
R2, DOES THIS WEATHER
AFFECT YOUR SENSORS?
[ Beeping ]
NOT IN THE SLIGHTEST.
OR SO HE SAYS.
GOOD. I'M GOING TO
LOOK FOR MASTER YODA.
- ALONE?
- NO. YOU TWO WILL ACCOMPANY ME.
[ Beeps ]
OH, DEAR.
WHAT IS IT, R2?
[ Beeping ]
OH. IT SEEMS THERE ARE
MULTIPLE OBJECTS APPROACHING
FROM THAT DIRECTION.
WHERE?
AMBUSH! I KNEW
THIS WAS A BAD IDEA!
[ C-3PO Gasping, Yelps ]
- GOTCHA.
- [ Beeping ]
R2 SAYS THERE ARE
TWO MORE STILL OUT THERE.
TWO MORE?
UH, 3PO, COULD YOU
GET MY COAT?
OF COURSE, MISS PADMEÉÉ.
OH! OH! OH!
I MUST BE
OUT OF MY CIRCUIT.
OH! OH!
[ Electronic Twittering ]
HELP! HELP!
I'VE BEEN BURIED ALIVE!
THANKS, 3PO.
OH, UH, IT WAS A PLEASURE,
MISS PADMEÉÉ.
[ Beeping ]
WHAT IS IT, R2?
MORE DROIDS?
MORE? OH, NO!
MASTER YODA!
I'M SO GLAD
YOU'RE ALL RIGHT.
SUCCESSFUL MY MISSION WAS.
SAFE THE JEDI ARE.
BUT PAIN MY HEART IS.
WHAT TROUBLES YOU,
MASTER YODA?
NEARLY DESTROYED THE TEMPLE WAS.
REVEALED ITS SECRET LOCATION IS.
BUT BY WHO I KNOW NOT.
YOU WILL FIND
THE TEMPLE ON ILUM.
DESTROY IT.
DOOKU.
[ Anakin ]
DO YOU HAVE HIS POSITION?
[ R4 Beeps ]
THAT'S CLOSE ENOUGH, R4.
WE'LL JUST HAVE TO SEARCH
THE IMMEDIATE AREA ON FOOT.
[ Beeps ]
WATCH THE SHIP, R4.
THIS WON'T TAKE LONG.
[ Animals Chittering,
Squawking ]
[ Loud Rumble ]
HUT, HUT, HUT,
HUT, HUT, HUT!
SECURE THE AREA.
SERGEANT.
COMMANDER SKYWALKER.
OBI-WAN?
YES, SIR.
GAVE YOU ORDERS
TO FOLLOW ME.
YES, SIR.
FINE. HAVE SOME MEN
PROTECT THE SHIPS.
THE REST ENCIRCLE THE CLEARING.
PREPARE TO SWEEP THE JUNGLE.
[ Rumbling ]
[ Rumbling Continues ]
[ Animals Chittering,
Squawking ]
OH!
SOMETHING'S NOT RIGHT.
I CAN FEEL IT.
[ Animals Chittering,
Squawking ]
[ Screaming ]
TROOPER?
- TROOPER?
- [ Groaning ]
TROOPER, ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHAT HAPPENED?
- R4!
- [ Beeping ]
I'M GOING TO MAKE YOU PAY
FOR WHAT YOU'VE DONE.
COME, PADAWAN.
YOUR FALL WILL BE
MY ASCENSION TO THE SITH.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Sizzles ]
[ Sizzling ]
[ Lightsaber Unsheathes ]
[ Water Dripping ]
[ Bone Snaps ]
[ Yells ]
[ Screams ]
[ Yell Echoes ]
BLAST HIM.
[ Obi-Wan ]
THE I.G. BANKING CLAN HAS
SURRENDERED. THE DAY IS OURS.
THE REPUBLIC IS VICTORIOUS.
[ Cheering ]
GENERAL KENOBI,
A SHIP IS APPROACHING...
THAT MATCHES THE ONE
COMMANDER SKYWALKER
FOLLOWED INTO HYPERSPACE.
I HAVE BATTERIES STANDING BY.
HOLD YOUR FIRE,
CAPTAIN.
COMMANDER SKYWALKER!
I'M SORRY, MASTER.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
IT WAS A TRAP--
LAID OUT BY THE SITH.
AND I RAN HEADLONG INTO IT.
BUT I EMERGED VICTORIOUS.
INDEED.
BUT THAT BATTLE SHOULD NEVER
HAVE BEEN FOUGHT.
I FIND THE SITH'S INTEREST
IN YOU MOST TROUBLESOME.
THIS IS PRECISELY WHY
YOU MUST FOLLOW MY ORDERS,
YOUNG ONE.
ANOTHER DEFIANCE
COULD LEAD US INTO A DAN--
[ Beeping ]
GENERAL KENOBI!
YES, MASTER BARREK.
NEED IMMEDIATE EVAC
FROM PLANET HYPORI!
OUR FORCES ARE
TOTALLY DESTROYED.
ONLY--
ONLY A FEW OF US LEFT.
NEW DROID GENERAL.
HE'S UNSTOPPABLE.
CAN'T HOLD OUT FOR LONG.
GENERAL GRIEVOUS IS HUNTING US.
MUST HURRY!
MASTER BARREK, COME IN.
COME IN.
MASTER BARREK!
COME IN!
[ Metal Creaking ]
WHY HAVE THEY STOPPED?
[ Man ]
MASTER?
GO. GO.
[ Grunting ]
UNSTOPPABLE.
HE IS UNSTOPPABLE.
NEVER HAVE WE BEEN
OUTMANEUVERED BY DROIDS.
HIS STRATEGY
IS WITHOUT FLAW.
THIS IS THE END.
WE'RE ALL DOOMED.
OUR PREDICAMENT IS DIRE,
BUT DO NOT DESPAIR.
FOCUS. WE ARE JEDI.
MMM.
[ Grievous ]
JEDI.
YOU ARE SURROUNDED.
YOUR ARMY IS DECIMATED.
MAKE PEACE WITH THE FORCE NOW,
FOR THIS IS YOUR FINAL HOUR.
BUT KNOW THAT I,
GENERAL GRIEVOUS,
AM NOT COMPLETELY WITHOUT MERCY.
I WILL GRANT YOU
A WARRIOR'S DEATH. PREPARE.
[ Droid Motor Whirring ]
[ Droid Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Man ]
I CAN'T SEE ANYTHING.
[ Droid Footsteps Approaching ]
THAT NOISE.
HE IS COMING ALONE.
- WE CAN'T FACE HIM.
- WE MUST TRY, PADAWAN.
[ Footsteps Continue
Approaching ]
IT'S CLOSE, BUT WHERE?
IT'S ALL AROUND US.
CALM YOURSELF.
[ Footsteps Continue
Approaching ]
STEADY.
[ Screams ]
NO!
GET BACK.
KI-ADI.
HURRY.
[ Yelps ]
NO. SHAAK TI.
HMM.
DARKER THE COMING STORM
GROWS, I FEAR.
THE DARK CLOUD OF THE SITH
SHROUDS US ALL.
[ Lightsaber Unsheathes, Hums ]
[ Bongo Drums,
Bullet Ricochets ]