Mum TiVo eating my underwear.
There is no evidence
for its accusations.
Gillian, your son is Sysco.
He  booby trap my hairdryer.
Nice hypothesis
but you cannot prove.
No, but I can hurt you.
- Mum.
They need medical care.
Come on TiVo
- Come here.
I hate this family.
Come here.
TiVo you getting time out!
Come on, guys.
Backpack.
What It is in style.
- It is Inappropriate.
Go Put some a jeans.
And spit out the gum .
So What colour do you wear today?
Red, blue, purple...?
- Pink Mum Pink
Farren.
What You said jeans.
I meant in your size.
Come on, guys.
-Come on we don't want to be late.
Come on, Sweaty.
No, get out.
Not fighting.
Allow me.
- Hi.
Hi.
Are we still on for dinner?
- I'll be there.
We have audience.
owe Yaq aim goanna vomit.
- He is such a loser.
I may like Bob, he is nice.
- It is a dull pen importer.
It is same routine Every day .
He Like a robot.
I think He is robot .A cyborg.
In the future it destroys humanity.
Starting with us.
Already three months.
Happy anniversary
What is that?
I have to tell you about my job.
This may chock you...
but you know everything
Before this relationship goes fader.
Do not, Bob.
- Why?
I am very happy when I with you.
Nobody let me laugh like you do.
And if I was single, women
I get  serious future for us.
but my package deal
What do you mean?
My kids are my priority and
How I can put this gently.
They hate me.
- Yes.
I can make them like me.
ooh see you can make kids like you
not mine or any ones
My kids has been though a lot and
I don’t think we should take next the step
until they warm up to you .
Does not your happiness count?
Excuse me.
Sorry, I got to go.
Emergency at work.
No ink?
- Much bigger.
sorry Really I explain everything tomorrow.
Ok I Well, see you tomorrow.
Why did you take so long?
- Six minutes.
Stopped for a late?
- I get it, what is the expression...
Chopping my bust
- close enough
Poldark and a few other
went just inside the refinery.
I was right.
She plans thing.
Maybe they want to get free gasoline.
No, that is as a villain. That may
eat nails with a corkscrew.
Gilbrough is the main authority
at Poldark. What is he up to?
If his mission to sabotage
the world's oil reserves...
Why he served for
as a small refiner?
I make sure that you can ask him.
How do you get about?
With a jetpack?
We take the 'shark'.
Wait for my signal
Yuri.
What is this?
- C4.
When we Done here
I want to blow up everything.
Quickly, I have not got all day.
There is no over time here.
Bob Ho.
I would like to catch up,
but I got to go.
GO GO Forward.
Stay where you are.
That was fun.
- Great aerobics.
We must do this again.
- Poldark, we go.
You had Poldark his face.
Good job, Bob. Unbelievable.
I do not like to see you leave,
you're the best agent ever.
Hey, count me out.
Maybe I can make
government that you lend your little longer.
No, this was my last assignment.
I retire.
- Still not Gillian?
I want to live. Wedding.
Not married. Take a woman you
over five years hate and give her your house.
Keep watch it.
To compliment the CIA.
Gillian, who is that woman
cover your next home lives?
Yes, they are already as this.
- I never give this life for a woman.
We are spies.
Every boy wants a spy.
It is life. All the hours
you spend in such a small room like this.
Cold food in a surveillance van.
It is all the time on your shot.
Learning to pee in a bottle
in a moving car.
You do it right.
- Any problem, her children hate me.
You rule.
- We miss you, success with the children.
I've shot down dictators,
how difficult three children?
Come on, Ringo. Get down.
Hi, kids.
Sorry about last night.
Never mind, that's your job.
- No, it was rude.
It never happens again, promised.
Mum, what with Ringo?
He'll come down
when he finished.
Want to see I'm working?
- Of course.
Come on, kitty.
It is not as high.
Please?
Please.
What do you think?
It remains to be finished.
But today I could not do anything...
the cat on the roof, satellite breaks down again.
I phoned two hours for a repairman.
And I always think of yesterday.
So...
so good between us?
I understand it, as a man with your
marries, he marries you all four.
Forget the pig,
the cat and the turtle does not.
Do you really nicely?
- Frightening.
You are truly the last honest
man in the world, I sometimes think.
I have cookies.
Yes?
- Are you really married to Bob?
What? Calm down.
- You cannot do, Gillian.
You're so much above him.
- He is boring and a nerd.
He is a very sweet man
who treats me very well.
He is a pen importer.
- He is a cyborg.
You know him like me.
He is very enthusiastic about the world...
and my art. He likes to talk
history, science...
and politics.
- So it is boring.
You call it boring,
I call it reliable.
I also want a man who
every day to work.
And who comes home every night.
Not lying or deceiving...
or who leaves his family and...
My luck also counts.
Old people as hateful feelings.
We need to see Bob working away.
What is the story here?
- Poldark was transported.
He's not escaped?
- He is so taken as can be.
This was one planned.
She knew that he came.
Say you have a mole is?
- No, only that he escaped.
Welcome back.
Get Chad.
You cannot imagine what it is...
the oppressive darkness and
agonizing torture and endless torment.
The prison is a hell.
- You were there four hours.
More than enough.
I need a new path
of the formula. As soon as possible.
In two days we test again.
I have to get dressed.
Something contemporary and fashionable.
And something to eat
that is not a toy.
Yes.
Honey, we make the finished pumpkins.
Are you?
Absolutely, because I'm a loser
and have no life.
Did I mention that we
to roast the pumpkin seeds?
Come on, Join us.
And what I want private.
- Do not be with me.
I do when I want.
- Farren.
I want you down...
- I do not. Way.
This is my house...
- You hold me!
I said outside, Gillian.
Downstairs, in five minutes.
- I hate this house and family. Way!
No, she hears me.
I sit on the roof.
The only place where I is private.
I cannot Gillian
that guy to marry.
No, he is indeed a hen,
but that is not the problem.
What if my dad comes back?
He lets me not only here,
he comes back.
And what if they married?
No idea.
Mum, Ian Devan gives bacon.
That is wrong.
- Why?
Bob Ho.
- Hi.
And how are the kids?
- I go picnicking with them.
I force them to like me.
- Hen force?
You may as well scratch your ear
with your elbow.
Guess. Poldark escaped.
Not my problem.
- I know.
But we have discovered a document.
An international portal to a website.
We have not cracked.
Maybe you see it.
Failing that, great.
If not, nothing wrong.
For you. Send it to my computer at home.
Already happened. Now I think of...
they think there is a mole in the agency.
They suspect me?
- No...
you're the sharpest hook on the wire.
No idea what you say.
Enjoy your picnic.
Call me when you look at that file.
Thank you.
I saw codes. Let's see.
Is it noon already?
- No, bad news.
My father lies in a hospital.
- That is terrible.
He played softball and slipped.
Now, his hip replaced.
Terrible. - I have children
leave to care for father.
Great.
- What?
Let me look at them.
We learn to know each other.
No, you and them?
I do not know.
My aunt flies over San Antonio.
She is very good with children.
She was in the army.
- This is perhaps what we need.
Can you really that busy?
Driving, homework, Halloween.
Their costume complete.
Decorate the house.
- No problem.
Halloween is my favourite.
They are perfectly safe with me.
About them, I am not worried.
That you kidding?
- Are there any other options?
Foster care, juvenile detention?
I love you.
I miss you.
- Yeah, so let us support you.
You survive it.
I buy something.
Bye! We love you.
Is not this great?
I get some things in
and we go to your home.
His computer. Let's see.
- Good idea.
There should be standing up dirt.
Fashion, Armageddon.
I do not remember.
I still see the file.
But this is important...
What is Halloween?
Do you realize what this is?
You excited? Fixed a
dictionary.
You confuse me with a very
different class of nerd.
Stockholm GBH.
Davis Bodily Harm.
Live in Stockholm. One of the
rarest concerts.
Why did Bob die?
- What does it matter?
I get it off.
This is my ticket to coolness.
This should I wear?
You wanted something contemporary.
- Just the First Prince of Belarus.
Let someone get elegant.
What is the problem?
I wanted to pick up the formula
and noticed that someone else had access.
If China has the formula,
they can develop the antimatter.
I urge the Ip address.
But it is really encrypted.
It takes a while.
Find out who my formula
picked and get it back.
And...?
- Kill them.
Thank you.
What is wrong with you?
- I kill you.
What? I you.
Do not hurt me!
She makes me hurt.
Stop, what's going on?
She threw a stink bomb in my room.
- Really not true.
So I threw in my own room?
To give you problems?
Pathetic.
So sad.
Farren, I am very disappointed.
You should be resting.
If we have homework on time,
we may stay up to twelve hours.
She also wants us adult films.
A tradition.
Here I have not thought about.
Nora, time for bed.
I would not go to sleep!
You can never catch.
Coming!
Come back.
I got you. Come back.
Come on.
Mum is just my clothes!
Mum always dresses me.
Is that your mom do that?
Now sleep.
Get Out!
Hello?
- You're alive.
That 's a good sign.
How are the kids?
A great night.
So simple.
Really? You and my kids, right?
Bob, last thing you wanted
about your job...
but I interrupted you.
Would you tell me?
That can wait until you get back.
This was really a good idea, I think.
The worst is definitely behind us.
Please wait.
I al
Fire!
Mistake.
Everything is good.
Almost done.
I sit in front.
- It is not your day.
Can you really go to school
Your mother?
Of course, Bob.
"Sure, Bob.
Bye.
- Have a nice day.
What do you do every day?
- Nothing, I'm lazy.
You're lying.
- Yeah, you're lying.
I picked up yesterday.
Really? Would have been pretty cool.
- Yeah, pretty cool.
Let's hear it then.
That's just a lot of noise.
I do not get it.
- I do. You're pathetic and a liar.
We get him.
Put me down!
Put me down.
- Okay, you asked for it.
You have heard of me,
through a lawyer.
Here do I pay for you all.
Tell me more about Halloween.
That's great. You get sweets,
you're dressed as someone else.
And nobody knows who you are.
That sounds familiar.
What would you be? Frankenstein?
A Zombie?
- Honey, would you a princess?
Well, princess.
No fee. A princess.
Princess.
Pink.
- Pink.
Princess.
- It is too big.
Too big?
Sorry.
You do not walk away.
- I'm sorry.
Let your costume going to pay.
With Ho.
Hold him until I get there.
May I say before we begin
only the current condition of the...
American Public School System
I filed is...
head first, into a bin and I get
then a penalty.
Who are you exactly?
I am his mother...
neighbour.
- Buurman.
I watch him a few days.
This is not the first time Ian
in trouble.
He lost in battle. He is lying.
- I'm not lying.
You've told everyone you Celina Gomez
have been invited to the spring dance.
Her coming to the USA was a problem.
You said that your New Year's Eve
have spent at the Playboy Mansion?
"Pay per view. It felt like I was there.
I tell you, lying is a dangerous game.
You sell pens. What...
Oh, no.
They are.
- Who?
These criminals have future
I put in the trash.
We have received punishment by you.
- Yes, by you.
There you go for pay.
- Gentlemen, we want no trouble.
Who is that. Your mother?
- My bodyguard.
I hired him.
Better watch out.
Is that true?
- No, he makes a joke.
I'm the babysitter.
- What are you doing?
You ask politely if we can through.
You are humiliating.
Why did not you?
Why did you I was your bodyguard?
I think it was too much stress.
How are you? I'm Ian.
You have a beautiful body.
Can I hold it against me?
At least you're not shy.
I wanted in the worst way
talk to her.
Mission accomplished.
Come here.
You look so beautiful.
I did not know you did gymnastics.
- Why?
You know nothing about me.
You go and you talk Gillian
Never us.
Come on.
The woman has a point.
I do not know who you are to send out
my clothes.
I want them killed.
You could even go.
- I'm the most wanted man in America.
I cannot stretch the
JCPenney to sniff.
Give me something that I can mix.
Something extremely American.
We are ready to test.
Beautiful.
She certainly has its plastic shoes.
It eats any petroleum product.
We are working on.
What happened to the bacteria?
- They live as long as they are fed.
If that path, then disappear.
- Just like my Jimmy Choo's.
Come inside.
About today...
- You had me to come.
I have to face come.
- Do it.
Unless you the rest of your life with your head
in the trash will spend.
Thanks for the advice.
All my problems are solved.
Do you get it in the lower?
- No, I read for pleasure.
You're smart.
It you're not so bad.
Why ruin everything?
Girls are not really impressed
of astro physical.
According to the sources I can design a rocket
build and launch a...
really in orbit around the moon would go.
But that cannot other guys.
They throw balls through a ring.
I do not want you any problems.
If you now try the truth
to tell...
tell your mom anything
about your date.
Really. That was almost cool.
For a guy who sells pens?
Come on, kids.
Bedtime.
Come on. Even a spoon.
Just one. That I learned in China
when I was young.
I agree.
I need your help.
I have a lot of fuss to make
to get all this stuff.
What did you say them?
- If I do not know what weapons...
Don, I get problems.
Where did you get this all for?
- In order to get kids ready for school.
As my mother always said,
when they were in East Berlin Sat...
spying is easy, parents are
is difficult. Good luck.
But come on.
You're there all morning.
Let me in there.
Farren, let me in there.
You're there all morning.
Let me in there.
Now it's my turn.
Farren, Daughter
a longer skirt.
This means war.
Stay with Bob.
Where is he?
- He is hiding.
He lets us fall into the trap,
so we open the door.
I will store?
You know the rules.
No soft drinks upstairs.
I just wanted a drink.
Breakfast is served.
Nora, bedtime.
Good night.
Cannot sleep?
- How did you find me?
Call it a gamble.
Why you say 'Gillian' to your mother
instead of Mom?
She is my mother.
- What do you mean?
My father has been married before.
And my mother died when I was little.
Gillian is my stepmother, and Ian and Nora
My half-brother and sister.
I'm the freak of the family.
He must have hurt you
when he left.
He'll come back to me.
I know he is not the world best dad
but he loves me.
And he let me not alone.
You should not climb on the roof,
that is not safe.
Please do not say that I
should not be.
Here I can chill.
I wanted to make a railing.
Are you bribe me so
I like you?
I just want you safe.
Can I chill with you?
- It's a free country.
Look at that star?
Good news. We have an address.
Well, take what men and
get that file back.
No survivors.
Boss, you find that?
Not nice?
May I propose a few fashion?
Women do not like
the shirt is tucked there.
Do you see her through the war.
Do you know anything about fashion?
- No, but I know the women.
Wear it so. That's cool.
I have seen in the film.
What movie? Octopus?
It is not 1985.
That I almost forgot.
- What is that?
Iggy Pop and David Bowie in Shanghai.
That is the greatest concert
of the world.
I guarantee that no school
in this district has.
Have you downloaded this for me?
- No worries, I've paid for.
How do you know this?
- Simple. I was there.
Bob, you are too efficient.
We are half hour early.
You are welcome.
Happy days.
Another cool?
- Thanks again.
Whatever.
Happy days.
That conversation on the roof, does
not that we're friends.
God forbid.
There is none.
I've cracked the computer, but the file
is downloaded to an external device.
I cannot find STATS.
I think I have just discovered
who live here.
Agent Ho.
Stop shooting at things.
I said it really was like the CIA
whether the Chinese had.
But he is both. Find him.
But keep him alive.
I need to know to whom he
This effort has shown.
Listen. Here.
We must find CIA agent.
He is very cunning. The best.
It is not easy to find.
Not now.
Imagine that you're Chinese.
Well trained.
And you want to disappear.
- I see him climbing on the roof with stuff.
He is not Conan the Barbarian.
Good try.
I see him. There.
Hurry.
Get him down.
Kill him not.
We need information.
Come here, sweetie.
Come back.
Here.
Let go.
Can you hold my turtle.
- Not now.
Hold on.
There you pay for.
Again.
Why have you brought us out of school?
- What does it matter. We are Fri
Why are you also on the front seat?
It is my day.
No, it is not.
- It's my day.
You're lying.
- No.
You sit there all of two days in a row.
- Silence.
I'm still hungry.
I do not think they have chicken legs.
Waiting inside.
I need to call.
This is firefly.
- By Bob Ho. I need help.
I get good grades at this university.
Best of the classroom. I would not brag.
Bob, this is Larry.
- Pleasant, sir.
Let's go get food.
- He goes to college.
He is a poet. Cool right?
He is rare. He is amazing.
He is the man.
Come on.
What embarrassing.
Most people may not be the first me
time they meet me. Larry is.
I have two words for you, Larry.
Thirteen.
I must.
- But come on.
You stay at the table.
I cannot go.
Note Pigs.
Careful.
The lion jumped on them, and I
I killed him with my bare hands.
And I have saved the life colonels.
- You're brave.
Thank you.
What do you think of this, Bob?
Nora and the waitress said
that Larry could sit here.
Is not that great.
- He has "Spade" invited or something.
We just kidding.
Nora, knock, knock.
- Who is it?
Irish Stew.
- Irish Stew, who?
Irish Stew in the name of the law.
Larry tells me everything about the university.
It sounds great.
I want you ever around.
- Calm down.
That decision not you.
You're not my father.
No, but I know that your mother
is not completely lost her mind.
It's just a tour.
He asks me out or anything.
Really?
It is but a kind offer.
Even though it was a date, it could
you do not stop me.
Where you study towards it?
English literature.
- Would you pass the soy sauce?
So I get my background in the classes.
Thank you.
- Please.
You speak Russian.
- What is going on?
This is painful.
- You are right in.
Hurry.
Maybe write a poem about here?
Well, he is too old for me.
I want a princess anymore,
but a cyborg.
How he found me so quickly?
That makes no sense.
Bob, what is going on?
- Still, I try to think.
Well.
I'm an international spy and
I'm with the CIA.
Of the Chinese CIA.
Someone wants me dead.
And Larry was a Russian spy.
Well, tell us not.
Cool.
Why is that came?
Stay here.
Where are the kids?
- Inside.
Nothing is more out until
the children are safe.
Of course. Colton has a secure home
regularly, as you requested.
Did you file with you?
- Which file?
Your download those sent by Colton
Poldark of his computer.
I have nothing downloaded.
I did not even open anything.
Take me in the leg. This is secret
material. I have all the necessary copies.
Why do you think I have something gedownkoad.
Unless someone told you that.
Someone who wanted it back.
Let's not more difficult than
it is. Give me that file.
You're a Korean officer.
Why are you doing this?
I want to get out. Same as you.
We step out there both for love.
I just love money.
And Anton Poldark is match.com.
The file.
Good work.
Can I say you're the best man
that my mother has so far selected.
Now at least I know how Larry
found us so quickly.
How?
- The watch.
Curtis told me that I had to keep watch.
There is a tracking device in it.
You're really a spy.
- Gillian goes from her roof.
What are you doing?
There is iron in these rocks. This hides
a signal. Please watch.
When I tell this story in school, get
I am one year’s sentence for lying.
Yes?
- Hi, partner.
Where are you?
Why do you ask?
- I had to pick up the sent file.
The one you had open.
Are you there?
I never saw you as a traitor.
- That's crazy, man.
There is something wrong,
We must come together and talk.
Nice try.
We are safe here, promised.
This is your plan?
Hide in a hotel?
They also seem not to have chicken legs.
This is great.
Shall we call room service?
Are you crazy. I'm going home.
- No.
You're only safe with me.
- If you?
Everyone wants you dead.
- Yes. Great, right?
If you want to marry my mom,
I personally write the invitations.
I love you, Bob.
Infinite Bob.
Hello.
- Hi, Gillian.
Hi, honey. Grandpa just sleeping.
I just wanted to call.
I must tell you something.
This will hurt you down,
but I must say.
You okay?
Yes. It's about Bob.
What then?
- It's not who you think.
He is a Chinese spy.
Terrorists want to kill him...
and now the CIA is after him...
- Farren, I know you do not...
but I do not expect Ian
but not yours.
What? It is true.
He is still our death.
Farren, this conversation is over.
Give me Bob.
Hi, Gillian.
- I'm sorry. I am not sure what she has.
It is the truth.
- What?
All she said.
What this is, it is not funny.
The children are safe.
I provide them, if you're back.
You tell me so that I my
children left behind by a madman?
Come and get it also.
Do you have cool spy stuff,
outside the watch?
Do not touch.
Very sharp.
What else?
Sorry.
Airport. Hit it.
Bob, are you awake?
- Really?
He always snore?
- Do you hear even here?
I always thought it was the pig.
It's over between you and Gillian, huh?
Yes, it's over.
You win.
Why does it not then?
If you really love her,
you would not easily give up.
It is because I love her
and you keep three...
I should leave.
Your security is important.
I thought I was my other life
could forget, but I cannot.
Be happy. You're lucky you
This family is not together.
You have no idea what it is like
you live where you do not belong.
Do not be sure.
I grew up an orphanage.
I never knew my parents,
but I had a family.
I had numerous brothers and sisters.
Without some kinship.
But I loved them all.
Family is not about blood...
but you love
and who loves you.
Mom.
- Gillian.
Gillian, I'm sorry for everything.
Tell me the truth.
Are you really a spy?
Yes. I wanted to tell you...
but you interrupted me.
- That I do not care.
You brought my children in danger.
Just go.
If we see you again?
Not.
Please do not.
Who sings Chinese songs for me then?
They were safe, promised.
- Stay away from my children.
Dearest Mum, I'm sorry,
but I cannot stay here.
My destiny is to be a spy,
just like Bob.
I go with him.
Love, your son Ian.
The signal was getting right back on.
We have him.
Action.
You leave your watch.
- What are you doing here?
We must go.
- Why, we just got here.
What a coincidence.
Tie him up.
What are you doing here?
- I want it, I would also be a spy.
Is that bad? I expected
he would be better dressed.
How did you find me?
I stuck one of your opspoorapparaatjes
in your pocket.
Impressive.
- Thank you.
Are we back in business?
- I am retired you know.
If someone download no secrets.
- I have never downloaded.
He is lying.
- Who do you...
me, or the traitor?
Someone here has been very naughty.
He has cameras everywhere
and microphones placed.
A good plan to film us together.
- How can you turn back the country?
Simple. I am a multi millionaire.
That file you downloaded is not...
is a formula for a bacterial hybrid.
This stuff literally eat oil.
Imagine. All world oil
go at night in one way.
Apart from Russia,
which are gold.
Colton How have you convinced?
- Colton, who has nothing to do here.
He has no idea what is happening.
For him is really struggling.
Let the boy go.
He has nothing to do.
Mr. tetterkont here has
just told the whole plan.
We cannot let him go.
He will tell.
Trust me, nobody believes him.
He has a point.
Baas. Look what I found.
Hello everyone.
- Please sit down.
This is not true.
Poldark, if you let the children go,
I think that you file for GBH.
GBH, GBH like Stockholm?
How do you know?
- It kidding.
Is all this because
He downloaded a concert?
What has he done?
Did you downloaded?
- You take piracy seriously.
You've played with my PC?
That is private.
I just wanted to be cool.
- No need, that you already
One of the coolest person I know.
- Really?
Here, a man with a gun.
Wait, I'm the only child you know.
Where is the file?
- On my iPod, home to the office.
If you really want to be a spy,
you should never tell the truth.
Sorry, this is still new to me.
Take people into
to his house and find the iPod.
What if his family home?
Since you've dyed your hair blond...
Take them off.
No, no!
- Come, Bring me the iPod.
And as for you...
Farren, we go.
I sit up front and decide the radio channel.
Hello?
- Gillian, listen to me.
Goodbye, Bob.
Wait! Do not hang on.
We have more than them.
Is there someone you vertouwt,
you can call the office?
Jule, but they took all my cameras.
I cannot prove anything.
Except when that happened,
I recorded everything on my phone.
Well done, idiot.
Colt. Listen to me.
I play something for you.
What is this?
- This is Halloween.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were upstairs.
Everyone quickly inside.
- Bob, we need to talk.
Mom, this is no joke.
Do what he says.
Find your iPod.
- IPod? I demand an explanation.
They are coming.
- Who?
The Russians.
- Russians?
They are there.
Russians?
- Yes, keep you informed.
Quick, everyone up.
Stay there.
Where is my stuff?
- Here, have some of this stuff.
What things are they?
- Protection.
Why did you a lighter?
I do not want you play with fire.
Okay, just this once.
Let's go.
What do you suggest?
- A Cyborg from the future...
to blow you away.
Mum, that man could fly.
I cannot believe in us
have done this.
You have my children at risk.
- It is never my intention.
I love your kids.
I want to marry you.
And I with you.
But our wedding gifts to open
by the Mine Action Service.
Okay Bob, played enough games now.
I'm finally a regular
man, someone who...
Can we talk about this later?
A belt?
Give me the IPod.
Come to his house.
Hi, guys.
I have to go.
Maybe we should only
steal candy from small children.
This is fun.
- Hey Larry, knock knock...
Fast in your room
and put the door.
I arrest you in the name of the law.
Sorry that my timing is so
bad, Bob.
Kill me and let the family go.
- They have seen too much.
But you go first,
then you do not look.
Hey, mister...
Do not think this changes anything.
Everybody stop!
- It is in order...
they are good.
Do something looser.
- Sorry, the handcuffs are too tight?
I do not know how they worked,
I'm just a hillbilly.
Does everyone like it?
- On some bumps and scratches after.
This is one of the really good people.
What have you here.
Good job you took that call.
This young man can sometimes
be a good spy.
How fast can you get me out of this suit?
Sorry I accused you.
- No problem, buddy.
Let's at
an account.
Thank you.
Sorry to you all this
had to make them.
Goodbye, Gillian.
Goodbye, kids.
I will miss you.
I miss you too.
Bob
Wait.
I know he lied,
but he did to protect us.
Mum?
You'll never again find such a man as Bob.
Never.
Never thought to say this again,
but I agree with Farren.
You'll probably also be here
what to say about it?
I want my dad Bob.
Do you, Gillian, Bob to be your lawful husband?
- Yes.
And you Bob, do you Gillian
to be your lawful husband?
Gillian.
There is one thing you must know,
My name is not really Bob.
That's okay.
Yes.
I now pronounce you
husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Ready and action.
He is a crook, he could eat nails...
The boy takes all free.
Take him to blame.
That is such a crook, he could eat nails...
Bob, I want a princess anymore
but...
I'm an international spy.
I belong to the CIA...
From the Chinese...
I grab some stuff and we
go to the house.
I'm an international spy.
I belong to the CIA. From the Chinese...
Information...
I've shot down dictators.
How difficult is it to 'three' to say.
Maybe write a poem about...
Maybe you drive a poem about...
Maybe you write...
I hate English.
And the man you married,
who marries you all four.
Forget the pig, and cat
and not the turkey. The turkey...
Turkey.
Where did that come from turkey?
My grandmother...
Sorry.
My grandmother is...
If they screw up, then
I am happy.
Well done.
Come out.
The camera needs you.
What are you doing?
- What are you doing? We are filming.
We make a movie.
Funny.
Camera ready?
Bye.