What's your point, Major Kiefer?
Sir...
Just make sure we find the bodies.
We need to make a count.
The funerals...
There will be no funerals.
No next-of-kin.
Nothing ever happened here.
Colonel...
Ah. Here's one of them now.
SCREAMING
HORN BLARES
I'm afraid it's the same
all over Hastings.
You could try the Royal, but I'm not
sure they'll have anything.
Major John Kiefer.
I have a reservation.
Major Kiefer. Yes.
I suppose you're on your way home?
Yeah, that's right.
Glad to get back to your family?
Look -
just give me the key, goddamnit,
and let me go to my room.
I'm sorry. I'm tired.
Thank you.
(SIGHS)
What some bunting, love?
How much?
Two and six a quarter yard -
and you don't need coupons.
That's outrageous.
You try and find any in the shops!
"Shift grease with Zixt hand soap!"
"Beecham's -
the golden rule of health."
I hope you take my point,
Miss Stewart.
Absolutely.
Short and pithy.
Six words, but they pin the product
down in the public mind.
That's what we'll be looking for
in a successful applicant.
I thought the position
was for a secretary, Mr Ingleton.
Secretary to our chief copywriter.
You'd also be his apprentice.
We're looking
for someone with imagination,
someone willing to grasp the nettle.
Oh, that's me.
I'm willing to grasp it.
So!
Convince me.
I'm sorry?
Six words. A slogan I can't resist.
One that will persuade me
to take you on.
Well, um...
Can't keep the client waiting,
Miss Stewart.
Um...
Sam Stewart.
She gets the job done!
(SIGHS) Seven words.
Well, he's certainly an active
little chap. Nothing wrong there.
Both of you are in good health.
The only question
we have to ask is -
is he going to wait
for the end of the war?
How long do you think it will be?
The war or the baby?
I'm afraid
I couldn't predict either.
But you've nothing to worry about,
Mrs Milner.
Have you a bed at St Mary's?
Yes. That's where I worked.
Let them look after you for once.
Have you chosen a name?
We're going to call him Winston.
The fourth Winston this week.
Not surprising, I suppose.
Winston Milner.
We're still talking about it.
Aren't we?
How are you feeling?
Tired. I'm afraid
this wasn't very well timed.
I couldn't be happier.
I bought two dozen nappies
yesterday - one coupon each.
I don't know what we're going to do
about his clothes.
Well, last time I saw Sam,
she'd got her hands
on an army blanket
and was turning it
into a romper suit.
That's a fine start in life.
An old blanket.
At least he'll be born
in a world without war.
Oh! If he waits that long.
Good morning, sir.
Morning.
We've started moving stuff out.
I'd never have guessed.
I can't believe they
want to close the old place down.
The new building on Wilder Road -
it's a bit of an eyesore.
Nothing to do with me, Sergeant.
There's a Mr Griffiths waiting
for you, sir. Local councillor.
I put him in your office.
I hope that's all right. Fine.
Morning, sir.
Morning. How is she?
Just seen the doctor, sir.
All's well. Good.
Have you heard yet, Mr Milner?
Not yet.
Promoted to DI and a dad!
Not bad for a week's work.
I haven't been promoted yet.
It's in the bag.
And when you get your pip, maybe
you can put in a word for me.
No, not there.
It's the victory day celebrations.
Is it? What's the matter with them?
Well, large numbers of people
out on the streets day and night.
The council has a responsibility,
and there are certain issues
we have to keep in mind.
What issues in particular?
As far as I'm concerned,
none at all.
But as you'll see, I've been asked
to chair a committee
to look into all aspects
of public order and safety.
We've taken a room at the museum.
It was the only space we could get.
Your name is at the top.
Well, ten o'clock tomorrow.
That's not a lot of notice.
We weren't given much notice
ourselves, Mr Foyle.
But I'm sure we can deal
with the matter expeditiously.
We do need to co-ordinate
with the police.
Well, of course.
Thank you.
Bye.
Thank you, Mr Longmate.
Shall we go inside?
..my wife's great-grandfather was
the first proprietor of the hotel.
So are you expecting the next
election soon, Mr Longmate?
Well, it can't happen soon enough
for me. There are certainly plenty
of Conservative MPs urging
the premier to end coalition.
And you're confident
of a Conservative victory?
Well, aren't you? I think
even most Labour MPs expect it.
Is it true you're planning
a victory celebration
in the streets of Hastings?
That's right.
You're paying for it yourself?
Yes.
You don't think
people might see that
as an inducement to vote for you
in the election?
You mean a bribe?
(TUTS) Well, I certainly hope not.
I think you underestimate
the electorate, Mr Charman.
You ask any of my staff
here at the hotel.
We deserve a party,
and we're going to have one.
The fact that I'm paying for it
is neither here nor there.
Thank you very much, sir.
Always glad to talk
to the Chronicle.
Sir, we've had a notification
of the committee meeting.
It's tomorrow
morning at ten o'clock.
At the town hall?
They had to move it to the museum.
There's a shortage of space.
Nothing surprises me.
This whole town's turned
on its head.
Would you like me to attend?
Ah, yes.
It would be good if you could take
minutes, Miss Hylton. Anything else?
We're getting an awful lot
of requests for rooms.
The telephone's
been ringing nonstop.
Hastings, the seaside,
the end of the war.
Where else would you want to be?
I've got something for you.
Oh, come in.
It didn't turn out quite as I hoped,
but...
It was that army blanket.
For the baby!
Oh! Thank you, Sam. It's...
Edith will love it.
Any news on the move yet?
I still haven't got my promotion.
Well, they'd be mad
not to promote you.
Oh, if you do go to Brighton,
will you need a driver?
I don't think I'll get a car.
Darn. Oh, well, better show my face.
Yeah.
KNOCK AT DOOR
Yeah?
Just to tell you I'm back, sir.
Thank you. How did it go?
Not very well, I'm afraid, sir.
Oh?
I really don't know
what I'll do after the war.
I am glad Adolf's finally copped it
and all that,
but a part of me can't help
wishing it would go on another year.
Well, I'm glad
we don't all think like that.
No. It's a stupid thing to say,
I suppose.
I don't know.
This place is closing down,
you're retiring,
Milner's transferring to Brighton.
We've been together so long,
I feel I'm losing my family.
I don't know what I'm going to do.
I've tried advertising, accountancy,
three other offices,
but nobody seems to want me.
I'll probably go back to Leominster,
live with my parents
and become a governess or something.
Something here might interest you.
Is it a job?
Well, sort of.
Organisation called SSAFA.
Mean anything?
No, sir. What is it?
Soldiers, Sailors, Airmen
and Families Association.
Um, they help returning servicemen.
Help them how?
I'm not altogether sure,
but they need volunteers,
and it could be right up your street.
All right, sir. I'll breeze along.
Don't you want to reconsider?
Reconsider what?
Retiring.
Um...no, thank you.
Did you get the bread?
Where did this come from?
What?
It was on the front door.
A tiger?
Yes. Who put it there?
I - I didn't see it.
It wasn't there this morning.
What is the matter with you, Mark?
What is it?
Nothing.
It must be something.
It's obviously upset you.
It's nothing.
Perhaps you ought to take something.
You're miles away.
I didn't get the bread.
All the bakers are sold out.
Right. Well, we won't have
bread with our tea, then.
It doesn't matter. I'll be in late.
You're always late.
Are you going to the pub? Mother.
You haven't been the same
since you came back.
I wish you'd tell me what happened.
You haven't been the same.
RADIO: 'I'm I'm in the village
of Luneberg,
and I'm watching the German army
coming into surrender.'
'German tanks, guns
a multitude of lorries
and infantrymen in their hundreds
have been arriving,
bringing with them beaten men.'
'In the midst
of these defeated soldiers
comes a huddle of RAF release
prisoners, cheering as they go by.'
'It's what we've been waiting for -
the end of the German army
in the north.'
I don't understand it, sir.
Hitler's dead, Goering's gone mad -
they say he's wearing a toga -
and the rest of them
are having their faces changed.
Why won't they announce
it's all over?
Beats me.
Station, sir?
No. The museum.
Taking a day off?
Wouldn't that be nice?
Oh, I spoke to the people at SSAFA.
I'm seeing them this afternoon.
Well, that's good.
Do you want me to wait for you, sir?
What a good idea.
Ziegler. That's a German name.
I was actually born in Austria.
Yes. Well, it's all the same now.
Forgive me, but I don't see what
business my nationality is of yours.
You don't come in here
without my say-so. Obviously.
If you want to disrupt this
committee because of my name...
Is there a problem?
No sir. Just checking the register.
Who are you?
Brown, sir.
Michael Brown. Assistant curator.
I've been asked to keep an eye
on you gentlemen while you're here.
I'm Henry Ziegler. Dr Ziegler.
How do you do? Christopher Foyle.
This gentleman seems to have
some problem with my parentage.
Not at all, sir.
I'm just doing my job.
All right for us to go in now,
do you think?
Oh, certainly, sir.
I'll tick you off. Up the stairs.
Odd place for a Victory Day
committee. Yeah, isn't it?
Oh, I think we must be through here.
..fortunately,
we still have supplies.
I just hope we're not going
to be accused of hoarding.
Ah, Mr Foyle. And Dr Ziegler.
May I introduce Martin Longmate,
who owns the Majestic Hotel.
Longmate. We've met, I think.
No. I don't think so.
Martin Longmate.
I feel sure I know the name.
You may have read about me.
Ah, yes? In the press.
I'm standing for parliament.
Perhaps.
And Miss Hylton has kindly
agreed to take the minutes.
How do you do?
So are we all here?
One more still to come.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Christopher!
John.
What are you doing?
What are YOU doing?
I'm on the committee.
Well, me too.
I suppose now I come to think of it,
you're the first person they'd ask.
How are you?
Much the same.
But you were transferred.
That's right. But I'm back.
I'm Major John Kiefer,
with the 215th US Engineers.
We built the air base
at Hawthorn Hill.
That monstrosity!
So you don't like it, huh?
Well, it helped us launch the
invasion in Europe and win the war.
You know, I'm really sorry
if it spoiled the landscape.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
No, no, no I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It just took a lot of the...
blood, sweat, toil and tears
your Mr Churchill goes on about.
Are you waiting for someone?
DCS Foyle.
Ah.
Do you work here?
Yeah. I'm assistant curator.
Yeah, I was in the Home Guard
until they stood us down.
Now I'm back here.
Do you know
how long they're going to be?
I couldn't believe it -
they've got a Jerry up there!
Did you see that?
No, I can't say I did.
I mean, you read
what that lot have been doing,
Belsen and all that stuff,
and it makes you sick.
They're not human.
Well,
forgive and forget, I suppose.
Not a bit of it. We ought
to kill the whole lot of them.
Wipe them off the face of the earth.
Nice talking to you.
Shall we start at the beginning?
Public order offences.
Like what, Mr Griffiths?
The destruction
of public property, for a start.
Are you aware that several park
benches have already disappeared,
dismantled, we believe,
to make bonfires?
Boy, that's the British. You come
out of a war and start worrying
about a few park benches.
Major Kiefer, I should remind you
there are many hundreds
of GIs here in Hastings,
not known for their orderly conduct
when it comes to street parties.
I guess you've got it in
for the Yanks, haven't you?
I didn't say that.
Maybe I should remind you,
Mr Griffiths,
the end of the war was announced
on US bases a week ago,
and, ah, we didn't
have any problems.
A week ago?
Actually, it was an error.
But uh, we didn't lose our heads.
No dead bodies.
Look, there will be offences -
drunkenness,
destroying public property.
But uh, surely to goodness,
after five years,
people deserve
to let their hair down.
And you're organising a party,
is that right?
It's to be the largest
in the south of England.
Mr Longmate's paying for it himself.
I'm just doing my bit,
as I wasn't able to fight.
You weren't fit for active service?
A problem with my eyes.
Your eyes?
That's right.
Anything else?
Besides park benches?
Right now,
we need all the help we can get.
Our main role is a practical one.
Information, to begin with.
You worked with the police?
Yes.
Well, a bit of detective work
may be called for.
We have thousands of soldiers
searching for friends and families.
People have moved.
Many have been bombed out.
And then there are
wounded or missing servicemen
with families searching for them.
How can I help?
Well, we have people coming in
every day,
and every single one of them
has a different need.
It may just be
a question of clothing.
Don't they get demob suits?
That's hardly adequate.
No, we have a central clothing branch
in London
that sends out almost
a million pieces of clothing a year.
Then there's food, housing
or just a friendly face,
someone they can talk to.
Well, that's me.
Miss Stewart,
I think I should warn you,
some of these men are more damaged
than any of us really understands.
Fighting in a war,
being taken prisoner, being injured -
just being away,
in some cases for years -
it takes its toll.
I'm sure.
So you think you can cope?
I'll give it my best shot.
Not quite the right expression
in the circumstances,
but let's see how you go.
Bodies.
Thank you, Major Kiefer.
Hundreds of them!
It was nobody's fault, Major.
That's not true.
You know it's not true.
Who cares about truth?
We win the war. That's all
that matters. Just get back home.
(ECHOING) Just get back home...
Just get back home...
Ahh!
(FIGHTS FOR BREATH)
Ah...
BIRDSONG
MUSIC ON RADIO
Eddie!
Be careful with that! That's a
hundred quid's worth of best china.
Best china? All we've got in
the canteen is a few cracked mugs.
Evidence, Miss Stewart. Nicked
from a warehouse in Eastbourne.
The case comes up next month.
Morning, sir.
Sergeant.
There's something in the paper
you ought to see.
Don't tell me.
They finally announced it's over?
No such luck.
No, it's on the employment page.
I thought it might suit you.
Prospective conservative
candidate seeks personal assistant.
I don't know, Brookie.
I don't know a thing about politics.
You don't know
about advertising either,
but that didn't stop you.
That's true.
It's a local number.
Why not give it a ring?
Yeah, I could do worse.
Then if he does get in,
you could be in Parliament.
Maybe I'll meet Winnie!
Yeah. Morning, Mr Milner.
Morning.
CLATTERING
What do you think you're doing?
Sorry, sir.
Sir?
Sergeant.
How was the committee?
Well, a complete waste of time.
A lot of talk
about nothing in particular,
no action at the end of it -
as expected, really.
At least it's over. No,
they want us back tomorrow. Hello?
Hotel reception, please.
A Saturday?
We have to be prepared
for every eventuality, it seems.
VE Day. That's what they're
calling it. Victory in Europe.
Hello? I understand you have
a Major Kiefer is staying with you.
Is that right?
Why didn't you tell me you were
coming home? All right, ain't it?
Stop and ask someone
if I could use the blower.
You could have written.
I only got out at the last minute.
There was a spare seat on a Dakota
and the CO said I could have it,
cos I'd been out there the longest.
So where were you?
I don't even know where you've been.
It was an island.
A place called Ist.
Ist?
That's a funny name.
Yeah.
We'll have to find it on the map.
It would have been easier
knowing where you were.
That was the worst of it.
Well, we moved around a bit.
Here...give me a hug.
You feel different.
What are you talking about?
I don't know. You've put on weight.
That's not a nice thing to say!
No. It suits you. It's funny though.
What?
Nothing.
You're different too, Eddie.
How?
I haven't seen you for four years.
You've been away for four years.
It's like I'm meeting you
for the first time.
Yeah...well, we've got
a lot of catching up to do.
Not now! I've got to get to work.
You're not serious.
Well, I'm not going to work.
Of course I'm not.
But I've got to let Mr Longmate
know.
I'll have to call in.
Who's Mr Longmate?
My boss. I wrote to you.
The Majestic Hotel.
He gave me a job.
Is that all he gave you?
Don't say things like that!
Why don't you come along with me?
Yeah. Maybe I will.
We'll go along together.
You can meet Mr Longmate.
Maybe he can help you.
Why should I need any help?
You need a job.
A job? Work?
The war's over, Eddie.
We need to start again.
Yeah.
You made it.
That's all that matters.
And we're together.
I can't bear it.
Your blood pressure is very high.
When did you last get
a proper night's sleep?
I can't sleep.
Maybe it's the silence.
You'd be surprised
how many people
find it impossible to sleep
without bombs dropping, and sirens.
I need something.
What you need is to rest.
Rest.
What is it you've got on your mind?
I'm being persecuted.
Persecuted?
Because of what happened.
It was terrible. Horrible.
But it wasn't just me.
Please, old chap.
Try to calm down.
You're not making sense.
Why are they blaming me?
Nobody's blaming you for anything.
You've worked yourself
up into a state.
I can't even go out of the house.
Look, I'm going to give you
a prescription.
Something to calm you down
and help you to sleep.
And I think you should give
our next committee meeting a miss.
You're in no state for anything.
It wasn't my fault!
I don't deserve this!
I'm very, very pleased to meet you,
Edward.
You didn't tell me
he was coming home.
I didn't know.
Can I get you anything?
A drink? Something to eat?
I'm all right, thank you, sir.
Do sit down.
Well, I imagine
you've been around the houses, then.
Tunisia, Greece, Albania,
Libya and Italy. That's right, sir.
Quite a war.
You could say that.
You're glad it's over?
I can imagine
you'll find it hard to adapt -
Civvy Street and all that.
I just need time to myself, sir.
With my wife.
Of course. Janice,
you must take
as much time as you need.
I hate to let you down, Mr Longmate.
Don't even think of it.
And Edward, when you've had
a chance to settle in a bit,
you must come and see me.
You were a joiner before the war?
A general carpenter, sir.
We've plenty of work.
We'll have a place for you.
What about the committee,
Mr Longmate?
Susan can come with me. Don't worry.
The luggage is in?
All in, sir.
LID BANGS
It's nothing, Eddie. Come on!
I have an appointment
with Mr Longmate. It's Miss Stewart.
I'll let him know you're here.
Well, here we are again.
Just like old times.
Is it?
You tell me.
Here. I brought you something.
That's very kind of you.
I figured supplies might be low.
You're right.
You can open it.
Oh, it's a bit early for me.
Not for me.
Sit down.
Water?
No, thanks.
How's your boy?
I wish I knew.
He's in Malta.
Haven't heard for quite a while.
So why do you want to see me?
I said I'd like to see you if you
had time. Not quite the same thing.
So this isn't official?
No.
Bottoms up.
Another?
No, thank you, Christopher.
I don't need another.
You asked me to come over here.
I want to know why.
Well, look, it just occurred to me
that after the surprise
of meeting the other day,
you've been in Hastings,
haven't been in touch - I wondered
if everything was all right.
I'm fine. Glad to be back.
You've been in Devon. Is that right?
Yeah.
And it rained even more
than it does here.
Do any fishing?
Never got the chance.
Well, listen, I'm going out tomorrow.
Interested?
I thought
we were all meeting again tomorrow.
The goddamn committee.
The goddamn committee
is in the afternoon.
We've got the morning.
No thanks, Christopher. I'll pass.
I kind of lost the taste
for fishing over the years.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I lost the taste
for a lot of things.
You know what?
I just want to go home.
That's about the size of it.
Well, here we are.
Please take a seat.
Um, tell me about your war,
Miss Stewart.
Well, there's not much to tell,
really.
I started out in the MTC.
Motorised Transport Corps.
And then I was transferred
to the police.
A detective?
No such luck.
A driver. And that's
what I've been doing ever since.
And are you interested in politics?
Absolutely.
So what are your views on,
for example, Beveridge
and his ideas
for a National Health Service?
Oh - I'm all for it.
But we also want to reduce taxation.
Can't you do both?
It may not be possible.
Ah. That is a bit tricky, isn't it?
Have you thought about Labour plans
for public ownership?
Constantly.
Look. I don't really know much
about politics, Mr Longmate.
In fact
I don't really know anything.
But it seems to me we trusted Mr
Churchill to get us through the war,
and we ought to trust him
with the peace.
Well, that's very honest of you,
Miss Stewart,
and honesty in politics
can be a very rare commodity.
I wonder if you'd have lunch
with me tomorrow?
Oh! Well, I'm not sure I'm -
I'm sorry. That's forward of me.
Please don't take it the wrong way.
You see, a large part of the work
being my personal assistant
will involve one-to-one contact
with me and with my constituents.
We need to know
that we can get along.
So all I'm proposing is something
a little less formal
than this interview.
I'm afraid I'm not free for lunch.
I'm working with SSAFA.
That's very commendable. Does you
credit. How about dinner?
Tomorrow?
The hotel has a very good cook.
I suppose so. All right.
Well, I'll see you here at seven
o'clock, and we can talk some more.
You're not eating anything.
I'm not hungry.
You must be hungry.
That's the best tinned salmon.
I don't know the last time I opened
a tin. I never have enough points.
Where did you get it?
The hotel.
Longmate?
What's wrong with you, Eddie?
Yes, he gave it to me for you.
He's looked after me.
What's that meant to mean?
He's given me a job!
I had to do something
while you were away.
Is this how it's going to be?
You've come back,
but it's like I hardly know you.
I need to see someone.
Who?
The quack. I've got gut-rot.
I need to see someone.
I'll make you an appointment.
It's all right. I've done it.
Dr Ziegler.
Ziegler?
I'm seeing him tomorrow.
You should let me look after you.
You can.
I'll tell you where you can start.
What is it you're not telling me?
Where've you been?
The pub. I felt like a drink.
You could have had a drink here.
There's nothing in the pantry.
Have you eaten?
No.
Would you like something?
It's all right, Mother.
You've got to eat.
What's this? I don't know.
It's addressed to you.
Who delivered it?
I didn't see.
Someone knocked on the door.
I went outside
and it was there on the step.
You didn't see them?
I just told you.
Are you going to open it?
No.
(SOBS)
VERA LYNN:
# When The Lights Go On Again
# All over the world
# And the boys are home again
Dad?
I thought I'd find you here.
# A kiss won't mean goodbye
# But hello to love... #
Here you are.
Cheers, Dad.
Hm! A full bottle of scotch.
Where on earth did you get that?
Well, it's bourbon.
Ah, Americans.
Yeah, a friend of mine. Well, he was.
So is this just a visit,
or are you back for good?
I'm not flying any more.
I had a touch of sinusitis
a couple of months ago.
More than a touch.
Four days in hospital.
Cured?
Don't ask. It was bloody painful.
Then the Group Captain sent me home.
So you're out of it?
Yes. I made it.
I can't stop thinking
about all the ones who didn't.
Rex Talbot. Charlie Paige.
So many of them.
They were my friends, and yet
it's like I hardly knew them.
Here one day, gone the next.
The best of the best.
Why them, not you?
That's what I wonder all the time.
Perhaps you were the better pilot.
You know, what they say
is exactly the opposite.
The real fliers, the ones
who knew what they were doing,
they were the easiest to bring down.
It was the lazy bastards,
the ones who cut corners,
who didn't do it by the book -
we got away with it because
Jerry didn't know what to expect.
You're definitely
leaving the police?
Can't wait.
How's Sam?
Why do you ask?
Just wondering.
You met somebody else, didn't you?
Yeah.
It didn't work out.
Debden was bloody awful,
if you want the truth, Dad.
It drizzled the whole time and the
only decent pubs were in Cambridge.
I didn't like the training.
I missed my Spit.
Kate was a nice girl.
In the WAAF.
I sort of persuaded myself
I was in love with her,
but I wasn't.
Well, Sam's all right.
I mean, she's still the driver,
and she's got some voluntary work
with SSAFA.
I'd like to see her.
Maybe I'll look her up.
You weren't very kind to her.
I know.
Stupid bloody war.
Do you think it was worth it, Dad?
Well, we've all paid a price,
some more than others,
but I have absolutely no doubt
whatsoever.
Yes.
And I'm very glad you're back.
PHONE RINGS
Hello?
'It was just a few numbers.'
Who is this? What do you want?
More than 700 American boys
died because of you.
That's not true.
I wasn't responsible.
You're mistaken. Now leave me alone!
You look like
you could do with a cup.
The sugar's had it, I'm afraid.
I don't take sugar.
That's all right, then.
I'm Sam Stewart.
Hylton. Edward. Ed.
Just back?
Yeah.
Where were you?
All around.
Army?
Y Patrol.
Long range desert group,
signals operator.
You must be glad to be out.
No. No, I'm not sure I am.
I don't know
why people aren't more cheerful.
The war's over,
but everyone seems the same.
Maybe it hasn't sunk in yet.
I was told you could help with work
and that sort of thing.
We can try.
So what can you do for me,
Miss Stewart?
Well, we have a booklet.
It tells you what kind of things
we have on offer -
university grants, training,
employment schemes and so on.
Are you all right for money?
I've got money. They gave me
eight weeks' paid leave.
And you have somewhere to live?
I have a house,
but I'm thinking of moving.
I don't want to stay in Hastings.
Maybe you should try
the Resettlement Advice Office.
There's one in Welham Road.
Welham Road.
And did you know
we have a married families club?
Are you married?
You might like to join.
I'm sorry.
If you want the honest truth,
this is my first day here
and I'm not much cop at it.
I'm all right at making a cup
of tea, but that's about it.
Do you want me to find someone else?
No. I've got nothing to say.
Is it really so bad, being back?
I don't know where I am any more.
I don't know what to believe.
Four years out there,
behind the lines,
doing what we did,
all of us together.
And they suddenly tell us
it's all over,
and we've got to come back
and start again.
How are we meant to do that?
How are we meant to
put it all behind us?
A cup of tea,
married families club...
Half my mates got killed out there.
Maybe they were the lucky ones.
I don't understand
why they keep hanging on.
It's bad for people, waiting
all the time for an announcement.
I'm getting a lot of patients
with nervous conditions,
depressed, unable to sleep.
I heard a rumour it'll be tomorrow.
I heard that rumour about today.
I have received confirmation
that when the victory is announced,
public houses are to remain open
until midnight.
Now where is it?
Licensing hours,
Hastings and Eastbourne.
Is that what you're looking for?
Thank you.
As Dr Ziegler said,
I haven't slept myself.
That's too bad.
Are you well enough to go on?
Yes, yes.
That's why we're all here.
More whisky and gin has been
distributed across the south coast,
in bottles marked
NOT TO BE SOLD UNTIL VICTORY NIGHT.
We need to be sure that's
strictly adhered to, Mr Foyle.
I don't quite see how
we're supposed to do that, exactly.
We can send officers
into as many pubs as you like,
but the chances of them coming out
again are pretty slim, I'd have said.
So what did he say?
Dr Ziegler wasn't there,
but the nurse saw me.
There's nothing to worry about.
The baby's being slow, that's all.
Janice!
I'm sorry?
It's Edith! You must remember.
We met at Dr Ziegler's.
No. You're wrong. I don't know you.
But you were...
I'm sorry. I must have
mistaken you for somebody else.
Who was she?
I don't know. I never met her.
She knew your name.
I didn't know hers.
You look tired, Edward.
I've got a few errands to run.
Why don't you go home on your own?
Right. I don't think there are
any other matters outstanding.
Well, if that's so,
would you mind very much
if I took myself off?
I still have a party to organise.
How many people are you inviting?
The whole town's invited, Dr Ziegler
- that includes you.
Ah, thank you. But I think I shall
be staying peacefully at home.
There'll be enough whisky and gin
for everyone, that I can promise.
Not to be sold until victory night.
Exactly.
We wouldn't want to be sending out
the wrong signals.
Miss Gilbert will take the minutes,
and I'll say good day.
I should be going as well.
Ah, Mr Foyle, there was one thing
I wanted to talk to you about.
Yeah?
Um, it's a private matter. I wonder
if I might call in at the station?
Are you there this afternoon?
I am. Any time you like.
Thank you.
You going my way?
No, I need some shuteye.
I'm heading back to the hotel.
Ah, right.
Are you all right?
Yes, thank you.
It's Saturday.
What are you doing here?
I thought you might like
to get out, sir.
The sooner the better.
Good day, Mr Griffith.
What are you doing with that?
What do you think? Burning it!
Good lads.
Bunting! Union Jacks!
Red, white and blue!
No street party's complete -
buy your colours.
A couple of flags, please.
Five bob each, mate.
Five bob? You're pulling my leg.
You want one, that's what you pay.
(SIGHS)
All right. I'll have this one.
That one's two quid.
What?
This one's five bob.
You're not serious!
Do I look like I'm joking?
You don't like it, go elsewhere.
People died for this flag.
Don't that mean something?
I'm trying to do business. No,
what you're doing is profiteering.
You hadn't noticed
there's a law against that?
Says who? The war's over, mate.
Or haven't they told you?
The law's still the law.
What are you going to do? Arrest me?
Yeah. That's what I'm going to do.
My name is Sergeant Brooke,
Sussex constabulary.
And you are coming with me.
Oh, bloody hell.
Stop that man!
Stop! Stop that man!
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
STOP!
Hey! Stop! Stop that man!
DOGS BARK
Stop!
Aargh!
(GROANS)
Miss Stewart.
How very good of you to come.
Thank you for inviting me.
Shall we go in?
Mm.
May I ask you something,
Mr Longmate?
Do you invite everyone who's
applied for this job to dinner?
Absolutely not. Shall we say you're
um...through to the second round.
Two advantages to owning an hotel.
Deep cellars, and...
I get to choose who drinks what.
How did you come to own an hotel?
I'd like to say that I started from
the bottom and worked my way up,
but I'm afraid that's not true.
I inherited the hotel
when my wife died.
I'm sorry.
It was at the very start of the war.
She was...visiting a friend
in London and er...
..took a direct hit.
Well, there have been so many
casualties, so much suffering,
and that's why this election
will be so important.
We've got to rebuild.
It's a chance to start again.
You never told me what you expect
your assistant to do.
To stay close to me.
To be someone I can trust.
That's not quite what it said
in the advertisement.
Well, I was paying by the word.
So you were in the MTC?
For a year.
And then the police.
That's rather unusual.
Who exactly did you drive?
A detective. Here in Hastings.
His name is Mr Foyle.
Christopher Foyle?
Yes.
Have you met him?
Yes, I was with him this afternoon.
Martin.
Miss Hylton!
I've been looking for you.
I'm afraid this is a private dinner.
I really can't talk now.
A private dinner?
I know what you're doing.
I know exactly what you're doing!
Janice,
remember, this is a public place.
you can't behave like this.
I need to speak to you.
Not now! Now!
SILENCE FALLS
Miss Stewart, I'm afraid
you're going to have to forgive me.
This is my current secretary,
who is a little distraught,
but er...to be honest, if I may,
I don't think you'd be right
for the post.
I'm very sorry.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
I've got to work.
You're not serious.
Well, it's not exactly how I'd choose
to spend my Sunday.
Who's been murdered this time?
A man called Ziegler. Dr Ziegler.
German?
Austrian.
But as English as you and me.
So who killed him?
Well, don't ask me, I've no idea.
What are you gonna do
while I'm gone?
Oh, I don't know.
Not much, I don't think.
Poor Dad!
It could only happen to you!
What do you mean?
The whole country preparing for
a giant knees-up,
and you're stuck with the body
in the library.
It was in the museum.
That's it, just to the left a bit.
Perfect.
Well, that's er...very colourful.
They were an absolute steal, sir.
They're just getting ready
for the big announcement.
Are you all right, by the way?
Dr Ziegler.
Yeah, he ran right into me, sir.
Well, I ran into him.
Speak to you?
Not a word, I'm afraid, sir.
It was just my luck, really.
If he'd said who stuck the knife in,
we could have all gone home.
Good morning, sir.
Sorry to drag you in on a Sunday.
I knew Dr Ziegler.
Did you?
So did I.
How did you know him?
He'd been treating Edith.
He was unmarried,
no family that we know of.
He'd been living in London,
came down to Hastings last year.
What else do we know about him?
Well, we know that the er...
last conversation I had with him
was about him wanting to see me
about something.
Do you think that's why
he was killed?
Could be.
You don't think it was his name,
do you, sir? Ziegler.
There's so much anti-German feeling,
what with these pictures of Belsen,
and the rest of it.
He didn't look or sound German.
What do we know about the knife?
The killer took it with him.
But the pathologist
looked at the wound
and said we're looking for something
with a long, curved blade.
(KNOCK)
Yeah.
Is it true someone's been murdered?
Perhaps.
I'll get the car.
I don't know. Really!
Dragging me back here on a Sunday!
Yeah, it's so inconsiderate getting
murdered on a weekend, isn't it?
Yes, yes, all right.
You didn't much care for Dr Ziegler,
I seem to remember.
I didn't have anything against him.
Not what I heard.
Oh?
Germans - kill the lot of them,
wipe them from the face of the earth.
Do you remember saying that?
You're not trying to say
I put a knife in him, are you?
It looks as if there's a knife
missing here, wouldn't you say?
I don't know anything about that.
And wouldn't this normally be locked?
Well, people are bringing stuff
in and out.
Someone must have forgotten
to lock it.
You were downstairs when the meeting
broke up yesterday, weren't you?
Well, I was er...I was at the door.
Hm. Do you remember, by any chance,
which of us came out first?
Well, I can't be certain because
I wasn't there the whole time.
Um... The Yank. Major Kiefer.
Yes, he was the first one out.
Yes, I can tell you that for sure.
And you'd remember that because...?
Well, I saw him and I heard him.
And then I went
along the corridor...
- call of nature, if you must know -
..and then the next person I saw
was er...
Mr Griffiths.
And there was a woman, as well.
Came out around the same time as me.
You remember her?
No, I didn't see her.
Were any of them carrying anything
suspicious when they left?
You mean like a great big
fishing knife? No, I didn't see.
He was killed on his way home
with a knife taken from the museum.
It seems probable that it was
someone in the meeting.
So that's Kiefer, Longmate,
Longmate's secretary...
And Griffiths.
From Ziegler's appointment book,
he saw him on Friday.
The notes mentioned blood pressure
and stress.
He was prescribed sleeping pills.
Really?
What happened?
It's a suicide. He took pills.
Mr Griffiths?
Yes.
Who authorised the removal
of the body?
I've no idea, guv.
But it's all cut and dried.
He left a note, apparently.
And, quite frankly,
I've got a party to get to.
No-one's hanging around here.
And this is definitely
your son's handwriting?
Yes, it is.
And this was on the kitchen table
when you came down this morning?
I've already told you.
"It wasn't me. I wasn't responsible.
I'm sorry, I can't live with this."
It's obviously a...
very great shock for you.
(SIGHS) The war's over.
He came through it.
And then he has to do this.
What's the point?
Wasn't responsible for what?
What do you think he meant by that?
I don't know.
He hadn't been the same
since he came back.
He wasn't eating. He was
spending time down at the pub,
he hardly said a word.
Since he came back from where?
Er... The West Country.
He was with the Royal Signal Corps.
He didn't tell me
any more than that.
The name Ziegler
mean anything to you?
That was Mark's doctor.
The one who gave him
the sleeping pills.
The ones he took.
Well, once again, we're um...
very sorry.
It doesn't make any difference.
This bloody war -
it's taken everything anyway.
It's taken everything
we ever cared about.
And people have become most strange.
Somebody sent him some sand.
Some sand?
An envelope full of sand.
When was that?
A few days ago. Friday.
Anything else?
He said he was being followed.
He thought someone was...
watching him.
I thought he was just
imagining things.
I told you, he hadn't been the same.
But there was a picture also
pinned to the door.
A picture? A picture of what?
It was cut out of a magazine.
It was an animal. A tiger.
Well, why would someone do that?
A tiger?
What's it meant to mean?
So, did you see the doctor?
I turned up for the appointment.
He weren't there.
So, how are you feeling?
Are you feeling better?
Why don't you tell me about her?
Who?
That woman we met. In the street.
I...I told you. I've never
seen her before in my life.
That's not what she thought.
Well, she was wrong.
Look, I'm fed up of this.
I've had enough of it!
You're lying to me, Janice.
I know you are!
I never met her before!
You're lying!
I'm sorry.
You can get 12's worth
of civilian clothing.
Don't forget your demob suit.
If you need any more information,
come back any time.
Thank you, Miss.
I already have my 12.
And my demob suit.
Not that I think I'll be wearing it.
But I was told you also gave advice.
When did you get back?
Yesterday.
From Debden?
No, I've been flying again.
I was in Malta.
How are you?
Well, I...I need someone to talk to.
Well, we've plenty of leaflets.
Yes. Yes, I can see.
But I don't think I'd find
the answer to my problem there.
What is your problem?
Well, er...
..it's like this, you see.
I was in Hastings for a while.
My squadron was only
a couple of miles away.
And while I was there, I...
sort of fell in love.
Well, no sort of about it.
I met this girl and the two of us
walked out for a time.
Andrew, please. And then I got
sent to this training centre.
And I was promoted to
Squadron Leader.
But I hated it there.
And the fact is, I must have been
a little bit out of my mind,
because I behaved like
a complete cad.
I broke it off with this girl.
I didn't even have the nerve
to tell her face to face.
I wrote her a letter and told her
I'd met someone else,
even though I knew the someone else
wasn't a patch on her,
and of course
it didn't last very long.
And there hasn't been a day when I
haven't regretted what I did...
..and wished I could somehow undo it
and take back the hurt
I know I must have caused.
And that's why I'm asking
your advice, you see, because...
..because I'm still looking
for a way.
I'm not sure there is a way, Andrew.
But if I saw her and...
..told her what a fool I was,
and begged her to consider?
I don't think she's the sort of girl
who would like begging.
Do you think
she'd at least consider?
Consider what?
Well, just seeing me.
Spending time together,
just being friends.
Well, she'd have to look
in the leaflets,
see what they advise.
(SCOFFS) You don't have a leaflet
about love.
No, but I've quite a few
on desertion.
Yes, well...
Well, thank you anyway.
You know, Sam, in all this time
you've hardly changed at all.
Really?
But I have.
Sir,
you know the man you're going
to see? Martin Longmate.
He owns the hotel, doesn't he?
He does.
Well, I think you ought to know,
I applied to be
his personal assistant.
Did you? Did you get it?
I don't think so.
Well, maybe best not to accept it
anyway, not just yet. Thank you.
Well, well, well!
Come to say goodbye?
You're leaving?
That's right. I got my 85 points.
That earns me a ticket on the good
ship Aquitania heading for New York.
I'm not sure that's going to be
possible.
Why's that?
You probably know about Ziegler.
Sure. But you're not gonna tell me I
had anything to do with that, right?
I mean, I hardly knew the man.
You may not know about Griffiths.
What about him?
He's dead.
Dead?
Sit down.
Since when?
Saturday night.
How?
An overdose.
Well, why would he do that?
I thought you might be able
to tell me.
I can't tell you anything.
Maybe it's pretty obvious.
Ziegler and Griffiths
died on the same day, right?
So maybe Griffiths killed Ziegler.
I don't know why -
you can find that out.
He killed him, then he regretted it
and he took his own life.
He left a note.
Yeah?
"It wasn't me, I wasn't responsible."
That's all it said.
There you are - it's a confession.
How well did you know him?
I never met him before in my life.
For a man you never met, he seemed to
have quite an affect on you.
He was the boring head of a boring
committee, we all felt the same.
How did you get to be
on that committee?
As a matter of fact, I volunteered.
I was killing time.
After you'd finished in Devon?
Yeah.
What is it you were doing in Devon?
What is this, the Third Degree?
Look, Christopher,
I'd like to help you,
I really would,
but you know I can't.
And I can't let you leave.
You know that.
You think you can stop me?
I have a wife.
I have two sons that I haven't seen
in over three years.
I'm sorry.
I thought we were friends,
Christopher.
Well, so did I.
Mr Longmate is ready to see you now.
Thank you.
I have to say,
this is a terrible business.
Almost unbelievable.
A murder, now of all times!
(SIGHS)
Well, have you made any progress?
Perhaps. Um... Just a couple of
things, if you don't mind.
Excuse me.
Well, anything I can do to help.
You first met Dr Ziegler when?
Same time as you, at the committee.
You were never a patient of his,
then?
No.
Mm-hm.
What's the matter with your eyes,
if you don't mind me asking?
I beg your pardon?
I remember you telling Dr Ziegler
your eyesight was the reason you
were exempt from the armed forces.
Nothing wrong with that, of course,
but you're not wearing glasses
and you didn't seem to have a problem
reading at the meeting.
Well, er...
I might as well come clean.
Actually, I lied.
The real reason why
I was exempted was angina.
I have a heart condition.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
I want to go into politics,
Mr Foyle.
Do you think the people of Hastings
would vote for someone
with a weak heart?
You feel they'd sooner vote
for someone who lies?
I think you're being a little harsh.
The next election may be tougher
than anyone thinks.
I just don't want to give
my political opponents
any ammunition, that's all.
I'm well enough to stand
for parliament, I know I am.
I want to serve my country,
Mr Foyle.
That may sound
hopelessly old-fashioned,
but I'm not gonna let this chance
pass me by.
Sir, did you notice the woman
leaving his office just then?
His assistant.
Mm.
I met her a few days ago with Edith.
They were both patients
of Dr Ziegler.
Know what he was treating her for?
No, but I have a pretty good idea.
Well, it's got to be one of them.
Major Kiefer or Martin Longmate.
They were both in the room.
Or it could have been
that curator chap, I suppose.
Michael Brown.
It could have been me.
Didn't like to mention it, sir.
What did you get on Griffiths'
military service?
Nothing, sir.
It's all definitely hush-hush.
I made a few calls,
but it's a brick wall.
But he was in the West Country.
As was Kiefer.
Has your letter arrived, by the way?
My promotion?
Mm-hm.
No, sir. Still no news.
Can't you give them a call, sir?
Chivvy them on a bit.
It'll come.
With your permission,
I'd like to talk to Mrs Hylton
while you're away. Certainly.
Where are you going, sir?
London.
You're about to run me
to the station.
Can I ask why
you're going to London, sir?
Course you can.
Miss Pierce?
Mr Foyle.
I was very surprised
to be getting your call.
I was very surprised to be making it,
quite honestly.
How's Hastings?
Much the same as here, I'd imagine.
We're just waiting.
The end of the war.
I understand Churchill and Stalin
are negotiating the exact moment
to announce it.
Meanwhile, I can reliably inform you
that you can expect an announcement
on the wireless this evening.
What, that it's over?
No.
The Ministry of Information
is going to announce
that there'll be
an announcement tomorrow.
In other words, the announcement
of the announcement.
Good to see the spirit of Colonel
Blimp is still alive and well.
You said you wanted my help.
That makes a pleasant change.
Well, since you've been so very
unhelpful on two separate occasions
during the course of the war so far,
I'm giving you a chance
to make up for it.
Point taken.
I just need some information.
Go on.
Sometime last year, maybe this,
in the west of England,
Devon perhaps, something happened.
A naval operation involving
the Americans on a beach, maybe.
Can you be a little more specific?
Well, no.
I just have one name. Griffiths.
Mark Griffiths, Royal Signals.
You've made inquiries?
Nobody will talk to me.
What makes you think
they'll talk to me?
I'll need a couple of hours.
All right.
Er... Where will you be?
Wherever you like.
How about Whitehall? Kingly Street
should be quiet enough.
You've seen -
there are crowds everywhere.
All waiting for the end.
Everyone's out there celebrating,
and here are you and I,
still stuck in the shadows.
I thought you liked the shadows.
Five o'clock. Good to see you again.
Mrs Hylton?
Yes.
Sergeant Milner, Hastings Police.
I've come about Dr Ziegler.
Well, you'd better come in.
Thank you.
Are you on your own?
No, my husband Eddie's upstairs,
asleep.
Demobbed?
Yeah, he was in Italy.
You don't remember meeting me,
do you?
No.
I was with my wife, Edith.
She's pregnant.
Your husband doesn't need to know
anything about this, but I do.
Please.
When you met my wife
at Dr Ziegler's surgery,
you were heavily pregnant.
Where is the baby?
She's with my mother.
And your husband has no idea?
He suspects. He knows something's
not right, but...
I do love him.
But he's been away for four years.
I was on my own.
I wish it hadn't happened,
but it did.
And now he's back, and I've been
tearing myself apart.
I can't tell him - he'd kill me.
But Dr Ziegler knew.
I was terrified he'd tell Eddie
about me, about me and the baby.
Is that why you went to the museum?
To see him?
No.
I went to see Martin. Mr Longmate.
He's the father.
Right.
We didn't mean for it to happen.
He was on his own, too.
His wife had died in a bombing raid.
I felt sorry for him, and...
one night we were working late...
Does he know the baby's his?
He wanted to get rid of it.
But I couldn't do that.
So then he said he knew people.
Said he could arrange
for it to be adopted.
And that's what we were gonna do.
But then your husband came home.
I've been so scared.
I don't want to lose him,
I couldn't bear that.
If he finds out...
Eddie mentioned he was seeing
Dr Ziegler.
I panicked.
I had to talk to someone,
and I thought Martin
would know what to do.
So I went to the museum.
But it was too late.
You didn't see Mr Longmate?
No. He'd already gone.
That's all I need to know.
Will you be coming back?
No.
I have everything.
I'll see myself out.
DOOR CLOSES
I heard.
Everything.
You like to inhabit
dangerous territory, Mr Foyle.
Well, not by choice.
This time,
even you should tread carefully.
I've stuck my neck out for you,
and I have to say,
I felt a very cold breeze indeed.
Operation Tiger -
does that mean anything to you?
Might.
Slapton Sands in Devon.
What happened there?
Nothing happened there.
That's the official verdict,
and that's how it shall remain
for years to come.
Unofficially?
You never spoke to me,
I never gave you this,
and it would be better
if nobody ever found out
you knew anything about it.
All right.
Just remember, a war always hides
a great many dirty secrets.
This has been a long war...
..and this secret's very dirty
indeed.
He wanted her to get rid of it,
but she refused,
so he was going to get it adopted.
It turns out Martin Longmate's not
as straightforward as he seems.
Was he ever?
Sergeant.
What's going on?
Oh, nothing, sir.
It's er...in the...
It's just that cartoon, sir.
You probably don't read it. Jane.
Not a stitch on today, I see.
You probably noticed that.
Yes, sir. The lads and I
were just commenting on it.
I suppose it's to mark the end
of the war.
Well, not a moment too soon,
if that's anything to go by.
Right, sir.
We're just off to Wilder Road,
take a peek at the new HQ.
I should.
Paul! It's here.
I should open it.
I've got it.
Darling!
Sir,
thank you.
Congratulations.
Oh!
Edith?
I came here at such a pace, I...
Paul, I think it's coming!
Er... Chair.
Get Brooke back, will you?
What's the um...hospital number?
383.
Where's Sam?
She's um...with the Servicemen's
Association this morning.
Oh, I'm sorry, Paul.
Don't worry.
(GROANS)
Missed him, sir.
Never mind. Thank you.
(DIALS NUMBER)
That's it. We're nearly there.
Thank you, sir.
Good luck.
I think it's time you explained.
If it's all in there,
what else do you want to know?
I want to hear it from your point
of view. I wasn't there.
It was a training exercise
at Slapton Sands,
for the landings at Utah Beach.
Operation Tiger.
A year ago, April 28.
I'd been transferred to
the amphibious truck company,
working on floating harbours
and LSTs.
Landing ships, tanks,
that kind of stuff.
I was billeted
with the 4th Infantry division.
I got to know a lot of the boys.
That's what most of them were.
Just kids.
A few years older than my own.
Anyway, one night, right in
the middle of an exercise...
..nine German U-boats
came out of nowhere.
And there was a whole fleet of LSTs,
just sitting there,
right in front of them.
So they opened fire.
749 of our soldiers and sailors
killed.
It was all hushed up.
They had to think about morale.
So why did nobody warn the kids
on the LSTs
that the Germans were on their way?
Well, I'll tell you.
They did.
But it turned out
there'd been a typing mistake.
Someone had sent out
the wrong radio frequency.
Just a couple of misplaced numbers,
that's all.
So no-one on the LSTs
heard anything,
and all those people died.
And that was Griffiths.
Took me a year to find out.
Talking to the right people.
Asking a lot of questions
about something
that wasn't supposed to
have happened.
But he was the one responsible.
Griffiths was a major
with the Royal Signals Corps,
Allied Liaison.
He did the right thing, then,
killing himself. No!
You don't understand.
I see those kids.
Every night, I see them.
I can't get them out of my head.
I just wanted him to accept
responsibility, that's all.
I thought if he did that,
then maybe I could make sense of it.
Well, the fact is
nobody knows what happened.
Radio frequencies were changed,
the Germans noticed
increased radio traffic.
While the corvettes didn't show up,
the LSTs were in the wrong formation,
so whatever you may think,
it wasn't one man's mistake.
Griffiths was in charge,
and at the end of it,
they just shipped him out,
they got rid of him.
As far as he was concerned,
that was the end of it.
He just ran out.
And it was really worth
hounding him to death?
I didn't want him to die.
That wasn't the idea, I swear to it.
I don't know what I wanted.
I should never have come.
Well, it's a bit late for that.
So now what?
From the law's point of view,
there's not a case against you
that would stand up in a court.
So you're free to go.
So that's it, then?
I think so, don't you?
Funny thing about war, Christopher -
people change.
Or are you the only one
who remained above it all?
So what are you going to do
with yourself, Sam?
After the war?
I don't even want to think about it.
But it looks as if advertising
and politics are out.
How about you?
I don't know.
Will you stay in Hastings?
Mm, I suppose so.
I'll go fishing with Dad,
and we'll spend some time together.
I haven't really got anywhere else
to go.
Well, will you fly again?
My eyesight is more or less shot
to pieces with the sinusitis, so no.
I think that's finished.
You'll have to go into business,
then.
Or maybe you can join the police.
Mm. Then you can be MY driver.
I don't think so!
(CHUCKLES)
That's the worst of it, Sam.
This feeling I have that maybe
the best of my life is over.
Flying the dawn patrol,
the friends I made.
Even the ones I lost.
How can I work in an office,
travel in and out on a 37 bus,
after what I've been through?
How can any of us?
Maybe you could write.
You used to write reams of poetry.
Well, I used to scribble a bit,
I suppose.
What was that poem you told me?
Oh, I don't remember.
Oh, please, Andrew.
Actually, I wrote one quite
recently, just before I left Malta.
Go on.
I don't know if it was any good
or not, but...
It's called "All Clear."
They've sounded out
the last all clear
And told us,
those who made it here...
..That very soon
we'll hold once more
Those things that we held dear.
Yet nothing's clear to me.
I gaze from darkness
to a summer haze.
And though they part, the clouds
of war lead only to uncertain days.
Do you really think that?
I think that's very sad.
(GROANS) Sam, I'm sorry.
I've got to watch out for myself.
I'm beginning to sound like
an old man.
Well, you don't look like one.
Sam, why don't we get married?
What?!
I mean it.
You don't know
what you're going to do,
I don't know what I'm going to do -
it makes sense to not know
what we're going to do together.
Is that why you invited me here?
Don't get angry with me.
I said I'd be your friend.
I said I'd see you again,
but that's all.
It's unfair to ask for more.
Especially in so unromantic
a fashion.
All right.
But I might as well tell you,
I'm going to work on you, Sam.
Until one day
you'll change your mind about me,
and forgive me
for being such a bloody fool.
And you will marry me.
Oh, yes?
If only because you'd secretly love
to have my dad
as your father-in-law.
Hm...
Let's drive back and get a pint.
All right.
Everything all right?
Mr Longmate, could I have a word?
Of course. Shall we use my office?
Probably wise.
Please, follow me.
Is this about Dr Ziegler?
Who else?
Well, please, sit down.
No, I won't stay longer
than I have to.
Perhaps you should.
Should I?
With a heart condition like yours,
you can't be too careful.
That's very considerate, but um...
I'll be fine, thank you.
How can I help you?
Well, we hoped you might help with
whatever you can remember
about your military service medical.
It was a long time ago, Mr Foyle.
I can't see why you'd be interested.
Some confusion about the details,
apparently.
Might you remember
where it took place?
Er... London,
though precisely where
I would be less sure about.
Mm-hm. Examining doctor, perhaps?
Afraid not.
I see.
Though there's probably
a record of it somewhere,
if you think it's important.
Well, there's um...
there's a record of it in my pocket.
A doctor's letter
recording an appointment for...
Martin Longmate, April 23rd, 1941.
At a surgery in London, Hampstead,
with signed confirmation of angina
and exemption from active service.
Would this be your appointment?
You'll forgive me pointing out,
but if you have the information,
I fail to see why you're
questioning me regarding it.
And why on earth you consider there
to be a problem.
Well, certainly not a problem for me.
It just looks as if it might be
for you.
It's a question of the signature here
of the examining doctor.
You're saying it's not genuine?
No, far from it.
I'm saying it's Dr Ziegler's.
Longmate. We've met, I think.
No, I don't think so.
Martin Longmate.
I feel sure I know the name.
So why say you hadn't met?
It was four years ago,
for God's sake.
I do meet a lot of people.
They all give you medicals?
Not a very good reason, perhaps,
is because you never had.
Because the Martin Longmate
he examined wasn't you, was it?
You don't know
what you're talking about.
He examined the man
you paid 150 to take your place,
who does have angina,
and who had a very nice line
in acquiring exemption certificates
for those interested
in avoiding military service,
until his arrest the other day.
He sends his regards.
It was actually er...200.
Was it?
Oh.
We'll remind him. Thank you.
Life, eh?
Almost the end of the war
and you run into the very last person
in England you want to see.
I panicked.
When he asked me about my exemption,
I told him it was my eyesight
because...if I'd said angina,
he might have put two and two
together.
There was too much to lose -
my...political ambitions,
my business.
And then when I heard him
asking to speak to you...
Actually, Mr Foyle, there was one
thing I wanted to talk to you about.
Um... It's a private matter.
I wonder if I might call in
at the police station.
Any time you like.
'All I could think of
was getting rid of Ziegler
before he could talk to you.
And that's exactly what I did.'
(GROANS)
What gave me away?
You were the first to leave
the committee room,
but Kiefer was the first out of the
building, according to the doorman.
Ah.
All so unnecessary and unfortunate.
What do you mean?
All Ziegler wanted to speak to me
about was Griffiths,
who was in a very bad state.
Ziegler was concerned.
And unfortunate, because er...
having evaded the draft,
murdered a member
of the medical profession,
tried to avoid detection
to feather your own nest,
I'd have said
you were a born politician.
But, the law being what it is,
hanging is perhaps the very best way
you can serve your country.
Make the most, lads.
It's a bona fide French champagne.
Well, congratulations, Mr Milner.
Just celebrating the new arrival,
sir. Hope you don't mind.
Well, of course not. Boy or a girl?
A girl, sir. Thank heavens.
Goodbye to Winston Milner.
But she wants to call her
Clementine - Mrs Churchill.
Where's this come from?
The evidence room, sir.
Somehow the label came adrift
and sadly, we couldn't place it.
Oh, yeah? Well, congratulations.
Cheers.
Congratulations.
Sir!
Cheers.
'The Prime Minister, The Right
Honourable Winston Churchill.'
CHURCHILL: 'Yesterday morning,
at 2:41am...
..at General Eisenhower's
headquarters,
General Jodl, the representative
of the German High Command,
and our Grand Admiral Donitz,
the designated head
of the German state,
signed the act of
unconditional surrender
of all German land,
sea and air forces in Europe
to the Allied Expeditionary Force.'
It's over.
I can't believe it.
Sir, I'd better get back to Edith
and er...Clementine.
Of course.
Good luck.
Thank you, sir.
And er...if you don't mind, sir,
I promised the lads that they could
join in the celebrations.
It seems only right.
Absolutely. Go ahead.
Cheers, sir. Enjoy the champers.
Thank you.
Come on, lads.
They said you drove Milner
and his wife to the hospital, sir.
I did.
But I thought you couldn't drive.
Are you telling me
that all these years...
I've never actually at any time
said I couldn't drive,
I just preferred not to.
So you never really needed me?
I wouldn't say that.
All hell's breaking loose outside.
You ought to come and join us.
I will.
I'm going to dance all night.
Will you dance with me?
I'll dance with anybody.
But especially you.
Are you coming, Dad?
No, I'll catch you up. You go on.
All right.
Are you sure? We'll never find you.
I'll make sure you do. Off you go.
Andrew.
# It's a lovely day tomorrow
# Tomorrow is a lovely day
# Come and feast
your tear-dimmed eyes
# On tomorrow's clear blue skies
# If today your heart is weary
# If every little thing looks grey
# Just forget your troubles
# And learn to say
# Tomorrow is a lovely day #
Sync by georgel 24
ITFC Subtitles
KATHARINE SEABROOK & JANE PARIS