[O.R. Chatter]
[Hawkeye]
#Are the stars out tonight #
[B.J.] No, they're not.
- #I don't know if it's cloudy or bright #
- [B.J.] Cloudy.
# 'Cause I only have eyes #
Clamp.
- Clamp.
- Clamp. Sorry, Doctor.
# For you, dear ##
You seem preoccupied, Donovan.
Is anything wrong?
- No, nothing. Thank you.
- If it's me, I can always
move to another war. Clamp.
Will you pipe down, Pierce!
We're working over here.
What do you think we're doing
over here, playing hearts?
You're always looking
for a fight.
I've certainly come
to the right place. Suture.
I don't mind singing
in the O.R.
I'm liable to bust out
myself any minute.
Oh, go right ahead, Colonel.
It'll do your old heart...
middle-aged heart good, sir.
[Chuckling]
You certainly have
a winning way, Junior.
- Colonel, I wonder if you could
help me with a problem.
- Well, I hope so.
I haven't received a letter
from my fiance in four days.
- You want me to write you one?
- Not much I can do, Major.
Maybe Penobscott's busy.
- Yeah. Learning to write.
- I'll ignore that
jealousy-inspired wisecrack.
- Has anybody been getting mail?
- Suture. I've been getting
fan mail from North Korea.
They want me to play
Panmunjom after the war.
Peace talks are playing there now.
It's a tough act to follow.
I got mail. I got a wonderful letter
from my old Sunday school teacher.
Tell us about it,
and I'll step on your foot.
I'm worried about Donald.
He works so hard.
- Maybe he strained himself thinking.
- Don't you wish.
He has a mind
like a steel trap.
That could be dangerous. If he gets an idea,
he'll snap his neck and swallow his face.
I feel like Rip Van Winkle.
How long have we been in there?
[Donovan]
Seven and a halfhours.
If I weren't certain
of being knighted, I'd resign.
- I wasn't much help to you doctors.
- You were fine.
I'm afraid I've got
too many things on my mind.
We all do. I can't decide on
who to ask to the movies tonight.
- I'll bet it isn't me.
- Don't be so sure.
- Well, how about you?
- You're asking me after him?
Well, he turned me down. I'm on the
rebound now. This is your big chance.
- I don't play second fiddle.
- Forget the fiddle. What do you play?
- Solitaire.
- Come on. What do you say?
Dinner in the Mess Tent...
the room that floats in fat.
Followed by a rotten motion picture.
It's a perfect evening.
- I'm busy.
- Going to the auto show?
Post-op. I'm helping B.J.
Follow up on some cases.
You're doing time
with Hunnicutt?
- Who sentenced you to that?
- I volunteered.
You're turning down a chance to be seen
with the Porfirio Rubirosa of Ouijongbu.
- What a tongue twister.
- Oh, you've heard about me.
- Maybe next time, Captain.
- I'll have my florist send...
- an armful of pussy willows to your tent.
- It won't help.
How about a box
of dehydrated chocolates?
- Poor girl's gone bonkers.
- Who, Donovan?
Yeah. She turned down a chance to hold
hands with me in the flicks tonight.
Ah. Someday she'll look back
and wanna pound her head on a rock.
Is she actually
helping you out in post-op?
Is that so crazy?
You two got the mutual
irresistables for each other?
[Laughs]
Come on.
Tell me, who's the most
devoted family man in the world?
Mickey Rooney.
- Who gets an "A" in fidelity?
- R.C.A. Victor.
No. You, both times.
So how come she turns down
a date with Dr. Jekyll...
- to go work in the lab with Mr. Hyde?
- She's helping me with cases.
I could use a little
of that kind of help myself.
Hawk, her husband's
back in the States...
and, uh, their marriage
is in trouble.
Gee, I can't understand why.
They're only 12,000 miles apart.
She's really upset about it,
and work's good therapy.
- Are you sure there's nothing
going on between you two kids?
- Honest.
- A little hanky-panky after taps?
- Scout's honor.
- Before? During?
- No.
- I'm happily married.
- Oh, yeah?
I thought that was
a contradiction in terms.
Colonel, how'd you like
a delicious cup of coffee?
- I'd love it.
- Me too. This stuff stinks.
- I just don't understand
why Donald hasn't written.
- Maybe there's another woman.
- Fat chance.
- Another man?
Donald is so devoted
it's scary.
I can certainly tell
when someone loves me.
When you kiss him,
he clicks his heels.
- I can feel his loving arms
all the way from Tokyo.
- Not bad for a stocky guy.
Maybe he's involved in some of that spy stuff,
like parachuting into North Korea.
- That's possible.
- Is he qualified?
- He's made 126 jumps.
- Once from a plane.
Mail call, Colonel.
You got a letter from Mrs. Colonel.
- Bless the dear girl.
- Captain Hunnicutt, you got
three from your wife.
- You got three?
- Gotta write 'em to get 'em.
Oh, I don't know. Melville wrote
Moby Dick, and he never wrote back.
- Probably on a cruise.
- Major Houlihan, a letter
from your lieutenant colonel.
Oh! Wonderful.
Wait a minute!
- This letter has been opened. Look.
- Sometimes they come like that.
And sometimes they're opened
by creepy company clerks...
who like to peek
at intimate personal passages.
- Come on, Margaret. That's uncalled for.
- It's not fair.
Yeah, and it wasn't even
very intimate either.
- Nosy jerk.
- Come on, Margaret.
Smell your letter and read it.
- Oh, this is terrible.
- What is it?
- Did peace break out?
- It's Donald. He's in Tokyo Army Hospital.
- What's wrong with him?
- He doesn't say, brave darling.
- Could be just a checkup.
- Maybe he's having a neck installed.
Or getting
his upper lip starched.
You're just jealous
because Donald is full-lipped.
- I'm getting excited.
- Eat your pudding.
- How you doing, Donovan?
- Okay.
Obviously. Anything I can do?
- No.
- Bad news from home?
It's a letter from my old man...
a Dear Jane.
He started out with, uh,
"Dear Carrie...
I just don't know how
to tell you this."
But he found a way.
Yeah, he did.
Listen, uh, why don't you skip
post-op tonight?
- No. I'll be there.
- You don't have to. I can handle it.
So can I.
- Okay.
- B.J.?
- Yeah?
- Thank you.
Sure.
You know, when you're hurting,
sometimes it helps to talk about it.
My wife bottles things up,
keeps everything inside.
So I get in her way
in the kitchen.
I keep nudging her till she gets
sore enough to swing at me.
Then out it comes...
the anger, tears...
the problem... everything.
- You must be a good husband.
- Yeah, but we miss a lot of dinners.
[Chuckles]
- Would you like to talk about it?
- N-No. Thanks.
Just like Peggy... stubborn.
I'll meet you in the kitchen.
- You can cork me two good ones.
- [Laughs]
To be honest, I'd like to talk.
But not here. Someplace where
we wouldn't be interrupted.
- How about Guam?
- How about my tent?
- Oh, that wouldn't do.
- Why not?
It wouldn't look right.
People might get the wrong idea.
You wanna talk in your tent,
we'll talk in your tent.
After I'm finished here,
I'll stop by.
Thanks, B.J.
No problem. Now beat it.
- [Snoring]
- Corporal! Corporal O'Reilly!
- Betty!
- [Screams]
- What are you doing!
- What?
- What am I doing? I don't know.
- You kissed a superior officer!
- I did? I didn't mean to.
- Why did you do that?
I don't know. I was sleeping,
and I was dreaming about...
- It's personal!
- Don't you ever do that again!
- I won't. Never!
- Hurry up. Get up. I want you
to make a call for me.
- Oh, okay.
- Get up. I want you to call Tokyo.
- Tokyo Army Hospital.
- Right. I got it.
I want to speak to Lieutenant
Colonel Donald Penobscott.
- Yeah, I know.
He's your whatchamacallit.
- My fiance, Corporal!
Right. Sparky? Yeah, Sparky, listen.
Get me Tokyo Army Hospital, quick.
And we won't ever mention to Lt. Col.
Penobscott about what just happened, will we?
- Oh, never, never, ever.
- 'Cause he's big and strong
and insanely jealous.
- And he's got the bite of a bulldog.
- Who said that?
Nobody. I mean, l-I just
overheard it someplace.
- Are you working that thing?
- Yes, right! Hello, Operator!
Yes. Ma'am, please, get me
Lt. Donald Col. Penobscott.
- A patient.
- A patient. And it's an emergency.
- What's going on in here?
Who are you calling, Radar?
- Oh, it's for me, Colonel.
We're calling my fiance in Tokyo.
I've been worried sick.
What? What, Operator?
- But... Ma'am, he's not accepting any calls.
- What?
- [Gasps] Leave a message.
- A message, Operator.
- Tell him to call Maj. Margaret Houlihan.
- Call Maj. Margaret Houlihan.
- MASH 4077.
- Worried to death.
- Love and kisses.
Aren't you in
a premature panic, Major?
He's not taking any calls.
This could be very serious.
- Maybe he's just resting.
- Colonel, request permission to go to Tokyo...
and attend my fiance
before he dies.
Why don't you relax,
find out what's wrong.
I'll take a chopper in the morning
to Kimpo and hitch a ride to Tokyo.
No, Major. Let's be patient
for another day.
I'm not tying up a chopper
and losing a nurse...
just to find out Penobscott
has a simple pimple on his butt.
"A simple pimple
on his butt"?
Radar, where'd you
get that lipstick?
Maj. Houlihan.
It was an accident!
- I told you to keep your mouth shut!
- Right. She did.
- It was an accident.
- Of course.
- Good night.
- Good night, Major.
[Clears Throat]
Why don't you get some rest, Romeo?
I thought I had a good marriage.
The war killed it.
"I wish you were writing
this letter instead of me.
"It'd be so much easier.
"I know I'll always love you.
- But I met someone..."
- Carrie.
I'm gonna make a little prediction.
One fine day, believe it
or not, you'll get over all this.
The hurt will pass.
You'll forgive him, and you'll
be ready to love again.
- It seems impossible.
- I know.
I know, but someday you'll be glad
that guy's outta your hair.
- A new fella will come along.
- [Chuckles]
Nice, bright guy...
a sucker for eyes like yours.
- [Sniffles]
- And you'll start dating.
He'll fall madly
in love with you.
And you'll turn around
and clobber the poor slob.
[Sighs]
- [Yawns]
- You want me to wake you up
when you're finished eating?
I didn't get any sleep
last night.
Gee, I dreamt I was dancing with Major
Houlihan, and Betty Grable woke me up.
Somethin' like that.
- Morning.
- You were out awful late last night.
- Lots to do in post-op.
- You were gone when I woke up this morning.
- Couldn't sleep.
If I didn't know better,
I'd say you were out all night.
- Mm-hmm.
- You could've called.
- Mother and I were worried sick.
- Dad? Shut up.
Ah, I hate to see them grow up.
I just hope you weren't wasting
your time with some nurse.
Let's say I was sitting up
with a sick friend.
Good. Start at the beginning
and tell me all about it.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Donovan, you look like a new woman, not that
there was anything wrong with the old one.
- Thanks. I feel better.
- Well, why shouldn't we all feel good?
Our work is so rewarding... always lending
a helping hand, doing unto others.
Hawk? Your mouth runneth over.
I'm just teasing. I mean,
do I know what I'm saying?
Whatever it is,
I don't mean it. Should I go?
- Just stop talking.
- I will as soon as I get
my foot out of my mouth.
I think I'll put it someplace else.
Ah, I'm being paged at the pool.
Well, you two carry on.
[Laughs] Strike that.
This is me leaving.
Here I go.
Bye. So long.
- Hello?
- Hi.
Anybody in there?
I'm sorry. I'm-I'm
a little, uh, preoccupied.
- Anything wrong?
- Oh, no. No.
I, uh... I see
you're trying the eggs.
You're braver than I am.
Will you excuse me, Carrie?
I've got a lot of work to do.
- [Knocking]
- One second, please.
- Major Houlihan.
- Major Burns.
- Am I disturbing you?
- Not yet.
Now you are.
What is it?
Firstly, may I say I'm sincerely
unhappy your fiance is terribly sick.
He's not terribly sick.
All I know is that he's in the hospital.
Oh, when they don't tell you,
it's usually pretty bad.
They haven't not told me.
I just haven't been able to find out.
And I'm sincerely not happy
you're unhappy.
Thank you, Frank.
Anything else?
Oh, yes. Uh, I have this little gift
to present to you.
- Oh.
- It's just a little inexpensive
token of sincerity.
How lovely.
A Japanese umbrella.
- Made in Texas.
- Thank you, Frank.
- That was very sweet.
- Well, giving is what it's all about.
We had a fine relationship
once, Margaret...
and this just goes to prove
that there's no hard feelings.
Oh, I get cranky at times, but...
we're still pals, okay?
- What a nice speech.
- It's off-the-cuff.
Thank you, Frank.
I hope we can always be friends.
Oh, why not?
I'm always ready if you need me.
I appreciate that, and I'm really
anxious for you to meet Donald.
I think about you in here
and me just across the compound.
- I think about the good times
we had. I'll never forget 'em.
- Neither will I, Frank.
- A lot of people knock this war,
but I can't. It gave me you.
- Oh, thank you.
Our friendship is real. It's warm.
It's honest. It's... convenient.
- Frank!
- I'm doing my best, Margaret!
- But it's not enough.
I can't stand it anymore.
- Frank, stop it!
- Hold on to yourself!
- Not me! You!
- Let go of me! You fake! You fake!
- Ow! Ow! Ow!
- Don't break it! I can get my money back!
- You pretend you're my friend!
Take it home,
you phony baloney!
[Whimpering]
Oh, Donald.
- How do you feel?
- Terrible.
- You wanna talk about it?
- No.
Nothing like an old fink
to tell your troubles to.
- I don't wanna talk about it.
- Come on.
Pour your heart out.
I'm a doctor. I can fix it.
[Sighs]
Hawk, you're looking at a guy
that fell off the fidelity wagon.
I thought I heard a thump
sometime last night.
And I'm miserable.
I'm a happily married man.
Not like Frank Burns is happy...
because his wife
owns real estate.
I adore my wife
and my kid and my marriage.
I know.
I don't like being unfaithful.
I'm not lookin' around.
- I'm lucky to have what I've got.
- You're right. You are lucky.
God help me.
B.J., you stumbled last night.
That's all.
You were helping somebody,
and it got out of hand.
- You made a mistake.
- I sure did.
- What's that?
- I'm writing Peg about it.
Wrong, wrong, wrong!
Don't be an idiot.
You made one lousy goof, and you wanna
punish yourself, but don't punish her.
Do not tell Peg. Don't tell anybody
what you just told me.
- This will pass.
- Like a kidney stone.
Simply take a vow.
Raise your right hand.
Come on. Come on.
I promise to be a good and faithful husband,
to write nice, cheerful letters home...
to think of Peg often, and to keep
my fat hands off Nurse Donovan.
Do you vow?
- I vow.
- I feel better about you already.
- Thanks.
- My pleasure.
There's probably a career for me
in saving marriages.
You know, I'm gonna
take a vow too.
- Good for you.
- I, Hawkeye Pierce, vow...
that someday I will take a vow
just like his. Amen.
But right now, I'm a little late
for a very important date.
No time to say hello, good-bye.
I'm late, I'm late, I'm late.
Lieutenant,
what can I do you for?
Oh, uh, it's a personal problem,
Colonel.
- Uh, my husband wants a divorce.
- Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
- Stateside, is he?
- Yes, Colonel.
Well, it's a wonder we don't have
more of this kind of casualty.
They say absence makes
the heart grow fonder...
but I think that's a lot
of buffalo bagels.
Excuse me.
Sit down, Donovan.
Um, I'd like a transfer, Colonel.
I'm making a mess of things
here at 4077.
You volunteered for this duty, Lieutenant,
and you've been doing good work.
- We need you.
- I'd be happier elsewhere.
If you've got problems...people problems...
I'd like you to work them out.
They don't mean anything compared
to what these boys are going through.
- Don't you agree?
- Yes, Colonel.
I don't want you leaving 'cause
you're hitting a rough stretch of road.
Hang on for a while. It's my opinion
you can ride it out. Okay?
- I'll try.
- Thank you, Lieutenant.
- Colonel Potter, sir.
- What do you want, Klinger?
- Justice, sir.
- Justice in the army?
- You're crazy.
- You might say that, Colonel.
Uh-oh. I don't like
those moist eyes.
Sir, you ever heard of
the Toledo Strangler?
No.
He's struck eight times.
The terror of Toledo.
- Kills only women motorcycle cops.
- So?
The fiend stands before you.
- You are the Toledo Strangler?
- I confess I am.
Extradite me. Send me back
to Toledo for a lengthy jury trial.
- Why do you do this, Klinger?
- The sirens, sir.
The sirens on the motorcycles
drive me bananas.
- Have you read this?
- What do you mean?
It says here the last murder
took place only two weeks ago.
This man's an imposter...
some nut trying to get in on my act.
Beat it, Klinger.
- But, sir, what about the newspaper clipping?
- What about it?
It says the killer's from Toledo...
and always uses a yellow scarf.
- I rest my case.
- Paste it in your scrapbook.
I could strangle somebody for you.
I don't mind auditioning.
- A person of your choice?
- Some other time.
Colonel, I don't expect you
to buy everything I bring in here...
but maybe just once, okay?
Out, Klinger, before I call
a woman motorcycle cop.
[Clicks Heels]
- Doctor? Captain Hunnicutt.
- What's wrong?
This one looks shocky.
He's waxy, and his lips are blue.
- What are his vital signs?
- Pulse 120. B.P. 94 over 52.
- Give me another unit of plasma.
- Right.
Nurse.
Yeah. Thanks.
- It was a good pickup, Carrie. Alert as hell.
- Thanks.
We're gonna have to
watch him for a while.
- How are you feeling?
- Why do you ask?
- What?
- What do you care?
Those are the first civil words
you've spoken to me in a week.
- You're exaggerating a bit, aren't you?
- No, I'm not.
You've been salty as hell,
a bear with hangnails.
- I wasn't aware of it.
- Wanna talk about it?
- No.
- Why not?
'Cause the last time
we talked, we didn't.
That's what
we ought to talk about.
B.J., it's important to me.
Okay.
Nurse.
Keep an eye on him for a few minutes.
I'll be right outside.
[Wind Blowing]
I know how you feel.
You feel guilty,
but you're blaming me.
No, I'm not.
I'm blaming myself.
Only partly. I get your anger
every time I come near you.
I don't need it.
Carrie, I'm sorry.
But you know what happened.
I got this enormous attack
of the guilts.
I've never done that before.
I'm hopelessly, passionately
in love with my wife.
- What's wrong with that?
- I don't want to mess that up.
I feel like I've betrayed her.
Why? Because you were kind
and considerate and sweet to me?
Because I was in despair one night,
and you helped me through it?
Are you ashamed of it?
No, of course not, but there
was more to it than that.
We didn't plan that.
We're still human beings, you know,
no matter how hard we try not to be.
Yes, I know,
and I'm still afraid.
- Of what?
- Of you.
Because you're right here...
and you're so attractive
and so close.
- And so vulnerable.
- Yes.
- You don't trust yourself.
- [Scoffs]
B.J., just because
I'm across the compound...
doesn't mean you can waltz
into my tent whenever you want to.
I needed you that night,
and you were there.
I'll always love you for that.
It doesn't mean
it's ever gonna happen again.
I can work out
my own problem.
I don't expect you
to be the answer to it.
[Sighs]
Does that make it easier?
Yes... and no.
We can be friends.
Yes, we can.
Closer than most.
[Chuckles]
Still friends.
Carrie...
you're very special.
I like you too.
Okay. Let's go back
to work, friend.
Hello! Hello!
Lt. Donald Col. Penobscott?
Yes. Maj. Houlihan calling.
- Thank heaven!
- Thank Radar.
Donald? Margaret.
How are you?
Oh, darling, I've been worried sick.
I was just saying l...
Colonel, Corporal, may I make
my call in private, please?
- Certainly.
- Sure.
Donald, how are you?
Darling, what's happened to you?
Oh, no! No!
Colonel, Corporal,
come back in here, please!
- What is it, Major?
- It's Donald. He's hurt himself...
a hernia doing the rope climb
on the obstacle course.
Donald, you're always
training so hard.
Colonel, request permission
to go to him, please.
- We're very busy, Major.
- But he's had a hernia operation.
- We need you here.
- He won't let me go.
- It's this stupid war.
- She's right. It's the war.
Colonel, Corporal, may I complete
my call in private, please?
- He'll be out of action
for about four weeks, Major.
- Never mind!
Donald, you've gotta be
more careful! The rope climb...
- A double hernia!
- [Potter] Eight weeks.
Oh, Donald! Donald,
you can't do this to me.
You have to be a little more considerate.
After all, you're an engaged person.