^^ [ Woman Vocalizing ]
[ Man Narrating ]
Prevlously on The Bible.
Human failings led to the great flood.
Wrong choices, wrong decisions.
[ Narrator ]
After Noah, a new beginning...
and a promise for Abraham.
God has spoken to me.
He will lead us to a new home.
He has promised descendants
as numerous as the stars.
[ Narrator ]
To help the Israelites fulfill the promise...
God sent Moses to free them from slavery.
Lord!
Joshua led them into the promised land.
Jericho is ours!
[ Shouts ]
[ All Shouting ]
[ Chanting ]
lsrael! lsrael!
[ Narrator ]
But the Israelites faced brutal opposltlon...
from the Philistines.
Some dared to fight back.
- [ Groans ]
- [ Shouts ]
[ Grunting ]
[ People Screaming ]
But not even Samson could overcome them.
The prophet SamueI
led the Israelites in God's name...
but the people wanted more-
someone to lead them in battle .
- What do you want?
- A king.
A king? They become tyrants.
[ Phineas ]
Not lf they are chosen by God.
Saul, l anoint you
the first king of lsrael.
May l, as God's prophet...
help you in any way l can.
[ Narrator ] But is any man good enough
to rule God's kingdom?
[ Horses Whinny ln Distance ]
[ Saul ]
Are the men ready?
They're ready.
Where is Samuel?
He should be here.
We must make a sacrifice before we attack.
We cannot wait any longer.
[ Bleating ]
[ Samuel ]
Saul! May God forgive you!
Samuel.
Where were you?
Seven days we have waited. Seven days.
My men are deserting.
Then be a king.
Leave the job of priest to me.
Do you think God values
your sacrifice more than mine?
Samuel.
God instructs you-
kill everyone...
and everything.
[ Narrator ]
A new era in Israelite history is beginning-
the perlod of prophets and kings.
They must work together
to secure the promised land.
[ Horse Whinnying ]
- [ Groans ]
- [ Man ] To arms!
[ Screaming ]
[ Man ]
Victory!
[ Men Chanting ]
Saul! Saul! Saul!
God is with me!
- God is with me!
- [ Cheering ]
You had one task...
one simple command from God.
- Destroy everything.
- We followed his commands.
Then what is this bleating
of goats in my ears?
What is this lowing of cattle
and wailing of lambs?
- Can the dead cry out?
- [ Laughing ]
And who is this pagan king?
[ Saul ]
He is to be put to death later.
When the Lord says spare, you spare.
When he says kill-
- [ Knife Plunges ]
- [ Groans ]
Samuel!
You are our prophet, but l am your king.
What the Lord gives, he can take away.
Are these God's words or yours?
Your descendants could have ruled
for over a thousand years.
But today...
God has forsaken you.
More divine words?
[ Cloth Rips ]
God has torn your power from you.
He wants a man after his own heart.
- Bring me wine.
- Sire.
Do you hear me? Now!
Yes, sire!
Perhaps l have been hasty.
l should ask Samuel's forgiveness.
- [ Liquid Pouring ]
- Bring Samuel to me.
He's gone, Majesty.
Gone?
Samuel!
[ Bleating ]
[ Narrator ]
After Saulls disobedlence...
God commands his prophet Samuel...
to find a new king.
- [ Snarling ]
- [ Bleating ]
[ Snarling Continues ]
[ Air Whlpping ]
- [ Thud ]
- [ Yelping ]
Young man!
What is your name?
David, sir.
My name is David.
l anoint you, David of Bethlehem...
to be the next king of lsrael...
once Saul is dead.
Father, what's wrong?
Tell me what's wrong.
Nothing is wrong.
lt was a great victory.
l need rest. That is all.
Sleep. Sleep.
Lord, forgive your servant!
[ Groans ]
^^ [ Soothing ]
[ Narrator ]
In time...
Davld becomes an attendant
in Saulls court-
a king in walting.
[ Loud Clattering ]
[ Clattering Continues ]
The Philistine threat continues to grow.
[ Thudding Footsteps ]
Now they have a new champlon-
[ Footsteps Trampling ]
Goliath.
Will one of you fight me?
lsraelites, you win...
and the Philistines will be your slaves.
l win...
and you...
will be our slaves.
- Someone must fight him!
- Not you, Jonathan.
The warrior who defeats him...
will be a rich man.
[ Goliath ]
Not one man in lsrael?
Not one of God's people.
l'll do it.
[ Quietly ]
David.
You're no soldier. You're a shepherd.
Yes, a shepherd.
As l protect my sheep,
God will protect me.
[ Goliath ]
Where is your faith?
Where is your god?
l will kill him.
You'll need this.
l'll be better without it.
[ Shields Clattering ]
Yea, though l walk in the valley
of the shadow of death...
l fear no evil...
for you are with me.
Thy rod and staff...
they comfort me.
You anoint my head with oil.
My cup overflows.
Surely goodness and mercy
shall follow me...
all the days of my life.
[ Clattering Continues ]
[ Men Laughing ]
[ Helmet Clatters ]
lsrael has found a champion.
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughter Subsides ]
Don't waste my time, little boy.
You're too young to die.
l will fight you.
[ Groans ]
[ Cheering ]
Father, he did it.
David did it.
[ Grunts ]
[ Shouting ]
Let us make slaves of them!
David!
My wolf in shepherd's clothing.
You've saved my kingdom,
my shepherd warrior!
Come with me, brother.
[ Groans ]
[ Narrator ]
Davld joins Saulls army...
and battles the Philistines for decades.
He becomes a warrlor...
a leader...
a hero.
[ People Chanting ]
Saul! Saul! Saul!
[ Man ]
Saul has killed thousands!
Saul! Saul! Saul!
Saul! Saul!
You hear that, Father?
l hear.
[ Chanting Continues ]
Saul! Saul!
Saul! Saul! Saul!
[ Cheering Grows Louder ]
[ Man ]
David has killed tens of thousands!
[ People Chanting ]
David! David!
David! David! David!
- David! David!
- He deserves their praise.
He'll want my crown next.
David! David!
[ Jonathan Chattering ]
[ David ] l thought you were going
to fall off your horse.
[ Jonathan ]
l did fall off my horse.
l think l killed a man
when l landed on him.
There was one point,
there were two men in front of me.
David.
Come here.
So...
once again, you are our champion.
You have killed thousands.
Tens of thousands.
Of course.
Our people are very grateful to you.
The Lord blessed us all.
l would like to reward you.
l offer you my daughter, Michal.
l'm very honored, Majesty.
David, we're brothers now.
[ Laughs ]
ln return-
100 dead Philistines.
Hmm? What say you?
100 dead Philistines
slain by your own hand.
Father...
he's risked his life enough, no?
What if he doesn't return?
l shall return.
God willing.
You love him like a brother, don't you?
l do.
[ Saul ]
As Abel, no doubt, once loved Cain.
He wants our crown.
- Can't you see?
- No.
- He's loyal to us both.
- Nonsense!
[ Footsteps Marching ]
[ Door Clanks ]
[ David ]
A few mementos for you.
And these.
Trophies taken from each of their bodies.
[ Flies Buzzing ]
- [ Bag Thuds ]
- From a hundred men?
200.
God was with me.
Michal.
[ Michal ]
Let's go.
[ Clatters ]
Get out, all of you.
Get out!
Father.
What demons possess you?
lf it wasn't for him,
we would all be slaves...
and you would not be king.
And with him, you never will be.
Your father, the king,
wishes to see David.
He can't. He's... not well.
Not well!
Not well, you say.
Well- Well, we shall see.
We shall see.
Not well.
- David?
- [ Pounds On Door ]
Yes.
You have helped him escape.
- You would rather be queen
than see your own father king!
- No!
You would betray your own brother!
Father, you need to rest!
So... even my own children
plot against me!
David!
Wherever you go, l shall hunt you down!
Priests!
Your king wishes to speak with you.
[ Blusters ]
- Come here! Out!
- Come on!
David was here, wasn't he?
- You sheltered him.
- [ Priest ] This is God's house.
We offer shelter to all his people.
Kill him.
l said kill him!
[ Groaning ]
Kill all of them.
l have served you faithfully, Lord.
As faithfully as a man can.
And yet still it seems it is not enough.
[ Echoing ]
Not enough.
God is with me!
[ Echoing ]
God is wlth me!
Lord!
[ Shouting ]
Do you hear your servant?
[ Urinating ]
[ Urinating Stops ]
Majesty.
David.
Why do you pursue me
when l have done you no harm?
l could have killed you.
Your life was mine to take.
Why didn't you take it then?
The Lord may revenge
the harm you have done to me...
but only evildoers do evil deeds.
So my hand will not touch you. Ever.
And God will reward you,
and you will be king!
- You are my king.
- And when you have my crown...
will you not kill my descendants,
bury my name?
- l will not.
- No?
l swear.
No?
Come then.
Come.
We'll go home together.
Why did you not kill him
when you had the chance?
Because he's one of the anointed.
lt's up to God to decide his destiny.
[ Jonathan ]
Father!
Father.
The Philistine army is in the next valley,
near Gilboa.
Jonathan, David is very near.
Forget about David.
You must defend your kingdom.
That is your duty.
You're right.
We must prepare for battle.
Tell the men we leave for Gilboa.
Tell them we leave at dawn.
[ Shouting ]
[ Shouts ]
Jonathan, save yourself!
No! We stand together!
Father, come on! Come on!
[ Shouts ]
[ Man ]
Draw!
[ Saul ]
Jonathan!
[ Groans ]
Jonathan. Jonathan.
[ Crying ]
Oh, my son!
Oh, why?
[ Kisses ]
Dear God.
Were my sins so great...
all of lsrael must suffer?
[ Sword Plunges ]
[ Groans ]
Hyah! Hyah!
A crushing victory...
for the Philistines.
And Saul?
Dead.
[ Laughing ]
You think the death
of God's anointed is a trivial thing?
What of Jonathan?
Captured?
Get rid of him!
How are the mighty fallen.
We can go home.
The people will look to you now...
to defend them, unite them.
Our time has come.
Yes, my king.
King David.
[ Narrator ]
Davld gathers followers.
But to unlte Israel
he needs a capltal clty.
Jerusalem.
Our new home.
Now we just need to find a way in.
How do we do that?
There is one way.
- We wait till nightfall.
- [ Whinnies ]
[ Men Coughing ]
[ Uriah ]
What do we do now?
Here.
[ Gasping ]
[ Men Chattering, Laughing ]
[ Chattering, Laughing Continue ]
...what happened to Saul!
[ Laughing ]
[ Panting ]
For lsrael.
- Look out!
- To arms!
Uriah!
lsrael!
[ Men Cheering, Shouting ]
- ^^ [ Drumming ]
- [ Cheering ]
[ Narrator ]
Jerusalem is now Davld 's clty...
a new center of power
for the Israelites...
and a home for the ultimate symboI
of their bond wlth God.
The Ark of the Covenant!
[ Cheering ]
- [ Crowd Chanting, Singing ]
- ^^ [ Drumming ]
Your wife's far too pretty for you,
my friend.
- You're right.
- [ Laughs ]
- Majesty.
- Come.
- You don't mind, Uriah.
- l mind.
Now God is truly with me.
[ Birds Chirping, Calling ]
Your Majesty.
Ah. Prophet.
Look.
My temple.
For the Ark.
For the Lord.
The world's never seen anything like it.
The Lord came to me last night.
He's pleased with our work?
The Lord told me the House of David
will rule lsrael forever.
We are blessed.
Your son will be king.
Your son will build the temple.
My temple.
God's temple.
A kingdom forever.
Thank you, Nathan.
[ Woman Laughs ]
[ Man ]
Your Majesty.
As you requested.
Leave us.
Bathsheba.
Majesty.
David.
ls there news of my husband?
No.
No, nothing like that.
He's safe enough, l believe...
although he is far away.
Fighting the enemy.
But you didn't go.
No need.
Not with men like Uriah to do it for me.
l am loyal to my husband.
What about your king?
This is wrong.
No one need know.
[ Narrator ]
Bathsheba becomes pregnant.
God's chosen king breaks his commandments.
Uriah, my friend. Welcome.
You sent for me, Majesty.
How's the war going?
Well. Very well.
And your commander, Joab,
all is well with him?
All is well.
Your fellow soldiers?
They fight well.
Excellent.
Well, you can give me
a fuller report in the morning.
l'm sure for now
you'd rather be with your wife.
[ Laughs ]
- l cannot stay with my wife.
- Of course you can.
While my men are camped in open country...
fighting the enemy?
This is a holy war.
How could l go to my home
and spend the night with my wife?
That does you credit, Uriah.
But, man to man...
who's to know?
l will know.
Good man.
Then let's drink.
Wine!
[ Narrator ] Davld cannot force Urlah
to sleep wlth Bathsheba.
So he finds another way...
to conceal his adultery.
[ Davld 's Voice ]
Commander Joab, I order you to send Urlah...
to where the fighting is flercest...
and abandon him there to dle .
We've been richly blessed.
You think you can just
sweep what you've done under the carpet?
You took everything from your most
loyal servant, Uriah.
- He deserved your respect.
- l did respect him.
Really?
- You took his wife, then you took his life.
- Prophet!
You think God doesn't see everything?
The Lord has spoken to me.
He will bring disaster on your house...
for the contempt you have shown the Lord.
- No.
- No!
He will take your son.
- [ Baby Cries ]
- We shall see.
[ Crying Continues ]
Anything, Lord.
Please spare my child.
Tell me.
Tell me what to do.
[ Sobs ]
Oh.
[ Sobbing ]
First my husband, now my son.
We are cursed.
But l was anointed.
God blessed me.
A king is never above his god.
You were supposed to rule in his name,
not your own.
We're finished.
Everyone will see that God has left us.
Prophet.
Even though you are weak,
he loves you, David.
You have forged God's nation on earth.
Take comfort in each other.
You will have another son.
[ All Laughing ]
[ Laughing ]
Be careful, Solomon.
Let him play.
lt's the house of the Lord.
One day, he'll have to build it.
[ Narrator ]
Solomon will build God's temple .
But like his father...
he will find lt impossible
to obey God's commandments.
Next time on The Bible.
[ Chanting ]
Nebuchadnezzar! Nebuchadnezzar!
[ Man ]
God is bringing disaster from Babylon!
[ Chanting ]
Nebuchadnezzar!
We move!
Jerusalem!
[ Shouting ]
Will you not speak for us
in our hour of need?
[ Man ]
Look out there.
You're too late.
- lt begins.
- [ Thunder Rumbling ]
Submit to King Nebuchadnezzar.
Bow your head.
And whatever is left of Jerusalem,
help yourselves!
This way, Daniel.
[ Screaming ]
[ Man ]
WilI we ever return to Jerusalem?
Jeremiah promised that one day we would.
[ Man ]
In the meantime, what do we do-
just bow our heads and serve this monster?
l will make them bow.
Bring me fire!
Lord! Save me!
[ Screaming ]
[ Danlel ] Cyrus will set us free
lf the prophecy is right.
[ Cyrus ]
I cannot go back on my word.
l promised them freedom to worship.
lt is merely a test of their loyalty.
lt's a trap for all of us.
They want us dead.
[ Roaring ]
[ Man ] There is one to come
who will baptize wlth fire.
l'm just a voice in the wilderness,
preparing the way for the-
[ Man ]
Lord.
What are we gonna do?
Change the world.
^^ [ Woman Vocalizing ]