Write to him.
How long will it take
to get to Germany?
I shouldn't let you do this.
Why are you doing this for me?
We are both exiles
in a strange land.
If we can't be human to each other
then what are we?
Where am I to leave the reply?
If one comes.
BUGLE CALL IN DISTANCE
CHATTER AND LAUGHTER IN DISTANCE
I want the commanding officer.
You are just an orderly
and therefore of no use to me.
With all due respect, sir,
you're making it rather difficult
for us to do our job. If you could
come with me to the ward...
And you're not the CO, unless
the Army's completely lost its mind.
Matron Carter.
Might I have your name?
Ballard. Major. J. 5th Punjab Rifles.
I'm not supposed to be here.
I'm not like these poor devils.
I need to get out and get back
to the front immediately.
I'll tell Colonel Brett
you want to speak to him.
In the meantime, I must ask
that you go quietly to the ward.
And I must also ask
that you give me your revolver.
It's not Army issue. It's mine.
Belongs to me. It's private property.
Nonetheless, before you go to
the ward, I still need to take it.
I do not enjoy being given orders
by a woman.
There is no point in you standing
there with your little paw out.
So, why don't you go
and find the CO?
Now, step to it.
HE SPEAKS PUNJABI
SHE SPEAKS PUNJABI
Well, well, well.
She speaks Punjabi.
The gun...is mine.
You'll do, Matron Carter.
Thank you, Nurse. Orderly,
can you take him? He can't walk.
Hold up.
He's still himself.
What, you know him?
Yeah. Me and him got business.
An Indian Army officer,
Ballard, wants to see you.
Him and several hundred others.
I'll put him on my list.
I'd like it if you could see him
quite promptly.
He's the type
to make his presence felt.
He'll go on my list.
Have you been running? I never run.
DOOR OPENS
That officer, Ballard.
You give him a message for us?
Depends on the message.
Just tell him
Gorman the sniper's here.
Tell him I said hello.
Is he going to want to say hello
to you? I reckon.
So, will you tell him?
Most important you get yourself
sorted out and have a kip first.
I'm nowhere near that yet.
Tomorrow, we'll have been here
for three months. I know.
Don't you think
we should throw a do?
I mean, we don't need a reason,
but it's the perfect reason.
We can invite the patients
and the staff. What kind of do?
You know,
just something little and fun.
Charades, songs round a piano.
Everybody loves a singsong.
People can do their party pieces.
Bet you have a party piece,
don't you, Corporal?
Yeah. Mopping.
Well, I'll organise it.
It will just be small.
But you can tell people,
and whoever wants to come can come.
I'm not singing. No, nor me.
Oh, for heaven's sake!
I'll start the singing.
We want them to get better,
not worse.
I'll have you know that at home,
I'm actually considered
rather tuneful.
What just happened?
I think we're throwing a do.
I'll pick some flowers
to decorate it,
and maybe even put up a stage.
And, of course,
there'll be a pianist, but not me.
I'm not very good at the piano,
but someone who IS good at the piano.
Have you put on concerts before?
Oh, yes, I have a great deal
of experience in theatricals.
I was in
the Worthing Operatic Society
where I took the role of a pirate
in Pirates Of Penzance.
Everyone commented on it...
very favourably.
I just thought it would be fun.
Give everyone a boost
and bring us all together.
Yes. Well, carry on, Marshall.
I shall watch and applaud.
Morning, Major Ballard.
Time to have your dressing changed.
No.
Why not, Major? Because I said not.
Where's the commanding officer?
Has he fallen down a hole?
What have I got to do
to speak to him?
He'll be round
as soon as he's ready.
Why doesn't anybody in this place
do what they're told?!
If I could just dress your arm...
Colonel Brett.
Delighted you could finally make it.
I did warn you.
I don't appreciate being summoned
by the sound of smashing crockery.
You have to sign me out
and send me back up to the front
as a matter of urgency.
Do I, indeed?
I've left 400 sepoys under
the command of a young lieutenant
two months out of school,
who has perfect Greek and Latin,
but not a word of the bloody lingo
spoken by my Sikh Lions.
Matron here speaks more Punjabi
than he does.
You have an open wound in your arm.
You're staying here.
Colonel...
This is confidential.
There's going to be a push.
How in hell are my men
supposed to execute that push
if there's no-one there
who can understand them?
There's nothing leaving
until dawn tomorrow.
But you won't be going anywhere
unless you pipe down
and get treated.
Well, in that case.
I want Matron to do it.
Matron has far too much work
to be dancing attendance on you.
Well, shall we ask her.
If it will mean less trouble.
You never said!
You never asked, sir.
I don't know why
you're so surprised.
You know I began my service
in India.
Yes, but I didn't know you grew up
there. I'm quite envious. Why?
Well...tigers and elephants.
We didn't have them in Godalming.
It was a perfectly ordinary
childhood.
You're a dark horse, Grace Carter.
I'm nothing of the sort.
Oh, Sister, when this chap of yours
gets some leave, you must tell us.
We can arrange something
so you can scoot off and join him.
Oh, sorry, of course.
I don't want you to think
that we're gossiping about you.
No, no, not at all.
It's very kind of you, sir.
It's bribery. We want to keep you.
I need you to cover night duty
tonight. Tonight, Matron?
Is that a problem?
No, of course not.
So, what sort of do
is this going to be?
Depravity and absinthe?
Will I plumb new depths of shame?
More tea and biscuits,
songs and charades, I'm afraid.
Hardly the last days of Rome.
They're ready for us in theatre.
Yep. Two minutes.
Are you musical, Captain?
No.
Two minutes.
Don't mind my friend.
One of the best, but the word
"abrupt" was coined for him.
I don't mind him.
We could do a duet.
A lush, swooning, romantic duet.
Gazing into each other's eyes.
Followed by a quick engagement,
become the most talked about people
in the place
and knock Sister Livesey here
right off her pedestal.
For God's sake. Can't everyone
find another subject to discuss?
Has everyone got
such boring little lives
that the only thing
they can talk about is me?!
God, is that the time?
DOOR CLOSES
You're shaking. What's wrong?
Joan, what is it?
Can't you leave me alone?
I just want everyone
to leave me alone.
Is that too much to ask?
BANGING ON DOOR
It all rather blossomed
into something more extravagant,
which means we've got far more
to be getting on with.
This is for you to do, and you.
Flora, I'm on the wards.
I don't have time to argue
about this. I'm far too busy!
I've got to organise
the acts and turns.
I thought we could sing something...
together.
What do you mean, together?
On a stage?
I'm not singing.
Ah, Matron.
I hope you can forgive me
for taking you away
from all those other vital duties.
Major, you don't care
if I forgive you or not.
You just want to be
the centre of attention
and have everything your own way.
What else would I expect
of a man from the regiment
who call themselves The Fire-Eaters.
How would you know
the nickname of our regiment?
I expect someone told me.
I expect they didn't.
That name hasn't been used
for 20 years. How would you know it?
You know, I had flattered myself
you might be interested in me,
but now I think you're interested
in the company of men that I keep.
Is there a question
you want to ask me?
Someone you want to know about?
I have no question for you, sir.
No.
Now you're lying.
I always know when a woman is lying.
You consider yourself an expert?
Real women, yes.
Not your type.
And what type are we, sir?
Army virgins.
Professional cold fish.
Unbreached.
Untouched.
Unloved.
You're trying to provoke me.
You let your guard down
when you spoke Punjabi.
There's something going on
underneath your armour plating.
As you said yourself.
You're no expert on types like us.
Then educate me.
What makes a woman like you put on
a uniform and behave like a nun?
At least a nun gets the ecstasy
of religious rapture.
What do you get?
I help people.
Yes, well, I don't need your help.
I'm only submitting to be good
and get out of here.
Then be good...
and you'll get what you want.
DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES
Excuse me, sir. Mm?
Um, there's a Private Gorman
outside. He says he knows you.
Who? Gorman, sir.
He's hoping to talk to you.
The name means nothing to me.
That's what he said, is it?
What is he to you?
He's a marksman.
He's the shot.
Even one-eyed.
No-one can bloody touch him.
Well, you see, I'm the shot too,
and he knows it, and he knows me.
Don't matter what he told you.
He knows me.
Think someone was going to cut them
up as rugs for the horses.
They'll need a bit of a shake.
Need more than a good shake.
There's going to be a lot of people
going to this concert
wanting to hear
Miss Marshall singing.
I take it the colonel
will be attending. I believe so.
That's nice.
Shows the proper spirit
of camaraderie.
Will you going to be joining in?
I've often been complimented
on my baritone
but, sadly, a quartermaster's work
is never done.
Sure it will be a very jolly event.
Watch out for that mud.
Are you all right?
Rosalie Berwick, you are a Right
Honourable! You're really a Lady.
What judgment are you going to make
of that, I wonder?
It was just a passing remark.
You always think I'm insulting you.
Let's just get on with this,
shall we?
Ohh! Oh!
SHE LAUGHS
DOOR SHUTS
Major Ballard!
Sir. You remember me?
Let me jog your memory.
My officer put me in a wager
against you,
see who had the best shot.
Long-range and short.
Be a good six months ago now. Yes.
And I won, as I recall.
You did, sir.
It was close, but you won.
My officer lost a fair few quid.
He weren't best pleased.
Yeah, sniper's feet.
Stood in a hole full of water
for five days without moving.
Skin split in me boots.
Still, got me man, though.
He moved first.
HE MIMICS A GUNSHOT
Got him.
Sir, you might have beaten me
back then, but now, I never miss.
Perhaps we might have
that wager again.
Yes, well, you're just going to
have to stay beaten.
I'm due back at the front imminently.
I'll see you up there, then, sir.
At your convenience. I can wait.
I can wait for ever
when I've got a man in me sights.
Sir.
I can't believe
you haven't thought of something
for us to do together yet,
especially when I'm so busy.
I told you, I'm not...
I don't see why you won't sing.
I bet you can.
And I know you can play the piano.
I've heard you in the church.
If someone hummed a tune,
I bet you could pick it up.
You're the one
that's used to performing.
I just... I don't like
being looked at very much.
I just really hoped
we could all do something together.
The three of us. I just thought
it would be so lovely.
All right. I'll sing with you.
I suppose I'll play.
PIANO PLAYS IN DISTANCE
Not rehearsing your party piece,
Sister?
I've got night duty.
He should be on the ward.
He won't come in yet.
He's got a score to settle.
♪ Two little maids... ♪
Are you all right? Yes.
SINGING AND CHATTER
Why are they staying?
They want to watch you rehearse.
Oh, I never rehearse
in front of an audience.
Goodness me, Flora,
you are precious.
It was Worthing Opera Society,
not Covent Garden.
Well, I'm just thinking of you two,
and you're more shy than I am.
Just tell them
it has to be a surprise for tomorrow.
SHE SIGHS
Where's Kitty?
Good evening.
Tom, are we really
going to ignore each other?
I'd prefer it, Miss Trevelyan.
You're in my way.
Can't we at least be civil?
I avoid you for a reason.
That's got to be clear.
But now you're in my way,
wanting me to do...what?
Come running
when you click your fingers?
I'm sorry to ruin your fun.
You think I'm having fun?
I don't know.
Maybe it's entertaining for you.
Maybe you collect men and tie us up
in knots for your amusement.
Well, find someone else
to dance to your tune,
because it's not going to be me.
SHE PLAYS NOTES DELICATELY
What's the matter with you?
Everybody's really rather good,
you know?
That's supposed to make you happy,
not miserable.
Can we rehearse now everyone's gone?
You know, I think you'd be much
better off doing it on your own.
Don't you dare. You...
You were the one that persuaded us.
You practically forced us into it.
I get such awful stage fright.
I told Colonel Brett
that I'd been really good
in Pirates Of Penzance,
but I froze
and nothing came out of my mouth
and I fell over some scenery
and everybody laughed.
Well, we just won't sing
anything at all, then.
Oh, no. No, you have to.
I've told everybody now.
Everybody's expecting it.
You'll be fine.
Where are you going?
I'm going to see Cook
about the sandwiches,
and I'll look after
the decorations too.
That's wonderful.
EXPLOSIONS BOOM IN FAR DISTANCE
Could I take a moment?
Can I get you anything, sir?
You just can't stay away,
can you? Hm?
I'm not an invalid. If I need
something, I can get it myself.
I beg your pardon.
Good night, sir.
HUSHED FOOTSTEPS
DOOR CLOSES
VOICES IN THE DISTANCE
What is it?
What's gone wrong? Nothing.
Is there anything for me?
No. And I'm sorry.
There was never any guarantee
that it would get through and...
it might have been stopped
in Switzerland.
But even if a letter comes now...
..I won't be able to get it to you.
We're leaving.
We have passes for England.
We won't stand out so much.
What do you mean, stand out?
Are you having trouble?
We have to leave.
It's not safe here any more.
I'm glad for you both.
I truly am.
It's so late for her to be out.
Yes. We leave now.
I wish I could have brought you
a reply.
I wish I could have helped.
I think I know in my heart...
..that he's dead.
I think I know it.
Good luck, Mr Tillens,
and thank you for trying.
BIRDSONG
Crocuses, daffodils and hyacinths.
I'm going to plant them everywhere,
but I'll start here.
It'll be something to look forward
to, during the winter,
when everything's so dreary,
and it's going to get ever so cold.
But in the spring,
there'll be a carpet of colour.
I feel very bad...
about letting it slip
about your engagement ring.
I wanted to try to make it up to you
a little.
It's probably a bit silly. No.
No.
It's lovely.
I just might not be here to see it.
You're not going to leave, are you?
I mean, none of us might be here.
Oh, yes, of course!
The war might all be over.
Anything's possible.
Nearly anything.
MEN SPEAK FRENCH
Cours a l'hopital,
va chercher l'infirmiere.
On part. On part aujourd'hui.
MAN SPEAKS FRENCH
S'il vous plait...
Pitie... Regardez ca. Pitie!
C'est l'allemand. Oui.
Ce n'est que de la poesie.
Ah! C'est quoi, ca?! Hein? Hein?!
I see what you mean.
Leave it with me.
Ballard.
One moment, Major.
I need to check something.
What's all this about?
It's just routine.
Read this for me, if you would.
Oh, for God's sake!
Haven't you got better things to do?
Just read it for me, please.
Feel free to turn your head,
if it makes it any easier.
This is her, isn't it?
I knew she was watching me.
It could be a variety of conditions.
It could be Stargardt's disease,
although, of course,
we're not allowed to call it that
now, because Stargardt was German.
But...
call it what you will. You're
losing your sight, aren't you?
How in hell have you been coping?
That man in the purple dressing
gown, I can see perfectly well.
You have peripheral sight.
You can see here and here.
No wonder you were in such a rush
to get out of here
before anyone noticed.
There's no push, is there?
How long's
it been getting worse for?
Perhaps over the last year.
And perhaps a rapid deterioration
over the last couple of months.
I'm afraid not answering won't
change the facts. This does happen.
Not to me.
I understand
that this is a cruel blow.
No, of course I don't.
How could I? I'm sorry.
But you can't stay here in France.
Don't send me back
to some hospital in England.
There's nowhere else I CAN send you.
When?
Tonight.
What's the matter?
Anglaise? What's she doing here?
Cherie, ou est ton papa?
Ou est ton papa, cherie?
FOOTSTEPS APPROACH
That was a low trick.
That was underhand.
It was necessary. You know,
we're both the same, you and I.
Army, no other life,
above and beyond.
You, more than anybody, should
understand why I needed to go back.
And you're an empty husk,
all rules and duty.
You know nothing about me!
Oh, look. Some passion.
Yes, it's a bit too late for that,
though, isn't it?
You need help.
Well...
..when I'm in England,
a country where I've never lived,
when I'm having my food
cut up for me
and being poked and prodded
by pitying hands,
when I'm just a diagnosis
on a scrap of paper...
..I shall think of you
standing here...
..and your remorseless help.
DOOR SLAMS
Still with us, then, sir?
All you've got to do
is agree to meet me with a backup.
Shot for shot, prove who's best.
Just agree to meet me. Shake on it
and I'll leave you alone, sir.
You're always yapping at my heels,
aren't you?
Every king must fall.
Must they?
It's just the way of the world, sir.
Now, will you shake on it?
All right, Gorman.
I'll agree to meet you.
You can have your wager.
You can have it right now.
Tu restes la.
Shit.
Sit tight. I'll be back.
Oh, it's Joan.
Go to the house.
Waiting for you.
Waiting for you. Sh. Waiting...
And here was me,
happy to settle for an handshake.
I might have known
you'd always be ready.
When I beat you,
I won't be crowing about it.
You'll have your dignity.
..It's good there, lads.
This do for you, sir?
Set it up.
GUNSHOT ECHOES
Sister Livesey...
He was found on the road.
Where's Mathilde?
Where's his little girl?
She's in Matron's office,
being looked after in the quiet.
She's unhurt, at least physically.
I need to ask you some questions.
Hello there. Here you go, Miss.
Thank you.
It's obvious they think
he was spying. It's just poetry.
No, it's not just anything
if it's found by the wrong people.
Do you know where
they would have been going?
Yes. He said they had friends in
London they were hoping to get to.
When did he tell you that?
The last time I treated him, sir.
Right.
Well, try and get these
into some sort of order.
I'll make sure they both get
to where they're supposed to be.
You don't think he's a spy?
I think he's been incredibly naive
and stupid.
Must have stood out like sore thumbs
in that village.
They look different,
they sound different.
What a world...
..where you're beaten up for a book.
Mind you,
he's lucky they didn't hang him.
DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES
Near miss. Still a hit.
I told you I got better, sir.
Yours might have been a hit, but...
I think I might just have the edge.
Shall we up the stakes?
FOOTSTEPS
GUNSHOT IN DISTANCE
I like you, sir.
I really do.
GUNSHOT REVERBERATES
My turn.
Well, you said you wanted a wager.
You changed your mind?
Never, sir.
(Stop.)
Don't move.
Can you even see him?
Can he what? What did she just say?
I can do this. And if you can't...
..you'll kill him.
Put it down.
You poor bastard.
I can't even call it a victory.
Where's Kitty? How should I know?
Oh! Why did I even say I'd do this?
Well, you did
and now we're doing it.
Leave them!
If Kitty doesn't come,
you'll have to sing.
Go ahead. I'll be there.
Mr Tillens... Joan.
You're still
going to get to your friends.
I am so, so sorry.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Go to the house.
Waiting for you.
Oh, why didn't you just let me
go back to my men?
Why did you have to be
such a bloody nurse?
My father...
..was a very difficult...
and a very unhappy man.
I grew up in a house full of guns.
Guns everywhere.
I spent my childhood...
..unloading his guns and trying
to hide the bullets from him.
Of course,
the inevitable happened...
..and I spent a long time
blaming myself for his death.
So, you feel compelled
to save everybody else.
Was it your father in the regiment?
No.
Are you ready now?
I don't even know
which direction I'm facing.
You know, I still think
you have a question for me.
If you do, you need to ask it now.
The Blighty convoy is here, Major.
Sir, in your regiment...
..do you know of
a Subedar Major Amar Singh?
Yes, I do.
He's fallen, I'm afraid.
Friend of yours? A passing
acquaintance of many years ago.
More than that.
Of course more than that.
Of course.
I always thought...
I'd know if he fell.
Somehow, I always thought I'd know.
You announce it. It's your concert.
No, you announce it.
I don't want to. You're in charge.
Get up there and introduce it.
First, we have a musical treat
from The Mikado.
Welcome to the concert.
CHEERING
♪ One little maid is a bride
Yum-Yum
♪ Two little maids in attendance come
♪ Three little maids is the total sum
♪ Three little maids from school
♪ Three little maids from school... ♪
SINGING CONTINUES IN DISTANCE
What are you doing in here?
Why are you going to their house?
To get Mathilde's storybook.
The father thought I was you.
He said, "Go to the house.
Waiting for you."
What's waiting for you, Joan?
He'd just been beaten.
Of course he wasn't making sense.
What's waiting for you
and why can't it come here?
Why do you have to go and get it?
Kitty, get out of my way...
He was beaten up
because people thought he was a spy.
He reads German. Lots of people do.
This fiance
that you tried to keep a secret.
This man that...
that you don't like talking about.
He's not British, is he?
They will crucify you, Joan.
They will crucify you.
It's just a letter.
That's all it is.
It's going to tell me whether he's
dead or alive.
I have to know.
It's just a letter.
Please.
Any singing of mucky songs,
any telling of mucky jokes,
I'll know about it
and arses will be kicked.
Now, bugger off. Sir. Thank you, sir.
Come on, Flora.
Kitty's not here yet,
so you'll have to sing.
HUSHED CHATTER FROM AUDIENCE
MUSIC: "There's A Long, Long Trail
A-Winding"
♪ Nights are growing very lonely
♪ Days are very long
♪ I'm a-growing weary only
TOGETHER: ♪ List'ning for your song
♪ There's a long, long trail
a-winding
♪ Into the land of my dreams
KITTY JOINS IN
♪ Where the nightingales are singing
♪ And the white moon beams
♪ There's a long, long night
of waiting
♪ Until my dreams all come true
♪ Till the day
when I'll be going down
♪ That long, long trail with you
♪ All night long I hear you calling
♪ Calling sweet and low
♪ Seem to hear your footsteps falling
♪ Ev'rywhere I go
♪ There's a long, long trail
a-winding
♪ Into the land of my dreams
♪ Where the nightingales are singing
♪ And the white moon beams
♪ There's a long, long night
of waiting
♪ Until my dreams all come true
♪ Till the day when I'll be going
♪ Down that long, long trail
with you. ♪
CREAKING
Liebchen?
SHE SOBS
Oh, my God!
SHE WAILS
I'm here.
I got your letter.
You're alive. You're alive.
You're alive.
(You're alive.)
Un, deux...
All right? You...
How did you get here?
I was taken prisoner.
I jumped from the train.
It's not safe.
You're going to ride away from
the village. There's a crossroads.
Hide yourself there
and watch the road for me.
I'm going to get you different
clothes, food, money. No.
I'll think of something. No. No. No.
I always think of something. I'm not
leaving you alone with them. Anton.
I'm the one
with the British uniform.
I'm not the one they'll hang.
I'm not the one they'll shoot.
You are.
So, you are leaving now.
Watch the road and I will come.
Ich liebe dich.
I love you.
ENGINE STARTS
Good evening, Sister.
What have you been up to?
Your loyalties lie with the enemy.
You're as much to blame as she is.
What are you going to do?
MAN SCREAMS
All senior staff
are to be questioned
as to his ability
to lead this hospital.
- How the hell can it get any worse?
- Control yourself!
No-one doubts you, Roland.
You understand
you're subject to military law.
Conviction by court martial,
you'll be liable to suffer death.