La fabrique
The Henrys Team: aspirat, beotienne,
do_Ob, Funi, karim HelenScott,
kiry, khillaree, mytom,neuceu, olaola. Cheerleader: Blek l'Andouille
My lords,
I do confess to you that,
although I've lain
with the Queen almost every
night these past weeks,
my conscience will not permit me
to consummate this marriage
because I feel there is some
impediment to it.
I have done as much as any man
to move the consent of my heart
and mind, but the obstacle
will not out of my thoughts.
Perhaps the truth is that
there existed a precontract
between the Duke of Lorraine's
son and the Princess after all,
from which she was never
released, and so therefore
I am really married
to another man's wife.
My lords,
I leave it to you to investigate
whether or not
my scruples are justified.
Your Majesty.
My Lord, you must find some way
to relieve His Majesty's conscience.
I tell you, Charles,
God will not grant me any more children
if I continue in this marriage.
Was she such a maid that
she didn't know what to do?
Not telling a woman what she
must expect on her wedding night is...
like sending a sailor
to sea with no biscuit.
I will force Cromwell to bring about
a dissolution of the marriage.
I went ahead with it for the sake
of the realm and now even
that reason is forgot.
The Emperor and the King of France
are at each other's throats again
and both have come courting.
Who needs Cleves?
My Lord Cromwell.
Was the match not his idea?
Princess Mary is here.
Princess, if you please.
I have received a letter
from a cousin of mine.
He is Duke Philip of Bavaria.
Philip'd like.
To come to England
and pay court to you
Why?
He has heard many things
about you, Princess Mary.
Many good things.
I suppose he's a Lutheran,
like you?
He is charming
and very good looking.
I think you might like him a little.
What shall I tell him?
Tell him...
Tell him he may come if he
pleases and if the King wishes.
But not to expect anything.
Father?
Gregory!
What on earth are you doing here?
Well, I noticed you forgot
your pills at the apothecary.
I didn't want you to be in pain.
Sit down.
What are you working on?
I'm preparing bills for Parliament
on the medical profession.
And I'm trying
to persuade His Majesty
to appoint councillors based
upon merit,
and nothing else.
You look tired, father.
How is His Majesty?
He's fine.
His leg bothers him;
it gets sore. He gets irritable.
Is that why he strikes you
on the head sometimes?
I resent the King nothing,
but others seek to undermine me,
since I was born so low
and they so high...
And
for other reasons too.
Think not on that.
Look after your own dear wife,
and the child in her belly.
Love them as you love God
and His Holy Word,
and all shall be well.
I'm sorry you failed to
capture that traitor
Reginald Pole, Sir Francis.
The King detests him above all men.
However,
he has other matters
on his mind now.
When I last spoke to His Majesty
he confessed he was,
- in some ways, tired with his life.
- His life or his wife?
They are much the same thing.
Can he not find distraction,
as he has always done before?
Easily.
But he is more jaded than before.
The usual remedies won't suit.
Something more...
extreme...
might tempt him.
In this matter at least, Your Grace,
I shall not fail the King.
- My Lady.
Sir?
Princess Mary, I hope
you can forgive my impetuosity.
I know we should have been
formally introduced, but...
I couldn't wait.
You are Duke Philip?
May I kiss your hand?
I hope I might
see you again, my Lady.
With my cousin the Queen
present, of course.
I had thought to leave court
tomorrow for the country.
I may delay my leaving,
if it pleases you.
For a day or so.
My sweet Francis, I missed you!
Handsome as ever.
We haven't seen you for ages.
What have you been doing?
- Trying to kill someone.
- Did you manage it?
Not yet.
I suppose you've come to look
over my little darlings?
Only after I've feasted
my eyes on you, my dear Lady.
Go along.
We have some new ones, I think.
Pretty little things.
I sometimes find it hard to
believe that whoever bore them
did not feel bothered
or obliged to raise them.
- Most of them were bastards.
- But
aristocratic bastards, my sweet boy.
Aristocratic bastards.
Make a dress for our doll.
- Who do you think he is?
- I don't know.
- He's been in a sword fight?
- Do you think he was?
Sir?
I have found someone
to amuse the King.
Who is she?
Miss Katherine Howard. She's a distant
relation to the Duke of Norfolk.
Her background is...
How shall I say?
Not entirely conventional.
I assume she's young and pretty.
See for yourself, my Lord.
You may come in now.
These are the excellent people
I told you of:
His Grace, the Duke of Suffolk,
and the Earl of Hertford.
- Your Graces.
- How old are you?
Seventeen.
I wonder who taught her to count.
Tell us something about
yourself. Your family. So on.
My mother died when I was little.
My father remarried,
but I didn't know his wife really.
I was sent to live in the household
of the Dowager Duchess.
That would be the Dowager
Duchess of Norfolk?
- The widow of the second Duke
- I suppose so, my Lord.
I didn't see her much.
There were other children there,
from lots of marriages.
We ran a little wild.
There was some fun in it.
Well, sweet Katherine,
I think the fun is
just about to start again.
What do you think, Your Grace?
I think,
I think she looks fit for a king.
Did you talk to him?
To Philip?
A little. Yes.
I believe he is a very
intelligent young man.
I couldn't tell.
And extremely good-looking.
He likes you a great deal.
He doesn't even know me.
We've nothing in common.
Your Majesty, Duke Philip
asks for an audience.
I don't want to see him.
Then go in there! Quickly.
Ah, Philip.
My dear cousin.
Majesty.
How do you find this country?
I like it very much.
I could most happily live here.
So, you've met Princess Mary?
It was only for a moment,
but I relive that moment
over and over again in my mind.
I was told before that she was
charming, intelligent,
well-read, gracious.
The true heir of Katherine of Aragon.
A true Princess.
But nothing prepared me
for her beauty.
But a beauty that comes from inside.
To me, she is the most beautiful
creature on God's earth.
The Council has acted upon
Your Majesty's request.
We demanded written evidence
of the Queen's envoy
about the pre-marriage contract
to the Duke of Lorraine's son.
They provided it, but the papers
seem to suggest that,
instead of the usual formula,
"per verba de futuro",
the actual wording
on the document reads
"per verba de presenti",
which is a binding contract
- which renunciation cannot undo.
- So it does seem
that Your Majesty has reason
to be optimistic.
The King has noticed you.
He may ask to see you.
What shall I say to him?
What should I do?
Just be yourself.
Who is that girl?
That is Katherine Howard.
She is a relation
to the Duke of Norfolk.
She has only just come to court.
Bring her to me.
Majesty.
Majesty, Miss Katherine Howard.
Thank you, Charles.
Katherine.
Your Majesty.
Please, be seated here.
- Are you married?
- No, Your Majesty.
Can you read?
- Enough to write a letter.
- Who writes to you?
Nobody.
Do you have many houses?
- Ouch!
- What is it?
You stepped on my foot.
Philip, I'm so very sorry!
I do apologize. I'm so sorry.
Philip, I'm so sorry!
- I thought...
- You didn't step on my foot.
How could you? Your feet
don't even touch the ground.
I wanted a moment alone with you.
I...
You're crying.
Only because I'm so happy.
Would you like me to kiss you again?
Do you know where
this ring comes from?
It once adorned the shrine
of Thomas Becket at Canterbury.
The whole shrine
glittered with jewels,
left by princes and pilgrims.
But this ring...
This ring was the most
valuable gift of all.
A King of France left it
as an offering
to save his mortal soul.
May I touch it?
Good night, Princess.
Good night, Your Grace.
Tell me, Mr. Cromwell,
how is work proceeding
on my palace at Nonsuch?
I am pleased to report
that it is almost complete,
and will be ready for your
personal inspection come July.
I want to give a gift of land
to Mistress Katherine Howard.
There is some we recently
confiscated from a felon
if I remember correctly.
With two large houses upon it?
I wish to grant the whole
to Mistress Howard.
Majesty.
I hear the Council found a flaw
in the Queen's precontract.
It was not such a flaw
that it could not be overcome
by the Queen's personal repudiation.
There must still be grounds.
Before God, I think she is not
my lawful wife.
Whatever people say, Mr. Cromwell,
either to your face
or behind your back,
you are still my first minister,
whose love and loyalty
I have no cause nor reason to doubt.
If there is anything
important to be done,
I know who best to do it.
Majesty.
- Mr. Cromwell!
- Mr. Cromwell, sir!
- Mr. Risley.
- Give it to Mr. Risley
- We're doing our best.
We'll do our best for you.
Very good, very good, very good.
- Mr. Risley! Thank you sir.
- Thank you. Thank you.
- The meeting with the French Ambassador?
- It was...
...very interesting, Your Majesty.
He told me that
the King was not averse to opening
secret negotiations with us,
with a view to disengaging the French
from their alliance with the Emperor.
Good.
The Ambassador also suggested to me
how much Anglo-French
relations would improve
if Lord Cromwell no longer
stood as an obstacle to them.
Mistress Howard?
The King would like
you to accept a gift.
It's lovely.
You must thank His Majesty.
You can thank him yourself.
Your Majesty.
Come.
Bishop Gardiner.
Just the man we needed.
Now, we may begin.
Gregory? What is it?
It's a boy.
It's a boy. I have a son.
Thanks be to God...
Prince Edward, Your Majesty.
My son.
Gentlemen, I call this council
meeting to order
Cromwell, do not sit there.
That is no place for you.
Traitors do not sit among gentlemen.
My Lord Cromwell,
you are arrested for treason.
I am no traitor.
I ask you, on your consciences,
am I a traitor?
Yes! Traitor! Traitor!
- Traitor! Traitor!
Traitor! Traitor!
Traitor!
I am no traitor!
I'm no traitor!
Princess Mary, do sit down.
I have some... some news.
Duke Philip has been
sent back to Bavaria.
Your father, the King,
sent him away. I am so sorry.
I cannot explain.
No need to explain.
It is of little matter.
The Duke was charming
but I would never have married him.
He is a Lutheran
and I am a Catholic.
My lords, I am come here...
to introduce a bill of attainder
against Thomas Cromwell
on a charge of treason.
Lord Cromwell,
whom His Majesty
has raised from a very base
and low degree, and enriched
with manifold gifts,
is proved to be
a most false and corrupt
traitor and deceiver.
Being a detestable heretic,
he has utterly disposed to set
and sow common sedition
among Your Majesty's
loyal and loving subjects.
As the vice-regent for religion
supposed to oversee reform,
Cromwell has, without
His Majesty's knowledge,
licensed heretics
to preach and teach.
My lords,
we have evidence that
on the night of March the 31st,
in the parish of St. Peter the Poor,
Lord Cromwell did arrogantly defend
these heretic preachers.
He said if the King...
should turn against reform,
he would not turn.
And if the King did turn,
and all his followers,
then he would stand fighting
in the field with his sword
in his hand, against the King
and against all his followers.
And he took out
his dagger, and he said,
"Or let this dagger
thrust me to the heart,
"if I would not die
for that quarrel.
"And if I should live a year or two,
"then it will no longer be
in the King's power
any more to resist or hinder
our reformation. "
And he swore a great oath!
Traitor!
Traitor! Traitor! Traitor!
Is it true that you loved
this man, Sir Richard?
As a friend.
But I chiefly loved him for
the love I thought I saw him bear
towards the King above all others.
But now, if he be a traitor,
then I am sorry
that I ever loved him
or trusted him,
and I am very glad
that his treason is discovered
in time.
Traitor!
Traitor! Justice!
I trust, Madam,
you are happy and well treated?
I have no complaints whatsoever.
Everywhere I go, I am treated
with great respect
and kindness from everyone.
I'm glad.
You are not eating.
Your Majesty...
I... I wondered...
I am sending you away for a
while, to my palace at Richmond.
For your health,
and for your pleasure.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I have some urgent business
to attend to.
Madam.
The Council considers it sufficient,
as Head of the Church,
that you can have
the bishops annul your union.
But...
it would be more diplomatic
if you should find proof that
the marriage was never consummated
and that Your Majesty never
truly consented to it.
Send a deputation to Mr. Cromwell.
Demand of him written evidence
supporting my annulment.
Doubtless he'll remember
how often I spoke to him
of how my nature
abhors that woman...
Mr. Cromwell.
Your Grace.
The King orders that
you write him a letter,
describing how he found
Anne of Cleves,
what passed between you
on that subject,
and whether he told you
he had consummated
his so-called marriage or not.
He also orders you to describe
the impediments to the marriage,
and whether knowing them
you still arranged it.
His Majesty charges that,
as you will answer God
on the dreadful day of judgment,
and also upon the extreme danger
and damnation of your soul
and conscience,
to write down exactly what you know.
I will most gladly do
as the King commands.
I trust to his pleasure
and satisfaction.
I desire more than anything else
the King's comfort,
and would most willingly die for it.
I wondered if you could see
your house from that window?
The fact is, Mr. Cromwell,
that only two hours
after your arrest
the King dispatched
his Treasurer there
to take away your goods.
The rabble came out
to cheer them on.
It was a pretty sight, I hear.
Guard.
"Finding Your Majesty not as pleased
"as I trusted to have done,
I was so bold
"to ask you how you liked the Queen.
"Your Majesty soberly answered,
"As you know, I liked her
not well before,
"but now I like her much worse.
"I have felt her belly
and her breasts
"and thereby, as I can judge,
"she should be no maid.
I left her as good a maid
as I found her!"
At the end.
What does he say at the end?
"I beseech Your Majesty most humbly
"to pardon my rude writing
and to consider that I,
"a most woeful prisoner,
am ready to take the death,
when it shall please
God and Your Majesty. "
Yet the frail flesh incites me
continually to call
to Your Grace for mercy
and grace for my offences,
and thus Christ save,
preserve, and keep you...
Written at the Tower this Wednesday,
... the last of June with heavy heart
and trembling hand
"of Your Highness' most heavy
and miserable prisoner
and poor slave. "
He's written something
right down at the bottom.
"Most gracious prince,
I cry for mercy, mercy.
Mercy. "
Will Your Grace be
on Tower Hill tomorrow?
Try to keep me away.
I can vouchsafe to Your Grace
his final end will be
the most ignominious ever.
So I have heard, Your Grace.
So I have heard.
What is he talking about?
Tell me.
Cromwell is set to appear
on the same scaffold
as Lord Hungerford...
otherwise known as Mad Walter,
who has been sentenced to death
for various offences
such as sodomy, raping his daughter,
and paying magicians to predict
the date of the King's death.
He won't have to pay them
to predict the date of his own.
Then Cromwell will be humiliated.
The false churl who was
so ambitious for others' blood!
Ah, that is not our only device.
Tom and I have conceived
some more sport
at His Lordship's expense.
What kind of sport?
Patience Edward.
Patience.
Let's have another beer.
Sorry, there; I've forgotten
your name, fellow.
- What is it again?
- Gurrea, sir.
Gurrea. D'you have the pox
or is it gone, 'urrea?
It's a big day tomorrow.
I ought to be abed.
A last pint! I'm paying.
And then let's drink
to old friends, huh?
Two more pints, my good man!
Master Gurrea,
I trust you're feeling
clear-headed this morning.
Madam, the Earl of Hartford is come.
My lords.
Madam, it is my duty to
inform you that Parliament,
the convocations
of Canterbury and York
have found your marriage
to the King to be invalid
on the grounds of your
precontract with Lorraine,
His Majesty's lack of consent
to the marriage,
and its non-consummation.
The marriage is thus declared
null and void,
and from henceforth
it is the King's pleasure
that you call yourself his sister.
Do you consent?
In which case,
I can tell you that the King
has settled upon you
a handsome annuity
of 4,000 pounds per annum,
as well as the manors
of Bletchingly and Richmond,
and also Hever Castle, so long
as you remain in England.
And since His Majesty confirms
that you are still a maid,
you are free to marry
whom you choose.
Please...
tell the King that...
I hope I will sometimes
have the pleasure
of his most noble presence,
and beseech the Almighty to send
him long life
and good health.
Oh, my Lady.
Father!
Good people,
I am come here to die,
and not to purge myself,
as some may think I should.
I am by law condemned to die
and I thank my Lord God
that has granted me
this death for my offence.
For since I came of age
I have lived as a sinner
and offended my Lord God,
for which I ask Him heartily
for forgiveness.
Get it over with! For Christ's
sake, get it over with!
I have also offended my Prince,
for which I ask him hearty amnesty.
I heartily desire you to pray
for the King's Grace
and that he may long live with
you in health and prosperity.
and that after him his son,
Prince Edward,
may long reign over you.
There it is.
Nonsuch Palace.
My Fool told me it didn't exist.
Gentlemen,
you should all take warning from me,
who was, as you know, from
a poor man made by the Prince
into a great gentleman and that I,
I not contented with that,
not with having the kingdom
at my orders,
presumed to a still higher state.
My pride has brought its punishment.
Lord, grant me that when these
eyes shall lose their use,
the eyes of my soul may see Thee.
God Lord and father, that when
this mouth shall lose his use...
Kill him!
... that my heart
will say unto Thee:
Father, into your hands
I commend my spirit.
Come on now!
Take his head off!
Pray for the Prince
and for the Lords of the Council
and for the clergy
and for the people.
Now I beg you again that
you will pray for me.
Pray, if possible, cut off
the head with one blow...
that I may not suffer much.
Chop it off!
Your Majesty.