(theme music playing)
(men speaking)
I could settle for something
to eat right now.
This looks like
fucking poo.
Always replacing
the army.
- (man shouts)
- Smitty, Burke, let's go! Move!
- Son of a bitch.
- Let's go!
(baby crying)
(people speaking
Japanese)
Are those
Jap prisoners?
- No.
- On account of we don't take prisoners.
(explosion)
Hey, take it easy.
- That's outgoing.
- (explosions)
- They're Okinawans.
- They look like Japs.
Shut the fuck up, Kathy.
Don't you hear good?
- They're Okinawites.
- Fuck off.
(plane engines roaring)
- What you say, boot?
- The name's Peck... Tony Peck.
Hey, Pecker, let me see that photo
of your wife Kathy again.
- She's gorgeous.
- Thanks.
I need something
to jerk-off to.
She's perfect.
"Oh, Kathy.
Oh, Kathy.
Harder. Harder!"
(both speak Japanese)
- Shit.
- The new ponchos are full of chemicals.
- Chemicals, huh?
- What chemicals?
They done treat 'em
with all kinds of chemicals.
That shit'll make you sick...
real real sick.
- I didn't hear that.
- Yeah, you think they're gonna tell you?
Here, take mine.
Okay, thanks.
Semper fi.
Burgin:
Well, look what we've got here.
I thought you didn't
take prisoners.
Those are
army prisoners, boot.
- (spits)
- (mimicking monkey)
You fucking monkeys.
Dirty little Nips.
- (spits)
- (yells in Japanese)
Snafu:
Out of the way, Hirohito.
Move, you slant-eyed
bastard. Move!
- Man: Shoot him!
- Sit down.
- Move!
- Sit down!
- (marines yelling)
- Do it! Fucking do it!
- Do it!
- Fucking shoot him!
(speaking Japanese)
- Move!
- Sit the fuck down!
- You can't mistreat these men.
They're protected
by the Geneva Conventions.
- Fuck the Geneva Code!
- Mac: Hey hey!
- What's the hold up?
- These men attacked my prisoners.
I want his rank
and serial number!
- Get your hands off of him.
- Man: Oh, come on!
I command these men.
I'll take care of them.
Do you speak Japanese?
I'm an intelligence officer.
Right. Well, maybe you should use
your fucking intelligence
and get these people
off the trail.
(prisoner crying)
You hit another Japanese prisoner,
I'll have you court-martialed.
- (man #2 yells)
- (explosion)
(machine guns firing)
Man #3: Cover!
Head for cover!
Come on, let's go!
Look out for the leg!
Keep moving!
Get that radio set up!
Right now!
In here!
Let's go! Mortars over here!
Let's go go!
Stay down!
- Get that gun set up!
- You're the officer relieving us?
I'm the CO
of K company,
- 3rd Battalion, 5th Marines!
- Stay down!
We couldn't hold 'em!
The Japs are dug in deep!
We lost a lot
of good men out there!
- Where's the rest of your company?
- This is it!
You're gonna need
more than that!
Stumpy:
Like I said, this is it!
All right, Mac,
get them up the hill!
Go! Let's go!
Let's go! Go!
- Stumpy: Move move!
- (explosion)
Let's go, people!
Move it up there!
- (gunfire continues)
- Move out! Move it!
- Move it along!
- Get up the hill! Move it!
Let's go!
Get up there!
Everybody up!
Keep moving!
First and second squad!
Second squad here!
Hamm! Hamm!
- Hamm, over here!
- Come on!
Stumpy:
Stay with me! Get down!
Set up the mortar
base plate too!
First squad...
first squad here!
Stay the fuck down!
- Hanging.
- Fire!
(man yells)
- Burgin: Come on, move!
- Shit. Let's go.
Lock it in there.
Make sure this is straight.
- Snafu: Hurry the fuck up!
- Come on, boys. Come on.
We're not on level
ground yet. Come on.
- Hanging.
- Fire!
- (hissing)
- (rain pattering)
(machine guns firing)
You're gonna drown in that hole without
a trench for the runoff.
Huh?
Put a small hole at the bottom.
It helps with the drainage.
Don't know why you bother.
They'll be dead in a few days.
Don't want
to know their names.
My name is Hamm...
H-A, two Ms.
Just use it
to get my attention.
Hamm with two Ms.
Now I've got
to forget something.
I need some long thin ones.
- Try this.
- I've got one.
Hey, Kathy. Give me those ready rounds.
Break out some more.
(pounding)
- (wood cracks)
- Holy hell.
Snafu:
Jesus Christ!
What the fuck
is that stench?!
- Sledge: Shit.
- (Hamm coughs)
Unbelievable.
Start digging.
- Snafu: Fucking horseshit.
- Sledge: Oh, man.
Mac: What are
you doing, Private?
Holes are supposed
to be five yards apart.
Sir, there's a dead body
in there.
The whole island's
a graveyard.
Get in your hole
and start digging.
Man: Send him down
another 15 yards!
How come the Japs are buried
and our guys aren't?
- (flare hissing)
- (gunfire continues)
Fire mission 16!
Fire mission!
- Sledge: Fire mission!
- Burgin: Gun one, fire!
Gun three, fire HE
for effect on the pre-plots!
Hanging!
- Fire!
- (distant explosions)
- Short round!
- Both: Short round!
Short round!
Shit.
Let's go. Try again.
Hanging.
- Fuck!
- Misfire!
Misfire!
- It's hot.
- Clear it.
Easy.
- (mortar rattles)
- Got it.
- Man: Check the water!
- Try again?
No, our fucking rounds
are all wet.
(gunfire continues)
Keep firing, God damn it!
Pour it on!
Our rounds are wet!
Get more then!
There's ammo up the road!
- Go!
- Man: Hanging!
- Man #2: Fire!
- Let's go.
Dice, Hamm, with me.
You stay here!
Man #3: Open up!
Up the rate of fire!
- Let's go!
- (men yelling)
Let's go.
- What do you need?
- We need 60 mortars... HE.
Friendlies coming in!
Hold your fire!
(people yelling
in Japanese)
- Hey! That kid's still alive!
- Get down.
- That kid's still alive!
- Man: Covering fire!
- Let's go.
- Dice!
- Sledge: He's dead. Keep moving.
(man #2 yells)
- Hanging!
- Man #3: Fire!
- Hanging two!
- Fire!
- Hanging three!
(men yelling)
- (distant explosions)
- (man shouting)
Why aren't we
giving them safe passage?
What are you
talking about?
The civilians.
We should be
giving them safe conduct.
A lot of them are
helping the Nips, Hamm.
That family wasn't.
Only thing that matters
up here is killing Japs.
Man:
Get this gear, Gavanoff.
You know, the first time
you see someone get killed...
it's something.
You get used to it.
I was 15.
A buddy and I were hopping
subway cars in Brooklyn.
We went through a tunnel that was
a little bit too small.
I fractured my skull.
He, uh...
his brains
and bones got spread
all over
my face and chest.
You never ever forget
something like that.
Good thing your damn head
is so fucking hard.
You've got nine lives,
Bill Leyden.
(distant gunfire)
What's the matter, Kathy?
One day of combat,
you're all wore out.
More excitement's
on the way, princess.
Japs are fighting
for their own turf now.
Every damn foot
we go south
they'll get meaner
and meaner.
You'd better
get mean too, boot.
Ooh.
Ooh, la la la.
Now that's
a piece of ass.
Careful. That's the man's wife
you're talking about.
Snafu: Mmm.
Wow.
- Yeah.
- I'd marry her.
Leyden: Marry?
Who said anything
about marriage?
Give her back.
"Kathy Jones"?
I thought you said
your name was Peck.
(gunfire and explosions
continue)
She's not...
she's not your wife.
(laughs)
Oh, that's rich.
What's the missus think
about kitty cat?
I met her
after I was drafted.
- What?
- Drafted?
What kind
of marine is drafted?
Hamm, were you
drafted too?
No.
I don't believe it.
No way that broad is
banging some drafted marine.
- No way.
- I don't care what you think.
(men yelling
in Japanese)
They're leaving.
Japs are retreating.
K company, let's move!
Let's move!
Burgin, 2nd Battalion's
broken through on the left.
We need
to guard their flank.
Third platoon
in reserve!
First and second,
form a skirmish line.
- Burgin...
- Man: First platoon, hold tight!
...I need all the men
you can spare.
Let's go!
Let's go! Move it!
The Japs are falling back!
Let's go!
- Second squad, let's go.
- Why us?
Because your squad's
low on ammo.
Mac: Move it!
Get on that hill!
If it makes any damn difference to you,
I'm coming with you.
So grab
a rifle and move.
- Shit.
- Burgin: Second squad, let's go.
- On me!
- Fuck.
- Man: We're moving up.
- Burgin: We're taking some ground!
Great. 'Cause of you,
we're gonna get our asses shot up.
(machinegun firing)
Mac: Extend the left!
Extend the left!
It's about time
you stateside boys got to see
- what the war's all about.
- Not now, Bill.
Snafu:
We need more damn men up here.
Burgin: All right!
Let's go! Move out!
Oh Lord.
Okay okay.
- Okay okay.
- Burgin: Stay on line!
Spread out!
Break to the left!
Get on line!
Make sure
to check everything!
Man:
Get help right there!
Mac:
Move slow in the center!
Check everything!
Stay as low as you can.
Follow my lead.
Keep your intervals.
Mac: First platoon,
get up on the rocks!
- (rifle fires)
- Man: Sniper!
Man #2:
Put some fire on that crew!
- Man: Move it!
- Let's go.
Mac: Tell them
to try to hold it!
Wait for word!
Happy
to be back, Bill?
What the fuck are
we doing here?
(baby crying)
(woman speaking
Japanese)
- Man: Civilians!
- Man #2: Civilians!
Burgin: Let's go.
Move 'em through.
Come on, get out
of the way. Come on.
Sledge,
what do you see?
(baby crying)
(sobbing,
speaking Japanese)
- She's trying to give us the baby.
- What do we do?
- Man: Booby-trapped!
- Oh, no.
- Man #2: She's wired!
- (guns firing)
(screaming)
(machine gun firing)
- (all yelling)
- Take her!
Man: We can't move!
Get that damn gun!
Stay down!
Mac: Incoming!
Cease fire!
Cease fire,
God damn it!
(people moaning)
(gunfire)
- Corpsman!
- Get up here!
(crying)
- (distant explosion)
- Oh Lord.
- (bombs whistling)
- Man: Incoming!
- Man #2: Take cover!
- Those are ours.
- Short round!
- Our own fuckers are shelling us.
Mac: Pull back!
Back to the other ridge!
- Go go!
- Fall back!
Men: Fall back!
Fall back!
- Son of a bitch!
- Fall back to the start point!
They have us targeted!
(all yelling)
Mac:
Move! Move!
- Move!
- Let's go! Go!
Come on!
This is
fucking bullshit!
I ever find the fucking FO
that called that arty,
I'll shoot him!
The sons of bitches
will just do it again.
Why did they shell us?
Because some asshole officer
read a map wrong,
and nobody gives
a shit about us.
- There is no goddamn reason.
- Man: Got a body over here!
Man #2:
Get out there and police 'em up.
(explosions continue)
- (rain pattering)
- (men chattering)
Man:
Get me a count.
Move those casualties back
to the collection point.
Ready, lift.
Eugene.
(distant gunfire)
- (distant explosion)
- My dog died.
I'm sorry.
He was a good dog.
How old was he?
Got him as a pup
about nine years ago,
maybe 10.
They say
dogs live, what,
seven years
to every one of ours?
Man: Take those cleaning rags
to second squad.
My brother was
on the Bunker Hill.
Wow.
Ship got hit
by two kamikazes.
500 guys died, asshole.
How the fuck
can they do that?
Fly themselves
into a ship?
Emperor is God.
Duty to God.
They can't
fucking surrender?
(distant machine-gun fire)
I hope they don't.
I hope we get to kill
every last one of them.
- God damn it, give it back.
- Forget about her.
You're fucking
married, anyway.
Fuck you!
- Burgin: Stop it, Bill.
- Man: Hey, knock that shit off.
Bill. Bill.
God damn it, Bill.
Bill. Hey! Bill.
What the fuck's the matter with you, Bill?
The Japs ain't enough?
What the fuck
is this about?
It's just a damn picture, Peck.
Get the fuck out of here.
She sent him
a letter.
You know, a letter.
Burgin:
Who gives a shit?
- We don't need this crap, Bill.
- Leyden: You think I need it?
We don't need it, Bill.
- Bill! Bill!
- Oh shit! Oh shit!
- Sledge!
- Corpsman!
- (bombs exploding)
- Bill!
- (moaning)
- Man: Corpsman, we've got wounded!
- Snafu!
- Corpsman! Corpsman!
- Bill!
- Come on. Come on. Come on.
Man:
Get him to BAS!
- (groaning)
- Come on.
(men chatting)
(distant machine-gun fire)
Hey, why don't you
get a newer poncho off a dead body?
This one
suits me just fine.
Man, I thought
it'd be different.
Different from what?
Books you read?
Movies you saw?
No, I just...
I'm just saying.
Grow up, Hamm.
Fuck you, Sledge.
(laughs)
Why don't you pull yourself in the hole
the next time, okay?
That's the talk.
Yeah.
Fuck you too.
(chuckles)
The Hammbone did learn
something in boot camp.
Where you from,
Hamm with two Ms?
So now you want to know
where they're from?
(distant explosions)
Jesus, can't they
give it a rest?
(farts)
What's the date?
June 5th maybe.
Might be the 6th.
We're never getting
off this island.
Burgin:
Hey. Hey.
You dig that any deeper,
they'll get you
for desertion.
(men chatting)
We got here
April 1st.
Easter Sunday.
Fucking April Fools,
no matter how you look at it.
That's 66 days.
We're never getting
off this island.
Oh, come on, Kathy.
Summer's right
around the corner,
then Halloween
and then there's
Thanksgiving.
Look. I'm already working
on your Christmas present.
(distant
machine-gun fire)
Out of the sticks in '46.
Hell to heaven in '47.
The Golden Gate in '48.
(whispers)
Oh, shit.
Mac: Let's go!
Come on up here!
I need
a stovepipe boy up top.
Sledge, that's you.
Bring some comm wire.
Yes, sir.
Hamm, get a spool.
Fuck!
(panting)
Mac: Sledge,
where the fuck are you?!
- Get your ass up here!
- Yes, sir!
Man:
OP coming in!
Sledge?
- Here you go.
- They're moving back into that ridge.
Kutner saw Japs move
into the hut
to the left
of the big tomb.
I want a round on it.
Hamm, wire in.
(radio whirrs)
XO wants a round
on the farmhouse in sector 2.
Azimuth 3-1-0,
range 300.
One round, HE.
Man: 3-1-0. 300.
One round, H.E., on the way.
(distant boom)
Left 2-0.
Add 50 and try again.
Left 2-0, add 50.
One round, HE.
(distant boom)
Target. Mark it concentration Baker
for this sector.
(man shouts
in Japanese)
(men shouting)
Wait. Wait till
they're close.
(rifles firing)
Mac:
Cease fire! Cease fire!
(grunting)
Jesus, Sledge.
Leave him.
What for?
He's a Jap, ain't he?
Mac: Cease fire!
Cease fire, God damn it!
I told you to cease fire.
What are you doing?
Killing Japs.
You just gave away
our goddamn position.
I think they've got a pretty good idea
of where we are.
I told you to cease fire and you're
supposed to be observing.
I see you
with a goddamn sidearm.
We were all sent here
to kill Japs, weren't we?
So what the hell difference does it make
what weapon we use?!
I'd use my goddamn hands
if I had to.
(rain pattering)
Screw it.
We need some
reinforcements up here.
- Give it a rest.
- Fuck you, Eugene.
Yeah, fuck you too,
Shelton.
Fuck, I'm so fucking tired.
I'm fucking tired
of this maggoty stench.
First they order us to push forward when
we ain't got enough bodies,
- then they order us to sit in our own shit.
- Shut up.
They fucking shell us
with our own artillery.
Shut up.
I'm so fucking tired of not having
enough fucking bodies!
- Jesus Christ! Shut up!
- Fuck you!
- Sledge: Shut up!
- Snafu: Fuck you, Sledge!
- Shut up, Shelton!
- Fuck you!
Hey, Peck!
Peck, sit down!
- Peck!
- Come on, you fuckers!
- Kathy: Come on!
- Peck!
- You fuckers!
- (guns firing)
- Come on!
- Peck!
- Come and fucking get me!
Come on!
- Come on, you motherfuckers!
- Peck!
- Peck, come on.
- Come on and get me!
- Come on.
- Come on!
Come on!
- Come and fucking shoot me!
- Eugene!
Somebody come for me!
Come on! Come on!
Hey, Peck!
Peck!
- Stay down!
- (grunts)
(softly)
You stupid bastard. You stupid...
(yelling)
You stupid stupid stupid bastard!
You fucking idiot!
You stupid
stupid bastard!
Peck.
You're okay, Peck.
- You're okay.
- Mac: Hey.
What the fuck happened?
Hamm's dead...
and Peck's gone.
- You two, get him out of here.
- Aye, sir.
Mac:
Get some shut-eye, both of you.
- (machine guns firing)
- Mac: Down the hill!
- Bring up the rear!
- (explosions)
Let's go! Move it!
Come on! Move it!
Find cover!
(men shouting)
Man: Let's go!
Get up there!
Man #2:
Get behind that entrance!
First squad,
get behind that trash!
Clear that pillbox!
First platoon,
left flank!
- Let's go! Let's move it!
- Man #2: Let's go! Get a move on!
Get up that hill!
Man:
Machine guns, high and right!
Get up the hill!
Let's go!
- Man #2: Fire in the hole!
- Fire in the hole!
(yells)
(coughs)
(baby crying)
Might be a trap.
Lots of people
fired mortars up here.
That doesn't matter.
What the hell is the matter
with you two?
(crying continues)
- (metal chimes)
- (woman speaking Japanese)
(moaning)
(wind blowing)
(exhales)
- Find anything?
- No.
All right, let's get
these boots squared away.
Where's Burgie?
(men chatting)
- (gunshot)
- Man: Yeah-ha-ha! I got him!
How's that?
A clean shot.
- I got me a Jap.
- You see him go down?
- Man #2: Heck of a shot.
- Man: Yeah, I got him.
- (men laugh)
- Hey, what the hell is wrong with you?
Do you feel good? Huh?
Killed your first Jap?
He's a damn kid!
What's your problem?
He's a Jap.
We're here
to kill Japs, ain't we?
Check him out.
Don't look like he's
got anything at all.
(waves crashing)
(men chatting)
Burgie.
Where'd you get this,
Hammer?
Gunny Haney
gave it to me.
Pops.
Took it with him
from Guadalcanal
all the way
to Peleliu.
I heard Leyden made it
back to the States.
Son of a bitch always
said he was first.
(chuckles)
All right, enough with the sunbathing.
Let's go, move out.
We dropped some new bomb
on the Jap mainland.
- Don't that beat all.
- No. Oh, no.
This one's different...
vaporized an entire city
- in the blink of an eye.
- (man shouts)
- How?
- I don't know.
Anyway,
killed a lot of Japs.
Oh, word is battalion mess is serving
Cokes and steaks tonight.
Might even
get a movie.
Man:
Let's go! Load up!
- Let's go! Get it in tight!
- (truck starts)
Man #2:
Let's get aboard! Let's move!
- (truck starts)
- Man #2: We're heading home!
Man:
Move out!
(theme music playing)