[Speaking Russian over PA system]
CIC, Bridge.
What are we dealing with here?
Sir, EW reports
it's an old version
of a Kirov-class
guided missile cruiser.
Nuclear powered and
possibly carrying warheads.
I thought those were mothballed
in the '90s.
They're old and ugly,
but they're still dangerous.
With whom do I have the pleasure
of speaking?
I am Konstantin
Nicolayevitch Ruskov,
a former vice admiral
of the Red Banner
Northern Fleet
of the Russian Federation.
Messenger of the watch.
Please go to my at-sea cabin and
grab me a book off the shelf,
the one in Russian.
Aye, Captain.
Admiral, I need to advise you
that you are in United States
territorial waters
and are standing into danger.
Withdraw seaward or you will be
subject to defensive action.
Commander Chandler, I have
pursued you across the globe,
but I wish no further conflict.
After you have met my demands,
you and your crew
will be free
to leave the harbor
and travel the Earth
as you please.
And what would
those demands be?
Well, let's not be coy.
You have the primordial strain
of the virus
that is killing the world.
You will hand it over to me,
along with Dr. Rachel Scott
and all of her research.
Sorry, Admiral, but I don't know
what you're talking about.
And the thing is,
I don't take orders from you.
And now I'm gonna
ask you one more time.
Move your ship.
Your Navy and your country
no longer exist.
There is no higher authority
but me.
If you don't do as I say,
you and your crew
will leave this harbor
atop a mushroom cloud.
You saw what happened
to France.
You know what my ship
is capable of.
Admiral Ruskov,
I suggest we meet somewhere
face to face,
negotiate a peaceful solution
to our problem.
It will be my pleasure.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Who else has been working
on a vaccine?
What, in the world?
Everyone.
What about the Russians?
Were they close?
I mean, nobody was making
any real progress.
And I hate to say it, but they're
probably all dead anyway. Why?
If somebody had the primordial
strain of the virus,
the stuff you found in the ice,
could they make a vaccine?
I suppose, if they had
the right equipment
and someone qualified
to run it.
But they'd be months behind us.
I need to borrow
Dr. Tophet.
Can you spare him?
[Indistinct shouting]
- Out of the fryin' pan, huh, fellas?
- What?
You joining the team?
Captain thought I'd be useful,
seeing as you're all playing
in my backyard.
And before the plague,
the Fufu Cantina,
that was the place, boy.
Old Juan Carlo, he made
the best mimosas locas.
[Chuckles]
We got to get some of that.
God help us.
Suppose there's no way
to convince you not to go?
Konstantin Ruskov's
a military genius.
Literally wrote the book
on modern naval warfare.
Maybe you can ask him
to sign your copy.
Seriously, Captain, there's only
one way out of this harbor.
Every minute we sit here gives
that asshole time to dig in.
He's already dug in.
Meeting him is the only way.
I need to look him in the eyes.
Smith, Berchem,
establish the perimeter.
Masks up.
You needn't bother
with the masks.
We're not infected.
[Filtered] Well, we'll
test you just the same.
I'm unarmed.
[Speaks Russian]
Make a fist.
How can you wear those costumes
in this heat?
Still, better
than the Arctic, no?
Chandler: The Arctic was bad
for both of us, Admiral.
As I recall,
you lost five airships.
Helicopters are easy
to replace.
Look around you.
The world is ours
for the taking.
He's clean.
You see? Clean.
[Chuckles]
Jeter:
XO, take a look.
Slattery:
They're mining the bay.
We could scare 'em off
with the .50-cals.
No.
Can't risk a fire fight
with the CO off the bridge.
TAO, Bridge.
Get the Hunter in the water.
Find me a clear route
out of this harbor.
And spin Tomahawks
one through six.
If I don't hear from the Captain
in one hour,
we're unloading on that Russian
son of a bitch.
Mines.
I hate freakin' mines.
I told Moscow it was suicide
and that we must remain at sea
if we are to survive
this plague,
but they insisted--
"All ships must
return to home ports."
And so I took matters
into my own hands.
You are looking
at the last admiral
of the last ship of
the once great Russian Navy.
So the uniform we wear
matters no more.
Well, it matters to me.
Whether mine is one of a dozen
or the last ship to survive,
we're all sailors
of the United States Navy.
Of course you are.
Still, that we are here
is cause to rejoice, no?
You got a funny way
of celebrating, Admiral--
firing a nuclear weapon
at France.
How many people do you think
you killed-- 5, 10 million?
France was already dead.
That missile
was meant to stop you,
to keep you from refueling
and sneaking home
with the vaccine
in your pocket.
We have no interest in keeping the
vaccine to ourselves. It's for the world.
Do you know what was going on
in the world
while you were playing
your war games in the Arctic?
The virus spread
like an invisible fire,
destroying everything
in its path.
Bodies piled up sky-high.
The fear spread even quicker
than the virus itself--
turned country against country,
brother against brother,
governments
against their own people.
60 million Chinese were murdered
in three days
like they were culling
so many piglets.
The world...
is not worth saving.
So, what? You want to keep
the vaccine for yourself?
What I want
is of no concern to you.
Well, I don't have it.
Not yet, at least.
And you won't,
because you are missing
an ingredient only I possess.
Now, you will give me
what you have--
the primordial sample,
your research,
and Dr. Scott.
Or you die in Cuba.
You won't fire on my ship
as long as we have what you want.
And this little game of chicken
you're playing right now
will only cause millions
more to die.
So why don't I lead
with my best offer?
A sample of
the primordial virus.
With my compliments.
I'm sorry.
That will not do, not at all.
Tex: You heard
the Captain, Boris.
You ain't getting
our scientist.
Don't be foolish, Captain.
You cannot win.
I'll go.
I'll go with them.
- I can do what's needed. I'm capable...
- No!
Not him. Dr. Rachel Scott.
She is the one I want.
Well, that's not gonna happen.
I can outlast you
and your band of cowboys.
My ship has enough nuclear fuel
to patrol this harbor
for the next 25 years.
Then you get nothing, Admiral.
And while you're sitting
out there,
you can wonder,
"How am I gonna feed my men
when the Americans have all
the food on the island?"
Viktor.
[Speaks Russian]
Drop it!
Aah!
One mouth less to feed.
Gator: RMS picked up
over a dozen mines
blocking the only channel
out of here.
We can kill the ones we need,
but not without
making a lot of noise.
You were right.
Ruskov was using the extra time
to strengthen his position.
Well, it's not like we could
just sneak out of the harbor.
Even under cover of night,
we're glowing big and bright
on his radar.
We've got the world's
best fighting machine
and an entire naval base
at our disposal.
Gator, find us a way
out of here.
Lieutenant Green,
I want a tactical plan.
Work with Tex.
He's not Navy, but he knows
the island and he can fight.
We need all hands.
Yes, sir.
Doctor, Admiral Ruskov said
he had something you don't,
something you can't make
the vaccine without.
Any idea what
he was talking about?
He's bluffing.
So, what would you like me
to do now?
Well, you said you were close to
a breakthrough on the vaccine.
Keep working.
That's all that matters.
[Door closes]
[Distant upbeat music plays]
Jeter: We're at GQ, and the
Russians are having a party.
They must still keep vodka
on their ships.
You know, I wasn't even supposed
to be on this ship.
I was two days from reporting
to shore duty in Portsmouth.
And some last-minute change of
orders put me on Nathan James.
I guess that
makes you lucky, huh?
Gator: I think I found a way
out of here.
Navy used to send frigates
through this canal all the time.
Yeah, they stopped dredging that
a while back.
From what I heard, it's all
gunked up with coral and rock.
Well, that's why the Russians
didn't bother mining it.
It's too shallow for us
to get through.
Well, it's too shallow
for a DDG,
but I could mount some GLMs
on a RIB,
sail through it,
sneak up on their 180,
and launch a few HE grenades
over their stern.
A ship that size,
it's gonna take more than that.
Tex, what kind of assets
are available at Gitmo?
Army's facility has mortars,
vehicle-mounted weapons.
I got the keys to the joint.
Hell, I can get y'all
a Bradley tank.
You get us in,
we'll do the rest.
Before we do anything,
I want that canal scouted.
Ruskov's no fool.
He knows we're gonna be looking
for another way
out of this harbor.
Aye, sir.
If we start here...
[Filtered] [ Chuckles]
This is beautiful.
Reminds me of
my honeymoon video--
at least the footage
I let people see.
Too much information.
Berchem, it's probably
comments like that
that led to your divorce.
[ Chuckles]
Tex, how long to get the guns
from the army
to the top of the hill?
- A couple hours, Cap'n.
- Good.
It's not deep, but the canal
looks better than we thought.
Only real problem is that
outcropping, probably coral.
It may give us a tight squeeze.
Smith: Yeah, we'll have to blow
the coral to get a clean path.
Hang on.
I'll take you to the surface.
We can blow it, but it'll make
a hell of a boom.
- Contact!
Berchem: - Dive! Dive!
[ Both grunting]
No.
No! No!
Berchem! Smith!
Berchem, come in!
Berchem!
Berchem, come in.
Smith!
Ruskov!
Have you reconsidered my offer?
Look out your window,
starboard side.
Put 'em in the drink.
Slattery:
TAO, Bridge.
One round,
ten yards off the bow.
- TAO, aye. Break, Surface.
- Surface, aye.
Killing track 81652 with guns,
10 yard forward offset,
one round H-E-P-D.
Chandler:
Consider that a warning,
which is more than you gave
to my men.
Next time, I won't miss.
I am disappointed in you,
Captain.
You're not the leader
I imagined.
_
I will sink you.
This is an Arleigh Burke
destroyer.
It was built to fight.
You'd better know how.
CIC, this is your Captain.
Prepare to fire again
on my order.
This time, I want a direct hit.
Kara: Guns, Surface.
Cover track 85150 with guns.
5...
[Indistinct shouting]
4...
Guns, aye. Cover track 85150.
Target acquired.
3...
2...
1...
What do you want?
Shut your weapons down.
Back out of the harbor
and over the horizon.
I don't want to see
your ugly-ass ship
out of my front window.
Very well.
You have 24 hours
to turn over the doctor.
If you attempt to leave
or are planning
another brilliant sneak attack,
we will see you.
24 hours, Captain.
CIC, XO.
Cease track.
Train mount 5-1 to ready air.
_
We should have blown them
out of the water.
Soon as they're over
the horizon,
send a search and recovery team
for Smith and Berchem.
They're standing by.
_
This new thermal cycler
is a godsend.
We'll absolutely be able
to identify the gene.
How's it coming
with that centrifuge?
I was worried that the humidity
on the isla--
- Quincy, what are you doing?
- I need you to come with me now.
- What are you--
- Just go! Move!
Why are you doing this?!
Get down the stairs.
Now move!
Quincy, have you gone insane?
What is it that you want?
Getting off this ship.
Now shut up!
Quincy, you'll destroy
all the samples!
I said shut up!
Now jump.
You've got to be kidding.
Rachel,
I don't want to hurt you,
but that's exactly what will
happen if you don't do as I say.
Now jump.
Man: Hey!
What are you doing?!
[Indistinct announcement
over PA system]
He's got a gun!
Nobody move!
- Quincy!
- Hands up!
- Stay back!
- Don't shoot!
- Drop your weapon!
- Stay back!
- Drop the weapon!
Rachel:
Don't shoot him!
Quincy.
Okay.
Quincy, no!
If I open this,
the virus will kill everybody
on the ship!
So put your weapons down
and back away!
Look, Doctor.
I don't know why you did this,
but I know
we can talk this through.
We solve problems.
That's what we do.
Rachel,
you have to come with me.
It's you they want.
Just you.
I'm not going anywhere.
You're gonna have
to kill me, too.
Jeter:
Put your weapons down.
Stay back!
Rachel:
Give me the vial, Quincy.
Rachel, they're not
gonna hurt you.
They promised me.
So, please...
Please come with me.
You're not gonna kill
all these people.
It's not who you are.
Give me the vial?
Please.
[Screaming]
He must have been talking
to the Russians all along.
That's how they were able
to follow us.
I mean, he was my partner
for almost 10 years.
I'm at a complete loss!
What were his connections
to the Russians?
I don't know.
I mean, he studied there
years ago.
He has friends, he has
colleagues-- We both do.
[Sighs]
It doesn't make sense.
I told you, I hadn't met him,
not until yesterday!
So, what were you two,
like, Facebook friends?
I need to see the Captain.
My family is in grave danger.
Yeah, we'll get to that.
First you're gonna tell me
about your relationship
- with the Admiral.
- There is no relationship.
There never was a relationship!
Please, my daughter is
a prisoner on his ship!
You almost killed
my entire crew,
so I recommend
you start talking.
It wasn't supposed to happen
like this.
During the hysteria
of the outbreak,
governments were pressuring
their biologists
to deliberately withhold
vital information,
research that could possibly
contribute to a vaccine.
I disagreed.
And I began sharing information
with another scientist,
Sergei Yumanov.
Sharing?
You mean leaking.
You don't understand!
While governments bickered
amongst themselves,
the virus was winning!
I couldn't let that happen!
Ruskov suggested he had someone
or something on his ship
to help him make a vaccine.
Is that your friend?
Sergei's dead.
I'd been communicating with him
on the sat phone.
Then two weeks before the
Russians attacked us on the ice,
I called Sergei,
and it was Ruskov
on the end of the line.
He'd murdered Sergei
[Voice breaking]
and taken my family--
my daughter and my wife.
It was a Brit that kept us
in the harbor
by pretending to be CO
of that UK destroyer.
Quite a performance
by your wife.
Kelly had nothing to do
with this.
Ruskov is using her
to get to me
and, more importantly, Rachel.
Listen.
I did a stupid, stupid thing.
Do what you want with me,
but please don't make my family
pay for my mistakes.
Ruskov will kill them
if I don't do as he says.
What exactly
was your plan tonight?
I was supposed to take Rachel
and the samples
to the other side of the beach.
There's a boat I can use
to get us to the Vyerni.
Who am I impersonating
at this godforsaken hour,
the Queen of England?
No, your work is done,
duschenka.
Now it's up to your husband,
and we will see.
See... what?
If he loves his family
as much as you say.
I must admit, I have mixed
feelings about his success.
I've come to enjoy
our time together.
Chandler: The Russians
are expecting Quincy
to show up with Dr. Scott
on the civilian vessel
some time tonight
while there's no moon.
The meeting will go off
as planned
with a few important
differences.
Sir, unless we completely
cripple the Vyerni,
he'll still have
retaliatory capability.
By then, we'll be safely
out of the harbor.
Smith and Berchem
didn't die in vain.
They showed us we can make our
escape through the old canal.
Sir, forgive me, but it's one
thing to send a RHIB through.
This is a destroyer.
The water's not deep enough.
It's not possible.
Exactly why the Russians
won't expect it.
At high tide, we'll have
two, three feet clearance.
That canal is so narrow,
we won't have any margin
for error.
And then there's
the coral growth.
It'll rip our hull apart.
So we blast ourselves a hole.
But, sir, the minute
we move the ship,
Ruskov will see us
on his radar.
He's staring right at us.
Chandler:
He's not looking at us.
He's looking at a red dot
on a radar screen.
On that screen, we could be
any ship in this port.
Let's prepare the Bridge Team.
Chandler:
Lieutenant Foster.
We need a female
for this mission.
You grew up on a farm.
Can you still handle a rifle?
Qualified as expert marksman
last year.
I can knock the nipples
off a chicken
from a thousand yards, sir.
Okay, you're on Alpha Team
with Rowler.
Yes, sir.
Sir?
I don't feel comfortable
having Lieutenant Foster
on this mission.
She's never seen action
like this before.
Objection noted, Lieutenant.
- She's going.
- Then I'm riding Alpha.
Sir, I've...
I've already lost two men while
standing on the sidelines.
Search Team couldn't even
recover their bodies.
I need to be out there
this time.
Thank you, sir.
Slattery: High tide in exactly
2 hours and 48 minutes.
We're gonna take this ship
through the eye of the needle.
To avoid Russian radar,
we're gonna do it
at EMCON Alpha 1--
no sonar, no radar.
But we're up to the challenge.
Yes, sir!
- Let's get the low-vis watch
team on the bow. - Sir.
Sir, without radar,
we're gonna be awfully close
to that coral
in order to hit the mark.
We won't get a second chance.
We'll just have to get it right
the first time.
Aye, sir.
_
[All shout in Russian]
Just keep your head down!
Keeping my head down's kinda
gonna defeat the purpose,
don't you think?
We're good to go.
Next radio click comes
when they're 500 yards
from impact zone.
Chandler: Single up.
When the Master Chief's back
on board, take in all lines.
Everyone watch the clock.
We're timing this
down to the second.
Together: Aye, sir.
Last time I navigated
by dead reckoning
was the sailing team
at the academy.
I'm more nervous about being
blown out of the water.
On the bright side,
with our radar turned off,
we won't see it coming.
All right, Miller.
Find a spot right here.
All right.
I don't mean to sound dim, sir,
but how's a roll
of aluminum foil
supposed to look like
a 500-foot destroyer?
It's all about reflections,
my man.
The James has low reflectivity,
which makes us hard
to pick up on radar.
In fact, to the Russians,
we look just about the same
as a few square feet
of tin foil,
pointed in the right direction.
[Chuckles]
Master Chief, you about ready?
Yes, sir.
On your order.
Prepare to go EMCON Alpha 1.
I say again, all radar
and radio transmissions
go down on my count.
3...
2...
1...
now!
Sir, all crew back on board.
Lieutenant Granderson,
all ahead 1/3, 3 knots.
Make your course 1-3-5.
Engage prairie masker.
Aye, sir.
Helmsman,
come to course 1-3-5,
all ahead 1/3 for 3 knots.
Course 1-3-5,
Aye.
Time to disappear.
St. Nicholas point channel
light 2-6-2.
Corinaso point light 1-9-0.
Woman: Corinaso point light
1-9-0, aye.
Gator, I need a report.
Speed over ground 4.6 knots.
Course over ground 112.
I hold you at 50 yards
right of track,
recommend course 1-0-7
to regain track.
Recommended course 1-0-7,
aye.
Helmsman come to left
to course 1-0-7.
My rudder is left,
coming to new course 1-0-7.
What's our depth, Gator?
Four feet clearance
beneath the sonar dome.
To a rocky bottom.
If we're on track,
we should be hearing from them.
That's it.
They're in open water,
500 yards out, 10 knots.
Calculated impact
in five minutes.
Chandler:
We don't blast the coral
until Green and Foster
have reached their target.
We wait until
we see their blast.
Is that clear?
All: Aye, sir.
_
Ruskov should see them by now.
Let's hope he buys it.
He already thinks he's won.
_
[Speaking Russian
over loudspeaker]
Man: We're hot!
Here we go.
_
Man:
I have the reef visually
at about 800 yards
off the port bow.
OOD, based on a good fix,
holds us at 20 yards
left of track.
Helmsman, come right
five degrees rudder.
Right five degrees rudder, aye.
TAO, I'm gonna need
to blast that coral.
What's your status?
Torpedo is armed and ready.
Firing bearing set.
What are you doing?
Just bail!
I got this!
Danny, not yet!
We're gonna be late!
Speed up!
Something happened.
Alisha:
Impact is overdue, sir.
Why aren't we seeing anything?
Where are they?
Hang on.
Sir, that canal is too tight
to turn around in.
I can't slow down without
losing maneuverability.
We have to blast that coral,
sir, or it'll tear us apart!
Hang on.
You can just bail!
I'm not going anywhere!
We got to go!
[Speaking Russian
over loudspeaker]
Come on.
We're gonna hit the coral
in 15 seconds.
Hang on.
[Man speaks Russian
over loudspeaker]
Admiral?
_
Alisha:
10 seconds, sir.
Come on.
Chyort!
Aah!
Fire torpedoes!
DC Central, Captain.
Damage report.
Man: Bridge, DC Central.
Initial report...
no apparent hull damage.
OOD, let's pick up our cargo
and get the hell out of here.
Aye, sir.
All engines ahead 2/3.
Man: Rescue boat moving
to extract.
_
Nice work, Lieutenant.
[Applause]
Danny.
We were late.
I could have blown
the whole mission
and gotten all of us killed,
the whole crew.
But you didn't.
And we got out fine.
I lost my focus because of you.
Because of me?
I didn't do anything.
You throttled down
and wanted me to bail.
- No.
- Danny.
This is-- This is why
we're not supposed to...
I love you.
Just stay away from me.
[Inhales sharply]
Did Ruskov have a backup plan?
In case you couldn't get
Dr. Scott off the ship?
I haven't the faintest idea.
So, that's it, then?
They're dead.
You killed my family.
No, you killed your family!
You killed them,
and two of my best men
the minute you took up
with Ruskov!
I had no choice!
You always have a choice!
You could have asked for help!
Instead, you took the fate
of the entire world
in your hands,
and you almost threw it away!
And what would you have done?
If it were your family
on Ruskov's ship,
what would you have done?!
Answer me!
What would you have done?!
[Sighs]
Niels: [Scandinavian accent]
This is ridiculous.
Come on.
I can't believe this.
Ah, damn it!
Damn it!
Elva!
[Light clatter]
Elva, this is ridiculous.
[Sighs]
You didn't get her, did you?
No.
I thought we were all dead.
How bad is the ship?
We'll fix it.
Yeah, well...
[Scoffs]
I mean, I need that woman,
and I need the primordial.
We'll get her and the virus,
I assure you.
[Clatter]
No. Damn it!
Do I need to send someone in
to help you...
clean up?
No, please.
I'll do it.
Ah!
I hate how your men look at me.
Like I'm some sort
of circus attraction.
Oh, I'm still waiting
on that microwave oven!
I need mice!
[Screeching]
[Exhales slowly]