SONG: ♪ Do you remember ♪
♪ When we used to laugh and cry? ♪
♪ And do you remember ♪
♪ When we dreamed of things ♪
♪ And places to go? ♪
♪ We'll stand together
and forever ♪
♪ Hold on, be strong ♪
♪ Things'll be just
like they used to be ♪
♪ Where we belong ♪
♪ In the time that was before. ♪
♪ This fire burning higher ♪
♪ Get closer, it's
getting hotter ♪
♪ I melt, I'm made of water ♪
♪ Warm, warm ♪
♪ I swear this love is toxic ♪
♪ It swells up like a toxin ♪
♪ The lady and the
fox are warm, warm ♪
♪ The hotter that you make it ♪
♪ It's stronger, won't
you taste it? ♪
♪ The hotter that you make it ♪
♪ It's stronger, won't
you taste it? ♪
SOLDIER 1: Get down now!
Get down!
SOLDIER 2:
Put your hands on your head!
I said get down!
(EXPLOSION)
SOLDIER: On me. Let's go!
Come on, move!
SOLDIER: Over here!
I have them!
(GUNSHOT) Oh!
SOLDIER: This way. Let's go!
Come on!
(GUNFIRE)
- Aarggh!
- Quick!
(GUNFIRE)
SOLDIER: Main Street!
(EXPLOSION)
SOLDIER: Forget them!
(LEE COUGHS AND GROANS)
(SOLDIERS SHOUT IN DISTANCE)
(LEE GROANS)
(PANTS)
- SOLDIER 1: Clear!
- SOLDIER 2: Clear!
SOLDIER 1: Clear!
(DOOR RATTLES)
SOLDIER 1: Go! Go!
Upstairs. You two. Up top.
Nothing.
Cool room.
Ready?
SOLDIER: Whoa! (COUGHS)
Clear! Shut it!
SOLDIER: Sweep these streets.
Report any contact.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Chris!
- Watch the cereal.
- Oh, my God.
You're OK. Where's Mum?
- Is she here?
- No.
We've been invaded.
The army, they're
all over the place.
We're out of milk.
What?
Stuff in the fridge is
off and it's disgusting.
What's wrong with you?
Have you got any milk?
(ENGINE APPROACHES)
You're out of it, aren't you?
- You idiot!
- Fi, shush.
Mum and Dad could be dead.
Well, that's Dad.
- I'll bet he's got milk.
- No!
SOLDIER: Heads! On the stairs!
- Chris!
- Take them down!
Show me your hands.
Show me your hands!
Chris, you're OK, mate.
SOLDIER: Nobody move!
- It's OK.
- On your knees!
He's just a kid.
Put your hands behind your back.
- You're alright.
- On your feet. Move!
We have to go. Now.
- That's my family.
- I know.
- Where are they going?
- They're together. They'll be OK.
- You're just saying that.
- There's nothing you can do.
- There has to be.
- We have to go now. Come on!
Move it.
SOLDIER 2: Stay on me.
- Clear left.
- Clear right.
SOLDIER: Main Street's locked down.
Patrols remain on duty.
(COUGHS AND RETCHES)
(DISTANT EXPLOSION)
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
SOLDIER: The other street!
Eyes on the buildings!
Report any contact!
All clear. Nothing here.
Movement, 6 o'clock.
Rebel on the move.
Get him. Get him!
(GUNSHOT)
Rebel down!
I need two men over here!
(HELICOPTER APPROACHES)
(VEHICLE DRIVES AWAY)
Come on! Come on!
(GROANS)
Homer.
CORRIE: I can't hear anything.
He's been creeping up on
me since we were kids.
- FI: Where are Robyn and Lee?
- We don't know.
The whole town's trashed.
There's guards everywhere.
Guns, armoured trucks,
helicopters, the lot.
And the showground's a prison.
HOMER: That's probably where
they've taken them.
- Taken who?
- Chris and Dad.
They were at Fi's house.
Did you see my mum?
I saw my mum, and Ellie's.
There were other people but
I didn't get time to see.
What happened?
Soldiers chased us. They nearly
got us up near the Surf Club.
They freaked us out. Ellie made
a bomb out of a lawnmower.
She saved us.
I'll find another one inside.
SOLDIER: Keep moving!
Stay in your designated area!
MAN: (OVER LOUDSPEAKER)
Attention! Attention!
Processing of women and children
civilians will commence immediately.
Have all personal papers ready.
LIZ: You're wasting battery.
They're not going to
let us keep them.
There's no signal.
SOLDIER: Down!
We don't even know
if Ellie's alive.
- SOLDIER: Move it! Move it!
- I'm sorry.
Can we have some water, please?
MAN: (OVER LOUDSPEAKER)
Attention, Katherine McKenzie.
Katherine McKenzie, you
will identify yourself now.
Katherine McKenzie,
identify yourself.
Katherine McKenzie, you
will identify yourself now.
SOLDIER 1: Over here!
SOLDIER 2: I have her.
Liz. Liz!
SOLDIER: Stand back!
- Back off!
- Leave her. Kath!
Where are you taking me?
Leave her alone.
She's done nothing!
Come here. She'll be fine.
She'll be alright.
- LEE: How's it look?
- It's stopped bleeding.
Not too bad.
I took an advanced first
aid course last year.
You'll be OK.
You're lucky.
Don't know if I call
getting shot being lucky.
They were trying to kill you.
They would have got to me
if you hadn't dragged me in.
Thanks.
You know you have to leave me.
It's too dangerous.
There's soldiers everywhere,
all looking for us.
Either this leg will
get me or they will.
I'll go find the others.
We'll come back and get you out.
Must be painful.
We will get you out.
That's a promise and I
never break my promises.
OK. I believe you.
You smell like off prawns.
Not as bad as mouldy pig.
(BOTH LAUGH)
I don't know why
you're laughing.
You've got to get back in there.
♪ Na, na, na, na, na
Na, na, na, na, na ♪
♪ The time has come,
so go and get it ♪
♪ You put in the work,
but are you ready? ♪
♪ Clap along ♪
♪ Game on ♪
♪ Clap, clap along ♪
♪ Game on... ♪
(CLATTERING)
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Clap along ♪
♪ Game on ♪
♪ Clap along... ♪
MAN: Get out. We're here. Move!
♪ Game on ♪
♪ Game on... ♪
Is this her?
Easier if you don't ask questions.
You can just work for us now.
These are the petrol
bomb victims.
Left to right, third-degree burns,
severe internal haemorrhaging,
possible amputation.
Shrapnel severed the
femoral artery.
(MACHINES BEEP)
MAN: (OVER LOUDSPEAKER) Have any
identification papers ready.
- JACK: They're taking names.
- You will be processed...
LIZ: Why?
..and you will return
to your compounds.
So they know who's still out there
and who they've got to find.
SOLDIER: Stay in line.
Keep in family groups and you
will be processed shortly.
Kath.
I've just been working
at the hospital.
Three soldiers have been
hit by a petrol bomb.
I heard them describe who did it.
It sounds like our kids.
They're alive.
They might have got
hurt when it went off.
One of the soldiers'
legs had to be amputated
and the girl with burns, I'm not
sure she's going to make it.
We've got to get to those
kids before they do.
Yeah, how?
I don't know.
Best chance we've got is now
before they get more organised.
They're going to ask
if we have children.
We have to say no.
Right now they don't
know who they are.
But when they get
names, addresses...
When they ask if you have
children, you have to lie.
It's the only way we can
protect them right now.
SOLDIER: You have a phone?
Give it to me.
They're taking phones.
Delete photos.
Umar. George.
Umar, George, delete your photos.
Get your phone.
Delete your photos, now. Quick.
Delete 'em all.
Rachel!
(RACHEL CRIES)
SOLDIER: Keep moving.
Keep moving.
Stay in line.
MAN: Name?
Daniel Maxwell.
My wife is Rachel.
I have a daughter,
Fiona, and a son, Chris.
Step forward.
What is your occupation?
I'm a corporate lawyer.
Corporate lawyer?
If there's anything I
could help with...
There isn't.
Found it when I was
looking for a shirt.
They were our age.
This is a war.
They tried to kill you.
They're the ones that tore
up the rule book, not us.
You could always climb trees
higher than anyone else.
You were never scared.
I just hid it better.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRS IN DISTANCE)
- Name?
- Rachel Maxwell.
- Marital status?
- Married.
- Husband's name?
- Daniel Maxwell.
- Dependants?
- No.
- No children?
- No, I don't have any.
Your husband is Daniel Maxwell.
Is he OK? Is he here?
I'll take over from
here, Sergeant.
Mrs Maxwell, I am Colonel Lee.
I'm in command of this operation.
This, uh, change in the status
quo is difficult for you.
Yes.
I do understand,
and if I was in your position, I
would protect my family as well.
However, choosing not to cooperate
is not the wisest course of action.
You have alternatives,
for the moment.
Your husband is safe.
As is your son.
But your daughter, Fiona,
is in very grave danger.
As long as she remains out
there, I cannot protect her.
Or anyone she's with.
For the safety of these
children, I need you...
..to tell me who they are.
(DOG GROWLS)
MAN: (OVER LOUDSPEAKER)
Attention, collect your mattresses
and return to your allocated areas.
If you lose anything that
has been issued to you,
it will not be replaced.
You are responsible
for yourself.
There will be a muster tomorrow
morning at 7am in the main arena.
Keep all thoroughfares clear
and do not attempt to move
from your designated area.
- Did you tell them about the kids?
- No.
Did they believe you?
I think so.
What's that smell?
It's cow poo.
I think it's you.
Oh, God! I stepped in it.
I've got these.
Jack, what?
I'm gonna get us out of here.
(BIRDS CHIRP AND FLUTTER)
Shh!
We have to go now.
What if they find him?
He got shot. He can't even walk.
Before we go anywhere, we have
to come up with a plan, OK?
Maybe they've
already killed Lee.
We barely made it here alive.
I can't believe we're talking
about going back in there
to rescue someone who
might already be dead.
You only care about yourself.
How is it selfish to care
about everyone's safety?
We can't just leave him there.
We have to find out.
This should be about
safety, not friendship.
Well, it's about numbers. The more
we have, the stronger we are.
Hey, these guys are hardcore.
They've got tanks
and assault rifles.
We've got something
for shooting rabbits.
And you want to talk
about numbers -
they've got them, not us.
Yeah, all true, but
we still have to try.
We don't all have to go. It's
better if we don't. Less risky.
It's a suicide mission!
I'll go.
So will I.
No, not you, Rob.
You need to rest.
Ellie and I will go get Lee.
I'm in too.
I thought you said it
was a suicide mission.
It is.
The rest of you can't stay here.
It's too close to town.
- Let's go to my place.
- Good. So that's it.
The three of us sneak in, we'll grab
Lee and we'll meet at Corrie's.
But we'll have to find a safer place
to crash, away from Wirrawee.
Where's that?
Hell.
CORRIE: We'll need another
bike for you, Fi.
I can walk to yours.
- I can't ride a bike.
- Come on, we can both get on this.
- Ready? You OK?
- Yeah, I think so.
SOLDIER: Keep this area clear!
SOLDIER 2: Move back
from the gates!
Rations. Food rations.
Remember, only one
ration pack per person.
I need you to talk
to your friend.
Oh, yeah, what friend
might that be?
Come on, George.
You need to convince them
to let us move the cattle.
I know you've been getting these
things longer than anybody else.
People won't like that, George.
We have to find the kids.
Jack's got a plan to get us out.
There's bush behind the abattoir.
We overpower the guards
and do a runner.
- They'll shoot us!
- The kids built a bomb, George.
They're going to get
themselves killed.
You're going to get yourself
killed, that's what'll happen.
- George!
- No. You know what?
We don't even know that
Homer's with Ellie, OK?
- Where else would he be?
- How the hell should I know?
- Righto, Liz.
- Exactly. You never know where he is.
No, you know what? That's it.
I'm done. I'm out of this.
Can I borrow this?
I'll give it back to you.
These aren't enough. People
need something to sustain them.
If you don't look after
the cattle, they'll die.
You're left with rotten
carcasses, disease.
There's an abattoir
on the edge of town.
Take the cattle there,
all of us, you included.
Stay fed. Stay healthy.
I'm a cattle farmer.
I can take 'em.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh,
ooh, ooh Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh,
ooh, ooh Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ Cold, the air
inside his lungs ♪
♪ Harsh, the winter
morning sun ♪
♪ He fights to keep
from falling home ♪
♪ Where the monsters
from last night roam ♪
♪ They roam, they roam ♪
♪ So run, boy, run for your
heart and run for your soul ♪
story, and let it be told ♪
♪ So come now, so come
now into the cold ♪
♪ Into the cold ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, Ooh, ooh, ooh ♪
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh,
ooh Ooh, ooh, ooh... ♪
- He's not breathing.
- Ellie?
HOMER: Oh, pay that.
KEVIN: Sucked in!
(GROANS) That's not funny.
I wasn't trying to be funny.
I-I heard footsteps.
- I thought it was soldiers.
- Fair call.
This place is
crawling with them.
What are you doing up here anyway?
This is a terrible hiding place.
I wasn't hiding.
I came to get this.
- It was a little bit funny.
- No, it wasn't.
No pressure, guys, but
we don't have long.
They'll start moving
from shop to shop soon.
- So how are we going to do this?
- Can you walk?
Sort of.
- What happens if we help you?
- I'll give it a shot.
- OK.
- I'll try.
One, two...
(GROANS)
No, dumb idea, dumb idea, dumb idea.
We need a better plan.
Yeah, really?
Um, how about we go
back for the Landie?
OK, dumb idea.
How many soldiers are out there?
Too many. And there's
heaps of trucks.
(DISTANT SHOUTING)
You're right. We need a vehicle,
but... one that won't stand out.
- We nick one?
- That's your usual style.
Too easy.
- Should I feel nervous?
- Hey, bro, have a little faith.
We don't want anyone seeing in.
This is all so awful.
When we were riding
and it was so beautiful,
and the bike was so nice...
..I forgot to be sad.
It's OK.
It's not OK. It's not OK that I
left Lee behind when he got shot.
Robyn...
It's not OK that our families
are locked up and might die.
We all might.
(PANTS)
It's not! It's not!
Robyn, what are you doing?
Robyn, no!
(SOBS)
Robyn!
Shhhh!
(CRIES)
Just breathe. Breathe.
Think of the good stuff.
There's no good stuff. Not now.
There's us. We're together.
I'm sorry. I'm just so scared.
We all are.
(DOOR SHUTS)
(CRIES)
(COW LOWS)
(CRIES) Oh, Aggie!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Rachel!
Rach! Rach!
Hey.
I should have been
home with you.
It's OK.
You alright?
Chris with you?
It's OK. He came with me.
They separated us
for some reason.
Where's Fi?
I don't know.
You need to talk to Jack Linton.
- He's planning something.
- OK. Alright.
- You, come with us!
- Hey. Hey!
SOLDIER: Stand back.
Keep your hands off us! Stand back now.
Who is that?
Rachel's husband. He must
have been rounded up.
Hmm.
He looks like a man
of importance.
- Whatever you're planning, I want in.
- What are you doing, mate?
I want in.
Are you OK? Ohh!
Are you OK? (CRIES)
SOLDIER: Everyone out.
Come on, out, out!
SOLDIER 2: Go, go, go!
(STARTS ENGINE)
Come on, move!
Someone's gonna see us.
Just stay calm.
Easy for you to say,
being chauffeured.
I have to drive, as close
as I can to the kerb.
Like you normally do.
(LEE EXCLAIMS)
- You're kidding me.
- You can do it.
Ready? Off you go.
(GRUNTS)
Lee's not moving.
(LAUGHS) Oh, he's cool.
SOLDIER: Coming through. One, two,
in the rear. The rest with me.
Therese!
Give this to Umar. Tell Lee...
No. You're going to be fine.
I promise.
MAN: Move! With me now!
Stay with me! Wake up!
Hello! Stay with me!
Patient unresponsive.
(MACHINE BEEPS STEADILY)
Starting CPR.
Come on. Come on!
- We've got to dump this ride.
- Why?
Well, they're patrolling
with helicopters.
If they see an army truck driving
alone on a country road,
we may as well draw a big
red target on our backs.
(VEHICLE APPROACHES)
- Homer, it's Dad!
- Wait, that's Fi's father.
Dad! Dad!
Stop waving! They'll see us!
What are you doing?
- Don't!
- We can't do anything!
Don't!
Ellie, listen to me!
Listen. This is serious.
If you get out of this truck,
those soldiers aren't going
to wait and ask questions.
Let it go, Ellie.
You can't risk your life.
Or his.
Let it go.
MAN: We need a doctor!
Injured man here!
- We need help now!
- OK, OK. OK, stand back. Stand back.
Hello, hello, can you hear me?
What is his name?
Has he been shot?
I need a gurney now.
Nurse! Nurse!
Gurney, now. Now!
WOMAN: Out of the way!
Coming through.
MAN: Everyone, get back in the room.
Get back in the room!
Therese. It's going to be OK.
This'll ease the pain.
(GASPS)
WOMAN: Get out of the way.
MAN: Keep this area clear.
Did she say anything?
She told me you were
a wonderful husband.
SOLDIER: Keep moving.
The hospital's informed me that
the soldier with the burns has died.
The helicopters have moved further
out, as you instructed, sir.
- And the cows have gone.
- Gone?
To the abattoir. Some prisoners
volunteered to take them.
Which prisoners?
MAN: (OVER LOUDSPEAKER)
You are to pull over immediately.
I repeat, you are to pull
over and stop immediately.
Do you copy?
What if they don't come back?
ROBYN: We have to
believe they will.
This used to be my
favourite time of day.
Her mother was sick after she was
born and couldn't raise her.
So I did the hand-raising thing.
I was little, so was she.
She taught me how to
care for something.
I hope she gets better.
As requested, sir, the cattle's
been delivered to the abattoir
and the prisoners
returned to the compound.
And we now have the
addresses of the children.
(COW LOWS)
SOLDIER: Fiona Maxwell.
8 Federation Street.
Robyn Mathers.
98 Waratah Drive.
Lee Takkam.
33 Main Street.
Eleanor Linton.
7 Valley View Road.
Homer Ianos.
140 Waratah Drive.
Corrie McKenzie.
9 Ironbark Road.
Kill them.
(GUNSHOT)
Synced and Corrected by Clog.