Lothbrok:
Previously on Vikings...
Ecbert: I am determined
to honor our treaty.
In return, some of you,
Must fight for
Princess Kwenthrith.
Lothbrok: That is not part
of our original agreement,
But, I will fight.
Kwenthrith:
My uncle's name is Brihtwulf.
He has usurped my crown.
And your younger brother?
His name is Burgred.
My uncle has
poisoned his mind.
Why are they
just attacking my uncle?
(all shouting battle cries)
(yelling)
(grunts)
Athelstan:
King Ecbert says that
all this land is yours.
There are many farms
on this land for you
to take possession of.
Ragnar and Lagertha
talk only of farming.
Persuade your family to
support me as Earl.
(if I had a heart playing)
(soldiers shouting
in distance)
(men laughing)
You're not eating.
I know.
I'm not hungry.
For the first time in
your life.
There's a first time
for everything.
Here. These will help.
Thank you.
May Freya lie with you
tonight, and take
care of you, my friend.
I am so happy that
my uncle is dead.
But I still don't believe it.
You saw him killed.
Yes.
Yes I did.
But now...
Now I want his head!
I want his head,
I need his head.
And then I will believe it.
Floki.
(in native tongue)
Why do you hate your
uncle so much?
Do you think that
my older brother was
the only member
Of my family who raped
me when I was a child?
It was my uncle who first
brought him to me.
Since I was six years old,
he abused me.
He violated my body
and my soul.
And he told me not to
resist the attentions
of the many men
That he brought to me,
saying that they all
wanted the pleasure...
(gasping)
They all wanted the pleasure
of sleeping with a child.
And the last was
my brother, who shared
me with my uncle.
And even when
I cried and I said
that they were hurting me,
They didn't stop.
They never stopped.
(chopping and grunting)
(in native tongue)
Give this to me.
(breathing deeply)
(gasping and stabbing)
(giggling)
(spitting)
(laughing)
(all laughing)
It was good today.
I enjoyed fighting.
You fought well today,
I watched.
But you took too many risks.
You jumped
into battle, you did
not stay by my side.
Don't do that, Porunn.
You have much to learn.
Do you suddenly
not believe in our gods?
Do you not believe in fate?
Is that really Bjorn,
Son of Ragnar,
Or some impostor
who just looks like him?
I only do this because
I care about you.
Or because I'm a woman.
- (scoffs) No.
- Yes.
Marry me.
What?
I asked you to marry me.
What is your answer?
Yes.
I will marry you, Bjorn.
I will marry you.
Good.
(birds chirping)
(heartbeat thudding)
(screaming)
(indistinct shouting)
Why did you do that?
It's just the angle
of the leg.
Couldn't help myself.
(chuckling)
Kwenthrith: There you are!
I'm looking for your king.
(laughing)
Of course,
you don't understand
a word I'm saying.
(giggling drunkenly)
Oh, thank you.
(humming)
(Kwenthrith laughing)
(men laughing)
No!
At least you
understood that!
Didn't you?
(both chuckling)
No.
Lothbrok: Rollo!
Athelstan, ask the king
who used to farm this land
he has given us.
(in native tongue)
He confesses that he
has had to remove
Several saxon farmers
from their lands.
Then ask him if they will
not be hostile to us?
And if so,
Who will guarantee
the safety of our own
farms and communities?
(in native tongue)
He will personally
guarantee our
safety and security.
I thank the king
from the bottom
of my heart.
It was always
Ragnar's dream to find
land to farm
For our young folk,
and to live peacefully
with others.
Now, it is my dream, also.
(translating in native tongue)
(in native tongue)
What does he say?
He asks if you
are a free woman?
(indistinct shouting)
They are coming!
Let us prepare!
- Look at what they've done!
- Look at the lead boat.
(speaking latin)
My lord, your army
has abandoned you and
gone. Save yourself!
Burgred! Beloved brother!
Stay yourself.
Wait and I will see
that you come to no harm!
Burgred, please,
you must trust me!
Abandon your
false advisors.
You must not trust her.
She killed your brother
and she will kill you.
-But I do love her.
-Survive first,
love afterwards.
Come. Come now,
or it's too late.
My lord.
Burgred, wait!
(grunting)
Athelstan:
King ecbert has arranged
For some of the laborers
who worked here
to help us farm the land.
Whoa.
(horses whinnying)
- (in native tongue)
- (chuckling)
What are they saying?
They're saying
their grandfathers used
some of these tools.
(in native tongue)
(children laughing)
Helga:
May I tell you something?
I have had a dream.
I dreamed of a stranger,
Who was a man,
but he had no face.
Or none that I could well see.
There was snow on the ground
and he was walking towards
me through the snow,
So his footsteps
made no sound.
His arms were outstretched,
and in one hand,
He carried a ball
of flaming snow.
-In his other hand...
-His other hand was
covered in bright blood.
-And the blood left a trail
in the snow behind him.
-Yes.
And the drops were smoking
in the frozen ground?
- You too?
- Yes.
-Both of you?
-We have all dreamed
the same dream.
- Were you frightened?
- No.
I felt excited.
I felt a sense of expectation.
And when I woke up,
I was so disappointed
it was only a dream.
You are a Volva.
You say you can see things.
What does it mean?
I have no idea.
I do not know.
(thunder rumbling)
I see a harvest
celebrated in blood.
I see a trickster whose
weapon cleaves you.
I see that a marriage
of plow and sword
will sustain you,
Until you become
a virgin once more.
(in native tongue)
Athelstan, you should
bless this house.
Ask god to bless
its new occupants.
Let us pray.
In the name of
the father, the son,
and the holy spirit, amen.
I am thy lord, thy god,
which have brought you
out of the land of Egypt.
Out of the house of bondage,
thou shalt...
Kalf: Earl ingstad
has left you
to farm in England.
What good is that to us?
(crowd murmuring)
Peacefully, legally,
we have removed the
earl that was never here,
The Earl that came
to power by murder...
And the Earl who has
nothing between his legs,
but a goat's beard.
(all laughing)
I will lead you as Earl,
if you will have me.
All hail Earl Kalf!
Crowd: All hail Earl Kalf!
Hup, hup!
(in native tongue)
She will come.
Where would he have gone?
Ragnar, my brother
is a prisoner
of his advisors.
Then where would
they take him?
-To the town, to get
reinforcements.
-That is not good.
Go and find the town.
Lead on.
Why did you not go with them?
Judith: Have we
any news of our army?
Not yet.
But with Ragnar Lothbrok,
how can we fail?
Ever since I saw
Ragnar Lothbrok
and his kin
At my father's house,
I've been fascinated
by these northmen,
Especially by
their pagan ways.
You were a monk
at Lindisfarne, Athelstan.
But you lived amongst
the pagans.
Tell me, what was it like?
Lady Judith, you are a good
christian woman.
How could I describe
such things to you?
Try me.
Imagine that the sun
shone at night, and the
moon during the day.
And then imagine
that everything you
knew about Jesus Christ
Was not true,
And that the true god
was a living man,
With a single eye, a cloak,
a wide-brimmed hat,
And that this man, odin,
the all-father, knew the
secret of every heart,
And the destiny of all men.
And that he, too, was hanged
from a tree, and died
and was reborn.
Only, it happened
a long time before christ.
Before our lord.
And do you believe
in this odin?
I've had to ask myself,
"what is belief?" my lady.
(in native tongue)
Stones are much easier
to wear than earth.
(athelstan translating)
May I?
Beautiful.
Ancient one?
Where are you?
(labored breathing)
(screaming)
-(whispering)
He was bound...
-Helga: And bleeding.
So much blood upon him.
So much blood everywhere.
It was only a dream.
Yes. Only a dream.
Halt!
You know of Lord Burgred.
Of course you do.
But where is he?
I don't know.
Where were you riding to?
I had business in repton.
It must be very important
business. You were
riding like the wind.
I don't know where
Lord Burgred is.
Believe me.
(clears throat)
(sighing)
I don't believe you. Sorry.
(whimpering)
I could remove an eye,
or some teeth.
Do you have a preference?
(whimpers)
Why don't you just
say something?
Mention a place...
(shouting) A name!
(groaning)
Even if it's a lie,
it might just save your sight
for a little while.
(wailing)
There's an iron age fort
on top of the hill of the ash!
Burgred and his army
have gone there.
-They're waiting
for reinforcements.
-All right.
(sighing)
It's strange...
How you always know
When someone is
telling the truth.
I have no argument
with you, my friend.
Let's sup together.
We are not all like
The Northmen.
Forgive me, my lady, I...
I did not want to disturb you.
I was just remembering...
I'm sure you can
never forget being
an artist. Nor a monk.
Which is why I've
come to ask you a favor.
I want you to
hear my confession.
I was never a priest,
I couldn't...
Bishop Edmund,
my confessor, is not here.
And I must confess
or live in purgatory.
(bells tolling in distance)
Forgive me, father,
for I have sinned.
In what ways have you
sinned, my child?
I have sinned in thought,
but not in deed.
Then your sins are not
so great as they might be.
(whispering)
They are still great.
What are these thoughts
you've had?
I have dreamed
of lying naked...
Beside a man who is
not my husband.
And did you just lie
beside him, or...
We made love.
And I enjoyed it
very much.
You've certainly sinned.
Yes.
Who...
Who was this man you lay with?
It was you, Athelstan.
(gasping)
Kalf: I had a dream
last night.
And in my dream...
Ragnar Lothbrok
tore the liver from my body...
And began to eat it.
I begged him to stop...
By saying that the liver
Is the seat of life.
But he just smiled
and went on eating,
With blood streaming
down his chin.
Einar: What did it mean?
Kalf: Who knows with dreams?
Einar: Are you afraid of
Ragnar Lothbrok?
What sensible man would
not be afraid of a farmer
who made himself a king?
Yes, but you, too,
had humble beginnings.
And not so humble dreams.
So, you want to be
like Ragnar?
I want to be famous
like Ragnar...
Yes.
I desire fame
above all things.
I want the poets to sing
of my exploits as
they sing of Ragnar's.
I want the gods to pay
an interest in me,
And prepare the bright halls
for my coming.
They say Ragnar is
descended from Odin.
He is still human.
If you cut him,
he will bleed.
(coins clinking)
- (clattering)
- (laughs)
(grunts)
- (coins clinking)
- (crowd reacting)
Hey! You bastards.
What, you couldn't have
done better, Torstein!
I don't care about that game.
I want you to cut off my arm.
-Why not keep it?
-Because it's killing me,
stupid.
It's no good to me anymore.
I don't want it.
In fact, I've always
hated this arm.
It has to go.
(exhales and sniffs)
I'll do it.
Ah, Bjorn.
Always so considerate.
A real credit to your father.
But...
I want Floki to do it.
Will you do it, floki?
I suppose so.
I would do the same for you.
I know.
That is why I shall do it.
Cut off his sleeve.
Come here.
(exclaiming)
You sure you want to go ahead?
No, not my head.
Just cut off the
stinking arm, man.
Get on with it.
Too bad it's not
your flicking arm.
You could have saved
some money.
(sizzling)
(hacking)
(screaming)
(sizzling and screaming)
Frey and Freya, ye gods,
be with him now.
(screaming and panting)
(indistinct chattering)
Earl Ingstad and I
would like to thank
both of you
For your hospitality
and kindness.
King Ecbert,
we remain in your debt
For this gift of land,
and hope.
No, I remain in
your debt, Athelstan,
For, on this journey,
you have suffered grievously.
And yet, it is you who has
taught me that it is possible
to respect two cultures,
And to live in amity
between them.
Thank you.
Please tell Earl Ingstad
how much I admire her
and that she is always,
Always welcome at my hearth.
(translating in native tongue)
(in native tongue)
It is so beautiful,
that it must have been
made by dwarves.
(chuckling)
We don't have dwarves
in England.
(in native tongue)
She says, "of course you do.
You just don't see them."
You did not wait to hear
your penance.
Here is my penance.
You are leaving.
Is that not a good thing?
It saves you from further sin.
So you love our
young monk, do you?
I do not love him.
He fascinates me.
Well, be careful, Judith,
who you choose
to be fascinated by.
It is true that
the more complicated
a person is,
The more interesting he is.
But at the same time,
The more dangerous he is.
And would you say that
about yourself, father-in-law?
Man in distance: I see them!
Man: My lord.
- I know where they are.
- Where are they?
On top of that hill.
-They're drawing us away
from our boats.
-Assemble the men.
- Aye, my lord.
- Yes, my lord. Straight on!
(inaudible)
(gasping)
I've injured my hand
rather badly, as you can see.
I wonder...
Can you help me?
(sizzling)
(door opening)