MAN: Before my father died,
he said the worst thing about growing old
was that other men stopped
seeing you as dangerous.
I've always remembered that, how being
dangerous was sacred, a badge of honor.
You live your life by a code, an ethos.
Every man does. It's your shoreline.
It's what guides you home.
And, trust me,
you're always trying to get home.
(FABRIC WHIPPING IN WIND)
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(BEEPING)
(HONKING, ENGINE WHIRRING)
(CHATTERING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(BELL JINGLES)
MAN OVER RADIO: Authorities say
the ring is centered in Costa Rica,
with the primary export being...
(HORN HONKING)
(MAN SHOUTS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(LAUGHING, CHATTERING)
(HORN HONKS)
(ENGINE RACING)
MAN OVER RADIO: ...widely unknown if
the war on drugs is connecting them...
(LAUGHING, CHATTERING)
("CAMPTOWN RACES" PLAYS
FROM ICE CREAM TRUCK)
MAN OVER RADIO: ...in the region
have been known to retaliate using a...
- ("CAMPTOWN RACES" CONTINUES)
- (HORN HONKS)
MAN OVER RADIO:
...25,000 troops...
- (CHILDREN CHEERING)
- (HORN HONKING)
(SONG CONTINUES)
(CHILDREN SHOUTING)
MAN OVER RADIO:
...flying from the US to control that...
- (CHILDREN SHOUTING)
- (MAN SHOUTS)
(MAN CACKLES PLAYFULLY)
Can we get some ice cream?
- No, we gotta go.
- You always say no.
- Well, are you gonna buy?
- No, you buy.
OK, what are
we getting today?
- Passion fruit.
- OK, passion fruit.
(CHILDREN CLAMORING)
MAN: How about macadamia nut?
(MUSIC AND CHATTER FADE)
(EXPLOSION ROARS)
(SCREAMING)
WOMAN OVER RADIO:
...claimed responsibility for the attack
at the International School in Manila.
MAN: Your father was a reader.
Churchill, of course, but also Faulkner
and books about Tecumseh.
He loved artists who painted people
with bodies that looked like boxes.
I'd give him hell about that.
He'd just say,
"You gotta look harder."
(MAN SHOUTING ORDERS
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Ambassador Margullies had long
been a strong supporter
ofjoint counterterrorism operations
conducted within this region.
Not one group has yet claimed responsibility
for the attacks on the International School.
- Here's your coffee, Rorke.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- How's it going?
- Hey, you want the usual?
- Sounds good, thank you.
- You're late again, Dave.
(LAUGHS)
I didn't say anything.
What do you got
going on over here?
- Are you serious, man?
- We're not telling anyone yet.
You a little nervous, though, huh?
Last time I checked,
they don't come with directions.
Yeah, tell me about it.
- Hey.
My man here is having a baby.
Hey, congratulations.
Hey, everybody,
Rorke's having a baby.
- (CHEERING)
- WOMAN: Congratulations, Rorke!
- Whoo!
- (APPLAUSE)
- What did I just say?
- Ah, don't worry about it, man.
You're gonna be awesome. I'm so excited
for you, man. You're gonna be a good dad.
Hey, tomorrow Jackie and I
are heading down to the beach.
Bring Sandy and the kids.
I'll bring an extra board for you.
- You know I don't surf.
- I know you don't surf, but it'll be good
- to get the families together.
- All right.
But now that you've told everyone in the bar,
try and contain yourself tomorrow.
I will try.
(BEEPING)
DAVE: "Look harder,"
your father would say.
I always knew he wasn'tjust talking
about those boxy abstract paintings.
There's threats everywhere,
and the world is draped in camouflage.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING, CHATTERING)
(CHEERING)
CHRISTO: Huh?
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Hey, I'll be right down, all right?
Whatever you say, Boss.
(DOG BARKS)
WOMAN: How was the ride?
MAN: I left Colombia this morning.
- Colombia to here in one day?
- Piece of cake.
Anyway, estimates say
that Christo is worth
- close to a billion.
- That's with a "B"?
Yeah, and he gives back a lot
to this community over here
with medical clinics,
schools, political donations,
you name it, so this is the deal:
They are extremely
loyal to him over here.
When did the DEA hand him over to us?
When they intercepted a 707 of his
filled with Soviet weapons.
Listen, Langley says that
the boys over at NSA,
they found some interesting
intercepts connecting Christo
to a jihadist network
out of Southeast Asia.
Apparently, Christo and one
of the guys running the network,
they're childhood friends.
(CAMERA CLICKING)
DAVE: Your father's
grandfather gave up his life
flying a B-24 in World War II.
He kept the Liberator aloft
just long enough for everyone to jump,
and then he went down
with the plane.
That's the blood
that courses in your veins.
- Daddy, can I come with you?
- You want to come with me?
Did you feel how cold it is out there?
I'll tell you what,
go hang out with Mommy for a little while,
help out with the baby.
When I come back in, if you still want
to go out, I'll take you out with me.
- Promise?
- I promise. Hurry up, go.
- What's going on, sir?
- What's up, brother?
- Nothing much, man.
- Now, I know you got the New York heritage,
but this isn't exactly like
sitting back in Staten Island.
You got to actually work hard
to get through the surf.
- Yeah, I know.
- Twelve-plus years on the Teams,
and you don't know
how to do this?
Hey, wait till you
have five kids, man.
You'll see how much time
you got to play in the surf.
You ready to get
in the drink or what?
All right, man, lead the way.
- All right, don't embarrass us.
- All right.
DAVE: Your father was my Boss,
and I was his Chief.
What we knew about each other
strengthened our bond as operators.
There was a brotherhood between us,
and we depended on each other
more than a family.
Tecumseh said,
"Although a single twig will break,
a bundle of twigs is strong."
(WOMAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
OK, OK, gracias.
Wow, this is unbelievable.
I still can't believe you
ordered Chinese in this place.
It's really good.
("TE VI" PLAYS OVER RADIO)
(CHUCKLES)
Double word score,
18 points.
- "Dumb"?
- Read it and weep, sugar.
(CHUCKLES)
I'll try not to.
Look at this, look at this.
Thirty-eight points for me.
"Adumbrating,"
that's not even a word.
OK, first of all,
it's pronounced "adumbrating,"
and it means pretending,
foreshadowing.
- (DOORBELL BUZZES)
- Hm...
Guess who's buying dinner
tonight, sugar.
("TE VI" CONTINUING OVER RADIO)
Fine.
In most cases,
officers get tactical partners.
Langley sets me up
with some sort of SCRABBLE hustler.
WOMAN: SCRABBLE Yoda, OK?
Get it right.
(SIGHS)
- How much do I owe you?
- Nada.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (MAN YELLS IN SPANISH)
- Shit.
- ("TE VI" CONTINUING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (MAN YELLING)
- (SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
- (WOMAN GRUNTS)
(MEN SPEAKING SPANISH)
("TE VI" FADING)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(CHURCH BELL TOLLING IN DISTANCE)
("TE VI" PLAYING ON CAR STEREO)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
DAVE: Our platoon
was headed downrange.
We had Weimy, our sniper.
He grew up in the middle
of the Mojave Desert.
Most excitement he found
as a kid was bowling frozen turkeys
down the aisle at the grocery store.
Ray, our comms guy, our radioman,
he grew up in East LA gangland.
He had a Silver Star for pulling
a wounded teammate out of the fray.
Sonny, he was made of granite.
This guy didn't even do push-ups
'cause he was afraid his chest
was gonna get too big.
Ajayjoined the Teams
late in his 30s.
He'd been a Muay Thai fighter
early in life.
Before that, he grew up
dirt-poor in Trinidad.
Mikey had 20 years in the Teams.
But as humble as he was,
you'd never even know it.
He kept a picture of his wife in his helmet
and a lock of her hair in his pocket.
Quiet as the breeze.
And finally, Senior Chief.
I couldn't really
tell you much about him...
...other than I'd rather
take a knife into a gunfight
than have to be interrogated by him.
(INAUDIBLE CHATTER)
That last night at home,
you think about how you could
have been a better dad,
a better husband.
That bedtime story you should have read
or that anniversary you forgot.
You don't expect your family
to understand what you're doing,
you just hope they'll accept it.
When you get home, you hope you
can pick up right where you left off.
- What up?
- (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- You putting the wild bunch down?
- Yeah, yeah.
Hey, Senior, you mind giving
us a couple minutes, man?
- Nah, you got 'em, Jefe.
- Thanks.
Hey, fellas, you know
I only got so many speeches
in a given work-up or deployment, but, uh...
...it's like Chief and I said right
at the beginning of this platoon:
Once we step off on campaign, once this
bird's ready and we're downrange,
everything back home
needs to be in balance.
We're not gonna be worth a damn
to each other or ourselves
if we get over there
and something's out of whack.
I mean, if things
aren't right with the family,
things aren't right with the finances
or something's off,
it's gonna put us all out of balance, so we
need to have that tight before we launch.
If somebody's got an issue,
bring it up.
Chief can take care of it, I can take care
of it. Everybody's got each other's back.
Let's make sure we lock that down
so when we're ready to roll,
all our focus is on the mission.
DAVE: For all those
who have been downrange,
to us and those like us,
damn few.
- Cheers.
- Hear, hear.
I still like the name James.
I'll think about it,
if it's a boy.
Come here.
- I'm proud of you.
- Thanks, baby.
Hey, little one, you make sure
you keep Mama away from Aunt Carol.
I don't like that
chain-smoking at all.
I got it, Lieutenant.
- OK.
- It's gonna be OK.
- All right.
- It's gonna be fine.
Try to keep this as long
as you can for a while, yeah?
Anything else, Commander?
Yeah. I'd like to be able to look into
your eyes when our first child is born.
You know I'll do my best.
I love you, baby.
Love you.
DAVE: War is a country of will.
There's no room for sympathy.
If you're not willing to give up everything,
you've already lost.
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
MAN: Tell me, what is it
about you Americans that makes
you feel entitled to fuck
with the way I make my living?
(BEEPING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I know who you are, Miss Morales,
and I know who you work for.
So why don't you
save us both some time
and tell me exactly
what you think you know?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(PANTING)
(PANTING ON PHONE)
CHRISTO: How did that feel,
Miss Morales?
Have a great day at the spa.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
MAN ON PHONE: Si, jefe.
(DISTORTED DIALOGUE OF
MAN AND MORALES ARGUING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- Hey, fellas, what's up?
- Hey.
It's hotter than two rats screwing
in a wool sock out there, yeah?
Africa-hot...
Tarzan couldn't take this heat.
Anyway, here's the deal.
Time to get your frogman on.
Lights. Three days ago,
two CIA agents, a Walter Ross
and a Miss Lisa Morales,
were ambushed inside their
hotel room here in Costa Rica
by a unknown amount
of heavily armed assholes.
Unfortunately, Mr. Ross was murdered,
and Miss Morales has been abducted.
We believe that this has been the work
of a guy named Mikhail Troykavitch,
aka Christo.
LT's going to give you
the skinny on him.
Thanks, Senior.
Mikhail Troykavitch, aka Christo.
This guy is believed to have been
working cocaine-for-weapons deals
between the Russian mafia, the FARC
guerrillas, and the Mexican drug cartels
ever since the late 1990s.
Now, before she was captured,
Morales was working a possible link
between our boy Christo
and this guy Abu Shabal.
Glory to Allah,
Lord of the worlds,
who has created us as Muslims
and delivered us with the jihad
on his direct path.
Peace be upon those who follow his
direct path till the Day of Judgment.
Let me explain this to you Americans.
We are not separatists.
We Chechens are not
a legal part of anyone,
but you Americans are willingly
or unwillingly assisting
in the genocide of our people
by demanding that we obey certain rules,
and by your continued
occupation of all Muslim countries.
With the grace of Allah,
glorious and exalted is he,
America will never be safe
until safety becomes a reality for us.
Allahu Akbar.
LT: Abu Shabal is
a Chechen terrorist
who's associated with
the Beslan School Massacre.
He's been jumping between training camps
in Indonesia and the Philippines.
Now, the connection between Christo
and Abu Shabal is still a little bit fuzzy,
but if this was the lead
that Morales was working on,
it could be why
she was abducted. Senior?
All right, this is a personnel
recovery of Miss Morales.
All right, who's got questions?
Senior Chief, you got
any updated source intel
on numbers inside the camp,
and what about roving patrols?
Maybe eight to ten, bro, but we don't
know anything about roving patrols.
You're just gonna have to assume
that they're out there
walking around, squared away.
They do this for a living, too.
Senior, what kind ofweapons-on-target
are we looking at?
Heavy weapons.
These guys are narco-traffickers,
so they can have anything
from Soviet-bloc DShKs.
They could have M2HP,
.50-cals out there, we don't know.
So if there is a weapons' emplacement up
there, I suggest you guys bring rockets.
Of course, rockets and foliage don't match,
so make sure you got a clear shot.
- All right, what else?
- Any idea whether she's ambulatory or not?
There was a ton of blood on the scene,
and a lot of it was Mr. Ross',
we confirmed that.
Miss Morales may have bled there, too,
but these guys are savages,
so you're gonna have to assume
that she is non-ambulatory,
so you're gonna have
to bring stuff to carry her out.
MAN OVER PA:
Two minutes to drop.
Hey, LT.
You got to let us know who that guy is,
so when we get back, we can kick his ass.
What guy?
The guy that gave you
that fucked-up haircut.
- Fuck.
- AJAY: Damn, Sonny,
you should be the last guy to talk.
You look like the Dominican Mr. Clean.
SONNY: That means my head
shines like your gold teeth, huh?
- (LAUGHTER)
- Don't be like that,
- that's harsh.
- Ramp!
(METAL CLATTERS)
Mask up.
Man, I tell you what. The only thing better
than this right here is being a dad,
except for that whole
changing diaper thing, but...
...Sandy does that for me anyway, so...
I'm actually looking forward to it.
MAN OVER PA:
Blackbeard, green light in ten.
Five.
(BEEPING)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(NOCTURNAL ANIMALS CHATTERING)
(BUZZING)
(RADIO STATIC CRACKLES)
Blackbeard Main, Blackbeard Main,
this is Blackbeard Actual.
Radio check. Over.
Blackbeard Main, Blackbeard Main,
this is Blackbeard Actual. Over.
MAN OVER RADIO:
Roger, Actual. This is Main.
- We have you Lima Charlie.
- Roger, Main.
All boots are on the ground.
I pass T-bird.
Any traffic for my station
at this time?
MAN OVER RADIO: Actual,
imagery picked up an increase in traffic
at secondary location,
known to be enemy QRF,
eight clicks from primary target.
The SWCC boats will insert
at 0600 for your extract.
- How copy?
- Roger, Main.
- You ready?
- Roger that, sir.
We got about 4.7 clicks
at three-five-five.
Take it out.
MAN OVER RADIO:
Whiplash, one minute out.
Thirty seconds.
Ten by ten.
Whiplash, go.
WHIPLASH OVER RADIO:
All boots on deck.
(ENGINE STARTS UP)
Line secure.
MAN OVER RADIO:
Whiplash, Bucket One and Two are out.
(BEEPING)
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard.
Radio check. Over.
Blackbeard, it's Whiplash.
Have you loud and clear.
Standing by on the set.
Roger, Whiplash.
What is your ETA to my pos?
WHIPLASH OVER RADIO:
ETA 20 mikes.
Be advised, Raven is in flight
and pushing to your location.
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
- (WHIRRING)
- (GROANS)
(WHIRRING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
- No!
- (LOUD WHIRRING)
No!
(SCREAMS)
Hey, sir, we gotta go.
(SCREAMING IN DISTANCE)
Roger. Take it out.
I feel like we're pretty thin.
I'd like to take you guys with us.
Chief, I got a SBT coming up on-step.
I got a Raven pushing my pos.
Weimy and I are
in good overwatch position,
and I got to keep reporting
back to Blackbeard Main.
- We're staying here.
- Roger that.
- Keep it tight.
- (WHISPERS) Got it.
(BEEPING)
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard.
Assault force is moving to the target early.
Request immediate fire support.
WHIPLASH OVER RADIO:
Blackbeard, it's Whiplash. Good copy.
Requesting fire support.
Pushing to your location in 15 mikes.
Whiplash, this is Blackbeard.
I have positive control of the Raven.
(WATER BUBBLING)
(SILENCED GUNSHOT)
(BREATHING STEADILY)
Chief, are you set?
(RADIO STATIC CRACKLES)
(SILENCED GUNSHOT)
RORKE OVER RADIO:
Chief, Chief, hold it.
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BREATHING STEADILY)
One o'clock, base of the tower.
- Got him.
- (SILENCED GUNSHOT)
RORKE OVER RADIO:
You're clear to the door.
(BREATHING STEADILY)
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BREATHING STOPS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(BREATHING RESUMES)
(NEARBY VOICES IN SPANISH)
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
I've got two squirters
coming out the back door.
- (MAN SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
- (RAPID GUNFIRE)
Going in!
- Clear!
- All clear!
Weimy, eleven o'clock.
Driver's side, truck.
- Got him.
- (GUNSHOT)
- Fuck.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(SHOUTING)
- Come on.
- Go in! Go in!
- Clear!
- All clear!
- Target's secure.
- Chief, I'm going to get Mikey.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
LT, this is Chief.
Target is secure.
Stand by for confirmation
of the package.
Be advised Mikey is down.
Mikey is down. Status to follow.
Roger. You have the package.
Chief, I got his cell phone.
LT? LT?
Chief, looks like you have two aggressor
vehicles approaching from the north,
about one mike out. You can take
the truck outside the west door.
Meet us at extract.
Miss Morales, I'm bringing you home.
I just need to ask you a few questions.
What's your mother's maiden name?
Rosales.
What street you were born on?
Hot Springs.
All right. Just hang on.
Whiplash, we have enemy QRF
approaching from the north.
Roger. You have enemy QRF
coming in from the north.
Chief, you need to start your exfil now.
- We'll meet you at secondary extract.
- Roger that.
Hey, boys, we gotta roll!
Shit. Sir, it's those trucks,
- about 1,000 yards.
- Yep.
Ma'am, I'm taking you out right now.
Hey, Chief, he took a round to the eye
with the exit wound behind the ear.
He's alive, but we gotta get moving now!
Weimy, coming out.
OVER RADIO:
We'll meet you at the rally point.
Let's go! Let's go! Move it!
- Heads up! Fast movement on the left!
- Right turn! Right turn!
(PANTING)
Hey, man, we're not going
to make it to secondary extract.
I got to find us a route.
Stay on this road.
- Left, left, left.
- Left turn! Left turn!
Mikey, come on, buddy.
Hey, Chief!
We're not gonna make secondary extract!
- You're gonna have to figure it out, man!
- Hold on!
Come on. Stay with me.
Stay with me.
Stay with us.
Come on, Mike. Wake up.
Wake up. Come on, man.
- Contact!
- Pick it up, pick it up.
Yo, Chief!
We can make it to rally point!
- Sounds good! Pass it to LT!
- Come on, man.
LT, LT, this is assault team.
We just lost the secondary extract.
I say again, we just lost
secondary extract.
Moving to rally point.
How copy, over?
(GUNFIRE)
- We're about a click out.
- Mikey, wake up.
One click out!
Let's go, Mike.
Wake up. Come on, buddy.
Come on, Mikey! Wake up!
- Good?
- Backstage clear.
- Rocket out!
- (ROCKET WHISTLES)
- (SHOUTING)
- He's not breathing!
- Breathe, Mikey!
- We're up! We're up!
Chief, let me get your M-4!
Sir, what's the status
on those boats?
I lost Whiplash on the run.
Told 'em you hit the target early.
They're coming in hot.
- Roger that.
- Fuck! Take this, man.
Breathe, Mikey. Come on, Mikey.
- I got no pulse.
- Contact rear!
Contact rear!
- [yelling]
- Holy shit!
Taking rounds in...
Pick it up. Pick it up.
Ajay! QRF coming up the rear!
Whiplash! Whiplash!
Secondary extract is burnt.
Moving to tertiary extract.
I have eight packs,
seven Sierras, one package.
OVER RADIO: Package
with multiple wounds.
The Sierra has gunshot wound
to the head.
This will be a hot extract.
What the fuck?!
- Oh, shit!
- Mikey, stay down!
- Keep him down, man!
- MIKEY: Where the fuck am I?!
- Calm down, brother.
- Mikey's up, man. Mikey's up.
Stay down, brother. Calm.
Be easy. We're almost out of here.
We're almost out of here.
(MUTED DIALOGUE)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
- Mikey!
- (MIKEY SHOUTING)
- Hang on, buddy.
- MIKEY: Where are we?
- We're on our way to extract.
- What happened?
You're good to go.
You took one to the face, man.
You're a hard motherfucker.
- Did we get her?
- Yes.
- Oh, my God.
- We're on our way to extract.
- Ajay, splash it. Splash it.
- (GUNFIRE)
Water! Water! Water!
Going in! Going in!
I got her! I got her!
It's fucking going under.
Out! Get the fuck out!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
(SHELLS RATTLING)
(SHOUTING)
(GUNFIRE)
- (SHOUTING)
- (GUNFIRE)
(GUNFIRE ECHOING)
ECHOING: It wasn't for nothing.
(MUTED DIALOGUE)
(BIRD CALLING)
(BEEPING)
(PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC)
(TRAIN WHISTLES IN DISTANCE)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(VIOLIN PLAYING)
(BIRD CALLS)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
(BEEPING)
- (CHATTER ON TV)
- (YELLING)
(MAN SPEAKING
FOREIGN LANGUAGE ON TV)
(BELL TOLLING IN DISTANCE)
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(CHUCKLES)
You know, from time to time,
I get to see my old friends
from my old life.
(CHUCKLES)
And it's always, always disappointing.
Some become assholes,
other boring,
and I can't believe I tried to get them
in bed all those years ago.
(LAUGHS)
Hey.
It is nice not to be disappointed, Yuri.
(CHUCKLES)
- That's not my name.
- I know.
Mohammed Abu Shabal,
the son of Shabal.
Come on.
Your father's name is Yevgeny.
Things change.
SubtitleSync (http://www.subtitlesync.com.ar)