(Man) What... What do you want to know?
I live in a shit barracks,
constant threat,
I could get shot at any minute,
through any window.
I wake up every morning,
do the same patrols every day.
Basically,
the only thing I'm fighting for
that I know that I'm fighting for,
is to make it home each and every
day without getting killed.
Because I don't know why we're here.
Well, I know why we're here,
but I don't know...
Yeah. I don't know why we're here.
I mean, I've seen a, I'd say
about a 60-year-old woman
all dressed in black in a burka,
whatever they call them dresses,
pull out a AK from under her skirt
and start spraying.
Needless to say, she got...
I mean, she became a combatant,
and that's the truth, you know.
Man, woman, child, if they pick up
a gun and start shooting at you,
they're considered a combatant.
That's reality.
It's also just like hunting.
I've hunted deer
and coyotes and shit.
It's like,
a person thinks the same...
tries to think like another
person would with a weapon.
So it's the ultimate style of
hunting, is war.
This is the Planet Earth, the body,
right?
The body's Planet Earth.
And Iraq is the corn hole.
The brown hole, the asshole,
whatever you wanna call it.
With a bunch of dingle berries,
insurgents...
A bunch of dingleberries
hanging around
just waiting for a shit storm.
And we just happen to be the fucking
turds going through the asshole,
and all the dingleberries are
surrounding us, trying to kill us.
That's what I think about Iraq.
It's a giant butthole.
(# Ministry: Lies Lies Lies)
# We're on a mission to never forget
# Three thousand people
that I've never met
# We want some answers
and all we can get
# Is some kind of shit
about a terrorist threat
# Lies, lies, lies, lies
Lies, lies, lies
# Surprise, surprise...
(Whooping)
(Laughing and whooping)
Yeah, yeah, fuck, yeah!
Do you like that shit?
Kiss my fucking ass!
Hey, this is why I fucking love
the Marine Corps!
# Lies, lies, lies, lies
Lies, lies, lies
# Surprise, surprise #
All right, let's go.
Hey, Corporal Marcus, take your
fire team across the street.
(Urinating)
- Look, look, look, Jase.
- What the fuck, Doc?!
- I've never seen a dick that small!
- Put your little dick away! Let's go.
Hey, you hear that? His dick's so
small he's peeing on his nuts.
Hurry up, get back in formation.
- Hey, Cuthbert.
- Yes, Corporal?
- You ready to get some?
- Oorah!
We've found 119 IEDs,
and these faggots are playing
on the side of the road.
All the insurgents came from Fallujah.
They all here waiting for us.
You know that, right?
- Yes, Corporal.
- We just live bait.
Now, you retards, stop fucking around.
(Call to prayer)
(Horns blare)
(ln Arabic)
(Clucking and squawking)
(Siren)
(Speak in Arabic)
(TV on)
(Speaks in Arabic)
(Reporter speaks in Arabic)
(George Bush) Democracy will succeed
because every month
more and more Iraqis are fighting
for their own country.
People we have liberated will not
surrender their freedom.
Democracy will succeed
because
the United States of America
will not be intimidated
by a bunch of thugs.
(Cheering and screaming)
Thank you all.
(Voice over soldiers' radio)
(Horns blare)
- You got DVDs?
- Yeah, sure, I got. You want? Yeah.
These are the only DVDs you have?
Let me imagine
what you're looking for.
Looking for boom boom?
- (AIl) Boom boom!
- That's what I'm talking about!
Try it and you must trust me.
Try it and trust you.
I don't trust you motherfuckers
for anything.
- (Horn)
- I'm sorry, I have to go.
I leave you with my uncle. He give
you a good deal, OK?
(ln Arabic)
(lraqi music)
(Beeps horn)
Hey, Marcus,
check this fucking video out.
I bought this downtown at the electrical
shop off a bunch of fucking kids.
It's on Al Qaeda TV
and they burn it to a DVD.
It's all our guys that were here before us,
patrolling these same streets.
Makes me wanna go out there
and fucking just kill the motherfuckers.
Kill more people. If they're gonna
go out and do this shit to us,
we should kill more of
them, you know.
(Chatter and laughter)
I'm not fucking dying in Iraq.
Oh, yeah.
- I'm gonna die fucking drowning.
- You're gonna die on the rag.
- You'd rather die, what?
- Surfing.
- Surfing?
- What, a fucking shark?
Butt surfing?
- Dick surfing!
- (Laughter)
- Ramirez. Why'd you join the Marines?
- Why did I join the Marines?
To get the fuck out of Philly.
What was wrong with Philly?
What the fuck was wrong with Philly?
It was the year of the
cheese steak depression...
- (Laughter)
...and everything was going downhill.
Nah, man.
I mean, it's the murder capital.
Who the fuck wants to live there?
Let me guess. You was in a gang.
No, Philadelphia doesn't
even have gangs, dude.
So you left the murder capital
of the United States
to come to Fallujah and Haditha,
the murder capitals of the world.
Good job, you're moving up, buddy (!)
(Man on radio)... is the Apache nearby?
Suspect seen on Highway 1 moving east.
Who the fuck are they?
I really don't know
whose fucking are they, sir.
They talking about
misunderstanding with their friend...
Corporal Ramirez, Corporal Marcus
reporting as ordered, Sir.
Follow me.
OK, I want you guys to go down
from Camp Sparta
down Market, make a left on the
zebra, go over to the roadblock,
make sure the Marines have chow.
We having door issues back there?
Fucking shut it.
Thank you.
Hey, we gotta go down Market Street
and make a right on Chestnut
then on over the bridge over
to the vehicle checkpoint.
I don't think
everybody likes us here.
Whoa! Cuthbert, you fucking retard!
What?
Are you a fucking idiot?
- Shit!
- What was that?
Cuthbert just smacked
the fifty cal on a truck, man!
- I know, I saw.
- A born dildo.
Goddamn boob.
(lraqi music)
(lndistinct speech over
soldiers' radio)
Come. Come here. Go over there.
Ali, can you get them for me, please?
- Cuthbert, what are you doing?
- They're kids. Sergeant, sorry.
Stop! Stop!
- (Child crying)
- Tell him stay there.
Step this way, please.
- Stop. Put your hands up.
- (lnterpreter translates into Arabic)
Put your hands up.
- Tell 'em to hurry up.
- (lnterpreter translates into Arabic)
Go.
Stop.
Get your hands in the air.
(lnterpreter translates)
Put your hands in the air.
- Away from the door?
- Yes.
Vehicle good.
- Tell 'em hurry up.
- (lnterpreter translates)
(Horn blares)
(Music on radio)
(Goats' bells tinkling)
(Goats bleating)
(Laughing)
Here you go, son.
- Here you go.
- You just wait, man.
Don't fall asleep.
(Shouting)
- How you doing, sir?
- Pretty good.
All right, gents, good job.
- Did you get anything?
- Still working on it.
We've been playing that little game
of Marco Polo.
Think about cleaning them fucking
rifles, we'll have chow.
- You have some fucking chow.
- (Belching)
Hey, clean your fucking magazines,
too, CLP. Remember that shit.
- All right, Sarge.
- Last time I saw your fucking bolt,
it was dry like a fucking 80-year-old
granny's fucking coochie.
- (Laughter)
- You think that's funny?
I don't think
so when your weapon's jammed.
It's not funny then, but funny then.
Shut up. Get on your fucking face
right now.
Hey, douche bag, get on your face.
What's up with the fucking jokes?
Sorry, Sergeant.
Say "I will not be funny any more".
I will not...
- Louder!
...be funny any more.
(Shouting)
I will not be funny any more.
Someone get the Doc!
Someone get the Doc! Get the Doc!
(Ramirez) Hey, Cuthbert, yo, come here.
What's up?
- You know I'm always on your ass, right?
- You don't like me?
No, 'cause you fucking remind me of me,
dipshit.
On my first appointment, man,
I almost lost my fucking leg.
They sat here and fucking told me
I would never be able to
fucking run again.
Doesn't the Corps take care of you
after you're hurt?
You know they offered me to get out?
They said if I wanted to
I can get out with my injury.
They said, "We'll give you 10 per cent".
You know what 10 per cent is?
That's 300 dollars a month.
That's why I'm telling you. Nobody
gives a shit about you but you.
Take care of yourself.
The Marine Corps don't,
and this fucking country don't.
Remember that.
(Shouts) One, two, three!
- (All) One!
- One, two three!
- (All) Two!
- One, two, three!
- (All) Three!
(Sampson) # I love hand to hand
(AIl) # I love hand to hand
(Sampson) # Stab you in the eye
with my K1, baby
(AIl) # Stab you in the eye
# I love hand to hand
(AIl) # I love hand to hand
# Smash you in the grape
with my E2, baby
(AIl) # Smash you in the grape
with my E2, baby #
Your buddy goes down,
you ain't there fucking crying.
You're a fucking machine
and you act like a machine.
You go right through him.
You understand?
(AIl) Oorah, Sergeant.
- I don't fucking feel it.
- (Louder) Oorah, Sergeant!
I'm ready to take down
some ragheads, Sergeant.
I know you are. That's good.
That's why we train, train, train.
To kill, kill, kill.
I got my motivation right here.
- She's always on my mind.
- There you go.
She goes in my helmet.
Every time I'm ready for battle,
I stare at her and I remember
why I'm fighting this war.
- To protect freedom and her.
- She's watching over you.
Move in!
Stack up. Stack up.
Get down, get down. There's a
window right behind. Get down!
Moving in!
Hey!
Hey, Rambo!
When do you ever jump...
...just go into a house by yourself?
When?
Never. Stack, everyone stack.
Everyone stack. Everyone stack. Go.
This is a hostile environment.
Everyone in there, man, woman,
child, they all go.
- You understand that?
- (AIl) Oorah!
Women will strap a fucking bomb
on them if they lost a son or a husband.
They will strap a bomb to a baby.
To them, they're going to heaven
if they kill us.
You go in this house,
anybody has a weapon,
anyone's hiding behind
someone with a weapon, they all go!
Don't think twice.
It's gonna get someone killed!
- You understand that?
- Oorah!
(Goats bleating)
(Child cries)
(Children crying)
(Baby screaming)
(Panting)
(Gasping for breath)
(Whistling and ululating)
(Singing and ululating)
(lmpersonates machine gun)
(# Ministry: Lies Lies Lies)
# 3,000 people that I've never met
# We want some answers
and all that we get
# Some kind of shit
about a terrorist threat
# Lies, lies, lies
Lies, lies, lies...
Corporal Ramirez reporting for orders.
- You guys ready?
- Yes, sir.
When you go out tonight,
I want you to go down Market Street,
past Chestnut, right here, first
two houses on the left Intel says
- there's suspected insurgent activity.
- Roger that, sir.
Round up the suspects.
There's a list of them right here.
You got the grid co- ordinates on there.
Make it happen.
(Shouting)
Hey, shut the fuck up!
Hey! Hey!
Shut the fuck up!
Shut up! Corporal's trying to speak.
Hey, listen up.
Hey, we getting ready to go do
these fucking night raids.
I want you to remember
this is a IED factory,
possible insurgents.
Remember the fifty Marines
that just got slaughtered
before we fucking got here.
The six that got drug
through them city streets.
Pay back!
Marines that are dying every day
from IEDs from these rag heads!
Let's get on with this shit, man!
You all ready to do what the fuck
you're trained for?
- (Shouting)
- You all ready to fucking kill?
Then let's all fucking go right now!
Let's go.
(Shouting and yelling)
(Whooping)
Hey, Cuthbert.
Remember what the fuck I said.
Yes, Corporal.
Let's go, baby! Let's go!
(Speech drowned out by engine)
(Dog barks in distance)
- OK, set?
- Set.
(Loading gun)
Get down! Get down!
- Tell them all get down.
- (Translates)
Tell them to get down on the floor.
Hey. Come here.
Come on. Out. Everyone out.
- (Glass breaking)
- (Women weeping)
Tell the men to go over there.
Ali! Hey, hey! Get over there!
Tell him to go over there.
- Clear?
- Yeah, there ain't jackshit in there.
Ask them if there's any insurgents
near here or anything.
Is he an insurgent?
He got some pictures.
- Tell him to go get them.
- (Translates)
Shit. Jesus Christ.
Look what the fuck they did
to this dude, man.
Fuck.
- Ask him who did this to him.
- (Translates)
Mujahidin.
He says the terrorists
and insurgents.
I don't know what they belong to,
but I call them like they are out of law.
- Jesus Christ.
- They tease him up, huh?
- Fuck.
- Hey, man, they're all clear here, man.
(Music and clapping)
(Ululating)
(Child cries)
(Rock music)
Go, go, go, go!
(Gunfire)
Holy fucking shit.
Hey, call fucking explosives.
Hey, let's get the fuck back down.
Hey, Ramirez!
- Ramirez!
- Yes?
Hey, we got a shit load of bomb shit.
Where's Ali?
He speaks a little English, said
nothing. He knows everything.
Let's go.
Hey, six fucking gas tanks, man.
Hold him securely.
Very scary.
Hey, we got women and children right
here. All the men are right here.
Whose bombs are those upstairs?
- (Translates)
- I don't know anything about that.
You don't know anything?
Who knows?
It's in your fucking house! Who knows?
There's a fucking factory upstairs.
You don't know shit about that, huh?
Hey, that's fine.
Hey, Ali, come here. Hey!
Tell him to stand up.
- Whose bombs are those upstairs?
- (Translates)
- What?
- He doesn't know.
You don't fucking know?
Get down.
Down on your knees.
(Radio) Squads 2 and 3,
return to camp base.
Get the rest of these guys out here.
(Music, drumming, singing)
(Gunfire)
(Music and drumming continues)
Sir, we've got a north west
co-ordinate from the drones.
Drone 4 shows military-age male
with shovel on roadside.
Might be planting an IED.
Take him out.
Roger that. Five seconds.
(Beeping)
Five, four,
three, two,
one.
(Ramirez) Jesus Christ.
(Prisoner) Thirsty.
(Ramirez) Coming down.
Intelligence is gonna take them one
by one and interrogate them.
(Translates)
We know they're guilty.
We found the explosives.
(Translates)
So they'd better not lie because
we have their family for ransom.
They're fucking with the wrong
people. This is the US Marines.
Not the fucking boy scouts.
Tell them to fucking answer me.
Fucking answer!
(Translator shouts)
(Watch alarm beeping)
(Running water)
Morning, sir.
Hey, what's up, Ramirez?
Can I speak to you in private?
Yeah, sure. Over here.
About as private as it gets.
What's up?
Sir, I have a question.
I'm kinda having... having
difficulty sleeping at night.
Why? What's bothering you?
Just bad dreams, shit I've seen.
I was wondering, is there any way
I could speak... Speak to a doctor?
(Sighs) I'm sorry but
you can't see a doctor
until your tour of duty's over.
It's just the way Marine policy is.
You're gonna have to wait till
your tour of duty's over
and see a doctor on your leave.
Hey, listen up, gents.
We're gonna take this food over
to vehicle checkpoint, all right?
Let's go.
(lndistinct voice over radio)
(Dog barking)
Red 2, Red 3, this is Red 1. Over.
We're gonna head down Market
Street, make a right down Chestnut,
over the bridge
to the vehicle checkpoint.
(Shouting)
Hey, TJ.
- What's up?
- Gimme a kiss.
In your dreams, bitch.
Hey, Rakeef. Pull over.
Pull over!
What the fuck was that?
(Woman screaming)
Allahu Akbar.
Hey, watch the left side!
Watch the left side!
Fire!
Let's go, go, go, go, go!
(Ramirez) Shit. TJ!
(Shouting)
Hey, Doc, get over there!
Fire!
(Gunfire)
(Shouting and gunfire)
Cease fire.
They're fucking gone.
Ramirez, I'm calling a medevac.
Roger that. Keep a watch over
that fucking wall just in case.
- You're gonna be all right, man.
- We need a medevac.
We've been hit by an IED at the
intersection of Chestnut and Market.
There's reports of one killed Marine
and two severely wounded.
Let me clarify.
We got one... You said one killed?
One killed
and two severely wounded, sir.
Two wounded. Eh,
call the medevac right now.
Two wounded, one killed.
I want the LZ to be the corner
of Market and Chestnut.
- (Groaning)
- Doc's gonna take care of you.
Fuck, man. Hey,
Doc's gonna fix you, man.
(Ramirez) Hey. Hey, look at me.
Hey, Roberts.
Stay with us. You gonna be all right.
Look at me. Hey! Hey!
- Doc!
- You gonna be all right.
Doc's gonna take care of you.
You're gonna be good.
- Ramirez!
- Yeah?
Cuthbert!
Shit. Cuthbert!
(Whispered) Oh, fuck.
Fuck me.
(Fire blazing)
I'm sorry that you're down, man.
Hey! Get two fire teams ready
to cross over there
and clear those houses!
My fire team, we're going over there
and clear those.
Whoever did this shit
is around somewhere.
We're gonna make them
fucking pay! Fuck that!
ASAP! Get those fire teams ready!
My fire team, let's move.
Hey, who the fuck
are these motherfuckers?
Hey, get out the vehicle!
Get out! Get out!
Let's go, yeah, get out!
- Get the fuck out!
Get the fuck over there. Move!
Move!
You motherfuckers wanna sit around
and do shit?
Who the fuck pulled that trigger?
Who the fuck set that bomb off?
Nobody wants to talk?
You don't wanna fucking talk?
You don't know who fucking did it?
- All right, motherfuckers!
- (Gunshot)
You still don't fucking know?
(Screaming)
- (Shouting)
- Fuck the motherfuckers!
(Screaming)
Cease fire! Cease fire!
Hey! I want you to take
a sniper position up there.
You, take a sniper position
up on that rooftop.
Shoot anything
that fucking moves! Go!
Let's go, let's go.
Their co- ordinates, 23 kilometres.
Sir, this is Captain Sampson.
I had Third Squad out on a patrol.
They just got hit...
... by an IED.
They got one killed, two wounded,
one severely.
I don't want any more Marines killed.
- Am I clear?
- Yes, sir.
Take whatever action's necessary.
We just took small arms fire
from this building.
Permission to go and engage
and clear out their house, sir.
The second or third house?
You got positive
identification on that?
You've seen people firing?
Take the house.
Roger that. Over.
Hey, my fire team, we're moving!
Hey, make sure you keep security
on this side
just in case anybody pops up.
- Let's go. We're fucking moving.
- (Marines) Oorah!
Move it, move it, move it.
(Gunfire nearby)
Let's go.
Frag out.
Go! Go!
- (Gunfire)
- Watch the roof!
(Gunfire)
Get your fucking hands up!
- (Gunfire)
- (Screaming)
(Shouting)
(Gunfire)
Stop!
Move! Move! Move!
(Firing)
Goddamnit!
- Fuck this shit!
- Take this shit off!
(Crying)
(Explosion)
- Go, go, go!
- You fucking killed my brother!
(Shouting)
Fuck! They got out the back door.
Roger that, they went to
the fourth house?
All right, go get them.
Get the motherfuckers.
They're going from this house, into this
house. That's where the trigger guy went.
(Weeps)
Rashied!
(Coughing)
Hiba!
Hiba! Hiba!
- (Child cries)
- (Helicopter whirrs)
(# Kathem al Saher)
(Music drowns out speech)
I got drone footage of the guys
moving from house one to house two.
Keep an eye on the surrounding area.
Drone number two, move two points.
Move! Move! Move! Move!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on.
(Gunfire)
Move, move, move.
(Coughing)
22.877 kilometres northeast.
- Sir, I've got a visual on that.
- OK.
Border break and two cars parked.
10 men with weapons. Co-ordinated
insurgent attack suspected.
Engage the target.
Roger that.
Give me five seconds.
- (Beeping)
- Five, four...
three, two, one.
Get up! I've got you. Get up!
Look what I've found!
- Is that fucking yours?
- Whose the fuck is this?
I don't fucking understand you!
Shut up or I'm taking you too!
- Get up.
- Get the fuck up!
Yallah! Yallah!
Move!
Make sure every one of these
motherfuckers gets blindfolded
- and flexi-cuffed.
- Get down!
One of these motherfuckers know
who planted the IED.
They saw it being planted
and they didn't say shit.
Nobody move. Nobody knows
something, right?
Fuck that.
They're all fucking cowards.
They set off IEDs and they fucking
hide in their fucking homes.
Fuck that.
Hey, you searched
every one of them? Sosa?
Sosa! You searched them all?
I searched them all.
Ramirez, we ain't got nothing.
Don't you fucking move!
(Helicopter blades whirr)
Hiba!
(Screams) Hiba!
(Marine) They're open on Saturdays,
right?
Holy shit.
There's a runner at 12 o'clock.
- Holy shit!
- Target on the move!
- (Whooping)
- Holy shit!
Did you see that shit?
Did you get that shit?
Oh, yeah!
Let me see. Let me see
through the scope.
- Look at that.
- Holy fuck.
(Sosa) You see that shit?
Safa.
Hey, get over here!
Hey, this is where the motherfuckers were.
Look, they fucking saw us
the whole time.
I'm radioing it in.
Hey, how many kills you guys got?
Ramirez, I have a female runner
along the ridge!
(Screams) Rashied!
Ah!
Rashied!
Rashied! Rashied!
(Screams) Rashied!
Rashied!
Hey, Ramirez!
Yeah, got you covered.
Hey! Hey!
Move away from the body!
(Goat bells)
Hey! Move away from the body.
Go.
(Crying)
Hey.
Hey. Get away from the body.
Please, get away.
(Spitting)
(Whimpering)
Come on.
Please.
(Coughing and retching)
- Oh, fuck.
- (Chuckling)
Give me the last on that. Is it dead?
No.
What's up?
- So how you doing, man?
- I'm good, man. I'm good.
You look good.
You look like a million bucks (!)
I feel good.
I'm gonna get over here.
(Groaning)
- Oorah, Marines!
- Oorah, sir!
Hey, gather round. I'm gonna say
a prayer for PFC Cuthbert.
Bow your heads.
Lord, we lost
a great, young warrior today.
But the battle was won.
Please give his family the strength
to move on with their lives.
We know he's in a better place
with you, Lord.
Please give the United States
Marine Corps
the courage and ability
to destroy our enemy who hides
like cowards amongst civilians.
We thank you, Lord.
We have to make some difficult
decisions sometimes out here.
And we know you understand.
Thank you. And oorah.
- Oorah, Marines.
- (AIl) Oorah!
Outstanding job.
Corporal Ramirez.
Yes, sir?
You handled yourself like
a true professional out there.
I'm gonna promote you to sergeant
and recommend you for the bronze star.
- Thank you, sir.
- You kept your head in the game...
...and kept your Marines alive.
Good to go?
- Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
- All right, job well done, Marine.
- All of you. Great job.
- Oorah, sir.
Oorah.
Fucking sergeant.
- Hey, man.
- What's up?
- Have you been getting nightmares lately?
- Nightmares?
No, man.
It's like I can't fucking sleep, man.
Like last night, man.
I kept hearing, like cries and shit, like.
I keep seeing these fucking bodies, man.
These fucking women laid out,
fucking dead.
Their kids.
It's not so much the guys, man.
It's more like the women.
And then I see pictures of, like, my
fucking mother laying next to them.
I just wish I could fucking change
a lot of shit, man.
What are you talking about?
I feel like a lot of those fucking
people I killed personally.
You know what I mean?
And I'm fucking gonna live with this
guilt for the rest of my life, man.
And nobody fucking
understands it either, man.
I feel like I'm personally responsible
for all those motherfuckers
that died underneath me.
Every Marine that died under...
...underneath me, I feel like
I'm personally responsible.
Like I could have fucking changed it,
you know what I mean?
Fucking hate the motherfuckers,
the officers that send us in.
Fucking hate 'em!
Ramirez, you all right?
Fucking hate 'em, man!
Every one of them!
(Sobbing)
All they fucking give a fuck about
is their fucking medals, man.
They don't give a fuck about us.
(Birdsong)
(Chanting)
(Wailing)
(Sobbing)
(Gunfire)
(Man speaks in Arabic)
(Singing and chanting)
There's the mosque.
Er, do not engage the mosque.
The square building is a mosque
or is it a rec...
The rectangle.
- The rectangle building is a mosque.
- Roger that.
Major General, sir.
We've run a check
of all the Iraqi dead,
and none match
our insurgent database.
Nothing that you say causes me
any undue concern.
It's clearly a co- ordinated attack
and standard operating procedures
were followed.
This is the official press release.
"A US Marine and 15 Iraqi civilians
were killed yesterday
"from the blast of a roadside bomb
in Haditha.
"Iraqi army soldiers and Marines
returned fire
"killing eight insurgents
and wounding another."
(Sobbing)
(Reporter) The case came to light
when a Time magazine reporter
received video footage shot by
a local Iraqi journalism student.
It showed the gruesome aftermath
of the incident.
It also has interviews
with some of the survivors.
Safa Yunis, 12 years old,
is the only living survivor
from her family of nine.
She claims that the Marines
came into her house
and shot her entire family.
Hiba Adullah and three children
were the only survivors
of a family of 12.
If it had not been for the
Time magazine report,
this case would never have
come to light.
The Marine high command
failed to investigate
the events of November 19th
for over two months.
The blame, they say,
must not be allowed to stay
at the enlisted level,
but should be traced to its source,
which is the Secretary of Defence
and the Commander in Chief.
I am troubled by
the initial news stories.
Um, I am, er, mindful
that there is a thorough
investigation going on.
If in fact the er, you know...
... laws were broken,
there'll be punishment.
One of the charged Marines,
a Corporal Ramirez,
according to his attorney,
was nominated for a bronze star
for his heroism on the very day
the incident took place.
The Marines claim that they were
merely following their standard
operating procedures
whilst in an extremely hostile
environment.
Sir. Corporal Ramirez
reporting as ordered, sir.
At ease.
Corporal Ramirez.
You're being investigated
for 13 counts of murder.
Corporal Del Cruz,
five counts of murder.
Corporal Matthews,
three counts of murder,
and Sergeant Ross,
three counts of murder.
Now, it is my job,
and your job as Marines...
...to protect the reputation, the honour
and the future of this Corps.
And I will not have
a band of reckless Marines
ruin that future...
(Voice starts echoing)
...and that reputation.
Holy shit.
Hey, Matthews, check that fire out.
Ramirez!
Ramirez, are you OK?
(Ramirez) We've all seen a lot of
action at a young age.
I'm 20 years old and
this is my third tour of duty.
We've all seen things that'll haunt
us for the rest of our lives.
And I guess after a while
you just get hardened.
You become numb.
(# Ministry: Lies Lies Lies)
# I'm on a mission to never forget
# 3,000 people that I've never met
# We want some answers
and all that we get
# Some kind of shit about
a terrorist threat
# Lies, lies, lies, lies
lies, lies, lies
# Lies, lies, lies, lies,
# Surprise surprise
# Lies
# I'm on a mission to dig up the truth
# You think we're stupid
and there's no proof
# Well, let me tell you
that the time has come
# To pull the trigger
on the smoking gun
# Lies, lies, lies, lies,
lies, lies, lies
# Surprise surprise
# Lies
# Don't listen to me
# Listen to your head
# Don't listen
# Don't listen to anything
# They've said
# Don't listen
# Lies
Lies
America has been hijacked
Not by Al Qaeda, not by Bin Laden
But by a group of tyrants
That should be of great concern
to all Americans
ENGLISH SDH
ripped by rogard