(birdsong)
Goodnight Mister Tom
(church bells)
John Thaw
Nick Robinson
Get your hands out of your pockets.
(wireless playing music)
(interference)
"..SEEDS, WAIT UNTIL..."
- (gasps)
- Sorry about that!
"This is London."
"You will now hear a statement
by the Prime Minister."
(Chamberlain) "I am speaking to you...
..from the cabinet room
at 10 Downing Street."
"This morning
the British Ambassador in Berlin...
..handed the German Government
a final note...
..stating that, unless we heard
from them by 11 o'clock...
..that they were prepared at once
to withdraw their troops from Poland,...
..a state of war would exist between us."
"I have to tell you now that
no such undertaking has been received...
..and that, consequently,...
..this country is at war with Germany."
Give them an inch, they take a yard!
Excuse me.
Oh, um, Mr Oakley... I thought
I spotted you sitting at the back there.
Only, um, you've heard that
our choirmaster, Walter Wingate,...
- ..has just been called up...
- No.
Which presents us with
a bit of a problem.
Oh.
I have it on good authority
you're something of a musician yourself?
I used to play the organ a bit...
..if that's what you mean. Doesn't mean
I know about choirs. Or would want to.
We all have to do our bit. It's your duty.
And when I need you to tell me what
my duty is, Mrs Ford, I'll let you know.
At least tell me you'll think about it,
Mr Oakley.
I'll think about it.
(train whistle)
(barking)
(guard's whistle)
Now wait here.
(knock at door)
Well?
- You realise I am the billeting officer of this area?
- What's that to do with me?
His name is William Beech.
His mother will only let him be evacuated
if he's with someone...
..who's religious or lives near a church.
And the Home Office says
it is obligatory to take one.
I'm sorry, but he has to go somewhere.
You'd best come in, then.
Come on.
Well, take your mac off.
Look,...
..if you've had enough,...
..leave it.
(slurping)
So, where you from?
London.
Look, er, I have to go out. You'll be
all right for a bit on your own, will ya?
Yeah.
Right.
Have a look outside if you want.
(door closes)
(church bell)
(bicycle bell)
I'm not having him and that's that.
What do I know about kids?
Excuse me, Mr Oakley, you have got him,
whether you like it or not.
And if you don't,
you'll just have to lump it, won't you?
I wasn't happy about leaving the child
with you, either,...
..but it's a case of needs must, Mr Oakley.
There's not another spare room
in the entire village.
- Then try another village.
- That is out of the question!
We all have to put our shoulders
to the wheel. Even you.
There is a war on, you know!
Mr Oakley, about the choir practice.
Yes, I've said I'll try and be there.
Hello!
- You're one of the London lot, aren't you?
- Yes, miss.
A regular wild bunch, I've heard.
- (man) What's your name, then?
- William Beech.
Well, William Beech, I expect
I'll be seeing you in my class shortly.
And it's not Miss, it's Mrs.
Mrs Hartridge, all right?
- Who are you billeted with?
- He lives there.
Oh. You mean Tom.
Well... Goodbye, William.
(barking)
Get away!
Get away or I'll kill ya!
We'll have no talk about killin'! All right?
I reckon we've enough of that already!
Now, as far as the dog's concerned,...
..it's my dog there.
His name's Sammy,...
..and he's soft as me pocket, really.
So don't you go takin'
no more sticks to him.
Do you hear?
Well, now what?
(poker sizzling)
(barking)
Well, surely he never thought...
(church bell)
"Dear Sir or Madam,...
..I asked if Willie could stay
with God-fearing people,...
..so I hope he has."
"Like most boys he's full of sin,
but he has promised to be good."
"But, just in case, I've put the belt in."
Goodnight, then.
Goodnight, mister.
You can... call me Tom.
Goodnight, Mister Tom!
(digging)
Sorry, mister.
Get them wet things off.
And the jacket.
Now, here's the post office.
If you just get a stamp
and, er, post this for me...
..while I have a quick word
with the doctor.
- Your mum won't be able to read that.
- Yes, she will. She's got one of these, too.
And this way, you see,
you get twice as much on.
Thank you.
You see, when I got him up this morning
I found he'd wet the bed.
A not uncommon occurrence, Tom,...
..with a child who's been ripped out of his
home and dumped in some alien place.
What am I supposed to do about it?
- What we're all having to do, Tom.
- Oh?
The best we can under the circumstances.
So, what's your name?
William. William Beech. What's yours?
Zacharias Wrench.
My parents' idea of a joke, I think.
But you can call me Zach.
- Who've they put you with?
- Mister Tom.
I'm here with the doctor and his wife.
Friends of my mum and dad's.
It'll come in handy, I suppose,
if I'm ever ill.
- All right?
- Yeah.
Come on, then.
- See you around.
- Yeah. Bye.
Good lads!
- Have you got your Anderson up yet?
- It's been delivered.
I'll send the lads round if you like,
give you a hand.
- I can manage, thanks.
- Who said you couldn't?
You still a member of that knitting circle
round at the church?
Of course.
Only, you'll have heard I've been landed
with one of these evacuees.
Talk of the village!
I'll bet.
The only clothes he's got
are what he's standing up in, you see.
You haven't gotta clothe 'em, you know!
I wasn't planning to.
It's just that...
..I was wondering if,...
..between you, you could
rustle him up a couple of things.
I'll think about it.
- What's all this?
- Me mam sent 'em, for young William.
There's no way our George
can get into 'em any more.
Right. Thanks.
- See you later, Mr Oakley.
- Will ya?
- Give you a hand with the Anderson.
- Oh. That.
(door closes)
- For me?
- Well, who else?
Well, come on, let's see if they fit.
Never mind.
Come on, then.
(Sammy whimpering)
(digging)
Now I thought you were
supposed to be helpin'.
- My new shirt'll get dirty.
- Then take it off!
Go and change it, then.
Aren't you roastin'
in that jumper, William?
No.
He's got a temperature. Trying to sweat it
out of himself if you must know.
Come on, chop-chop!
Want this finishin' by tonight!
I'm going over to the church for a bit.
Back in about an hour. All right?
All right.
(# organ)
# And did those feet in ancient time
Just a minute, just a minute!
I mean,...
..have I been wastin' my time
these last months or what?
It's upliftin' people want, not buryin'!
Now start again.
Let's put a bit of beef into it this time.
Some sort of problem, is there,
Mr Oakley?
Nothin' I can't sort out...
..if left to get on with it.
Right.
Now, this time, I wanna hear you.
All right?
So...
# And did those feet
# in ancient time
# Walk upon England's mountains green
# And was the holy Lamb of God
# On England's pleasant pastures seen!
# And did the countenance divine
# Shine forth upon our clouded hills?
# And was Jerusalem builded here
# Among those dark satanic mills?
# Bring me my bow of burning gold
# Bring me my arrows of desire
# Bring me my spear: O clouds unfold
# Bring me my chariot of fire!
# I will not cease from mental fight
# Nor shall my sword sleep in my hand
# Till we have built Jerusalem
# In England's green and pleasant land
(organ continues)
(organ stops)
William!
Have you no more sense than
to be out here at this time of night!
- D'you wanna catch your death!
- You said we had to finish it tonight.
What?
All right, come inside, then.
Come on.
(hooter)
(# organ)
Don't ever touch that instrument again
without my permission.
Is that clear?
Look,...
..I'm going fishin' this afternoon
if you want to come.
Need any help?
I think I can just about manage, thanks.
Is Will about?
- Will?
- My name for William.
I think Willie sounds silly.
So, is Will in?
- We were just off out, actually.
- Oh. Going somewhere nice?
- Fishin'.
- Really? Can I come?
Afternoon.
Zach...
- Is your dad really an actor?
- And my mum.
Course, Dad's an auxiliary fireman now.
(aeroplane)
Wow!
Mrs Hartridge's husband's a pilot.
I wish I was.
(aeroplane)
Well, cheer up.
It's only school you're goin' off to.
Not your own hangin'.
Got everythin', have ya?
Right.
Off you go, then.
(children playing)
Will!
I'm sorry, William.
It's the door just across the hall.
(hammering)
William!
(door closes)
What's the matter?
They put me with the babies.
(children playing)
Can we have a word?
Of course, Mr Oakley.
William tells me you've put him
in the babies' class.
That's right, Mr Oakley.
Would you tell me why, when you've got
all his friends in your class.
Because they can read and write.
Now, join up the dots...
..and see what you end up with.
Never mind.
Now,...
..try again.
Only this time...
..take your time.
Don't try stabbin' it to death.
Here y'are. Have another go.
It's bad, innit?
No, it isn't. Not bad at all!
Just get on with the next one.
That's it.
There you are!
You've written your own name!
Oh, Mister Tom!
Now... draw a line under that
and get it copied.
Only, before you do,
just you draw me another line.
Them's straighter than I can do with
a ruler! Wherever did you learn to do that?
Just did it.
Go on, then, get it copied.
Won't I go to hell?
Hell?
You go to hell if you copy, don't ya?
- It's cheatin'.
- Whatever lunatic told you that!
Never mind. Just do it.
And if a chap with horns and a pitchfork
comes looking for ya,...
..blame me. All right?
"The... Tinder Box."
"A soldier was marchin'
along the high road..."
"Right-left, right-left."
"Everybody used to mock him
and make fun of him."
"The eldest son wanted to go
and cut wood."
"The kingdom was cer... cer... cer...
..cert-certainly very small."
What's it say, Mister Tom?
"In loving memory of Rachel Oakley,...
..aged 27 years."
"A dearly beloved wife."
"Also John Oakley, aged five years."
"A dear son. Now with God."
And did they just die?
No. They caught scarlatina.
What's scarlatina?
A disease.
A killer.
At least in them days.
Two weeks it was all over,...
..or so I'm told.
- Why didn't you catch it?
- Because I wasn't here, was I?
No. I was on a ship on convoy duty.
Fightin' for King and country, as they say.
No way of gettin' home, of course.
In fact, by the time I did,
they was already in the ground.
What was he like - John?
He was bright as a button!
Sharp as sixpence!
Bit naughty sometimes, but...
..full of life... to the brim.
In fact, very much like her, really.
Anyway, what's this?
Out here in your 'jamas,
and not even dressed yet!
- I wanted to show you something.
- Oh?
Come on!
Well?
Dry, Mister Tom! It's dry!
That's great, William!
That's really great!
Somebody's birthday, is it?
Been steaming 'em open again, Matthew?
- Any from London?
- Never noticed any London postmarks.
You do surprise me.
- Two and six?!
- This is quality stuff, Mr Oakley.
I suppose it was only a matter of time,
once the war had started,...
..before the profiteers started
comin' out the woodwork.
Thank you.
(thunder)
So this is where
you've been hiding yourself!
You realise your tea's been
on the table for half an hour?
Sorry, Mister Tom.
I should think you are!
# Happy birthday to you!
# Happy birthday, dear William!
(applause/cheering)
Go on, then! Blow!
If you blow them all out,
you get to make a wish.
- You can't tell anybody cos...
- Just blow the damn things out, William.
(cheering)
Who's going to have the very last bun?
Anybody want the last rock cake?
(laughter)
- Didn't she even send him a card, then?
- Nothing.
Shame on her!
Now come on, let's have a tune out of you.
Come on, Alice.
You know better than to ask that.
Rachel wouldn't thank you
for lettin' it rot away...
..just cos she's not here to play it
any more. You can't grieve for ever, Tom.
(children laughing/shouting)
(Zach) Pop it! Go on, pop the balloon!
(pop!)
(cheering)
(boy) Cor, look,
that one's a bright one, innit!
(boy) Pass me that scone over!
(# "It's A Long Way To Tipperary")
#..to Tipperary
# It's a long way to go
# It's a long way to Tipperary
# To the sweetest girl I know
# Goodbye, Piccadilly
# Farewell, Leicester Square
# It's a long, long way to Tipperary
# But my heart's right there
(cheering)
Well done, Tom!
- Night!
- Night, William!
Oh, and er...
this is for you as well, by the way.
Nearly forgot to give it to ya.
- Happy birthday.
- Thanks, Mister Tom.
This has been the best time
I've had in my whole life.
(retching)
(William vomiting)
Obviously.
(school bell)
Come in.
Mrs Black said I were to see you
before I went home.
That's right, William.
I've got a bit of news for you.
Mister Tom, I've been moved up
to Mrs Hartridge's class!
She says I can read and write
good enough now!
It's from your mum, William.
Seems she's not been very well.
Wants you back.
Whoa...
Where have they come from, Mister Tom?
A place called Dunkirk.
Lucky to get out alive, I heard.
Walk on!
(train whistle)
Now don't forget to write.
And, um... if you change your mind
about them paintings of yours...
..just let me know and I'll post 'em to ya.
All right?
They belong here with you. And they'll
be here when I get back, won't they?
Course they will.
I will be comin' back,...
..won't I?
Course you will!
Now you just take good care of yourself,
d'you hear?
You just... take your time.
You haven't seen your mother
for a few months, so...
..it's bound to be a bit awkward at first.
I'll miss ya.
- You'll make sure he gets off all right?
- Don't worry.
(train whistle)
(Tannoy) Stand clear for the train arriving
at platform one.
Here you are, then, son. Rise and shine!
Willie?
You look different.
Put weight on.
- I'll take that for you.
- I'll say what to take and not to take!
So, how are you feelin' now?
Fine. I'm fine!
- Only, they said you was ill.
- Did they?
So, what you got in the bag, then?
Just me things.
And a present for you from Mister Tom.
- Mr Tom?
- Mr Oakley. The man I stays with.
- I don't need charity, thank you!
- It's just some bed socks!
And Mrs Little, the doctor's wife,
sent tonic wine.
Wine?! Haven't I told you
about the evils of drink!
It ain't a real drink, like you get in a pub.
It's got iron in it
to help get your strength back.
And what would you know about
what you get in a pub?
When we get 'ome,
I want no noise from you. All right?
Why?
Cos nobody has to know
that you're 'ere, that's why.
And when we get inside
I've got a surprise for ya.
(keys)
What's that smell?
What smell?
Doesn't matter.
Not a dog, is it, this surprise?
- What surprise?
- This surprise you've got for me.
It's over there, in the box.
It's a baby!
It's a present from Jesus.
(baby crying)
Don't you dare!
- A bit of discipline, that's all she needs.
- She's just a baby, Mum!
Sit down!
Now!
My God! Isn't my life bad enough as it is!
Stuck 'ere on me own in this 'ouse,...
..frightened out of me head half the time,...
- ..without you starting!
- What are you afraid of? The air raids?
The air raids(!)
If we're killed, we're killed.
That's God's will, right?
So what are you frightened of, then?
By what's goin' on out there, of course!
Oh, Willie, if you knew... If you only knew
what's goin' on out there!
The filth!
The risin' tide... of filth!
Perhaps you should see somebody, Mum.
Like who?
Like an 'ead doctor?
That's what you think, is it?
That I'm off my 'ead
cos I know what's goin' on out there?
You keep a civil tongue in your head,
my lad,...
..or else.
You have brought it back, haven't ya?
The belt?
I forgot.
Liar.
Liar!
Aghh!
You left it behind on purpose, didn't ya?
No, Mum! Honest!
But I can get another.
I know a shop that sells lots of 'em.
Now get upstairs out of my sight!
(baby crying)
And you can shut up an' all!
(crying continues)
(cat screeching)
(baby grizzling)
Your favourite.
Certainly got your appetite back, anyway.
Must be all that fresh air, I expect.
Ohh... such a beautiful baby
you were, though.
Proud as punch I was,
wheelin' you out in your pram.
Sun shinin', people stoppin'...
Just stoppin', just to look at you.
Where'd you get him from, then, missis?
Heaven?
Happiest days
of my entire life then, Willie.
Finished?
Mum...
- What's this?
- My present to ya.
- It was Mister Tom's idea.
- Mr Tom?
I told ya, the man I stay with down there.
Well, go on, open it.
It's where I live down there.
Did you steal this?
- I did it meself!
- Liar!
- I did, Mum! Honest I did!
- And these?
Where did these come from?
Did you steal these as well?
- They're presents from Ginnie and Carrie!
- Girls? You've been mixing with girls?!
They're nice, Mum, and they
all go to church. Except Zach.
- Zach?
- He's me best friend.
- Why doesn't he go to church?
- They ain't got one there. A synagogue.
A synagogue?
- That's what they call their church.
- He's Jewish?
You've been consorting with Jews?
What's wrong with Jews, Mum? Like Zach
says, Jesus was a Jew, wasn't he?
Blasphemer... Blasphemer!
You know what we do with blasphemers!
No, Mum! Please!
Not there! Please, Mum! Not there!
(baby cries)
(# It's A Long Way To Tipperary"
played sadly)
(wireless) "Right across the city, German
raiders are leaving blazing buildings."
"Overhead I can hear the pulsing drone
of the circling bombers."
"In the shelters, men, women and children
listen to the muffled sounds...
..of bombs and anti-aircraft fire."
Mr Oakley?
Still no news, then?
'Fraid not.
Sorry, Tom.
Still nothin' from London, I'm afraid.
What's it been? Weeks now, eh?
Bit of bad news for Mrs Hartridge...
..up at the school. That young husband
of hers - one who flies Spits?
Missing, believed dead.
Ohh...!
Contact him, Mr Oakley?
I thought I'd have heard from him by now,
you see.
It's been over a month.
It does tend to happen like that, you know.
Once they get back into
the home environment.
And only natural for a boy of that age,
I suppose,...
..to prefer to be with his own.
(train whistle)
(air-raid siren)
Get a move on there!
Everybody down in the shelter!
- Lost, are we, sir?
- Looks like it.
Never mind about that now.
Let's get down the shelter. Come on.
Come on.
Come on, hurry up!
I'm sorry, mate,
no dogs allowed in the shelter.
So what am I supposed to do with him?
Leave him out here to be blown to bits?
Oh, come on, then.
And he definitely didn't run away,
you say?
Only it happens all the time,
kids takin' off, comin' back to London.
No question of that.
Look, I just wanna make sure
he's all right, that's all.
And you've got an address for him
round here, have you?
Well, tomorrow mornin', God willin',
we'll see if we can find him.
(explosion)
(baby cries)
(all-clear siren)
(ambulance bell)
Young couple, just married.
He was home on embarkation leave.
- And are they... are they both...?
- Oh, yeah.
Bloody, bloody war.
Well, I suppose you'll be wantin'
to find this kid of yours.
- If it's not...
- Just give me 10 minutes.
Of course.
(knocks on door)
If it's Mrs Beech you want, she's not 'ere.
- D'you know where she's gone?
- The coast, she said.
- And the boy? Did he go with her?
- Can't remember seein' a boy.
Little lad. 10 years old.
Oh, young Willie, you mean!
Evacuated to the country, last I heard.
Probably just as well.
Quiet boy, no friends as such,
bullied a lot. Sittin' target, really.
I mean,...
..this house... real house of mystery.
You hear some funny things sometimes.
- What sort of things?
- Well, whimpers sometimes. Bumps.
- Bumps?
- Like somebody humpin' furniture about.
- Well, people do move furniture about.
- At three o'clock in the mornin'?
- So when did you last see her?
- About a week ago.
I was shocked when she condescended
to speak to me. Talk about la-di-da!
- (whining)
- There's nobody in there, Rover.
(Sammy whining)
Not like him to make a fuss
over nothin', though.
Smell somethin', do ya?
Er, look, I'll see if I can find a copper.
Oi! Hang on a minute!
Cor! What died in 'ere, then!
(Sammy whining)
Quiet, Sam.
(Sammy still whining)
'Ere, let me.
(gasps)
God Almighty!
What the hell's been goin' on 'ere?
(coughing)
All right, let me have the baby, son.
Get away!
Let me.
What's his name, then, William?
It's a her. I call her Trudy.
Trudy.
That's a nice name.
Are you gonna let me have a hold, then?
Why didn't you come?
I kept callin' for you but you didn't come.
(ambulance bell)
- Are you related to this child?
- No.
- Then who are you?
- The one who found him.
Just in time, I'd say.
(Tannoy) Dr Westward to Casualty.
Take him to Children's.
See that he gets a tetanus.
What the hell is that dog doing in here?
You really will have to get that animal
out of here.
I won't be far away, don't you worry.
Tom!
How is he?
Any news about the mother?
No. But it'll be prison for her, I reckon,
when they do catch up with her.
- Is there a husband?
- There was once, apparently.
Found dead in an alley.
Choked on his own vomit.
His idea of family life
was drinkin' hisself silly,...
..then comin' home and
usin' her as a punchbag.
The kid as well, I shouldn't wonder.
- Go back to the country now, will you?
- Not without William, I won't.
(screaming)
Keep an eye on him, will ya?
- Of course.
- Thanks.
(Sammy whines)
He's in deep shock, Mr Oakley.
We've had to keep him well sedated,
I'm afraid.
Well...
Saves combin', I suppose.
(visitors' bell)
How are you feelin' now?
I had a nightmare.
They stuck this needle in me.
Can't I come home with you, Mister Tom?
I'm afraid you have to leave now.
Don't go! Stay a bit more!
Now you just concentrate
on gettin' yourself better. All right?
Not something I have a lot of faith in,
myself - drugging them.
- You'll be Mister Tom, then.
- Tom Oakley.
My name's Stelton. I'm a psychiatrist.
I work with the children's home.
Our feeling is that he'd benefit
from treatment there.
What sort of treatment?
Psychiatric treatment.
I'd like him to come back home with me.
As I understand it, you aren't
actually related to him, Mr Oakley.
Are there any other relatives
who'd take him in?
- That's something we'd have to go into.
- And if there aren't?
As I said, there is the children's home.
Woof!
Won't be long.
(Sammy whines)
(barking)
Quiet! Quiet!
Woof-woof!
Mister Tom... how did I get 'ere?
I kidnapped ya.
Oh.
That's what I did, boy, I kidnapped ya.
I kidnapped ya!
I KIDNAPPED YA...!
They seem to have patched you up
pretty well at the hospital, William.
Now you just settle down and
I'll call in again tomorrow. All right?
The sores will soon heal, of course.
It's the wounds inside
that we need to worry about.
You do realise they're bound
to come looking for him?
No...! They're far too busy
to go chasin' evacuees.
Besides, they didn't even know
he was in London. She saw to that.
- Goodnight, then, Tom.
- Goodnight, Doctor.
And you will let young Zach
know he's back?
You mean he hasn't been round here yet?
No! No! No! No! No!
No! No! Get away!
Hey...!
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey! Come on now, come on!
It's him, Mister Tom! It's him!
How are you feelin'?
I wanna come down.
All right.
- Ahh!
- Oh! Oh, dear!
It's all right, all right. Get back in.
There we are.
Don't worry. Don't worry.
They'll get stronger.
There we are.
- Don't you ever knock?
- Sorry.
Can I see him today, Mr Oakley?
- When he's had his breakfast you can.
- But he takes ages. He chews everything.
I thought we all did.
I just give mine a quick bite
and swallow it.
(William) Mister Tom!
Yes?
Is that Zach down there?
Go on, then. You take that up.
Thanks, Mr Oakley.
So what's been happenin'?
Not a lot. Been dead boring, really.
Except Mrs Hartridge's husband
got shot down and killed.
Least, they never found him.
- But she still had the baby okay.
- Baby?
- You did know she was having a baby?
- No.
But you must have noticed
how big she'd got!
You do know about sex and stuff,...
..don't you?
- Only it's dirty and you go to hell for it.
- That's rubbish, Will.
My dad says sex is a man and a woman's
way of showing their love for each other.
We wouldn't be here if it wasn't for sex.
But can't a lady have a baby on her own?
Of course not!
There has to be a man involved.
Right, Zach, home time for you, I think.
We don't want William overdoin' it.
- But I can come tomorrow, Mr Oakley?
- Course you can.
In that case, I'll see you tomorrow, Will.
So, what was all that about, then?
Zach says a lady can't have a baby
without a man.
- Oh, yeah?
- Is that right?
Yeah.
Trudy's dead, ain't she?
I think you knew that already.
- And I killed her.
- You killed her?
- I should've got out. I did try, honest I did!
- Well, of course you did!
Only, you were tied up. Right?
What you have to remember is that
the way she treated you and the baby...
..was because
your mum was sick, William.
In fact, very sick, I'd say,
to do what she did.
The trouble was,...
..with this war on, people so busy
survivin' themselves to even notice,...
..there was no-one to help.
Now, you tell me somethin', William.
This nightmare you keep havin'.
It's always the same one, right?
And it's always the same man.
Who is he, this man?
Just this man.
And what does this man do,
in your dream?
Just keeps sayin' I have to go with him.
Hello! What are you doin' here?
- I've come to see Mrs Hartridge.
- She's round the back.
Hello, William.
Now,...
..this is my Peggy.
Looks just like her dad, they reckon.
So, how are you feeling now?
I'm all right.
Oh, well... At least you're back
safe and sound, eh?
So, how about a glass of lemonade, then?
Yeah. Please.
Then you just hold on to Peggy for me,
will you, while I get it?
That's where my dad's based.
In the East End.
He'll be all right.
Course he will.
I'm afraid we have bad news for you,
William. It's about your mother.
She don't want me back again, does she?
She's dead, William.
Dead?
She drowned herself, son.
Dr Stelton's here from a children's home
in Sussex. Lovely place, I'm told.
- Right out in the country.
- I'm sure you'll like it, William.
I wanna stay 'ere with Mister Tom!
Mister Tom, I wanna stay 'ere with you!
Enough of that, my lad.
Mr Oakley is in trouble enough as it is.
- A serious offence is kidnappin'.
- I were rescued!
Why doesn't William wait upstairs?
Go on, then. Up you go.
William!
The man in your dream.
Is that him? The one with the moustache?
Right.
This, er... children's home
you're on about takin' him to.
Oh, yes?
- You're in charge there, are ya?
- That's right.
Only, he's been havin'
these nightmares, you see,...
..ever since I got him back.
It's hardly surprising...
- About you, apparently.
- Me, Mr Oakley?
That you're gonna take him away again.
In fact, he wakes up regularly,
screamin' about it.
Which bears out what I said: what the lad
needs is specialist medical treatment.
What the lad needs is love, Dr Stelton.
Somethin' he hadn't seen a lot of,
apparently, before he came to me.
Are you people really tryin' to tell me...
..that he'll get more of that where you
wanna take him to, than he will here?
If you are,
you're talkin' a right load of rubbish!
Mr Oakley, Dr Stelton is one
of the very best in his field.
And, along with the rest of us, his one and
only concern is for the boy's own welfare.
Let's get a spot of fresh air,
shall we, Mr Oakley?
(door closes)
It isn't the boy's welfare this is about,
really. Is it, Mr Oakley?
- Isn't it?
- It's about you, I'd say. Your welfare.
Me?
A lonely and, from what I hear,
embittered old man...
..facing a lonely and bitter old age?
You really think that's
the only reason I want him back?
To be company for me when I'm past it?
Well, isn't it?
No! It bloody well isn't!
And I resent the implication!
Doesn't it bother you
that when you're 70...
..he'll be in his teens?
Course it bothers me! I'm not stupid!
There's not a lot
we can do about that, is there?
Look, I know it's not an ideal situation.
Anything but.
But... well, put it this way...
It's gotta be a damn sight more ideal
than your Dr Stelton in there...
..turnin' him into
some sort of human guinea pig!
Just tell me one thing, Mr Oakley.
Why is the boy suddenly so important
to you? He's an evacuee, for God's sake.
And one that, as I understand it, you took
violent exception to having foisted on you.
Isn't it obvious?
Not to me, no. Nor to Dr Stelton.
Because I love him, of course.
As if he was my own flesh and blood I do.
And, for what it's worth,
I think he loves me as well.
And is that really enough, do you think,
in this day and age?
Well, I suppose it has to be, Mr Greenway.
In this day and age or any other.
Because if it isn't... what else is there, eh?
(door)
I won't go with them, Mister Tom!
I won't go with them!
- Oh, won't ya?
- No, I won't!
Just as well, then, isn't it?
Nobody's askin' you to.
What?
Come 'ere.
You see that one in the dark suit?
Yeah.
He's from somethin'
called the Home Office.
He reckons that,
after all the trouble you've caused,...
..they don't want you back any more,
thanks.
So...
..as long as I adopt you,
all legal and proper like,...
..looks like I'm stuck with you.
Oh, Mister Tom!
Mrs Little, can I see Zach?
I've got some really great news to tell him!
Of course you can, William.
He's upstairs... packing.
- Packin'?
- Yes. He's just had some news himself.
Not very good news, I'm afraid.
I got a phone call from my mum.
They bombed the docks.
My dad was there.
I'm sure he'll be all right, of course. Take
more than a German bomb to stop him.
Only I have to go and see him.
Just in case he's...
(bombers overhead)
Are they gonna bomb us, Mister Tom?
They're saving 'em for London, I expect.
"This is the BBC Home Service.
Here is the news."
"Last night's mass air raid on London...
..is estimated to have been
the heaviest so far."
"At least 400 people have been killed...
..and 1400 seriously injured.
Fires are burning all over the city,...
..and many homes in the East End
have been razed to the ground."
Still no word from Zach, then?
'Fraid not.
That poor child!
(boy) Stop pushing!
(woman) Come along.
(train whistle)
Oh. William.
William...
- Does anybody know where William is?
- (class) No, Mrs Hartridge.
William?
(bicycle bell)
Yeah...!
Whoo...!
Yeah...! Whoo...!
I hate you, God!
I hate you! I hate you!
I really hate you!
Is William all right, Mr Oakley?
Well...
He's, er, still very upset, of course, but...
Why?
Only that he didn't turn up
at school today.
Or rather he did, then...
(door opens)
Where have you been?
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Up you go and wash, then.
- Tea'll be on the table in five minutes.
- I'm not hungry.
(knock at door)
- Can we have a word, Doctor?
- Course, Tom. Come in.
Dr Little sent it round.
Thought you might like to learn to ride it.
I'm sure Zach would have
wanted you to have it.
Now you just come with me for a minute.
Come on!
You think you're the only person
who ever lost anybody?
It's happenin' to people all over.
This very minute.
And all because some maniac
wants to rule the world.
And how do you think I felt
when it happened to me?
Not just my wife I lost, you know.
She was my best pal as well.
My very best.
And my lad.
And me not even here.
Except I didn't lose 'em, you see?
Not really... because they're still here...
..inside here.
And always will be.
Just like Zach'll be for you.
In every little thing
you'll ever remember about him.
And that is somethin' that nobody
can ever take away from ya. Nobody.
Ever.
- (bicycle bell)
- William!
William!
- What's wrong, Mrs Hartridge?
- Nothing's wrong, William.
It's just... Well, I have to tell somebody!
I've had this telegram about my David,
and he isn't dead after all!
He's alive! A prisoner of war!
Isn't that wonderful, William?
Isn't that absolutely wonderful!
Yes, Mrs Hartridge! Really wonderful!
(baby crying)
Yeah...!
(bicycle bell)
Whoo!
Yeah...!
Whoo! Yeah...!
I can ride, Dad!
I can really ride!
Right!
^ BugTitleZ ^