[Ranting In German]
[Crowd Shouting In German]
[Hitler Ranting]
[Ranting Continues]
## [Tattoo]
[Man] Gentlemen, Nazi motorized divisions
are already massed on our frontiers.
Unless a miracle happens,
we shall be invaded.
This factory will be one
of their first objectives.
I have special instructions here
from the minister of the interior.
"In no circumstances must Herr
Bomasch or his G.K. armor plating...
be allowed to pass into Nazi hands".
But my work is not yet completed.
The tests that you have made were
good enough to show its possibilities.
Isn't that understating it? If it's successful,
it will revolutionize defensive warfare.
And it is a revolution that we do not wish
to have brought about by the Third Reich.
- Then I am to leave the country.
- As soon as the Nazi invasion starts.
I have here passports for
yourself and your daughter.
Arrangements have been made for you to
carry on your work in another country.
Where, you will be told when the time comes.
I have made out lists...
[Droning In Distance]
[Airplanes Approaching]
Ours?
No. Theirs.
If we resist German protection,
Prague will be bombed.
[Man] Rrotection. Rrotection from what?
Give me a direct line to the
Ministry of the Interior, at once!
What?
The minister left 10 minutes ago
for the Central Radio Station.
[Man On Radio] The German command
has given the order to march.
At this moment, Nazi troops are
streaming across our frontiers.
In our present defenseless condition...
resistance is worse than useless.
Citizens of Czechoslovakia...
we must bear the trials that lie ahead...
with fortitude and courage.
Be of good heart.
And remember-
long live Czechoslovakial
But will the British
government give me facilities?
Everything is arranged.
You will be met at Croydon.
Here are the details. Now,
you haven't a minute to lose.
The plane leaves the airfield in
half an hour, and it will be the last.
- But, uh, will you be there?
- I must stay.
Axel, your daughter.
Is that you, Anna? You have heard?
Listen, dear. I don't want to alarm you,
but we have to leave the country at once.
Go to the airport.
I will be waiting for you.
Immediately. Do you understand?
Yes. Yes, at once. Where are we going?
England?
Yes, of course.
- What's happening, Miss Anna?
- Martha, I've got to leave at once.
Help me put some things in a bag.
Anna Bomasch, you are under arrest.
[Engines Idling]
- We cannot wait any longer!
- Please, another moment!
My daughter was leaving at once.
But the city's occupied already. We must go!
Away! Come on!
Schnelll Schnelll
[Mutters]
[Shouts Order In German]
[German]
Marsch.
[Soldier Continues Shouting Orders]
Marschl
Aufschliessenl
Halt!
Turn right.
Edward Klein, for laziness.
Sentence: 12 lashes.
My heart will never stand it, Herr Doctor.
- Heart's fit.
- I have been under treatment for...
Take him away. Next man.
Karl Marsen, for insubordination.
Sentence: 20 lashes.
Good for twice the number by the look of him.
You will soon learn that it's
better to keep your mouth shut...
and to do as you are told.
Thank you. I have no wish to become a Nazi.
We shall also teach you
that insolence does not pay.
With the aid of those pillars of Nazi culture
- the whip and the jackboot.
- Silence!
- I shall say what I like!
You hate the truth...
because, in the end, it will destroy
you and your bankrupt philosophy.
You will perish because
you have nothing to offer...
because you can't forever
replace tolerance and decency...
with brute force, because you...
[Whip Strikes]
Stand away from him.
Get back to your work.
[Quietly] Better leave me.
Mmm?
Halt!
Get along. No talking.
Good Samaritan.
I wanted to thank you for yesterday.
The swine!
Don't look at me. We shall be seen.
Why did they send you here?
Oh.
I'm a desperate character.
I had a little school on the Sudeten border.
I was ordered to abolish our
language and to teach in German...
by an illiterate Nazi group leader.
So here I am.
Shh.
- And you?
- My father escaped to England.
I almost went back with him.
- Back?
- I was at school there.
They arrested me to find
out where he was hiding...
and because I couldn't tell them...
That's all.
England.
Well, good luck to him.
I have been a fool. I...
I should have held my tongue and-and waited.
- We shan't always be here.
- No?
Somehow, I'm going to join my father.
How?
- Well, we have friends outside.
- Yes.
But between them and us...
There must be a way.
Past searchlights, machine guns, barbed wire?
I should take any risk if I
thought there was a chance.
But there is none.
There isn't one of us
who doesn't lie awake...
- Keep your mouths shut!
- [Gasps]
You know the order!
Get back, you. I told...
Silence.
What is it? Do you know him?
He studied with me for a
job in the civil bureau.
He might help us.
- But isn't he a German?
- Yes.
From the Sudetenland.
When it was occupied by
Germany, he was desperate.
I gave him the advice.
Become a good Nazi, Paul.
Join the party... and wait.
Then you think that...
Yes.
Now there may be a chance.
- What's wrong up there?
- It's fused!
It's all right!
[Alarm Ringing]
[Ship Horn Blows]
- You should be asleep.
- Karl, what's that noise?
- That's the Goodwin lightship, miss.
- We should be in England in an hour or two.
But it'll be light then.
You don't mean we're going ashore
without any passports in broad daylight?
In broad daylight!
## [Brass Band]
[Reople Chattering]
[Woman] Why not?
Come on. Only a shilling.
- Aye, aye, knock it. Turn it up.
What's the idea?
- Oh, I'm so sorry.
Think you're the Mauretania? I might have
had a Lillian Gish on the end of that.
- I'm very sorry indeed.
- All right. Granted, me ol' cock.
- Have you caught anything?
- New eels.
Oh! That's a night fish.
You've been out in a ketch.
Not like me
- fishing to keep away from the old woman.
- Where do we change?
- The beach.
- And then London?
- Yes.
There I shall go to see
a friend of my family.
He fled to England last
September. He'll help us.
He's living at a place called
Hampstead. You've heard of it?
Yes. Karl, if you only knew
how glad I am to be back here...
where people can still laugh and be happy.
Come away, Alfie. If you're not falling
in something, you're dragging in something.
Go on.
- Good evening.
- Uh, good evening.
- I should like to see Dr. Fredericks.
- Have you an appointment?
No, but, uh, if you would give him
my name. It is Marsen. Karl Marsen.
- Well, will you come in, please?
- Thank you.
Now, if you will take this
to Gilby's, the opticians.
They're just around the corner.
If you mention my name, they will make up
your little girl's glasses at a reduced charge.
Thank you, Doctor.
And don't worry. With care,
she will grow out of it.
- Thank you, Doctor. Good night.
- Good night.
There's a gentleman to see
you, Doctor, a Mr. Marsen.
Marsen?
Oh, very well. Show him in.
- The doctor will see you now.
- Thank you.
Good luck.
Mr. Marsen.
- Good evening.
- How do you do, Doctor?
I was given your name. I'm suffering from
an, uh, eyestrain and should like a test.
- Headaches and so forth?
- Hmm, yes.
If you will be good enough
to sit in this chair, please?
Thank you.
- Warm this evening, isn't it?
- Rather.
I hear there may be a storm brewing.
Now, will you read the top line, please?
K, M, S...
Q, R, Y.
And now the line underneath.
M, O, 2...
6, 7, 3, G.
I don't think that is quite
right. Will you repeat it, please?
M, O, 2...
6, 7, 3, G.
- [Clicks Heels]
- Heil Hitler.
Well?
I have to report that on instructions
from Gestapo headquarters...
I successfully made contact
with the woman Bomasch...
in Concentration Camp Number
Four, Reichsprotektorat of Bohemia.
I escaped with her, as
arranged, on the 27 th ofJuly...
and came ashore this morning at
11:15, from the freighter Stovendam.
We are staying at an apartment house...
at 124 Paddington Lane, Marylebone.
Good. She has, of course, made
no attempt to locate her father.
No. I am awaiting your instructions.
This is all we know.
Bomasch is working for the British
admiralty. Where, we have no idea.
He is certainly well hidden and well guarded.
- Therefore, we must move cautiously.
- Understood, sir.
So do not appear too eager.
Impress upon her that you are
aliens and must move carefully.
Suggest that she places an
advertisement to this effect...
in the personal column of the London Times...
signed perhaps with some nickname
which her father will know at once.
You will see that that advertisement
is repeated daily until it is answered.
When that happens, you
will report to me instantly.
- You understand?
- Yes, sir.
That is all. Heil Hitler.
- [Clicks Heels]
- Heil Hitlerl
I see that fellow
Ribbentrop's going to Moscow.
Hmm. So did Napoleon.
[Woman] Miss Bomasch,
you're wanted on the phone.
Nice time of night to ring up, I must say.
- [Anna] Who is it?
- Oh, he didn't say.
[Footsteps]
Hello? Yes, I'm Anna Bomasch.
In the Times, yes. Who is it?
Yes, I'm alone. Who is it, please?
I can't answer questions.
Now please listen carefully.
At the post office in Prairie
Street, a letter is waiting for you...
containing a railway ticket.
Go to the destination on the ticket,
and when you get to the town...
ask for a man named Gus Bennett.
You've got the name? Gus Bennett.
- Yes, but who do I ask?
- Everyone there knows Gus Bennett.
You say nothing of this to
anyone. That is most important.
Hello?
Hello!
[Knocking]
- Yes?
- It's Anna. May I come in?
Yes, come in.
Karl, I've just heard. Somebody telephoned.
- We found him.
- Where?
- I don't know yet.
- But, uh, what did he say?
Karl, I'd love to tell you, but whoever it
was said I wasn't to say a word to anyone.
- Oh.
- I don't mean you're just anyone.
- Of course you're not, but...
- Anna, I...
I would much rather you didn't tell me.
We don't know what your father is doing, and
it's probably right you should take precautions.
There's no one in the
world I'd rather confide in.
I don't know what I'd have
done if it hadn't been for you.
No.
- You are happy now?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, that's all that matters.
Good night, Karl.
[Telegraph Clicking]
[Horn Honking]
- ## [Man Singing]
- I'm looking for Mr. Gus Bennett.
I was told I'd find him here.
Oh, he's along here, all right.
You hear a warbling note like an air
raid siren? Well, that's him singing.
- # Only love can cheer the day #
- Over there?
[Man] Churns out the same moldy
songs from 9:00 in the morning.
A human barrel organ, he is.
- # Lots in life may be denied #
- ## [Piano]
# But hearts can laugh #
# When love's inside #
# For only love can lead the way #
# As time rolls on and on ##
The song of the century!
When "Home Sweet Home" and "Annie Laurie"
are forgotten, this song will live on.
Now, madam, only the
price of a stick of rock.
Sixpence, sir. The ballad of the age.
"Only Love Can Lead the Way".
Here, buy a copy for the sergeant
major. Thank you, gentlemen! Thank you!
Anyone else want to buy a
copy of this haunting melody?
How would you like to be
haunted for a sixpence, miss?
- Mr. Gus Bennett?
- In the flesh. You want me to autograph it?
I'll throw that in.
- I'm Anna Bomasch.
- How do you do?
Don't go away, ladies and gentlemen!
I'm not gonna sing again yet.
- I was told to come and see you, Mr. Bennett.
- Hmm? Who by?
- I don't know.
- Is this a gag?
Well, somebody phoned me. They
said you'd have news of my father.
Your father? Never heard of
him. Somebody's pulling your leg.
"Only Love Can Lead the Way".
A tonic so far.
We give the tonic.
You provide the "so far".
Thank you, madam. Hey, don't go away.
I'm just going to tear off another number.
Then we'll have a talk.
I'm now going to sing the
sentimental song hit of the year.
They say the hand that rocks
the cradle rules the world...
but, believe me, it's songs
like this that fill it.
# It's true #
# Oh, what it does to me to know it's true #
# She loves me ##
[Slurping] Are you... Are you sure
it was Gus Bennett they said?
- Yes, I'm certain.
- Your father's not in the song business?
- No.
- Well, it's beyond me. How did you lose him?
- He escaped.
- Escaped? You mean he's still at large?
- I-I mean, you haven't seen him since?
- No.
You see, I was in a concentration camp.
- Were you really? Where?
- Near Prague.
Prague.
- You here by yourself?
- Yes.
- Anyone know you're here?
- No.
- Would you like another one of these?
- No, thank you.
[Woman] Alfie?
I don't understand it. It's extraordinary.
Well, it amounts to this.
You don't know my father...
you don't know anything about
him, and you can't help me.
Is that him?
Father!
Anna!
Here it is
- Brightbourne, a health resort.
But I hardly think that Herr
Bomasch is there for his health.
You notice across the bay
is the Dartland naval base.
Reports says he's been there
three times in the last week.
Probably conducting experiments, sir.
Precisely. We can't afford
to delay a moment longer.
There's another reason for haste.
Any day now, Poland may provoke us
into invading her in self-defense.
England will not stand by Poland.
We have the personal assurance
of Herr von Ribbentrop as to that.
Hmm. So I understand.
Nevertheless, instruct Fredericks that we
are putting arrangements in hand at once.
Very good, sir.
# You nonchalantly go around #
# Completely unaware #
# It's just another ordinary day #
# You meet a sweet who
sweeps you off your feet #
# Your heart skips a beat and runs away #
# You can't recall a tender
thought to show how much you care #
# You can't think of a single thing to say #
# You'll meet, so meek You'll
talk, but you don't speak #
# Your heart skips a beat and runs away #
# It may be Tuesday or Sunday #
# Thursday or Monday #
# Love never warns you at all #
- Is the coffee ready?
- It won't be a minute.
- Thank you, dear.
- ## [Woman Continues, Indistinct]
- [Door Opens]
- Oh, hello.
- Hello there.
- Come to see Father?
No.
- Want some?
- Thank you.
- Where did you get that from?
- Post office stopped it.
- Why?
- I gave them instructions.
What have my private letters to do with you?
A postmark's a dangerous thing.
- This letter's to a friend of mine.
- British?
- No.
- Refugee?
I'm not going to be cross-examined.
I must remind you that the government
pay me a wage -small but regular-
to look after your father.
It's obviously not small enough.
You don't suppose I'd write
to anybody I couldn't trust.
Why, if it wasn't for
Karl, I wouldn't be here.
What did you say?
- He escaped with me.
- But you never told me.
- I told my father.
- But not me.
If I didn't, it's simply because
Karl is an alien without a passport.
He was afraid he might be deported.
- Known him long?
- No. What are you doing?
Just want to check up on him.
Have you ever heard of an organized escape?
- Organized?
- To lead them to your father.
But that's fantastic. Karl
doesn't even know where I am.
Are you sure of that?
- Of course. I told no one.
- Good.
Honestly, I don't want to throw
a monkey wrench into the romance.
Thank you. I appreciate that you're
inspired by the highest motives...
and that you'll go to any
lengths to pursue them.
- Any lengths.
- Even to exhibiting yourself
in public as a singer.
Well, nature endowed me with a gift,
and I just accepted it. That's all.
It's a pity it didn't endow you with a voice.
Nothing that happened to me
in that concentration camp...
was quite as dreadful as
listening to you day after day...
singing those appalling songs.
With those few words, you've knocked
the bottom out of my entire existence.
A pity I only knocked it.
[Knocking]
- Mr. Bomasch about?
- Yes, he is.
Admiral Baldwin sends his compliments.
He'd like Mr. Bomasch to have
dinner with him this evening.
- And his daughter.
- Hmm. I'll tell him.
Uh, just a minute. Didn't Admiral Baldwin
leave for the Mediterranean last Tuesday?
No. He's aboard the
flagship lying off Dartland.
- But I understood that...
- [Blow Lands]
[Motor Chugging]
Isn't he going too far out for Dartland?
[Man Speaking German]
[Man #2 Speaking German]
[Bell Chiming]
[Bell Tolling]
Sorry to barge in. I say,
Charles, the wife's just phoned.
- I understand you're coming over
to tea on Sunday.
- Yes, so I believe.
Well, she wants you to remind
Beryl to bring some recipe book-
pickling walnuts or something.
- Oh, yes. Will do.
- Right.
- Oh, hello, Randall. How are you?
- Hello. Hi.
We were just discussing the Bomasch affair.
Oh, yes, you slipped up
rather badly there, didn't you?
- Yes, I...
- Well, it wasn't exactly his fault.
We ought to have known about Karl Marsen.
The War Office has been stinking about him.
They take the view that this
armor plating of Bomasch's...
will make all the difference in the next war.
Probably nothing of the sort,
but, well, there you are.
And by tonight, Bomasch will be in Berlin...
where they won't lose any time before
putting the screws on the poor devil.
Tomorrow night?
That means he won't be
at the admiralty until, let's see
- Saturday morning.
That's about it. Why?
Twenty-four, maybe 48 hours.
Why? What are you driving at?
Well, they got him out of England.
Why shouldn't I get him back?
But that's quite impossible.
Why? I know my way about.
I was three years in Berlin.
- Drinking lager.
- Mmm. Vodka now, isn't it?
What about the Polish situation?
Germany may march at any
moment. You know what that means.
I shall be back before then. Well, sir?
Well, you know perfectly well I
can't give you permission to do it.
And the fact that you make the request
at all shows you're not yourself.
- Don't you think so, Gaskin?
- Oh, well, I...
I quite agree with you.
Now, I suggest you take
a week's sick leave...
to enable you to get a
complete change of air, hmm?
Thank you, sir. I understand. I think
it might be very good for both of us.
Mm-hmm. Now, I expect you'd like
to have a little chat about it.
Yes, I would, sir.
Oh, well, uh, Charles, you won't
forget about that recipe, will you?
No, no. I'll remember.
Now look here. I don't
know what your plans are...
but I expect you'll want a
few letters of introduction.
Mm-hmm.
[Horns Honking]
[Horn Honking]
[Man] Reichssender Königs
Wusterhausen calling.
Early this morning, the
Polish hoards attacked Germany.
The führer immediately gave orders to
our glorious army to invade Roland...
and to destroy these
intolerable aggressors...
of peace-loving Germany.
Naval High Command, Herr Major.
- How can I reach you?
- I'll ring you tonight.
I'll be waiting. Good luck.
All identity cards.
All identity cards to be shown.
Identity card? Come on, come on, come on.
I've worked here for 10 years. You
Gestapo fellows must want a job.
- All right, all right.
- This is a fine country to live in.
- Hey. What's that?
- Nothing.
- Name. Department.
- Schwab. Records. Intelligence.
- Report that man.
- Excellent, Officer.
While we have men like you at home,
we have nothing to fear. Nothing.
Oh, I have an appointment
with Commander Kampfeldt.
- Where can I find him?
- Second floor, sir.
Thank you.
This is a very grave matter, very grave.
It has just been reported to me that
you've been heard expressing sentiments...
hostile to the fatherland.
- What, me, sir?
- What is it?
Major Herzoff to see you.
He asked me to give you this.
Can't you see I'm engaged?
I warn you, Schwab, such treasonable conduct
will lead you to a concentration camp.
But, sir, what did I say?
You were distinctly heard to remark,
"This is a fine country to live in".
Oh, no, sir. There's some mistake.
No, what I said was,
"This is a fine country to live in".
Huh?
- You sure?
- Yes, sir.
Hmm. I see.
Well, in future, don't make
remarks that can be taken two ways.
- Much wiser not to talk politics at all.
- Yes, sir.
- You may go.
- Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler.
This is a fine country to live in.
This is a bloody awful country to live in.
Shall I show Major Herzoff in, sir?
- Uh, yes, yes.
- Yes, sir.
Please.
Major Herzoff.
- Heil Hitler.
- Sit down, Major.
- Thank you.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
"This is to introduce to
you Major Ulrich Herzoff...
"of the Corps of Engineers.
"Major Herzoff is in Berlin on
an important technical mission...
"for which he requires admiralty assistance.
"I am sure, my dear Kampfeldt, that
you will give him your best cooperation.
Heil Hitler. " Et cetera,
et cetera, et cetera.
I wish these War Office fellows
would learn to write properly.
Signature might be anything.
Whose is it?
Well, I have no idea.
As usual, I was taken
from one office to another.
- I suppose it couldn't be Sardvitz.
- Sardvitz?
Or did he go in the purge?
- I can't remember.
- I believe he did.
Hmm. Whoever he was, he
spoke very highly of you.
He did?
Might be Meidvidtz.
Not very likely though.
However, the important thing
is, what can I do for you?
I want to refer to certain
technical evidence...
given before the Naval Heavy
Armaments 1935 Committee.
If you will let me have a
report of the copy, Commander.
Certainly. It will take only a moment.
I have my own filing system here.
A copy of the Naval Heavy
Armaments 1935 Committee's report.
- Have you been in Berlin long, Major?
- No.
I only left the Siegfried line last Tuesday.
Really? How is it there?
Things are pretty hectic, I expect.
Pumping night and day.
I was there in a consultative capacity.
Steel fortifications.
You possibly have heard.
Oh, yes, yes. Major Herzoff, of course.
Looks rather like Stuckner.
But I believe he is doing
diplomatic work in the Balkans.
- And who is not?
- [Door Opens]
I'm afraid we haven't a
copy of the 1935 report, sir.
- What's that?
- We have one of'34, but not '35.
Are you sure there was a '35 committee?
I sat in it myself as army liaison officer.
I beg your pardon. Very well, very well.
It's these fellows at the top.
They forget to send copies on.
Perhaps the construction
department might be able to help.
The very thing. They might have
one. I'll ring them at once.
- Oh, I'm sorry...
- No trouble at all.
Commander Prada.
I have with me Major Ulrich
Herzoff of the Corps of Engineers.
He is well known for his splendid
technical achievements on our west wall...
as you're no doubt aware.
He will be greatly obliged if
you can give him some assistance.
You'll see him at once? Thank you, sir.
1935, you said. I guess I could
get hold of a copy for you.
Now, Commander Prada, you may
be able to help me more directly.
- You know, I just left the Siegfried line.
- Mm-hmm.
- So Kampfeldt said. How is everything?
- The Krupp's armor plating is the trouble.
Confidentially, that's why I am in Berlin.
Do you realize that the steel used by the
Czechs is better than anything we have got?
Mm-hmm. So I've heard. But surely,
now that we control the Harska works...
Not enough. We let the only man who
counted there slip through our fingers.
- Bomasch.
- Yes. I knew Axel Bomasch personally.
I was present at the first gunnery test
of his G.K. plating. Incredible results.
Where is he? Working for Britain.
But if we can't trace this 1935 report-
One moment, Major. You will be surprised to
hear that Bomasch is no longer in England.
What?
He was brought back to
Germany only a few hours ago.
In fact, he's in this building now.
But this completely alters my plans.
Perhaps you can arrange for
me to see Herr Bomasch at once.
I'm afraid it's impossible.
He's with the controller.
Surely there's no harm in my
asking him a few questions.
It's beyond my province, Major.
I'll pass you on to Captain Viengarten,
but frankly I don't think
it will get you any further.
The controller's office is rather
like the kingdom of heaven...
and, if anything, a little more exclusive.
But you are no longer living
in a decadent democracy...
ruled by a pack of raving intellectuals!
This is the Third Reich, and
the führer does not tolerate...
stupid, insolent obstinacy!
You have been asked to work for
Germany, Herr Bomasch, and you will.
Can't you leave him alone? You've bullied
and shouted at him ever since we got here!
- He's had no sleep!
- He must agree!
Can I have another word with him, sir?
As you please.
Anna. It's useless for your
father to resist like this.
You must persuade him. You will
both be given reasonable freedom.
Freedom here?
In time, you will see things the way I do...
the way everyone in Germany does.
I'm not a German.
Germany is as much your
country as it is ours now.
We don't hate the Czechs.
We only wish to protect them.
As you're protecting the people of Poland?
You have been too long in Britain,
listening to their smug hypocrisy!
If I listened to hypocrisy in
Britain, it was not from the British.
I was doing my duty...
as a citizen of the Reich
and a subject of the führer...
for whose sacred mission
no sacrifice is too great.
That sounds rather like
something you learnt from a book.
For years, you've had this sort of thing drilled
into you until it's all you know or care about!
You're a fanatic with a
set of stupid, fixed ideasl
If you hadn't made me hate you more than
I thought I could possibly hate anybody...
I think I should feel sorry for you.
You have expressed yourself
very clearly, Fraulein Bomasch.
You will be placed in a concentration
camp until your father comes to his senses.
- Must you drag my daughter into this?
- It rests with you, Herr Bomasch.
Hello? What, here?
Very good.
Admiral Hassinger is on his way up.
The Chief of Naval Staff,
Vice Admiral Count Hassinger.
Come in, my dear fellow. Come in.
Strasse, let me present Major
Herzoff of the Corps of Engineers.
I expect you have heard of him.
The man behind the
Siegfried line, eh, Herzoff?
[Randall] Only one of the men, sir.
The führer is responsible for the line
as he is responsible for everything.
Well, what progress?
You remember me, Herr Bomasch. I
did not expect to see you again here.
And you, Fraulein Bomasch.
I see you have not forgotten.
It must be... four years.
[Clicks Heels]
Major Herzoff is preparing a highly
confidential report on armor plating.
He has been on several missions to Prague.
- He met Bomasch there.
- Just one moment, sir.
Marsen, conduct Herr Bomasch and
his daughter into the next room.
- Mr. Bomasch.
- Maybe we shall meet again, later.
I thought it unwise to
speak in front of Bomasch.
- So far, we've made no impression on him.
- I do not agree. He looks 10 years older.
My orders are to obtain quick results.
At the Reich, we are rather
inclined to believe...
that the knuckle-duster is
the best diplomatic weapon.
- Do I understand that you question?
- I question nothing. I am an army officer.
Personally, I do not
follow any of this at all.
Bomasch is not the man to be
bullied into cooperation, sir.
Well, what do you suggest?
I knew Fraulein Bomasch in Prague.
She has a great influence with her father and is
the one person who can make him change his mind.
Oh, Marsen here has tried
that, but she refused to listen.
He is largely responsible for
tracing Bomasch in England...
completely outwitting the
British military intelligence.
So, may I express a soldier's admiration...
for one who can carry out his mission under
the very eyes of the enemy secret service?
Thank you, sir.
But if I may say so, I
hardly think the captain...
is a suitable person to influence the lady.
And who do you think would be more suitable?
Why, uh, myself, for instance.
- You?
- Why not?
Herzoff was very friendly
with her in Prague, you know.
A little more than friendly.
You saw the way she looked
at me when I came in.
Oh, yes, of course. Seems to me
you are a bit of a dog, Herzoff.
A technician, Admiral. One does
not talk about these things...
but I think if I were to spend
a few hours alone with her...
I might induce her to reason with her father.
Oh. What do you think about that, Strasse?
I cannot promise, mind you.
Four years is a long time.
It seems to me it is worth attempting.
- After all, the business is urgent, Strasse.
- It is indeed, sir.
You really believe that you could
influence a girl in a matter of hours?
- Shall we say overnight?
- I see.
Knowing Fraulein Bomasch, sir, I
doubt whether even his qualities...
will make any impression on her.
- You aren't acquainted with my qualities.
- Strasse, we'll let him try it.
No harm done if he doesn't succeed.
Leave all the arrangements to me.
This requires a knowledge of
maneuvers. Come along, Herzoff.
You may be right, my dear.
Bennett may be trying to help us.
But why have they brought us to this
hotel, provided you with clothes?
It doesn't make sense to me.
Well, Bennett's behind it, obviously.
He's organized the whole thing.
How?
Well, how did he manage to get into
the German admiralty as a Nazi officer?
But I don't see how he can
get us away from here, Anna.
Oh, Father, don't worry about it.
Perhaps you'd better go to bed now, eh?
We'll find out what it's
all about in the morning.
- Good night.
Good night, my dear.
[Knocking]
Come in.
- Fraulein Bomasch?
- Yes.
Thank you.
- You are expecting me. Major Herzoff.
- Yes, sir. Good evening.
Your room is Number 18.
Your bags have been taken up.
- My flowers arrive?
- Yes, sir. The lady has them.
- Thank you. Good night.
- Good night, sir.
[Motor Whirring]
[Door Opens]
My darling, you look as charming as ever.
Those same sweet lips, like warm carnations.
Those sweet, mysterious
eyes, darker and softer...
than the bluest dusk of August violets.
As the poet has it, and I hope he was Aryan.
No one under the bed, I trust.
Uh, bring me a bottle of Krug '28.
- That will be excellent.
- What's happening?
Well, you may have gathered that we were
partners in a highly romantic interlude
in Prague four years ago.
- By the way, did you like the flowers?
- Does that matter?
- It cost me 12 coupons.
- Well, go on.
Well, tomorrow morning I'm
going to phone the admiral...
and say that your father is now
prepared to work for Germany.
- What?
- I shall say that I persuaded you
to reason with him.
They're bound to ask me
to take you both along.
The Gestapo man downstairs
will let us pass and then...
- Yes, but how do you know he will?
- They listen in to the phone. They always do.
Then instead of driving to the admiralty,
we shall go to a meadow outside Berlin...
where a plane is waiting.
I see. But why should the admiralty
believe you've persuaded me?
I shall indicate that, uh, once
again you have succumbed to my charms.
Once again?
It happened in Prague, I'm afraid.
And you told them a
fantastic story like that?
Fantastic? Well, it was four years
ago, there was a harvest moon...
and I was younger and more dashing then.
But you really mean all this?
It sounds far too simple.
I have a very simple mind.
But there is one small complication. Uh...
I shall have to spend the night here...
in a purely professional spirit, of course.
- That is necessary?
- Well, sort of fits into the picture.
The place is absolutely
crawling with Gestapo.
- Have you any sporting instinct?
- Why?
Well, I'll, uh, toss you
who sleeps on the couch.
But you're treating all this
as if it were some sort of joke.
- You don't seem to realize
how much depends upon it.
- It's no good being intense about it.
- You don't think I like the idea
of a firing squad, do you?
- What?
England may be at war with Germany tomorrow.
Oh, I see. But don't you think I
ought to tell my father about all this?
- No.
- Why not?
It'd hardly look right for a lovesick
girl to go popping back to her dad.
- [Sighs]
- [Knocking]
That'll be the waiter. If you can pretend
you find me almost unbearably attractive,
so much the better.
- All right. I'll try.
- Thank you.
My little Anna.
[Door Closes]
## [Whistling Tune]
## [Whistling Continues]
- Is it, uh, raining?
- No, miss.
## [Whistling Continues]
Is anything the matter?
That tune you were whistling, sir
- it is an English tune, isn't it?
- How do you know?
- I heard it on the radio from London last night.
Are you not aware that listening to
the foreign broadcasts is forbidden?
- That there is a strict penalty?
- Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
I will not report you on this occasion, but
see that you are more discreet in future.
Get out.
- [Door Closes]
- [Sighs] Very awkward.
Lucky it wasn't "Rule, Britannia!"
I handled it rather neatly, I thought.
If a woman ever loved you like you love yourself,
it would be one of the romances of history.
As I'm unlikely to think of an adequate reply
to that, I think we ought to drink a toast.
England expects that every secret
service man this night shall do his duty.
- [Mild Pop]
- Flat.
[Rhone Rings]
[Ringing Continues]
- They're ringing your room.
- I'll take it here. It looks better.
- Hello? Is that call for me?
- [Ringing Continues, Stops]
It's German Admiralty.
Yes. Herzoff here. Yes, sir.
I'm sorry to disturb you at this hour,
Herzoff, but we have to alter our plans.
We have just received instructions
from headquarters in Munich...
that Bomasch is to go there
at once by the first train.
But this is ridiculous, sir.
Couldn't you delay it for a few hours?
Impossible. It is on the führer's orders.
The train leaves in an hour's time.
But, sir, what is the use of sending Herr Bomasch
to headquarters in his present frame of mind?
What do you suppose the führer's
frame of mind would be if we didn't?
I'm sorry, Herzoff. [Sighs]
- What's happening?
- They're sending you to Munich at once.
- There's only one chance.
- What?
- Leave the hotel, scuttle...
an old German custom.
- But the guards downstairs.
We got into the admiralty.
We'll get out of here.
Get your clothes on. Tell your
father we leave here in five minutes.
[Motor Whirring]
I've been instructed to leave immediately with
Herr Bomasch. I shall not require you. Dismissed.
- [Clerk] Shall I get you a taxi, sir?
- I'll call one myself.
- Good morning, sir.
- [Bennett] Good morning.
I'm here to escort Herr Bomasch
and Fraulein Bomasch to Munich.
The controller phoned me 10 minutes ago.
I was about to drive them
to the admiralty myself.
My orders are to take them
straight to the station.
The train leaves in 50 minutes.
Evidently a misunderstanding on my part.
- Very well. We are ready.
- You, sir?
Certainly. Were you not told?
I have the admiral's
authority to travel with them.
He feels it essential that Herr Bomasch should
be persuaded to comply with our wishes...
before he reaches headquarters.
I was progressing extremely well with
Fraulein Bomasch when this happened.
I see. Very good, sir.
[Clicks Heels]
- [Man] Zigaretten! Zigarren!
- [Reople Chattering]
[Trolley Bell Ringing]
- [Man] There's not a copy of this week's Runch?
- Please?
Runch. English magazine.
Very humorous. You must have a copy.
No.
She hasn't got a Runch, old man.
- Hasn't she?
- No.
Well. Sold out, I suppose.
[Conductor] You will all leave
here and find places elsewhere.
This compartment is commandeered by the
police. Come along. No delay, please.
They've got La Vie Rarisienne, old boy.
La Vie Rarisienne? All right.
Don't bother about a Runch.
[Candy Vendor Continues In German]
Oh.
Everyone's hopped it.
[Murmurs] Must have got in
the wrong train, I expect.
- [Bell Ringing]
- We can have a side each to ourselves now.
- Put our feet up.
- There.
Bought a copy of Mein Kampf.
Occurred to me it might shed a spot
of light on all this how-do-you-do.
- Ever read it?
- Never had the time.
I understand they give a copy to
all the bridal couples over here.
Oh, I don't think it's
that sort of book, old man.
This is the compart
- Why are you still here?
- What?
- You must find other places at once.
We have first-class tickets, you know.
Outside, please. This compartment has
been commandeered by the authorities.
- That is beside the point.
- Yes. We are British subjects.
Yes. Look here.
"We, Edward Frederick
Lindley, Viscount Halifax...
His Majesty's Principal
Secretary of State" et cetera...
"request all whom it may concern...
"to allow the bearer to pass
without let or hindrance...
and to afford him or her"-
Outside!
- Hmm.
- [Murmurs]
- No good arguing, I suppose.
- Apparently not.
Waste of time, all this
bilge in the passport.
[No Audible Dialogue]
Come, please.
- It's hopeless. We'll never get away now.
- We'll think of something.
- Outside. Come along. Hurry!
- All right. All right.
Hel...
Excuse me.
[Bennett] Now, don't forget that
you're terribly attracted to me.
The two guards' compartment is in there, sir.
All right. Thank you.
- Would you like to face the engine?
- Whatever you like.
Did you notice that German officer
who came into our compartment?
Yes. Why?
Well, I could've sworn
it was old Dicky Randall.
Dicky Randall?
- [Train Whistle Blows]
- Yes. We were at Balliol together.
You must have heard me talking about
him. He used to bowl slow leg breaks.
Played for the Gentlemen once.
Caught and bowled for a duck, I remember.
Oh, yes. Dicky Randall.
Well, if he's a German officer,
how can he be Dicky Randall?
Well, I knew him quite well.
His rooms were next to mine.
Why on earth...
You don't think he's working for the
Nazis like that fellow what's-his-name?
Traitor? Hardly, old man.
He played for the Gentlemen.
Only once.
[Whistle Blowing]
It was last Easter. I was looking
in a shop window in the Graben...
and I saw the reflection of a girl.
For a moment, I thought it was you.
- Were you by yourself?
- Yes. Why?
I just wondered.
It's a blackout.
You know what that means so far west as this.
England and France have declared war.
We have nothing to fear. The
nation is behind the führer.
Yes, but how far behind?
[Anna] We're stopping.
- [Brakes Squealing]
- [Blows Whistle]
Everybody out at once, please!
[Conductor] Everybody out on the platform.
Everybody out of the compartment,
please. Everybody out at once, please.
- [Marsen] Why are we stopping here?
- I don't know yet, sir. Just had the order.
Everybody out, please.
Everybody out. Everybody out.
[Female Conductor Continues, Indistinct]
- How far are we from Munich?
- About an hour's journey.
All passengers off the train, please.
All passengers off the train.
- What's happening?
- Everybody-
Heil Hitlerl This train
is required for troops.
There will be only a small amount
of room available for passengers.
- [Marsen] My party must have
the same accommodations.
- Oh, yes.
The train leaves again in 20 minutes.
May I have your carriage number, please, sir?
- Yes. It's, uh, 0735.
- 0735.
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Aren't you old Dicky Randall?
Major Herzoff, Corps of Engineers.
Oh, I'm frightfully sorry.
It was very silly of me,
but it's an amazing likeness.
Yes, you'd better come along, old man.
Extraordinary. English, I presume.
- Apparently.
- They're a very peculiar race.
We have a small waiting room, sir.
Perhaps you would prefer to wait in there.
- Thank you.
- This way, please.
Please. Please, this way.
Everybody off the train now, please!
Everybody off the train!
You know, you... you made me feel
painfully embarrassed, Caldicott.
Well, I can't help it if old
Dicky Randall has a double.
You must realize that we're
traveling in very difficult times.
- [Chuckling]
- What's the matter?
I can't help thinking of your face when he said,
"Major Herzoff, Corps of Engineers".
Well, all I can say, Charters,
is that when it comes to humor...
we live in entirely different worlds.
This waiting room is required.
Every passenger must wait outside. Come on.
Und you too, please. Come
on. So quick like possible.
- This is getting beyond a joke.
- Yes. We can't stand for this.
Come on, please. Out.
Everybody out so quick as possible.
Everybody must wait outside.
All passengers must wait outside. Rlease go.
No good being undignified, old man.
No, quite right.
Come on. Please, please,
please, please. Come on. Come on.
Come on. So. Please. Please. Please.
Oh, Major. May I phone Munich
to notify them of our delay?
Of course.
My absence may provide the opportunity for
Fraulein Bomasch to approach her father.
It might help.
You seem to have made a considerable
impression on the lady, Major.
I apologize for doubting your capabilities.
Stay on guard here. See
that no one enters or leaves.
Understand? No one.
- That man who spoke to you, did you know him?
- Yes, I did. A fellow called Caldicott.
It's probably the first time he's ever left
England before the end of the cricket season.
- Just my luck. He gave me a very nasty moment.
- No one would have guessed it.
I was a member of the Foreign
Office operatic society.
Do you know I once played Pooh-Bah
to the Foreign Secretary's Ko-Ko?
- Have you thought of any way
of getting us out of this?
- I have.
A car will be waiting at Munich
to take us to headquarters.
We'll be quite a crowd, and I shall ask
for a second car so that we can be alone.
- Suppose they don't give it to us.
- They will.
Because by that time, we shall be on the verge
of persuading your father to work for Germany.
You, on the other hand, must
be asking for time to think.
- You get the idea?
- Yes, but...
- Then we only have the chauffeur to deal with.
And after that
- Switzerland.
- Switzerland?
- Well, we can hardly break through
the Siegfried line.
Yes, but Switzerland's
a long way from Munich.
If we can bluff them into giving
us that car, we'll make it.
So from now on, Mr. Bomasch,
you've got to make up your mind...
whether to keep your armor
plating or let it go rusty.
- Is that quite clear?
- I think so.
And you're still so crazy about me
that you would sell the armor plating
for a very small lock of my hair.
All right.
You can't sit here!
- Why not?
- This truck is required.
Come on. Off, off, off, off, off, off.
I suppose these bags aren't required too?
Off, off, off, off, off, off, off.
Pushed about from pillar to post by this
railway ever since we got on the train.
- Everything we sit on seems to be required.
- It's monstrous.
- We shall write to the company about this.
- Hmm!
You're not at war with England yet, you know.
But you are mistaken.
France declared war this afternoon.
Und England declared war this morning. So!
Achtungl
War.
[Rapers Flop]
Yes.
- Good heavens.
- What's the matter?
My golf clubs.
Where are they?
I lent them to Max in Berlin.
Like a fool, I said he needn't
bring them back till next Wednesday.
[Exhales] Probably seen the last of them.
Yes. I expect they'll require
them for something or other.
I read in the paper that
they're pulling up park railings.
I don't see the connection, old man.
Well, your clubs are steel, aren't they?
- Yes.
- So.
There you are then.
Whip shafts too.
Especially made for me.
Why not get in touch with Max?
- How?
- On the telephone.
Ask him to send them to London immediately.
It's a desperate chance,
but it's worth taking.
I shall never be able to replace them.
- Oh, uh, telephone?
- Hmm?
Stationmaster's office.
Captain Strasse? Marsen here.
- I'm speaking from Kurtbaden.
- Oh, I beg your pardon.
It concerns Major Herzoff, sir.
I think a full inquiry
should be made at once...
in view of something which
happened a few minutes ago.
A few minutes ago? You mean he's with you?
Admiral Hassinger gave him the authority.
Hassinger did? He never told me.
That's very suspicious.
Yes, but the admiral himself introduced him.
I'll ask him. I'll phone you back.
Uh, what is your number there?
Yes, yes, yes. In a few minutes.
Admiral Hassinger, please.
[Train Rassing]
Hello? I want a
long-distance call to Berlin.
Oliver
2-4-double 6.
What? Yes. Yes, of course it's important.
- It's all in German.
- Hmm.
What?
Well, how long then? Oh, all right.
Blasted junction's engaged by the
military. They'll call me back.
These people seem to have
no idea of business as usual.
If I were asked to give a snap
judgment, I should say that was an "S."
- More like an "F."
- I do not know, sir.
I used to know someone
who made his S's like that.
- Someone in the War Office?
- Well, no.
Ach. We can't afford to waste time.
You didn't give him permission to
travel with the prisoners, did you, sir?
No, no. But he may have assumed it.
If you remember, we more or
less gave him carte blanche.
The only thing is to check
up with the War Office, sir.
- I suppose so.
- War Office.
If he's right, this will be
very serious for you, Kampfeldt.
Very serious indeed.
The letter was addressed to you.
There's no denying that, Kampfeldt.
Quite right. I'm afraid I
shall have to sack my secretary.
Hello?
[Soldier Speaking German]
- [Rhone Rings]
- That'll be our call.
- [Soldier Continues]
- [Ringing Continues]
Aufschliessen!
Hmm! What infernal impudence.
I'll bet it's my call.
Marsen speaking. Yes, sir.
Listen, Marsen. You were right.
We have been completely fooled.
Herzoff is not known at the War Office.
There is no officer of
that name on the army list.
Then, uh...
Yes, sir. Obviously. An enemy agent.
I say, Charters, there's
another phone in there.
What? Oh. Lucky.
- [Soldier Shouts In German]
- Hello? Hello? Hello!
- Gone dead.
- [Cradle Clattering]
- Hello!
- Why not try the thingamy? Yeah.
- You know, the... gadget.
- Oh.
Hello...
It's the extension. That chap out there.
Well, perhaps he'll be
off the line in a minute.
- Shh!
- What's up?
They're talking
about what's-his-name.
You know, Herzoff.
No. He doesn't suspect.
Yes, sir. I see.
[Female Conductor] All
passengers aboard, pleasel
No time to stand here now,
sir. The train is leaving.
What? Listen, we can't afford to take risks.
Carry on with Herzoff to Munich.
Let him think he's getting
away with it. Understand?
I'll get on to army headquarters there.
Very good, sir.
All passengers aboard, pleasel
- Everybody on the trainl
- What is it?
Well, as far as I can make
out, Herzoff isn't Herzoff.
- What?
- No.
They're sending an escort to arrest him
- when we get to Munich.
- Herzoff?
- Yes.
- Well
- Then...
- Listen, if... if Herzoff isn't Herzoff...
- What?
- Well, he must be Dicky Randall.
- Yes.
Everybody on the train! All
passengers aboard, please!
All passengers on the last two coaches only!
All passengers aboard!
- All passengers aboard.
- After you, Major.
All passengers on the last two coaches only.
All passengers on the last two coaches.
All passengers aboard.
All passengers on the last two coaches only.
All passengers on the last two coaches.
All passengers aboard.
Keep within call. I shall need
you at Munich, perhaps before.
[Blows Whistle]
- One thing emerges very clearly from all this.
- [Train Whistle Blows]
- Caldicott!
- The train! There it goes!
Oh, my, my! That's a mess!
[Train Departing]
- [Panting]
- [Caldicott] That was a near thing.
[Charters] I thought we were going to be
in this infernal country for the duration.
Oh, my Lord.
Don't anticipate, old man.
What were you saying just now about
something emerging very clearly?
- I said?
- Mmm.
- When?
- On the platform.
- About something emerging?
- Mmm.
What was it?
- What was what?
- What emerged.
- You never said.
- Oh.
We do not wish to persuade you to become
a National Socialist, Herr Bomasch.
I explained that to your
daughter. Have I not?
And you may work wherever you choose, Father.
- Isn't that so?
- Quite.
- After all, we should have our freedom.
- I know, my dear.
But freedom is strangely
interpreted in this country.
I do not agree with you, Herr Bomasch.
Freedom in Germany is a great
advance on freedom elsewhere.
It's properly organized
and controlled by the state.
I'd much rather we kept politics out of it.
Herr Bomasch unfortunately
refuses to understand...
the sacred importance of
the Nazi world mission.
- His stay in England perhaps.
- No doubt. A corrupt influence.
A corrupt country.
Controlled by international
Freemasons and theJew Churchill.
[Clicks]
But since you wish it, Herr
Bomasch, we will drop politics...
and discuss it from a more personal basis.
I'm certain, Charters, that
what you were about to say...
was that we've stumbled on
something pretty serious.
There's no doubt which
side Randall's playing for.
- Ours?
- Yes.
Yes. That's what was emerging so clearly.
It's up to us to find
some way of warning him.
Yes. Come on. Let's find him.
- I say, Caldicott.
- Yes?
- Do you think we're wise rushing into this?
- How do you mean?
Well, I mean we've no proof that
Randall's working for England.
- Well, everything points to it.
- Yes, but is that enough?
We're enemy aliens...
and these Nazis are pretty
free with their firing party.
Hmm. Well, ought we to
let that stand in our way?
Well, certainly not.
I mean if
- if we were certain.
As it is, we've just got to bear it in mind.
I don't see what else he can be doing.
For all we know, he may
be an international crook.
Crooks don't generally
play for the Gentlemen.
Raffles did.
That's fiction.
Still, you may be right, Charters.
Of course, if we were certain,
we'd do our duty and take the risk.
Yes, of course.
As it is, I can get on with Mein Kampf.
Haven't got out of Hitler's boyhood yet.
And, Herr Bomasch, what
is even more important...
your daughter will be able to live
with you or wherever she pleases.
- You must give me time to think.
- Certainly.
We should be in Munich in... 40 minutes.
Indeed. For the first time, I will
be sorry when the journey's over.
Yes. I
- I can believe that.
- I think we should order something to eat.
- An excellent idea.
Just in case we do not find headquarters
in a very... hospitable frame of mind.
- Please.
- Oh, sorry.
You don't choose to stand up
when a German officer passes?
You see, we're English.
Your passports.
Oh, beg your pardon. You're quite right.
The English should not stand up.
They should go down on
their fat bellies and crawl.
- Now look here!
- So, you are standing up.
Very well. We shall generously
permit you to run back to England...
no doubt to find yourselves safe jobs.
Meanwhile, you may sit down.
- "Fat bellies".
- "Safe jobs".
As if they weren't all taken by now anyway.
Caldicott, this is absolutely
and finally the last straw.
- Yes, Charters.
- We'll warn Dicky Randall at once,
come what may.
I'm with you, old man.
It's things like that
that bring it home to you.
Sandwiches, biscuits. Yes, sir.
Will you take tea substitute
or coffee substitute?
Tea for me, please.
- Tea.
- Fine.
He's in there. That
Gestapo fellow's there too.
Yes. A couple of storm troopers in there.
How the devil are we going to pass him
the word without that fellow spotting it?
- We've got to do it somehow.
- Yes.
Of course, he... he might come out for a minute.
I mean, most people do.
We must act, Charters. It's no good
hanging about on the off chance.
Excuse, please.
- Wait a minute. That steward.
- What about him?
Well, he's bound to come back
sometime to bring their order.
ByJove, yes.
Here he comes.
- ## [Whistling]
- Excuse, please.
- Oh, what... what time do we get to Munich?
- In about 30 minutes, sir.
Thank you.
- All right?
- Yes. I put it underneath a doughnut.
Good. What? But how do
you know they're for him?
Well, I suddenly remembered that
Dicky Randall always had doughnuts...
sent up to his room for afternoon tea.
[Chuckles] That's very
clever of you, old man.
- Better get along there, hey?
- Mmm, right.
- Oh, my Lord.
- Why, what's up?
Why, I'm
- I'm wondering if it was doughnuts.
- What?
- I-I believe it was rock cakes.
[Exhales]
Have you made all arrangements
for transport at Munich, Marsen?
Every arrangement, sir.
- Will there be more than one car?
- Almost certainly two.
Then let's see, that will
make seven. Rather a crowd.
I think in order to finish my talk with Herr
Bomasch, you had better take the second car.
Very good, sir.
I believe Herr Bomasch is really beginning
to see that I am doing my best to help him.
I'm sure he knows that.
Yes, yes, Major. Your attitude
has been most reasonable.
You must remember it's only a few hours since
Father was taken out of England by force.
Captain Marsen was only obeying orders.
Members of the Gestapo are
frequently asked to perform duties...
which others find too objectionable.
Some are objectionable.
Others I find extremely satisfying.
[Bennett] I often envy
you your opportunities.
[Train Whistle Blowing]
What is that, the bill? I will pay.
No, please. I am escorting the party.
My dear Marsen, it's my privilege.
In fact, it is an order.
Terrible. The way prices
have gone up already.
Excuse me.
[Clicks Heels]
- Yes, I-I'm Randall.
- How are you, old man?
- You remember me?
- Yes.
- This is Charters, an old friend of mine.
- How do you do? Well, what is it?
- We don't know what you're up to, of course.
- Never mind about that.
But whatever it is, you appear to be on
the spot. Tell him about it, Charters.
Well, I was phoning
Berlin about my golf clubs.
By the way, I'm resigned to the fact I
shall never see them again, Caldicott.
- Yes, well, get on with it.
- I was just coming to that.
I was telephoning and got on the other
chap's line... you know, that Gestapo fellow.
I overheard him saying they
were sending a military escort...
to arrest you when you get to Munich.
You see, you're rumbled. They
know that you're not Herzoff.
Now listen. I can't tell you
everything. There isn't time.
But I've got to get that old man and the
girl out of this country at all costs.
Oh, a
- an official job.
- Are you two fellows game to help me?
- What, against Germany?
I'll say we are after all they've
done to us. What do you say, Caldicott?
- Absolutely, old man. Backs to the wall.
- I hope not.
I say, could you give me a
little more room to think?
[Clicks Heels]
- Is there any tea left?
- Yes, I think so, Ulrich.
There's no time for tea. We
reach Munich in a few minutes.
Oh, time for just one cup. Cake, darling?
No, thank you.
I am afraid I must ask you
to drop this little comedy.
It is very entertaining, but I have
certain formalities to attend to.
Comedy? What do you mean?
Oh, thank you.
You're merely pretending to
be infatuated with this man.
There's no such person as Major Herzoff.
He's a British agent trying to get
you and your father out of Germany.
You must be crazy. Ulrich.
I don't propose to waste the
time of the Gestapo denying it.
Thank you.
You... You're going to give yourself up?
Well, they have lots of proof, Mr. Bomasch.
An escort will be waiting at
Munich to take you in charge.
You can't do this.
- He's an enemy agent.
- Weren't you?
Didn't you do exactly the same as he's doing?
With a slight but important
difference. I wasn't caught.
- Are you just going to sit there and do nothing?
- Now, please don't make a scene.
- Don't you realize what this means?
- Yes, I do.
But he has a gun, and I haven't. And
he's got a couple of reserves next door.
Who do you take me for
- Bulldog Drummond?
[Sighs]
Can't you be serious even now?
I told you this would happen.
I told you your scheme was absolutely
childish, but you wouldn't listen to me.
Why didn't you stay in England
instead of coming over here...
and deliberately throwing
your life away, you fool?
I have no time to listen
to this ridiculous display.
Steiner! Dreimund!
[Train Whistle Blowing]
[Soldier Shouting Orders In German]
[Soldier #2 Shouting Orders]
[Bell Ringing]
If there is more than
one major on the train...
how are we to know which one to arrest?
Our man's got a Gestapo officer watching him.
Hmm. Who has not these days?
- [Train Whistle Blowing]
- The train.
[Brakes Squealing]
- Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitlerl
Marsen. I'm on instruction from Fifth
Army Headquarters to arrest Major Herzoff.
I fear you will need a stretcher.
The prisoner tried to escape, and I had to, uh
- to deal with him.
You will find him in the
last compartment, Coach 66.
Uh, what... what transport have you?
- Two cars.
- Excellent.
Now, this is Herr Axel Bomasch
from Harska and his daughter.
They are in protective custody,
and I have instructions...
to take them to General
von Komwitz without delay.
With your permission, I
will use one of the cars.
- [Officer] Certainly.
- I'll leave you to take charge of the prisoner.
Will you show me my car?
- Brunner.
- [Clicks Heels]
Take this S.S. officer to the car.
- Coach 66 you said?
- The last compartment.
Full length on the seat.
Sergeant, get a stretcher from
the stationmaster and follow me.
Olson, you will take the S.S.
officer and his party in your car.
One moment. Is your chauffeur to be trusted?
I think so. He is a very
old member of the party.
Anti-Russian perhaps. I think
I'd rather take one of my own men.
- I'm traveling to a place
of the greatest secrecy.
- Very good.
- You will not be needed, Olson.
- Very good, sir.
Rumplemeyer, you will drive.
- Heil Hitler.
Come on, quick.
[Engine Revs]
Right, man! Right! You're not in England.
- Oh, I'd forgotten.
- [Vehicle Horn Honks]
Not much of a life, a secret agent.
And the pay is bad too, sir.
[Man Grunts]
I was just thinking, Charters.
In the last war, the army took over Lord's
Cricket Ground for drilling troops on.
- Wonder if they'll do it this time.
- Shortsighted, you know.
Better pull up here, Charters. We can't
get to Switzerland by any of the main roads.
Let me take over, will you?
Age around 22, height 5'4".
Slim figure, dark, brown eyes.
That's the lot. Phone these descriptions to
all stations within a hundred-mile radius.
A report has just come in, sir, that the
car has left the city by the south road.
So they are making for Switzerland.
- We take the road.
- Very good.
There's one thing that's
worrying me, Randall, old man.
It may be silly of me, of course, but...
How exactly are we going to
get across the Swiss frontier?
I know a little place where
I used to go climbing...
about 8,000 feet up where
Switzerland and Germany meet.
You're not going to ask us to
hang about on ropes, I hope.
I'm not, but they may. There's a
narrow road leads right to the top.
- What's over the top?
- Switzerland.
- Anything in between?
- 6,000-feet drop.
- Well, how can we, uh...
- Skip it.
Skip it?
[Tires Screeching]
- There's a car following us!
- Is there? Well, here we go.
Don't let them get away!
[Shouting In German]
[Horn Honking]
[Air Hissing]
I'll have to change the wheel!
Watch the road, Charters.
Hello! Anybody here? Caldicott.
Anybody around?
- Switzerland.
- [Footsteps On Stairs]
Good morning to you, sir. Good morning.
- [Bennett] Are you in charge here?
- Yes. There's only me.
- I want to cross to Switzerland.
- Now, sir?
- Yes, now.
- But we're at war.
I had orders yesterday
to close the teleferic.
My orders come from a higher source.
Higher than the chief of police at Maxberg?
- Gestapo headquarters at Munich.
- Oh.
I have been instructed to show this
lady and gentleman safely out of Germany.
I better ring Christopher.
[Attendant] Yes. Right away.
- There's a car coming. Looks like them.
- There are five of them altogether.
- Keep an eye on them.
- How are the goats, Christopher?
Yes, thank you, Christopher.
I got it. And the butter.
Do you want to be dismissed for incompetence?
They'll be leaving in about
two minutes, Christopher.
I shall require to see your papers,
sir. Have you got your passports?
How long does this take to cross the valley?
- About four minutes.
- Once it's in midair, can it be stopped?
Why, yes, sir, if anyone wanted to stop it.
Will you follow me to the office?
This way, please.
- Can you see them?
- No, but I can hear the engine.
- How does this thing work?
- That shouldn't be difficult.
- Well, how?
- Yes, obviously, this starts it.
- Yes?
- [Rounding On Door]
- Yes. This is the speed regulator.
- Speed regulator, right. Get in quick.
- All of you! Quick! Caldicott!
- [Rounding Continues]
- What about you?
- I'll start it and then jump on.
They're here!
- Come on. Jump in.
- Yes, but they...
they'll stop us halfway across.
Get in, will you!
Come on! Quickly!
There it is!
[Marsen] Stand aside!
[Gunshots]
Olson, go around back!
The téléfériquel
They're potting at us! Duck down!
[Gunshots]
[Gunshots Continue]
[Glass Shatters]
[Gunshots]
[Groans]
[Gunshots Continue]
Get down there and draw his fire.
I'll get in over the roof.
Right.
Come here and stop the machinery! Come back!
[Clicks]