This Tale is about the brave
warrior whos.
tale wont be made
a history by the traitor
But couldn't stop to become
a story..
Are you from london times..
Are you with him
So tell me one thing..
here in entire country
Everybody is talking about
violence..
Why they dont believe on british kingdom
dont belive on traitors..
since 1862
when chandangarh attacked
on madavgarh
Yuvraj higness
We cant wait,chandargarh warrior
are heavy at us..
lts not nesscery that we
won by the sword..
they are about to come
Are you wasting your worriors
life for them.
Who are you draging in muck
As you know pidari are
the truth follower..
Eventhen you dont belive
that they.
always drunk that pindari
they are wild but..
when they rides the horse with
the sword
lt will be workable for us
in the happiness of victory,
king has sent you a pac..
The leader of pindari,
haidar ali..
Only drinks with kings
go along, and get the mesure
of our land.
calm down
your father sangram singh also.
dont dare to call the name
of pindari leader only haider ali
keep your attitude for enemies.
We've to win all emperior
sure, win it..
but our support was till here
and in exchange of it you'd was going
to give me land back.
Sure.
first you meet with my friends
your father told me that english
are with chandangarh
We only drinks the english blood
in which generation are living in?
we should not be enemy of
the person who rules half world
just give me my lands paper
and get out
land
where do you want land
there
or beneth our castles stairs..
where you'll feel the our
greatness
and remains about your
companion
look there
betray..
have to save our pindaris.
its our mistake
we believed on wrong person
l'm the only guilty..
therefore the result..
what kinda result,
here we have less lost of our brothers
then one more
we'll leave our home..
burn our field
and will gether new farmers
and warriors in new places
We'll get rid of anglo's
and kings..and occupy manavgarh
because the revange of 4500
pindaris death..
will be taken after killing
that raja..
So l give you word
l'll kill all the companion of raja
and himself.
or be cutted myself.
no prithvi,
we are illetrate people
how come we can have
the thouth like a anglos
its a son
congratulation
the kid will be wet
he have to run
till very far
he's my veer
for him no rain what strom
you just see my fighting
one day i will throw you in water
try to carry your fury
time is in hope by you
from wherever l grabs,
l takes 5 gram flesh..
there a box inside
here is nobody,here's no treasure,
its the ladies compartment
l heared the pindari's a guard
of womens and kinds
take these jewellry but give back that
This is the last symbol
of his mother..
veer has come
everybody has come back
look your son has looted the
whole train.
Are you saying truth.
l did it all
Tell dada, how many weapons
he want to buy so buy it
why are you fighting like red indians
if you want to do this so
why you got educated
still didn't ,,
want him more educated
one day l'll throw you in the water
l'll wait for that day
did you see how are my sons
And l..
lts a misery.
About the matter
we have forgot.
by which kind a misery
the mothers of lambs..
So will we kill the lambs.
to got heavy on the clumsy..
is the power of clumsy
This sword of my dadda..
is only for the head of
the anglos..
london is the country of white women,
l dont want to go, you go
l want to find her,
even you haven't her address
Dadda is coming,
make some excuse
dont want to go to london?
at one side you talks about killing anglo,
and other side you want send us their country
their power is thier natural habit
how they handles the situation,
we should know how they work
you're going london.
london is very beutiful place
how beautifull is the castle
of the queen
our tomb are more beautifull
than it..
didn't you see the taj mahal
when you've come here so
why dont you come completly
its only about 2 years
lf she got married in 2 years so?
dont know what happend
to thinking of dadda..
send us here among anglo,
should send us manavgarh with sword
l beg pardon for this.
you take this..
can see in london
that train girl..
when l will get rid
of this hallucination
come my brother to india..
is someone gives hankerchief
in the dreams..
she's smiling
This england is very strange place.
everybody knows english here..
as same in india..
hey teacher
just hold it
lf our country is so dirty,
where dust,mock,
so you,
since 140 years..
what are you doing in our country
cleaning
l tell you
our country is a golder bird
to whom you people want to sale it
your stomach will be bust
but bird wont come in your mouth
because that bird became a hawk
which will eat you..
our dadda has sent us here
to learn..
only for leaning
otherwise l'd have teach you today
The pees on the pot which
by the drinks water
bravo, gajendar singh..
Even you dont play bad..
so what was she saying
We came to know that boy
had no mistake
management misbehaved
we should talk
why you are like that
some wild gave you your thing back
so you think wild are good?
you're right.
lts the favour of that anglos..
that they got public training
and leaved.
if it'd be ratangarh so..
that anglo says right,, that our
country has poverty and presperation
but what is the reason of it
its reason is,
all kings are seprate.
who is guilty
you?
or anglo
in our country first 187 anglo had came..
then 2000
then 10000
then 100000
and that 100000 anglo
rules on 300000 indians..
do you know how
because they only know
how to break.
in the name of hunger..
and greed..
in the name of language
and we only know how
to be seprate..
in the name of religion,
caste..
and you know they knowledge they're
giving us,is their trap
They want to put their british soul
in natives.
for getting their thought very deeply.
we both brothers got in their
standard..
bless me
write that london suits you
l'll write it to dadda.
lts royal party,you'll get girl here soon,
then take care of yourself
where are you going,
you remember what dadda told
Have to understand anglo,
so have to first anglo women
l dont want to talk to you but
with yashoda..
Dont have manners,.
You came abroad but forgot the manners
dont know what that anglo saw in them
that gave them chance to come here
we know what that anglo sees in us..
but you people are born
to be rule the kingdom
so what you sees in that anglos..
which by you made their slave..
look, they stands in front of us like that
he was saying us slave.
he was kiddin..
dont be frustrated..
l was justjoking..
so let me do joke to me..
you didn't got rid of your
passion of love.
this love is not in your control
you're laid in that bed since many days.
3 more months are remaining,
your love story has been end
give me shoes, you cant
wear socks properly,
on the cheast..
on cheast.
where are these..
be carefull..
yes
how is your feet?
fine
so did you forgave to brother.
no
in the playing there's always
strange activity
there's no fault of him
thanks..
no need of it
l'm in oblight of you
take care of your feet
you take care of yourself.
will yo
thank you for your one more favor..
we all understands protocol
but music dont understand protocol
so everyone keep your heart tight
that it wont be that our voice
will take place in your heart.
and royalty will be forcefull
to dance ..
lf you likes my voice,
so why didn't you dance with me there?
dont knwo
you thought lf you'll dance with me,
so l'll dance a lot..
And my broken leg will be break more
but l can get you rid of this
misunderstanding..
lf you grant me so.
l want introduce you with someone
special..
he has come.
sit them..
he's there..
what are you doing
here everybody are big people
and knew that you'll not
dance here with me
You're right..
l cant break protocol daily
lf breaking is joint with joining
so is that called breaking.?
why your father wants to meet me
because he's king
from where?
from shikarpur/
He has come to meet queen,
this time he'll remove pindari's
You know,
they're barbaric..
once in the train where we were in..
they looted that.
Didn't they harmed you?
no,,
but he cutted the kings hand..
its thanks..
his head got saved.
l heared that he killed thousands
pindaries by decieve..
its wrong
he wanted to make them civillize.
by snatching their land..
after getting them houseless
pindari has only one motive
how can you say that..
you've to go veer
he knows everything about you
he has gone to hostel to find you
how dare you ..
came along us.
at our sister..
says right.
fathers incomplete work,
son have to complete..
where is your brother.
its good that he's not here.
from where l grabs..
will drag the 5gm flesh.
leave him veer.
l forgave him
no,
he's the brother of yashoda..
our enemity is not with him
but with his father.
no
go away from here..
go veer
promise me veer,that you'll never
come back madavgarh
l promise you
that l'll definetly come madavgarh
With the orders of dadd.
or with you
will get married.
or will burn the madavgarh
will meet later
l promise you,
To keep walking on this path,
ln any situation,
l will never lose hope,
and l will do my job with
my dignity,
l promise you,
from today my nation and it's happiness
will be my first priority,
l take oath,
from today madhavgarh's brother,
will be my brother,
and Madhavgarh's soldier,
will be my solider,
Yuvraaj!
After yuvraaj's death like you
supported me in front of British Queen,
You paid your duty to save our religion
who exist from 7 centuries,
l am proud of you,
But my political agents and few royal
Prince have a question,
How would you fulfill your oath
to demolish all soldiers besides....
l have decided to give your answer
about this question,
Let's arrange your choosing
life partner ceremony,
The gift of your marriage will be the
first blood of veer's blood.
Veer killed tota's son,
What are you going to do?
Don't tell dada about yashudhara,
He will kill you,
You haven't brought any english
babe for me,
like you love your wife,
Same as that your veer love someone,
Can you speak it without drink,
Even l can introduce you,
My son is in love,
My veer is in love,
You are saved,
What happen to you?
Dada!
Speak!
Won't you ask me her name,
ls is necessary?
lt's necessary.
then tell me,
Dhara!
Yashudhara!
She is princess,
She is a princess.
of Madhavgarh.
What a son l have?
What a dadda l have?
Mangla!
come here!
She was also a enemy's daughter,
Her father was not agreed,
So l brought her here,
Sardar Hyder Ali's message
has arrived,
All preparations will be done
on next full moon night,
More than 15000 Pindari will
be headed to Madhavgarh,
that day.....
....that day Prithvi will do 2 things,
One!
Along with Raja he will kill all
white soldiers and fly a flag,
and second....
He will bring his wife,
Dadda!
When you were gone to take mom,
did you brought army there,
No!
then how did you think?
that your son will take his army,
Now tell....
So shall we give him bengal.
l don't understand,
what is this nonsense,
Strange habit,
that she came here from far away,
to take animal photo shot,
Madhavgarh's political agent's
daughter have lost her mind,
daughter?
Don't do it veer,
She is already unconsicious.
When Lord Ram is with us then
everything is goona be fine,
and by the way if someone else
would be on my place,
then he would do the same,
Jungle have been searched,
All soldiers have decided that
lake is the best place of check post,
We have to use check posts
like strategy,
what should be the reason
of our security,
and the death circle of Pendaris,
You have done a bravery job,
We drink this bravery in our tea,
Where you belong?
from Lusai Ghati,
Lusai ghati?
lt's 14 days away from Lahore,
towards Kelash Mansawar,
ln our area....
we have a danger of forest area,
After cutting our soils
they escaped to ice,
like pendaris killed your people
and escape to desert,
and to demolish them....
We need long distance shooter tanks,
that's why we were going
to Viday Nagar,
We have decided that this time
we will enter in ice,
and we will make those
robber's grave their,
Nice to meet you,
Nice to meet you too.
Me too.
Excuse me,
No problem!
When some of our own raise
his hand to shake hand with me,
then that moment reminds me,
when that pendari cut my hand,
then l feel happy to think
about that moment,
When l will cut his head,
because l never forgot my enemies,
l never forget my enemies either,
l take out his quarter of meat
from anywhere l catch him,
l don't miss that quarter too,
Amazing!
l have learn another lesson,
l promise you,
that l won't left single piece
on enemy's body,
He handled the situation that
everyone has relaxed,
What do you call in hindi?
Veer!
You learn all this for me,
l send message for Prince 2
days earlier,
He didn't come to meet me,
He was gone with Angela that day,
now where he is?
You are learning so soon,
You are playing in right tone,
But l.....
What do you think?
l am watching what you're showing,
Enough!
When angela will know the truth,
what is truth?
Why don't you understand my problem,
Your promise is fulfilled,
Now go from here,
How could?
How could l go?
Your father has invited me,
of your wedding ceremony,
before tomorrow evening,
if you didn't leave Madhavgarh,
then l will do the same what a
Yuvraki have to do till yet,
So veer didn't go,
Respected Father,
l have committed a sin,
From my emotions,
l forgot my duty,
Kunwar Mahinder Pratab Singh
is Veer.
Your Yashudhara,
That letter,
not letter,
these are my army details.
Thank God.
When....
....they could enter in ice
behind their enemies in winter,
then why we wan't go to desert,
that's why we gather the collusion
army with our army
and send them to desert,
You can't see enything after 12 yards.
Desert storm can kill our army,
these conditions applies to Pendaris,
l hope they didn't come out
in desert storm,
lt is the right time,
to find their hide outs,
and to kill unaware and
unarmed Pendaris,
Why do you understand my feelings,
Who have to understand he....
Madhavgarh is in danger,
Return me that letter,
but l gave that letter to Veer.
What?
l hid this truth from you,
because my emotions about him...
l have understand your plans,
Pendari's hand is not a hand
but it's iron,
You will be tired,
You made watch on my wrist,
Now my good time has decided,
Truth is your love or conspiracy,
what should l suppose,
My dadda has sent bengal for you,
Tell me one thing,
lf you have to choose one from me
and your dadda,
then who you will choose?
l will choose truth,
lf your father is true,
he is good then everyone
supports him,
But if father is wrong,
then what should a child do?
Should he leave him,
Nor leave him
neither support him,
bring him on right path,
What path we should show him,
they shouldn't pay their emperor duty,
they shouldn't transfer their royality
to their next generation.
To cheat and kill 4500 Pendaris,
that's what you call to fulfill duty,
To turn madhavgarh british slave,
ls it trasnferring their royality.
Your state have no danger
from Pendaris.
but from your own father,
lf that time your father would
have fulfill his promise,
then circumstances would
be change today.
What oath you took for your
state's goodness,
l will support you to fulfill it,
Mark my words,
Your army will be save.
Pendari's won't attack until.
you attack them first,
This bengal...
now l will wear you.
When you will have courage
to speak truth.
ln front of entire world,
you will call me VEER.
We will meet again.
How do l call you veer?
Lucky Bastard!
When they both are in my arms,
then notjust Madhavgarh l can
win entire world.
Leave the world.
Ask Veer,
Did he won Princess,
What are you asking him?
Ask me,
Man should have balls.
To all Pendari Brothers.
who are not between us anymore,
Veer!
you mean to say....
....that we don't have to fight war,
We have to rust our swords.
We have to wait in this hot weather,
First check it out what's
running in veer's mind,
Do we have shit in our minds,
that we will listen this young boy,
lf decision would be made from swords,
so we shouldn't lost our brothers.
New point of view,
Veeru came from abroad to
take new vision.
Only veer will take the decisions of
this war.
25 years ago....
You have trusted Prithvi and send
him to meet King,
and our 4500 Pendaris were cheated,
and today you are committing another
mistake to believe on his son.
This young boy,
studied in abroad,
now he will decide our destiny,
He just studied from there,
He is not white man's son,
He is your son.
but your son scared and ran
away from white people,
Let me see,
What's running in his mind since
many years, what do you mean?
They couldn't cheat us if l would
go to take letter,
l would kill that king there,
but you escaped from there,
Coward!
You are abusing my dadda.
l will bury you here.
Start digging,
l will see who will bury whom,
Don't forget your words.
lf you are the Prithvi's son...
....then only our death will decide it,
Shut up!
He is just a fool.
Why we pendaris fighting with
each other.
This battle will happen,
and whoever will survive.
that will decide the destiny
of 15000 pendaris.
You have abused my dadda.
Everyone take your place behind
Madhavgarh's mountains.
Dadda! we will meet again when
l will marry Yashodhara.
Today is the special day for Madhavgarh.
Just give me the identity of
that pendari once,
then you better watch what will l
do with the killer of your brother,
Whoever Prince will defeat
this Giant warrior,
that will marry with Yuvraghi,
ls any real man here,
l have to see how much a
Rajput's blood can boil.
Rajput's blood is warmed,
if itjust touch you,
then white skin will become black,
l am Veer.
Prithvi Singh's son,
and a pendari.
l will chop you in pieces like....
Child!
From this one hand,
don't know how many hours
l bruned,
l made you sleep from one hand,
that's why l still followed
a father's path.
but for me veer's path is
her religion.
Yashudhara is prithvi singh's daughter
in law and veer's wife.
lf someone will try to harm her,
then veer will bring disaster,
what earth quake couldn't bring,
Calm down,
and we learned betray from you.
We have come to Madhavgarh for
preparation, our half army has gone
to forest,
we have broken your all tanks.
and look at this you have no way out,
Do you hear this sound.
Listen to this sound carefully.
Pendaris have surrounded Madhavgarh,
behind long castle walls.
now you can't be secure anymore,
Sooner or later you will
have to open the doors.
for food and water,
and if you won't open them then your
thirsty and hunger people will eat you.
Who will cut who?
l will see.
We didn't gave you lead that you
think about british people.
l am not think about british.
l am thinking about entire country.
Veer!
how did this country come,
This was is ours.
this country is ours too.
l understand one thing in england,
that nothing will happen to
kill few british soldiers.
We have to remove them from country.
then let's remove them,
let's remove them from entire country.
We will remove 2000 here,
and 10000 will escape from there.
Sardar!
notjust white in fight,
notjust all rajas, pendaris and
madhavgarh's army will be cut,
but all thousands of innocent will
be die who lives in castle.
When we can get Madhavgarh
without fight then why blood shed.
then what should l do?
like you want.
that Raja and Frazer
l give them all safe passage.
What a solution they found
to escape from here.
l need blood in Madhavgarh,
They put our brothers in fire.
Did you forgot that?
What do you think?
lf we will spare them,
then they won't betray us again.
They won't fight back.
and then there will be no casualities.
they will betray and attack too.
we will have casualities.
but then we will have casualities not
for revenge but that will be goal.
that will be for country.
Think about it.
lf we will spare them today,
if they will bring huge army back.
then we have our strength but
we will have
Madhavgarh's entire army,
and nation of Madhavgarh.
and all these rajas will be aware
and they will realise that
they are only slaves.
then death....
...won't be death that will be
martyry.
and that will burn entire country.
Today we have chance,
someone must have to flash light.
and how do we lose this chance,
because the revenge of 4500 pendaris
will be done from to kill that raja
and his every white supporter.
then l am giving you my words.
l will cut raja and his
every white supporter,
or l will die.
Veer!
How a pendari shall take
his words back.
When it's the matter of country.
then you can't take your words back.
then in Mahabharat....
...why Pitama didn't take
his words back.
then fine.
Tomorrow morning,
decision will be made between
Prithvi and Veer.
Pendari never cries.
l want to win too.
Your wife....
...want to spend her entire
life with you.
We will meet back.
Dadda!
Your son is not such a big veer,
who could walk this way of religion,
You are on right path,
Pick up the sword.
Don't let world give a chance,
that you are not dadda's son,
You pay your duty.
and let me fulfill the promise
what l gave to Pendaris.
Winner will takes all.
l won't let this claim to you,
that a father killed his son,
and l won't let you live with burdon,
that people say that a son
killed his father.
You were fighting to
save these traitors.
You were fighting with us for them,
No!
l was fighing for that.
He is fighting for us,
British are not ours.
We have to remove them from lndia.
You are very greedy of land,
Where you need land?
l won't give you land,
because whenever rajas like
you get the land,
country become slave,
One day only one flag will be
in entire lndia.
Tell Mom,
We will meet again,
you don't go anywhere.
l will be back.
and now my veer's son,
is heading towards with that
freedom light.
Pendari gave his words.
why he couldn't come back.
l am still better than your mom,
Where is dadda?
l told you,
one day l will must throw
you in this water.
l was waiting for this moment since
many years.
Pendari never cries.
l know.
but today let me cry.