We don't get too many transfers
to this place.
- Where you from?
- Albany.
I'm just so excited
to be in the big city.
Yeah, well, don't get too excited.
Same rooms as the ones
you cleaned in Albany.
Same beds, same carpets,
same mess every morning.
[ Gasps ]
Oh, my God.
Do I smell coffee?
If you do, it was made by elves.
- Ohh! - Aah!
- Aah!
Geez!
You scared me.
Yeah, I think we all just
kick-started our day.
[ Sighs ] What are you doing here?
[ Cellphone chimes ]
Oh, my tutoring job went late,
and the train
wasn't running back to my place,
so I crashed here.
Hope you don't mind.
No! No, of course not.
Matter of fact,
um, now that you've broken up
with your boyfriend,
there's really no reason
you can't move back in here.
Actually, there are many reasons,
starting with "I have a lease."
Ah. I told you
I would help you with that.
And you know I... I don't like you
living in that place alone.
Dad, it's fine. I can handle it.
I got to go. I have an early class.
[ Smooches ]
And we have an early murder.
[ Door opens and closes ]
Well, it was one thing
when she was living there with Pi,
but now that she's alone,
why not dump the dump and come home?
[ Chuckling ] Well, maybe
she's enjoying her independence.
She doesn't have time for independence.
She's got her tutoring gigs,
her classes, her work-study job.
She's exhausted.
Well, Castle,
I mean, she's strong-willed.
Maybe it's pride.
If it were pride,
she'd be more... well, proud.
No, there's something else...
Another reason
why she's not coming home.
Sito!
Yeah.
Someone miss a check-out?
No, he checked out, all right.
Housekeeping found this guy,
Justin Marquette,
dead in room 147.
His driver's license
says he lives nearby.
Single gunshot to the chest?
One is all it took.
Based on the entry wound,
I'd say a small-caliber handgun.
Lividity and liver temp
put the time of death
between 10:00 P.M. and midnight.
And he wasn't found until morning?
So how come no one heard the shot?
All the neighboring rooms are empty.
The manager says that the place
is only about 40% occupied.
Did the manager mention
him checking in with anyone?
The room was in his name alone.
Ryan's trying to track down
the desk clerk from last night
to see if he can get some more details.
There's no sign of forced entry, though.
So either the killer was with him,
- or the victim let him in.
- Yeah.
It looks like he took a bottle of water
from this mini-fridge,
turned back around, got shot,
and then he took the chair down
with him.
There's no luggage.
You said he lives nearby.
What was he doing here?
I don't know. I checked his phone.
There was no indication of a meeting.
There was no appointments,
calls, or texts
in the hours leading up to his death.
Hey.
[ Sighs ]
Found the desk clerk
who checked in Justin Marquette.
Something's up with this guy.
Jane: Uh, Mr. Marquette
came at about 8:00.
No reservation, which is not unusual.
Jane, tell them about the room.
Well, that was unusual.
He asked to stay in room 147.
In fact, he insisted on it.
Is there anything special about 147?
No, all our rooms are identical.
That's why it was so strange.
Had he been here before?
Well, he's not in the system,
which means he's never been a guest
at any Best Traveler hotel.
Did he mention why he was staying?
He didn't have to.
Good-looking guy, no bags,
checking in for one night?
In my experience, that means
he was here to hook up.
Did he come here with anyone?
No, but he was texting with someone.
I figured that's who he was meeting.
He texted? Are you sure?
We didn't find any texts on his phone.
I'm positive.
There.
See? He's texting.
On a flip phone.
That's not the phone we found.
As far as I can tell,
that's the only cellphone
registered to Justin Marquette.
So the one we saw in the video
must be a second, secret one.
Which the killer took
to hide their identity.
So who is this guy,
why a second phone, and why room 147?
I didn't get much
from hotel security video.
Coverage is sketchy,
and there are no cameras
in the hallway outside Justin's room.
Did you get ahold of next of kin?
Not yet, but I did find out
about our victim
through his personal website.
He's got his own website?
Yeah, he was an actor...
a struggling one,
judging by his credits.
"Justin Marquette"
"is a member
of the Rooster Theater Company"
"and is currently appearing"
"in their off-off-off
Broadway production"
"of Chekhov's 'Platonov.'"
That's a lot of "off" s.
Let's see if anyone down there
knows what he was into.
This is the absolute end.
What's going on out there?
Osip's been lynched by the villagers.
I'm sorry. This is a closed rehearsal.
NYPD. I'm detective Beckett.
We're here about Justin Marquette.
What about Justin? Is he okay?
[ Sniffles ]
We met through the theater company
and started dating three months ago.
[ Sniffles ]
I knew something was wrong
when he didn't show up
for rehearsal today.
And when was the last time you saw him?
Yesterday morning at my place.
We, um... we went for a run,
and then he showered and left for work.
Where did he work?
Temp jobs, mostly.
He wasn't getting much recently,
but he said that he didn't mind,
because...
because it gave him more time
to spend with me.
Any idea what he would be doing
at the Best Traveler Hotel last night?
No... uh, hotel?
He was... he was at a hotel?
[ Sighs ] Look, Laura,
I know this is difficult,
but is it possible that Justin
was seeing someone else?
What? No.
Was he involved in anything
dangerous or illegal?
No, not... not that I know of. No.
Was there anyone in his life
that might have wanted to harm him?
There was that thing
the other day, remember?
What thing?
Some crazy woman walked up
to him on the street
and threatened him.
That's right.
Justin was totally rattled.
He could barely perform that night.
- Did he know who she was?
- Mnh-mnh.
And he did not want to
talk about it, either.
All he said was that it happened
outside a coffee shop
on 9th and Mercer.
Thanks. Hey.
That was the coffee shop.
A barista saw the whole thing go down.
A woman walked up to Justin outside
and started yelling at him.
- You get a description?
- I did better than that.
The woman's a regular customer.
She's got a loyalty card,
and her name's Anita Miller.
I'll send a unit to pick her up.
Great.
Thanks for coming in, Ms. Miller.
I'm detective Beckett.
Uh, I just need to ask you
a few questions about...
Justin Marquette.
So you know him.
I more than know him, detective.
In fact... I killed him.
Are you confessing?
Just give me some paper.
I want to write it all down.
Yeah.
[ Door opens ]
11 seconds to a confession.
That's got to be your personal best.
[ Laughs ]
You sound like
you're disappointed, Castle.
Well, I am, a little.
I mean, a secret phone, room 147...
this case had conspiratorial promise.
Well, most likely Justin was cheating
on his girlfriend with Anita,
and the two of them met up at the hotel,
and that's where things went south.
Yes, well, most likely, that is boring.
Look, not every case
has to be shrouded
in mystery and intrigue.
Yo.
Uh, we got a problem.
What's wrong?
Well, I was looking into
Anita Miller's whereabouts
to try to tie her to the hotel,
except her credit-card records
show that she was at
Le Fagio restaurant last night.
So maybe someone else
used her credit card.
Nah. The manager I.D.'d her.
And he said that she split
the bill with another guy,
her A.A. sponsor.
I just spoke to him, and he confirmed
that they were together
from 9:30 P.M. to 12:30 A.M.
But that's our entire
time-of-death window.
If that's true,
then Anita can't be our killer.
Then why is she confessing?
Not so boring after all.
Castle 6x16 - Room 147
Original air date February 24, 2014
Sync and corrections by atrn97g
for www.addic7ed.com
So, Anita Miller
is confessing to the murder,
and she has an alibi.
Yeah, we're still trying
to make sense of it, sir.
Is it possible that we misjudged
the time of death?
No. No, Lanie stands behind
her examination.
Okay, then, what about the alibi?
Esposito verified it
with the restaurant.
The manager, the hostess,
even the waiter
confirmed that Anita
was there all evening.
Not only that,
but this restaurant
is nowhere near the hotel.
Then she couldn't
have killed the victim,
so find out why she's lying.
It's all there, everything
I remember about what I did.
Well, we just wanted
to go over this in person,
just to clear up any discrepancies.
What discrepancies?
Well, why don't you
just tell us what happened?
Well, I went to see him in his room.
Which room was that?
Room 147.
Room 147?
At the Best Traveler Hotel.
[ Knock on door ]
I knocked on the door.
He opened it almost immediately.
Been waiting for you. Come on in.
Let me get you a water.
He offered me a bottle of water,
and then he went to the mini-fridge.
That's when I took out the gun.
He turned around
to give me the water, and I...
I shot him.
I shot him in the chest.
And then what happened?
He looked surprised.
He staggered back.
He dropped the bottle of water,
and he kind of gripped onto
the back of this chair.
Then he fell and knocked it over.
That's exactly
how we found the crime scene.
She must've been there.
How? How is that possible?
Anita, what was your relationship
with Justin Marquette?
My relationship?
Were the two of you involved?
Uh, I don't think so.
Then how did you know him?
I'm not sure.
If you don't know how you knew him,
then why would you kill him?
I'm an alcoholic.
He was responsible for my drinking.
How was he responsible?
[ Sighs ]
I don't know. I'm... I'm sorry.
I've been really confused lately.
Because of the drinking.
No, I've been sober for four years.
[ Sighs ]
I mean, God knows I still struggle,
but these last two weeks,
they've just been really... blurry.
Do you remember going to dinner
with your sponsor last night?
Was that last night?
Mm-hmm.
Yes, you're right. It was.
So, then, when did you go to
the hotel and meet Justin?
I don't remember.
Anita, we have a witness
that saw you accost Justin
outside of a coffee shop
a couple of days ago.
- Do you remember that?
- Yes, I do.
Uh, he was talking
to this big, bald man.
I had to warn Justin,
to tell him he was in danger.
- From the bald man.
- No, from me.
The moment I saw Justin,
I just had this awful feeling
that I was gonna hurt him.
And I did.
All right. Thanks.
No... no one at the hotel
saw Anita last night,
and tech can't find her in any
of the security-cam footage.
This doesn't make any sense.
She knows details about our crime
that only our killer could know.
What about forensics?
Did CSU come up with anything?
In a hotel room in New York City?
[ Groans ]
They found all kinds of fun stuff,
but nothing that tied Anita
back to room 147.
Ryan: You know, maybe it's an act,
you know, some kind of smokescreen,
and she's taking the fall
for someone else.
Except she had to have known
that we would check her alibi,
which completely contradicts
her confession.
Hmm.
All right. Come on.
Hmm?
Give us one of your theories, bro.
- Come on.
- And whatever it is, it can't be any crazier
than what we're already dealing with.
[ Clears throat ]
Okay.
I think...
I'm man enough to admit
I'm completely theory-less.
Maybe Anita suffered
some kind of psychotic break.
I've ordered a psych eval,
but psychosis doesn't explain
how she knew all about the murder.
Or why she killed the guy
in the first place.
I double-checked her phone records.
There's not a single call or text
between her and Justin Marquette.
It's like they had no history at all.
Okay, why don't you guys
go over to her apartment
and check everything...
e-mails, calendars, her diary...
and let's see
if we can find anything there
that'll connect her to our victim.
We're on it.
Detective Beckett, Mr. Castle,
good to see you.
Thank you so much for coming in,
Dr. Holloway.
I gather you have a patient for me.
Oh, yeah.
Well, we've been through
every room in the house.
No gun, no bloody clothes,
nothing that links Anita back to
that crime scene or to Justin.
Maybe not, but check out her date book.
Some pages have been ripped out,
including all of the last two weeks.
- Two weeks? Wait a minute.
- Yeah.
- That's how long Anita says she's been
feeling "blurry." - Mm-hmm.
Maybe she kept a calendar
on her computer.
[ Mouse clicking ]
Yeah, looks like she did,
but the same two weeks have been erased.
Seems like someone's
trying to cover something up.
Yeah, but who? And what?
As much as I love a good mystery,
a small part of me is hoping
he can give us some clarity
on what the hell is going on.
Uh, speaking of clarity,
what did you mean
when you said that there
might be something else
that's keeping Alexis
from moving back to your loft?
I don't know!
And Alexis won't talk about it, so...
Maybe when Dr. Holloway's
done talking to Anita,
I can get him to talk to Alexis.
[ Door opens ]
Hey. So, what's the verdict?
Based on my examination so far,
I find her to be mentally competent,
if somewhat disoriented.
By all indications, she seems
to be telling the truth.
Meaning she did kill Justin Marquette?
Or she believes she did, anyway.
And what about the disorientation?
How do you account for that?
Could be medical
or a neurologic condition,
adverse reaction to drugs.
It's possible she experienced
a traumatic event
which caused some sort
of retrograde amnesia.
So, traumatic like killing someone?
Potentially.
I'm gonna do a full work-up.
I'll know more
when the results come back.
Thank you, doctor.
So, Anita Miller
believes she killed the victim,
but the facts say she couldn't have.
No, not all the facts.
I mean, we know she accosted
Justin outside the coffee shop,
she confessed to the murder,
and she has intimate knowledge
of the crime.
So, look.
Clearly, we haven't
explained everything, but...
but you believe she killed him.
[ Sighs ]
I think that until something changes,
she's our best suspect.
Detective, there's someone here
you need to talk to.
This is Sam Carson.
Tell her what you told me.
I want to confess to a murder.
I killed Justin Marquette.
I'd say something just changed.
Yeah, it was me.
Don't get me wrong...
it's not like I'm proud of it.
Did I hear right?
Another person
has confessed to this murder?
Yeah, but I just think he's
some kind of attention-seeker.
Yeah... so far, the confession
is just a rehash of the news report.
Mr. Carson, do you realize
that making false statements
to the police is a crime?
I'm telling you the truth.
I killed the guy in his hotel room.
Okay, fine. What room was that?
Um...
[ Sighs ]
147.
It was room 147.
I need you to tell me
exactly what happened.
I was in his room, uh...
No, no. I need details.
Were you hiding in the closet?
Did you kick down the door?
No. I knocked.
Been waiting for you. Come on in.
Let me get you a water.
He let me in, offered me a water.
Beckett: A water?
Yeah, like, a bottle.
Then he... he went to the fridge.
That's when I pulled out my gun.
He turned around, and I shot him...
right in the chest.
And then what?
He fell back, grabbed for a chair,
knocked it over when he fell down.
Then I left.
Why did you kill him?
Why?
Yeah.
'Cause I was angry.
I got anger issues, you know?
And when I saw him,
I was just so filled with rage.
Because he did what to you?
That's... that's the part
I'm not too clear on.
The last... last couple of weeks
have been just kind of hazy.
How did you know the victim?
I don't... I don't know that I do.
Okay.
[ Inhales sharply ]
He filled you with rage,
and you don't know him?
- Did he contact you?
- I don't remember.
How do you not remember?
What kind of game are you playing here?
- I'm not playing any game!
- You know what I think you're doing?
You're trying to sabotage my case!
You know that no D.A.
is going to get a conviction
with multiple confessions!
Multiple confessions?
Yeah, you and Anita Miller
are working together on this.
You're either covering for each other,
or you're covering
for someone else out there.
Who the hell is Anita Miller?
You know who she is.
I've never seen that woman
before in my life.
I'm telling you, I don't know him.
Are you sure about that?
Because Sam told us
the same story you did,
but that he killed Justin.
Well, he's lying.
I killed Justin Marquette.
So, we can't find a link
between Sam and Anita,
or between either one of them
and our victim.
What about Sam's alibi?
His brother says that he and Sam
were at the batting cages
all last night.
And based on the security video,
Sam never set foot in the hotel.
They both believe they killed Justin,
they both know details about the murder,
and they both have
similar memory problems.
I mean, they must be connected.
What if their lives intersect,
just not in such a...
literal sense?
No. Castle, no. Please.
If this is some
alternate-universe theory,
I'm not in the mood.
Really?
Alternate universe...
that's how little you think of me.
I'm sorry. I'm... I'm sorry.
I just... I thought that you...
No, they're psychically linked.
And not just to each other,
but to the actual killer.
See, they're seeing the crime
through his or her eyes.
And the experience is so visceral
that both Sam and Anita
think that they committed
the crime themselves.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm sorry. It's just, you got excited.
- It's kind of cute.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know how I like the weird stuff.
[ Cellphone chimes ]
Who's that?
Oh, uh, it's nobody. Nothing.
It's... it's nothing.
Officer: - Detective?
- Uh...
We got another one.
Another what?
I'm Dwight Carruthers, CPA.
I'm here to turn myself in...
...for killing Justin Marquette.
No.
All right. This is now
officially... outstanding.
Hey. You guys need to see this.
Wait, I... I need to confess.
Yeah, take a number.
Once we realized that someone might've
gone through Anita's apartment,
we had UNIs canvass the area.
Now, one of Anita's neighbors
remembers seeing a red van
parked outside her place
about two weeks ago.
Right when she started
feeling disoriented.
Yeah, not only that, we checked in
with Sam Carson's neighbors.
Turns out, one of them remembers
seeing the same red van
parked outside of Carson's house
a few nights later.
She remembers it because she
thought it looked suspicious.
Did you get a plate number?
No, but she took a picture
with her phone.
Take a look who's behind the wheel.
Is that...
A big, bald man,
just like the one Anita said she saw
talking to our victim
outside the coffee shop.
So our victim and two suspects
do have something in common.
Yeah... him.
- So, now there are three of them.
- Yes, sir.
But we believe that this man
is the key to our case.
His van was seen outside
both Anita and Sam's apartments,
and Anita I.D.'d him as the guy
that was talking to our victim
outside the coffee shop.
And what is this man's
connection to Mr. Carruthers?
That's what I'm gonna find out.
I... I'm prepared
to take full responsibility
and admit to what I did.
Yes, I'm sure you are.
Now, do you recognize this man?
Don't you want to hear my confession?
Best Traveler Hotel, room 147,
Justin offered you water,
and then you shot him.
How... how did you know?
Beckett? Just like the one Anita drew.
Dwight, what does that symbol mean?
I... uh, uh, I don't... I don't know.
It's just been stuck in my head lately.
But what difference does that make?
- I... I shot a guy!
- We know.
Now, can you take a close look
at these pictures
and tell me if you recognize that man?
Uh... no, but the van looks familiar.
You've seen it before? Where?
Uh, I'm not sure.
I've... I've been...
Confused recently,
like the last two weeks?
Dwight, think. This is important.
Uh...
it... it was last Tuesday...
a... around noon.
I was coming home from...
assertiveness training,
and... and that van
was parked on Houston street
outside my apartment.
There are traffic cams on Houston.
They might've caught a plate number.
Um... seriously?
I killed someone,
and all you care about is a van?
All right. Techs scrubbed
traffic cam footage
from last Tuesday on Houston.
They got a hit on our vehicle.
It's registered to a Miles Madsen.
Great. That's our guy.
So, what do we know about him?
That he's in the wind...
uniforms hit his apartment,
but the landlord said
he hasn't seen Madsen in weeks.
[ Cellphone chimes ]
[ Sighs ] Okay, put out an APB.
Find out everything you can about him.
Right now, he's the only link
connecting all these people.
Where you going?
Uh, I've got an errand to run.
Can you tell Castle
that I'll be back in an hour?
Yeah. Thanks.
Hey.
Thanks for meeting with me.
Yeah. What's so important?
Um...
You know that I don't take sides
on anything
between you and your dad, right?
Yeah. I appreciate that.
Okay, well...
your dad wants you to move back home.
And I know that you said
you have a lease,
but you also said
that there were other reasons
why you didn't want to
move back, and I... I just...
I want to make sure that one
of those reasons isn't me.
Oh, no.
No, no, it's... it's not you at all.
Are you sure?
'Cause the last thing I want to do
is make you feel unwelcome
in your own home.
No, it's... not you, it's me.
All those things my dad said
when I was moving out...
about me making a mistake
moving in with my boyfriend...
he was right.
[ Sighs ]
I can see it so clearly now.
Why didn't I then?
You were in the love haze.
The love haze?
It's like a drug!
It makes intelligent people
do stupid things.
Then it clears, and you look around,
and you wonder, "what was I thinking?"
Your dad just wants to help.
It's okay to let him.
Yes, but this was my mistake.
He shouldn't have to pay for it,
so I will tutor
and do whatever I have to
until the lease is up.
Okay.
I get it.
[ Sighs ] Look.
I know what you're doing
seems noble, but it's not.
I mean, the long hours,
the exhaustion...
what you're actually doing
is punishing yourself.
Trust me. I've been there.
This... this isn't necessary.
Your dad loves you.
He worries about you.
I think your penance is paid.
[ Cellphone chimes ]
[ Sighs ]
I'm sorry. I have to go.
Uh, just think about it, okay?
I'll see you.
[ Elevator bell dings ]
Hey, did you guys find Madsen?
No, but we're getting close.
We figured out that he's
an independent contractor
for Apollo Pinnacle, Inc.
Ryan: Which turns out to be a front
for another organization called E.H.I.,
or Eternal Horizons Institute.
And what is that?
Well, to quote their website,
"E.H.I. provides sanctuary,
enlightenment,"
"and pathways to the ultimate self."
They claim to have thousands
of followers all over the world.
But not all of them
are satisfied customers.
In 2005, three of those followers died
in some kind of sweat-lodge initiation.
Charges were filed, but, ultimately,
the deaths were ruled accidental.
Followers? Initiations?
This thing sounds like a cult.
Oh, it's a cult, all right,
complete with charismatic
and sinister leader,
brought to you courtesy
of this recruitment video.
[ Ethereal music playing ]
Hello, and welcome.
My name is Dr. Gustavo Bauer,
founder of
the Eternal Horizons Institute.
Dr. Gustavo Bauer?
So, what is he a doctor of?
Says here he holds a PHD
in trans-personal psychology.
From Never-Heard-Of-It University.
...bio-cognitive program
to help free you
from the negative anchors
holding you down
so you can soar.
Visit us at one of
the Eternal Horizon Institute's
many reception centers
and take the first step
at becoming the person
you were truly meant to be.
Wait for it.
That's the symbol that Anita
and Dwight were drawing.
Yes, and the boys checked.
Sam's been drawing it, as well.
Okay, so, the three of them
must have been a part of
whatever the hell this thing is.
That's our connection.
Except we asked each of them.
They all denied being members.
Yeah, but they also said that
they killed Justin Marquette,
and we know
that that's not true, either.
So, where is this E.H.I.?
Right here in the city... Midtown.
This case is exceeding
even my lofty expectations.
An impossible murder
connected to a shadowy
and mysterious cult.
Not to mention prosperous.
This is prime Manhattan real estate.
[ Elevator bell dings ]
Hi. We're here to see Dr. Bauer.
- I'm...
- Detective Beckett.
Richard Castle.
Welcome to E.H.I.
Dr. Bauer's expecting you.
How? We didn't make an appointment.
Dr. Bauer's a brilliant man.
Right this way.
He's just inside.
Yeah, uh...
No, he's not!
On the contrary.
Whoa.
[ Chuckling ]
That is so... Big Brother.
Greetings, detective Beckett,
Mr. Castle.
What can I do for you?
Well, uh, you could start
by speaking to us in person.
Regrettably, I'm in Stockholm,
conducting a seminar.
Okay. Well, then...
do you know this man, Justin Marquette?
I'm afraid not.
What about this man, Miles Madsen?
I understand he works for you.
Mr. Madsen has not been employed
by E.H.I. for some time...
years, in fact.
Well, what did Mr. Madsen do
when he worked for you?
Since he is no longer in my employ,
I don't see the relevance.
The relevance
is that he is connected
to a murder investigation.
I'm struck by the level
of your hostility, detective.
It's not healthy.
You know what I'm struck by
is your total lack of curiosity
as to why a homicide detective
is asking about your employee.
Former employee.
Well, whatever he is, he is
definitely involved in this case,
along with three other members
of your... little group...
Anita Miller, Sam Carson,
Dwight Carruthers.
I'm sorry, detective.
Those people are not part of E.H.I.
Wow. That's...
amazing how you would just know that
off the top of your head.
I make a point of meeting every
member of my E.H.I. family.
The people you mentioned
are not among them.
Well, then, I'm sure you won't mind
if we check your files,
along with the records
that you have on Miles Madsen.
You'd need a warrant for that, detective,
and you won't get one.
What's that?
They're ready.
I'm sorry. My session is starting.
Jasmine will show you out.
No. Dr. Bauer, I... uh...
Right this way.
Bauer was right.
The judge turned us down
for a search warrant.
You really think E.H.I.'s
grand pooh-bah is behind this?
I think that he knows where Madsen is
and that Madsen
is still working for him.
But doing what?
And what does any of this have to do
with a struggling actor
like Justin Marquette?
- Huh.
- "Huh" what?
Uh, the E.H.I. website...
the testimonials claim
that they have programs
that help people quit smoking,
quit drinking, uh,
take charge of their lives.
So?
So, all three of our confessors
have had problems in their
lives... uh, alcoholism,
anger management,
assertiveness issues...
all things that they could've
gone through E.H.I. to treat.
But they all claim that they didn't.
But what if they did?
What if they did,
but something made E.H.I.
want to eliminate
any record of their involvement?
Torn date-book pages, wiped calendars.
Maybe that's why Madsen
went to their apartments...
to erase any trace
of their connection to E.H.I.
Castle, you can't just do that
by wiping out calendars.
You'd have to... wipe memories.
Think about it.
The fogginess, the confusion
over the last two weeks.
So y... you're saying that
a glorified self-help group
can erase people's memories? How?
With drugs.
Anita Miller's tests came back.
Found unusual levels
of a Propranolol derivative
in her system,
so I tested Mr. Carson
and Mr. Carruthers.
It was in their blood, as well.
Propranolol?
In small doses, it's mainly
a blood-pressure drug.
In high doses, it's been found
to alter memories,
even eliminate them.
If it can alter memories,
could it make someone believe
they had done something
they actually hadn't?
Under normal circumstances,
the human brain is very suggestible.
Combined with a drug like this,
I'd say it's entirely possible.
[ Cellphone rings ]
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
Outstanding.
This is straight out of "Inception."
Someone planted the memory of the murder
in all three of their heads,
while erasing any knowledge
of their connection to E.H.I.
Castle, do you have any idea
how insane that sounds?
It's a diabolical plan.
Have three suspects
confess to the same crime,
making it impossible
for the police to arrest anyone.
But none of this explains
how they all knew the details
of the murder
without actually being there.
Maybe... they were there,
just... not in person.
What if Justin's killer
filmed the murder
and then showed it to these people
while they were in
their drug-induced state?
They would think the images were drawn
from their own experience.
If they were shown the actual murder,
then that makes
all three of them witnesses.
With details of the crime
that could lead to our real killer.
I'm telling you,
I pulled the trigger myself.
So did I.
Look, I understand
that it seems real to you,
but it may not be.
But why would somebody do this to us?
To get away with murder.
We just need you to tell us
everything you "remember"
about being in that hotel room,
down to the last overheard whisper or...
or glimpse of a shadow in a mirror.
Now, keep in mind that what
seems like a minor detail to you
may actually be the key
to us solving this case.
So, let's start with Anita.
The first thing I remember
is knocking on the door of 147.
After a few seconds, Justin opened it.
He smiled flirtatiously, and...
okay, he did not flirt with me.
No, he was businesslike.
And, uh, what did you see
when you went in the room?
I remember the carpet. It was beige.
The wallpaper
had a subtle floral pattern,
and there was a painting
above the fridge.
I... I think it was a landscape.
Yeah, of a countryside.
And when he pulled out
the bottle of water from the fridge,
I remember there were six other bottles
in the fridge door there.
No, there were five.
I remember that clear as day.
Nuh-unh. There were six.
I remember five, too.
See? I know what I saw.
[ Chuckles ]
You saw wrong.
- There were five.
- He saw five. I saw five. You saw what?
Castle, if they can't agree
on the details,
then I don't think
we're gonna learn anything here.
Au contraire.
We've already learned something
very, very important.
Come with me.
Where we going?
Back to the hotel.
You guys are clearly lying, okay?
I...
Come on, Castle.
Could you just tell me
what this is all about?
Not until I know I'm right.
Which...
I am.
You should know
you're engaged to a genius.
Yes, a genius at annoying me.
So, I'm Justin,
and you are one of
the several people who shot me.
I'm starting to feel the urge.
I go to get you a bottle
of water, and...
tell me how many bottles
do you see in the fridge?
None. The door's blocking it.
Exactly.
Which means Anita, Sam, or Dwight
couldn't have seen it, either.
Whatever they saw...
It didn't happen in this room!
Okay, if they didn't witness
the actual murder,
then what did they see?
Something that happened
at another Best Traveler Hotel
i... in another room 147.
We checked other branches in the area.
Now, three weeks ago,
the Best Traveler in Long Island City
rented an entire floor,
including room 147, to E.H.I.
Their room 147 is identical
to the one where we found our victim.
Except that fridge opens exactly
like our witnesses described it.
What was E.H.I. doing there?
They told the hotel it was
some kind of member event.
But they brought their own security,
and they kept hotel staff
off the floor for hours.
Something happened that day,
something connected to Justin's murder,
that E.H.I. wants everyone to forget.
[ Knock on door ]
I got something.
All right, so I was going
through surveillance footage
of the Best Traveler Inn
in Long Island City.
I wanted to see if any
of our three confessors
did attend that E.H.I. event.
And...?
No sign of them, but I did see this.
- That's our victim.
- And look who he's with.
Dr. Bauer lied to us.
He did know Justin.
We got enough for a warrant now?
[ Police radio chatter ]
Please, you can't take those files!
Really? That's not what my warrant says.
Now, where's Dr. Bauer?
I told you, he's in Stockholm!
Where in Stockholm? What hotel?
I don't know!
He didn't leave a contact number!
Detective, I traced the signal
from Bauer's video conference
with detective Beckett.
So where in Stockholm is he?
That's the thing.
The signal was routed through Stockholm,
but it looks like it originated
from a local I.P. address.
Local, as in Manhattan?
As in inside this building.
Where?
[ Scoffs quietly ]
You can't go back there!
This... this area's restricted!
That one.
Don't move!
So this is Stockholm.
All right. Yes. I knew him.
But I know nothing about his death.
And yet you were shredding files,
files on Anita, Sam, Dwight, Madsen...
all people connected with this case.
What happened that day?
Why were you there with Justin?
All we did was make a film.
A film?
I didn't kill Justin.
I hired him as an actor.
[ Sighs ]
[ Knock on door ]
It was part of
our image therapy pilot program.
Been waiting for you. Come on in.
Let me get you a water.
[ Mini-fridge door opens ]
[ Pop ]
Bang.
[ Groans ]
The viewer was supposed to
project their problems on a person...
in this case, Justin.
That's why Anita blamed him
for her drinking,
and... and why he was the focus
of Sam's anger issues.
I knew it. You were implanting memories.
No!
No, it was supposed to
help them take control
of their problems
by literally shooting them dead.
We... we made two versions,
one for women and another for men.
For the therapy to work,
we had to put subjects
in a chemically induced suggestive state
while showing them this footage,
uh, but it was just too real.
They began to internalize
the experience.
And then they... they started to believe
they'd actually killed Justin.
We... we halted the program immediately.
But the damage was already done.
They threatened to sue.
They said we were using them
as Guinea pigs.
Which you were.
We tried to help them.
We brought them back
for one final session
to... correct the problem.
And by correcting,
you mean dosing them with Propranolol
so that they would forget
they ever visited E.H.I.?
We were just trying to help people.
Is that why you sent madsen
after Justin... to "help" him?
Madsen only talked with Justin
to remind him
of the confidentiality agreement
that prohibited him
from talking about the program.
We knew nothing about his murder.
And yet his death was staged
to mirror that video exactly.
Why would we do that
when we were just trying
to make this go away?
No, no, no, no, no.
Someone's targeting us,
someone who knew about that tape
and knew they could use it against us.
Uh, uh, one of the other test subjects,
someone on the crew.
I'm gonna need a list
of all of the people
that knew about that video.
Pam: Be sure not to step
any further downstage,
or the backdrop will smack you
in the head when it flies in.
[ Chuckles ]
Roger that.
Detective Beckett.
Do you have news about Justin's case?
We do.
We now believe that Justin was killed
because of a video that he acted in.
A video?
It was made for an organization
called E.H.I.,
and it just so happens it was
edited by Kahn Post Production.
Eddie: Kahn Post?
Pam, isn't that where your day job is?
Yeah, but I don't know about any video.
We think you do.
And when you saw the video,
you saw an opportunity.
Pam, we checked your credit card.
We know that
you just bought a flip phone.
So?
So just before Justin died,
he was texting someone on a flip phone,
presumably his killer.
Beckett: When we looked into
the phone records,
there were texts supposedly
from E.H.I. to Justin,
offering him $5,000 to
reprise his role in that video.
I'm betting that you gave Justin
that phone,
probably told him someone from E.H.I.
dropped by, wanted him to have it.
But it wasn't E.H.I. that
sent those texts. It was you.
You lured him to that hotel,
and then you killed him.
Wait. This is crazy.
[ Chuckles ]
Justin was my friend.
Why would I do that?
We checked your background, Pam.
One of the men that was killed
in that E.H.I. sweat-lodge
initiation was Alan Clark...
your brother.
E.H.I. was to blame,
but no one was held accountable.
His death was ruled accidental.
And when you watched that video,
you realized you had the perfect
chance to take them down.
But you knew that you needed Justin
in order to pull it off,
so you found a way to get close to him.
Oh, my God. That's why you
joined our theater company.
Pam, what did you do?
You don't understand.
I had to do it...
for Alan, for the others.
Those monsters had to be stopped.
By killing an innocent man?
Justin was not innocent.
He was one of them.
He was just an actor, hired for the day.
Then why did he stonewall me
when I tried to talk to him about it?!
They are all accountable!
Somebody had to stop them!
Somebody had to show the world
what they really are!
Pam, turn around. You're under arrest.
[ Handcuffs clicking ]
Carson: So all of this
was about revenge?
Yeah, and, unfortunately,
you just got caught in the middle.
What about Dr. Bauer?
E.H.I. has been shut down,
effective immediately,
and the FBI is launching
a full-scale investigation.
And the guy in the red van,
the one who drugged us?
Border patrol caught him
trying to cross into Canada.
He's being extradited back here now.
Carruthers: What I don't understand
is what made us come in when we did,
all on the same day.
Dr. Holloway figures
it was some kind of trigger.
Maybe you read an article on the murder
or you saw something on TV.
Yeah, but whatever it was,
it's over now.
You're all free to go.
Dwight, are you okay?
Uh, it's... it's nothing.
No, what?
I just never got to confess.
Well, if it makes you
feel better, I'll hear it.
Yeah. Me, too. Come on.
I'll buy us all a slice.
Okay, uh...
[ Chuckles ]
So, I... I walk up to room 147,
knock on the door...
If I have to hear
that confession one more time,
I'm gonna shoot somebody.
Here's a little something
to help you forget.
[ Chuckles ]
It's okay, Castle.
You know I like the weird ones.
Mmm.
It's interesting
how malleable the human mind is.
I mean, all those people
wanted was a little help.
But instead, they became Guinea pigs,
all because they turned to
the wrong person for answers.
Yeah, well, sometimes it's hard to know
who the right person is.
After all, it took you three tries.
True, but I figured it out,
and you didn't even have to drug me.
How do you know what I do to you
when you're sleeping?
Whoa.
Well, whatever it is,
wake me up for it next time.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Knock on door ]
Excuse me.
Alexis.
What's going on?
Dad...
[Sighs]
can I come home?
Come here.
[ Chuckles ]
Sync and corrections by atrn97g
for www.addic7ed.com