Previously on
"Once Upon a Time"
It was Excalibur.
it was just a small cut.
A wound from it
cannot be healed.
I can use
the Promethean Flame
to release you
from Excalibur,
and then I can tether
hook's life to it instead.
[straining] I'm not as strong
as you are.
I've succumbed
to darkness.
But our future.
Really?
[sword clangs, whooshing]
I found this
outside.
I suppose it's not
the Dark One...
more like the Dark Ones.
Are you ready to learn what else
happened in Camelot?
Aye. But first we have to
take care of her.
Get on with it, Captain.
That quid ink's
going to wear off soon.
[Emma] Killian, please.
What are you doing?
You took
my memories, Swan.
You tried to stop me
from knowing the truth.
And now I'm going
to return the favor.
[whooshing, tinkling]
[laughs]
By the look
on your face,
it would appear someone
needs restraining.
There.
No more magic
for you.
Now, I assume,
given my helpfulness,
you'll allow me to go about
my business undeterred.
As long as you don't get
in my way,
I won't get in yours.
Ah. I like this
new you.
Tell me, how does it feel
to be a Dark One?
It feels like
I've been reborn.
[soft grunting]
♪♪
[whooshing]
[screaming]
[slashing sound]
[Hook screaming]
Milah!
You're no less
a coward.
- [Rumple] I want you to suffer.
- [Hook] Just do it.
[Rumple] I promised you
we'd have some fun first.
[Hook] Emma, please!
[squelching, bubbling]
♪♪
[squelching, bubbling continue]
Hi.
Bloody crocodile.
Not exactly, but I understand
the confusion.
[yells]
That's not gonna work.
I'm not out here.
I'm in there.
I am your guide...
The voice in your head.
Save your speech.
I know who you are.
All the Dark Ones
in my head.
But it doesn't matter...
I won't listen to you.
What if I told you
that together,
I could get you
the one thing
you've wanted for hundreds
of years?
Your revenge.
[giggles]
That's right.
I saw what you saw, dearie.
I saw your pain.
And I can ease it.
Stick with me
and you will finally do
what you never
could before.
And what's that?
Why, kill me,
of course.
Once Upon a Time S05E10
"Broken Heart"
Sync and corrected by
Gianluca Belfiglio
[Mary Margaret] Emma!
- [David] I'll check the basement.
- [Regina] I'll get the upstairs.
Emma! Emma!
Emma. Hey.
What happened?
You turned Hook
into a Dark One?
It was the only way
to save him.
And you didn't think of the
consequences to everyone else?
I couldn't
just let him die.
You can understand that.
Well, yes, but...
[sighs] now we have
a bigger problem.
I know.
I didn't think any of this
would happen.
I was trying to get rid
of the darkness for good.
You can't tell me, after all
Zelena's done to you,
your life wouldn't be easier
if she were gone.
I was doing you
a favor.
[Mary Margaret] Come on.
This is premeditated murder,
Emma.
There had to be another way.
You should have come to us.
And risk losing
someone else?
I thought the best way
to control the darkness
was to isolate myself.
But when I did that,
there was no one around
to give me hope or tell me
when I was being stupid!
Fine. You're being stupid.
So stop it.
Right now, we have to
clean up this mess.
No. We don't.
Give us back
our memories.
Your dreamcatchers...
Regina can access them,
can't she?
We can piece together
Hook's plan and stop him.
I'm afraid not.
Dreamcatchers you said
were in the shed...
they're gone.
What the hell is
Captain Dark One up to?
[Belle] Emma turned you
into a Dark One?
And now you've come
for your revenge.
[Hook] The thought
had crossed my mind.
For this lovely piece
of hardware,
I think
I'll take your hand.
For Milah, your heart.
For filling Emma
with the darkness...
hmm, I think your head
will do quite nicely.
So what are you waiting for?
Get on with it.
No, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no. no.
I've been waiting centuries
for this moment.
And I really want to...
[breathes deeply]
...savor it.
[sword clangs]
Get your affairs
in order, dearie,
for we duel at noon
on my ship.
Where it all began.
[Gold] How poetic.
But we both know this weapon
cannot kill you.
Ah, true.
That sword can't kill me.
But this one... can.
Excalibur.
You have it.
Aye.
Well, now that it's whole,
it can no longer control me.
But it can... oh, oh, oh!
Kill me.
All you have to do
is take it from me.
So, what say you,
crocodile?
Shall we finish
what we started?
Indeed.
Once a pirate,
always a pirate.
As a man, Hook spent centuries
trying to kill me.
It makes sense that revenge
would be on his mind.
Why wipe my memory
if he was
going to announce
his plan anyway?
There must be
more to it.
Yeah, well,
even if there is,
we only have until noon
to stop him.
And to save you.
What about
Merlin's message?
He said this "Nimue" is the key
to stopping the Dark One.
Nimue was
Merlin's true love.
And she was also
the first Dark One.
I know.
How do we find out
more about her?
Start your search
with the Dark One chronicles.
There are many texts
that can help us.
As much as I appreciate
devotion to scholarship,
there is an easier way.
I am still a Dark One.
I can protect you,
Gold.
You just have to
take off the cuff.
[Gold chuckles]
You don't trust me.
Well, if the situations were
reversed, would you trust me?
So it's true.
You're here.
[Emma] Henry.
I need you to tell them it's
okay to take off this cuff.
It's the only way
to figure it all out.
No.
What?
You lied to us... about Hook,
about everything.
Why should we
trust you now?
Henry,
I'm your mother.
Are you?
Because the mom I knew
wouldn't keep things from me.
I thought you were the one
person who would understand.
person I could trust.
So you can forgive
Regina and Gold
for everything they've done,
but not me?
They've changed.
They showed me
they changed.
So did I.
When
we first met, yeah.
But the minute things got tough,
you didn't come to anybody.
You decided that you would
figure it out on your own.
We were a team.
"Operation Cobra."
I remember.
But now you just want
your dark magic back
so you can do it alone.
And I've seen what you do
with dark magic.
[Regina] He needs time,
Emma.
[Belle] We should really get
to the library.
We've got
a lot to do.
[Regina] I have a stop
to make first.
I'll meet you there.
Let me guess...
I'm not invited.
Emma.
We love you.
You don't trust me.
We don't trust
the darkness.
Stay here
and let us save you.
It's for the best.
[Merlin] There's nothing
we can do.
It's too late.
The vault has already forged
Hook as its new Dark One.
He went this way.
This way!
And then
the tracks disappear.
We should split up,
search the woods.
He's a Dark One.
He can transport himself
anywhere.
So can Emma.
We've got to start
looking somewhere.
[Merlin] There's
no time.
Of all the paths I foresaw
for your daughter,
I'm afraid that
this was the darkest.
[crickets chirping]
[night animals calling]
We should return
to Granny's.
Even without
my magic,
I still have enough ingredients
to make preparations.
I don't care how bad
things got...
- Emma wouldn't hurt us.
- Maybe.
But this new
Dark One,
we need as many allies
as we can get.
Lancelot, your mother's
the Lady of the Lake.
Could she help us?
- Perhaps.
- Perhaps?
[sighs]
[Merlin] Lancelot,
you should go.
She does have
great power.
The lake is but a two-day
journey from here.
It's worth a try.
And if I don't
make it in time?
Well,
then you get to spend
your last moments
with your mother.
We were so close,
Mary Margaret.
Emma was
seconds away
from destroying the darkness
and ending this.
And Hook
would have been dead.
She chose love,
David.
And we would have done
the same thing.
We'd share
one heart
because we took the same kind
of risk that Emma took.
We save each other.
That is what our family does.
So have some
faith in her.
I do.
I just hope her faith in Hook
is justified.
What the devil
am I wearing?
Why must Dark Ones
dress like monks?
[puffing, whooshing]
Yes, much better.
I went leather as well.
Get out of here.
[puffing]
Try to ignore me.
bet you can't.
Talk all you want, spirit.
I know you're lying.
There's no way that
I can get my revenge
when Gold's in Storybrooke and
I'm trapped here in Camelot.
Well, that's where
we come in, dearie.
Might I suggest
a dark curse?
And crush the heart of the one
I love most to enact it?
No, no, no.
I won't kill Emma.
Yeah, but there's always
a loophole.
Killian! It worked!
- You're alive!
- Aye. It did.
After spending centuries
quelling my bloodlust,
you threw me right back
into that darkness!
Job well-done, Emma!
Binding you to Excalibur
was the only way to save you.
Right, Excalibur.
And where is my shiny
new tether?
I don't know. It disappeared
right after you did...
Ah.
Isn't that convenient?
How long has he been
with you?
You can still see him?
Sadly, yes.
I mean, she's still a Dark One.
No matter how ineffectual
she may be.
Don't listen to him.
He's not real.
But I am.
I'm right here.
Look at me.
That future you told me
not to be afraid of...
we can have it.
The house in
Storybrooke.
I'm not afraid
anymore.
I want it.
With you.
It's ours.
You just have
to want it, too.
Aye, love, I do.
More than anything.
Killian...
look.
♪♪
[crickets chirping]
[gasps]
The demon's gone.
We can do this.
We can get the darkness
out of both of us for good.
How?
By doing what I just did
with you.
By going to those
we love.
♪♪
Rumple?
What's wrong?
Aren't you coming?
I'm afraid my preparations
for this battle
can't be found
in a book.
Well,
but this was your idea.
For you
and the others,
there might be some way
to protect yourself.
For me...
I've spent an entire life
running away from battles.
Time to stop.
You don't have anything
to prove anymore.
You saved me
from Merida.
You're a hero now.
But that doesn't erase
a lifetime of cowardice...
Nothing can.
Belle...
I know that I've hurt you
in unforgivable ways.
But I also know
that not wanting me to die
isn't the same
as wanting to be with me.
So if I survive this,
I want to do better by you.
I want to love you in a way
I never could before.
With honesty
and courage.
Let me be the man
you deserve.
The man I swore on my son's
grave that I would be.
I... I don't know
what to say.
Don't say anything.
If I win...
If I win, I go to the well
where we were married.
And if you meet me there,
I'll know how you feel.
[door thumps]
You!
The mayor told me explicitly
not to let you through.
Well, then,
you're just doing your job.
[whoosh]
Poorly,
but you're doing it.
Kudos to you.
Not so fast, sis.
Sister, dear.
Thank you so much for looking
after my bundle of joy
while I was off
being kidnapped.
But I've come to take
her back now.
- Bye.
- Good luck with that.
[sighing]
Where's
my daughter?!
[chuckling] Did you
really think,
after everything
you've done,
we wouldn't protect
that child from you?
She is my child!
She's also Robin's.
And you will never
take her away from him.
You just can't stand,
that after a lifetime of you
getting everything,
it's finally my turn!
The only reason you have
that baby
is because
you killed Marian
and you deceived Robin
in the most
vile way imaginable.
[scoffs] Is that
a compliment?
This insanity has
to stop.
Agreed.
But I don't think
it can.
Actually,
I think maybe it can.
You know, when Regina asked me
to guard you,
the last thing I wanted to do
was be in the same room as you.
Now that we're here,
this isn't so bad.
[Emma] Put it down,
Merida.
We both know you're not
going to shoot me.
Oh, won't I? After everything
you've done to me.
Fine. I'd say an arrow to the
knee would do you right good.
Maybe me too.
[Hook] Don't worry,
love.
[pulls bow string]
[arrow hissing]
[whoosh]
[Merida gasps]
A broken knee is nothing
on a broken heart.
Isn't that right,
Swan?
What is this?
I expected to find
you and the heroes
huddled over a mountain
of books,
trying to figure out
my terrible plan.
That's not why
you're here.
You're here because you still
have feelings for me.
[sighs] Oh, Swan.
Of course I still have
feelings for you...
Anger.
Hatred.
Disappointment.
You don't mean that.
When you tethered me
to Excalibur,
you opened my eyes.
And I now see you
for what you really are...
An anchor.
[chuckles] And
I see clearly now
that you were
nothing more
than a pretty blonde
distraction.
But guess what, Swan?
I am a free man now.
And you will never
hold me back
from getting
what I want again.
Hook... Killian...
whatever deal you made to get
your revenge on Gold,
it's not worth it.
The darkness is
using you.
It doesn't care
what you want.
It only cares
what it wants.
Well, you're only
a pawn
if you don't know
you're being used.
As long as I get
what I want,
I don't give a damn
about the rest.
And you of all people
should understand that.
Everything I did,
I did for you.
Well, you see,
that's your problem, Swan.
You're so afraid of losing
the people that you love
that you push them
away.
And that's why you'll
always be an orphan.
You don't need some villain
swooping in
to destroy
your happiness.
You do that quite well
all on your own.
Why are you doing
this?
Because...
I want to hurt you...
like you hurt me.
♪♪
[crickets chirping]
[soft moaning, smooches]
[laughs] All right,
enough distractions.
I am going
to go scout our path.
I'll go replenish
our water supply.
[eerie whispering]
Oh, what the devil
is that noise?
[Rumple] That's the sound of the dagger
singing to the sword.
And if you can hear it,
that means Excalibur
is quite close.
No, it's impossible.
Emma said it disappeared.
Wake up, dearie!
Your lover's lying.
She has the sword.
Why would
she lie to me?
So she can
control you.
Not that
she needs Excalibur.
She's quite good at doing that
all on her own.
What the bloody hell
is that supposed to mean?
You!
Get out of here!
Oh, we were just
talking about you.
Why don't you
ask her yourself?
Ask me what?
Hook,
what the hell's going on?
Emma, do you know
where Excalibur is?
[eerie whispering continues]
Killian...
Rumple is manipulating you.
That's what he does.
[panting] Are you lying
to me?
I can hear it calling
to the dagger, Emma.
[whispering continues]
Do you have Excalibur?
Yes.
[puffing, whooshing]
Did you use it
on me?
What?
No, of course not.
I was never...
Then why not
tell me the truth?
Are you afraid I was
gonna ask you for it?
You never planned on giving it
to me, did you?
I did it to protect you.
You told me yourself
you were not strong enough
to resist the darkness.
Which is why I begged you
not to turn me
into the bloody Dark One
in the first place!
But you went
and did it anyway.
[voice breaking] You were dying.
You know the worst part,
Swan?
When your own
mother
wanted to use the dagger
to stop you
from crushing
Merida's heart,
I'm the one
that convinced her
that you needed to make
that decision yourself.
There's never been a moment
where I didn't believe in you,
where
I didn't trust you.
But you clearly don't believe
in me anymore,
so how am I supposed
to fight this?
- Killian...
- Don't.
[whooshing]
[watch ticking]
[sword clangs]
[door opens, bell jingles]
Hello, Dark One.
Sorry the, uh, shop's
in a bit of a mess
since you sent Merida here
to kill Belle.
Forgive me
if I don't offer you tea.
What can I do
for you today?
Because I assume this isn't
just a social visit.
I need help.
to stop Hook,
I need to get everyone's
memories back, including my own.
And how do you plan
on doing that?
Zelena and Hook used squid ink
to immobilize me.
There's still some left.
And you want me to use this
on him during our duel.
All I ask is that
you last long enough
to occupy him while I steal back
the dreamcatchers.
Ah, yes.
But for that...
I don't need this.
This... [keys jingle] is
where that magic belongs.
What are you doing?
[vault lock clicks]
You can't beat
Hook without it.
Well, my feud with the Captain
predates you by centuries.
And if I am gonna beat him,
I'm gonna do it with honor.
And I will.
You're on
a suicide mission.
[scoffing] Oh,
we'll see.
But my stakes...
are me.
Yours are far greater.
Do you really think you can win
on your own?
I know I can.
[laughs]
Here's the thing about
confidence, Miss Swan...
It's great at starting
a fight,
not so great
at finishing one.
Good luck.
[bell jingles, door closes]
Before we go in,
let me remind you that you
may have your powers back,
but I've also got mine.
What are we doing here?
Because if
it's more lectures
about hope, decency,
and redemption,
I can save you the trouble...
I've heard it all.
[baby coos]
- Zelena.
- [Zelena] Did you miss me?
Told you. Once you go green,
you'll never go queen.
- Regina...
- [Regina exhales sharply]
...we talked about this.
Oh, couples therapy?
I should imagine you two
need that now.
Let me remind you
of something.
As wicked as
you may think you are,
you're not even
in my league.
I've spent so many years
doing terrible...
terrible things
beyond your imagination.
But you know how
I turned it around?
Henry.
It took having a child...
That unconditional love...
it made me
my best self.
[scoffs]
And I'm hoping that kind of love
will do the same for you.
[baby coos]
Make no mistake,
Zelena,
we are never gonna be a family,
the three of us.
[scoffs]
But Regina and I
have agreed
you are her mother.
So against
our best instincts,
we still have hope
for you. So...
you can visit
with our child
as long as one of us
are present.
[baby crying]
There, there,
my little green bean.
There, there.
[gasps]
I'm your mommy.
[cries]
[baby coos]
[sighs]
[turning page]
Henry!
Mom.
You escaped?
And for
good reason.
I know how to figure
this all out.
I need your help.
I need you to trust me.
- I told you...
- I know...
I know,
and I heard you.
I really heard you.
I am not asking you
to remove my cuff.
Then how are you gonna do it
without magic?
I'm gonna do it with help.
With you.
Hook stole
the dreamcatchers.
He took
my memories, too,
which means I must know
something.
If we can get it back,
I can help everyone.
And, kid...
no one was ever better
at figuring out
how to break a spell
than you.
"Operation Cobra,"
remember?
[paper rustling]
A locator spell.
There's one
at grandpa's shop.
All I need is the stuff you used
to make the dreamcatchers.
It will take us
to the others.
So you will help me?
I just need
one more thing.
What's that?
A name.
"Operation Cobra,"
part two?
That'll do.
♪♪
[Emma] Killian?
[crickets chirping]
Killian?
[sighs]
[chirping continues]
[puffing]
Dark One,
I summon thee.
[whoosh]
I'm sorry. I didn't know
how else to get you here.
You could have given me
a choice.
We need to talk
about this.
Do you have any idea
how it feels
to not be in control
of yourself?
The last time a Dark One
controlled me,
I had to watch as
Rumplestiltskin almost killed you.
I had to kneel,
powerless,
while he almost crushed
my heart!
I know exactly
how it feels!
All my life, everyone I loved
abandoned me!
- I didn't abandon you.
- I know.
But I was about to lose you
to the darkness.
When I'm scared,
that's when my walls go up.
That's when I stop trusting
the people around me.
You know this.
It doesn't
make it fair, Swan.
Killian, wait!
Ugh!
I didn't mean to do that.
Aye, but you did...
and that's my point!
That's not why
I called you here!
I called you here because
I do believe in you!
I do trust you to control
your own fate!
It's yours
if you want it.
[panting]
We are going to get the darkness
out of both of us.
We are going
to do it together.
[panting]
I promise you,
I will never try
to control you again.
I love you.
What?
It's just I'm usually the one
that has to say that first.
Yeah, well...
I love you, too.
♪♪
[whoosh]
[bell dings once]
[water sloshing]
[sword shimmers]
I wasn't sure
you'd show.
And miss my chance to take
your other hand?
No, this won't do.
This has to be
a fair fight.
I can't have your surviving
family members
blame this loss
on your limp.
[whoosh]
[indistinct bird calling]
[water sloshing]
[cane clatters on floor]
It's been centuries
since I stood here a mortal.
Oh, you mean
when I took Milah?
I remember
thinking that day,
what type
of sad little man
is too afraid to fight
for his own wife?
Yeah, well,
I'm not afraid anymore.
I know I have to fight
for the people I love.
Don't you mean die
for the people you love?
[sword shimmers]
We shall see.
♪♪
[metal clashing]
[fighting grunts]
[blades clang]
[crickets chirping]
There you are!
We've looked everywhere
for you.
[Snow White] Emma.
What happened to you?
Are you okay?
For now.
It looks worse
than it is.
- Are you sure?
- [Hook] Aye.
We're ready to get the sickness
out of us. Where's Merlin?
He's inside.
Well, let's get on
with it, then.
I'll go get him.
wait here.
[water boiling]
If you're receiving this message,
then things are worse than I feared.
There is only
one person
who can help you defeat
the Dark One now.
Her name... [sighs]
is Nimue.
If you want to destroy the
darkness, then you must...
[bell jingles]
[sighs]
The Dark One's found me already.
[door shuts, bell jingles]
[lock clicks]
Heard you preparing
for the worst-case scenario.
I'm sorry, mate.
It's already here.
♪♪
[heart squelching]
[Merlin gasping]
[gasping]
Careful, dearie.
That's the oldest heart
in all the realms.
Let's cut it open
and count the rings.
You're too late.
I've already left a message
for the others.
Well, they can't do anything
to stop me.
Not while I have this.
Excalibur.
What do you want?
My revenge.
And for that,
I need to get back
to Storybrooke.
Do you want
to cast a curse?
It's not possible.
Not without crushing the heart
of the thing you love most.
Which is why I am
not going to crush it.
But someone else will...
Someone who might actually have
feelings for you, dearie.
And that's not me.
But it is me.
- Nimue.
- Remember?
I am all Dark Ones.
[heart pounds in background]
It's romantic, isn't it?
After all that's happened
between us,
you're still the thing
I love most.
And I do love you.
I always have.
But you're not
really here.
[Hook] Aye, mate.
But she is.
She lives in
all Dark Ones.
So when I crush your heart,
so will she.
[swords clanging]
[groaning, grunting]
[body thuds]
[panting]
[clanging resumes]
[Gold grunts]
[flesh piercing]
Oh! [chuckles]
We can do this
all day.
But until
you have Excalibur,
it won't make a lick
of difference.
They say the first cut
is the deepest.
Well, they lied.
[tinkling]
This is it.
You put them here.
[dreamcatchers clattering]
Makes no sense.
Why would hook keep
the dreamcatchers
where we could so easily
get to them?
[whooshing]
Because we can't get to them.
He knew I wouldn't
have magic.
He's toying with me,
tormenting me.
Good thing
the locator spell
wasn't the only thing I took
from Gold's shop.
Call me an optimist,
but I was hoping
I'd have to use it.
Henry,
are you sure?
You didn't have to include me
in this operation,
but you did.
You didn't try
and do it alone.
If you're willing to take
that first step back, so am I.
♪♪
I will make it up
to you.
You want to start
by saving the day?
[bell jingles]
[door shuts]
[heart beating]
You were playing me
the whole time.
Once you lied about Excalibur,
all bets were off.
I knew it was just
a matter of time
before you tried
controlling me.
And now no one will ever
control me again.
Go back
from whence you came.
Back to stone.
[beating sound continues]
I don't understand.
Why are you helping him
get his revenge?
[Nimue] Don't be naive,
Emma.
Dark Ones never
do anything
without getting something
in return.
- What do you want?
- You're a Dark One.
You know what we want.
You want it too.
No.
You can't.
Yes, we can.
And we will.
Killian...
your revenge is not
your happy ending.
I am.
You told me that.
If you destroy
this heart,
you will destroy your happy
ending along with it.
No, Killian Jones
told you that.
Your lovesick
puppy dog.
But that man died
the moment you turned him
into a Dark One.
[heart pounding, crushing]
[Nimue whimpering]
[dirt rustling]
[Merlin gasps]
[body thuds]
♪♪
[dust rustling]
[steam whooshing]
[bell dinging]
Well, I have to hand it
to you, crocodile.
You lasted a lot longer
than I expected.
If you'd fought me with
such vigor back in the day,
I might have given you
your wife back.
Soiled... [sniffs]
but returned.
What are you waiting for,
pirate? Finish him.
[rope creaks, cutting through air]
♪♪
[Hook laughing]
Well, get on with it,
crocodile.
There's nothing I'd like better
than to run you through.
But I think... I think
I'd rather let you live,
knowing for the rest of
your life that I bested you.
Today.
[whooshing]
[sword clangs]
♪♪
[birds chirping]
[Belle] You...
You did it!
You won.
And you came.
Oh, Belle,
I'm so glad you're here.
I'm ready to do this right,
put the past behind us.
Rumple...
[exhales sharply]
This isn't easy
for me.
I love you.
And some part of me
will always love you.
But you've broken my heart
too many times.
There's just too
much broken trust.
But I've changed.
My heart
is pure now.
Yeah, you... you have,
and it is.
You're... You're
the man
that I always hoped
you would be.
Then why are you
doing this now?
Now we have a chance
to make this work.
I don't know that I want
to make it work.
But I do know that if I'm gonna
try and figure that out,
I need to do that
on my own.
I can't...
I have spent too many years
trying to mend your heart.
Now I... I need
to protect mine.
Belle, please.
[whoosh]
Oh, don't take it
too bad.
I mean, he died
for a good cause.
I'm sorry.
Rest in peace.
It's over, Emma.
I told you
I would never abandon you.
I'm not
going to start now.
I'm sorry, love.
Once a curse has been enacted,
you can't stop it.
Yes. I might not be able
to stop it...
but I can make you forget
why you cast it.
[whoosh]
[body thuds]
And that you were ever the
Dark One in the first place.
[whoosh]
Clever, dearie.
♪♪
[tinkling]
When you wake up,
you'll be the man you were.
The man I love.
The man
who loves me.
Ah, you'll have to do
more than that
if you want him to forget
he was ever a Dark One.
I know.
[whooshing]
I need to erase the memories
[dreamcatcher tinkling]
of everyone who knew...
that I turned Hook...
into a Dark One.
[Rumple] Right.
Because no one could
possibly understand.
Why trust
your family to help
when you can do it
all yourself?
This was my fault.
I'm the one
who's going to fix this.
By using dark magic to add
a memory wipe to the curse.
♪♪
[whooshing]
[liquid boiling]
But you won't like
where it leads.
Or worse...
you will.
[thunder rumbling]
♪♪
[thunder crashes]
[horse whinnying]
[rumbling]
How did this
get back here?
Arthur.
What is that?
♪♪
Dark magic.
Extremely dark magic.
[thunder rumbles, crashes]
♪♪
[Merida] And we're meant
to believe
you're gonna give back our
memories, just like that?
[Henry] We can trust her.
Can we?
Yes.
Okay.
[whooshing]
[tinkling]
Emma,
what's wrong?
I remember.
I know what he's doing.
I know what they are doing.
Congratulations.
You didn't completely fail.
You returned
from your duel
with exactly the right
ingredients for our plan.
The blood of a man who'd been
to hell and back.
Rumplestiltskin has done
what few can claim.
He died,
and then he returned.
This pond holds a portal
to the underworld itself.
This is where the fury tried
to drag Robin Hood to hell.
I thought the portal
only appeared
when the moon reaches
its Zenith.
Yes, for a fury.
But it's always existed,
dearie.
You just have to know how
to open it.
♪♪
[sloshing]
[gentle whooshing]
[eerie ghostly sound]
Bloody hell.
That's exactly
where that came from.
♪♪
Nimue.
We're here.
All of us, as promised,
in the flesh.
And now it's time
to get to work,
to do what Dark Ones
do best...
Snuff out the light.
♪♪
Welcome to Storybrooke,
love.
Sync and corrected by
Gianluca Belfiglio