Spartacus:
There is but one path...
we kill them all.
(screaming)
(woman screaming)
(men grunting)
I am your dominus!
I will have your fucking hearts!
Quintus.
Lucretia.
What would you do
to hold your wife again,
to feel the warmth of her skin,
the taste of her lips?
How many men would you kill?
Quintus: I left the deed
in Barca's hands.
Now you're free.
Quintus: We are betrayed by
the Beast of fucking Carthage.
You are beneath me.
Lucretia:
He is a magistrate.
Solonius: One can never know
who is plotting violence, can one?
Quintus: Or when they may
commit the act.
Your wife... she moves ever closer
even as we speak.
My word is kept.
They're reunited.
Lucretia: You will become
the greatest lanista in the Republic.
Quintus: Under such a title
we will climb beyond our station,
beyond Capua,
perhaps to the very steps
of the Senate itself.
(crowd shouting)
The fights are particularly
entertaining today.
You'd enjoy them more
viewed from the pulvenus.
Fucking shit-eater.
Let Vettius preen like a woman.
You'll school him in the ways of men
when Gannicus takes to the sands.
Absent Tullius and the magistrate
to bear witness,
what's the fucking purpose?
One man in today's games,
one only,
and the seats needing to impress
stand empty
as Vettius' fucking head.
Get up!
(shouts)
Solonius, what news?
Tullius and the magistrate were delayed
with pressing business,
but arrive shortly,
as long as this current match
continues.
No. Get up!
Capua!
Get up, get up, you fuck.
(people shouting)
Vettius begins the match
without proper introduction.
- Proper?
- Capua!
Quintus: Vettius and the word
are of distant relations.
I, for one, am grateful
to be spared his oratory.
The man's voice
causes skull to ache.
Arghh!
Gannicus takes position.
(crowd cheering)
Now there's a fucking gladiator!
Man:
Tear his fucking face off!
Man #2:
Fucking kill him!
Begin.
(Gannicus laughing)
(laughing)
Is your man
ever of a serious note?
He can strip naked and fight
with his cock, as long as he wins.
Gannicus, I love you!
(gladiator yelling)
(laughing)
(yelling)
What's he doing, Quintus?
Fucking kill him!
No. Wait for the magistrate.
Kill kill kill!
Gannicus, do not kill him!
Do not kill him yet!
Oh, now they arrive.
A victory regardless.
Won in dewy morn.
None of the important
matches happen
till after the midday sun
has passed.
Consider yourself fortunate
to have a man in the games at all.
Good Solonius stands
with empty hands.
Come then, let us see them
filled with drink.
Tell Doctore to see Gannicus
back to the ludus
and have him properly
rewarded for his showing.
Lucretia: Can we not stay
for the rest of the games?
Vettius' men command
the prominent matches.
He has more than enough eyes
to watch him stroke his cock.
I would not add ours
to the sight.
Gannicus:
Now you want me, Capua.
(Gannicus laughing)
Doctore.
Dominus orders Gannicus
returned to the ludus,
and seen to reward.
Perhaps one day
the pretty little bitch
will fight later
in the afternoon,
with the rest of the men.
You and your tiny cock
best pray that day never come.
(kisses)
(grunts, spits)
Save blood for the fucking
sands, Gannicus.
What seized fucking brain,
releasing your swords
in the arena?
I could have killed the man
absent an arm and both fucking legs.
Hubris...
a fine quality
often possessed by cunts
who perish from it.
(screaming)
Did you catch
the manner of his eye
as he gazed down
from the pulvenus?
Fucking Vettius...
barely free
of his mother's tit,
yet he carries himself above lanistas
of more deserving years.
Lucretia: Youth often imagines itself
swollen beyond worth.
Solonius: Time will cure him
of the condition,
as it does
all foolish young men.
Time is what he holds
in abundance.
The new arena will be finished
in but a handful of months.
If we are excluded
from the opening games...
Vettius is but shit
from a shit town.
How can Tullius
and the magistrate
favor a boy from Nola
over one of Capua's own sons?
Well, how do they do it now?
We must prove ourselves
in the more important bouts
in the old arena
and secure position.
To fight later in the day,
we must first distinguish ourselves
against Vettius' men.
Yet Vettius' men only fight...
Together:
Later in the day.
A vexing conundrum.
Lucretia?
- Gaia. Gaia.
- (laughing)
Will you come to Capua
without telling me?
I have only
this moment returned,
with intentions
of seeking you out.
Do you travel
with your husband?
He takes to road no more,
not in this life at least.
Apologies.
None required.
It was his time.
Are you occupied?
I'm fit to bursting
with stories of my adventures.
Quintus?
What man dares stand
between women and gossip?
You must tell me everything.
Secret no detail.
Removed from the ears of men,
my lips willingly part.
Gaia returns unencumbered
and in enticing form.
Huh, that woman is
a force of fucking nature,
one that has blown many
an unsuspecting man to his ruin.
You require someone
more refined
to grace arm
as our fortunes rise.
Have eyes ever beheld
such a marvel?
A sight to put the Circus Maximus
in Rome to bitter shame.
We will be the ones shamed
if grand ceremony passes
absent our gladiators.
We must force advantage
before opportunity slips from grasp.
No, we must be patient.
Your father would venture forth
with respect and caution.
Then a blessing
he is not present.
Perhaps we should send word
to him in Sicilia, petition advice?
I can already divine
the content of his reply,
which is why he never rose
above his humble station.
Fuck patience.
Look to Tullius for the way.
He seizes opportunity
by the balls
while lesser men
are left holding cock.
A simple merchant,
yet he gives honored counsel
to the magistrate
and all the rest of the noble
shit-eaters of Capua.
Truth told,
yet at excessive volume.
I would shout his praise
to the fucking heavens.
His hands shaped events
resulting in the erection
of the new arena.
He supplies slaves
from the farthest reaches of
the Republic to speed its completion.
Through the ambitions
of Tullius,
Capua is elevated...
a lesson to be studied
and reproduced in kind.
Is that all?
A simple task then, Batiatus.
- Slave: Dominus.
- Between us,
we have the greatest
gladiators in Capua...
Barca, Acadeus, Gannicus...
men forged into something
beyond their worth,
beyond anything that smug
little piss Vettius
could ever hope to offer.
(men grunting)
Perhaps Tullius
should not have strayed
so far abroad
in acquiring his slaves.
Man: What's he doing?
Pick him up.
Crixus,
you know the rules...
no one breaks the line.
Quintus: Hold.
Is this one
of good Tullius's slaves?
It is.
- I would make purchase.
- Purchase?
- What's the man's worth?
- He is not for sale.
50 denarii.
- What are you doing?
- Seizing balls.
The man is barely worth 10.
Why would you pay
such a sum for a shit Gaul?
Shit?
Do you not see
the promise in his eyes,
the spark smoldering
in his breast?
I would give it tender,
to ignite in the arena.
50.
Add another five
to weight your own purse.
Lend me 20 denarii.
You pay too much for the man.
Quintus:
The man is nothing.
I pay to gain favor
with Tullius.
A waste of coin.
The shit fuck
will never be a gladiator.
Quintus: Even the lowest man
can rise beyond the heavens,
if tempted
with the proper reward.
(grunting)
(women laughing)
He was well satisfied?
Very well.
Dominus will be pleased.
Not as much as I am.
When are you not so,
especially with yourself?
It is a curse,
being blessed
with so much to offer.
And so few interested
in sharing it.
(laughs)
See yourselves well scrubbed.
I would not
have you smell of goat.
Goat?
A dead one.
(laughs)
The smell of victory, brother.
Well-earned.
The men all speak
of your triumph.
As they will of yours,
when you return to the arena.
The crowd will come
in great geysers,
drenching the gods
gathered to witness
Oenomaus once more
upon the sands.
I would have words
with my wife,
absent your cock,
which has escaped you.
It will be missed.
Has Dominus spoken
of my return?
I have not heard it.
More than a year has passed
since I faced Theokoles.
Perhaps Dominus
does not intend...
You were the only one
to ever stand
against the Shadow of Death
and live.
Batiatus would be a fool
to keep you from the arena.
Or I am the fool
for ever dreaming
of such a thing.
You are many things.
Foolish is not among them.
Batiatus waits
but for the perfect day
for his champion
to retake glory.
Is it true that his thing is
as large as a horse's?
Diona!
Are you not curious?
Is Gannicus really that big?
(laughing)
Where is Domina?
In the triclinium with her guest.
Diona, see the girls bathed.
Yes, Melitta.
It is exciting
speaking of such things, is it not?
I was of a similar age
not so long ago.
I know the giddy enticement
of the subject.
Yet you and Diona
should turn thought from it.
Soon enough your flowers
will be plucked.
Hastening the moment
will only result
in bruising of the petals.
Yes, Melitta.
And in regards to Gannicus,
I've seen bigger.
Well, you don't seem overly
distraught at his passing.
How would you present,
after years enduring
withered flesh groping at you?
But when you left Capua
I thought you madly in love.
I was... with his purse.
Sadly his fortunes went dry
towards the end.
And did you aid
in their evaporation?
What can I say?
I am the glorious sun...
returned to bless loving rays
upon favored friend.
(Lucretia gasps)
Gaia.
I have far too many baubles
brought from Rome,
along with other pleasures
to be shared.
It suits you.
It would dazzle Venus herself.
I fear I have nothing
so exquisite to give in return.
Your company
is all I ever desire.
And?
And I would not refuse the comforts
of a well-appointed villa
until I manage
other arrangements.
Involving a ripe purse?
(laughs)
I shall ask Quintus
when he returns.
Ask?
Women do not ask
their husbands for permission.
They maneuver them
to proper answer
before question
is ever put to tongue.
Oh, Gaia.
So many years have passed,
and yet nothing has changed.
Everything has changed,
and for the better,
by the judging of it.
When last we parted,
this house was but a tomb
haunted by the living specter
of your husband's father
and you,
forced to smile and cater,
bringing him his
honeyed wine every evening.
I thought the crusty
old bastard
would never succumb
to the afterlife.
He is not yet so far removed,
merely retired to Sicilia
for his health.
So he yet controls the ludus?
No. My husband does
as his proxy.
Was Gannicus
well-attended then?
He was, Domina.
Gannicus?
That Celt
with the ridiculously
charming smile?
He has risen to prominence
in the ludus
ever since Oenomaus was
injured against Theokoles...
In an amazing display
of bravery.
Gaia:
Gannicus, Oenomaus...
all the hard, rippling men
right beneath our feet.
One moistens at the thought.
Gaia. They are but slaves.
Please.
In all the years
you've called this ludus home,
you've never once considered
fucking one of them?
The very thought of that
turns my stomach.
I would never lay with any man
besides my husband,
let alone a filthy gladiator.
Man: Fucking Gaul.
Ashur: Another sacrifice
to the gods of the arena.
(speaks foreign language)
Dagan thinks you of a form,
giving odds in your favor.
Odds?
Do you know
where you are, friend?
The House of Batiatus,
trainer of gladiators.
Yes. You stand among
his latest recruits.
Bound by pain and blood,
together we toil
beneath the cruel sting
of Doctore's whip.
There were eight of us
when training began.
Now we're but three.
Four.
And how are we so blessed
by a swelling number, hmm?
By what means do you find yourself
among such storied company?
My own.
I was bound to Appius the slaver,
carrying stone toward purpose
at the new arena.
I saw Batiatus and knew him
by his words of gladiators.
So I gained his attention.
You willingly present ass
for fucking?
No.
No, young Indus.
Do you not see it in his eyes?
This is a man with dreams
of blood and glory.
I doubt he'll live to see the test.
Test?
Ashur: Our last trial.
We must all face
one of the seasoned men
and demonstrate to the dominus
what we have learned.
Live, and receive
the mark of the Brotherhood,
proving yourself
worthy of the arena.
I will stand upon its sands.
(speaking foreign language)
Oh, he longs to call you brother
and join you as gladiator.
(laughs)
Tell him the feeling
is well shared.
Quintus:
Oh, Jupiter's cock.
50 denarii
for a fucking stone hauler.
Lucretia:
Coin well spent.
Was it?
Word surely has reached
Tullius's ear,
yet none of gratitude return.
50 denarii.
Solonius was right.
I should temper patience
as my father would.
You're not your father,
nor would I have it so.
Perhaps tomorrow you will find
yourself in the market,
where, you have
often mentioned,
Tullius frequents
upon a certain hour
overseeing his concerns.
A chance encounter
to gauge reaction?
Lucretia:
Certain to be favorable,
as I know your reply
to my request will be.
Give it voice
and see it considered.
I would have Gaia
remain with us,
just for a few days,
until she can manage
other arrangements.
The request does not surprise.
Is that a yes?
Ask for the moon and I would
wrest it from the heavens.
Gaia will be so pleased
at your answer.
Let her keep company
with her wine a moment longer.
Has a wife ever had
such a husband?
He but honors her
and the gods
for guiding her to his arms.
(men grunting)
(laughs)
Crixus, you lower your shield
when you thrust.
See it raised, or your fucking
brains on the sand.
Yes, Doctore.
A lucky blow.
A blow well-struck.
I will not make the same mistake.
Ha ha! Good.
Again.
Doctore.
I would work the palus
in the shade.
I would not let gaze linger.
Gannicus is a fucking fool,
yet one of deadly skill.
He's often rewarded
for his victories with wine and cunt.
Gain Dominus's favor,
and such delights
could be yours.
Drink and women
are not my concern.
Ah, more for me then.
Fucking recruits...
smaller and smaller each year.
Apologies.
Oenomaus,
you return to form.
Pair with Crixus
and bring him up to speed.
Dominus.
Gratitude for your instructions.
Lesson one...
never drop your fucking guard.
Do you lay eyes?
No. Perhaps Tullius
did not come today.
He always arrives,
and seldom departs
before noonday sun.
Are you his shadow now,
adhered to each footstep?
I but study my subject,
as any proper student would
in the pursuit of knowledge.
Tullius' man.
I seek your master... good Tullius.
Would he be within?
Yeah.
I wish to express
my gratitude
for allowing me to purchase
his slave Crixus.
The Gaul shows great promise
towards the arena.
Perhaps you could pass
word of my presence.
You owe me a few of those,
if you recall.
A costly enterprise
for us both.
That one prays will turn profit.
(pigs squealing,
sheep bleating)
Good Batiatus.
The gods answer.
In mocking tone.
Tullius: I hoped for occasion
to give gratitude
for relieving me
of that troublesome Gaul.
Think nothing of it...
a gesture of respect
for a man deserving of it.
Received with all intentions.
Yet I fear you have overpaid.
A common mistake for those
with no head towards business.
50 denarii, minus the 10
of the Gaul's actual worth.
Well...
I do not ask for its return.
Fair bargain was struck.
Fair?
A clumsy maneuver
to gain position
for your ill-trained men.
- Vettius.
- Ill-trained?
Any one of my men could
best yours fucking blindfolded,
you pissy little shit.
- Listen how the rooster crows.
- Let us calm ourselves.
You doubt my words?
Test them.
Request the match
in the next month's games.
Why delay?
Let us see it here in the morning,
the people to judge
who holds the better man.
In the market?
Surely the magistrate
would not approve
such disruption.
Good Tullius has his ear.
The magistrate could be
swayed to allow it,
if that is what you wish.
It is, and long past due.
Tomorrow then.
A friendly rivalry
well-settled.
You press beyond advantage.
No, I fucking press towards it.
You should have seen
young Vettius,
so easily goaded
into making challenge,
the fucking child.
All men are reduced in years
when faced with superior mind.
Superior in all accounting...
a fact Tullius
and the rest of the city
will bear witness to
in the marketplace.
Sleep will come
with difficulty tonight.
It's been ages
since I've seen a decent match
or Tullius.
In the blush of youth,
he was forever attempting
to slip beneath my robes.
Ha! You should have
fucking let him.
Tullius has grown
to be a man of worth,
one to be emulated and admired.
And who will you choose
to impress him?
Vettius's foolishness
presents rare opportunity.
The question begs
careful consideration.
I have news to lift the heart.
Vettius has made challenge.
- The coward finds his cock.
- And I would see it shriveled.
My best man is to meet his dog
in the marketplace come morning.
The market?
Eh, detail of no consequence.
My question to you is plain...
is our man prepared
for such a vital match?
Yes, Dominus.
I long to honor
this house once again.
I fear you have
mistaken intentions.
I speak of Gannicus.
Gannicus?
The question is better put
to Doctore.
Leave.
His counsel is always valued,
yet he is my father's man,
his judgment clouded
through a haze
of outdated traditions.
I seek a more visceral
assessment.
You and I practically
grew up together in this ludus.
You have witnessed the rise
and fall of a dozen champions.
What now does your gut
tell you of Gannicus?
Is he worthy of the mantle?
I believe it so.
He must truly be,
for you to offer support
despite your own desires.
I would not give false tongue
to gain advantage.
There are few
that would stand with you so.
Your wife's weekly visit...
two nights hence?
Yes, Dominus.
I would see her to your bed
tonight as well
in gratitude
for honest thoughts.
Dominus.
Oenomaus: Do the gods
ever answer your prayers?
They often reveal
their leanings,
though not in words...
much like my husband.
Dominus summoned me
to ask of Gannicus.
Gannicus?
He has chosen him
as champion.
He is to face Vettius's man
in the marketplace tomorrow.
And this is why you sulk?
The streets are no place
for the mighty Oenomaus
to make his return.
The arena will be home
to your triumphs
when the time comes.
And I will be there
to witness it.
I will dream of your touch.
As I dream of yours every night.
Gannicus: ? Blood rains down
from an angry sky ?
? My cock rages on,
my cock rages on ?
? Blood rains down
from an angry sky ?
? My cock rages on,
my cock rages on. ?
Gannicus.
Brother. Brother,
come drink, join me.
Lower voice.
If the guards were to hear you...
The guards have already passed
and were well plied with wine
to keep nose
from fucking business.
Tomorrow you fight
for the honor of this ludus.
Now is not the time for drink.
Every night is a time for drink,
for the morning sun
may greet you
with your last
fucking day.
(laughing)
Fall to your bed,
or risk steeper plummet
against Vettius's man.
Words of wisdom
well-received,
well... well-received.
Oenomaus.
It should be you tomorrow.
Where is good Vettius?
Is he among you?
Or did he come to his sense
and remain within the warm safety
of his bed?
Ah, there he stands,
fresh and young
as a newborn calf.
The fool at last shows himself.
Batiatus.
We had begun to fret
on your arrival,
although I see you arrive
with unexpected gift.
It has been too long, Gaia.
And grows longer still.
Apologies for my delay.
I had much difficulty
in the choosing of a man...
an imposing task,
when each among my stable
stands a titan.
Perhaps young Vettius
should have taken more time
with the choosing of his own.
Words fall from your mouth
as shit from ass.
Let us not become mired
in base exchange.
We are gathered
this glorious day
to witness honorable contest
between respected rivals.
Clear space!
The years have favored Tullius.
And his purse.
A brawl in the streets?
Where is the honor in such a thing?
Fuck honor.
This is business.
Gratitude to Magistrate Sextus...
The event turns
larger than expected.
- Your mad schemes may yet bear fruit.
- For allowing such thrilling event...
Enough for both of us
to feast upon.
...in the streets
of the great city of Capua!
Batiatus, present your man.
In honor of the magistrate,
esteemed Tullius
and the good people of Capua,
I give you the fiercest Celt
ever to take up arms
in the arena,
slayer of beasts,
conqueror of giants.
Behold Gannicus,
Champion of
the House of Batiatus!
Arghh!
A fine choice.
Vettius, present your man.
I have no tongue
for overripe embellishment,
nor is it required.
Otho, stand forth.
(roars)
Your day finally comes.
And yours ends.
Gratitude to Batiatus and Vettius.
Now let us judge
who stands the better house.
Apologies, Magistrate.
There appears to be
something missing.
Where is your man's blindfold?
(crowd muttering)
Blindfold? What the fuck?
That was your boast,
was it not...
that your gladiator could best
any of my men
absent sight?
You did voice such challenge.
A simple figure of speech,
not meant to be...
good Tullius...
If Batiatus does not wish
to honor terms,
he should remove himself
with tail between legs.
Doctore.
Come.
The task should not be
that difficult.
I need only direct my blades
towards the smell of shit.
Gannicus, ever the fool.
Are you going to
allow this, Quintus?
The choice has been
removed from my hands.
Begin.
(yelling)
Yes!
How thrilling.
I have never seen
such a thing.
For good reason.
A noble attempt.
To be remembered
only in its failing.
Get up!
Yes.
Get up.
Yes!
Fucking kill him!
Have you ever
fucking seen the like?
Perhaps good Vettius should pit
a man less prone to death
against the mighty Gannicus.
An impressive display,
Batiatus,
one not soon forgotten.
Gannicus is truly a wonder.
One deserving more prominent
position in the games.
You gaze upon
my very thoughts.
Commitments beckon.
Join me at Nestor's shop
after the market closes
and we shall discuss
your man at length.
Only mad Gannicus could
win contest fucking blindfolded.
Barca could do the same.
And I would kill you
for being a fool.
Oenomaus:
Auctus speaks truth.
Facing Vettius's man absent sight
was beyond foolish.
The gods must have taken pity
on your addled brain.
The gods had naught
to do with it.
Otho... he grunts like a stuck pig
before each attack.
His squeals...
they gave away position.
(laughing)
Your victory lifts the heart.
You will not be rid
of Gannicus so easily, brother.
Dominus... he rewards me
with all the wine that I can drink.
And I would share it
with my brothers.
(cheering)
Those that bear the mark.
(men laughing)
One day.
Gannicus' victory
forges path to greater glory.
With Tullius's support,
we can finally gain
proper position in games.
Lucretia: Maybe a place in the opening
ceremony of the new arena.
After such a magnificent showing,
I have no doubt
Gannicus will be offered
a place in the primus.
Primus?
Yeah.
I favor the fucking sound
of that.
Expect late return.
I would seek out
Solonius afterwards
to discuss extending advantage
to his house as well.
Send Tullius my regards
and gauge his response
in remembering me.
(laughs)
How could he fucking forget you?
It staggers mind...
the change in him.
Change?
You know my meaning.
He always seemed
so demure and cowed.
And now he
positively burns.
He has always done so.
His light was merely muted
by the shadow of his father.
The man could turn day to night
with disapproving frown.
He never cared much for me
or, I suspect, anything
that smacked of enjoyment.
And what might this be?
More gifts from Rome.
The finest opium,
carried from Cyprus.
I have not partaken
in many years.
My husband...
Will be gone
most of the night.
Good Batiatus.
Word of Gannicus's victory
has spread throughout the city.
His name, and yours,
fall from every mouth.
May they always find
the taste pleasing.
Everyone clamors
to see your man again,
with exception of poor Vettius.
He is fit for seizure
from the ordeal.
Unfortunate that he
could not provide
a more worthy opponent.
His stock is well known
to be of inferior quality,
as is the boy himself.
The manner in which
he tends the ludus...
the child has no fucking
talent for it.
You surprise me, Batiatus.
Your disposition
towards business
is much more aggressive
than your father's.
We are of diverging
temperament
and desires.
How does he fare in Sicilia?
The clime is more agreeable
to various conditions
brought about
by the passing of the years.
How did the magistrate take
to Gannicus' display?
Ignited by it,
as was the crowd.
He even broached subject
of retaining the man
for the opening games
of the new arena.
Gannicus in the opening games?
If you could aid
in such a thing,
I would forever be
in your debt.
It merely requires a word
in the proper ear.
All that remains
is to agree upon a price.
Well, of course
I would be happy
to see coin to your hand
in exchange for assistance.
What sum
did you have in mind?
(laughs)
You misunderstand, Batiatus.
I do not offer
to broker arrangement.
I offer to purchase your man.
Purchase?
But why would you want a gladiator?
You're not a lanista.
Jupiter's cock, no.
Yet I have many
vested interests
in shipping,
goods and services,
this very shop
and young Vettius's ludus.
Vettius:
Look at the little fuck now,
about to shit himself.
Tullius:
Still your tongue.
The grown-ups are talking.
200 denarii...
a generous offer
in respect of your father.
Apologies.
I would not part with the man.
I allow you
to purchase
one of my slaves,
yet now you deny me
the same opportunity?
Gannicus is not for sale.
Everything is for sale, Batiatus.
The question is but price.
(yelling)
(Gaia laughing)
(grunting)
I make fair offer
and you produce cock
to piss on me?
Do you know what that
feels like, Batiatus?
(chuckling)
Reconsider your answer
or be excluded
from the games forever.
(Tullius laughs)
(theme music playing)