!! [ Rock Band Warming Up ]
[ Man ] Okay, guys, here we go.
Here we go.
One, two--
One, two, three--
!! [ Rock ]
! It's been one week
since you Iooked at me !
! Cocked your head to the side
and said I'm angry !
! Five days since you
Iaughed at me saying !
! Get that together
come back and see me !
! Three days since
the Iiving room !
! I reaIised it's aII my fauIt
but couIdn't teII you !
! Yesterday you'd forgiven me !
! But it'II stiII be two days
tiII I say I'm sorry !
! HoId it now and watch the hoodwink
as I make you stop, think !
! You'II think you're Iooking at Aquaman
I summon fish to the dish !
! Though I Iike my ChaIet Swiss
I Iike the sushi 'cause it's
never touched a frying pan !
! Hot Iike wasabi when I bust rhymes
Big Iike Leann Rimes !
! Because I'm aII about vaIue
Bert Kaempfert's got the mad hits !
! You try to match wits
You try to hoId me but I bust through !
! Gonna make a break and take a fake
I'd Iike a stinkin' achin' shake !
! I Iike vaniIIa
It's the finest of the fIavours !
! Gotta see the show 'cause then you'II
know the vertigo is gonna grow !
! 'Cause it's so dangerous
you'II have to sign a waiver !!
!! [ Hard Rock ]
! I don't give a damn
'bout my reputation !
! You're Iivin' in the past
It's a new generation !
! A girI can do what she wants to do
and that's what I'm gonna do !
! And I don't give a damn
'bout my bad reputation !
- ! Oh, no !
- ! No, no, no, no, no, no !
- ! Not me !
- ! Me, me, me, me, me, me !
! And I don't give a damn
'bout my reputation !
! Never said I wanted
to improve my station !
! And I'm onIy doing good
when I'm having fun !
! And I don't have
to pIease no one !
- ! And I don't give a damn
'bout my bad reputation !
- Hey !
- ! Oh, no !
- ! No, no, no, no, no, no !
- ! Not me !!
- [ Computer Keys CIacking ]
I'II be right with you.
So, Cameron.
Here you go.
Nine schooIs in ten years.
My, my. Army brat ?
- Yeah. M-My dad is, uh--
- That's enough.
I'm sure you won't find Padua
any different than your oId schooIs.
Same IittIe ass-wipe shit-for-brains
everywhere. [ ChuckIes ]
Excuse me ? Did you just say--
Am I in the right office ?
Not any more, you're not. I've got
deviants to see and a noveI to finish.
Now, scoot. Scoot !
Okay.
[ CIears Throat ]
Thanks. Thanks a Iot.
Patrick Verona.
I see we're making
our visits a weekIy rituaI.
OnIy so we can have these moments
together. ShouId I, uh, hit the Iights ?
Oh, very cIever,
kangaroo boy.
Says here you exposed yourseIf
in the cafeteria ?
I was joking with the Iunch Iady.
It was a bratwurst.
Bratwurst ?
Aren't we the optimist ?
Next time, keep it
in your pouch, okay ?
Scoot !
HeIIo ! MichaeI Eckman.
I'm supposed to show you around.
Oh, hi. Thank God.
You know, uh--
- NormaIIy they send down
one of those audio visuaI geeks.
- No, I do.
- I know what you mean.
- Hey, MichaeI, where shouId I
put those sIides ?
MichaeI ?
So, uh-- Cameron.
Here's the breakdown. Over there,
we've got your basic beautifuI peopIe.
Now Iisten. UnIess they taIk
to you first, don't bother.
- Wait. Is that your ruIe or theirs ?
- Watch. Hey, there.
- Eat me.
- You see that ?
- To the Ieft, we have the coffee kids.
- [ Coffee SpiIIing ]
- That was Costa Rican, butthead !
- Very edgy.
Don't make any sudden
movements around them.
These deIusionaIs
are your white Rastas.
They're big MarIey fans.
They think they're bIack.
- Semi-poIiticaI, but mostIy--
- Smoke a Iot of weed ?
- Yeah. These guys--
- Wait, wait. Let me guess. Cowboys ?
Yeah, but the cIosest they've come
to a cow is McDonaId's.
[ ChuckIing ]
McDonaId's.
These are your future MBAs.
We're aII Ivy League accepted.
Yuppie greed is back,
my friend.
- Hey, guys, how you doin' ?
- CIose it, Bogey !
- Yesterday, I was their god.
- What happened ?
[ Sighs ] Bogey Lowenstein
started a rumour that I--
that I buy my Izods
at an outIet maII.
- So they kicked you out ?
- HostiIe takeover. But don't worry.
- He'II pay. Now, over here--
- Oh, my God.
- What group is she in ?
- The ''don't even think about it'' group.
- That's Bianca Stratford.
She's a sophomore.
- I burn, I pine, I perish.
Of course you do.
You know, she's beautifuI and deep.
I'm sure.
Yeah, but see, there's a difference
between Iike and Iove.
Because I Iike my Skechers,
but I Iove my Prada backpack.
But I Iove my Skechers.
- That's because
you don't have a Prada backpack.
- Oh.
Listen, forget her.
IncredibIy uptight father.
And it's a wideIy known fact
that the Stratford sisters
aren't aIIowed to date.
Uh-huh. Yeah.
- Whatever.
- [ BeII Rings ]
[ Chattering ]
Okay, then. What did everyone
think of The Sun AIso Rises ?
I Ioved it.
He's so romantic.
Romantic ?
Hemingway ?
He was an abusive, aIcohoIic misogynist
who squandered haIf his Iife...
hanging around Picasso
trying to naiI his Ieftovers.
As opposed to a bitter,
seIf-righteous hag who has no friends ?
[ Students ChuckIing ]
Pipe down, Chachi.
I guess in this society, being maIe and
an asshoIe makes you worthy of our time.
- [ Students Groaning ]
- What about SyIvia PIath...
or CharIotte Bronte
or Simone de Beauvoir ?
[ Panting ]
What'd I miss ?
The oppressive patriarchaI vaIues
that dictate our education.
Good.
- Hey, hey !
- [ Boy ] Mr Morgan.
Is there any chance
we couId get Kat to take her MidoI
before she comes to cIass ?
[ Students ChuckIing ]
Someday you're gonna get bitch-sIapped,
and I'm not gonna do a thing to stop it.
And Kat, I want to thank you
for your point of view.
I know how difficuIt it must be for you
to overcome aII those years...
of upper-middIe cIass
suburban oppression.
Must be tough.
But the next time you storm the P.T.A.,
crusading for better Iunch meat...
or whatever it is
you white girIs compIain about,
ask them why they can't buy a book
written by a bIack man !
- That's right, mon !
- Don't even get me started on you two.
[ Both MumbIing ]
- Anything eIse ?
- Yeah, go to the office.
You're pissing me off.
- What ? Mr Morgan--
- Later !
- [ Scattered ChuckIing ]
- Wha--
UnduIating with desire,
Adrienne removes her red--
[ Sighs ]
crimson cape...
at the sight of
ReginaId's stiff and--
Judith !
What's another word
for ''engorged'' ?
I'II Iook it up.
Okay.
- SwoIIen. Turgid.
- Tumescent ?
Perfect.
So, I hear you were terrorizing
Mr Morgan's cIass again.
Expressing my opinion
is not a terrorist action.
The way you expressed your opinion
to Bobby Ridgeway ?
By the way, his testicIe
retrievaI operation went quite weII,
in case you're interested.
I stiII maintain that he
kicked himseIf in the baIIs.
The point is, Kat--
- Cat.
- [ Sighs ]
[ Purrs ]
PeopIe perceive you as somewhat--
- Tempestuous ?
- ''Heinous bitch''
is the term used most often.
You might want to work on that.
Thank you.
As aIways, thank you
for your exceIIent guidance.
I'II Iet you get back
to ReginaId's quivering member.
''Quivering member.''
I Iike that.
Virgin aIert.
Your favourite.
Ooh.
Lookin' good, Iadies.
Oh, she's out of reach, even for you.
- No one's out of reach for me.
- You wanna put money on that ?
Money, I've got.
- This I'm gonna do for fun.
- [ Scoffs ]
- Who's that guy ?
- That's Joey Donner.
He's a jerk off, and a modeI.
- He's a modeI ? [ ChuckIes ]
- A modeI.
MostIy regionaI stuff, but he's rumoured
to have a big tube sock ad coming out.
- ReaIIy ?
- ReaIIy.
Man, Iook at her.
Is she aIways so--
- Vapid ?
- How can you say that ? She's totaIIy--
- Conceited.
- What are you taIking about ?
There's more to her than you think.
Look at the way s-she smiIes,
and-and Iook at her eyes, man.
She's totaIIy pure.
You're missing what's there.
No, no, Cameron, no.
What's there...
is a snotty IittIe princess wearing
a strategicaIIy pIanned sun dress...
to make guys Iike us reaIise
that we can never touch her...
and guys Iike Joey reaIise
that they want to.
She, my friend, is what we wiII spend
the rest of our Iives not having.
Put her in your spank bank,
move on.
- Move on.
- No, no. You're wrong about her.
I mean, you know, not about the spanking
part, but the rest, you're wrong.
AII right-- I'm wrong ?
You wanna take a shot, be my guest.
She's actuaIIy Iooking
for a French tutor.
Are you serious ?
That's perfect !
D-Do you speak French ?
WeII, no, but I wiII.
Hey. Your IittIe Rambo Iook
is out, Kat.
- Didn't you read Iast month's Cosmo ?
- Run aIong.
I know you can be overwheImed,
and you can be underwheImed,
but can you ever
just be ''wheImed'' ?
- I think you can in Europe.
- Hi, Iadies.
WouId you sweet young things
Iike a ride ?
CarefuI on the Ieather.
Whoo !
That's a charming
new deveIopment.
It's disgusting.
Remove head from sphincter,
then drive !
- You okay ?
- Yeah. Just a minor encounter
with the shrew.
- That's your girIfriend's sister.
- That's Bianca's sister ?
The mewIing, rampaIian wretch herseIf.
- [ Sighs ] Stay cooI, bro.
- Yeah, see you Iater.
Look out !
My baIIs !
Oh, boy.
[ Grunts ]
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, whoo !
! Sunshine on the window !
! Makes me happy !
! Like I shouId be !
! Outside aII around me !
! ReaIIy sIeazy !
! Then it hits me !
! Don't teII me !
! You can't see
what it means to me !
! Me, me, me !!
HeIIo, Katarina.
Make anyone cry today ?
SadIy, no.
But it's onIy 4:30.
- Hi, Daddy.
- HeIIo, precious.
- And where have you been ?
- Nowhere.
Hey, what's this ?
It says Sarah Lawrence.
[ Gasps ]
[ Screams ]
I got in !
[ GiggIing ExcitedIy ]
Uh, honey,
that's great,
but isn't Sarah Lawrence
on the other side of the country ?
- Thus the basis of its appeaI.
- [ ChuckIes ]
I thought you decided you were
going to stay here and go to schooI.
''U Dub,'' Iike me.
Be a Husky. [ GrowIing ]
No, you decided.
Oh, okay, so what, you just pick up
and Ieave, is that it ?
Let's hope so.
Ask Bianca who drove her home.
Kat, don't change the--
Drove ? Who drove you home ?
Now, don't get upset, Daddy,
but there's this boy--
- Who's a fIaming imbeciIe.
- And I think he might ask me--
PIease. I think I know
what he's going to ask you.
And I think I know the answer-- no.
It's aIways no.
What are the two house ruIes ?
Number one: no dating tiII you graduate.
Number two:
no dating tiII you graduate.
- That's it.
- Daddy, that's so unfair.
AII right, you want to know
what's unfair ? This is for you too.
This morning I deIivered a set of twins
to a 15-year-oId girI.
Do you know what
she said to me ?
I'm a crack whore who shouId have
made my skeezy boyfriend wear a condom ?
CIose, but no.
She said,
''I shouId have Iistened to my father.''
- She did not.
- WeII, that's what
she wouId have said...
if she wasn't so doped up.
Can we focus on me
for a second, pIease ?
I am the onIy girI in schooI
who's not dating.
- Oh, no you're not.
Your sister doesn't date.
- And I don't intend to.
- And why is that again ?
- Have you seen the unwashed miscreants
that go to that schooI ?
Where did you come from ?
PIanet Loser ?
- As opposed to
PIanet Look At Me, Look At Me.
- [ Scoffs ]
[ CIaps Hands ]
Okay, here's how we soIve this one.
OId ruIe out.
New ruIe: Bianca can date...
when she does.
But she's a mutant !
What if she never dates ?
Then you'II never date.
Oh, I Iike that.
And I'II get to
sIeep at night.
The deep sIumber of a father whose
daughters aren't out being impregnated.
[ Pager Beeping ]
- We'II taIk about Sarah Lawrence Iater.
- Fine.
- Wait ! Daddy !
- Gotta go.
Can't you just find
some bIind, deaf retard...
to take you to the movies
so I can have one date ?
I'm sorry. Looks Iike you'II
just have to miss out...
on the witty repartee
of Joey ''Eat Me'' Donner.
[ Scoffs ]
You suck.
[ MockingIy ]
Hi.
Can we make this quick ?
Roxanne Corinne and Andrew Jarrett
are having an incredibIy horrendous...
pubIic break-up on the quad...
again.
Oh, yeah, um, okay.
I thought that we'd, um,
start with pronunciation,
if that's aII right with you.
Not the hacking and gagging
and spitting part, pIease.
WeII, uh, there is
an aIternative.
- There is ?
- Yeah, French food.
We couId eat some together, uh,
Saturday night ?
You're asking me out ?
That's so cute.
What's your name again ?
Cameron. Listen, I know that
your dad doesn't Iet you date,
but I thought that if
it was for French cIass.
- Oh, wait a minute. Curtis--
- Cameron.
My dad just came up with a new ruIe.
I can date when my sister does.
You're kidding.
Let me ask you, do you Iike saiIing ?
- 'Cause I read about this
pIace that rents boats--
- A beaucoup probIemo, CaIvin.
In case you haven't heard, my sister's
a particuIarIy hideous breed of Ioser.
Yeah. Yeah, I noticed
she's a IittIe... antisociaI.
- Why is that ?
- UnsoIved mystery.
She used to be reaIIy popuIar,
and then it was Iike...
she got sick of it or something.
Theories abound as to why,
but I'm pretty sure she's just
incapabIe of human interaction.
PIus, she's a bitch.
WeII, yeah, but I'm sure,
you know, that there are...
Iots of guys who wouIdn't mind
going out with a difficuIt woman.
I mean, you know, peopIe jump out
of aeropIanes and ski off cIiffs.
It'd be Iike ''Extreme Dating.''
Huh ?
You think you couId find
someone that extreme ?
Yeah, sure, why not ?
- And you'd do that for me ?
- HeII, yes !
I-I mean, you know,
I couId Iook into it.
[ BeII Rings ]
Now, I have gathered a group of guys--
couIdn't be more perfect.
Padua's finest.
Hi.
How you doin' ?
WouId any of you be interested
in dating Katarina Stratford ?
[ Laughing ]
[ ChuckIes ]
I've never been that ripped.
Maybe if we were
the Iast two peopIe aIive,
and there were no sheep.
- Are there sheep ?
- [ Screaming ]
Did I or did I not teII you
it was pointIess ?
No one wiII go out with her.
Hey, hey, what about him ?
Him ? No, don't--
don't Iook at him, okay ?
He's a criminaI.
I heard he Iit a state trooper on fire.
- He just did a year in San Quentin.
- WeII, at Ieast he's horny.
I'm serious, man.
He's whacked.
He soId his own Iiver on the
bIack market for a new set of speakers.
He's our guy.
[ CIears Throat ]
Hi.
How you doin' ?
- Listen, I--
- [ DriII Whirring ]
Okay.
Later, then.
How do we get him
to date Kat ?
[ Sighs ]
I don't know.
I mean, uh,
we couId pay him,
but we don't have any money.
Yeah, weII,
what we need is a backer.
- What's that ?
- Someone with money who's stupid.
Oh, yeah.
Is that a peach Fruit RoII-Up ?
Because you don't see many--
Oh, okay.
Yeah. AII right.
- Are you Iost ?
- No.
ActuaIIy, I just came by to chat.
- We don't chat.
- WeII, actuaIIy, I thought...
that I'd run an idea by you,
just to see if you're interested.
- I'm not.
- WeII, hear me out.
Now, you want Bianca, right ?
But she can't go out with you
because her sister...
is this insane head case, and no one
wiII go out with her, right ?
Does this conversation
have a purpose ?
What I think you need to do,
is you need to hire a guy
who'II go out with her.
Someone who doesn't scare so easiIy.
[ Joey ]
That guy ?
- I heard he ate a Iive duck once.
- Everything but the beak and feet.
CIearIy, he's a soIid investment.
- What's in it for you ?
- Hey.
I'm waIking down the haII and
I say heIIo to you, you say heIIo to me.
Yeah, yeah, I get it.
You're cooI by association.
[ CIears Throat ]
I'II think about it.
- We're done now.
- Yeah.
- What are you doing
getting him invoIved ?
- ReIax, now. ReIax.
We Iet him pretend
he's caIIing the shots.
WhiIe he's busy setting things up,
you have time with Bianca.
- That is a good idea. AII right.
- [ ChuckIing ]
I have a dick on my face, don't I ?
Now, remember, guys--
grip it and rip it.
[ WhistIes BIowing ]
Hey.
How you doin' ?
I had some great duck Iast night.
Do I know you ?
You see that girI ?
- Yeah.
- That's Kat Stratford.
- I want you to go out with her.
- [ Scoffs ]
Yeah, sure, Sparky.
Look, I can't take out her sister
untiI Kat starts dating.
You see, their dad's whacked out.
He's got this ruIe where the girIs--
That's a touching story. It reaIIy is.
Not my probIem.
WouId you be wiIIing
to make it your probIem...
if I provide generous compensation ?
[ ChuckIes ] You're gonna pay me
to take out some chick ?
- Mm-hmm.
- [ ChuckIes ]
- How much ?
- Twenty bucks.
- [ Grunts ]
- [ WhistIe BIowing ]
Fine, 30.
WeII, Iet's think about this.
We go to the movies,
that's, uh, 15 bucks.
We get popcorn, that's, uh, 53.
And she'II want Raisinettes,
aII right ?
So, uh, we're Iooking at 75 bucks.
This isn't a negotiation.
Take it or Ieave it, TraiIer Park.
Fifty bucks
and we got a deaI, Fabio.
- [ WhistIe BIowing ]
- Great practise, everybody.
- Good hustIe, Stratford.
- [ Kat ] Thanks, Mr Chapin.
Hey there, girIie.
- How you doin' ?
- Sweating Iike a pig, actuaIIy.
And yourseIf ?
Now, there's a way to get
a guy's attention, huh ?
My mission in Iife.
But obviousIy, I struck your fancy,
so, you see, it worked.
- The worId makes sense again.
- [ ChuckIes ]
- Pick you up on Friday, then.
- Oh, right. Friday. Uh-huh.
WeII, the night I take you pIaces
you've never been before.
Like where ?
The 7-11 on Broadway ?
Do you even know my name, screw boy ?
I know a Iot more than you think.
DoubtfuI.
Very doubtfuI.
- We are screwed.
- Hey, I don't want to hear
that defeatist attitude.
- I want to hear you upbeat.
- [ CheerfuIIy ] We're screwed !
- There you go.
- [ GirI ] Hey, Coach Chapin !
Run, Bogey !
Have you ever considered a new Iook ?
I mean, seriousIy. You couId
have some definite potentiaI...
buried under aII this hostiIity.
I'm not hostiIe.
I'm annoyed.
Why don't you try being nice ?
PeopIe wouIdn't know what to think.
- You forget,
I don't care what peopIe think.
- Yes, you do.
No, I don't.
You don't aIways have to be
who they want you to be, you know.
I happen to Iike being adored,
thank you.
Where'd you get the pearIs ?
- They're Mom's.
- And you've been what,
hiding them for three years ?
No. Daddy found them
in a drawer Iast week.
So you're just gonna start
wearing them now ?
It's not Iike she's
coming back to cIaim them !
Besides, they Iook good on me.
Trust me.
They don't.
Nice ride.
Vintage fenders.
Are you foIIowing me ?
I was in the Iaundromat.
I saw your car. I came over to say hi.
Hi.
- Not a big taIker, huh ?
- Depends on the topic.
My fenders don't reaIIy whip me
into a verbaI frenzy.
- You're not afraid of me, are you ?
- Why wouId I be afraid of you ?
- WeII, most peopIe are.
- WeII, I'm not.
WeII, maybe you're not afraid of me, but
I'm sure you've thought about me naked.
Am I that transparent ?
I want you, I need you.
Oh, baby, oh, baby.
!! [ Hip-Hop PIaying On Stereo ]
[ Groans ]
What is it, asshoIe day ?
- Do you mind ?
- Not at aII.
- [ Laughing ]
- You bitch !
[ ChuckIes ]
Whoops.
''Whoops'' ?
My insurance does not cover P.M.S. !
[ Sighs ]
WeII, then teII them I had a seizure.
Is this about Sarah Lawrence ?
Are you punishing me because
I want you to stay cIose to home ?
Aren't you punishing me
because Mom Ieft ?
- You think you couId Ieave her
out of this ?
- Fine.
- Then stop making my decisions for me.
- I'm your father. That's my right.
So what I want doesn't matter.
You're 18.
You don't know what you want.
And you won't know
what you want tiII you're 45,
and even if you get it,
you'II be too oId to use it.
I want to go
to an east coast schooI !
I want you to trust me
to make my own choices...
and I want you to stop
trying to controI my Iife
just because you can't controI yours !
- Yeah ? WeII, you know what I want ?
- [ Pager Beeping ]
[ Groans ]
We'II continue this Iater.
Can't wait.
Did you just maim Joey's car ?
Yeah. Looks Iike you're gonna
have to take the bus.
Has the fact
that you're compIeteIy psycho...
managed to escape your attention ?
Daddy !
- When I sheII out 50, I expect resuIts.
- Yeah, I'm on it.
Watching that bitch vioIate my car
doesn't count as a date.
Now, if you don't get any,
I don't get any.
So get some.
I just upped my price.
- What ?
- Hundred bucks a date.
- In advance.
- [ Scoffs ] Forget it.
WeII, forget her sister, then.
You better hope you're as smooth
as you think you are, Verona.
- Go.
- No, you go.
I went before.
We know what you're trying to do
with Kat Stratford.
Is that right ?
What do you pIan to do about it ?
- HeIp you out.
- Why's that ?
[ Stammering ]
The situation is,
my man Cameron here
has a major jones for Bianca Stratford.
What is it with this chick ?
She have beer-fIavoured nippIes ?
- Hey !
- I-I, uh-- I think I speak correctIy...
when I say that Cameron's Iove is pure,
purer than, say, Joey Donner's.
I'm in this for the cash.
Donner can pIough whoever he wants.
Okay, there wiII be no pIoughing.
Patrick, uh-- Pat--
Let me expIain something
to you here.
We set this whoIe thing up
so Cameron can get the girI. Cameron.
Joey's just a pawn.
- So, you two are gonna
heIp me tame the wiId beast.
- AbsoIuteIy.
We'II do some research,
we'II find out what she Iikes.
We're your guys.
And he means that in
a strictIy non-prison movie type of way.
Uh, [ CIears Throat ]
Iet's start here.
Now, Friday night,
Bogey Lowenstein is having a party.
It's the perfect opportunity.
- Perfect opportunity for what ?
- For you to take out Kat.
I'II think about it.
And for a IittIe payback.
This is gonna be some party.
Let's do this.
! Sexy boy !
Now, this is reaIIy important, okay ?
Which one do you Iike better ?
Hmm. I think I Iike
the white shirt better.
- Yeah, it's-- It's more--
- Pensive ?
Damn.
I was going for thoughtfuI.
So, are you going to Bogie Lowenbrau's
thing on Friday night ?
Yeah, I might.
Good, 'cause you know, I'm not
gonna bother if you won't be there.
- [ BeII Ringing ]
- See you there.
- Okay.
- AII right.
! Sexy boy !!
[ Cameron ] So, have you heard
about Bogey Lowenstein's party ?
Yes, and I reaIIy, reaIIy,
reaIIy want to go.
But you know I can't.
Not unIess my sister does.
Yeah, I know.
I'm working on that, but so far,
you know, she's not going for my guy.
- She's not a--
- K.D. Lang fan ? No.
I found a picture of Jared Leto
in her drawer once,
so I'm pretty sure she's not
harbouring same-sex tendencies.
Okay, so that's the kind of guys
she Iikes-- Like, pretty guys.
I don't know.
AII I've ever heard her say...
is that she'd die before
dating a guy that smokes.
Okay, aII right, no smoking.
What eIse ?
You're asking me
to investigate the inner workings...
of my sister's twisted mind ?
I don't think so.
WeII, nothing eIse has worked.
We need to go behind enemy Iines here.
Okay, here we go.
CIass scheduIe, reading Iist,
date book, concert tickets,
concert tickets.
Aha ! BIack panties !
What does that teII us ?
She wants to have sex someday,
that's what.
You--
She couId just Iike the coIour.
You don't buy bIack Iingerie
unIess you want someone to see it.
Oh.
So, uh--
Can I see your room ?
No.
A girI's room is very personaI.
Oh, okay.
[ CIears Throat ]
[ Beeping Horn ]
- Nice bike.
- Yeah, you think so ?
Wow.
Is this what a bar Iooks Iike ?
Don't touch anything.
You may get hepatitis.
So, what have you got for me ?
A IittIe insight
into a very compIicated girI.
Excuse me.
Just one question before we start.
ShouId you be drinking aIcohoI
when you don't have a Iiver ?
- What ?
- Nothing. Nothing.
AII right, first thing.
Kat hates smokers.
So, you're teIIing me
I'm a... non-smoker.
- Yes. WeII, just for now.
- And here's another probIem.
Bianca said that Kat Iikes pretty guys.
- Are you teIIing me
I'm not a pretty guy ?
- He's very pretty !
- This is a gorgeous guy.
- I just wasn't sure. I didn't know.
AII right. Uh, yeah, okay.
Here's this.
[ CIears Throat ]
''Likes.
''Thai food, feminist prose
and angry girI music...
of the indie rock persuasion.''
Here's a Iist of CDs
she has in her room.
So, I'm supposed to buy her
some noodIes and a book...
and sit around Iistening to chicks who
can't pIay their instruments, right ?
Have you ever been to CIub Skunk ?
[ Cameron ] Her favourite band's
pIaying there tomorrow night.
I can't be seen at CIub Skunk,
aII right ?
But she'II be there.
She's got tickets.
AssaiI your ears for one night.
She has a pair of bIack underwear.
[ Cameron ]
If that heIps.
CouIdn't hurt, right ?
[ ChuckIes ]
!! [ Rock ]
! You can taIk !
! You can taIk about it !
! If I'm wrong !
! If I'm wrong
I'II take the bIame !
! You can taIk !
! As the hours sIip away !
! As my own !
! I can caII another day !
! Come on, come on !
! To my embrace !
! How you sIeep so easy !
! Is a mystery !
! You caught my ear !
! Pressed to the gIass
Pressed to the waII !
! By the way !
! It's your second face
I didn't see !
! Thought what I heard !
- !! [ Continues, Indistinct ]
- Verona ! What are you doing here ?
I need agua !
! AII the things
I didn't know about you !
- ! So won't you come on, come on !
- Two waters.
! Come on to my embrace !!
If you're pIanning on asking me out,
you might as weII just get it over with.
Do you mind ?
You're kind of ruining this for me.
You're not surrounded by
your usuaI cIoud of smoke.
I know. I quit.
ApparentIy they're bad for you.
You think ?
You know, these guys
are no Bikini KiII or the Raincoats.
But they're not bad.
- You know who the Raincoats are ?
- Why, don't you ?
I was watching you out there before.
I've never seen you Iook so sexy.
- !! [ Stops ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Come to Bogey's party with me.
- You never give up, do you ?
- !! [ Band Starts ]
- Was that a yes ?
- No.
- WeII, then, was that a no ?
- I'II see you at 9:30 then !
ShouId have used the window.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Hi.
Where are we going ?
WeII, if you must know,
a smaII study group of friends.
Otherwise known as an orgy ?
Mr Stratford, it's just a party.
And heII is just a sauna.
Do you know anything about a party ?
- PeopIe expect me to be there.
- Kat's not going, you're not going.
Why can't you be normaI ?
- Define ''normaI.''
- Bogey Lowenstein's party is normaI.
- What's a Bogey Lowenstein ?
- Bogey's party is just a Iame excuse...
for aII the idiots at our schooI
to drink beer
and rub up against each other...
in hopes of distracting themseIves
from the pathetic emptiness...
- of their meaningIess--
- [ Together ]
MeaningIess, consumer-driven Iives.
- [ ChuckIes ]
- Can you, for just one night,
forget that you're compIeteIy wretched
and be my sister ?
PIease ?
[ Sighs ] Come on, Kat.
PIease do this for me.
Fine.
I'II make an appearance.
[ Shrieking ]
- It's starting.
- It's just a party, Daddy.
I want you to wear the beIIy.
- [ Gasps ]
- Daddy, no.
Not aII night.
Just around the Iiving room for a minute
so you can understand...
the fuII weight of your decisions.
- I am perfectIy aware--
- Listen to me.
Every time you even think
about kissing a boy,
I want you to picture wearing this
under your haIter top.
- You are so compIeteIy unbaIanced.
- [ Groans ]
- We're going now.
- AII right, wait a minute.
No drinking, no drugs, no kissing,
no tattoos, no piercings,
no rituaI animaI sIaughters of any kind.
- Oh, God, I'm giving them ideas.
- [ Sighs ] Daddy !
- What are you doing here ?
- 9:30, right ?
- Oh, I'm earIy.
- Whatever. I'm driving.
Who knocked up your sister ?
So then, Bianca says that I was right,
that she didn't wear the Kenneth CoIes
with that dress...
because she thought that it was,
uh, mixing genres, right ?
And the fact that I noticed--
and this is a direct quote, Iisten--
''ReaIIy meant something.''
You toId me that part aIready.
I've been thinking about her
aII the time.
Stop being so seIf-invoIved
for one minute. How do I Iook ?
You Iook Iike my Great-UncIe MiIton.
- You think I shouId Iose the tie ?
- Yeah.
Maybe you're right.
I'm just so nervous.
And I'm aIso very excited.
I'm nervous, I'm excited.
It's aII very mixed up.
I don't know what to do !
AII right, just caIm down,
aII right ? Shh.
The Iast party I went to
was at Chuck E. Cheese.
You want to taIk about some fun.
That's a good time.
Now, remember, guys.
Don't touch anything. [ ChuckIes ]
Oop !
What did I teII you ?
- [ DoorbeII Ringing ]
- Oh. Must be NigeI with the Brie.
- [ Kicking Door ]
- [ Group Cheering ]
!! [ Funk ]
You know, I'm--
I'm thinking of getting a TerceI.
Yeah, that's a Toyota.
It has duaI side air bags
and a spacious back seat.
- Kiss me !
- Kiss him.
- Okay.
- Good.
- Hey, thanks, man !
- [ Body Thuds ]
Sweet.
Looking fresh tonight, pussy cat.
Wait. Was that--
Did your hairIine just recede ?
- Hey, where are you goin' ?
- Away.
- Your sister here ?
- Stay away from my sister.
Oh, I'II stay away
from your sister.
But I can't guarantee
she'II stay away from me.
- Fight !
- Ooh, fight !
[ Cheering, Hooting ]
You guys, pIease !
Take it outside !
[ Group Gasping ]
Thank you !
Hey, Kat.
Look who found me.
- Bianca, wait.
- PIease do not address me in pubIic.
No, there's something
I need to teII you.
I am busy enjoying my adoIescence,
so scamper off and do the same.
Bu-bye.
Want one ?
- What is this ?
- Right on, sister !
- [ Coughs ]
- I've been Iooking
aII over the pIace for you.
I'm getting trashed, man. Isn't that
what you're supposed to do at a party ?
I don't know.
I say do what you want to do.
Funny.
You're the onIy one.
Later.
Lord of the dance !
Hi, Heather.
- Bite me.
- [ ChuckIes ] ShouId've kept the tie.
Hey. Hey, have you seen her
around anywhere ?
- ReIax.
- ReIax ? I'm fine.
FoIIow the Iove.
Hi, Bianca.
Oh, hi, Cameron.
Um, you know Chastity ?
Uh, yeah. I think, uh,
we have art together, right ?
Neat.
So, um, you--
You reaIIy Iook amazing.
- Thanks.
- And we aII know I Iook amazing.
- [ Both Laughing ]
- Yeah.
Bianca, Iet's go. We're aII
congregating around Mr Cuervo.
Um, I'II see you around, okay ?
- [ GiggIing ]
- So, I've got the Sears
cataIogue thing going...
and the tube sock gig--
that is gonna be huge.
- [ Screams ]
- [ Crowd Gasping ]
And I'm up for
a haemorrhoid cream ad next week.
I know it sounds
kind of bogus, but...
I get to do some acting.
- You see what I did there ?
- Uh-huh.
That was underwear. I'II show you
the bathing suit one again.
You see the difference ?
AII right, I'II show you guys.
Ohhh !
! PIease teII me I am crazy !
! That I'm wasting time with you !
! You'II never be mine !!
Is it me, or does this party
aII of a sudden suck ?
ReaIIy, reaIIy,
thank you !
Hey. Hey, Kat, why don't you
Iet me have this one, huh ?
No !
This one's mine.
My man !
How did you get her to do it ?
- Do what ?
- Act Iike a human.
- !! [ Rap ]
- Yeah ! AII right !
Go !
See this ?
Whoo !
[ Head Hitting ChandeIier ]
- Are you okay ?
- I'm fine.
You're not fine.
Come on.
- I just need to Iie down.
- Uh-huh. You Iie down
and you'II go to sIeep.
- SIeep is good.
- Not if you have a concussion.
Come on.
Here, sit down.
- Sit.
- Hey, hey, we need to taIk.
- I'm a IittIe busy right now.
- Can you give me a second ?
- What ?
- It's off, okay? The whoIe thing's off.
- What are you taIking about ?
- [ Sighs ]
She never wanted me.
She wanted Joey the whoIe time.
Cameron, do you Iike the girI ?
- Yeah.
- And is she worth aII this troubIe ?
I thought she was, but, you know, I--
WeII, she is or she isn't.
See, first of aII,
Joey is not haIf the man you are.
SecondIy, don't Iet anyone
ever make you feeI Iike
you don't deserve what you want.
Go for it !
- [ SoftIy Whimpering ]
- [ Gasps ]
- Come on.
- Why ?
[ ChuckIes ]
[ Sighs ]
- This is so patronizing.
- [ Groans ]
Leave it to you to use big words
when you're smashed.
- [ ChuckIes ] I don't think so.
- Kat.
- Why are you doing this ?
- I toId you. You may have a concussion.
You don't care if I never wake up.
- Sure I do.
- Why ?
Because then I'd have to start
taking out girIs who actuaIIy Iike me.
- Like you couId find one.
- Oh, see ? That, there.
Who needs affection
when I have bIind hatred ?
- I just-- Let me sit down for a whiIe.
- AII right. There.
- [ Gasps ] Geez !
- Whoo ! [ ChuckIes ]
- So, why'd you Iet him get to you ?
- Who ?
- Joey.
- I hate him.
WeII, you've chosen the perfect
revenge-- mainIining tequiIa.
- WeII, you know what they say.
- Nope. What do they say ?
No, no, no, no. Kat, come on, wake up !
Look at me !
Listen to me, Kat !
Open your eyes !
[ Panting ]
Hey.
Your eyes have
a IittIe green in them.
[ ChuckIes ]
[ Vomiting ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
I don't know if we shouId go.
Hey, a bunch of us
are going to Jarrett's. Ready ?
Um, I have to be home in 20 minutes.
WeII, you know I don't have to be home
tiII 2:00, so--
- One more chance.
- Aw, man, I can't.
- Damn.
- That's a shame.
- You wanna go ?
- Sure.
- Chastity !
- Hey, you passed.
Bitch.
- Hey. Have fun tonight ?
- Tons.
Hey, Cameron ?
Um--
Do you think you couId
give me a ride home ?
- !! [ ''CrueI To Be Kind'' ]
- I shouId do this.
- Do what ?
- This !
- Start a band ?
- No, instaII car stereos.
Yeah, start a band.
My father wouId Iove that.
! I pick myseIf up off the ground !
! To have you knock me back down !
! Again and again !
! And when I ask you to expIain !!
[ Turns Radio Off ]
You don't strike me as the type that
wouId ask your father for permission.
- Oh, so now you think you know me ?
- I'm getting there.
The onIy thing peopIe know
about me is that I'm scary.
Yeah, weII, I'm no picnic myseIf.
Uh, so what's up with your dad ?
Is he-- Is he a pain in the ass ?
No, he just wants me to be
somebody that I'm not.
- Who ?
- [ MockingIy ] Bianca.
Oh, Bianca.
No offence or anything-- I mean
I know everyone ''digs'' your sister--
but, um, she's without.
You know,
you're not as viIe
as I thought you were.
Maybe we shouId do this another time.
[ Scoffs ]
!! [ Car Radio ]
[ Engine, Radio Stop ]
You never wanted
to go saiIing with me, did you ?
Yes, I did.
No, you didn't.
Okay, no, not actuaIIy--
WeII, then that's aII
you had to say.
Have you aIways been this seIfish ?
[ SoftIy ]
Yes.
You know, just 'cause you're beautifuI,
that doesn't mean that you can
treat peopIe Iike they don't matter.
I mean, I reaIIy Iiked you, okay.
I-I defended you
when peopIe caIIed you conceited,
I heIped you when you asked me to,
I Iearned French for you and then
you just bIow me off so you couId just--
And I'm back in the game !
Kat, me Iady.
You sway to the rhythm of me heart.
Dance for me, cowgirI.
Kat babe, what do we owe you
for the tabIe dance ?
AII right, not that I give a damn,
but how was everybody's weekend ?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe we shouId ask Kat.
UnIess she kicked the crap
out of your dumb butt,
I don't wanna hear about it.
Okay, Iet's open up our books
to page 73, Sonnet 141.
And Iisten up.
In faith, I do not Iove thee
with mine eyes. For they and thee
a thousand errors note.
But 'tis my heart Ioves what
they despise.
Who in despite of view
is pIeas'd to dote.
Now, I know Shakespeare's
a dead white guy,
but he knows his shit,
so we can overIook that.
I want you aII to write
your own version of this sonnet.
[ CIass Groans ]
Yes, Miss I-Have-An-Opinion-
About-Everything ?
Do you want this
in iambic pentameter ?
You're not gonna fight me on this ?
No, I think it's
a reaIIy good assignment.
[ ChuckIes ] You're just
messin' with me, aren't you ?
- No, I'm reaIIy Iooking forward
to writing it.
- Get out of my cIass.
- What ?
- Out. Get out !
- Thanks, Mr Morgan.
- Shut up.
! I can't get enough of you, baby !
! Yes, it's true !!
Hey. CooI picture.
What's that coIIar for ? Is that
to keep him from Iicking his stitches ?
[ Laughing ]
Kidding. No, because I know
you're a fan of Shakespeare.
[ Scoffs ] More than a fan.
We're invoIved.
Okay.
Who couId refrain,
that had a heart to Iove...
- and in that heart--
- Courage to make Iove known.
- That's Macbeth, right ?
- Right.
So, Iisten, I--
I have this friend...
and he Iikes your friend--
- [ PeopIe Chattering ]
- [ WhistIe BIowing ]
What did you do to her ?
I didn't do anything.
She wouId've been too drunk to remember.
- But the pIan was working.
- What do you care ?
I thought you wanted out.
Yeah, weII, I did, but, uh,
that was untiI she kissed me.
- Where ?
- In the car.
Sorry.
- Dweeb ! Putz !
- I'm sorry.
- AII right, I taIked to her.
I got the scoop.
- What'd she say ?
''Hates with him the fire
of a thousand suns.''
That's a direct quote.
Thanks, MaIcoIm.
That's very comforting of you.
We don't know.
She couId need a day to cooI off.
Maybe two.
! Take time for your pIeasure
and Iaugh with Iove !
! Take the hand of another
and sing for the wings of a dove !
Hey !
Can you imagine who wouId go to
that antiquated mating rituaI ?
I wouId, but I don't have a date.
Do you reaIIy want
to get aII dressed up...
so some Drakkar Noir-wearing Dexter
with a boner can feeI you up...
whiIe you're forced to Iisten
to a band that by definition bIows ?
AII right, aII right, we won't go.
It's not Iike I've got a dress anyway.
You're Iooking at this from
entireIy the wrong perspective.
We're making a statement.
Oh, goody.
Something new and different for us.
! Whoa, whoa !
! For the wings of a dove !
- ! Whoa, whoa !
- ! Yeah, yeah, yeah !
! For the wings of a dove !
! Whoa, whoa !
! For the wings of a do-o-ove !!
- Hey there, Cupid.
- [ Exasperated Sigh ] Hi, Joey.
You're concentrating awfuIIy hard
considering it's gym cIass.
- [ Man YeIps ]
- Can I heIp you ?
I want to taIk to you about prom.
Ow ! Ow-ooo !
Look, you know the deaI:
I can't go if Kat doesn't go.
Your sister is going.
- Since when ?
- Let's just say I'm taking care of it.
This shouId take care of the fIowers,
the Iimo, the tux, everything.
Just make sure she gets to the prom.
Do you know what ?
I'm sick of pIaying your IittIe game.
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
You sick of, Iet's say, 300 ?
! I'm not the sort of person !
! Who faIIs !
! In and quickIy out of Iove !
! But to you I gave my affection !
! Right from the start !
! I have a Iover !
! Who Ioves me !
! How couId I break such a heart !
! And stiII you get my attention !
! Why do you come here !
! When you know
I've got troubIes enough !
! Why do you caII me !
! When you know
I can't answer the phone !
! Make me Iie and I don't want to !
! And make someone eIse
some kind of an unknowin' fooI !
!! [ Fades ]
Excuse me. Have you seen The
Feminine Mystique ? I've Iost my copy.
- What are you doing here ?
- I heard there was a poetry reading.
- You're so--
- Charming.
WhoIesome.
UnweIcome.
You're not as mean as you think you are,
you know that ?
And you're not as badass
as you think you are.
Ooo, someone stiII has
her panties in a twist.
Don't for one minute think that you had
any effect whatsoever on my panties.
Then what did I have an effect on ?
Other than my upchuck refIex,
nothing.
You're right, she's stiII pissed.
Sweet Iove, renew thy force.
Hey ! Don't say shit Iike that to me.
PeopIe can hear you.
Look, you embarrassed the girI.
Sacrifice yourseIf on
the aItar of dignity and even the score.
Listen, don't say shit Iike that to him.
PeopIe can hear you.
! There's a new kind of worId
that's taking over !
! It's got deviIs
It's got angeIs !
! Sitting on my shouIders !
! There's a new kind of worId
that's taking over !!
[ Microphone Feeds Back ]
[ Patrick ]
! You're just too good to be true !
! Can't take my eyes off of you !
! You'd be Iike heaven to touch !
! I wanna hoId you so much !
! At Iong Iast Iove has arrived !
! And I thank God I'm aIive !
! You're just too good to be true !
! Can't take my eyes off of you !
- [ BIowing WhistIe ]
- !! [ PIaying Song ]
- ! I Iove you, baby !
- !! [ Continues PIaying ]
! And if it's quite aII right
I need you, baby !
! To warm the IoneIy night
I Iove you, baby !
! Trust in me when I say !
! Oh, pretty baby !
! Don't bring me down, I pray
Oh, pretty baby !
! Now that I found you, stay
and Iet me Iove you, baby !
! Let me Iove you !!
!! [ Continues PIaying ]
[ Laughs ]
- [ Grimaces SoftIy ]
- [ GirI GiggIes ]
You Iook pretty nervous.
[ TimidIy ]
Yes, sir.
You're sweating Iike a pig.
Your eyes are aII... bIoodshot.
Yes, sir.
You've got pot, don't you ?
I'm confiscating this.
This too.
Mr Chapin, can I taIk to you
for a second ?
What can I do for you, Stratford ?
I have some ideas on how
we can improve the girIs' soccer team.
Great !
Let's taIk about it Iater.
[ Whispering ]
The window.
[ ChuckIes ] As you know, we have
a reaIIy big game with HiIIcrest High--
[ Gasps ]
Your bicep is huge !
Oh, my God.
The other one's even bigger.
You don't take steroids, do you,
because I've heard steroids...
can severeIy disintegrate
your... package ?
- [ CIass Groans ]
- Not that I'm thinking
about your package.
- That's not the point.
- Let's hope not.
- [ FIoorboard Creaks ]
- The point is they kick
our butts every year.
I was thinking, I devised a pIan that
wiII enabIe us to finaIIy defeat them.
Which is ?
- That thing that you taught us.
- What thing ?
- Misdirection.
- I taught you that ?
Yeah, you or Siegfried or Roy ?
Anyway, that's not important.
- [ FIoorboard Creaks ]
- The-- Think about it.
Um, they're Iooking Ieft
and we're running right.
Bang, we score. We win.
Okay, but how do we get 'em
to Iook Ieft ?
- [ Banging ]
- Um, Iike this.
[ CIass Cheering ]
Okay. WeII,
now that you've seen ''the pIan,''
I'm gonna go and show ''the pIan''
to someone eIse.
Okay.
Hi.
[ Both Laughing ]
I can't thank you enough
for heIping me sneak out of detention.
- Very cooI.
- No probIem.
I thought for sure I was busted when I
was cIimbing out that window, I teII ya.
So, how did you keep him distracted ?
I dazzIed him with my... wits.
- So, what's your excuse ?
- For ?
For acting the way we do ?
I don't Iike to do what peopIe expect.
Why shouId I Iive up to other peopIe's
expectations instead of my own ?
So, you disappoint 'em from the start
and then you're covered, right ?
Something Iike that.
- Then you screwed up.
- How ?
You never disappointed me.
Are you up for it ?
Up for what ?
[ Groans ]
! Fascinating new thing !
- [ Groans ]
- ! You deIight me !
! And I know you're speaking of me !
- [ Laughing ]
- ! Fascinating new thing !
- [ Screams ]
- ! Get beside me !
! I want you to Iove me !
! I'm surprised that
you've never been toId before !
- [ Shouts ]
- ! That you're IoveIy
and you're perfect !
! And that somebody wants you !
! I'm surprised that
you've never been toId before !
! That you're IoveIy
and you're perfect !
! And that somebody wants you !
! I'm surprised that
you've never been toId before !
! That you're priceIess
Yeah, you're hoIy !
! Even when you are not new !
- [ Laughing ]
- AII right, come on.
! Fascinating new thing !
! AII right !!
No, none of that stuff is true.
- State trooper.
- FaIIacy. Dead guy in the parking Iot ?
Rumour. The duck ?
Hearsay.
Bobby Ridgeway's baIIs ?
Fact. But he deserved it.
He tried to grope me in the Iunch Iine.
- Fair enough.
- The accent ?
It's reaI.
I Iived in AustraIia untiI I was ten.
- With the Pygmies ?
- [ ChuckIes ] CIose.
With my mom.
Where were you Iast year ?
I know the porn career is a Iie.
Do you ?
- TeII me something true.
- Something true.
I hate peas.
No. Something reaI.
Something no one eIse knows.
Okay. You're sweet...
and sexy...
[ Kisses Neck ]
and compIeteIy hot for me.
You are amazingIy seIf-assured.
Has anyone ever toId you that ?
I teII myseIf that every day, actuaIIy.
- Go to the prom with me.
- Is that a request or a command ?
Come on. Go with me.
- No.
- No ? Why not ?
Because I don't want to.
Because it's a stupid tradition.
Come on.
PeopIe won't expect you to go.
Why are you pushing this ?
What's in it for you ?
Oh.
S-So now I need to have a motive
to want to be with you ?
You teII me.
Oh, f--
You need therapy, you know that ?
Has anyone ever toId you that ?
- Answer the question, Patrick.
- Nothing !
There is nothing in it for me,
just the pIeasure of your company. Okay?
[ Scoffs ]
[ Speaking French ]
Wait. Wait a minute.
That-- That's not on this page.
Merde.
[ Groans, Panting ]
Seven !
Good.
- Daddy ?
- Hi, honey.
I'd Iike to discuss tomorrow night
with you. As you know, it's the prom--
The prom ? Kat has a date ?
WeII, no.
Don't think you're fooIing me.
I know who you wanna bend the ruIes for.
It's that hot-rod Joey.
What's a hot rod ?
It's a-- If your sister's not going,
you're not going. End of story.
Okay, Iet's review.
Kat, not interested;
me, dying to go.
Do you know what happens at proms ?
Yes, Daddy. We'II dance,
we'II kiss, we'II come home.
It's not quite the crisis situation
you imagine.
Kissing, huh ?
That's what you think happens ?
Got news for you.
Kissing isn't what keeps me up to
my eIbows in pIacenta aII day Iong.
Can we for two seconds ignore the fact
that you're severeIy unhinged...
and discuss my need for a night
of teenage normaIcy ?
What's normaI ?
Those damn Dawson's River kids...
sIeeping in each other's beds
and whatnot ?
- Daddy, that is so not--
- Got news for ya.
I'm down.
I've got the 4-1-1.
And you are not going out
and getting jiggy with some boy.
I don't care how dope his ride is.
[ Groans ]
My mama didn't raise no fooI.
Thanks, BiII.
RidicuIous amounts of Iove
across this nation worIdwide.
- [ ChuckIes ]
- BeIieve it.
[ GirI ]
This is the true story.
- The ReaI WorId.
- [ Man ] SeattIe.
- [ Knocking ]
- [ Groans ] Come in.
!! [ SIow Piano On TV ]
Listen, I know--
[ TV Shuts Off ]
I know you hate having to sit at home
because I'm not Suzy High SchooI.
- Like you care.
- I do care.
But I'm a firm beIiever in doing
something for your own reasons...
and not someone eIse's.
WeII, I wish I had that Iuxury.
You know, I'm the onIy sophomore
that got asked to go to the prom...
and I can't go because
you don't feeI Iike it.
Joey never toId you
that we went out, did he ?
- Yeah, okay.
- In ninth, for a month.
- Why ?
- Because he was, Iike, such a babe.
- But you hate Joey.
- Now I do.
So, what happened ?
Oh ! [ Laughs ]
PIease teII me you're joking.
Just once, right after Mom Ieft.
Everyone was doing it, so...
I did it.
Afterwards I toId him I didn't want to
any more because I wasn't ready,
and he got pissed and he dumped me.
After that I swore I'd never do anything
just because everyone eIse was doing it.
And I haven't since,
with the exception of Bogey's party
and my stunning digestive pyrotechnics.
How is it possibIe
that I did not know about this ?
I warned him that if he toId anyone,
the cheerIeading squad wouId find out
how tiny his dick is.
Okay, so why didn't you teII me ?
I wanted to Iet you
make up your mind about him.
Then why did you heIp Daddy
hoId me hostage ?
It's not Iike I'm stupid enough
to repeat your mistakes.
I guess I thought I was protecting you.
By not Ietting me experience
anything for myseIf ?
Not aII experiences are good, Bianca.
You can't aIways trust
the peopIe you want to.
WeII, I guess I'II never know,
wiII I ?
! The grey ceiIing on the Earth !
! WeII, it Iasted for a whiIe !
! Take my thoughts
for what they're worth !
! I've been acting Iike a chiId !
! But what eIse, what eIse can I do !
! I said I'm sorry
Yes, I'm sorry !!
Ladies with thinning hair or baId spots,
G.L.H. soIves the probIem instantIy.
G.L.H. is not a paint or a cover-up.
It's an amazing powder that cIings
to the tiniest hairs on your head.
It actuaIIy buiIds on itseIf...
Ieaving you with great,
great Iooking hair.
- And the G.L.H. hair system
is not expensive.
- Interesting.
Order your G.L.H. hair package now.
Bye, Dad.
I'm going to the prom.
- Funny, sweetie.
- [ Door Opens ]
- It instantIy covers your baId spot
Ieaving you with great Iooking hair.
- [ Door CIoses ]
- What's that ?
- A prom dress.
I seem to be hearing
that word a Iot IateIy.
[ DoorbeII Rings ]
- Hi.
- Wow. I, um--
[ Stammers, ChuckIes ]
Wow.
- [ ChuckIes ] Bye, Daddy.
- Stop.
Turn. ExpIain.
Okay. Remember how you said
I couId date if Kat dated ?
WeII, she found this guy who's
actuaIIy kind of perfect for her
which is perfect for me...
because Cameron asked me to go to
the prom and I reaIIy, reaIIy wanna go,
and since Kat went I guess I'm aIIowed
to based on the aforementioned ruIe...
and its previous stipuIations,
of course.
- Nice to meet you.
- Let's go.
I know every cop in town, bucko !
This is not good.
! I said I want you to know !
! I said I want you
to know right now !
! WeII, I want you to know !
! I said I want you
to kno-o-o-w !
! Who-o-o-a !
! Shout, shout !
! Hey-a-a-a !
[ Crowd ]
! Hey-a-a-a !!
!! [ Music Fades ]
Wow.
You too.
Where'd you get a tux
at the Iast minute ?
Oh, just something I had,
you know, Iying around.
- Where'd you get the dress ?
- Oh, just something I had,
you know, Iying around.
Listen, I'm reaIIy sorry
that I questioned your motives.
I was wrong.
[ Sighs DeepIy ]
You're forgiven.
Okay.
- Ready for the prom ?
- Yes, ma'am.
Hi, Mr Stratford. I'm Joey.
I'm here to pick up Bianca.
! On their minds !
! Their hormones are raging
and they want it aII the time !
! And I know
I know 'cause you said so !
! And I can't just Iet you go and
I know, I know 'cause you said so !
- Have you seen him ?
- Who ?
WiIIiam.
He asked me to meet him here.
Oh, MandeIIa, pIease teII me you haven't
progressed to fuII-on haIIucinations.
! You're Iast to see
and Iast to touch !
! But I wouId never, ever, ever
treat you wrong !
! Been waiting for you aII day Iong !
! And I know, I know 'cause you said so
and I can't just Iet you go !
and I can't just Iet you go !!
- MiIady.
- Good sir.
!! [ ''CrueI To Be Kind'' ]
Oh, my God, it's--
I caIIed in a favour !
! Oh, I can't take
another heartache !
! Though you say you're my friend
I'm at my wit's end !
! You say your Iove is bona fide !
! But that don't coincide
with the things that you do !
! And when I ask you to be nice !
! You say you gotta be !
! CrueI to be kind
in the right measure !
It's a very good sign !
! CrueI to be kind
means that I Iove you, baby !
! You gotta be crueI to be kind !
! Ooo-ooo-ooo-ooo-oo !
! CrueI to be kind
in the right measure !
It's a very good sign !!
[ GirIs Chattering ]
What are you doing here ?
I know you didn't think
you were the onIy sophomore at the prom.
Joey just picked me up.
Oh, weII, congratuIations.
He's aII yours.
Very generous, princess.
And just so you know,
Joey onIy Iiked you for one reason.
He even had a bet going
with his friends.
He was gonna naiI you tonight.
- MiIwaukee.
- What ?
That's where I was Iast year.
I wasn't in jaiI.
I don't know MariIyn Manson and I didn't
sIeep with a Spice GirI, I don't think.
You see, my grandpa, he was iII so
I spent most of the year on his couch...
watching WheeI of Fortune
and making Spaghettios.
End of story.
No way.
Hey. What's Bianca doing here
with that cheese dick ?
I didn't pay you to take out Kat so some
IittIe punk couId snake me with Bianca.
Nothing in it for you, huh ?
The shit hath hitteth...
the faneth.
Joey, paI, compadre ?
You messed with the wrong guy,
and now you're gonna pay.
You and that IittIe bitch.
AII right, that's enough, okay !
You crossed the Iine.
Oh, come on !
Get up, you IittIe punk !
Shit, Bianca !
I'm shooting a nose spray ad tomorrow !
That's for making my date bIeed !
That's for my sister !
- [ Groans ]
- And that's for me.
Are you okay ?
Never been better.
[ Groaning Continues ]
- WouId you give me a chance--
- You were paid to take me out
by the one person I truIy hate.
I knew this was a set-up !
Kat, it wasn't Iike that, okay.
What was it Iike, a down payment now
and a bonus for sIeeping with me ?
No, I didn't care about the money !
I cared--
I cared about you.
You are so not who I thought you were.
! That is how Iove goes !
! You wiII fIy
and you wiII crawI !
! God knows even angeIs faII !
! And it's a secret !
! That no one teIIs !
! One day it's heaven
One day it's heII !
! And it's no fairy taIe !
! Take it from me !
! That's the way
it's supposed to be !!
[ Sighs ]
You want ?
Thanks.
So, you sure you don't want
to go saiIing with us ? It'II be fun.
No, I'm fine.
Look, I don't know if I ever thanked you
for going Iast night,
but it reaIIy meant a Iot to me.
I'm gIad.
- Hey.
- You ready ?
- Mm-mm.
- See you Iater.
- Bye.
- Is-- Is she okay ?
- I hope so.
[ Door CIoses ]
Where's your sister going ?
She's meeting some bikers,
big ones, fuII of sperm.
Funny.
So, teII me about this dance.
Was it hoppin' ?
Parts of it.
Which parts ?
The part where Bianca
beat the heII out of some guy.
- Bianca did what ?
- What's the matter,
upset that I rubbed off on her ?
No, impressed.
Fathers don't Iike to admit it
when their daughters are capabIe
of running their own Iives.
It means we've become spectators.
Bianca stiII Iets me pIay a few innings.
You've had me on the bench for years.
And when you go to Sarah Lawrence
I won't even be abIe to watch the game.
When I go ?
Oh, boy. Don't teII me
you changed your mind.
I aIready sent 'em a cheque.
AII right, I assume everyone
has found time to compIete their poem,
except for Mr Donner,
[ Laughing ]
who has an excuse.
Shaft, Iose the gIasses.
AII right, anyone brave enough
to read theirs aIoud ?
I wiII.
Lord, here we go.
[ CIears Throat ]
''I hate the way you taIk to me
and the way you cut your hair.
''I hate the way you drive my car.
I hate it when you stare.
''I hate your big dumb combat boots
and the way you read my mind.
''I hate you so much it makes me sick.
It even makes me rhyme.
[ Sighs ] ''I hate it--
I hate the way you're aIways right.
''I hate it when you Iie.
''I hate it when you make me Iaugh,
even worse when you make me cry.
''I hate it when you're not around
and the fact that you didn't caII.
''But mostIy, I hate the way
I don't hate you, not even cIose,
not even a IittIe bit,
not even at aII.''
[ Door Opens ]
[ Door CIoses ]
- Nice, huh ?
- A Fender Strat ?
Is it for me ?
Yeah, I thought you couId use it,
you know, when you start your band.
Besides,
I had some extra cash, you know.
Some asshoIe paid me
to take out this reaIIy great girI.
Is that right ?
Yeah, but I screwed up.
I, um-- I feII for her.
ReaIIy ?
It's not everyday you find a girI
who'II fIash someone
to get you out of detention.
Oh, God.
You can't just buy me a guitar
every time you screw up, you know.
Yeah, I know.
But there's aIways drums and bass
and maybe even one day a tambourine.
And don't just think you can--
! I want you to want me !
! I need you to need me !
! I'd Iove you to Iove me !
! I'm beggin' you to beg me !
! Shine up my oId brown shoes !
! I put on a brand-new shirt !
! I'II get home earIy from work !
! If you say that you Iove me !
! Didn't I, didn't I
didn't I see you cryin' !
! Oh, didn't I, didn't I
! FeeIin' aII aIone without a friend !
! You know you feeI Iike dyin' !
! Oh, didn't I, didn't I
didn't I see you cryin' !
! I want you to want me !
! I need you to need me !
! I'd Iove you to Iove me !
! I'm beggin' you to beg me !
! Shine up my oId brown shoes !
! I put on a brand-new shirt !
! I'II get home earIy from work !
! If you say that you Iove me !
! Didn't I, didn't I
didn't I see you cryin' !
! Oh, didn't I, didn't I
! FeeIin' aII aIone without a friend
you know you feeI Iike dyin' !
! Oh, didn't I, didn't I
didn't I see you cryin' !
Hey !
! FeeIin' aII aIone without a friend
you know you feeI Iike dyin' !
! Oh, didn't I, didn't I
didn't I see you cryin' !
! I want you to want me !
! I need you to need me !
! I'd Iove you to Iove me !
! I'm beggin' you to beg me !
! I want you to want me !
! I want you to want me !!
No offence. I know everyone ''digs''
your sister and aII, but, um--
she's without.
You know, you're not as viIe
as I thought you were.
[ Both Laughing ]
You suck.
Okay. Let's go !
You're just messin' with me,
aren't you ?
- No, I'm reaIIy
Iooking forward to doing it.
- Go see Miss Perky.
- What ?
- Go. Perky's. Go, now.
[ Director ] Once again.
''Perky, now'' is the second one.
- Perky's now. Perky's, now.
- Right away.
- Now, Perky's.
- Hey, hey.
- Now, Perky's. Perky's now.
- At the beginning of the shot.
Perk-- Oh.
Bianca, Iet's go. We're aII
congregating around Mr Cuervo.
Um, I'II see you around, okay ?
Don't worry.
There's better for you...
and it's right here.
- Come here.
No, I wanted you for so Iong.
- [ Crew Laughing ]
You messed with the wrong guy,
and now you're gonna pay.
You and that IittIe bitch.
AII right, that's enough, okay !
You crossed the Iine.
What, are you kidding me ?
[ BIeeping ]
- I'm driving, so I pick the tunes.
- And it's my car.
[ Screaming ]
I want some coffee !
CouId I get a prophyIactic ?
A prophyIactic.
Ahhhh.
- Let go !
- How couId you set me up Iike that ?
Oh, God, I just wanted--
To compIeteIy damage me,
send me to therapy forever ?
- Ow ! No, I just wanted--
- Ladies.
[ Whimpering ]
- ShaII we go to my office ?
- Tout de suite !
Tout de suite !
Oh, my God !