##[Drumbeats]
##
##[Drumbeats Continue]
- Shorter here.
- Shorter?
- Shorter.
- That is short enough.
- Okay, superstar?
- Wow.
What's with the shirt?
[Sniffs, Clears Throat]
That is the most frightening thing
I've ever seen in my life.
- Looks like a deformity.
- I'll fix that.
- Oh, God. Yeah.
- That's better.
If you was a guy,
I might even wanna fuck you.
You mean, if you was a guy
you might even wanna fuck me.
So you're a boy?
Now what?
Come on.
No fuckir way.
Yes fuckir way!
- Ajoke is a joke. Now, come on.
- Don't be a pussy! Ow!
I'm no fuckir pussy.
Let's go home.
Someone's inside.
You've got a date?
I gotta go!
Come here!
Can I talk to you
just for a minute?
You look like a fuckir idiot
in that hat.
I'll be back.
Teena.
##[Rock And Roll]
##
#I don't mind you hanging out #
# Or talking in your sleep #
Yeah, athletic's nice.
But the thing is he's sweet.
And good hair. That's important.
I'm Billy.
Are, are you Nicole?
# Or talking in your sleep #
#I guess you're just what I needed #
#I needed someone to bleed #
You don't seem like
you're from around here.
Where, where do I
seem like I'm from?
Someplace beautiful.
Okay. Hey.
I'm gonna stand right here
until you're safe inside. Okay?
Okay.
# You're just what I needed #
# You're just what I needed, yeah ##
[Man]
You're not goiranywhere! Fucker!
- Get back here, you frucker!
- Scumbag!
You fuckir dyke!
You freak!
You frucked my sister! Open the fruckir
door, you fruckirfraggot!
Open the fuckir door!
Fuck you!
- You fruckirasshole!
- Brothers.
- Alicia.
- Alicia? Who is Alicia?
- Damn! There's a lot of'em!
- What the fuck have you done?
I'll get your fuckir
faggot cousin, too!
- What is the matter with you?
- I don't know!
I don't know what went wrong.
You are not a boy! That is what
went wrong! You are not a boy!
Tell them that. They say
I'm the best boyfriend they ever had.
Do you want your mother to lock
you up again? Is that what you want?
No.
- Then why don't you admit
that you're a dyke?
- Because I'm not a dyke.
- [Man] Fucker!
- [Glass Shattering]
- Fuck. What are you doir?
- The money you owe me.
- Get out of my fuckir pants.
- I want it back. All of it.
Jesus Christ! Careful with that.
You didn't have to do that.
You're not crashing here anymore, Teena!
Get your stuff and go!
##[Country Western]
##
[Exhales]
[Male Singer OverJukebox]
# Why are you hangir 'round my door #
#Never frelt so lonely befrore #
#Faded on my heart #
Bad night?
The worst.
[Sighs]
#Now I know what it's like to cry #
# What it's like to want to die #
- What's your name?
- [Giggles] Candace.
I hate it, though.
I'm thinking of changing it.
[Chuckles]
Sometimes that helps.
I'm Brandon.
I'll pay if you get 'em.
- Sure.
- Marlboros.
I'll be right back.
#Is a new shade ofr blue ##
Check this out.
- My friend's sitting there.
- So?
I said get off.
Excuse me. Why don't you leave the lady
alone? I don't want any trouble.
You've gotta be kidding me.
I didn't ask you
what you wanted, you little fag.
You frucker!
You motherfrucker!
- I'm gonna kick...
- Hold on. Can't I leave you without you
getting us into deeper shit?
[Brandon]
Fuck! I'm gonna get your ass!
Come on, stud.
You got us into this.
Fucker!
[Sirens Wailing]
[Candace] Oh, shit!
Go, John, go!
Go, John. Go, John, go.
Come on!
Cops, man.
They suck.
I would've had those guys
if you wouldn't have stopped me.
Oh, my God.
- What?
- John, look.
Yeah, you're gonna have
a shiner in the morning.
- I am?
- Yeah.
Oh, shit!
- You got a light, man?
- Oh, yeah, here.
Mmm.
- You have got the tiniest hands. Yeah.
- No.
They're big!
Joe Louis had tiny hands.
So? He didn't throw
wild punches without defrense.
If you're gonna get into fights
over girls like Candace,
you've gotta learn a few moves.
- Come on.
- Hey, pussy!
- Fuck you, man!
- Tom, this is Brandon.
- Hi.
John. We'll give you a ride home
as soon as we find the goddamn car!
Sorry. It's up here somewhere.
We're goir to a party. Wanna come?
Candace.
- It's 70 miles away.
- I don't care. The night is young.
And I am a mess, so...
- [John Screams]
- John.
Good.
[Groans]
Are we there yet?
Just up ahead, unless you wanna stop at
a roadhouse and get into another fight.
[Banging]
I don't know where
the fuck I am.
Falls City?
What are you doir down there?
That's not even on the map.
Oh, fuck.
Lonny, my life is a fuckir nightmare.
I got this big court date next week,
and I don't got anywhere to stay.
[Brandon] If I don't make it,
I'm fucked. Can I stay at your house?
- What about those doctors?
- I went.
That shit's insane! You gotta see
shrinks, shoot hormones up your butt.
It costs a fuckir fortune.
I'm gonna be an old man
by the time I get that kind of money.
Do something. You can't
just keep running because...
you're gonna end up in jail.
Forever.
- You really think I can do it?
- You're the butch.
Come straight to my house.
No stopping in bars,
no stealing and no more girls.
No more girls.
- Hey, handsome. Sleep all right?
- Yeah.
Candace.
I remember.
- This is Cody.
- Cody.
Wow. Beautiful.
You still brooding
over your fiancee?
What? Oh. It's a real,
real long story. Hey, hey.
God, you're really good
with kids.
Yeah.
I got one of my own.
Hey, Brandon!
Good news.
I got you a ride.
- All right.
- He's goir to Lincoln later tonight.
Wow.
Cool.
You suck.
Ah, hey, champ!
You headir home tonight?
Tom only dates girls that got
a little butt and a long crack.
You know what I mean?
That's how he picks 'em.
[Snorts]
Tom likes 'em coyote ugly.
You know coyote ugly?
I'm all over some booty.
Thank you.
Looks like you're ridir home
with Ted Bundy.
Shut up, John!
He looks fine, right?
- Just like family.
- [Tom] Speaking ofr.
- Where's Lana?
- We were gonna go on,
but she wandered off.
You got some time
to stick around, right?
Lfr these girls get their shit together,
they're gonna do some karaoke.
Lana!
Where you been?
Come on, Lana. Let's go on, already.
It was your idea.
Who are you?
[John Whooping]
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
[Whooping]
[Laughing]
# The lonesome Texas sun
was setting slow #
#And in the rearview mirror
I watched it go #
[Glass Shattering]
- [Laughing]
- Shut the fuck up!
- #In her golden hair #
- [Laughing Continues]
# I close my eyes for a moment #
# I'm still there #
#The bluest eyes in Texas #
#Are haunting me tonight #
#Another town #
#Another hotel room #
#Another dream
that ended way too soon #
# Left me lonely #
#Praying fror the dawn #
# Searching for the strength
to carry on #
#The bluest eyes in Texas #
#Are haunting me tonight ##
- [Candace] Come on.
- [Kate] Whoo!
What the fuckir fuck? I thought
you were gonna be like five minutes!
We got stuck...
- in time warp.
- Get in the car already.
Hey, Brandon.
- Come with us.
- He's a psycho-killer anyway.
Crash with me again.
[John]
Come on, buddy.
Whoo-hoo!
[Whooping]
Like I was saying,
when I get to the house,
my sister was totally naked
and totally on fire, right?
Oh, yeah. Tom was like
"Where's my camera?" Right?
You saved everyone?
Oh, yeah. Tom's a big hero.
He rescued everybody. Right, dickwad?
Yeah, so when they brought me in,
they were like,
"This is the biggest fire we seen here
in 50 years. You're a hero, man."
I was like, "Yeah?"
They were like, "Yeah."
That's why they put me in
all of'em Lincoln newspapers.
- Probably seen 'em. That was me.
- [Brandon] That's cool.
- [Brandon] What the hell is that?
- [Tom] Bumper skiing.
[Brandon]
Thank you.
[Tom] Flippirburgers.
That's for squares, man. I mean, give me
real work like in the oil fields.
I was thinkir about becoming a
smoke jumper out in Mount Saint Helens.
Fightir fires,
makir lots of money.
- Then traveling all around.
Memphis, Graceland, Tennessee.
- [Tom] You dick.
- Graceland is in Memphis.
And Memphis is in Tennessee.
- [Laughing]
[Laughing]
I know.
[Coughing]
- Maybe you've had enough.
- I ain't had any.
[Tom] No shit, man.
People like you don't need drugs.
You just hallucinate
24 hours a day.
- Oh, shit!
- [Laughing]
All right, Tom, you're up.
Not me, man.
I'm drinking.
All right, Brandon,
that means you. Come on.
- Yeah, stud. Let's go, cowboy.
- Come on, you can do it.
Come on. Come on.
[John]
This here's Brandon.
A mean prizefighter from Lincoln,
so be careful what you say to him.
Very tough.
Don't let 'em scare you.
You can do it.
[Whooping]
[Groans]
- He is a freak.
- [Laughing]
- Come on!
You can do better than that!
- One more time. One more time.
- John, come on. Stop it, John.
- Oh, okay, okay.
- Stop it!
- [Candace Laughing]
- Ow!
- [John] Take it easy.
- [Brandon] No, I'm fne.
- Yeah, you're fne.
- I'm fne!
- Bring that truck back around!
- You're a crazy fucker.
What are we gonna do with you?
- Man, it's nothing.
- Yeah, it's nothing.
[John] Wait, where are you going?
I'll drive!
[Lana]
You don't have a car.
[Sighs]
[Female Singer]
# There's a diamond in her eye #
#It's a-shining up above #
#And the moon in the sky #
#Say you won't tell why #
# We're gamblers that tell you lies #
#Should take a tumble and never lose #
- #In the morning #
- [Whistles]
#She wears a smile
She's made ofr stone ##
Oh, hey.
Ah, you sell...
Ruffles?
Ruffles.
Right over there.
Thank you.
[Bell Ringing]
Dream on, Lana.
- I can't be selling you no beer tonight.
- Fine, I'll browse.
[Bell Ringing]
The beer's in the back
if you want it.
Oh.
- Hey.
- Space cowboy.
I'm so wasted. I don't know
if I'm ever gonna come down.
- That's okay.
- I need beer.
[Whispering] Come here.
Shh. Come here.
It's okay. It's okay.
Stay right here.
It's okay.
Here, um... it's for me.
- Can I see some I.D.?
- Sure.
Oh, look how beautiful.
Jesus Christ! I feel like I'm on acid.
It's like an album cover.
You care to join me?
- Come on.
- Fuck off!
- Hey, hey.
- Don't talk to me like that,
you skanky little snake!
[Phone Ringing]
Kwik Stop.
Hey, Lana!
Lana, wait.
- I'll drive you. I got Candace's car.
- I'm walkir.
Here.
What are you still hanging
around here for anyway?
I thought someone ought to walk you home
before you get an M.I.P. Or somethir.
I don't need anybody
to walk me anywhere.
- Jeez, watch it.
- I don't need you
to stop me from trippir.
Lana, you are
one cranky girl.
You'd be cranky too, " Mr. I'm Going
To Memphis-Graceland-Tennessee,"
if you were stuck in a town
where there's nothing to do but
bumper skiing and chase bats...
every night of your evil fucking life.
I been bored my whole life.
Yeah? Is that why you letJohn tie you
up to the truck and drag you like a dog?
No. I just thought
that's what guys do around here.
Wait a minute.
What's your name again?
Brandon.
The disks took off from here.
[Man On TV]
That's all there is. Let's go back.
Lana?
Just go on home, okay?
God, I hate my life.
Lana!
I hate your life too.
[Exhales]
Don't look at my stupid house.
I'm not looking at your stupid house.
I'm looking at you.
What was I thinking?
Mom?
Come on.
- Come on.
- [Groans]
- Did you eat?
- Uh-uh.
- Upsy. Oh.
- Oh, dear.
- It's all right.
- Okay.
[Lana] Don't.
It's okay.
Hi. Here, drink this.
You'll feel better in the morning.
Come on.
Oh, here.
Yuck.
It's good for ya.
I got a thing fror cow.
I know a song about cows.
My dad taught it to me.
You're not gonna sing
it for me, are you?
[Laughing] No.
I can't sing to save my life.
- Me neither.
- What?
Sure you can.
You sing great.
That wasrt me.
It was karaoke.
So? You were still great.
I couldn't do it.
A lot ofr people I know couldn't.
You don't know any songs
about cows.
Sure, I do.
[Radio. Female Reporter] Comirto you
this beautifrul Friday, October 27.
This is "Corn Report."
It is 8.00 a.m.
It's 45 degrees.
You better watch out.
That winter is coming.
Hey.
Is it always this nice here
in the morning?
I made you a little breakfast.
Wow.
Thank you.
[Lana's Mother]
My hand sucks.
How come Aunt Lana's asleep?
Your Aunt Lana, she is a nice girl,
but she is as lazy...
as the day is long.
Don't you be like that.
Okay? Huh?
April, you answer somebody
when they ask you a question.
- How are things goir with her mother?
- She gave me April for a couple days.
- [Radio. Male Singers]
# Who's that lady #
- I love this song! Yes!
- [Chorus] # Who's that lady #
- # Who's that lady #
- # Who's that lady
Beautifrul lady #
- #A real, real fne lady #
#I wish somebody would
introduce her to me #
Come on, get up.
Dance with me. Come on.
Get up.
#I asked her to dance #
#It was love at frst sight ##
April? Come here.
Jesus! Would you turn down the
goddamn music? I'm trying to sleep!
Whoo, yeah!
- Come on, honey, loosen up.
- No, let me go.
Let me go!
You motherfuckers! Why'd they ever
let you fuckheads out of jail?
[Male Singers]
#L.A. Is crazy #
#I got a shake in my head #
#I freel like I'm dying
And I wish I was dead #
#lfr I live till tomorrow
that'll be a long time #
#I'll reel and I'll frall
but I'll rise on Cod'ine #
# You'll frorget you're a woman #
# You'll frorget about men #
# Try it just once
and you'll try it again #
# You'll frorget about lifre
You'll frorget about time #
#And live all your days
a slave to Cod'ine #
#It's real
Lord, it's real #
# One more time #
#And some ofr them frall #
# To rise on Cod'ine ##
I'm an asshole.
Uh-oh.
- What?
- Blowout.
- [Candace] What happened?
- I'm in the doghouse again,
you know what I mean?
- I've been there my whole life.
- Women, right?
Yeah.
Mmm. You gonna do
a little damage control?
- Then you're gonna
fuck it up all over again.
- Yep. Come on.
Oh, my goodness!
- Hey, who are you?
What's your name, huh?
- April.
April? How'd you get
such a pretty name?
- My daddy.
- Yeah, that's true. I named her.
- Where you goir?
- See Grandma.
All right, go on.
- Got an extra cig, man?
- Mm-hmm.
Thanks, man.
Is she, um, Lana's?
Lana's? No.
No. I had April
with a different girl. Mallory.
This here's my real family,
even if it isn't my real home. You know?
I mean, uh...
Lana...
I don't know.
It's kinda hard to explain.
Well, I got 12 more
like this at home.
I keep it in a secret place.
She wrote to me
when I was in lockup.
Lana did?
Yep. She wrote to me. Even my own mom
didn't write to me, but she did.
Lana and her mom.
They took me in.
Fuck.
Fucker.
- Brandon, honey,
where'd you say your folks are from?
- I'm frrom Lincoln.
But my dad's out in...
in Memphis right now.
And my mom's in Hollywood.
- Hollywood? Oh, wow.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, my sister is a model.
- That's glamorous.
Brandon, while you're up, why don't you
clean these ashtrays for us?
- Fuck you.
- Just playir with you, bud.
Brandon, come here.
Over here.
Closer where I can see you. Let me
look at you in the light. Come on.
Come here. Let me.
I can believe you got a model
for a sister.
You're like
a little movie star yourself.
[Tom]
Hey, April?
- Want a beer?
- Hey!
What the fuck
are you doing?
Here you go, hon.
Have some of Dad's.
Come on. Come on.
Little bit.
Four years ago, you wouldn't
have thought he could take care
ofr himselfr, let alone that kid.
Shit, frour years ago you wouldn't
have been able to talk to him.
Prison. Mm-hmm.
And her mother!
Jesus Christ!
And this one, this one
kept that boy's spirit alive.
Would you just forget
about that?
[John Groaning]
The bastard pissed on me!
This never would've happened
ifr she had the proper training.
- Your mother's an asshole!
- John, she had an accident.
[Candace] It's okay, sweetie.
It's not your frault.
Having fun?
Yeah.
What do you think of my mom?
She's pretty weird, huh?
No, I like her.
You know, I think she's funny.
Are you for real?
Excuse me.
Am I interrupting something?
Brandon, I want you to take
a picture of me and my daughter.
Lana's dad gave us that.
I don't feel like having
my picture taken now.
Come on, honey. Just one.
Come on, son.
Hey!
Well, refill time.
Bring it in
when you're ready, okay?
Okay.
Here, look.
It's not bad, huh?
- Oh! [Groans]
- What?
- No!
- Why not? You're beautiful.
Come over here.
I had a dream
about you last night.
You did?
What happened?
- [Squealing] No!
- Come on, tell me the dream.
Someone walked me home
last night.
I think it was you.
No frair!
Lana, time to go to work.
John, you're too fucked up.
Why don't you let Brandon drive?
Hey, here you go,
little buddy.
You all right?
Tom!
[Engine Sputtering]
[Brakes Squeal]
[Girl]
Nice car.
Why don't you turn down
your radio?
[Mockingly]
Yeah, totally!
- What the fuck are you looking at?
- Wall people.
- What the fuck did you say?
- I said, "Wall people."
[Shouting]
- Bite me, you fuckir fudgepacker!
- Eat me.
[John]
Fuck you!
[Shouting]
Go!
Come on, pussy!
Go faster, you cocksucker.
Go, go, go!
[Kate]
Bitches! Bitches!
Whoo!
[Siren Wailing]
It's the man!
Fuck!
- [Tom] It's the piggers.
- Oh, fuck.
[Tom] He's catching up.
What the fruck?
- Fuck.
- Don't stop, don't stop. Go faster.
Brandon.
Go faster.
- Brandon, stop!
- [Chuckling]
[Tom] They ain't got
no fruckirballs!
[Siren Wailing]
When you hit the gravel,
drop to 40.
[Brandon]
I can't see.
[John] That's okay.
Neither can he. You're flyir.
[Breathing Heavily]
[Siren Wailing]
[Deputy]
Take it out.
[Laughs]
Get off me, Dave.
I wasrt doing anything.
Going awful fast back there,
Mr. Brayman.
- Mind telling me what
you're doing in Falls City?
- Just visiting, officer, sir.
Where are you staying?
[Lana]
He's staying with me.
I can't run a check on this, son,
'cause our computers are down.
But I could run you all in right now.
You could let these guys
go, huh, man?
They ain't got anything to do with it.
I got carried away.
We don't got anything
like this in Lincoln.
Dustless highways?
Only one in Nebraska.
That's a 100 foot drop.
[Sarcastic Chuckle]
- I'm not gonna lock you up,
but you're gettir a ticket.
- Okay.
Those are residential streets
back there, so you slow down.
- Do you read me, Mr. Brayman?
- Absolutely, sir.
Let me see this I.D.
That's pretty slick. Charles Brayman.
I let you down.
I'm sorry.
Man, don't worry about it. We'll take
you down to the tunnel, chase some bats.
Yeah, it's like
the tunnel of love.
God, Candace,
would you get a grip?
- Is that your real birthday?
- No, November 10, '72.
Hey, that's next week.
Let's have a party.
[Candace] Twenty-one!
You're gonna be a man!
Shit.
Don't you never pull
that shit again.
What?
You heard me. I said
don't never pull that shit again.
You got me stopped
by the fuckir cops.
Why, but you're the one
who told me to race after 'em.
I had you in the clear
and you frucked up.
[Sighs]
John, it's over.
Don't get upset.
I'm not upset.
You almost got us killed.
[Clears Throat]
I almost got us killed?
Whoo.
Brandon.
You're the one who led us
90 miles an hour into a cloud of dust,
then shut your eyes when we were
about to go off some 400 froot ravine.
Fuck!
Get out of my goddamn car!
Get out of my motherfucking car!
Get out of my goddamn,
motherfucking, shit-eating car!
Get out ofr my goddamn,
motherfruckin; shit-eating car!
- Not you!
- Fuck you!
No, not you.
[Car Engine Revs]
- [Chuckles]
- Welcome to the psycho ward.
Come on, Kate.
He's taking us to work.
You know,
Tom set that fire hisself.
That's my car!
Doctors say he ain't got
no impulse control.
I'm the only one
who can control that fucker.
Come on.
We'll walk you home, Candace.
You ever try this?
Tom.
Did you set
your own framily's house on fre?
What about this?
You ever do this?
What the fuck, Tom?
Some people punch holes in walls.
This helps snap me back
into reality.
Gets a control ofr this thing
inside ofr me so I don't,
you know, lash out at someone.
Me and John used to do it to ourselves
all the time in lockup.
I could always
go deeper than him.
He's such a wuss.
Try it.
God, I guess I am a pussy
compared to you.
[Chuckles] I'm just jokir
with you, man.
[Whispering]
Fuck.
Fuck!
[Knocking On Door]
Brandon. Hey.
Lana.
I'm so sorry.
I just had to see someone nice.
I just got off work
and I'm having a nervous breakdown.
Just a minute.
I have to pee, okay?
God, I was scared to death
that Candace was gonna catch me.
You know she's obsessed
with fnding a husband.
I'm positive
you're her fravorite candidate.
I can't believe you worked last night.
You must be exhausted.
Me, neither. I do it all the time. You
don't have to be sober to weigh spinach.
- Thanks for the coffee.
- Yeah.
I'm crashing really hard, though.
I, um, have to go back to Lincoln
to take care of some stuff.
- You're really leaving?
- Yeah.
Are you gonna see your sister?
The model.
Yeah.
Oh. Nicole. She's pretty.
Is she gonna be there?
Yeah.
Now that she's married,
we're gonna be taking off any second.
So,
where are you going
on your big trip out of here?
Oh, I don't know.
I guess it's not
all worked out yet.
That's okay.
Um,
thanks for giving
your address to the cops.
It was nothing.
I might hitchhike.
Really?
I've never done that.
Me, neither.
[Clears Throat]
Well...
This might sound really stupid,
but do you think there's anywhere
I could make money doing karaoke?
Why not? People make money
doing all sorts of things.
Did you really write letters
to him in prison?
Give me a break.
I was 13 years old.
Who told you that?
My mom?
He did.
You better go.
Yeah, yeah.
[Male Singer]
# That rusty nail over our frront door #
#Is where I hung our tears
in the rain #
#I threw that horseshoe
into the weeds #
# To see what luck can bring #
# 'Cause you're in your bed
And I'm in mine #
# On either side ofr town #
#I think I might take a ride ##
[Knocking]
Please, please don't get mad.
Um, one night.
One night and I'm gone.
[Sighs] They're not gonna
lock me up, are they?
Teena, how the fuck
do I know what they're gonna do?
- I'm sick ofr watching you fruck up.
- But...
But I'm not fuckir up.
It is so good down there.
In Falls City? They hang faggots there.
Did you know that?
You've never even
been there. Look.
Look.
See, isn't she beautiful?
If you like white trash.
I'm gonna ask her to marry me.
Before or after
your sex change operation?
- Befrore or after you tell her
that you're a girl?
- Shut up!
It's different.
It's working.
No, I'm not gonna fuck it up
this time.
I hope they do
lock you up tomorrow.
[Judge] Keith Pierce, fror the crime ofr
spray painting and smashing 50 new cars,
you are sentenced to six months
at the juvenile detention center.
- [Gavel Bangs]
- Teena Brandon.
Teena Brandon.
Docket 7-2-3-9-1.
Teena Brandon. Docket 7-2-3-9-1.
Grand theft, auto.
[Siren Wailing]
- [Camera Clicks]
- Lana.
Down here.
Brandon.
- Where'd you get that?
- Nice hat.
I gotta go.
My break's almost over.
It looks so different
from the outside.
[Whispering]
You're so pretty.
I feel like
I'm in a trance.
Am I goir too fast?
[Gasping]
[Panting]
[Moaning]
[Coughing]
I cannot wear these.
They make me look fat.
Quit changing the subject.
[Clears Throat]
I saved your ass at work.
Tell us what's goir on?
[Candace] Yeah, I bet Brandon
doesn't think you're frat.
Nobody looks fat
when they're laying down.
I knew it!
I fucking knew it!
We just drove around
taking pictures.
Yeah, right.
[Laughing]
Ooh!
I cannot talk about it.
It's too intense.
Come on, Lana.
I can't take it.
[Panting]
[Moans]
[Brandors Voice]
Are you okay?
[Lana's Voice]
Yeah.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- What?
- I mean...
I don't know.
You're so handsome.
And then we took off our clothes
and went swimmir.
Don't be scared, Brandon.
- Did you do it?
- What do you think?
Whoo!
- ##[Rock And Roll]
- [Shouting, Cheering]
What'd you wish for?
I know what he wished for.
Yeah, baby!
Oh, Mom!
Don't talk so gross.
I'm being frun.
[Sighs]
- Happy birthday.
- [Brandon] You shouldn't have, really.
[Whistles]
Keeping me strong, Mom?
- Happy birthday, sweetheart.
- Thanks, Mom.
Sorry, I forgot mine.
- [Brandon] It's okay.
- I haven't wrapped mine yet.
- Hey, grease monkey.
- How ya doir?
Man, we were doing a job in Omaha.
We could've used a lookout, right, John?
[Mom Chuckling]
John Lotter.
I know your mother,
and I know she taught you how to knock.
We could've been lying around here
naked, fror all you know, baby.
- Where's Lana?
- She's in her room.
Come on, get a beer.
It's Brandors birthday.
Sit with us.