MAN:
There's something l want to tell you.
After l got shot,
you want to know the very first thing
that entered my mind
before l blacked out?
Coins.
l'm 8 years old again
on a tour of the U.S. Mint.
l'm listening to a guide explain
how coins are made.
How they're punched
out of sheet metal.
How they're rimmed and bevelled.
How they are stamped
and cleaned.
And how each and every batch
of coins are personally examined
just in case any have
slipped through with
the slightest imperfection.
That's what popped into my head.
l am a coin
in the United States Army.
l was minted in the year 1980.
l've been punched from sheet metal.
l've been stamped and cleaned.
My ridges have been rimmed
and bevelled.
But now l have
two small holes in me.
l'm no longer in perfect condition.
So there's something else
l want to tell you.
Right before
everything went black,
you want to know the very last
thing that entered my mind?
You.
WOMAN:
Why not? Because there are
a lot of things that you'd be doing.
Just like playing tennis.
RANDY:
Wimbledon? l don't know.
Just going to go. l'm going to
host the thing. Six-thirty.
And you and l could,
like, go at 10?
RANDY: Oh, shit!
SAVANNAH: Oh, no!
Oh, no, Randy, no!
l'm sorry. l'm--
l'll get it, l'll get it,
l'm on it. l'm sorry.
l'm sorry.
Okay? l'm on it.
My whole life
is in that bag.
l got it. l got it.
You got it.
Dude. l was
going to get that.
Yeah, l just--
l mean, thanks for jumping in.
Yeah, no problem.
But l mean, hey, l'll take it.
Thank you so much!
RANDY:
Who jumps off a 20-foot pier?
Wow. Ugh.
Gosh, l'm a mess.
You are a lifesaver.
l'm Savannah.
John.
Brave man.
Uh, this is my life
in here, so l owe--
l owe you.
Don't worry about it.
Nice to meet you, John.
Nice to meet you too.
Y'all have a good night.
Yeah, thanks. l was
in the water for that.
l was seriously
getting it for you.
RANDY: This guy's crazy.
JOHN: Yeah, no, l swear l'm not.
l'm not stalking you.
l just got to get my board.
SAVANNAH:
Um, are you staying here?
JOHN: Yeah, yeah,
l'm from around here.
SAVANNAH:
Hey, John, do you want to--?
My house is right over there.
We were actually
going back right now.
Do you want to join us?
We're just going to
have a barbecue.
No, it's okay. l don't want to,
you know, intrude on y'all.
My dad's making dinner, so...
Okay.
Well, l could at least give you
a beer for the walk home.
Where is it?
Right over there.
{PEOPLE LAUGHING
AND CHATTERING}
{311'S ''AMBER''
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS}
You in the military or something?
Yeah.
Really?
Mm-hm.
What branch
are you in?
Army,
Special Forces.
Oh, Special Forces.
That's, uh...
That's impressive. That's...
ls that like a Special Forces
ring they give you?
ls that what it says on it?
it looks nice on you.
Aren't you supposed
to be wearing a hat too?
Like a French hat, a beret.
Right? That's what it's called?
SAVANNAH: Randy. Randy?
What? l'm just joking with him.
You shouldn't
make fun of a guy
who can kill you
with his bare hands.
Oh-ho! Ooh. Ooh!
Big guy.
Rock them, sock them,
let's go.
How about that?
You know,
l'm going to go get a beer.
Soldier. Pleasure.
l'm sorry about him.
He thinks he likes me.
Yeah, l think
he likes you too.
No, l'm not his type.
He just doesn't know it yet.
{WAILING SOULS'
''THINGS & TIME''
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS}
Mm-hm.
What?
Come on, l just think you're
probably everybody's type.
Whoa!
See what l mean?
ls this who l think it is?
Alan, Alan.
Whoa! Hey, buddy,
l want you to meet
my friend John.
John, this is Alan.
Alan, nice to meet you.
Say hi.
He's a little bit shy,
isn't he?
Hey, where's your dad?
Over there.
MAN:
Two steps behind, as usual.
Sorry, he's like
a heat-seeking missile
every time he sees you.
Oh, hey, l'm Tim.
JOHN: John.
SAVANNAH:
Sorry.
JOHN:
Nice to meet you.
TIM: Oh, you
Special Forces, huh?
JOHN:
Uh, yes, sir.
ALAN:
Vroom! Vroom!
You, uh, stationed
out at Fort Bragg?
No, uh, Germany,
actually.
Oh, you're on leave.
Yes, sir.
Oh. Well, l hope you're
enjoying yourself.
Yeah, uh, l think l am.
l'm sorry, l didn't mean to interrupt.
it뭩 nice to meet you though.
Nice to meet you too.
Come on, son. Let's go.
Let's go.
Hello. Hello, John.
Hello, Alan.
Wow, that was
really amazing.
Yeah?
He never talks to anybody.
Only his family.
He talked to you.
Yeah, but l'm practically
his family. l've known him
since he was born.
Yeah?
{ROSI GOLAN'S ''THINK OF ME''
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS}
{PEOPLE LAUGHING
AND CHATTERING}
When do you go back?
Two weeks.
it must be scary
what you do.
Boring mostly. You know,
long stretches of boring.
Occasional flashes
of scary.
Full moon tonight.
Do you ever notice
how big the moon is
when it's rising?
And how little it gets
when it's up in the sky.
JOHN:
You know, that's just
your perspective.
it actually doesn't matter
where it is in the sky or
where you are in the world
if you hold your hand up
and close one of your eyes.
it뭩 never bigger
than your thumb.
SAVANNAH:
Where'd you learn that?
JOHN:
l don't know.
Somewhere.
JOHN:
Yeah.
SAVANNAH:
Wow.
You just-- You just
made your own fire.
That's very impressive.
Very primal.
But you're still not
going to be able to cook
that hotdog, l fear.
l fear that as well.
l should probably
be getting going anyways.
l'm sorry. l hope you
don't get into, um,
too much trouble.
l think it's probably
too late for that.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Yeah. No, you're welcome.
Would you want to maybe
do this again tomorrow night?
Tomorrow night
is chicken.
l don't think you're
going to want to try it.
Yeah, l was kind of hoping
maybe we'd let somebody
else do the cooking.
Type of thing.
Okay.
Yeah?
So maybe l'll come by around,
uh, 6 or something?
Okay.
All right.
Ah!
Whoa.
So l'll see you soon, then?
l'll see you soon, then.
Yeah. Soon.
TIM: Hey.
Hey, man.
We're headed into town
for some ice cream.
You want a ride?
No, no, no, it's fine.
l don't mind walking
at all. it뭩 fine. Heh.
Sure?
ALAN:
Vroom, vroom!
All right. l appreciate it.
Yeah.
Hey, Alan,
move on over here.
Here, l'll undo your belt.
ALAN:
Five, six, seven, eight,
So how long y'all in town for?
nine.
Oh, we live here
year-round now.
Yeah, we were driving down
every weekend anyways,
so l finally just convinced my wife
this just made the most sense.
JOHN:
Mm.
She didn't want ice cream?
TIM: Who? Oh, my wife?
JOHN: Mm-hm.
Uh, no.
No, actually
she's on vacation herself.
White sheep, white sheep,
white sheep.
it뭩 kind of difficult
to take trips together.
White sheep.
it뭩 fine. We make it work.
l'm up here on the left.
TIM:
Hey, uh, John.
For the record, if you do
anything to hurt Savannah,
l'm going to
have to break something.
Something in your leg.
Some-- One of the bones
in there.
Okay.
it뭩 just l know her father
and he would expect me
to say something like that.
It'd just sound a lot more natural
coming out of his mouth.
it sounded fine.
No, it--
Yes, it did.
No, it didn't.
it did. it really did.
it didn't. But thank you.
ALAN: it really did.
TIM: You think so?
ALAN: Yeah, it did.
TIM: Okay.
TIM: Hey, don't honk
the horn, it's night time.
ALAN:
Vroom, vroom!
TIM: Good night, John.
JOHN: Good night, Tim.
Thanks for the ride.
Yeah, no problem.
Hey, Dad, l'm not,
uh, going to be able
to stay for dinner.
Well, l made
lasagne.
l know you made lasagne.
it뭩 Sunday.
Um...
Can l borrow the car?
Thanks.
SAVANNAH:
Best seafood you'll ever have.
Heh. Yeah, l know.
l used to come here all the time.
Really?
Are you sure you don't
want to go somewhere,
l don't know, nice?
Nice? No, l want to go
somewhere good.
Okay.
{THE DONKEYS'
''EXCELSIOR LADY''
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS}
What the hell
you doing here?
Come on, Steve.
it뭩 been three years already.
l don't want
any trouble here.
JOHN:
You're not going to
get any. l promise.
All right.
Thank you.
What happened
with that guy out there?
What guy?
What's the story with him?
No story.
Really?
Yeah.
He's an old buddy of mine.
What?
Your dad get mad
at you for coming
home late last night?
No. Uh-uh. He's not really
the type that gets mad.
What kind of guy
is he then?
Um...
Quiet one?
Could be worse, l guess.
l guess.
And your mom?
Nope, just me and my dad.
Did he raise you
all by himself?
Yeah.
Why do you want to know
so much about my dad?
Just curious.
Curious about
where you come from.
{RYAN ADAMS'
''ANSWERING BELL''
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS}
l want to meet
your dad.
Tonight.
JOHN: Look, you're--
You're not going to get
very much out of him.
So, l don't know,
just don't take it
personally, okay?
Hey, Pop.
l got somebody
l want you to meet.
SAVANNAH:
Hey.
JOHN:
This is Savannah.
Hi.
it뭩 nice to meet you,
Mr. Tyree.
Um... Hm.
Wow.
He-- This is my--
He collects coins.
He, um-- it뭩 kind of
like his big hobby.
This is amazing.
You have so many coins.
How did you get started
in all this?
Uh... Uh...
Through John, actually.
But it's not his
thing anymore.
Hey, you know, we should
probably maybe go.
SAVANNAH: What is this coin?
MR. TYREE: Uh...
That's a-- That's a
Sacagawea mule.
it뭩 actually...
Wow, it's a mule.
Do you want to see some more?
Absolutely, yes, if you don't mind.
Put this, uh,
glove on then.
Thanks.
MR. TYREE:
This is a humorous one.
This is a satirical coin.
This is massive.
Yeah, William Jennings Bryan,
when he ran for president,
he was-- He believed in--
No, don't turn it over.
Leave it here.
Do you remember that he had
the free silver policy. You remember.
Oh.
And McKinley was his opponent
and he's-- Wait, here.
Now see, that's a real silver dollar.
That's the size of a silver dollar.
And McKinley said that
Wow. That's so weird.
if Bryan had his way,
then the silver dollars
would be that big. Yeah.
That's amazing.
Can you imagine
No.
walking around with that
in your pocket?
SAVANNAH: That's really funny.
MR. TYREE: That's humorous.
Now, these--
Pop, we can't do
this right now. l got to--
We can't be here all night.
l have-- l have some
to show you.
This is fascinating.
MR. TYREE:
These are all matched in colour.
l had fun tonight.
l like your dad.
You shouldn't be
too hard on him.
He loves you.
l can tell
even if you can't.
Whoa, whoa, wait a minute.
Wait, Savannah. l mean...
So l guess l'll see
you soon, then?
l'll see you soon, then.
Where you
been all day?
l've been busy.
You're on
spring break.
You're supposed
to be lounging on
the beach all day.
You're not supposed
to be busy doing things.
l want to show you
something.
SAVANNAH:
The family that lived here,
their home was severely
damaged by the hurricane.
JOHN:
What, so now you're rebuilding it?
SAVANNAH:
Yup. Well, not just me.
You're starting to
make me a little nervous.
Why am l starting
to make you nervous?
Because l'm starting to
think you might be too
good of a person for me.
Oh. No, l'm not
that good of a person.
You're sneaking off every
day to do manual labour
on a house for charity.
On your spring break.
Yeah, you're right.
it뭩 selfish, really,
me being this generous.
But no, seriously.
You don't drink, you don't smoke.
Nope. Nope.
You probably don't sleep around.
Absolutely not.
Mm.
Okay, look, you
got to have a fault.
l do.
Okay, care to enlighten me?
l curse.
No.
l do.
No, you don't.
Yes, l do.
l haven't heard you.
Well, that's because
it's in my mind.
There's a never-ending
stream of curse words
that l'm thinking at all times.
Okay, fine, just say one then.
No, l can't tell you
because it's filthy.
Right.
Yeah.
Okay, all right. Fair enough.
No, l have faults, John.
Trust me, l have plenty
of them. You'll see.
l hope so.
SAVANNAH:
We have to be finished with
this entire house in three weeks.
Hope that
actually happens.
Um, these are going to
be the bedrooms,
the parents' room,
the boys' rooms,
two boys, 7 and 9.
Uh, living room
and the bathroom.
And then this
is the kitchen.
This is the best room because
the mom's a really good cook.
We're going to make
it really beautiful
with white tile floors
and tiles on
the countertops,
and there's going to be a roof.
Ah!
Here, John, come here.
A roof would definitely be good.
it뭩 going to be like this,
but it's going to be everywhere.
it뭩 the only cover
we have.
Nice, we're going to
be here for a while.
Where'd you get
your scar?
Hm?
That one?
Oh. Um...
A knife fight.
it was five years ago,
we were really drunk
and the guy went for my eye.
That's terrible.
Why? He missed.
The way people
act around you,
the way they treated you
at that restaurant...
it뭩 like they're scared of you.
They're not scared of me.
They might be scared
of who l used to be.
And who is that?
Somebody different?
So when did you change?
When you went into the Army?
Yeah. Yeah,
l mean, partly yeah.
And the other part?
l don't know,
l'm still working on that.
So you used to be tough.
And maybe you
still are a little bit.
Mm-hm.
You don't scare me, John.
No?
Mm-mm.
Mm-mm?
Well, you scare me.
{JOSHUA RADIN & SCHUYLER
FISK'S ''PAPERWEIGHT'' PLAYING}
Don't worry about him.
SAVANNAH:
John!
{SAVANNAH SCREAMS
AND LAUGHS}
JOHN:
Heh. Oh!
What, you think you're
safe in there? Okay.
SAVANNAH:
No!
it뭩 all right.
Everybody understands.
Oh! Wow.
What are you
doing over here?
Hm? You're missing
the party.
The party's just managing
fine without me.
What's wrong?
Hm?
Why are you all the way
over here by yourself?
l'm dying, John.
What?
That's not
even funny.
l'm going to miss you.
it뭩 almost over.
No, it's not
almost over.
Yes, it is.
Mm-mm.
l leave tomorrow.
l have to go back to school.
So?
And you.
No, and me nothing.
My commitment's up
in 12 months.
And then l'm back.
For good.
A lot could happen
in 12 months, John.
You don't think
l know that?
l know that.
And l'm not
afraid at all.
l promise you
that it'll all be over
sooner than you think.
Then l'll be
back for good.
You promise?
l promise.
{PEOPLE LAUGHING
AND CHATTERING}
l'm probably going to
be out of the Army way
before you're out of school.
Am l going to be
in the audience
when you graduate?
Oh, l think l might take
a little longer to graduate.
Been spending so much
time around your dad,
and l think now l want
to teach special education.
You don't say.
l don't know
why it's taken me
so long to realize.
l mean, l've lived next
to Alan my whole life--
Wait, l'm sorry, back up.
What does that have to do
with my dad?
Um...
Well, there's...
l mean, there's an
explanation for why
he is the way he is.
Forget it. Never mind.
No, no, no.
No, let's go. Come here.
What? So, just,
what were you saying?
Um...
l grew up next
to a kid with autism.
l kind of have a frame of reference.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, autistic?
You saying my dad's like Alan?
You're saying my dad's
retarded or something?
No, Alan's not retarded,
John. He's autistic.
And there are milder
forms of it, and these
things go undiagnosed.
ls this what
you've been doing?
This entire time you've
just been studying my dad?
No. How could
you even say that?
l've lived with my
dad my entire life.
l've put up with him
my entire life.
You think l don't know
that he's not normal?
Yeah?
You think l need you
to tell me he's not normal?
Yeah.
RANDY:
Hey, soldier, leaving so soon, huh?
Here, have a beer. it뭩 on me.
Come on, you should drink that.
It'll make you feel better.
Now's not a good time, all right?
You a little sad?
No, come on. You just need
to relax, okay? Come on.
Just relax a little bit.
Look, how about just--?
What's going on with Savannah?
Just leave me alone, all right?
How about you get
your hands off me?
Come on, soldier.
What is happening
with you and Savannah--?
Hey, man,
what are you doing?
John!
WOMAN:
Oh, my-- Oh, my God!
SAVANNAH:
John!
WOMAN:
Stop him. What is he doing?
WOMAN: Help him!
Oh, l'm so sorry.
l don't think
she's home now.
But she hasn't
gone back to school yet.
She normally comes by
and says goodbye before
she heads back, but...
Oh, shit, Tim.
Jesus, l'm sorry, man.
Hey, l like it.
l think it makes me look
pretty tough.
l just-- l had no idea
it was you back there.
Hey, it was my fault.
l don't know what l was thinking,
sneaking up behind an angry
green beret like that.
Hey, if you see her,
can you give her
a message for me?
Yeah.
Just tell her l came by
and that l...
You want to
write it down?
Yeah.
l'll make sure
she gets it.
Thank you.
Hey, Pop.
Uh...
l didn't know if anyone
else was coming,
so l made double.
No, l'll do it.
l got it, Dad. it뭩 okay. l got it.
They're clean, Pop.
l'll do it. l'll do it.
Okay.
Looks like you're going to
have leftovers for once.
Oh, l'll have it next Sunday.
Excuse me, Pop.
Got your note.
Short, sweet, to the point.
l'm sorry.
SAVANNAH:
John, l'm sorry.
l'm so sorry.
JOHN:
No, l'm sorry.
SAVANNAH:
l didn't mean to make
you feel that way.
l have no idea what
l'm talking about.
l had no business
pretending l'm a doctor.
l was watching him today.
John.
Please, l'm serious.
l don't know what
l'm talking about.
l really don't.
it means nothing.
Okay?
l'm headed back
to school.
And l just wanted to make
sure that, you know...
Make sure that what?
l made you a promise,
didn't l?
Yeah.
Um, you wrote
your first note
so l wrote mine.
Don't read it now.
Wait till l'm gone.
Okay.
Hey, can you--? You hungry?
Yes.
Yeah? My dad made
a little extra for you.
You know, it's Sunday.
Okay.
l can only stay for a little while.
l know.
Come on.
SAVANNAH:
Dear John,
two weeks together,
that's all it took.
Two weeks for me
to fall in love with you.
Now we have one year apart.
But what's one year apart
after two weeks like that together?
JOHN: All right, Pop.
MR. TYREE: Okay.
l got to go.
Um...
You be good, okay?
Okay.
So...
We're good.
All right.
See you later.
Okay.
You made me a promise.
A promise l know you'll keep.
So l only want one more
promise from you during
this time we spend apart.
Tell me everything.
Write it all down, John.
Scribble it in a notebook.
Type it out, e-mail it to me,
l don't care,
but l want to know everything.
And that way we'll be with
each other all the time, even if
we're not with each other at all.
That way before we know it,
l'll see you soon, then.
What's up, girls?
MAN 1: Johnny!
Whoa. What up, man?
MAN 2: Hey, there he is.
MAN 3: Look who it is.
MAN 4: Welcome back, John.
MAN 5: Aw, look at you.
Welcome back.
Take a look at your voucher.
All right.
How was Atlantic City, man?
No, laugh it up. That's great.
Yeah. That's the one thing
l ask him.
l didn't say a word.
This is the first time
l've seen him.
You wouldn't ask if you didn't know.
How could he know?
MAN 6:
Don't even bother unpacking, guys.
We move out bright
and early. Enjoy.
MAN 7:
Well, l'm excited.
JOHN:
Dear Savannah, l promise.
l promise l'll see you soon, then.
l promise l'll write all the time.
l promise l'll tell you everything.
Be patient with me,
it may take a while for these
letters to get back to you.
We've already been deployed
out on a mission.
STONE: Come on, soldier,
move it, move it. Let's go!
The problem is we can't exactly
use the local postal system here.
And there's no such thing
as Internet connection.
So l have to send everything
from here out by airmail.
Can you get this out for me?
Yeah. Yeah.
Don't lose it, all right?
Yeah, l gotcha.
Unfortunately, l'm not allowed
to say exactly where here is.
So all l can tell you is that
the place that we've been sent
makes me miss America
very much.
And the lack of anything
resembling an ocean
makes me miss Charleston.
And everything around me
makes me miss you.
We move around a lot. So letters
tend to come late and out of order.
We may want to number our
letters from here on out, though,
just so we know which order
we wrote them in.
But when they do finally get here,
it's a good day.
Whenever they don't...
NOODLES:
All right, let's see here.
Not for me. Not for me.
Not for me.
And not for me.
Figures.
it's not.
Sorry, dude.
Nothing for you either.
But l know they'll still come.
l know it.
That's right.
SAVANNAH:
Letter Number 8.
Dear John, l'm back
at my parents' farm
for the weekend.
And they have some
house guests you may know.
ALAN:
Savannah!
l think that horse
suits you just fine.
l took Alan out riding with me today.
it was his first time on a horse.
You're looking good
on that horse, Alan.
You've heard of horse sense,
how horses are somehow
able to sense danger?
Sense out evil?
Well, l think autistic kids
have that too,
so l had this idea.
This dream.
l want to open up
a summer camp for autistic kids.
l've never seen him
act like this before.
ALAN:
Are you hungry?
A place where they can ride horses
as much as they want.
Are you hungry?
For at least once in their life,
a place where they won't
have to worry about a thing.
What do you think?
Pipe dream, huh?
JOHN:
No, it's not a pipe dream.
it뭩 a perfect dream.
Erget. Merry Christmas.
John, to a Mr. John Tyree.
Shut up, man.
Seven?
Stop moving around.
Can l keep this one?
JOHN:
Letter Number 33.
Dear Savannah, the good news is
we've been sent somewhere new.
Although l can't tell you
where that is either.
The bad news is, this place actually
makes me miss the old place.
But it's a full moon here tonight,
which makes me think of you.
Because l know that no matter what
l'm doing, no matter where l am,
this moon will always be
the same size as yours.
Half a world away.
SAVANNAH:
Dear John,
most nights l fall asleep
worrying about you.
Wondering where
you may be out there.
Not tonight.
Tonight you're here with me.
l visited your dad yesterday.
Summer's almost over
and l wanted to see him
before l went back to school.
l hope that's okay.
Hey.
l made you a pie.
He made me dinner.
it was Sunday so we had lasagne.
And l got him talking about his coins.
So we had plenty of conversation.
This one is kind of a cull,
a coin that's in really bad shape.
Worthless to most collectors.
But not to you.
No, not to me.
What is your
favourite coin?
Out of all the coins that
you have, what is your
absolute favourite coin?
Do you have one?
MR. TYREE:
'Seventy-eight Jefferson mule.
SAVANNAH: Wow.
MR. TYREE: That'd be my favourite.
Definitely.
Why? ls it worth
the most?
Well, it's worth a lot,
not the most.
But, you know...
What's the story behind it?
Um...
Here's one...
So l'll ask you instead, John,
wherever you may be.
JOHN:
Dear Savannah, only because
l promised to tell you everything.
Thank you.
When l was 7 years old,
l bought an ice cream cone.
On the way home, l noticed one of
the pennies wasn't actually a penny.
l don't know.
Never seen anything like it.
Did you find this, son? Huh?
Yeah?
No, it's a mule.
it뭩 a what?
A mule. An error coin.
Every now and then
they make a mistake,
batch accidentally
slips through, this thing,
head's a nickel,
tail's a penny.
Thing's a mule.
Really more of a novelty
than anything.
Remember the horse sense
you were talking about?
--the kid found it
l will buy it anyway.
Twenty bucks. Huh?
No, thank you.
Well, my dad has it too.
Now, wait a minute.
Hang on.
Hey, sir. Sir, let me take
another look at that real quick.
John, let's go.
l'll be damned.
Do you know what this is?
No.
Look at that.
That's your coin.
You want my advice?
Dad to Dad?
Keep it.
Hold on to it.
Pass it down to your son.
Let him pass it to his son
and on and on and on,
and l'll tell you what,
30, 40, a hundred
years from now...
you're going to have
something worth a whole
lot more than $4000.
l promise you.
Hey.
Do you want to keep it?
Good for you.
Thank you. Thank you.
At first l loved chasing after
those mules with my father.
We finally had something
to talk about.
You know, something
we could do together.
But he became obsessed with them.
You know how he is.
And then l became a teenager
and you know how l am.
All the way up to Wooster
for another coin show.
l'm just--
No, l'm not doing that.
You're going to one
every weekend now.
Oh, that's good.
l love warm milk.
That's nice.
You spend all of our
money on coins.
Get a fricking fridge
that works.
Eventually he stopped talking
about coins with me altogether.
And then when that happened,
we found there wasn't all that
much left to talk about.
{ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO}
So that's the story.
l miss you so much it hurts.
Sorry, sorry.
GIRL: Oh, my God.
My brother was in the towers.
BOY 1:
l love you too, babe.
BOY 2:
Please call me as soon as you can.
{STUDENTS CHATTERING
AND SOBBING}
BOY 3:
Susan. Susan, is my dad there?
BOY 4:
Just calm down.
{MAN SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE ON TV}
All right, fells, here's the deal.
Requesting permission
to extend my tour, sir.
to extend as well, sir.
Requesting permission
STONE:
Okay, guys, listen.
We're going to get our orders
from Operations on Monday.
So before we do anything rash,
let's take the weekend to mull
this all over, all right?
l got a wife and kids
to think about here.
DANIELS:
Nobody's asking you
to stay on too, captain.
STONE:
Yeah, you are. This is my team.
Where you go, l go.
Where we go, we all go.
lf everyone still wants to extend
on Monday, then we'll do it.
Together.
Y'all don't get into
trouble over there.
Take care of yourself.
Always.
Yo, let's go, man.
The plane to Paris
leaves in an hour.
You ready? Are you ready?
it뭩 going to be amazing.
l can't go.
What are you talking about?
Of course you're going.
l can't go to Paris.
l got to go to Charleston.
You're going to Charleston?
Yup.
Dude, what are you, nuts?
We got two days off, man.
By the time you fly there and back,
you're going to have like 18 hours
on the ground, tops.
it뭩 18 more than
l had this morning.
l don't know when
l'll get that again,
so l got to go.
All right, man.
Nothing l can say
to change your mind?
Nope.
{JOSHUA RADIN & SCHUYLER
Fiske ''PAPERWEIGHT'' PLAYING}
SAVANNAH:
John!
John. John.
You sure he--?
He actually said that?
He wants to come?
l think he will.
He wasn't so sure about it, but...
Yeah, l'll bet he wasn't.
MAN : --has asked
President Bush to activate
thousands of military reservists.
{MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON TV}
Hey, Pop!
Hey, what are you
doing in here?
Look at you.
Wow.
Spiffy.
Are you coming with us?
Please. My parents
are so excited to
meet you, Mr. Tyree.
Yeah. Uh...
You hungry?
l made meatloaf.
l know you made meatloaf,
Pop. it뭩 Saturday.
SAVANNAH:
We can take it with us.
Yeah, we can take it
with us. You mind if
we take it with us?
Uh, well, l don't...
ls that okay?
Um...
l'll wrap it up.
MR. TYREE:
Uh...
l'm-- l don't mean--
l'm sorry, but, uh, could--?
Could you stop the car,
because l need to go back.
Oh, did you--?
Should l turn around?
No, just stop the car,
please. Stop the car.
Forget something?
Okay.
No, l need to get out
of the car. Please.
All right, just-- Just relax, okay?
MR. TYREE: Yeah.
l don't think
l can do this.
Look, you're fine. You're fine.
No, l just-- Please.
l need to get out.
Please.
You're okay, Pop.
it뭩 fine.
Look, stop the car, l can't--
Okay, no, l'll turn around.
We're fine, we're fine, we're fine.
l got to get out. Stop the car.
Okay, all right.
Come on, Dad, stop!
Okay.
Pop. Come on, don't do that.
SAVANNAH:
Hey, Mr. Tyree.
Hey, you all right?
You okay?
MR. TYREE: l'm sorry.
SAVANNAH: it뭩 okay.
But, hey, let's, um...
We're going to wait for you
in the car, all right?
MR. TYREE: No, l'm fine, l'm fine.
SAVANNAH: No, don't, honestly,
We can stay.
Let's just stay.
Okay? Let's stay,
because l can go
next year.
Pop, l only
got one night.
l mean, l got to go back.
l mean, do you understand that?
You should go.
You both should go.
MAN :
New York Mayor
Rudolph Giuliani said
Hey.
Wall Street will re-open on Monday.
He tried. At least he tried.
{MAN SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON RADIO}
Hello, welcome.
My girl.
Mom, this is John.
John, l feel like l already
know you. Where's your
father, did he come too?
No, ma'am.
Oh, well, that's okay.
l'm just glad that you
made it home safe.
We thought about cancelling
with everything that's going on,
but we felt like everybody
should be together.
SAVANNAH:
So l've been briefing him in
the car and l think he's good.
it was good Intel.
With solid tactical training,
l'm about as ready
as l'll ever be.
l love him already.
Mrs. Curtis, Savannah.
Hey, dude, how's it going?
John.
it뭩 good to see you again.
All right, You know what?
You look like you could
use a drink.
l'll grab one for you.
Yes, thank you.
John.
What's he doing here?
He's here because l invited him.
His family lives just up the street.
What are you, like,
hanging out now?
He's really not that bad
once you get to know him,
l swear to you, John.
Here you go.
it뭩 just bourbon,
it's not going to kill you.
SAVANNAH:
Be right back.
Look, l feel like we got off on the
wrong foot and l want to apologize
for the way l treated you before.
lf l would have known that
Savannah was actually
going to stay with you,
you know, l wouldn't have
treated you that way.
in all seriousness,
l'm sorry.
Fair enough.
lf you need anything and,
uh... Enjoy yourself.
Right.
So this is him.
Yup. No tough-guy
routine from you, Dad.
Routine? l bench press
refrigerators, honey.
Your boyfriends need
to know these things.
He's absolutely right.
Nice to meet you, Mr. Curtis.
But l think that Tim here
might have already beat
you to the punch.
He said he'd rough me up
if ever l hurt your daughter.
l was very convincing too.
l think l made quite an impact.
Well, cheers, son.
Glad you could join us.
Thank you, sir.
Billy! You actually showed up!
See, hard part's over.
Whoa.
Good to see you again, John.
How you doing, Tim?
Hi. Hey, Tim,
how are you doing?
Good.
Good. l haven't seen your wife.
ls she here?
TIM:
Yeah, she's on vacation actually.
So l'll tell her you said hello.
WOMAN: Please do.
l will.
Alan, remember
what we talked about?
JOHN:
Another vacation?
Yeah.
Alan ever ask
about her?
Yeah, he does.
l just don't know
what to say.
Hey, look, l'm not a father.
So...
You know, l'm really in no position
to give you advice at all.
When l was a kid,
l waited around every day
hoping that today
would finally be the day
that my mom
would come home.
l waited around 1 5 years.
So l know how painful
it might have been for
my dad to
just tell me the truth.
But it would have saved me
a lot of waiting around.
You know?
Well, l guess if the worst thing
you can say about your father
is he tried to protect you
too much...
then that's a pretty good
father, isn't it?
l'm sorry.
You're John, right?
Savannah's John?
Yes, sir.
l want to thank you
for what you're doing.
Know that our prayers are with you.
l just hope that whatever happens,
it'll be over soon. So you boys
can come home safe and sound.
MR. CURTIS:
Oh, it won't be over anytime soon.
Afghanistan will just be
the first stop of many.
He's right, you know.
Pretty soon they're
going to be asking y'all to
reenlist for another tour.
Slowly but surely they'll
stop asking and start telling.
None of the soldiers l know
need to be asked, sir.
And we sure
don't need to be told.
What do you mean by we?
MAN: it was great to see
you guys. See you next year.
Savannah...
So you're going to reenlist,
just like that?
it뭩 something
we should talk about.
Two more years, John.
Have you already done it?
Have you already
re-upped?
No.
But you decided
that you're going to?
Do l have a say?
Do l have a say in this?
You don't understand.
Don't ever tell me l don't understand.
Leave me alone,
John.
Please.
What do you...?
What do you want from me?
Savannah, l mean...
Just tell me what you want
from me. Because-- l mean,
you want me to quit?
ls that it?
Look, l don't know
how we got here.
l don't know
what happened.
Just woke up
and there's buildings
falling and...
l mean, l had a plan--
l had a plan, but now l don't.
And l have no idea
what to do.
l don't know what to do
and l just-- All l know is
l want to stay here.
l just want to stay right
here with you as long
as l possibly can.
You're just all that matters, okay?
You're all that matters to me.
l'm trying to figure out what
the right thing is to do and
l don't know what that is.
l don't have any fricking idea
how to get there. l just--
Because l need you to tell me.
l just need you to tell me, okay?
Can you just tell me, please--?
Just tell me what you want me to do.
l want you
to come with me.
{THE SWELL SEASON'S
''THE MOON'' PLAYING}
Hey, Pop.
Uh, thank you.
Thank you for coming.
Well...
So you think you're going to be
okay by yourself this time?
Yeah, why wouldn't l be?
Mm-hm.
l should probably
be getting going.
Take care of yourself.
So are we, um...?
l mean, we're okay though.
Right? Nothing has changed?
Be careful not to step
in any fires, okay?
Okay. l will.
So l'll see you soon, then.
l'll see you soon, then.
Mm-hm.
STONE:
Welcome back, guys.
Hope you had a good weekend.
Wish it could've been longer,
but sometimes you got
to take what you can get.
So that's it then?
it뭩 unanimous?
Okay.
l'll start the paperwork.
{FINK'S ''THIS IS THE THING''
PLAYING}
{PROFESSOR SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY}
Thank you, sir.
O'Neill, here you go!
This smells pretty good, Russ.
And we got Daniels.
Where's he at?
Move, move, move,
up and shoot!
Move, move, move, up and shoot!
Hey, yo.
Yeah, nothing today, man. Sorry.
MAN:
Go, go, go.
NOODLES:
Yo, you guys seen John?
ls he back here?
Yo, John.
Got one for you, dude.
Yeah?
That's it, though.
SAVANNAH:
Dear John, l know it's been
way too long since l last wrote you.
l've been staring at this blank page
for the last two hours.
Well, if l'm being honest,
l've been staring at it
for the last two months.
Please forgive me
for what l'm about to say.
And know that this
is the hardest thing
l've ever had to do.
My life without you
has no meaning.
And l cannot live... l'm sorry.
Yo, listen to this,
hedge fund manager
on Wall Street, right?
How much do you think
he made at his regular job?
Twenty-seven million dollars,
he ran a hedge fund.
Works on Wall Street.
That is amazing.
You making
mud pies, buddy?
NOODLES:
What's going on, man?
You want to
talk about it?
Nothing
to talk about.
She, uh...
She found somebody else.
You got any idea who it is?
No, she didn't say.
l mean, l got a pretty good idea.
Look, man, um,
you know, this happens, dude.
l mean, you'll get her back.
As soon as you get home,
she comes running.
it뭩 the whole cycle, dude.
They already got engaged.
Jesus.
Hey, l'm sorry, man.
Let me know if l can do
anything, all right?
SOLDIER 1:
--off the bottom rim.
You wouldn't think a squirrel
could swim, but l swear,
swam 20 yards
to the shoreline.
Swimming squirrel.
SOLDIER 2: That's crazy, dude.
Hey, notice that.
Did y'all see that?
l mean, that's as sexy
as it gets around here.
They can't show their legs,
so they got fishnets on their faces.
l'm going to bring that back
to the States and make
my girl wear that.
How mysterious.
SOLDIERS:
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Back up, back up!
What's he saying?
Hey, he's speaking Turkish.
What is he saying, though?
l don't know, man.
l don't know.
Come on, language
specialist, figure it out!
Look, man, l speak
Pashtu, l speak Farsi,
l speak all kinds of shit.
What kind of languages
you speak? Come here, man.
Good work, man.
SOLDIER: Stay right there.
Hey, where are you going?
Somebody's got to figure out
what he's saying.
Noodles, go with him.
Yeah.
STARKS:
Back up, back up.
STONE :
Tyree!
Wait for further instructions.
Let's move out.
Good?
Yeah, you?
JOHN: We got a man down!
Noodles, you're going to be
all right, man! Hold on, man!
SOLDIER: Copy that,
man down! Man down!
Come here.
You see it?
Come on, l got you.
Get your hands up!
STONE:
Tyree, do you read?
Talk to me, Tyree.
You lucky son of a bitch.
it hit your plate.
Oh, Jesus, l never loved
a piece of clothing more in
my entire life, l swear to God.
NOODLES:
John!
Man down! Medic!
Medic! John.
Come on, man.
Medic!
Look at me. Come on,
you're going to be fine,
all right? it뭩 nothing.
it뭩 nothing. You got this.
Stay awake, okay? You just look
in my eyes, just look in my eyes!
Keep your eyes open, okay?
Eyes, awake, awake,
right at me, okay?
DANIELS:
Jakes!
Welcome back, Sergeant Tyree.
Rest easy, okay? You're in
the hospital in Germany.
And you're
going to be just fine.
Tyree.
You look good, man.
Thank you, sir.
l just wanted
to come by
and let you know
l'll be extending.
Extending. Tyree,
it's been three months.
l'm impressed,
but l'm not stupid.
Go home, John.
Get some R&R.
Keep your dad some
company for a while.
Have a seat.
Listen, l'm being
transferred.
Now, this has nothing to do
with what happened.
But my captain duties
are done here.
Going back to Fort Bragg.
l actually miss my family.
That's good, sir.
Berry and Daniels
are getting out,
most of the others are
coming down on assignment.
And you've got less
than four months until--
l'm definitely extending.
Your war is over, John.
You served your country well.
You know what?
l might just make this a career.
No talking you
out of this, huh?
Mark, on my mark!
Mark!
BERG:
Where you
thinking next? Huh?
JOHN:
Oh, man. l don't know,
wherever they send us.
Actually, we're sending you
home to the States, John.
l'm sorry,
we just got the news.
MAN:
He's conscious,
but he's not lucid.
And he's hardly
ever responsive.
it뭩 hard for me to say how
severe the stroke really is
because we just don't
know how long he was down
before they found him there.
lf l'd have been there
to find him like that earlier,
do you think it would've
made a difference?
l doubt it.
l really doubt it.
WOMAN: Hey, Jeff, here's that scan.
MAN: No problem.
Hey, Pop.
What--? What
the heck do you--?
Excuse me, ma'am,
why do you have him out here?
You okay?
How you feeling?
l, um...
l mean, it's nothing,
but l wrote you--
l wrote you a letter.
No, no, l mean, don't read
it now. You don't have to--
l mean, l didn't even
think you would be--
Why don't you read it
when l'm not around?
You know what?
The hell with it.
l'll just read it to you.
''Dear Dad.
There's something
l've been wanting to tell you.
You remember
a few years back
when l got shot.
Well, you want to know
the very first thing
that entered my mind
at that moment?
Right before
l blacked out?
Coins.
Suddenly l was
8 years old again.
l was on that tour
of the U.S. Mint.
l was listening to the guide
explain how coins are made.
How they're punched out
of sheet metal and how
they're rimmed and bevelled.
How they're stamped
and cleaned.
And how each and every batch
of coins are personally examined
just in case any have
slipped through with
the slightest imperfection.
Do you remember
that, Dad?
l mean, do you remember
that trip to Philadelphia we took?
Well, that's what popped
into my head.
l'm a coin of the
United States Army.
And l was minted
in the year 1980.
l've been punched
from sheet metal.
l've been stamped and cleaned.
And my edges have been
rimmed and bevelled.
But now l have
two small holes in me.
So l'm no longer
in perfect condition.''
How about it, Dad?
You know, we're just
a couple of culls here, huh?
''But there's one--
There's one more thing
that l want to tell you too.
After l got shot, you know,
right before l blacked out.
You want to know the very
last thing l thought of?''
l'm sorry. Uh...
The very last thing l thought of...
You want to know the very
last thing l thought of?
Uh, l'm so sorry,
l don't want to rush you,
but we have another
service coming in.
John.
What brings you home?
it뭩 my dad.
How is your dad?
He, um...
Oh.
l'm sorry.
l wish l had known.
it뭩 okay.
it wouldn't have made
any difference.
l'm so sorry.
He's-- He was
a really good man.
You finally did it, huh?
Camp Horse Sense.
No.
l didn't. l tried.
it only lasted one summer
after we took over this place
from my parents.
it was... it was expensive.
But...
Do you want to
come inside?
it뭩 just me.
When do you
have to go back?
As soon as l get
my dad's stuff
squared away.
Have you--? Have you
settled down yet?
No. Mm-mm.
But you must be
dating a lot, huh?
Oh, no. l don't think you
can call it dating exactly.
it뭩 so good to see you.
Here. Alive.
Hold on. l'm just going to--
l'm sorry.
Hello?
Hey.
No, l'm fine.
Um...
l...
Well, John--
John is here.
Yeah, John Tyree.
Yeah. Yeah,
l'm going to leave soon.
Okay, l'll see you.
l'll be there in like
20 minutes, okay?
l love you too.
Bye.
He wants to see you.
Wait, what?
Um...
it뭩 Tim?
SAVANNAH:
Initially after he was diagnosed,
he was so optimistic.
He wasn't really concerned
about himself, all he cared
about was Alan,
which was inspiring.
And it wasn't until after the
cancer spread to stage four
that l noticed a big change.
JOHN:
What kind of cancer is it?
SAVANNAH:
Lymphoma.
He's had it with being
cooped up in that room,
so he basically just spends
all his time out here.
Sometimes with Alan.
Can l have
a crumble cake?
Alan, do you
remember John?
Hello, John.
Hey, Alan.
He's gotten big.
How are you?
Good.
Um...
l'm going to get him
a crumble cake.
Oh, that's a good idea.
He's been talking about that.
Come on, Alan.
l guess you must want
to kick my ass, huh?
There's not a lot l can do
about it here, is there?
it뭩 all part
of my master plan.
Hell of a plan.
l love her.
Everything that happened
in my life before, it's gone now.
it뭩 been wiped clean.
l wanted
to tell you that.
And l'm sorry.
l'm sorry for how it happened
with you so far away.
But l know now that Alan
will always have someone
to take care of him.
He will always be
in good hands.
She still loves you,
you know.
Why is it black?
it뭩 plain as day, you can
see it all over her face.
l wish that
weren't the case,
but she's never looked at me
the way she used to look at you.
You should know that.
SAVANNAH:
Be careful, Alan.
He still loves
those horses, huh?
Yeah, he'll be out
there till bedtime.
l got to get him
out of that hospital.
He needs to come home.
There's a company in Texas
with an experimental drug.
That might help.
But the insurance companies
don't pay for it, of course.
My parents sold their
beach house a year ago.
Which was a godsend.
We've done a few fundraisers.
But l never would have guessed
that we would run out so fast.
Stay for dinner, okay?
So you drink now.
Just a glass or two at dinner.
Tim got me started
a couple years ago.
Why are you looking at me
like that?
What do you mean?
How am l looking at you?
Differently.
l don't know, how do you
want me to look at you?
You're different.
Oh...
l don't know--
l don't know why l came here.
l mean, what are we doing?
We're sitting here and we're
eating and we're talking,
but no one's actually
saying anything.
What do you want me to say?
What do you want to talk about?
Why didn't you call?
Why didn't you call me?
l mean, did l not deserve
any more explanation than
that letter?
You couldn't have
called me?
You couldn't have given me
some sort of chance to,
like, change your mind?
Don't you think
you owed me that?
l couldn't.
You couldn't?
You thought that little
of me that you couldn't
have just called me.
Why?
Because l couldn't.
Give me an answer.
Why? Why not?
Because l couldn't.
l want an answer.
Because just hearing your voice,
l would have changed my mind.
ls that what you
want to hear, John?
ls that what you came
all this way to hear from me?
You think it was
tough out there?
And, what, you think it was
easy for me without you?
You thought that
every single day it wasn't
a goddamn marathon
of my life without you?
Tim was sick.
He was sick and he needed me.
He needed me to help him.
He needed me to help him
with Alan, with everything.
l was alone and l had
no idea what l was doing.
l didn't plan this. l didn't know
that it was going to happen to me.
But it did.
But you don't think l've tried--?
l picked up the phone
a thousand times to try
to call you.
You think that l really
want to be standing here
in front of you like this?
l had no choice.
l know.
l saved every single
one of them.
You've been so many places.
Mm-hm.
l think the yellow envelopes
are from Africa or something.
Really?
Mm-hm.
l even have your first,
your very first letter to me.
Tim's water bill.
Hmm.
Sorry.
it뭩 okay.
SAVANNAH:
Hope you have more
where that came from.
l'm going to put
a pot of coffee on.
l should go.
l'll see you soon, then?
Say it back.
When l say it,
you say it.
Remember?
John?
Just say it.
Goodbye, Savannah.
JOHN:
l don't think you remember me.
But l believe you knew
my father, Bill Tyree.
Oh, yeah, of course
l did. Yeah.
l haven't seen him
in a while, though.
How is he?
Uh, he recently passed.
l'm sorry.
l think you might've offered
to buy his coin collection
one time. ls that right?
Sure did.
More than once.
Just out of curiosity,
how much do you think
a collection like his is worth?
Phew. A collection that big?
l don't know, l'd have to see it.
Look, l only got
about one condition.
All the mules,
they got to stay together.
l don't care, you can
sell them as a set or
keep them for yourself.
But they have
to stay together.
You're really truly going
to sell me all his coins?
Yes, sir.
All but one.
JOHN:
This comes up nickel, we're going to
set up right here. We got shade.
it comes up penny, we'll be up
on the ridge. We got visibility.
That'd be penny side.
All right, let's go to the ridge.
SOLDIER:
Sergeant.
JOHN:
Thank you.
SAVANNAH:
Dear John,
it's been almost five years
since l wrote a letter with
an actual pen
on an actual sheet of paper.
But l thought maybe l could
write you now and tell you
all that's happened
since l saw you last.
A few weeks
after you showed up here,
Tim received
an anonymous donation.
A donation that was enough
to give him
what the insurance
companies wouldn't:
Time.
Time to finally come home.
Time to spend with his son.
Time to say goodbye.
The problem with time,
l've learned,
whether it's those first two weeks
l got to spend with you
or those final two months
l got to spend with him,
eventually time always runs out.
l have no idea where you are
out there in the world, John.
But l understand that l lost the right
to know these things long ago.
No matter how many years go by,
l know one thing
to be as true as it ever was.
l'll see you soon, then.
떰