[Car Trunk Lid, Door Closing]
[Car Engine Starts]
[Sighs]
[Sighs, Groans]
[Groans]
[Exhales]
[Horn Blows]
[Man On P.A.]
Montauk train on track "B."
[Man] Random thoughts
for Valentine's Day, 2004.
Today is a holiday invented
by greeting card companies...
[Man On P.A. Continues]
Last call...
to make people
feel like crap.
I ditched work today.
Took a train out to Montauk.
[Man On P.A.] Montauk
train boarding on track "B."
I don't know why.
Aah!
I'm not an impulsive person.
[Panting]
I guess I just woke up
in a funk this morning.
I gotta get my car fixed.
Hi. Cindy?
It's Joel. Joel!
Listen, I don't
feel very well today.
No, food poisoning,
I think.
[Joel Continues]
It's goddamn freezing on this beach.
Montauk in February.
Brilliant, Joel.
Page is ripped out.
Don't remember doing that.
It appears this is
my fixirst entry in two years.
Sand is overrated.
It's just tiny little rocks.
If only I could
meet someone new.
I guess my chances of that happening
are somewhat diminished,
seeing that I'm incapable of making
eye contact with a woman I don't know.
Maybe I should
get back together with Naomi.
She was nice.
Nice is good.
She loved me.
[Woman Speaking, Faint]
[Chuckles Softly]
[Joel Continues] Why do I fall
in love with every woman I see...
who shows me
the least bit of attention?
[Train Horn Blows]
Hi.
I'm sorry?
- I just said hi.
- Hi. Hello. Hi.
Okay if I sit closer?
How far are you going?
Uh, Rockville Center.
Get out! Me too!
Really?
What are the odds?
Do I know you?
Do you ever shop
at Barnes & Noble?
Sure. Sure.
That's it!
Yeah?
I've seen you, man!
Book slave there
for, like, five years now.
Ah. I would have thought I would've
remembered you. Jesus! Is it five years?
It might be the hair.
What might?
It changes a lot.
The color. That's why you
might not recognize me.
It's called Blue Ruin,
the color. Right. Yeah.
Snappy name, huh?
I like it.
Yeah.
Anyway, this company makes a whole line
of colors with equally snappy names.
Red... Red Menace, Yellow
Fever, Green Revolution.
That'd be a job,
coming up with those names.
You think there could
possibly be a job like that?
I mean, how many hair colors
could there be? Fifty, maybe.
Someone's got that job.
Agent Orange!
I came up with that one.
I apply my personality
in a paste.
Oh, I doubt that very much.
Well, you don't know me,
so...
you don't know, do you?
Sorry. I was just...
I'm trying to be nice.
Yeah. I got it.
[Inhaling]
[Sniffs]
[Sighs]
My name's Clementine,
by the way. I'm Joel.
Hi, Joel.
Hey.
No jokes about my name.
Oh, no, you wouldn't do that.
You're trying to be nice.
I don't know any jokes
about your name.
Huckleberry Hound.
I don't know what that means.
Huckleberry Hound?
What are you, nuts?
It's been suggested.
[Chuckles]
Oh, my darlin', oh, my darlin'
Oh, my darlin' Clementine
You were lost
and gone forever
Dreadful sorry
Clementine
[Laughing]
No?
I'm sorry. Just... It's a pretty
name, though. It really is nice.
It's, uh...
It means "merciful."
Right? Clemency?
Although it hardly fits.
I'm a vindictive little bitch,
truth be told.
Gee, I-I wouldn't
think that about you.
Why wouldn't you think
that about me? I don't know.
I just...
I don't know.
I just, uh...
You seem nice, so...
Oh, now I'm nice?
Oh, God. Don't you know
any other adjectives?
I don't need "nice."
I don't need myself to be it, and I don't
need anybody else to be it at me. Okay.
[Clementine]
Joel?
It's Joel, right?
Yes.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
I'm a little out of sorts today.
[Exhales]
My embarrassing admission is,
I really like
that you're nice right now.
I mean, I can't tell from one moment
to the next what I'm gonna like,
but right now...
I'm glad you are.
[Giggles]
I have so much stuff
that, uh, I probably should, uh...
Oh! I'm sorry. Okay.
I-I'm writing, and...
No, no. I just...
Sure. No. That's okay.
I just have... You
know, this is... Okay.
- Ohh! Hey!
- Take care, then.
Jesus!
[Radio: Pop]
Hi. I could, uh,
give you a ride, if you need.
It's cold.
Yeah. Okay. Yeah.
Yeah?
It is frosty.
You're not a stalker or anything,
right? I'm not a stalker.
You're the one that talked to me.
Remember?
That is the oldest trick
in the stalker book.
Really?
There's a stalker book?
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
I gotta read that one.
Look, I'm sorry if I came off
sorta nutso. I'm not, really.
Oh, it's okay.
I didn't think you were.
Did you wanna have a drink?
I have lots of drinks,
and I could, um...
Um...
[Chuckles]
Never mind.
Sorry. That was stupid. I'm
embarrassed now. No, no, no, no.
Good night, Joel.
Two Blue Ruins.
Thank you.
Drink up, young man.
It'll make the whole
seduction part less repugnant.
I'm just kidding!
[Laughs]
Come on.
[Exhales]
You're kinda closed-mouthed,
aren't you?
[Whispers]
I'm sorry.
It's just, you know,
my life isn't that interesting.
I go to work, I come home.
Don't know what to say.
You should read my journal.
I mean, it's just... blank.
Really? Does that make
you sad or anxious?
I mean, I'm always anxious, thinking
I'm not living my life to the fullest,
taking advantage
of every possibility,
making sure I'm not wasting one
second of the little time I have.
I think about that.
Yeah?
[Both Laughing]
You're really nice.
Ohh! God, I have to stop saying that.
I'm gonna marry you.
I know it.
[Slurps Drink]
Um... okay.
Joel, you should come up
to the Charles with me sometime.
It gets frozen this time of year.
That sounds scary.
Exactly.
I'll pack a picnic.
A night picnic.
Night picnics are different.
And, um, we could...
Sounds good.
But I... I should, uh, go.
Now.
You should stay.
No, I really... I'm... I...
I have to get up so early.
I would like you
to call me.
Would you do that?
I would like it.
Yes.
Wish me a happy Valentine's Day
when you call!
That'd be nice.
[Beeping]
[Line Ringing]
[Clementine]
What took you so long?
I just walked in.
Mm-hmm. You miss me?
Yeah.
Oddly enough, I do.
Oh!
[Laughs]
You said "I do."
I guess that means were married.
[Laughs]
I guess so.
Tomorrow night?
Honeymoon on ice?
It's really solid
this time of year.
Whoa! I don't know.
Come on. Come on. Eee!
Come on.
Come on, come on.
[Sighs]
Whew.
Oh. So beautiful.
[Clementine]
Isn't it?
[Sighs]
[Giggling]
Uh, don't go too far.
- Whoo! Oww! Ow!
- Whoa! Oh!
- Are you okay?
- Ouch! Fuck it.
Ohh! Oh, my ass!
[Grunts]
I think I should go back.
Come on. Come on!
What if it breaks?
- "What if"? Do you really care right now?
- Huh?
Come here. Please.
[Whispers]
Come on.
[Mutters]
Ohh.
Ooh-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Slidy-slidy. Slidy-slidy.
Whoa! [Chuckles]
This is good. Here, let
me show you this one thing.
What are you doing?
Whoa.
[Sighs]
Come on.
Think I heard a crack.
[Laughing] It's not
gonna crack or break or...
It's so thick.
Show me which constellations
you know.
Um... Oh.
I don't... know any.
Show me
which ones you know.
Okay.
Oh. Here's Osidius.
Where?
Right there.
See?
Sort of a swoop
and a cross.
Osidius the Emphatic.
[Laughs]
You're full of shit. Right? Nope.
Osidius is right there.
Swoop and cross.
[Laughing]
Shut the fuck up!
[Whispers]
Clementine.
Cock-a-doodle-doo.
Hey.
Hey. Sorry to wake
you, but we're... here.
[Sighs]
Ahh.
Can I come over
to your house...
to sleep?
I'm so tired.
[Sighs]
Okay. Um, yeah. Sure.
Let me get my toothbrush.
Yeah. Oh.
Just...
Yes?
Can I help you?
What do you mean?
Can I help you with something?
[Sniffles]
No.
What are you doing here?
I'm not really sure
what you're asking me.
Oh.
Thanks.
I need your lovin'
Like the sunshine
Everybody's gotta learn sometime
[Stops]
[Man #1] We're looking for 159.
[Man #2] What number's that?
[Man #1]
I don't know where that is.
Jesus Christ, you'd think they'd light
the number, or at least put a number on...
[Man #2] Is that him?
[Man #1] I think so.
Yeah, that's him.
Wait. That's him.
[Giggling]
Hey, Joel.
Frank.
Oh, shit.
Jesus. The only Valentine's Day
cards I get are from my mother.
How pathetic is that, huh?
You're lucky
you have Clementine, man.
She is way cool.
Hey, you got any big
Valentine's Day plans with her?
No.
Well, it's only a day away. Better
make some reservations or something.
Don't want to end up at
Mickey D's. Right? [Chuckling]
McRomance!
You want some fries
with that shake?
I have to, uh,
go to sleep now, Frank.
It's 8:30.
[Man #1 Singing, Falsetto]
[Man #2] Patrick, stop it.
[Sighs]
Ohh! Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Whew. Okay.
[Man #1]
Showtime at the Apollo.
Shh, shh, shh. Hey.
[Whispers]
Quiet.
[Grunting]
[Equipment Dropping Onto Floor]
[Frank]
Hey, Joel. What's up?
[Joel]
Oh. Hi, Frank.
[Mailbox Door Opening,
Closing] [Keys Jingling]
[Sighs] I only get Valentine's
Day cards from my mom.
How pathetic is that? [Man's
Voice Echoing, Indistinct]
You're lucky
you have Clementine, Joel.
Hey, you got, uh, any, uh, big
Valentine's Day plans with her?
[Whispers]
No.
It's only a day away.
Better make a reservation
or something.
Don't wanna end up
at Mickey D's.
[Chuckling] [Woman] Oh, no!
[Joel] Yes! Valentine's Day is three
goddamn days away! I want it resolved.
I'm willing to be
the one to resolve it.
So I call her,
and she's changed her number.
[Joel] So I walked over to Antic
Attic, you know, to get her something.
I thought I'd go over to work,
give her an early valentine, and...
You won't believe it.
She's there with...
this guy,
this really young guy.
And she looks at me like
she doesn't even know who I am.
Excuse me?
Can I help you
find something, sir?
[Chuckles]
Hey, Clem-ato.
Patrick! Baby boy.
What you doing here, baby?
[Patrick] Just came to surprise you.
Let me know if you need
something, sir. You look good.
- [Patrick] Hi.
- [Kiss]
How are you? [Clementine] Pretty
good. Pretty bored. Pretty tired.
[Patrick]
Uh-huh.
[Clementine] I so want
what's in your suit. Oh, good.
[Panting]
Why?
Why would she do that to me?
Hey, does anybody want a joint?
Oh, God, Rob, give it a rest.
Oh, God.
She's punishing me.
I know, honey.
For being honest.
It's horrible.
I should just go to her house.
No! No, no, no. You don't wanna go
there, man. You don't wanna go there.
Get off. It's too...
Right.
Yeah.
I don't want to seem desperate.
Joel, why don't you just see this as a sign,
make a clean break. Right?
Right?
[Joel Groans]
All right, Joel,
look, man, seriously.
[Woman] Rob! Here's the deal.
Don't do that. Rob, what are
you doing? No, no, no, no.
What's your fucking suggestion, Carrie?
What's your brilliant, reasoned solution?
You're gonna make this about our
shit now? This isn't about us.
I agree. It's not about us. It's
aboutJoel, who's an adult. Okay?
Not Mama Carrie's kid.
- What are you...
- That's your laundry!
That's great. That's good. [Dog Barks]
Okay.
What is it? [Rob] I don't know.
It's some place that does a thing.
[Woman]
Good morning. Lacuna.
No, I'm sorry. That offer
expired after the new year.
Yeah, sure.
We can fit you in...
How about on the fifth?
That's a Wednesday. All right,
great. Could you spell that, please?
Okay, and we'll need
a daytime phone number.
Great. Have a nice day.
See you then.
May I help you?
I'm Joel Barish.
Excuse me?
I'm Joel. Barish.
I have an appointment with Dr...
Mierzwiak.
- Here. Could you please fill this out?
- I just want to talk to him.
You still need to fill
the form out, sir. Really?
- Thank you.
- [Mutters] Great.
I don't have a pen.
There's a pen right there.
[Phone Rings]
Good morning. Lacuna.
Oh.
Oh, yeah, that offer. That's done now.
That expired after the new year.
Mr. Barish?
How are we today?
Not too good, actually.
Boo!
Oh, my God! Stan!
Sorry. Sorry, I was just... I'm working!
[Mutters]
Sorry. Sorry.
[Whispers] Here, Doctor. Thank you.
You should not
have seen this.
I apologize.
This is a hoax, right?
I mean, this is Clem...
I assure you, no. [Woman] No.
Mm-mmm.
There's no such thing as this.
Look, our files are confidential,
Mr. Barish,
so I can't show you evidence.
Suffice it to say that Miss, uh...
Miss Kruczynski was not happy,
and she wanted to move on.
[Dr. Mierzwiak]
We provide that possibility.
"Miss Kruczynski was not happy
and wanted to move on. [Banging]
We provide
that possibility."
What the hell is that?
Nicest guy
she ever went out with.
[Rob]
Oww! Fuck!
God, Rob! Give it a rest!
It's okay.
It's all right.
Carrie, I am making
a birdhouse.
What can I say, Joel?
You know Clementine. She's like that.
She's impulsive.
She decided to erase you
almost as a lark.
[Sighs]
A lark.
[Sobbing] Why? Why?
Why? Why did you do that?
[Woman]
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
I'm sorry, Doctor.
He just barged right in here.
Okay. I want it done. I told him
pre-Valentine's Day is our busy time.
- Oh, th-th-that's... that's okay, Mary.
- But there are people waiting.
Mr. Barish, if you'd like to, uh...
to come inside.
And, Mary, if you could take care of Mrs.
Woo. Good-bye, Mrs. Woo. Yes, of course.
Now, the, uh...
the first thing
we need you to do, Mr. Barish,
is to go home...
and collect everything you own
that has some association with Clementine.
Anything.
And we'll use these items to create
a map of Clementine in your brain.
Okay?
So we'll need, uh,
uh, photos, clothing, gifts,
books she may have bought you,
CDs you may have bought together,
journal entries.
We want to empty your home...
We want to empty your life
of Clementine.
And after the mapping is done, our technicians
will do the erasing in your home tonight.
That way, when you awake
in the morning,
you'll fixind yourself in your own bed
as if nothing had happened...
a new life awaiting you.
[Tires Screech] [Driver] Wake up, buddy!
[Mary]
No, I'm sorry, Mrs. Sobel.
You can't have the procedure done
three times in one month.
Well, it's just not our policy...
How are you today, Mr. Barish?
Hello. I'm right here.
I know it's an emergency, and we'll do everything
we can... We can fit you in on the first of March.
Maybe you could talk to the doctor,
a- and he...
All right, so let's make an appointment.
What day would you like to come in this week?
Mr. Barish. Um, he's
really busy this afternoon.
Maybe tomorrow would be better.
Around 12:15? Can you do that?
February is very busy for us
because of Valentine's Day.
[Chuckles]
[Knocks]
[Dixieland Jazz]
This is, uh, Stan Fink,
one of our most experienced
and skilled technicians.
[Continues]
He'll be handling
your case tonight.
Great to meet you,
Mr. Barish.
My name is Joel Barish,
and I'm here to erase
Clementine Kruczynski.
Very good.
Now, tell me about, uh, Clementine.
Uh, I was...
living with this woman, Naomi,
uh, a couple years ago,
and my friends Rob and Carrie invited us to
this party at the beach... I don't like parties.
Naomi couldn't go, but I went...
and I, uh, met Clementine.
[Pencils Clattering On Floor]
I'm sorry.
Let's start with
your most recent memories...
and work backwards from there,
more or less.
There's an emotional core...
to each of our memories,
and when you eradicate that core
it starts its degradation process.
By the time you wake up
in the morning,
all the memories we've targeted
will have withered and disappeared,
as in a dream upon waking.
Is there any risk
of brain damage?
Well, uh, technically speaking,
the procedure is brain damage,
but it's on a par with
a night of heavy drinking.
Nothing you'll miss.
Comfortable?
What we're doing here, Mr. Barish,
is actually creating a map of your brain.
[Mierzwiak]
Okay, let's get started.
If we want to get this procedure
underway tonight, we have some work to do.
I want you to react to these
objects, Mr. Barish, if you will.
[Clementine Whooping, Laughing]
There's a good story
behind this one...
Uh, actually, Mr. Barish, I'll get
a much better emotional readout...
if you refrain from any sort of
verbal description of the items.
Just try to focus on the memories.
Oh. Sorry. Okay.
[Stan] Healthy activity up there
again. Healthy readouts. Very good.
- Here's another object.
- [Clementine's Voice] That's so...
Next item. Okay.
Potato head.
[Chuckles]
- Next item. Okay.
- [Electronic Crackling]
[Stan, Voice Electronically Processed] Just
focus on the memories. Patrick, do me a favor.
[Stan] Hey, Patrick, do me a
favor, will ya? [Patrick] Yeah.
[Stan] Can you check the voltage
regulator? What do we got there?
Uh, voltage looks fine.
Really?
Well, I'm not wiping as clean
as I like here. I'm... [Scoffs]
[Mierzwiak's Voice, Distant] Well, uh,
technically the procedure is brain damage.
Check the, uh...
Check the connections, please.
Oh, there you are.
I...
Why am I... I don't
understand what I'm looking at.
Why am I
standing here and...
Oh, my God.
Déjà vu.
This is so...
All right, we should get started.
If we're gonna get the procedure...
[Simultaneously] Underway
tonight, we have some work to do.
[Whispering] I'm in my
head already, aren't I?
I suppose so.
Uh, this is about right.
This is what it...
This is what it would look like.
Very good.
[Simultaneously] We'll dispose of
these mementos when we're done here.
That way you won't be confused later
by their unexplainable presence in your home.
[Stan]
Ah, there we go.
Patrick?
Yeah?
[Stan's Voice, Echoing] Patrick,
can you check... Patrick?
I'm getting some sort of readout
of my own voice. Patrick? Patrick?
- Why are there so many wires?
- [Stan] A lot of equipment.
- Does that help?
- [Stan] Are you sure you set that thing up properly?
[Patrick] How's that? [Mary]
How are you today, Mr. Barish?
There we are, Mr. Barish.
[Stan's Voice] That's better.
- I don't know if I like this.
- Think I might try this, then.
We're almost done now.
Mmm. Journal.
That would be invaluable.
[Stan's Voice, Electronically Accelerated] "I
met someone tonight. I don't know what to do.
Her name is Clementine,
and she's amazing. "
- [Screaming]
- Whoa! Jesus!
What? What? Come on! Careful! Step back!
Just take it easy.
[Beeps]
That's fine.
Let's not roach the guy.
[Sighs]
All right, you got that one.
This place is sort of a dump, don't
you think? It's an apartment, Patrick.
[Whispers]
Patrick.
Well, not a dump, then,
but sorta plain. Uninspired.
And there's sort of
a stale smell.
Patrick, can we just please
get through this?
We got a very long night ahead
of us. Come on. Yeah. Yeah.
[Door Unlocking, Opening]
[Joel Whispering]
This is the last time I saw you.
[Joel Clears Throat, Sighs]
[Heavy Sigh]
It's 3:00.
I kinda sorta wrecked your car.
[Sighs]
Were you driving drunk?
It's pathetic.
I was a little tipsy.
Don't call me pathetic.
Well, it is pathetic.
It's fucking irresponsible. Could've
killed somebody. [Sighs] Oh, God.
Maybe you did kill somebody. Should we
turn on the news and see? Oh, Christ!
Should I check the grill to see if there's any
children or small animals? I didn't kill anybody!
It's just a fucking dent, Joel.
You're like an old lady or something.
Well, what are you like?
A wino?
[Laughing] Jesus, are you
from the '50s or something?
A wino?
Face it, Joely.
You're freaked out because
I was out late without you,
and in your little wormy brain...
you're trying to figure out,
did she fuck someone tonight?
No, see, Clem,
I assume
you fucked someone tonight.
Isn't that how you get people
to like you?
[Sighs]
I'm sorry. Okay?
Clem, I didn't mean it.
All right?
Clem?
Your keys.
I was just... I was just...
[Sighs] I won't need them anymore.
Angry or annoyed or something,
I don't know.
[Door Slams]
Clem?
[Computer Beeps] [Stan] Got it.
Mary's coming over tonight.
[Patrick] Yeah? Yeah.
Just thought you'd wanna know.
[Patrick] I like Mary. I like when she comes
to visit. I just don't think she likes me.
She likes you okay.
Maybe I should invite my girlfriend over.
I have a girlfriend now.
Do whatever you want.
Did I tell you I have...
[Clicks Tongue]
Yeah.
[Keyboard Typing]
Did I tell you
I have a new girlfriend?
We gotta focus here,
Patrick.
Yeah, the thing is,
our situation is...
is a little weird.
My girlfriend situation.
I'm sure it is.
[Laughs]
You gotta be...
[Engine Starts]
Clem, let me drive you home.
Get out of my face, faggot!
Look at it out here!
It's all falling apart!
I'm erasing you, and I'm happy!
You did it to me first!
I can't believe you did
this to me. Goddamn it.
Clem! Can you hear me?
By morning you'll be gone!
The perfect ending
to this piece-of-shit story!
[Engine Knocking]
[Patrick] Is there something wrong with a
girl being attracted to me? Is that a problem?
[Stan]
No, I think it's... funny.
[Patrick] So, who do you think's
better-looking, me or this guy?
[Stan]
Patrick, let's focus, buddy.
[Patrick] Remember that
girl we did last week?
The one with the... potatoes?
[Stan] That girl?
That's this guy's girl.
[Patrick] Right. [Stan] Yeah.
[Stan Chuckling]
Was. We took care of that.
Oh, God!
Well, uh...
I kinda fell in love with her
that night.
[Laughing]
What? You little fuck...
What?
She was unconscious, man.
Well, she was beautiful, and...
I stole a pair of her panties
as well.
Jesus!
What?
It's not like...
I mean, they were clean and all. Don't tell me
this stuff, man! I don't wanna hear this shit!
[Patrick] They were clean!
[Stan] What? D-Don't! Stop!
[Patrick] Okay. Yeah! All
right! [Stan] We got work to do.
[Computer Beeps] [Stan]
Give me my papers.
[Crunching]
[Slurps]
[Patrick] There's, um... [Sighs]
There's more.
After we did her, I kind of...
went to where she works
and asked her out.
[Stan]
You what?
[Mutters] Jesus. Jesus, Patrick!
Do you have... any idea...
how unethical...
[Laughing]
It's not really that bad.
What? Get that look off your face.
What's wrong?
[Stan Continues, Echoing]
Patrick, you stole a girl's panties!
[High-pitched Giggling]
[Laughing]
There's someone here.
He stole your underwear.
[Voice Wavering, Electronically Altered]
I don't see anyone.
[Clock Ticking]
[TV: Man Talking, Audience
Laugh Track] [Clementine]Joel?
Where are my boots?
[TV: Man] Why are you showing me
poisons? Can't you understand English?
"Potions," I said.
Potions.
[Laugh Track Continues]
[TV: Grandpa Munster]
Love potion, please.
I'm fucking crawling
out of my skin!
Should've left you
at the flea market.
[TV: Grandpa Munster]
First thing to do is...
[Chuckles] Sift in a cup
of powdered whale heart.
Wanna go?
I want to have a baby.
[Chuckles]
Let's talk about it later.
No! I want to have a baby.
I don't think we're ready.
You're not ready.
Clem, do you really think
you could take care of a kid?
[Scoffs]
What?
[Mutters] I don't wanna
talk about it here.
I can't hear you. I can never the
fuck understand what you're saying.
[Whispering] I don't wanna talk
about this! Fucking ventriloquist!
We're fucking gonna talk about
it! I... don't... want... to...
You can't just say something like that
and say you don't wanna talk about it!
[Whispering] I'm sorry, Clem.
I'd make a fucking good mother!
I love children, I'm creative and smart, and
I'd make a fucking great mother! Oh, God... Mmm!
[Voice Echoing] It's you, Joel. It's
you who can't commit to anything!
It's going! It's going! You have no idea
how lucky you are I'm interested in you!
[Voice Fading, Echoing] Maybe I
should end this right here, Joel!
Leave you at the flea market with this stupid
costume jewelry! It's done. This is crap.
Maybe you could find yourself an antique rocking
chair to die in! All the pain, confusion...
[Doorbell Rings]
Oh. Hi, Patrick.
Hi, Mary. How's it goin'?
Hey, you.
Oh, it's freezing outside.
[Stan] Find us okay? [Mary] Yeah.
Mmm.
Hot!
Poor guy.
Mmm? Oh.
Don't you have
anything real to drink?
Uh, we haven't really
checked yet.
Patrick?
Uh, yeah.
Uh, let me do the honors.
Mary hates me.
Never really had much luck
with the ladies.
Maybe if you stop
stealing their panties.
[Typing On Keyboard] [Patrick
Whispering] Stan. Stan.
There's more.
No!
Yes.
Hey, hey! [Mock
Whispering] [Stan Laughing]
Oh, you didn't want any,
did you, Patrick?
Uh, no, that's okay.
Wait.
"Blessed are the forgetful, for they
get the better even of their blunders."
[Clink]
[Laughing]
Oh.
Oh!
[Patrick Laughing]
Mmm!
[Groans]
That's Nietzsche.
Beyond Good and Evil.
I found it in my Bartlett's.
What's your Bartlett's?
It's a quote book, Patrick.
It's a book of quotations.
I think Howard will be
in Bartlett's one day.
Definitely.
Howard is pure Bartlett's.
[Crash] [Mary Laughs] God!
[Patrick Laughing]
Can you wake him up?
You can't wake him up.
[Patrick Continues Laughing]
[Stan Yells]
Mmm.
[Moans]
You don't tell me things, Joel.
I'm an open book.
I tell you everything.
Every damn embarrassing thing.
You don't trust me.
Constantly talking
isn't necessarily communicating.
I don't do that.
I want to know you.
Hmm?
I don't constantly talk.
Jesus!
People have to
share things, Joel.
Mm-hmm.
That's what intimacy is.
I'm really pissed
that you said that to me.
I'm sorry.
It just... really just
isn't that interesting.
[Clementine] I wanna read some of those
journals you're constantly scribbling in.
What do you write in there if you don't
have any thoughts or passions or...
Iove?
[Joel's Voice]
November 19, 2003.
Dinner at Kang's again.
Are we like those poor couples...
you feel sorry for in restaurants?
Are we the dining dead?
I can't stand the idea of us being
a couple people think that about.
[Whispers]
I like that.
How's the chicken?
Good.
More?
No. No. Thank you.
[Joel's Voice] She's gonna
be drunk and stupid now.
Hey, would you
do me a favor...
and clean the goddamn hair off the soap
when you're done in the shower?
Yeah. Oh. Yeah.
It's really...
- Gross.
- It's just...
- Repulsive.
It's repulsive.
[Phone Beep Dialing]
[Line Ringing] [Stan] Patrick,
can we get through this?
Patrick.
[Patrick]
Hey, Tangerine.
[Clementine On Phone]
Oh, Patrick, it's you.
[Sighs]
I'm so miserable right now.
[Patrick] Why? What's wrong?
[Clementine] I don't know.
[Voice Electronically Altered]
Excuse me? I'm so confused!
Can I help you
fixind something, sir?
[Patrick] Confused? What are you
confused about? Everything's fixine.
[Voice Electronically Altered]
Baby, come here.
[Patrick]
Scared of what?
[Clementine] Do you love
me? [Patrick] Of course I do.
[Whispers]
Where's the self-help section?
[Clementine Sobbing]
Do you think I'm ugly?
[Patrick] No! You're
beautiful! [Dishes Rattle]
Maybe I should come
over. [Clementine] No, no.
I don't know.
I- I'm a mess, Patrick.
[Patrick] Well, just let me
come over. I'll cheer you up.
[Clementine]
Okay.
Stan, can I leave for a while?
My girlfriend's really upset.
We're right in the middle
of erasing this poor man's...
[Garbled]
Let him go, Stan!
Let him go. I'll help.
See?
How hard can it be?
- She hates me. She wants me to go.
- Go.
All right.
I'll be right over, Tangerine.
You like?
[Laughing]
Oh, man!
I matched my sweatshirt exactly.
I like it.
You do?
You look like a tangerine.
Ohh!
"Clemen-teen" the tangerine.
Mmm! Juicy!
And seedless.
I like that.
I like tangerines!
Can you see me doing ducks?
Tangerine. Joel. Ducks. Quack-quack.
How does he know to call
you that? How did who know?
Oh, my God. Clem? [Mary]
This is pretty cool.
That's what
they called themselves.
The Clash...
the only band that mattered.
They called themselves that
for a reason.
It's amazing, isn't it? Like social
justice... Yeah, it's totally incredible.
What Howard
gives to the world.
Yeah.
[Beeping]
To let people begin again.
[Punches Keys]
It's beautiful.
You look at a baby, and it's so
pure and so free and so clean.
And adults are, like,
this mess of sadness...
and... phobias.
Howard just makes it all go away.
Oh, my God.
Baby, what's going on? I
don't know. I don't know!
I'm lost, I'm scared,
I feel like I'm disappearing.
Disappearing? My skin's
coming off! I'm getting old!
Nothing makes any sense to me!
You're not getting old.
Nothing makes any sense. Nothing
makes any sense. Ohh, Tangerine.
Nothing makes any sense.
Nothing makes any sense, Patrick.
It's okay. It's okay.
Hey, let's go out dancing. Yeah?
You wanna go out to Montauk with me?
Montauk?
Yeah.
No! Come up to Boston with me.
Sure. Yeah. We can go next weekend.
No, no. Now. Now.
Yeah. I have to go now.
I have to see
the frozen Charles now.
[Rock]
[Giggling]
[Answering Machine: Joel]
Hi, it's Joel.
Um, leave a message after the beep
and I'll get back to you.
[Beeps]
[Patrick On Answering Machine]
Pick up! Pick up, man!
W-W-W-W-Whoa. Hold on,
hold on, hold on. [Laughing]
[Continues]
Hello? Yeah, what's up?
I got into a little situation
with the old lady.
Can you handle things tonight alone?
I'm really sorry, man.
Don't worry about it. I got it under
control, man. [Continues Giggling]
He's pretty much on autopilot right now
anyway. Thanks, Stan. I owe you big-time.
Dude, I gotta go.
I gotta go.
[Muttering]
Charles.
Come on, Charles.
"Look! You and me on the Charles River.
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just happy. I've never felt that
before. I'm just exactly where I want..."
I'm so excited. Yea.
I'm excited too!
Cool.
Oh, uh, I, uh...
I got you this...
What?
Thing, um...
Happy early Valentine's Day.
Oh!
Wow. What is it?
Uh, I don't know.
Open it up.
Oh.
It... It's gorgeous!
- You like it?
- Yeah. It's just my taste. Really.
I've never gone out with a guy
who bought me a piece of jewelry I liked.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Okay.
Joely?
Yeah, Tangerine?
Am I ugly?
Mm-mmm. When I was a
kid, I thought I was.
[Sighs]
Can't believe I'm crying already.
Sometimes I think people don't
understand how lonely it is to be a kid.
Like you don't matter.
So, I'm eight...
and I have these toys,
these dolls.
My favorite is this ugly girl doll
who I call Clementine.
And I keep yelling at her:
"You can't be ugly! Be pretty!"
It's weird.
Like if I can transform her,
[Sniffles]
I would magically change too.
You're pretty.
Joely, don't ever leave me.
Pretty. Pretty.
[Joel's Voice] Mierzwiak,
please let me keep this memory.
Just this one.
[Clementine] I don't wanna
hold your hand. Come on.
Whoo!
Whoa!
[Clementine Whoops]
Stop it!
[Clementine Laughing]
I could die right now, Clem.
I'm just...
happy.
I've never felt that before.
Mmm.
I'm just exactly...
where I wanna be.
Clem?