- How much?
- $1.50.
Miss?
Miss, your change.
I PA] If you wish to
find the express train,
try the B.M.T.
[Man]
Spare a little change?
Anybody spare
a little change?
Lady, a little change?
I need some lunch.
- Watch where y0u're going.
- Anybody?
a)' f Reggae]
AU'
- Look at you!
- Hi, Anton.
I've never seen you
all dressed up like this.
- Well, do I look the part?
- Sure. Look at me.
[Sighs]
- Coffee?
- No. Yes! I'm so nervous.
- You're supposed to be nervous
on your wedding day. - Right.
You really look
absolutely gorgeous.
- Thanks. I borrowed the dress.
- [ Chuckles ]
- It's a marvellous thing you're
doing, Bronte. - Anton, no speeches.
Really. You and Georges--
Okay, no speeches.
Hey, Georges!
[ Speaking French]
[Anton]
Coming?
[ Cheering]
More!
- Nice to meet you.
- You, too.
- You were very good.
- So were you.
[ Bronte 1
Oh, here's Anton.
That's a copy
for you, Bronte.
Ce c'est pour toi.
Voila.
Merci.
Formidable.
L1lnever
forget Afrika.
- Africa?
- Yes, where we met.
Oh, the coffee-shop.
Right.
Good luck
with your life.
Et merci, Anton.
Enchanté.
- Good luck with your composing.
- With what?
Your music.
Oh, yes. Right.
Yes. Okay.
[ Bronte]
So what happens next?
[' A nton j That is" f2'. You don
'z' ha ve t0 see hi??? agaxh.
Africa?
Yes.
That's where we met.
He's there now...
again.
I wish
he were here,
but he's not.
He'd love the apartment,
though.
He travels
a great deal.
But he's the quiet type.
We both are, really.
- What's he doing there?
- He's a composer.
African music.
Not drums!
We c0uldn't have someone
who played the drums here.
Oh, no, no.
He studies
their music.
He, himself,
is not... African?
- He's French.
- Oh, oh, French.
What is this?
- “Green Guerillas.” Not some army, is it?
- It's a volunteer...
garden group. They do
good work amongst the poor.
Mrs Faure is also with
our city parks department.
We did have problems
with a recent tenant,
a single gentleman who neglected
the responsibilities...
associated
with 12-F.
That's why
the board feels...
that a young
married couple...
would be
more suitable.
Mrs Faure
is a horticulturist.
That's in her favour.
But it is irregular to give
our approval without meeting--
I like the couple from the bank,
not the one with the dog.
I'm aware of
the situation.
lt'sjust that I could
bring the garden...
back to the way the
late professor had it.
I don't want
to get technical,
but the moracus syconia
needs thinning.
The crinums and zamias
are sadly neglected.
The chamaedoreafs
root bound.
Special care
must be taken...
for the poor
cyathaceae dicksonia.
Not to mention the cordyline
or the heliconia.
Then there's work
nurturing the aspidistra,
begonias,
the bromeliads.
Ohhh.
Yo, baby.
Yo, Bronte!
The city fathers give their
blessing to the project.
- All right!
- Talk about the 77th hour, huh?
- I've got some good news.
- Whats that?
- How 'bout 3,000 square feet
ofquality topsoil? - You're kidding?
Burger King does this press hype
at the Sheraton Centre.
They recreate Texas
or something,
giant burger city
in the middle ofTexas.
They don't know what
they're gonna do with the soil.
Dave says, “I know
the guy to take it.” Me.
- How ya doin'?
- We're officially approved.
Let's g0!
All right!
Burger King!
- Burger King!
- Let's hear it for Phil!
Who can use a box
of periwinkles?
[Speaking Spanish]
Italian would be great.
Ask Bronte and Phil.
- Yeah, 'cause I'm starved.
- I am, too.
- Bronte, are you hungry?
- Oh, yeah.
- Want to get something to eat? You?
- Yeah.
- The four of us get something to eat?
- Okay, let's go.
- The All Nations okay?
- Yeah.
Maybe we can think of certain
plants we can put there.
- Can we order?
- I'm not your waiter.
Who is
our waiter?
- Hey, are you our waiter?
- No. Georges, Ies cartes.
♪ arrive.
Let's get out of here.
it's awful.
You have chosen?
Somebody else
go ahead.
What are
your specials?
From Switzerland
we have calves' liver.
- From old England, we have roast beef.
- I don't eat meat.
- Why not?
- Pardon me?
- If you don't eat meat, we have fish.
-/ don't eat fikh.
- I'm a vegetarian.
-Ah.
- You've a vegetarian special?
- All Nations vegetables.
I'll have that,
but no oil or salt.
No salt for you. Okay.
- I'll take the fish.
- Me, too.
Two for the fish.
And, uh...
Ahem...
For mademoiselle?
Or is it madame?
It's just here
on the right.
Right here.
- Let me come up?
- Mmm, no.
What is it?
A girls' dorm?
- What's with the secrecy?
- What secrecy?
Most girls I've known
have tried to crowd me,
except you.
- I need a little crowding from you.
-[CarH0r/7]
You coming or what?
- Okay-
- okay-
Evening,
Mrs Faure.
Hello, Oscar.
There's some mail, mostly
addressed to Miss Parrish.
I guess some folks
don't know you're married.
I still go by
the name Parrish.
- W0men's lib, huh?
- I guess so.
Nothing
from Africa.
- Oh.
- I already checked.
- I guess he's still on safari, huh?
- Something like that.
- Good night, Mrs Faure.
- Good night, Oscar.
[ Door Buzzer]
[Buzzer]
Hello?
- Mrs Faure?
- Yes.
My name is Gorsky.
I'm with the Investigations
Department of the I.N.S.
- The what?
- The Immigration.
My partner and I
are in the lobby.
We wondered if we might
have a word with you...
and your husband.
[Sighs]
What is it
you want to know?
I want to speak
with Georges Faure.
- He doesn't work here any more.
- What?
He was rude.
We don't stand for that.
No, please.
I must find him.
- Do you know where he lives?
- Georges Faure is trouble.
You would do best
to avoid him.
Excuse me, young lady.
I have customers waiting.
You're a friend
of Georges?
Yo. Yo!
Where are you going?
- I'm to see Mrs Faure.
- Oh'?
- And who are you?
- Mr Faure.
- Mr Faure?
-Yes.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I've never seen you before.
- Welcome back. How was Africa?
- Africa?
- You got any bags?
- No, just me.
When I first seen you,
I thought to myself,
“This guy just stepped
out of the jungle.”
I was right!
it's great to see you back.
I hate to see a young couple
separated like you've been.
- It's bad for the marriage. Call
me old-fashioned, - No, no, no.
But that's what's wrong
with this country.
- The family is going down the toilet.
-The toilet?
Yeah. 15 years I'm married
to the same woman.
- See my kids?
- Oh, yes.
I call her twice a day.
I don't go for women's lib,
- couples living in sin, that
sort of thing. - No good.
Terrible,
I tell you.
[ Doorbell]
So...
Well, come in.
Right.
These people
are due any minute.
I think we better talk
about the situation.
You got my note?
Of course you did,
otherwise you
wouldn't be here.
I spoke to my lawyer.
He said not to panic.
It's probably
just routine.
Have you got
some coffee?
- Coffee?
- Yeah.
Right!
Good idea.
We'll just have coffee
like any married couple.
How's
the composing?
Didn't you get the
bigjob in California?
No. I don't
like them, you know.
I prefer to be a waiter
than work for people like that.
But you're not at
the restaurant any more.
No, I quit.
They said
you were fired.
Really?
Huh. Funny.
I hate that captain,
you know.
He's really a snob type.
Ahh.
♪♪ [ Humming]
These people
are due any minute,
and you stroll around my
apartment touching my things.
Do you realize the situation
you've put me in?
I'm sorry, Betty.
It's Bronte.
Oh.
This is hopeless.
The coffee?
- The coffee?
- Yes.
I'm about to go to jail,
you're gonna be deported-
[Buzzer]
Oh, my God.
They're here.
Wait. Wait!
I'll get it.
- Yeah?
- May I speak with Mr Faure?
- This is Mr Faure.
- This is immigration.
Ah, okay.
Come on.
What?
- What are you doing?
- Better put them in my closet.
Oh, God!
Ring, ring.
[ Doorbell]
Oh, we have to talk,
for God's sake.
- About what?
- Our story. They're gonna ask questions.
They just want
to see us together.
This happened to a guy
at the restaurant.
- They see us, they go. Simple.
- [Doorbell]
Can you get it, chérie?
Let me do the talking.
No! You don't speak
much English.
No! Relax.
We're together.
Okay?
Don't panic.
- [Doorbell]
- Chérie?
Now go.
- Isn't this quaint.
-Thank you.
[ Bronte]
Come on up.
GBOFges?
This is Mrs Sheehan
and Mr Gorsky.
Hi.
Hello.
- Hi.
Please sit down.
- Mr Fame'?
- Georges, phase.
Yes. Now, you
entered the country...
- 5 months ago according to our records.
- Yes, and already I love it.
- Yes, well--
- Land of opportunity.
Such a great country.
Already I feel at home.
Ah.
So lucky.
Beautiful wife.
Apartment.
Plants.
Oh!
So lucky.
Your visa, a B-2,
a tourist visa,
allowed you
only 6 weeks.
That is an offence,
but more recent events
have overtaken that.
Your marriage gives you
automatic residency status.
This is your place
of residence?
- Of course.
- Yes.
- You moved here after the marriage?
- Yes. Mm-hmm.
We spoke to the chairperson
of the building.
He said you'd been away.
In Africa.
Yes.
Shooting elephants.
- Oh.
- [Bronte] With a camera.
He brought me back
some plants,
- some violets, African violets.
- The violets.
Mm-hmm.
Where did you live,
Mr Faure,
before
the marriage?
All over
the place.
In the park,
one night.
- And where do you work?
- Pardon?
My husbands a composer.
He's working...
on a composition based
on his African research.
A composer? We don't
have a note of that.
And you write,
what?
Rock 'n' roll?
Ballet.
- I write for the ballet.
- Ballet.
Your statement on your
passport application...
said you had no
criminal convictions.
Is that a true
and correct statement?
Of course.
- You speak French, Mrs Faure?
- Not really.
- [Speaking French]
- Not exactly.
No barrier to love,
though? Hmm?
Well, that
about does it.
We're sorry
to have troubled you.
There's been a clampdown
on illegal aliens...
marrying for
residency status...
and a green card.
It's come down
from the top.
The White House.
Well, you don't want
to get the wrong type.
Precisely.
We understand.
[ Mrs Sheehan] As a
matter of curiosity,
how did
you two meet?
I'm sure it
was very romantic.
- We-
- Well, uh-
- You go ahead.
- You, please.
- Wejust- - We sort of crashed
into each other. Boom!
Goodness.
I was
carrying parcels.
- Parcels?
- Yes, parcels.
- I picked up-
- Don't forget Anton.
- Yes, Anton.
- He was with Georges, and I knew him.
- He helped pick up the parcels.
-The point is, darling,
- that he introduced us.
- That's right.
He did, yes.
Anton.
- And?
- Well, so, um.
- Ah, it was raining.
- Yes! We got soaked.
I took one of her parcels
when I pick up mine.
You had parcels, too?
- Ahh.
- Everyone had parcels.
So many parcels.
[picked up
one of hers.
- By mistake.
- Yes, so I had...
my parcels
and her parcel.
And I was
staggering around...
like this.
[ Phone Ringing]
And, uh-
And-
Somebody better
get the telephone.
- It c0uldn't be for me.
- It could be, dear,
but don't worry,
I'll get it.
We don't want to have
a husband-and-wife fight...
in front
of our guests.
Hello?
Phil!
You're still upstate,
aren't you?
Do go on,
Mr Faure.
- Phil, I can't talk.
- Hmm?
- You were up to where you had her parcels.
- Ofzyes
[Whispering]
I'm excited.
I found this
extra parcel.
I knew I had 9,
and now 10.
“What was going on?”
I say to myself.
I open it
and it was...
ah,
ladies' underwears.
Ladies' underwear.
Exactement.
So...
I called Anton,
and he said,
“It must belong to Betty.”
You mean Bronte.
Yes.
Bronte.
But I didn't know
her name.
So, now I did.
That's it.
May I use
your bathroom?
Hmm?
Bathroom?
What for?
Ah, well,
I need to use it.
- Bathroom.
- Oh!
- Please go ahead.
- Where is it?
- What?
- The lavatory.
Could you show me
where it is?
Oh, yes.
Please follow me.
Why am I whispering?
Oh, that's great!
lust great.
Oh, that used
to be the bathroom...
before
the renovations.
Ikeep
forgetting.
This was the broom closet,
but we made it into the bedroom.
And this door
is the bathroom.
Voilà.
Merd e.
Let him move
into my apartment?
I can't believe
you're saying this.
Frankly, I think you have
your priorities all wrong.
You married a man you didn't know
in order to get a greenhouse.
That shocked me.
So I'm old-fashioned
when it comes to marriage.
I think that falling in love
has something to do with it.
You don't?
Fine.
If marrying a stranger
doesn't shock you,
then letting him move in
and sleep on the sofa...
- shouldn't 'z' shock you either'.
- This isn't happening.
They want a second
interview on Monday.
That gives you the weekend to
get your stories straight.
Move in? Can't he
meet me in the park?
This interviews
going to be in depth.
They're gonna question
you separately.
They want to know the colour
of each other's toothbrush.
What's he like to eat?
Does he snore?
You're gonna have to study
each other's habits.
- It's like you're cramming for an exam.
- Oh, God!
- Do I have no alternative?
- Sure.
You can confess now,
he'll be deported,
- you could face charges, and no more
greenhouse. - It's like a police state.
No, it's called
breaking the law.
No matter how trivial
it may have seemed to you,
that's what
you've done.
- You should introduce Georges
to your friends. - My friends?
Let him get
to know them.
- Say he's visiting from Paris.
- I c0uldn't bear that.
He's such a slob. I'll do it
without anybody knowing.
That's up to you,
but get that
story straight.
By Monday evening
this'll be over,
- and we can start planning the divorce.
- I can't wait.
For your pond.
Right. Thank you.
I'll show you around.
Not that there's much to see.
You know where the bathroom is.
Shoo, shoo.
Go on.
Shoo, shoo!
♪ J'[Whistling]
Do you mind
not smoking...
inside?
- What's this?
- It's coffee.
- No.
- Yes, it is. it's decaf.
Don't you have
any real coffee?
Afraid not.
I'll make you the best
coffee you ever had.
I only drink decaf.
You'll change
when you taste this.
I don't want anyone
to know about this.
So we have to
make up a story...
in case we run into any of
my friends. Something simple.
You're an old friend.
I admire your ballet music.
You're visiting
from Paris.
You're staying a couple
of nights. You're gay.
I don't want
to be gay.
Okay, you're not gay.
You'rejust an old friend...
and the hotels
are booked up.
- Not a very good story.
- Come up with a better one.
I don't know.
Something political?
Terrorist,
maybe?
Not a terrorist,
but p0litical's good.
A refugee.
That's it.
That?! work.
No, we don't
say anything.
Lust a friend staying
for a couple of nights.
This is New York.
You're right.
You sleep
on the couch,
and we split
expenses.
I'll cook, hmm?
[Sighs]
[ Bronte ] No, not here.
it's too expensive.
[ Bronte ] Let's go
to the supermarket.
It doesn't smell good.
Put it back, please.
- For your birds?
- What?
- This is birdseed, no?
- it's muesli.
Put it back.
I'll get some croissants.
But I like birdseed.
- No, okay.
- No.
- Go ahead.
- No, you.
- No, no.
- Please!
U B»?
Bronte?
It is you! Hey!
Lauren, what are you
doing here?
What am I
I'm, like, you know,
buying food.
It's just not
your neighbourhood.
Mother's having
a musical soiree.
I'm picking up
things for her.
- When am I goxng t0 see
your new apartment? - H i.
Hi.
You're together?
Sort of.
This is an old friend.
Georges Faure,
this is Lauren Adler.
Hi, Lauren.
That accent!
You're French, right?
- Oui.
- Ooh, exactement!
Everything in my life's
been French lately!
Monday I buy a jacket.
it's French.
Wednesday I go see
a French movie.
Then, last night Tony says,
“Let's eat French.”
it's like Carljung.
A coincidence?
Coincidence.
Exactement. Oui.
So... nice to meet you,
Bronte's French friend.
- Well, Lauren-
- Look,
if you want to eat
French again, I'm cooking.
For Bronte.
[ Bronte]
Uh...
- Hi, Mrs-
- Not right now!
Oh, Mr Faure!
Kids, meet Mr Faure.
He's been in Africa.
Hi.
Bonjour.
My kids.
- Maybe you two will be starting a family.
- Shh!
- Georges!
- Yes.
Hold the
elevator, wait!
[ Mrs Bird]
Going up! Hold it!
Hold it!
Going UP!
Wait for me!
They should fix those doors!
Somebody'll get killed.
What did those
government people want?
- It's nothing.
- We don't know exactly.
What's this?
Georges' visa,
a minor problem.
They said, does Mr Faure
do this and that?
And about Mrs Faure,
did she go to Africa and so on?
Mrs Faure?
Georges' mother.
- She died in Africa.
- I'm sorry.
Killed by elephants.
[Lauren] I could just sit and
watch you all day, Georges.
- Some stroke of luck, having a French
chef as a guest? - Stop it, Lauren.
What are you doing
in New York, Georges?
- I just crashed and-
-just a political--
- You go on.
- No, go on.
A political what?
Political...
um... ballet.
I can't imagine
a political ballet.
It's sort of a...
♪♪ [ Humming]
Georges writes for the ballet.
He's an old friend.
- He's-
- Not gay!
Good.
He c0uldn't find a hotel.
He's been in Africa.
- Look, we old friend.
- Yeah.
So I don't
fuck her.
[ Lauren] Did you kill
somebody for this place?
You probably cut them up
and used them for mulch.
This is amazing!
So is your French friend.
I want details later.
Lauren, please.
My mother would
adore this.
Speaking of my mother,
guess what!
- She and Daddy are leaving New York.
- What about her beautiful gardens?
They're leaving! Anyway, I've told
daddy all about the Green Worms.
- Green Guerillas.
- Being this great old liberal,
he'd like to give you and
your group all the plants.
No, not those
beautiful trees!
Everything.
That's fantastic!
Our stocks are so low.
Wait, there's a problem.
Mother won't
hear of it.
But I think if you talked
to her, she'd change her mind.
Georges...
ca c' est fantasflque.
- No.
- Yeah. Oui.
Bronte, you didn't
eat anything.
It's not my
kind of food.
She likes birdseed.
It's just not healthy,
all that butter.
What's the point of life
if you don't enjoy yourself?
Do you mind?
You're like
an old married couple.
How did
you two meet?
I was carrying
a lot of parcels.
Lauren, it's
a long story.
Can I tell you later?
I've got work to do.
I can
take a hint.
Finish your wine.
Merci.
Nice to have
met you, Georges.
Nice to meet you.
- Au revoir.
- See you again.
He's gorgeous!
- Lauren-
- I can say this now.
I did not like Phil.
So earnest, my God!
Phil and I are still
very much together.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm so embarrassed!
I mean,
I like Phil.
He's very concerned
about the environment.
Yes, he is.
- Typical me, putting my foot in it.
- Forget it.
Iw0uldn't mind
seeing Georges again.
He's dishy.
- Gardeners are so weird.
- Bye, Lauren.
♪♪ [ Humming]
Why did you ask her
to stay for lunch?
This is my apartment.
This is not going to work.
It won't work if I don't know
everything about you.
That silly story
about the parcels!
Your mother,
the elephants,
lying to my friends.
it's all so horrible.
I know you've got a cigarette.
Smoke it outside!
You begin the lie
when you married.
- I didn't make you lie.
- I didn't ask her to lunch.
You always blame me.
You did it, too.
- Did what?
- Married me!
I did it for the green card.
Why did you?
- No one made you!
- Outside!
If you push me,
I can be a beast!
So take care!
Look what you've done!
You silly...
French... oaf!
[ Glass Clattering]
Oh.
[ Phone Ringing]
Hello?
It's me. I just wanted
to thank you for lunch.
And that greenhouse,
I'm so jealous!
Lauren, I'm so sorry
about lying to you.
What are you
talking about?
I mean, not telling you,
not having you over before.
You're my
oldest friend.
Please,
forget it.
I haven't been
myself lately, you're right.
Things are
complicated right now.
Mother's having
this dinner tonight.
I just spoke to her
and she's invited you.
Great chance to
work on her about the trees.
You could
bring Georges.
What are you
doing in here?
I went and bought some
beautiful tomatoes for you.
Look,
that's sweet but-
And outside.
Come outside.
Here we have
radishes,
- peppers, carrots.
- Oh, no, my plants.
Just weeds.
I pulled them out.
No, this is
my research.
I'm sorry.
I bought this for you.
- Just don't touch anything, okay?
- Okay.
Don't go in the greenhouse.
That's all I ask.
It's my special place.
You like your plants
better than people.
Some people.
[ Wings Flapping]
Oh, God.
Look...
truce, okay?
I don't make the war.
You asked me before
why I did it, the marriage.
- It was for the greenhouse.
- Greenhouse?
I don't expect you
to understand.
I understand.
You want something,
you take it. Hmm?
We work tonight?
Study, just like school?
- I have to go out.
- I'll come, too.
No.
Why?
- Your boyfriend, the vegetarian?
- He's away.
It's Lauren's
parents' place.
Snob types,
you'd call them.
- Oh, I will embarrass you?
- No.
- Yes, too much oaf!
The Adlers might give some
trees to my gardening group.
- What's that?
-just a gardening group.
We go into poor areas
like the lower east side.
I came from that life.
You waste your time.
What? Nothing will
change down there.
It will always
be that way.
- Better to forget.
- Forget?
The trees are very good,
but you can't eat the trees.
Nothing changes
without hope.
- You think gardens make hope?
- Well, it's something.
The trees are
very good, yes,
but g0 to the country
if you want trees.
Try telling that
to the children.
They live with chaos,
despair.
You may think it's nothing
to give them a garden to plant,
but at least
it's doing something.
If it amuses you,
then do it.
Amuses me?
Chaos.
Despair.
[TV]
- Better down.
- What?
Your hair looks
better down.
I'll be back by 10:00.
We can work then.
Don't answer
the phone...
- or let anyone in.
- Don't be late.
Thanks a lot.
- In the garden.
- Thank you.
Bronte, how
exquisite you look!
Thank you
for asking me.
Not at all.
it's wonderful to see you.
Lauren tells us you've
got a new apartment.
Yes.
Is she here?
It's not whether
or not it's pornographic,
it's whether
it qualifies as art.
Your own daughter!
Have you seen her stuff?
Lafayette got off the horse
and saluted my ancestor...
- on both cheeks with a big kiss.
- Did he need to get off?
It's stupid for environmentalists
to plant trees...
when they don't know
what they're doing.
They don't listen to me,
needless to say.
I'm just your
average layman,
- but I have written the appropriate
authorities. - [Doorbell]
I'll go, Alberto.
That'll be Lauren.
As an artist, our daughter
reserves the right to be late.
- AUast'.
- Hi, Mother.
This is
Georges Faure...
from Paris.
Hi.
- Oh?
- Come on in, Georges.
He's Bronte's houseguest, but
she was too shy to bring him.
- You don't mind, do you?
- But of course not.
I went to pick up Bronte
and found him all alone.
Bonsoir et bienvenu.
Come in.
He's an important composer.
Y0u'H have lots to talk about.
Tres interessantes,
monsieur.
Mother plays the piano a little.
Get it? A little.
Alberto...
another place,
if you will.
I'd like
to present...
Georges Faure,
a leading
French composer.
Oh, no, no.
Bonsoir.
You see the man sitting
across from you?
[Whispering]
Do you live in Paris,
Georges?
He was all by himself. I really
think he wanted to come out.
It's okay.
Simon and Grace are about to
celebrate their 40th anniversary.
Are you married,
Georges?
Me?
We“...
not usually.
Whatever
do you mean?
Well... uh...
not normally.
You're getting
divorced?
Yes,
definitely!
- You'll never get married.
- What makes you say that?
You've turned down
enough offers.
You'll wind up a grand old Kate
Hepburn surrounded by plants.
Most men are too boring
or too vulgar...
to spend your life with.
- Change your brand of men.
- Really?
You're nice. You look for the
same thing in the man...
and you wind up
with two nices.
Nice, ugh.
What an awful word.
Phil's nice,
isn't he?
Phil's different.
He's a gardener.
Are you
any relation?
Relation?
- Any relation to the Faure?
- Who?
The Faure, Gabriel.
I love his
chamber music...
and his compositions
for the harp.
They're so... sensual.
Yeah.
Wejust don't have
any plants.
If you could see how these
gardens change childrerfs lives.
I hear what you're saying.
I do hope you understand.
To break up that garden
would be a crime.
I just can? do it, dear.
The pleasure it's given me,
it will give to
whoever buys the place.
You do understand?
I.' [Piano]
AU'
Thank you.
And now...
Georges Faure.
No, no, no.
I don't play well.
I'm not writing.
- Please, Georges.
- Perhaps an earl/erp/ece?
We should
be going.
Yes, we really must go.
Georges has jet lag.
Why not?
just one piece.
Do you mind?
It isn't often we have
a Faure in the house.
That's true.
Come on,
Georges.
♪♪ [ Tuneless Pounding]
AU'
♪♪ [Single Note]
It's not Mozart.
I know.
♪♪ [Soft Melody]
Would you translate
for me, madame?
Would I...
[Speaking French]
Once I heard the sound
of the wind in the trees.
I think that's it.
[ French 1
Once I heard the sound
of the laughter of children.
[French]
And I wept warm, salty
tears for the lost trees.
[ French 1
Let the little children
come unto the trees...
and I will give
them hope, he said.
[ French 1
But there are no trees
for the poor, lost children.
[French]
Decay is
their toy.
[ French 1
Despair is
their game.
[ French 1
They have only
chaos to climb.
AU'
Bravo!
[Applause ]
- Bravo!
- Magnifique!
I think you
just got your trees.
No, I've got it.
Excuse me.
♪♪ [ Humming]
Ah, Lauren.
La fille.
♪ J'[Whistling]
♪♪ [ Humming]
Monticello face cream.
“Monticello.”
Cream for the face.
Face cream, okay.
♪♪ [ Humming]
- I hope it's okay.
- What?
- The 501%.
- Oh, sure.
Sure.
- Thank you.
- What for?
For tonight.
The song, the poem.
I didn't do it for you.
I just did it for me.
- You were mad when I came with Lauren.
- Yes, I was.
And ifyou're mad,
we don't study.
And if we don't study,
I don't get a green card.
♪♪ [ Humming]
- Are you composing something?
- Composing?
You're always humming
that little tune.
Me, hum?
I don't hum.
Yes, you do.
All the time.
If it bothers you,
I'll stop.
No, I like it.
It's the first thing
you like about me.
I don't dislike you, Georges.
I have no opinion of you.
I want it over and my life
to continue as it was before.
And I am waiting
for my life to begin.
Okay,
let's get to work.
[Bronte j And these are at
my grandmother'? house.
She had these beautiful,
beautiful rose gardens.
Actually, it was my grandfather
who started the rose garden...
behind her house.
That's at the beach.
We always bought...
these little hats.
And this is
kindergarten.
- Oh, and these are my
brothers and sisters. - Oh.
My dad's a writer.
They live in Connecticut.
He named us all
after famous writers.
- Kind of puts a curse on your whole life.
- Mm-hmm.
I think he wanted me
to be something artistic.
It was okay
when I was a dancer,
- but he doesn't really care for gardening.
- Mm-hmm.
That's Colette,
Austen, Lawrence...
- and Elliot.
- Colette, Austen, Lawrence, Elliot.
- This is my dad. There's a better picture.
- Strong face.
He's a strong man
with very strong opinions.
In fact,
you and my father--
you c0uldn't get
two people more different.
Yeah, you'd hate
each other.
Why?
Well, you're so right-wing
about everything.
I'm not wing. You are
the one with the wing.
- All your ideas are from the same place.
- That's not true.
Huh?
These are
from college.
- Different demonstrations What
- for?
- Oh, everything.
- Everything?
This is Lauren.
Phil?
Yes, that's Phil.
You are in love
with him?
- Hmm?
-Yes, I am.
He's kind
and sensitive.
Vegetarian.
- He cares about what he puts in his body.
- Not like me, huh?
Big pig!
[Squeals]
I was 12 years old
when I made that.
- Didn't the kids at school tease you?
- School?
No, I left school
at 10 years.
This is the same
as my fathers.
He was a mechanic,
but he always dreamed
of the gypsies.
He would like to be
a gypsy, travelling.
This one given to me
by the putain.
You know “putain”?
Prostitute.
Two girls
in our town.
Liane and Michelle.
Michelle had
lovely red hair,
long red hair.
And this is how the heart is.
Love and hate.
If some people say they love
everything, it's not true.
This is how the heart is.
This is my honesty.
And this one...
when I was a bad boy
living in the street.
This is a knife,
for revenge.
When someone meant
something bad to you,
you make this tattoo
until you find him...
and kill him.
Then you make one here
with the knife put away.
- But you don't have that one.
- I don't find him yet.
- Were you ever in jail?
- Yeah.
- What for?
- lust kid stuff.
Stealing cars,
nothing serious.
Oh.
♪♪ [ Humming]
And, uh, when is
your menstruation?
_ My__
- Menstruation.
Beginning of the month?
The end of the month?
When?
It's at the...
the beginning of the month.
Beginning, okay.
I didn't really believe
that you were a composer.
We told so many lies, it's
hard to know what the truth is.
You just have to
trust your instinct.
Yeah.
- This was my first boyfriend from college.
- Hmm.
He was a musician, too.
He played...
the slide trombone.
And it was he who
first kissed those lips?
I don't think they're
gonna ask you that.
Good night.
Hmm.
[ Knocking 1
- Bronte?
- Yes?
What side of the bed
do you sleep on?
The right side.
Okay, I'll take
the left side.
Okay.
Huh.
♪♪ [ Humming]
♪♪ [ Classical]
Bronte, come on.
We have work to do.
Work.
“Africa, Sunday.
“Chérie,
“it is hot here
in Africa,
“and very green.
“The elephants
have been restless again.
“I think it
must be the drums.
“It makes them crazy.
“I miss you
every day,
“and I ask
the same question:
When are you coming,
chérie?”
[ Bronte]
“Dear Georges,
“the apartment
is looking beautiful.
“I only have to look in the
fish pond to think of you.
“Hurry home.
“You are never far
from my thoughts.
Much love, B. ”
- This is ridiculous!
- No, no, no. Look.
For the green card,
I do anything.
Give me camera.
We need blue sky.
Ah!
We are on honeymoon and
have to smile like oafs.
Okay, now do it,
yes.
- Do on the skis.
- Okay, I'll do one.
On the slaloms. I'm very good on
slalom, will you remember, hmm?
[ Chuckling 1
[ Laughing]
[ Bronte]
I need some blue sky.
♪♪ [ Radio:
'Surfin' Safari”]?
That's good.
Okay, that,
that's great!
Okay.
That's good.
Oh, lovely,
lovely!
- Political ballet.
- What?
- I make the oppressed. You
make the victory. - Okay.
- Victory!
- Victory.
- Okay?
- Okay. One more.
- Oh!
[ Bronte] The green- Yes.
Put the plant behind you.
Faites attention.
- Put the green plant-
- But of course.
That's good.
Okay.
- We feel the elephants?
- I feel them,
but maybe
with the knife,
like you could--
Yes.
Ah, uh-
Yes!
- This is so silly.
- No, no, no.
One more.
Smile.
[Laughing]
- One more.
- What now?
- Handyman.
- Handyman?
The good husband always
does handyman things.
Oh!
Okay, okay
How 'bout these?
Oh, great.
Great.
[Giggling]
- Smile. Okay, do some handyman thxhgs
- Yea h?
[Buzzer]
Stay here.
- Hello?
- Surprise.'
It's us, darling.
We're in your lobby.
Mother!
Why didn't you call?
- Can we come up?
- Of course! I look, um-
- You're sure ifs all right?
- Of course. Come on up.
Georges!
Georges,
it's my parents.
This is the worst.
You've gotta go.
- Okay. I'll change.
- There's no time.
Okay. Fine.
- Take the skis.
- The skis.
Put them back
in the closet.
Open, open this,
please.
Okay.
Thank you.
- Open!
- [ Chuckling]
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- it's okay.
Come on.
[ Doorbell]
just go.
I'll make something up.
Could I have a chat with you
and your husband?
- He was just leaving, Mrs Bird.
-Yes.
I want to know about
these government people.
- And last night I heard
drums,jungle drums. - No, no, no.
Not now, Mrs Bird.
They keep asking questions
about you and your husband.
He's not a spy
or something, is he?
Of course not.
1*; [ Humming]
- Georges.
Oh, Mom, Dad!
- What's going on?
- Hello, darling.
- I'll speak to you later.
- How about the drums?
- Later.
- What?
If y0u'd called,
I would have prepared something.
- / madeyou somethxhg - Since
you never visit, it's up to us.
[Mother]
No, it's not that.
- Your father had to see someone.
- Hokey sort of entrance.
It's lovely.
- This is Georges.
- Hello.
Hi.
A handyman.
If you could just finish,
Georges.
Right. I just
finish my work.
- Darling, it's beautiful.
- Pardon.
- I know now why you were so excited.
- It's small.
Did they sign
the big contracts, Dad?
- We're not gonna talk about that.
- Did they sign?
No! They backed out.
Liars!
- They lied to me.
- Dear, dorft upset yourself.
One thing I can't stand
is a liar.
We're gonna look
at the greenhouse.
- He's upset.
- Oh, yes.
[Mother]
It is too beautiful!
Do you want a hand,
Georges?
No, thanks.
I'm just measuring.
Oh!
Measuring.
[ Mother] She's had
the baby, premature.
- What'd they name her?
- Tiffany.
Now they have a Tiffany
and a Tarquin.
[Mother]
Thank you.
- Pretentious.
- Dear!
[Father] He is" a
pretentious writer; too.
Well, he is.
Don't you think so?
I need a screw.
Pardon?
I really
need a screw!
I thought
you were leaving.
- I just fixed the door, but I need a-
- / heard
In the cupboard
under the sink.
I'm gonna help Georges.
He seems a bit lost.
[ Mother]
You have t0 taste this.
Never mind your principles,
taste this.
Let's get
those orchids, Mom.
- I'm sure you want to be on your way.
- Oh, no, dear.
We're not in a hurry,
not at all.
You're not really a handyman,
are you Georges?
No.
I'm a composer.
Oh.
I used to be a cleaner
when I first started writing.
Long, longtime ago.
We'd just got married,
against the wishes
of my parents, I might add.
Didn't have
a bean.
We fell in love
right off.
It was difficult,
very difficult.
But when y0u're in love,
you know.
- Shipboard romance is what it was.
- Excuse me.
- I'll get it.
- It's okay.
Bronte, come here.
What is this?
Thank you.
It was right in the middle
of a lifeboat drill.
We suddenly found ourselves
in the same boat.
- Shouldn't you be going?
- Go outside with your mother.
- Georges and I have everything
under control. - But?
Go on.
Out you go.
We've been
talking about music...
and love
and skiing.
- And all manner of things, haven't
we, Georges? - [ Georges Chuckles]
I like your Georges,
Bronte.
- A charming man.
- He's not my Georges, Mother.
- He should have left.
- Well, he's keeping your father happy.
You know how restless
he gets in the city.
- So, Iefs be grateful.
- [Laughing]
Height,
five feet seven.
- Five eight.
Weight,
140 pounds.
_ No!
_ No?
- No,125.
-25?
EYES?
- Brown.
- Brown, yeah.
- Small scar on your ankle.
- How did you know?
I saw it.
Birthday,
24th August, 1959.
Correct.
Okay, my turn.
Eyes, green.
Height--
Nose, big!
- No!
-Yes, sure it is.
- Height, five eleven.
- Yeah.
_ O“ Weight?
oph! Weight!
You worry too much
about weight.
- At seventeen, you met Helene.
- Yeah.
She was at the
University of Paris.
She taught you
to read and write music.
- You lived together for seven years...
- Seven years.
Until she died.
Then you gave up
your music for many years.
Yes, but I
don't write music.
I just play piano,
always in the bars.
Yes!
[ Chuckling]
- Anton heard you one night in Paris,
- Yeah.
And said he'd help you
start over in America.
Yes! And I
wake up in America.
- Beautiful country, land of opportunity.
- Ha, ha, ha.
Okay, back to work.
You live
with two men.
First Peter,
then Stephen.
- Both nice guy.
- Nice?
Yes, that's
what you said.
Stephen wanted
to marriage you,
- but you think that marriage is boring.
- Ah! Except for ours.
Oh, yeah!
Then you met Phil.
Phil.
Him you really love,
huh?
You can't
tell them that.
- And I left Phil.
- And married me, because-
You're different...
and funny.
And don't forget
a good handyman.
Right.
You've had lots ofwomen,
but you haven't...
really loved anyone
since Helene, except for me.
And you fell in love
with me because-
Ah! What's
a good reason?
I just
can't think.
It can't be that hard
to think of a reason.
Let me see.
Ahh!
There must be
a reason.
Oh, yes!
Yes.
Because I begin
to hear music again.
Like when I
was a little girl.
The same thing.
- The pot.
- Sure.
[ Chuckles]
No, I gave you a five.
Yeah, okay.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
Ah, what?
Don't wait up
for me.
Phil?
- Phil!
- Hey-hey!
Hey!
Oh, ho!
You look beautiful.
- Let's go to your place.
- [Phil] Wait.
- Or we can go to Angela's.
- No.
- Oh, God. I'm hungry.
- It's all arranged.
Come on.
I made a reservation.
Let's go have dinner
around the corner.
[ Phil] I have it planned.
We'll just go this way.
- Tell me everything you did
while I was away. - Not much.
[ Phil]
You missed me?
- Oh, yes.
- Yes?
I missed you a lot.
Sure you missed me?
- Of course.
- You don't look like you did.
Looks to me like
I missed you more.
[ Bronte]
That's not true.
You should have been there.
It was beautiful.
I saw “us” there. Middle of
nowhere, grow our own food.
One night there was
this incredible moon.
- You sh0u/d've seen it. Wow!
- We had the same moon.
Yeah, but you
should have seen it...
without all the crap
in the sky.
It was glorious.
It was a cloudy night.
All of a sudden this giant shaft
of moonlight breaks through.
It was like daytime.
Giant shadows being
cast from the trees.
♪♪ [ Humming]
Ohh.
Oh, what a beauty.
[ Phil Laughing]
[Bronte]
NOW g0!
- No, the guard isn't here.
- Phil!
We'll get together
tomorrow, okay?
Just to the door,
Bronte.
There might be some
intruder lurking about.
[ Door Opening]
[ Phil]
Hey, this is nice!
You've seen me to the door.
Now g0.
I can? g0 until
I've seen the greenhouse.
Phil, you've had
too much to drink.
[Phil]
Come here. Mmm!
- You feel so good.
- Phil, no. Please.
Mmm.
Oh, Bronte.
Oh, oh!
- Phil.
- Mmm, mmm.
[ Bronte Chuckles]
Phil, no, no!
You heard
what she said!
Oh, merde!
She said go.
Okay?
- Who's this?
- Go 0/" / '// th/"o W you out.
- Georges, how dare you.
- Bronte, talk to me.
- Get out, vegetarian!
- Who do you think you are?
- I'm the husband, that's who.
- Aaah!
What?
That's my wife
you've been grabbing.
[ Georges]
Now, get out.
Bronte?
- Is this" true? - Yes, but it's
not the way you think. Oh, God.
- What"?
- Oh, God!
- Out!
- Wait a minute.
- Out, out, out!
- Hey!
You're the waiter
from that restaurant.
- Get out!
- I don't know what's going on,
- but I'm gonna find out, pal.
- Go on, get out!
Carrot!
Cucumber!
No!
- Now you go out!
- The interview!
- We go tomorrow. Are you upset?
- Upset? Upset!
- Out, out!
- But the interview!
I don't care.
I don't care what happens.
- Bronte, please? - Go or I'll
call the police or Immigration.
Jail would be better than this.
I'd have a cell to myself!
Come on, Bronte.
Don't be childish.
Bronte?
Ohhh!
Open, Bronte.
Bronte?
[Sighs]
[ Mrs Bird]
Get up.
Go on, get up.
Up!
- Out! Out!
- Oh, no.
- Up! Out! Back to the subway.
- [ Groaning]
- It's you!
- Good morning, Mrs Bird.
Since you moved in, there's
been nothing but trouble.
I didn't want
to wake you, chérie.
- You forgot your key again.
- Yes.
Always forgetting.
You should have gone
to a hotel, dear!
The board wouldrft
approve of such a thing!
Sleeping in the hallways.
This isn't Africa.
I realize that.
It won't happen again.
Mrs Bird!
Why did you do that
last night?
- I don't like vegetarians.
- Don't be ridiculous!
- The way he was bothering you, I
lost control. - Is that an apology?
- He's not right for you.
- Really?
He knows more about feelings
than you'll ever know.
You don't
have feelings!
- You snore and your manners are atrocious.
- You're a snob!
You're a slob, overweight,
and disgusting!
You say you're a rebel, but
you're afraid of your father.
My father's made
something of his life.
You live your life
like you got it from a book.
- You're 40 and sleep in the park.
-And Phil?
You make a nice love,
like vegetables.
- You need a fuck. - That's the language
of the gutter where you came from.
I am the gutter, yes.
But you're like a plant.
Cactus!
Sss!
I had no opinion of you,
but now I do.
- I really hate you!
- Good, your first feeling.
Oh, God,
the interview!
Oh, my God.
Oh, oh!
- Do you have-
- Yes, I'll do it.
Move it,
you stupid moron!
[ Bronte] Come on,
we'll take the subway.
You can take the subway,
but you ain't going nowhere.
- The water main broke.
- The park!
The whole city's
falling apart!
[ Bronte 1 We'll get a
cab on the other side.
The park is too far,
Bronte.
Bronte,
it's too far!
Come on.
Up there.
This way.
- You're sure, huh?
- Yes.
- Because we can't get lost.
- Of course, I'm sure.
- To the right.
- Where?
Right.
Come on, come on.
Run for it. Take care.
Ahh!
- We're nearly there.
- This way?
We're not far.
Come on!
- Taxi?
- Taxi! Wait!
Taxi?
Number 75.
We're the next.
Her father
is Sydney.
Face cream,
Monticello.
Your father's name,
was it Bertrand or Bernard?
- Rene.
- Oh.
[Beep]
76?
76!
You wait in here,
Mr Faure.
Mrs Faure,
follow me.
[ Footsteps]
Uh-uh, uh-uh.
Mr Faure, as you know,
we have doubts...
that your marriage
is bona fide.
I have here a number
of detailed questions.
Your answers will help us
make a determination.
I want you to be brief
and to the point.
I ask you to raise
your right hand.
Do you swear that the evidence
you're about to give...
is the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth?
I do.
- I do.
- Your name is Bronte Mitchell Faure?
Her father
is a writer.
- His name?
- Sydney, Sydney Parrish.
He didn't have
a formal education.
He ran away from home
when he was 12.
Plants. She loves
all flowers and weeds.
That's her research.
He knows
I love salads.
He likes all fatty
foods, being French.
She likes to eat
such thing as birdseed.
- Birdseed?
- Yes.
Muesli, and decaf.
Ugh, horrible coffee!
He hums
all the time.
Hums?
He's composing.
He hasn't written
in a longtime.
He says
he's not sensitive,
but that's
not true.
He's a very
sensitive man.
[ Chuckles]
[ Bronte]
He makes me laugh.
She's very kind
to people.
Me, I don't think
that way.
I don't trust people.
He's had a hard life.
In a way,
he hasn't learned to give.
But he's got
so much to give.
She has peace.
I don't have peace.
He has passion.
He eats life.
I'm sure that
just about does it.
Just a few more
details.
- Five feet eight.
- Five eleven.
- One hundred twenty-five.
- He won't tell me.
- She sleeps on the right side.
- He's on the left.
- Her toothbrush? Green.
- Mine's green.
Her face cream?
Monticello.
Monaco.
No.
Monte Carlo.
That's the
only answer...
I keep forgetting.
You remember all
the other answers?
Is not her fault.
Please, don't touch her.
I was good,
I think.
Me, too.
I think you're
gonna get what you want.
Your green card.
Oh, yes.
I'll see
you agam?
I mean, I have
to get my things.
- I can leave them with Oscar.
- Oscar. Good idea.
Right,
you're right.
As soon as we hear something,
we can start,
you know,
the divorce.
As soon as possible.
Yeah.
Good luck
with your music.
I hope you get
your big trees.
Good bye,
Georges.
Bronte.
Oh!
The ring.
Madame,
bijoux africains?
No, thank you.
[ Doorbell Ringing]
Good morning, Mrs Faure.
Mr Faurejust stopped by.
He said
to give you this.
I guess his
flight was delayed.
Yes.
Thank you, Oscar.
♪♪ [ Georges Humming]
AU'
[ Georges]
“Africa, Tuesday.
“Chérie,
“the elephants
have been restless again.
"50 restless,
I just can't sleep.
“I would love to say
a last goodbye...
before this
next safari.”
[Sighs]
'Ahh!
~ Oh!
- It's okay.
- What?
Monticello.
I think
I tried too hard.
I blew it.
Why didn't
you tell me?
It's all right.
We made a deal.
lfl leave quickly...
then you keep...
your beautiful
greenhouse.
I don't care
about the greenhouse.
It's time to go,
Mr Faure.
No, no!
- I write.
- Let's g0!
I write every day.
No w,
M!" Fa are.
The letters will
always say the same thing:
“When are you coming,
chérie?”
Ohh.
♪ Last night
I had a dream ♪
,>About a home ♪
No!
No.
♪ That was so bright ♪
♪ I d0n't know why
it has to be a dream ♪
Oh, chérie.
Do you still
have them?
Oh, yeah.
♪ Help me find
a home ♪
a' Keep your e yes;
♪ On the prize ♪
♪ Don't be dismayed ♪
I do.
♪ Deep in your heart
you must believe ♪
♪ Everything is gonna ♪
♪ Be all right ♪
So do I.
♪ Everything is gonna
be all right ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Sometimes hot ♪
JAnd sometimes cold ♪
♪ Sometimes I'm in
Sometimes I'm out ♪
♪ No, I haven't had
much to eat ♪
♪ Lord knows ♪
♪ I haven? had
much sleep ♪
a' Keep your e yes;
♪ On the prize ♪
♪ Don't be dismayed ♪
♪ Deep in your heart ♪
♪ You must believe ♪
♪ Everything is
gonna be all right ♪
♪ Someday ♪♪