[Thunder Rumbling]
[Thunder Rumbling Continues]
[Doris Day On Radio]
(music) When I was just a little girl (music)
(music) I asked my mother
what will I be (music)
(music) Will I be pretty
Will I be rich (music)
(music) Here's what she said
to me (music)
(music) Que sera...
- [TV] Have a nice day...
- Honey? Honey, I'm home.
- [Woman] Hi, honey.
- I'm here. I'm here.
- Hi.
- Are we having a baby?
- [Groaning] Oh, thank you.
- Uh-oh. Okay, okay.
- It's okay. We've got time. Hi.
- [Sighing]
- [Groaning]
- [Man Singing Scales]
[Sings Louder, Stops]
Mr. Harrison Winslow?
You're next.
Uh... I don't...
I couldn't...
If this gentleman would like to go
first, uh, I could use a moment if...
- Would you like to?
- That's kind of you. Thank you.
My pleasure.
- [Door Opens, Closes]
- [Woman] Billy!
- Where is your brother?
- [Kids Talking, Indistinct]
- Come inside. Where's your brother?
- Mom, it's not late.
- Brush your teeth. Get your butt in.
- [Grumbling]
- Mia, go home. Billy?
- [Woman] Here he is, Penny.
We're just feeding
these here pussycats.
We just feed these here
pussycats, Mama.
You and these pussycats keep
your mama itchin'. Come on.
- [Kids Shouting]
- I gotta go to work.
I'll be in
to look after them.
Come on inside. Agnes,
thanks for lookin' out for him.
That's my lover boy,
that one is.
- You're spoilin' my kids rotten.
- Mm-hmm.
- And them cats.
- Oh, shush about my cats.
- [Laughing]
- [Comedian] Oh, Wilbur, I'm sorry.
Hi. Did you get that job?
And he'll be on late at
the bicycle shop all week.
- I talked to the guys. We're excited.
- Here you go.
We really think you got something.
[Continues]
- You're beautiful.
- Ah, he's such a flirt.
- I think you'll agree with this...
- Julia!
That the only way
to make any loot on it...
- I've been looking all over for you.
- [Laughing]
- Not here!
- Well, I think right here is just fine.
- How about up here? I'm almost done.
- [Audience Laughing]
Well, I got a couple questions.
Now, all the pictures we got...
show either you
or Wilbur...
- So? So?
- So! So!
- You've been here for five months now.
- Five months is not so long.
It is, Julia, when you're
waiting for somebody.
You know, everybody thinks I'm crazy
for letting you do this.
- Letting me do this?
- All right, all right, I'm sorry.
John, I still
have to be sure.
I never lived in a city before.
I don't want to end up like my mother.
She never went anywhere
and she never did anything.
Julia, you're not gonna
end up like your mom.
- [Laughing]
Julia, you know, when you're not
around me, I don't care about anything.
There doesn't seem to be a reason
to do anything at all.
Anyway... what I really
came here to tell you...
was that I... made
a deal with the bank.
- I got the loan.
- You bought the Granger place?
[Laughing] Yes, 75 acres.
It goes across the road.
That's 300 acres, Julia,
and it's all ours.
[Sighs] Look, maybe I'm just
makin' a fool of myself here, but...
I love you...
and always have.
It just seems to me that
I deserve an answer. Yes or no?
Oh, John...
it's just that l...
Please, if you love me, can't you wait
just a little while longer until...
No, Julia, I've waited. I've waited
for years, and I guess I got my answer.
[Footsteps Leaving]
[Man Singing]
I'm just a lonely boy
Lonely and blue
I'm all alone
With nothing to do
I have got everything
You could think of
But all I want
[Sighs]
- Julia! Table 53, come on.
- Oh, sorry.
Well?
Well, he left.
He's really mad.
Don't worry, honey. A man drives
all the way in from Vacaville...
just to see you,
he's hooked.
You can reel him in anytime you want.
Danny, two Buds and a Pepsi.
[Glasses Rattling,
Ice Crunching]
Oh, Wanda, you're
so full of it.
I love him.
I'm gonna lose him...
unless I do something
right now.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait!
Wait, wait, wait!
- Didn't you audition
for the chorus last year?
- Yeah. Uh, yeah.
- You're with the library?
- Yes, that's right. [Coughs]
- And, uh, where have you sung before?
- Uh...
- [Indistinct Chattering]
- I haven't ever sung professionally.
I, uh...
I've studied a lot.
Oh, well, good luck.
Harrison Winslow.
He's our last one.
What did you sing
for us last year?
Uh... I didn't
actually sing.
I was, uh...
I was taken ill.
- Let's get on with it.
- Yes. [Clears Throat]
[Piano]
Excuse me, I'm...
[Stammers, Coughs]
- [Piano Stops]
- Ahem. Excuse me, I'm sorry.
[Piano]
[Music Fades, Stops]
I'm sorry, l... I can't.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
- I'm not gonna be your friend anymore.
- [Penny] Well, that's fine.
Night-night. Sleep tight.
Your mama has got to go to work tonight.
Why do you always have to work
in the nighttime?
Because I'm
on the night switchboard.
I'm sorry, sweetie.
I'm trying to get back on days.
But now until then, you know Agnes
is lookin' in on you, so... no worries!
Hug-a-bug. Mr. Hug-a-bug!
- Hurry. Come on. Yeah, yeah.
- Hug-a-bug. Mr. Hug-a-bug.
Mr. Hug-a-bug
Hug-a-bug
Hug-a-bug Bear
If you try to find him
Well, he won't be there
But if you're feelin' blue
And a little bit scared
He'll be right beside you
Mr. Hug-a-bug Bear
[Kisses]
Night-night, angel faces.
- Good night, Mom.
- Good night.
No worries.
- [Switches Lights On]
- [Gasps] Hey, Mr. Marco.
- How was dinner?
- Dinner was great, Milo.
[Exhales]
You lousy, double-crossing
son-of-a-bitch.
We should never
have swiped these.
You got paid.
You want your 50 bucks back?
Here. [Coughs]
What do you care? You got plenty of
stamps. Let me give these back, okay?
- Put 'em down!
- I'll tell you what.
I'm just gonna walk outta here.
That way nobody has to get hurt,
if you catch my drift.
- You lousy punk!
- [Groans]
[Grunts]
- Okay. [Groans]
- [Grunts]
Ohhh, ohhh!
Okay. Okay. Just...
You made your point.
No, that wasn't my point.
This is my point.
- [Grunts]
- [Groans]
Hey!
Hey, you! Where are you
going now, smart guy?
Huh? It's a long way down.
You got wings?
If I see you again, you're a dead man!
You hear me?
- A dead man!
- [Panting, Sighing]
[Grunts, Groans]
[Bus Approaching]
- There's another one! [Groaning]
- Ow.
- Frank, ohhh, the baby's coming now.
- Okay, okay.
- It's coming now.
- Okay, just, just hold on. Hold on.
Okay, just hold on.
We'll get there soon.
[Grunts]
Hey, did you get 'em?
Did you get my stamps?
Jesus, kid, what are you doin' here?
I told you I'd let you know!
Hey, look, squirt,
what do you want from me?
The guy, he pulls a.38,
all right?
I'm dodgin' bullets.
I'm lucky to get out alive.
Why'd you take 'em anyway?
My grandpa gave me those!
Look, kid,
life's tough, all right?
Sometimes you don't get what you want.
Mostly... you don't get what you want.
Yeah? Well,
you stink, mister!
You stink!
- Stop!
- Hey, pal, wait at the bus stop!
- Take me to a bus stop, I'll wait there.
- Oh, come on.
[Smacking]
["What'd I Say"
By Ray Charles]
See the girl
with the red dress on
She can do the Birdland
all night long
Yeah, yeah
What'd I say
All right
Well, tell me
What'd I say, yeah
Tell me what'd I say
right now
- [Groaning]
- Tell me what'd I say right now
Tell me what'd I say
Tell me what'd I say, yeah
- Uh-uhh, huh-uhh
- Uh-uhh
- Can you drive any faster?
- Honey, it's a Rambler.
Baby, it's all right
- Baby, it's all right
- [Screaming]
- [Tires Skidding, Horns Honking]
- Uhh, uhh, uhh!
- Okay, just hold it. Hold it. Okay.
- [Screams]
- Oh, God!
[Tires Skidding,
People Screaming]
[Grunting,
Screaming Continues]
- [Screaming]
- [Skidding]
[Crashing,
Glass Breaking]
[Electricity Crackling]
- Frank, it's coming. It's coming!
- Are you okay? It's coming?
- Okay, okay, uh, lie back. Lie back.
- Frank! Ohhh! Oh, God!
- You're gonna be fine.
- [Screaming]
[Electricity
Crackling Continues]
I'm okay.
Are you okay?
It looks like it, yeah.
- Hey, come on. How can we be okay?
- I don't know.
- Uhhh, uhhh.
- Ohhh!
What? What?
Oh. Ohhh!
Whoa, uh... Wha...
[Moaning]
- [Groaning, Gasping]
- Oh, no!
What is it?
- This can't happen to me.
- Oh, dear God, my kids!
I have to see my kids!
[Screams]
- It's a boy!
- Ohhh!
Oh, look at you.
[Julia] Where are we?
Is this heaven?
[Milo] It can't be heaven, lady.
It's a '58 Rambler.
[Penny]
And there's a new baby.
[Harrison]
There must be some mistake.
[Bells Jingling]
- [Gurgling]
- [Music Box]
What are you two
up to in there?
- [Baby Laughing]
- Thomas is laughing at the wall again.
[Thomas Laughing,
People Talking Baby Talk]
[Harrison] What a cookie boy.
What a cookie boy.
You should put some molasses in that
bottle. That baby's bowels are stiff.
- Go see daddy.
- Look at you.
- It's all right.
- Oh, your little bottle.
- Milo, please.
- Ewww, I hate it when you do that.
Hey, relax.
Thomas likes it, don't you?
No, you don't. No.
I knew you didn't.
- Honey, when do we eat?
- Hey, man!
- As soon as it's ready.
- Relax, okay, Papa?
I'm hoping to come back
with all my parts.
[Baby Talk Continues]
[Grunts, Groans]
- Again?
- At least twice a week.
Hey, I know what
the limit is, okay?
I just think we oughta
test it once in a while.
I mean they gotta let us get away
from this tyke sometime.
Could be worse. At least we're
with a good cookie boy like Thomas.
- Cookie boy.
- You're a cookie boy.
[Gurgling]
Guess he's off to laugh
at the kitchen now, huh?
Buy him all these toys,
he laughs at the walls.
Doesn't this bother you guys?
How long are we gonna
be dragged around like this?
Hasn't happened to me.
I'm not over there runnin' into walls.
- I'm just trying to test the envelope.
- You oughta test your I.Q.
- [Thomas] Hug-a-bug.
- What is that? "Hug-a-bug?"
- Where'd he get that?
- I thought you taught it to him.
[Thomas]
Hug-a-bug.
[Indistinct Chattering]
- [Thomas] I've been wondering.
- [Julia] What is it, honey?
How come I'm the only kid I know who
has invisible friends like you guys?
Um, that's a very good
question, Thomas.
- The Lord must have had some idea.
- I wish he'd let us in on it.
- When I see him, I'll ask him.
- Hold up, Thomas, hold on.
It's Miss Petersmann.
Oh, come on, baby, teach me somethin'.
Oh, yes! Oh, no!
- Damn!
- [Julia] We should have him neutered.
And that is why we say...
the battle of Gettysburg...
was the most famous battle
of the Civil War.
Any questions?
Yes, Thomas. You have
something to add,
- no doubt.
- Yes, ma'am.
- With enthusiasm.
- Oh, I love it when
he tells it Harrison's way.
- It's so much better.
- Thank you, Julia.
The battle of Gettysburg.
The third day.
Pickett's charge.
The air hung heavily.
- [Laughing]
- The acrid smell of gunpowder...
and the stench
of the dead.
- Ewww!
- Ooh-wa-ooh
- Your own father said
give her up, don't bother
- Ooh-wa-ooh, ooh-wa-ooh
- The world isn't coming to an end
- [Toilet Flushing]
I'm gonna walk
like a man, yeah
- Talk like a man
- Talk like a man, yeah
Walk like a man
my son
You know that no woman's worth
crawling on the earth
So walk like a man
my son
- My son
- Oooh
[Thomas]
Down, down, down-down-down
Down, down
down-down-down
- Down, down, down-down-down
- [Bugle Fanfare]
Silver Bullet in the fourth?
Buzz off, kid. This is for grown-ups.
- Go buy a soda. Next? Hey, ki...
- Oh, please, mister.
My dad said if I don't
place this bet for him,
- I shouldn't come home ever.
- He'll give me an awful beating.
He'll give me an awful beating.
[Crying]
So please take my money.
Please! Okay?
- Okay, okay.
- [Bell Rings]
[Milo Shouting] I wanna win!
Let's go, let's go!
- He's coming! Here he comes!
- Go, go, go!
- He's gonna do it! Go, Silver Bullet!
Yes! Yes! Oh!
Does this little buckaroo know how
to pick a winner or what? Bam, bam.
- [Drums]
- [Men Shouting] Go, go! Move!
- You're outta here, ha-ha!
- Yes! That's how you move the ball.
- Five more yards. This...
- That's exactly right. That's it.
[Franco Corelli
Singing Opera]
- Oh, it's so great.
- [Harrison] Right here, right here.
Listen to this, the leitmotiv.
It's beautiful.
Ooh, yeah, unbelievable.
Turn the page, Thomas. Turn the page.
Okay, fold that out
for me.
Oh. Oh, mounds of joy.
Hey, could we muzzle
this Mario Lanza guy?
It's Franco Corelli, for God's sakes!
You absorb nothing.
- Whatever!
- Hold that page a second.
[Penny]
My Billy is 11 years old today.
Wherever those kids are,
I'm sure they're safe...
- and happy.
- I just wish I knew.
You still think about John,
don't you?
Every day.
Sweetie. Mmm.
Let's go get the guys.
- [Laughing]
[Franco Corelli
Singing Continues]
Why don't you boys come up
and see the sunset?
Harrison.
- What?
- We're listening to Franco Corelli.
- The leitmotiv.
- Yeah.
[Ice Cream Truck]
- Mr. Reilly?
- Yes.
Charles Polito,
Child Welfare Department.
Neither of you
bets on the horses?
- I've never even been to a horse race.
- No.
You... Talk to anyone
who knows me.
Well, your son has been
seen at the track.
He's telling the story...
that you will give him a beating
if he doesn't place your bets.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Eva] How could you
even think it?
We are not putting our son
in some mental hospital!
Oh, Eva!
No one is saying that.
Dr. Beecham is a child psychiatrist.
He's just gonna do some tests.
- Tests?
- Therapy, tests, whatever it is!
Everyone says he needs help.
The guy from child welfare, his teacher.
That old battle-ax has no idea how to
handle a precocious child like Thomas.
Thomas has a serious problem. He blames
everything on these imaginary people!
I've been saying for years we should
get him proper care, and you know it!
- Because he has a vivid imagination?
- Stop living in a fantasy world.
You can't continue that.
You can't play his little games!
[Rain Falling]
[Thunder Rumbling]
Not one of you knows
what it's like to lose a child.
I lost three.
I'm not losing Thomas.
Penny, look what's going on here.
This is wrong.
Yeah, it's gotten
way out of hand.
Maybe we were never supposed to
talk to him or even let him see us.
Hey, come on.
We can't just go invisible on the kid.
It's stupid!
[Sighing] He's gonna hate us,
I'm tellin' you.
- Julia, we're his family.
- No, we're not his family.
We're...
I don't know what we are.
He's got a mother and a father.
We've gotta let them be his parents.
Leavin' Thomas would be
like dyin' all over again.
Penny...
I never had
any children...
but for a little while
with Thomas...
I got to feel like a father.
This isn't easy for any of us.
Now... Just wait.
Now, if we're so bad for Thomas, how
come we're stuck to him? Tell me that.
We don't know, okay?
So, what? What, we don't
let him see us or hear us?
What, we never even
talk to him?
We just... hang around?
Watch him for the rest
of his life?
What, like
a bunch of ghosts?
- That's gonna be hell.
- Maybe that's what this is, Milo.
- Well, I guess we better
wake him up and say good-bye.
- Wait!
Thomas. Thomas.
- Sweetie, Thomas?
- What?
Oh, goodness,
you are such a big boy.
[Harrison]
We love you, Thomas.
I love you too.
Thomas, you know
how we've always said...
we didn't know how long
we were gonna be with you?
Yes.
Well... um...
It's time for you
to be like other kids.
Just be with your mommy
and your daddy.
Thomas, we feel the time
has come for us to go away.
What? No!
Yeah, buddy.
It'll be a lot better for ya.
- Honest.
- We don't want to, but we have to go.
No, please!
I'll do anything you want.
I'll pretend you're not there,
okay? It will be a secret.
Oh, we can't do that, sweetie.
It doesn't work.
Don't cry. We're gonna be right here
watchin' over you.
Just quietly.
You'll be okay, kiddo.
You'll grow up,
forget about us.
No, I won't. I won't!
- So long, buckaroo.
- Come back. Don't leave me!
Milo!
I'm so sorry, Thomas.
[Crying]
You said you were my special friends,
and special friends don't go away.
[Julia] You're gonna
find new friends.
You certainly will.
You are a great guy.
I don't want new friends.
I want you.
[Crying Continues]
I just wish I could
give you a big hug.
- Julia!
- Good-bye, Sweetie.
- I love you.
Come back.
[Crying Continues]
Good-bye, Thomas.
Please stay!
Ohhh!
Harrison!
- Thomas.
- Huh?
I am so proud of you.
Don't go. Penny.
Thomas, no worries.
I need you.
Just come back, come back!
Come back, don't go!
Don't go, come back!
Milo! Julia!
Harrison!
[Crying Continues]
Julia! Harrison!
Penny! Milo!
[Crying Continues]
[Harrison] "I have a nice pair
of 100% wool socks.
I don't think
they're gonna bother you."
I said, "You're telling me what's
gonna bother me, what I'm allergic to."
- So I ended up getting a dozen pairs...
- Pairs, 25% nylon.
- Have I told you this before?
- When Thomas was about 15.
[Milo]
Where are we, anyway?
Stellar Aviation. Another bankruptcy.
Don't you ever pay attention?
[Penny] I wonder why they
always send Thomas to do this.
- 'Cause it doesn't seem to bother him.
- It does.
- [Tools Drilling]
- Ohh.
- Stop it. You're never gonna catch one.
- [Sighs]
- Hey, look, I'm a man.
- You're a dead man.
You bug my ass. You've been
buggin' my ass since the early '70s.
- This guy chose it.
- [Thomas] Patterson, how you doin'?
Use the same damn parts
if you got to, but get going.
- Dreyfuss!
- Patterson, where you been?
- What are you trying to do, Mr. Reilly?
- I'm trying to contact you.
I phoned, I faxed, I messengered,
I paged. You're very mysterious.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So get to the point, huh?
[Sighing] You're aware of
the bankruptcy hearing on Monday?
- Yes, of course I'm aware of it.
- Okay. Well,
I just dropped by to tell you my bank...
actually, the rest of your creditors...
have decided to push
for liquidation.
- What?
- [Equipment Drilling Continues]
Look, I'm not bankrupt.
I'm just behind a little.
A little behind,
6.4 million, $6,429,089.
We're gonna reorganize under chapter 11,
so it's gonna take some time.
So you and the others are just
gonna have to wait for your money.
See, we have waited,
and we've watched you drain
more money out of this company.
Think you can
take me on, Reilly?
If you think you have
a case for reorganization,
convince the judge.
[Milo] How many more years of this?
Huh? When's he gonna retire?
It's amazing these things
can get off the ground.
Look, Tim, I paid you 185 bucks
to detail my car, and you know what l...
No. I'm seeing streaks, streaks
on the windshield, streaks on the dash,
so I'm gonna bring it back in
Saturday, waste my weekend...
allowing you to explore
your incompetence, all right?
Oh, by the way...
[Dial Tone]
- I hate that phone. He's always on it.
- Saves him time.
Doesn't save him enough time to call
his mother and his father, does it?
[Telephone Rings, Beeps]
- Yeah?
- Hi, it's Noelle.
- What do ya got for me?
- A staff meeting this afternoon,
and Anne called.
- She cancelled your lunch at Post Trio.
- She did? Why?
She found this great new place,
nobody knows about it.
You should just meet her there.
Here's the address.
[Penny] Oh, I know this place.
I used to come here when I was a kid.
- Isn't it beautiful?
- But it isn't a restaurant, is it?
[Milo] Nah, it's full of plants
and flowers and stuff.
You know what? I broke into this joint.
Mid-50s, Valentine's Day.
My girlfriend needed flowers.
[Harrison] At least it's not crowded.
I hate it when people walk through me.
- Wow!
- [Milo] It depends on who it is.
[Harrison] That's another place
where we're different, Milo.
I always considered it
an invasion of my personal space.
[Thomas]
Sorry I'm late, honey.
- God, how did you get them
to let you use this place?
- They owe me.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, I did the P.R.
For their fund-raiser last year.
Mmm.
Stop it with your
"What's she getting me into?" look.
Oh, come on, Anne. You know,
you're... you're doing something here.
Yeah, lunch.
Well, it looks good.
[Clears Throat, Sighs]
- Ahhh, Barbados.
- Right. Very good.
Yeah, it was the closest
I could come on my lunch break.
[Sighs]
So... relax, eat.
I'm just trying to get us
out of our routine.
- Barbados?
- Where they first met.
Don't you remember anything?
I like this girl. Much better
than little Miss "Look At My Butt.
- Everybody, Thomas, look at my butt."
- [Men Laughing]
What about the other one with the legs?
I'm telling you...
this is the one.
You don't think she's getting
fed up with him already, do you?
Just because we do the same thing over
and over again doesn't, you know...
You call that routine?
Well, yeah, sure, anybody would.
I mean, so would... my parents.
- Speaking of my parents,
- Uh-huh?
They're gonna be in town tomorrow night,
and we'd love you to stop by.
- It's no big deal. If you're around.
- Uh-huh.
Bingo. Thirty seconds,
he's out of here.
No! It's high time
he should meet her parents.
Oh, God.
The parent moment, right?
Come on, Thomas. She's not gonna
wait around forever. Don't blow it.
- Marry her, don't marry her.
- Phone me when it's over.
Okay, the parent moment.
I don't have any problem
with meeting your parents.
- At some point.
- "At some point"?
God, you know,
listen to you.
Any time things get remotely
serious, you start...
I don't know,
wiggling around.
Hmm?
I thought you liked it
when I wiggled around.
God, where did I go wrong?
Guy likes to play the field,
you know. Takes after me.
A baboon in heat
takes after you.
[Laughing]
Oh, Julia, you're killin' me.
[Laughs]
You're killin' me. Oh, yeah,
I'm already dead. I forgot.
Huh.
[Clears Throat]
You guys. Oh.
It... is... time, whoo.
"It's time, whoo"?
All right, all right, all right.
I'm a little late. L...
I should have picked you up
about 15 or 20 years ago,
but, you know, up there,
time's a little relative.
Let's go, dead people.
Time to, you know,
t-t-to go.
[Bus Driver]
I'm taking you onwards.
I know you.
You're the bus driver.
Very good. Now come on.
You're the idiot
that got us all killed.
Yeah.
You lousy bastard.
Because of you,
I've spent the last 30 years...
coolin' my heels
with Mr. Excitement here.
I, I can't get a decent meal,
I can't get a smoke...
and especially,
I can't get laid.
You've turned me
into a goddamn monk!
Hey, back off!
I died in that crash too.
We are so sorry.
Aren't you even gonna
apologize for what you did?
Well, I-I'm doin' penance. I'm drivin'
this bus around for the next 500 years.
Believe me, I'm sorry.
- It's not like they gave me
the opportunities that you got.
- Opportunities?
- For what?
- We know we're not dead.
We know we're not alive.
We know we're not there.
For that matter, we're not here.
We're... what?
- What? What, what?
- What?
What, what is... What is this?
What am I, in the Twilight Zone here?
I'm talking about the opportunity
to resolve your lives.
You know, you get to do the one thing
you would've done before you died...
except you didn't get to do it
on account of some guy...
unintentionally cut your lives
a little... short.
We haven't done anything.
We haven't resolved anything!
You're joking.
I mean, you were told
about this?
The angel, he came down, he explained
it to you? That, that you would...
Okay, hold it.
A-all right, hold it.
All right, back off, back off.
All right, all right! Okay.
[Whispering]
[Stammering] Y-You've been hangin'
around in Limboville there...
since the '50s
just wonderin' what gives?
[Sighs]
Well, you see, what you're
supposed to have done...
is to take care of the one thing that
would have made your lives complete.
You know, I mean I'm not talkin'
about makin' a million dollars,
- or shackin' up with some
pinup girl or something.
- Shackin' up with some pinup...
- Shut up!
Well, how in the world are we
supposed to do that? We're spirits.
We can't make a phone call.
We can't...
Punch some bus driver
in the chops.
Your corporeal being.
You're supposed to use him
as a vehicle.
And if he won't do it, you enter
his body and you make him do it.
- Enter his body?
- We can take him over?
Well, that would've
been helpful to know.
I knew there was a reason
for all of this.
Yeah, yeah, sure. It's all part
of the grand scheme of things.
Which is worth diddly if someone
doesn't get his halo down here
and tell you what's goin' on.
Oh, thank God. I thought we were
gonna be stuck here forever!
Oh, this is great.
My kids!
I can find out about my kids!
No. No, no. No, no, no.
Wait a second now.
It's too late now. I mean,
I got the bus. It's right here.
What?
You can't take us now.
- Now that we know?
- I gotta take you now. It's time.
And there are new babies on the way,
and you guys are my responsibility.
It's your fault we're here!
I mean, don't you have a conscience?
Everybody gets cancellations.
- Not everybody.
- Oh, come on, please!
Think of your guilt.
Just a little while longer.
You're in charge!
- Look at your schedule.
- Think about your guilt.
All right.
Maybe I can hold off...
until each one of you
is actually needed.
Would you? You would.
I would, but it's not gonna be long,
I'm warning you.
[Groaning] I can't believe
I'm even doing this. It's crazy.
You know, I'm stickin'
my neck out here,
and when I come back for ya,
you better be ready.
- I got first dibs on him.
- [Julia] Oh, no, you don't!
- Hey, Thomas! Hey, man!
- Thomas!
Remember me? It's Milo.
Long time, no see, huh?
...the greatest times of my life.
- Long time, still no see.
[Arguing] You're not
doing it right. Let me try!
- [Arguing Continues]
- When we met, you had this... spark.
- Sure.
- What is she talking about?
- I'm just trying to bring that back.
- Thomas, can you hear us?
- I'll meet your parents tomorrow night.
- We're screwed.
- The guy's brain dead.
- Are you concentrating like we used to?
- [Arguing Continues]
- Yes, I'm concentrating!
- How are we gonna get through to him?
- We don't just scream at him.
Thomas!
Hey, wake up!
- Milo, shhh.
- [Horn Honks]
- Stop it. Sit down!
- You can't just yell at him.
Come on, we have to concentrate
together like we used to.
It's a lot easier
to disappear than to appear.
Sing "Walk Like A Man."
- "Walk Like A Man"?
- Good idea.
- Concentrate.
- Okay. Okay, okay, concentrate.
Walk like a man
Talk like a man
my son
No woman's worth
crawling on the earth
- So walk like a...
- This isn't working.
Oooh
[Yelling Together]
Thomas! Thomas!
Thomas, it's me.
It's Milo.
It's not, not the radio.
It's me! [Growls]
[Grunting]
Ohhh!
- Contact.
- Hope he doesn't take this badly.
[Yelling]
[Tires Screeching]
[Indistinct Shouting]
- You yelled at him in a moving car!
- I did not! I was just a bit loud.
You did. You always
yell everything!
It wasn't even my idea, okay?
It was Penny's. She was the one goin'...
As if... Don't try
to blame me, boy.
- How long's he gonna be out?
- Do I look like an anesthesiologist?
- We've lost a whole night already!
- Nice.
[Groaning]
My car. Uhh,
what happened to my car?
- Thomas?
- Ah, he may be a tad upset.
Thomas?
Sweetie pie,
can you hear us?
We're so sorry, Thomas.
Don't worry, you're gonna be okay.
- What have they got me on?
- How are ya?
You just cracked a couple of ribs,
but you're gonna be okay.
- Oh, my God!
- Thomas, it's been a very long time.
We hope you haven't forgotten us.
We really need your help.
[Gasping]
- God, they're back.
- He remembers us!
- [Shouting]
The hallucinations are back.
I never thought of us
as hallucinations.
- Me, neither. Where's he going?
- Wait!
- Thomas?
- Where are you going?
- Bathroom down here?
- We finally figured out
what we're supposed to do.
You're supposed to stay
deep, deep in my subconscious.
Don't run away from us!
- [Arguing]
- Don't jabber at him.
[Arguing Continues]
- [Elevator Bell Rings]
- [Indistinct Chattering]
- He's completely ignoring us!
- Pretending he don't know us.
- [Muttering]
- Oh, straitjacket city!
Thomas, you're not crazy!
- We're real, in our way.
- Hi, guys.
He's a lucky one.
He gets visitors.
- Yeah, sure. Yeah.
- I never get visitors.
[P.A.]
Dr. Singer, please call the operator.
[Sirens Wailing]
Hi.
No, not today.
I'm off medication.
[Sighing, Whispering]
This is gonna sound crazy.
Hmmm?
- Do you see any other people with me?
- No.
- [Sighing]
- Nobody... besides those four.
Do you really see them?
Yes.
What do they look like?
There's a gentleman in a brown hat,
a nice-looking black lady,
a blonde lady
with a pink dooley...
and a young buck
in a leather jacket.
I'm available.
Oh, and the naked guy
with the nose ring.
- Hmmm? No, there's no naked guy...
- I know that!
You double-check me;
I double-check you.
[Laughing]
You're lucky. Well,
the ones I see aren't real.
The ones I see come in the daytime,
and sometimes they stay around.
Like other planets. The stuff they send!
I mean, people from other places.
- Things from other places.
- You're real.
We've always thought so.
Yeah. I mean,
we can't do much.
- We can't do much.
- No.
[Sighing] See, I thought I had
these serious emotional problems.
- So I convinced myself I'd made you up.
- No, no.
We've been here right beside you
all the time, Thomas.
We were supposed to have you help finish
things for us, things we needed to do.
This is so amazing.
- [Laughing]
- Isn't it wonderful, Thomas?
The way the pieces all fit,
you and us... I mean...
What on earth makes you think I
would do anything to help you?
Thomas Kenneth Reilly,
you get back here!
I told ya, I told ya!
Don't leave him, he's gonna be mad!
Whoa! Help me. Oh!
[Milo] I'm real sorry. Really.
You have insurance, right?
- [Thomas] You may not ride in the car.
- [Penny] You drive too fast anyway.
Look, I said I was sorry,
and I have a name, you know.
I am not going to run all over
the place trying to fix things
you should have fixed years ago.
- Find some other kid
and screw up his life.
- Sorry, we're stuck to you.
Where do you get off being so pissed?
We had great times together.
That's true. You did things with us
no other kid ever got to do.
Yeah, right. And then
you left me all alone!
- [Julia] No, we didn't leave you.
- Oh, yeah, well...
you disappeared
when I was seven years old.
- We felt we had to.
- God, I've had no privacy.
You've been with me on my dates.
- Well, we didn't look.
- Yes, we did.
I was in therapy for years trying to
figure out what the hell happened to me.
- We know. We were there.
- I got more out of it that you did.
- You got something out of his therapy?
- That whole "self-esteem" thing.
- I really got in touch...
- Could you not speak for an hour?
- I have a life to lead here.
- Huh, is that what you call it?
Do me a favor,
fade out again.
He's not that
happy to see us.
Let's table that till next week and give
Jim a chance to analyze the prospectus.
Now, Thomas. Thomas!
We're gonna be with you forever
unless you help us!
- He's speaking to you!
- Yeah?
Where are we with Stellar Aviation?
Are we still going for liquidation?
Oh, yeah, well, if we want
to get our money back, yes.
I was actually just going over
the figures that I gave to the judge...
[Papers Ruffling]
The last quarter alone,
Stellar lost $3 million.
These clowns are going down fast.
I can't believe
he won't help us.
You know, the bus driver said
we could just take over his body.
Without his permission?
That's fairly aggressive.
Can we do that?
Let's find out.
The judge is with us on this.
He's a reasonable man.
- Okay, here goes.
- It's the same guy we used
on the MacKenzie liquidation.
He realizes that
the longer we delay...
the worse it is for us...
[Voice Fluctuating]
And... our... creditors.
Ohhh!
But enough about them.
Mmm. Oh, God,
it feels so good.
You know, Mitchell, for an older man,
you really are quite attractive.
[Mumbling]
- [Clears Throat] Thomas!
- I'm sorry.
You know, 11 men
and only one woman?
I think we can do
a little better than that.
- Don't you, Jim?
- Jesus, Thomas, what is this?
[Laughing]
- It works!
- It's nothing.
- We're still going to the game Saturday.
- It feels really weird.
Look, you, this is my livelihood.
You can't do this.
Oh, Thomas, you're so
cute when you get mad.
- Look, this is my livelihood!
- Thomas!
What is going on?
I'm just... I'm sorry.
Just... excuse me.
Look, this is all very illuminating,
all this business mumbo jumbo,
but basically,
who gives a shit...
when there's a beautiful
dish like you in the room?
- [Gasps]
- [Grunts]
You know how long it's been
since I've had sex?
- I'm quite a master.
I'll give you a preview.
- [Screams]
[Grunting, Groaning]
[Laughing]
[Yelling]
Don't go anywhere.
I'll be back in a few.
Ohhh!
Get out of my body!
It's just the beginning, pal.
[Grunts, Groans]
Myself, now I don't
run into walls. It hurts.
Listen, you jerk,
you know that happens to be...
the vice president of corporate finance
you were coming on to in there!
- Oh, yeah? Well, you better help us.
- Thomas, you deserved it.
You're not gonna bully me into this.
You're not gonna push me into anything.
Oh, yeah? It's time you tell your boss
what you think of him. How about that?
- Maybe I'll take your car for a spin.
- Yeah.
- I didn't know you knew how to drive.
- I'll take a shot at it.
Now, listen, listen.
Okay, okay? All right.
We're gonna work something out.
I am in such trouble. I have no idea how
to explain what just happened in there.
You were in a car accident.
The doctors mistakenly prescribed...
morphine and Percodan...
causing temporary...
uh, ha-hallucinations.
Percodan and morphine, right.
- Could that happen?
- [Harrison] I have no idea.
- [Milo] Turn the page!
- [Thomas] Okay.
So this guy takes you
to heaven on a bus?
A bus. Go figure.
"Marco." Here he is.
Here he is.
The bastard's still alive,
still living at the same address.
- Okay, let's go. Come on, let's go!
- "Let's go"? Wait, wait!
What? Where? When? You know,
what are you getting me into here?
[Sighs]
Okay.
I stole a lot of things in my life.
But just from rich people, you know.
But this one time,
I, um... I went too far.
L... I was doing a job
for this guy, and, uh,
he wanted to buy these stamps
from a ten-year-old kid.
Stamps? This is about postage stamps?
That's great.
Excuse me, the 1930 air mail
zeppelin stamp, full sheet.
- It's gotta be worth $100,000 today.
- Huh.
- See?
- So?
So, um... anyway...
the kid won't sell 'em,
no way, so...
the guy has me go back...
and steal 'em.
Lowest thing I ever did.
Once I gave them back,
I was gonna go straight,
but... next thing I know,
I'm dead.
So...
I'm a bad guy forever.
Let's go.
[Julia] He's coming back.
He looks happy.
- I found them.
He's still got 'em. Let's go.
- Yes!
I c-can't. I'm sorry. You know what
this is? This is grand larceny.
No, it's not. It's breaking and
entering. It's 90 days to a year, max.
Milo, you understand?
If you get caught, Thomas goes to jail.
Well, we're not gonna get caught, okay?
I'm a professional.
All right? Marco's upstairs taking
a shower. That gives us five minutes.
- We're in, we're out. Piece of cake.
- No, I'm... God!
This happened 33 years ago.
Does it even matter now?
Thomas, I gotta
set it right. Okay?
You don't get it?
It matters to me.
Okay, but if I'm gonna let you
in my body, you have to behave.
- I will. Okay.
- Okay.
- And be careful.
- Okay. Okay.
- I will... behave.
Thomas, I want your body.
[Laughs]
It's not funny.
Just get in and get it over with.
Where's that little kid I had so much
fun with, huh? Where did he go?
God, the man's tense,
you know what I mean?
Okay, ah... where's that stuff you...
Oh, I forgot, I'm him.
- [Chuckles]
- Let's go.
Let me go.
Okay, come on.
- [Barking]
- [Screaming]
[Screaming,
Barking Continues]
- Piece of cake? I'm a piece of dog food!
- We're okay.
[Barking Continues]
Hey, shut up,
you little chihuahua!
- Thomas!
- Hey, hey, hey.
What the hell?
Who the hell do you
think you are?
- [Sizzling]
- Hey, hey, watch out! Watch out!
[Grunts]
- Not this time, Marco.
- Who are you?
Oh, it's Milo.
Remember me?
Milo? No,
that guy's dead.
- Well, not at the moment.
- [Grunts]
Milo!
Stealing from a kid?
You oughta be ashamed of yourself.
[Barking Continues]
There was a house.
Had a house here.
Is this the way
professionals do it?
Because I have never met a professional
who has fouled up this big!
You didn't see a dog.
You didn't check for a dog!
Don't yell at a man
on a ledge.
Come on, don't get so upset.
I'll just do a... little...
- acrobatic type thing.
- "Acrobatic type thing"?
- What do you think you're doing?
- He's not a Flying Walenda!
Here, you wanna take over,
Harrison?
Oh, I hope you know what you're doing.
That's not your body.
- No problem.
- [Electricity Crackling]
- I'm okay.
- [Screaming]
[Grunts]
I got it. I got it.
[Screaming Continues]
[Grunts] Hey, what'd I tell you?
I'm a professional.
- I got it.
- [Screaming]
[Grunting]
Whew, and not a bruise
on him... mostly.
You're lucky
you're already dead.
- You don't think, Milo.
- Thomas could have been killed!
Let's not kill me until
everyone else has had a chance.
- We didn't get caught.
What's the big deal?
- Excuse me, sir.
Is there a problem,
Officer?
I'd say so.
Doesn't seem to be your day.
You're parked next to
a fire hydrant.
- [Sighs]
- [Laughing]
Is that all?
It would be, except for the $2,600
you have in outstanding parking tickets.
Ya see?
You get in trouble without me too.
- Shut up.
- What?
[Harrison] Milo, if it weren't
for you, I would never have...
- gotten to ride on one of these.
- Ya see?
Something good
comes outta everything.
[Man] That's $2,600
for the tickets.
With interest and penalty fees
that comes to $3,228.
[Thomas] Ten percent interest?
In this economy?
- Just say, "Thank you, Sergeant."
- Thank you, Sergeant.
Thank you
for shopping with us.
[Milo]
So far, so good, huh?
[Thomas] Shut up!
I'm out $3,000!
- [Milo] Put it on my tab, Tommy.
- Tab? What tab?
By the way, don't call me Tommy!
You are not my friends!
[Harrison] It's exactly that attitude
that alienates people.
[Thomas]
I forgot about Anne! Her parents!
[Harrison] Does it bother anyone else
that this is a one-way street?
- [Honking, Screeching Continues]
- [Yelling]
[Anne]
He gets so busy.
He never knows what
his schedule's gonna be.
- They really rely on him at work.
- Don't worry about it, darling.
- Maybe we'll meet him tomorrow.
- Hmm.
- Bye.
- Yeah, he really wants to meet you.
- Bye-bye, sweetie.
- Bye.
It must have been some kind
of emergency at work.
- Bankruptcies can be unpredictable.
- Relax, honey.
- We'll give him another chance.
Then we'll kill him.
- [Laughs]
[Car Engine Starting]
- [Horns Honking, Tires Screeching]
- [Thomas] You jerk!
[Milo] How long
is this gonna take?
Hey. I happen to care about
this woman. Okay?
Do you mind if I keep
one thing in my life on track?
Anne!
Hi. I'm sorry.
- I'm really sorry. You're angry.
- Don't be sorry.
- I can tell.
- I was angry.
I've been through concern,
worry, annoyance.
- Where are you now?
- I'm fine.
- I had a great time with my parents.
- Uh-huh.
- You could have called.
- I know, I should have called.
- I'm sorry I didn't.
- Let's just face it.
We get along okay,
but things are not going...
Wait. What do you mean,
"okay"?
I think there's more here
than just "okay." For me.
Things aren't
going anywhere.
Our relationship is not proceeding
along normal lines.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- When normal people get involved,
they just naturally
take a natural course.
Yeah.
It's like your keys.
My keys.
Yes. I don't even have
the keys to your apartment.
- Okay, you want my keys.
- No. No, it's a symbol.
A symbol of a relationship
that is going somewhere.
- Are you listening?
- Yeah, I'm sorry.
[Snaps Fingers]
I'm here, I'm here.
We meet,
we are attracted,
we trade keys
and you meet my parents.
I'm aware of the significance
of parent-meeting.
You think that I haven't screwed up
enough relationships to know that?
- I want to meet your parents.
- You do?
Mm-hmm.
They have tickets
to a concert tomorrow night.
- Great.
- No way. We can't.
- Thomas, we need you.
- Mmm, I can't do it tomorrow night.
- Aw, Jesus.
- Anne, please.
Things are
really complicated for me.
At work.
Okay? Th-There are
these people in town.
Four very pushy and annoying people,
okay, from this damn bankruptcy.
But I swear to god
I wanna meet your parents.
I'll walk to San Diego
on my knees to meet them.
- On your knees?
- Yes.
In a new suit, I hope?
Yes, in a new suit. You have no idea.
They're... You know.
- I'm still mad.
- You have every right to be.
- Good night.
- Good night. I'll call you.
- 'Night.
I like her.
She's strong without being pushy.
I like her too,
but I gotta return these stamps.
- I'm sorry. Let's go. I'll be brief.
- Very nice.
- Okay, you stay in bed.
- God, I hope it's the right guy.
How many Duane Dortmuellers
could there be?
- Yeah?
- It's him.
Look down.
Look down, for God's sakes!
- [Rattle Falls]
- Wha...
Gimme...
Honey!
Look at this!
- It's the stamps!
- [Door Closing]
[Laughing]
- I did it!
- [Laughing]
[Laughs] That was great!
Wasn't that great?
- I'd say... that was great.
- That was great.
- He looked so happy.
- This is gonna work! We can do this!
- Oooh
- You did a good thing. Smile!
You remember smiling?
Open your lips, show your teeth.
Wa-wa walk
- Oooh
- Like a man
- Bye-aye, baby
- Ooh-wa-ooh
- I don't mean maybe
- Gonna get along somehow
- Ooh-wa-ooh-wa, ooh-wa-ooh
- Soon you'll be cryin'
- Ooh-wa-ooh
- On account of all your lyin'
But, yeah, just look
who's laughing now
- I'm gonna
- Walk like a man, yeah
Fast as I can, yeah
Walk like a man
from you
I'll tell the world
forget about it, girl
And walk like a man
from you
Oooh
Oh, my God.
I need one of you now.
- Hello!
- Guess we're thinkin' about me, huh?
[Sighing]
Hey.
We had fun, huh?
- Yeah.
- [Laughs]
Buggin' you is what kept me
goin' all these years.
[Laughs]
You're the best mom
I ever knew, Penny.
- You go find your kids, okay?
- Oh, Milo.
- [Sighing]
- Milo,
- try not to...
- What?
- All of the above.
- [Laughs]
Hope you meet a good-lookin'
angel up there.
Go get 'em, buddy.
Good luck, you know.
I mean, whatever. This is strange.
I know.
[Laughs]
[Clears Throat]
Uh, listen.
[Chuckles]
Listen to this.
Now.
Why don't you come back
when we're all done...
and then you could take us
all at once, you know?
- Save you a lot of mileage.
- Hey, look, pal.
I bought you every second I could,
but a new life's being created...
and it needs a soul now!
You try to be a nice guy.
I'll be back
for you guys soon.
Hey, buckaroo.
You really came through for me
back there. That meant a lot to me.
- Hey, Milo.
- What?
So who's next?
Who's next? Excuse me.
Excuse me. I know I'm in the minority,
being the only living person here,
but I do have a life and I have a job
that I occasionally go to.
Thomas Reilly.
All right. I'll cancel the morning.
I'll cancel the day.
[Harrison Clears Throat]
I'm, uh... I'm not really comfortable.
[Julia]
Will you stop making excuses?
There are plenty of places
to sing.
- There's jazz clubs, karaoke.
- [Clearing Throat]
- Shoot, we could crash a wedding.
- It's 7:30 in the morning.
The only people singing
are drunk.
So look, we'll postpone
the singing, all right?
What about you two?
Penny, Julia?
John's farm is a couple hours drive.
Let's find Penny's kids.
- It's okay?
- [Julia] Yeah.
Okay, let's go for it. Nothing could
be harder than gettin' those stamps.
Adoption records
from the 1950s are sealed.
Even the adopted children
themselves...
need a court order
to open them.
- If they're lucky.
- A court order.
- How long does that take?
- Too long.
Plus a month.
- [Thomas] Do you live around here?
- Who are you, the man?
I'm not a cop. I'm trying to
help this lady find her kids.
What lady?
She lived here in the '50s.
Her name is...
[Harrison] This is something.
A bunch of people that don't exist...
Looking for children
that don't exist.
- We'll never find her kids.
- Here she comes. Shh!
It's no use. Nobody here will
ever remember me or my children.
Oh, Penny, come on.
We just started.
We'll try
a couple of other places.
Was there a store
you went to a lot?
We could go by, ask there.
Or church.
- Did you go to church?
- [Cats Meowing]
Could she
still be alive?
I know
where the girls are.
- [Gasps]
- Where?
They sent me birthday cards
for a while.
- What sweet children.
- Yes, they are.
- Especially Diane. She's so thoughtful.
- Where?
Oh, they sent them
to Sacramento.
There was
a nice family there.
Name of, uh...
Name of...
Timmer... Timmerson.
That's it, Timmerson.
Little Billy, though,
I lost track of him.
- They put him in a foster home.
- Oh!
And then they kept
moving him around.
Thomas, what are we
gonna do about Billy?
Those girls might know
where he is, though.
[Horns Honking]
I don't believe
this damn traffic!
- W-Where are they all going?
- [Julia] Don't worry, Penny.
It's gonna be okay.
We're gonna get there.
This is silly. We can't drive two hours
to Sacramento. It's not fair to you.
- It's not fair to Harrison.
- Don't worry. I'm happy to go last.
In fact, I've always
wanted to see Sacramento.
I can't believe you're trying to wiggle
out of it. Talk about your last chance.
W-What do you mean?
John's farm is on the way, isn't it?
- I've always wanted to see John's farm.
- Wait a minute. Thomas.
Find someplace to pull over.
Come on, pull over.
Look where
these people are going.
[Harrison] I don't wanna be here.
I don't feel that well.
I-I think I have
a cold coming on. A flu!
- [Harrison Clears Throat]
- [Julia] Stop complaining.
- Nah. They're sold out.
- Oh, sh...
- That's it, let's go.
- Will you stop it?
- They're sold out! We can't get in.
- We gotta find another place.
No, we don't.
- You just need a little help.
- No, no, no.
- Do it!
- Don't look at me like that.
- Not without my permission.
- May I please?
- Oh, God. No!
- Aaaah!
- It's sold out!
Excuse me. If you're gonna be back here,
you have to have a pass.
A pass?
A pass!
I'm gonna pass
some information onto you.
Youse bozos outside got their trucks
blockin' my car in. My Rolls Royce.
- Where did you park?
- Are you listenin' to me?
I said I parked between your trucks!
That's why I can't move.
Don't you give me attitude.
I'm a mother!
No, I mean, I'm a...
I'm a doctor!
I'm a surgeon. I come down here
as a favor to Mr. King.
His hands are insured for $1,000,000.
The insurance company's not gonna...
let him walk out on stage until
they had him checked out by me!
Meanwhile, I got a medical emergency,
but I can't get my damn car out!
- Sir, just calm down.
- Calm down? I am calm.
You want loud?
I will get loud...
- if you want me to get loud!
- No, no, no! I, uh...
You get that manager right now, get his
butt down here and I might calm down.
- Fine. I'll take you to him.
- I'm not goin' anywhere!
You bring him to me.
I'm a doctor!
I'll be right back.
[Laughing]
- Not bad.
- Drama class, City College.
- You got us in.
- Harrison, take it away!
What? You expect me to get up
in front of all those people?
- They don't wanna see me.
- They can't see you!
- Yeah, but I can see them!
- Penny, what exactly is your plan?
My plan was to
get you in here.
You're in, now you two
get out there and sing!
The second I walk out there,
they're gonna grab me.
We should be in Sacramento.
Thomas, you gotta
make him do it.
It's very important to him,
whether he admits it or not.
It's not that important.
What? No! No!
Ooooh, no!
- Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
- [Crowd Murmuring]
Please rise
for our national anthem.
You gotta be kiddin'!
Dear God, Thomas, that's
an incredibly difficult piece!
[Julia] Perfect! Sing it right,
they're gonna know you're good!
[Murmuring Continues]
They bought it.
- You're on.
- Okay, Harrison, I'm all yours.
- I can't even remember the words.
- Get your butt in there.
- Come on, man!
- To see B.B. King!
- Let's go!
I can't.
I can't!
What are you doing?
Look at me. I'm not even alive
and I'm perspiring!
You better not do this, Harrison.
Listen! This is it!
Who came up with this
ridiculous concept anyway?
Resolve your entire life in
one bold stroke? What if I fail?
And I will, I'll fail.
I'm telling you, I always fail.
Then my whole life
will be a complete failure.
No offense, Harrison, but you died
a failure because you never tried.
[Murmuring Continues]
Oh, say, can you see
By the dawn's early light
Wha...
What so proudly we hailed.
What so proudly we hailed
At the twilight's
last gleaming
Whose broad stripes
and bright stars
Through
the perilous fight
O'er the ramparts
we watched
Were so gallantly streaming
And the rocket's
red glare
- [Guitar]
- [Crowd Cheering]
The bombs bursting
in air
[Guitar]
- Gave proof through the night
- [Band]
- That our flag was still there
- [Band Continues]
Oh, say, does
that star-spangled
Banner yet wave
[Crowd Cheering]
O'er the land
of the free
And the home
Of the
Brave
- Bravo!
- Harrison, you did it!
Bravo!
Bravo, Harrison!
[Band:
"The Thrill Is Gone"]
Thank you, Thomas.
Thank you for believing in me.
I'm going on tour,
you know.
Thrill is gone
The thrill is gone away
The thrill is gone, baby
You done me wrong, baby
You'll be sorry
Don't get him mad.
Be really nice, Thomas.
We have to
get out of here fast.
Welcome back, Mr. Reilly.
How's show biz?
I assure you, Sergeant.
I'm not drunk, I'm not on drugs.
Your blood test shows that.
So what is wrong with you?
- [Phone Ringing]
- It was just... somethin' I had to do?
I'm going to assume that you've gotten
whatever it is out of your system.
- Oh, yeah.
- I'm gonna release you.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
It's the last you'll see of me.
- Bail is set at $300.
- Thank you, Sergeant.
It's the last you'll see of me.
- Bail is set at $300.
- All right. Can I get something to eat?
- It has to be to go.
- God!
- Oh, Thomas.
Anne! Hi!
God, what a night! God...
- How did you know I was here?
- I saw you get arrested.
I was at the concert
with my mother and father.
- This is really unfair.
- How could you do that to me?
- Baby...
- Don't call me baby.
- I have hung in there a long time.
- I know!
- You lied to me!
You said you had to work.
- I'm sorry.
You didn't say you had to sing
the national anthem and get arrested!
But I didn't know
I was gonna do that!
It was just
a spur of the moment thing?
Yeah! Actually,
actually, it was.
And how come I don't even know
you can sing like that?
- You keep that a secret.
- Because, because...
Because I don't do it
very often. That's why!
- Was it okay?
- Yeah, it was good. It was really good.
It's like you're leading a double life:
Banker, lunatic, performance artist.
Damn it, Anne, are you
gonna let me explain?
Yes! Explain.
I'm ready.
- Well, that clears it up for me!
- Anne, come on.
- Oh, God, I feel like such a jerk.
- Sweetheart.
You're acting like this is
Days Of Our Lives!
[Penny] Thomas, do not argue.
Just apologize!
- Anne, I'm sorry. I apologize.
- Good-bye, Thomas.
- Yeah, do this to me. Go away. Anne.
- [Car Engine Starting]
Anne, let's be grown-ups.
- Anne!
- [Tires Screeching]
Shit!
- You let her go.
- I did not let her go.
- You did.
What am I supposed to do?
Jump in front of the car?
You guys are a lot of help.
Come on.
- Maybe you should call her.
- We think you should call her.
- No. Enough!
- You'd feel better.
Have you forgotten your basic problem?
We've gotta keep moving.
- [Gasps]
- Oh, boy. Bad sound.
That's all right. I'll be quick.
I'll just give him the rest of my money.
Mr. Reilly, is it
something genetic with you?
Tell me you're not insured,
and you'll be three for three.
- No, I'm heavily insured, I promise.
- Ouch! Aaah!
- Penny, I'll tell him to take me.
- No, no.
I am so sorry.
- All right, you're sorry.
Can we get on with this?
- [Baby Crying]
- [Woman] She wants you.
- It's all right, sweetheart.
- Mr. Hug-a-bug
- I really have to go.
- Hug-a-bug, Hug-a-bug Bear
- Can I give you
my license and insurance?
- You can mail 'em to me.
- When you try and find him
He won't be there
But when you're feeling blue
and a little bit scared
- Thomas! That's...
- He'll be right beside you
- That's the song
you used to sing to Thomas.
- Mr. Hug-a-bug Bear
- I remember.
- I-I made that up!
I used to sing it to my kids before
I put 'em to bed. They loved it.
- Especially Billy.
- And a little bit scared
He'll be right beside you
Mr. Hug-a-bug Bear
- Why? Wait a minute. We had a deal.
- Wait.
- Come on.
- Give her a minute.
- What is the matter with him?
- I have only myself to blame.
I put him
back out on the street.
Ask him.
Ask him if he's Billy!
Are you... Billy?
- Is your name Billy? Your first name?
- To my friends.
Ask him, Thomas.
Ask him if he was adopted.
Sgt. Barclay, I was wondering if you
ever might happen to, maybe, be adopted.
If you don't shut up I'm gonna
take you back inside.
- He was! You can tell, Thomas!
- I know I sound absolutely nuts.
Was your mother's name
Penny Washington?
- Billy!
- [Screams]
This is my...
This is...
What is this about?
You've got two older sisters,
Shirley and Diane?
- Am I right?
- Who are you?
Is this some sort of sick joke? Did
I lock your brother up or something?
Do you know where
your sisters are?
- No.
- I do.
- That's ridiculous.
- No, it's not.
I've tried to find my sisters
for 20 years. The records
are sealed, even for a cop.
But remember this lady? This lady
with a million cats? Agnes Miller?
She still lives in
your old neighborhood.
- I do remember a lady with cats.
- I know you remember Agnes.
Call her. Then call a family
named Timmerson in Sacramento.
That's where
your sisters grew up.
- How can you possibly know any of this?
- This is my grandbaby!
My goodness!
Look at that child.
- Julia, she's so cute.
- She's adorable.
That's his wife.
Come here.
- Come. This is... Come here.
- No, I don't wanna get involved.
- But this is who l...
- No, really. I'm gonna... Come on.
Your mother and my mother wound up
in the same emergency room.
My parents told me
that before she died,
she was talkin' about
her kids...
and all she wanted was to make sure
that her kids were all right.
And she sang that song.
- I guess she was delirious by then.
- Hug-a-bug
- But my mom taught it to me.
- Hug-a-bug Bear
So when I heard you singing it,
I just knew.
When you try and find him
he won't be there
Your mother loved you
very much.
She would have been
real proud of you.
- Thomas, I have to do this.
- No.
I never left you.
Can you just get off of me?
Yeah, I'm sorry.
That was... Eee.
It's an emotional time
for us all.
I'm gonna check this out,
Reilly.
- And if it isn't true...
- It's true.
Believe me, it's true.
Come on, sweetheart.
He's such a cop!
"I'm gonna check this out."
That was really humiliating.
- [Sighing]
- [Car Engine Starting, Revving]
- Okay, I'm ready.
- Finally.
- Good-bye, darlin'.
- [Julia Laughing]
You take care.
I'll remember you,
Julia.
I'm really gonna miss you.
I'm saying good-bye
to both my sons.
- Thomas, don't work too hard.
- Okay.
And it's okay
to be a good guy.
Pay more attention to what
you're eating. Julia, hi to John.
You stop driving so fast
and call your mother once in a while.
I love you guys!
Hit it.
[Sighing]
[Rooster Crowing]
[Thunder Rumbling]
- Think it's okay?
- Uh, yeah. It's good.
- He'll believe it?
- He's gotta recognize your handwriting.
Let's go.
Here's what we'll do. I'll tell him
that after the bus accident,
your stuff got mixed up with
my mom's stuff at the hospital, and...
I just happened
to find this letter.
- What?
- He'll buy it. I'll be convincing.
Aw, shit!
They're trying to lose me?
Come on.
- I do you a favor,
you run from me like rabbits.
- Five minutes, okay?
- Just give us five minutes!
- No! It's time on the big clock.
- You take her over my dead body!
- Great. I got the bus right here.
- I don't care. Come on.
- Don't threaten me.
We're talking about right and wrong!
- Look, you watch it, mortal.
- I can't believe you.
You've got eternity on your hands,
she's asking for five lousy minutes.
- I find it hard to believe
you can't find five minutes.
- I don't have the authority.
- Authority for what?
- I can't just change everything.
How do you think I can do that?
- Be creative. Stall.
- Stall?
Stall Him?
- What?
- He's probably got a wife and kids.
I don't wanna...
I-I don't wanna cause a problem.
Come on. He'd still wanna know
that you cared about him.
He'd wanna know
that you loved him.
What if he's
forgotten all about me?
- Julia, no one could forget about you.
- [Door Opening]
Can I help you?
My name's Thomas Reilly and I have
a personal letter for John McBride.
Oh, well... I bought this place
from him seven years ago.
- Do you know where he is now?
- Sorry to have to say it,
- but he died
soon after he sold it to me.
- [Thunder Rumbling]
Are you sure?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I'm sure about that.
He wasn't well. I guess things
were kinda rough on him.
This place was kinda
falling apart when I got it.
Anyway, he moved down to San Leandro
and rented a little apartment.
Well...
that's where they found him.
Oh. I, uh...
- Thanks.
- Sorry.
[Thunder Rumbling]
- The rotor. Maybe it's the rotor.
- [Thomas] Hey!
- What is this crap?
- What? I beg your pardon?
- It didn't work!
She can't fix anything!
- Go on.
- It always works.
- No!
It might seem like these things
are going down to the wire,
- Wrong!
- But they always work out.
The guy's dead, all right!
He's been dead for seven years!
- But... That, that can't be.
- What to you mean, that can't be?
No, you know what?
Or he had to be the wrong guy.
No, it's not the wrong guy!
It's not the wrong guy, you idiot!
- How can it be the wrong guy?
- I don't know.
Thomas.
It's you.
- What's me?
- You and Anne.
- That's what I'm supposed to do.
- Meaning?
I made the same mistake with John
that you're making with Anne.
I pushed him away, kept him at arms
length and finally, he just left.
Only you've got the chance
to fix it.
No. See, Julia,
th-this isn't about me.
Yes, it is.
I've watched you
all these years.
You know how painful it's been
to know who you really are,
and watch you
keep it hidden from people?
I don't hide. I protect myself.
I'm cautious.
You're so afraid of being hurt,
you're gonna end up all alone.
It doesn't matter
if she says yes or no.
Don't let her go without telling her
how you really feel.
Promise me
you're gonna go to her.
Promise me you're gonna live the life
that I didn't get to live.
I promise.
Good.
I like that.
It has unity.
I can go now.
Oh! I wish I could
just give you a big hug.
Oh, wow.
[Laughing]
Thanks.
[Hal]
I'll be back for you...
in 50, 60 years.
I was afraid
you weren't gonna come.
Well,
I wasn't going to...
but... it was hard to ignore
the three phone messages,
the fax, telegram,
homing pigeon.
I, uh,
I got you this.
I've loved people before
and they went away.
So a long time ago, I made a decision
that I wasn't gonna need anyone anymore.
I wasted most of my life
that way.
And I know I'm late
and I know I don't deserve it.
I need you.
And I love you.
I love you.
Oooh
Walk, walk, walk, walk
Walk like a man
- Bye-aye, baby
- Ooh-wa-ooh
- I don't mean maybe
- Gonna get along somehow
- Ooh-wa-ooh-wa, ooh-wa-ooh
- Soon you'll be cryin'
- Ooh-wa-ooh
- On account of all your lyin'
Oh, yeah
just look who's laughing now
I'm gonna walk like a man
Fast as I can
Walk like a man
from you
I'll tell the world
forget about it, girl
And walk like a man
from you
Oooh
Mmmm
The years
they come and go
And change will come
I know
You won't
Be there
My heart
And soul
Different time and place
But time cannot erase
The smile
that lights your face
As you gaze in mine
It will always shine
And you
Will always be
An angel making sure I care
A memory that's always there
You dreams won't die
They live inside of me
You know you'll always be
My heart and soul
Oooh
If the years
can make you wise
Now I finally realize
That if I just close my eyes
I can see you there
And the love we share
And you
Will always be
A dream so real
it cannot die
The trust and faith
that lets me fly
A love so strong
it just belongs to me
You know you'll always be
My heart and soul
Oooh
An angel making sure I care
A memory that's always there
You'll always be my heart
And soul
Oooh
Yeah, yeah
5@y3