[baby crying]
- I know it's hard...
but you can't just leave him
in the hospital.
Why don't Fred and I keep him
just until
you get back on your feet?
- Yeah.
[baby crying]
[snoring]
- Flower?
Flower?
- What do you want?
- Did you buy
any chocolate milk?
- Did you see any in the fridge?
- No.
- Well, if I had bought some,
it would be in the fridge, right?
- Yeah.
There was a fox
at the foot of my bed last night.
- It was just a dream.
Down, down, down.
Yeah.
- Flower?
Flower?
Hey.
'Morning, Garnet.
'Morning, Flower.
- Did you stay all night?
- Yeah. I slept on the couch.
My head feels like a jackhammer's
been at it all night.
So I guess your father's
still sleeping.
Well, I guess I'll go home.
Um...
Yeah.
Hey, can I take
a little shampoo?
- Sure.
- I'll just put it in here
and I'll bring it back later.
- Okay.
- So I'll see you later.
See you, guys.
- See you.
Go away, Garnet.
I want to go back to sleep.
Garnet...
Go.
- Hey, Garnet.
Hey, look, I only took...
well, I took a little,
but I put the conditioner
in here as well,
so I only need one glass.
All right,
well, I'll see you later.
- What you doing, Garnet?
- Nothing.
- Looks to me
like you're eating dirt.
Well, if you're going to lay around
in back alleys all day,
just make sure
you don't get run over.
- Okay.
- Okay, then.
- Is grape your favourite?
- Mm-mm.
- My favourite's black cherry.
- Yeah, black cherry's good.
I'd have to say
it's my favourite, too.
- Really?
- Well, any kind of cherry.
- Anyway, I better go.
- You gonna come around
and see me again?
- Do you want me to?
- Of course.
Or maybe
I'll visit you sometime.
- Well, I guess you could
if you want, sometime.
Okay, bye.
- Hi, Garnet.
Your dad got a new mattress.
[beeping]
- Anything under five.
That's all you got.
You only play one card.
- Okay, I got a three.
- Play it.
- Okay.
- Maybe you should pass.
- No, I can play.
- And so how'd you lose
your licence?
- Drinking
under the influence of alcohol.
The suspension
is totally unfair.
You know,
they should measure out
how far you drive,
and I only drove two blocks,
so it's totally unfair.
[laughter]
- For nothing.
- Seven for nothing.
[laughter]
- Moths flying around
a street light?
- No.
- Stars?
- Yeah.
- I thought they were bugs.
- No.
- Birds?
- Erase it and start over.
The moon?
- No.
- Is it heaven?
[vehicle passing]
Who was that?
- I don't know.
[metal clattering]
[laughter]
[moaning]
[lullaby playing]
- What're you doing?
- Nothing.
Want some waffles?
- Not right now.
- Mr. Hansen threw these worms
into the back alley.
A car was gonna
run over them.
- Those worms are dead.
They need dirt to live.
Just dump those outside.
[shower running]
[television playing]
- Well, I'm gonna get going.
- I'll walk you to your car.
- Dad kissed Barb.
- You shouldn't spy on people.
Did you take something
from my room today?
- No.
- You better not
be taking things from my room.
- I didn't.
- In fact, don't even go
in my room when I'm not there.
- I don't.
- You better not be.
It'll be Garnet's birthday soon.
We should do something special
for him this year.
We should have a party
where we play
those old-fashioned games
that nobody plays anymore.
- Sounds good.
- Well, don't get
so damn excited,
for Christ's sake.
- Well, I said
it was a good idea.
Watch your language.
See who he wants to invite.
Maybe spend a little more
on his present this year.
Get him something special.
- I think you should get him
a present on your own this year.
- I wouldn't know
what to get him.
- Well, take a look at him.
What do you think he would like?
- Why don't you just go shopping
for the both of us?
- I'm getting him something
from myself this year.
- Hey, Garnet,
there's an ant war going on here.
Look at that.
See these big red bastards?
They're decimating
these little black ones,
so I'm like an act of God
making it fair.
You have a magnifying glass?
- No.
- No?
They're indispensable.
You know, you could get lost
in the woods or something,
and you'd be all right as long
as you had one of these.
Check it out.
Because...
you watch.
You, like, just focus...
focus the light here,
focus the beam.
Hmm, hmm.
You see that? You see that?
That's cool, huh?
Hey, would you like this?
- Okay.
- There you go.
There, all you need now
is a knife and a compass,
and you got all you need
to survive.
- You shouldn't have
burned those ants.
- They don't feel anything.
- If they didn't feel anything,
why would they
be running from it?
- Hey, Flower.
Hey, I just gave Garnet
this magnifying glass.
There's this ant war
going on here,
and I was helping out
the little guys.
Aren't you working today?
- No. I'm waiting for your dad.
- My dad had lunch
downtown today.
- Shit.
I'm gonna be late for work.
All right, see you guys later.
- Guess what, Garnet?
Dad and I are planning a party
for you this year.
Is there anything special
you'd like to do?
- A barbeque.
- A barbeque?
It's too cold for a barbeque.
- Thank you.
What?
- We just had sex,
we're sharing a cigarette,
and I'm wondering
what you're thinking.
That's pretty classic, eh?
- I'm not thinking anything.
- Nothing?
- I'm thinking
I should get back to work.
- Before that?
- Before that, I was thinking
that I should stop
sharing cigarettes
or I'm gonna get hooked again.
- My neighbours are gonna think
I'm a whore.
- Why would you say that?
- Because your truck's parked
out front of my place
for an hour
a couple of times a week.
- There's a big difference between
having a lover and being a whore.
- I don't know.
There's a grey zone.
- I told you this
when we started.
- It's been a year, Ed.
Everyone knows.
Everyone.
They do.
- The kids don't know.
- Well, so what if they did?
So what?
Anyway, Flower knows.
- You tell her?
- No, I didn't tell her.
Flower's quite capable
of figuring it out on her own.
- Well, Garnet doesn't know.
- I don't think you know
what Garnet knows.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I just don't see you
talking to him very often.
- My kids
are not up for discussion.
- Well, what is
up for discussion?
- I'm not talking to you
when you're like this.
- Oh, okay.
Well, nice to see you.
Thanks for dropping in.
- This is the living room.
You see that macrame frog?
I made that
when I was in Grade Four.
And Garnet made
that one over there.
It's supposed to be a star,
but it looks more like bird poo.
- What's down there?
- This is my room.
This is my dresser,
and that's my teddy
that I've had since I was a kid.
- If your dad shows up,
I'm gonna have to bolt.
- He won't be back until dinner.
This is a picture of me
when I was little.
- You were cute.
Your boobs have grown a lot
since then.
- Of course. I was eight.
It was taken a few weeks
before my mom died.
This is her.
She was at the lake.
She was 27.
- I can see why
your dad married her.
- People say
that I look like her.
- You do.
- They say
that we have the same eyes.
- You have beautiful eyes.
I've always noticed you.
- You did not.
- I did.
I always thought
how I would love to kiss you.
- You did not.
- I did. I could tell
you had a hot body.
I thought you were special.
That you were so beautiful.
That you were the most beautiful
girl I'd ever seen.
- We should close the door.
- When Barb stays overnight,
does it hurt, what you guys do?
- What are you talking about?
Barb doesn't stay over.
I mean, she has dinner here
sometimes,
we talk at night sometimes,
but she doesn't stay over.
What made you think
that she did?
- Nothing.
- Oh, man, I love this song.
Should have been all right
Could have been here tonight
Could have been
sweet as wine
Could have been a lady
So, Flower, huh?
- My dad would be so mad
if he found out you were driving.
- Hey, I can make up my own mind
about what I do.
It's not like I'm a kid.
You know, it's bad
to leave a car sitting.
An engine can seize, right?
They don't think of those things
when they take your licence away.
Hey, there's Henry
in his '68 Camaro.
Nice car.
Hey, looking good, Henry!
[laughter]
- Anybody want any ice
in their drink?
[laughter]
- Whose idea was it to have
a barbeque this time of year?
- Oh, damn.
- Garnet, where are you going?
- Washroom.
- Garnet...
you should open your presents
while everyone's still here.
Don't you want to make
a birthday wish?
[television playing]
When are you gonna
open your presents, Garnet?
I got you something special
just from me this year.
Go ahead, open it.
- What are you doing?
- It's a BB gun.
- I can see that.
- Garnet, you like it?
Here.
You hold the gun like this.
Move your hand down.
Okay, there.
You keep your finger off the trigger
until you're ready to shoot.
Okay, close your left eye and...
Close your left eye
and look through this notch
at the little tip here.
Okay, when you're ready,
you point it at the target,
you aim,
and then you pull the trigger
gently.
Okay, that's a start.
What were you aiming for?
Well, pick a target.
Make sure the tip is in the "V,"
but no higher
than the top of the "V."
Try Santa Claus.
Hey...
nice shot.
Okay, try to hit it again.
Try the goose.
Holy shit.
You sure
you haven't done this before?
The squirrel.
I think you found your calling.
- I'm too old for this shit.
- Why can't you just try
to enjoy what we have?
- 'Cause it's not enough.
- Well, maybe you want too much.
- Maybe we should end it.
- Okay.
- Just don't pretend
you're making some great sacrifice
for your kids or your dead wife,
because I'm pretty sure
if she were still around,
she'd be just as fed up as I am.
In fact, she might've even
left you by now.
Because the truth is you're just
too selfish to love anyone.
[television playing]
- Here.
Go see if Flower wants some.
- I think she wants
to be alone again.
[knock-knock!]
[television playing]
- I...
am...
pregnant.
- What did you say?
- I've been to the doctor.
- Pregnant? How the hell
did you get pregnant?
- What do you mean?
- How did you get pregnant?
- Well, just like anyone else.
What do you think?
- What are you talking about?
- I'm pregnant!
I had sex, and I'm pregnant!
What don't you understand?
- Don't you yell at me!
Don't you talk to me that way!
We'll make an appointment
to see the doctor tomorrow.
- I've already seen him.
- And you're going to talk
to him about your options.
- I don't need to talk to him
about options.
- Come here.
- What?
I wanna talk to you.
- I don't have
anything else to say.
- Come here.
Come here!
You're crazy if you think
you're going through with this.
- You have nothing
to say about it!
- Flower?
- Stop following me everywhere.
I'm not your mother, you know.
[music]
- One, two...
You can do this, just listen.
- Okay.
- Look...
one, move your foot back.
- Okay.
- Two, one.
- One, two, one.
You're getting it.
You're really graceful,
you know that?
- So who taught you
how to do this?
- Um...
I think it was my second wife,
Marlene.
- Shut up.
It was your mom, right?
- My mom?
- It was.
As you go to your home
by the ocean
May you never forget
those sweet hours
That we spent
in the Red River Valley
And the love we exchanged
'Mid the flowers
Come and sit by my side
if you love me
Do not hasten to bid me adieu
But remember
the Red River Valley
And the cowboy
that loved you so true
Carl...
do you love me?
- I like you...
very...
very, very much.
- 'Cause I'm pregnant,
and I'm wondering
what you're gonna do.
- Are you sure?
- I had tests.
- But I pulled out every time.
- Well, I guess
it wasn't soon enough every time.
- I'm going outside for a smoke.
- Go put those in the truck.
[vomiting]
- Hey, Flower.
- Hi.
Did you remember
the toilet paper and toothpaste?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I reminded him.
So what'd you get
at the library there?
- Some prenatal books.
- You mean,
like having a baby and stuff?
- Yeah.
- You get any books on what to do
once the baby is born?
- I don't need a book for that.
- You're not old enough
to be a mother.
- I've been one since I was six,
remember?
- You're not the one that woke up
every three hours to feed him.
- I was the only kid in Grade Two
who knew how to change a diaper.
- It's more than diapers, missy.
- How would you know?
- Okay. Okay, fine. Go ahead.
Right, you know it all.
I'm just glad your mother's
not here to see this.
- Stop.
Let me out.
Stop! Let me out!
- Close the door.
Garnet.
Garnet, wake up.
- What's wrong?
- Shh... Nothing.
Get dressed.
We're going fishing.
- Why are we going fishing?
- Fishing's fun.
Everyone likes fishing.
- Is Flower coming fishing?
[motor sputtering]
- This looks like a good place.
- You forgot the worms.
- Uh...
pass me those gummy bears.
- Do fish like gummy bears?
- Sure. Don't you?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, well,
fish are no different.
Watch the bobber.
When it goes under,
there's a fish on.
Then you gotta reel it in.
- Aren't you going to fish?
- Maybe later.
- I have to pee.
- Pee over the edge.
- What if I fall?
- Pee in here.
- It won't come.
- Go cross-eyed.
- What?
- Cross your eyes. It helps.
[bottle filling]
- How'd you know that?
- Ancient dad wisdom.
Fucker!
- That motor
was a piece of shit.
- Hold this.
- Flower?
Flower's room is empty.
- She moved to Barb's house.
- Why?
- I don't know.
She didn't want
to live with us anymore.
She's a woman now.
- So you gonna go after him
for child support?
- No.
If he doesn't want to be the father,
I don't want him involved at all.
Don't feel sorry for me.
I'm happy
to be having this baby.
- You got a clean shirt
for school tomorrow?
- Flower always used to
walk me to school.
- Yeah, well, you're big enough
to go to school by yourself.
What are you doing
still wearing your pajamas?
- I don't feel good.
- Don't bullshit me.
Get dressed.
You're not missing school.
- I feel sick.
- I'll give you something
to feel sick about.
You want a ride?
- No.
- Okay.
- Garnet, this is Tara.
She's gonna be helping us out
around here.
- Hi, Garnet.
[gunshot]
- Jesus Christ.
Donna keeps buying me
these goddamn bargain underwear.
- How much do they cost?
- About two bucks.
Only problem is,
most of the time
I've got
about a dollar-fifty of 'em
stuck up the crack of my ass.
- Up the crack of my...
- God bless her.
[crying]
What is it?
What?
Hey, you all right?
[gunshots]
- Hi, Garnet.
- Hi.
- What're you doing?
- Going home.
- How's it going?
- Are you coming home soon?
- I think I'm gonna get a place
of my own once the baby's born.
I heard Dad got a girl
to help around the house.
- Yeah.
- Is she nice?
Does she get the groceries now?
- Yeah.
- Does she remember
to get you chocolate milk?
- I didn't ask for any.
- Do you want to come to my place
for some hot chocolate?
- Okay.
- These are her eyelids.
They're closed now,
but they'll open later.
And this is her little nose
and mouth...
and her arms and her hands.
She has tiny,
tiny little fingers.
And this is her back...
and her legs.
She's only the size
of a grapefruit, but the doctor says
that she can curl up
and stretch out already.
He says that
it's gonna feel like there's
little butterflies inside me.
It'll just be her moving around.
And these are her little feet...
And up here is her little heart.
It sort of sounds
like a cricket.
Here.
Put your head here.
Can you hear it?
- No.
- Listen.
Here.
How about now?
- No.
- Listen.
You hear it?
Here.
Come here.
How you doing?
- Okay.
- Maybe you can come
to the clinic with me next time
and listen to her heart.
- Would you die if it died?
- Why would you ask that?
- You should get it out of you.
- What are you talking about?
- It's making you sick.
- Why can't you just be happy
for once in your life?
You ruin it for everyone.
Go.
Get out of here.
[TV]: . . Than the lower part
of the uterus.
It is about
the same consistency
as the tip of your nose.
The cervix begins dilation
during the early
active labour stage,
when it will dilate
between
one and four centimetres.
During active labour,
dilation will continue to between
five to eight centimetres.
By the transition stage...
- Jesus.
dilation should be completed,
and the cervix...
You know, I may not be big now,
but I was a really big baby,
And my mom had no trouble
whatsoever.
- Giving birth
is the most common thing on earth.
- Yeah, exactly.
[door closing]
- You're late.
Tara had to stay
and keep me company.
Wash up for dinner.
- I'm not hungry.
- Garnet, wash up
and come and eat.
And I'll talk to you later
about missing school
this afternoon.
Come Monday, I'll drive you
to school myself.
- Hi.
- I came by to talk to you
about Flower.
You're gonna be there
when the time comes, right?
- 'Course I will.
- It's funny
the way things turn out.
- You want to come in?
- No.
I'm just going home from work.
I'm tired.
You have to resolve
this thing with her.
- She can come back
anytime she wants.
- Have you told her that?
- I never told her to leave
in the first place.
- I bet you didn't ask her
to stay either.
Right?
She told me she's scared
she could die during labour.
- The thing that happened
to her mom was a total fluke,
one in 10,000.
- I know.
I told her that.
She asked me to be with her
during the birth.
I said I would.
- Thanks.
- I'll see you.
- Is Flower coming home tonight?
- No.
- Flower, I was thinking that,
uh...
maybe I could help you out
with the baby.
- Yeah?
Like watching her
when she's a bit older?
- No, I... well...
Actually, I was thinking that maybe
I could be the baby's father.
- You don't know anything
about being a father.
- Yeah, I know what not to do,
and that's more than some,
you know.
Besides, I can learn from books
and videos, like you do.
- I don't think so, Ronnie.
- You know, Flower,
I could be a really big help.
You know, I could drive you
when you need to
take her somewhere.
You know, I can watch her
when you need to take a nap.
You're gonna have to take
a nap sometimes, right?
You know, when you do,
I'll watch her.
You know,
I'll take her to the park
when she gets older.
You know, you could come, too,
and we'll all go to the park.
- You could be her uncle.
- I'm gonna stop drinking,
Flower.
I'm gonna quit.
You know what? I quit right now.
You see, I just quit drinking.
I'm gonna stop
fucking up, Flower.
I'm not gonna do that anymore.
I just...
I've always loved you, Flower.
I would love your baby
more than anything
in the whole world.
- But I don't love you
like that.
- Well, maybe you would.
You know, after awhile,
you probably would, you know.
I mean, I would work.
I would give you the money,
you know,
to buy things for the baby,
and for yourself, too.
You know, I just...
I know I would be a good father.
- I just need you
to keep being my friend.
- Okay.
- You're gonna have to
be careful with that, you know.
It takes awhile
to properly heal
neck injuries.
- Oh, hi, Mr. Cooper.
What happened to you?
- Oh...
Well, I hope
you get better soon.
- I didn't expect
to see any cops.
- Pulling doughnuts
in front of the police station,
you didn't
expect to see any cops?
You were drunk.
- You destroyed that wall.
You're just lucky
you didn't kill yourself.
You're too old
for this kind of shit.
They'll send you away, you know.
- I know.
- Does it hurt?
- Yeah.
- Well, there's no point
in me hanging around here.
See you later.
- Well, I'm gonna go, too.
Do you want a ride, Flower?
- Oh, no. I'll walk.
- Okay. See you.
- I got you some butter tarts.
I've had such
a sweet tooth lately,
because I'm pregnant, I guess.
- Thanks.
- Is it good?
- Yeah.
- I wish I could be
a better friend.
- You've been my best friend,
Ronnie.
[gunshot]
[whimpering]
- It's gonna be okay.
It's all right.
Don't die.
- What happened to you?
- I want you to leave
and don't come back.
- Well, that's not up to you.
Your dad wants me to stay.
Did you hurt yourself?
Is that blood?
What is your problem?
What are you doing?
[gunshot]
- The doctor said he'd talk to you
about how you're feeling inside,
if you want.
- No.
- That's...
that's what I told him...
And, well,
Flower and l, you can...
you can talk to us
if you want...
You know,
if there's something you need.
- Okay.
[inaudible]
- Well, how did he get his hands
on it in the first place?
- Jesus Christ, Flower,
that gun's been around for years.
He never once
showed any interest in it.
- Until you bought him one
for his birthday.
- A BB gun is a perfectly
normal thing for a boy to have.
Look, you can blame me
all you want,
but I'm doing the best I can.
Okay? I'm doing the best I can.
You need to come home.
- I'm about to have a baby,
and you expect me to come home
after what he just did?
- He was playing with something
that he shouldn't have
been playing with,
and he's learned his lesson.
- I talked to Tara, your helper,
and he wasn't playing, okay?
- Look, you went and got him
when he was a baby.
- I'm gonna have
my own child now.
You've got to take care
of yours.
Barb...
It's happening.
- It's all right, love.
You're gonna be fine.
- I want my dad!
Somebody get my dad.
- Okay, Mr. Buttle,
come this way.
Flower, your dad is here.
- Hi.
[door opening]
- Hi, Flower.
I'm just going to do
a brief examination, okay?
I'll just get you
to roll over onto your back.
- There we go.
There.
- Just try
and breathe normally, okay?
Everything's fine.
I need you to keep an eye
on her blood pressure
and on her temperature.
If her temperature goes up,
give me a phone call
right away, okay?
- Yes.
Okay, Flower, would you like
to go back on your side?
- Another one's coming.
- Just keep rolling over...
[screaming]
- It's okay, it's okay,
it's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
- Come on.
[screaming]
Keep breathing.
Just keep breathing.
Yeah, it's gonna be fine.
She's gonna be fine.
- Hi.
'Morning, Garnet.
- Where's my dad?
Go away.
- Garnet, let me talk to you.
- You should come in again.
- No, I'm just in the way.
- I think Flower liked
having you there.
Hi, Garnet.
- I want to see Flower.
- We're not allowed in there,
but Barb can go in
and tell Flower that you're here.
- I'll tell her.
She'll be glad.
- You might as well sit down.
You hungry?
They have cookies in here.
- Something's wrong with Flower.
- There's nothing wrong.
- I saw her.
There's something wrong.
- There's nothing wrong.
- She's dying.
- She's not dying. She's just
having a baby, for God's sake.
It's perfectly normal.
Why are you always making up problems
for yourself, always worrying?
Always did.
Always cried when you were little.
Drove me crazy.
Come on. The nurse
put out a blanket for you.
Let's go sit down.
- Fred, Garnet hasn't shown up
there by any chance, has he?
No, we've searched everywhere.
Well, he must be at the house.
No, no, no. I'll go.
Ok, bye.
I'll go check at home.
- All right.
Don't be long. She's close.
- If there's an emergency,
call me at the house.
Garnet?
[dring!]
Hello.
No, I can't find him anywhere.
Thanks.
I'II... I'll go check.
...the baby turns
to the posterior position,
which means she faces
the front of the pelvis.
If this happens,
her head puts added pressure
on the mother's back,
which may cause
painful back labour
and slower progress.
Due to the force
of contractions
and the shape of the pelvis,
a posterior baby
will usually turn on her own
to the anterior position
prior to birth.
The practitioner may suggest
the use of labour positions
that can help a posterior baby
turn,
or may attempt
to rotate the baby manually
by turning the baby's head...
Flower's wondering
where you are.
She had her baby...
And they're both fine.
She told me
to come and find you.
She wants us to come
and visit her...
and the baby.
She's waiting for us.
- You didn't want me.
- I wanted my wife back.
It wasn't your fault.
I'm sorry
I never told you that.
But it wasn't...
- How's Flower?
She's all right?
Good.
Well, does she look
just like her?
Yeah, her brown eyes?
Jeez.
Well...
Oh, that's great,
that's great.
Well, tell her I say hi.
Well, what's her name?
Oh, that's perfect,
that's perfect,
'cause it's like Rose
and her little...
Flower and her little Rose,
right, right.
Wow.
Okay, well,
I'll be home in 10 days.
Yeah.
Tell her I say hi.
Tell her I say hi, Ed.
Okay.
Okay, bye. Bye.
- Could I hold her, Flower?
- Careful, she's fragile.
- I know.