[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Wolf Howling ]
[ Groans ]
[ Bird Squawking ]
[ Boots Rattling ]
[ Rattling Continues ]
[ Gurgling ]
[ Wolf Howling ]
[ Man's Voice ]
l am the lord of darkness.
l require the solace
of the shadows...
and the dark of the night.
Sunshine is my destroyer.
All this shall change.
Tonight, the sun sets forever.
There shall never be
another dawn...
[ Knocking ]
Enter!
[ Door Creaking ]
[ Boots Rattling ]
Ah, Blix.
Come closer.
You summoned me, lordship?
Are you not the most loathsome
of my goblins?
[ Gurgling ]
Truly, master.
And is your heart black
and full of hate?
Black as midnight,
black as pitch,
blacker than
the foulest witch.
That is why
I have called you here.
Since I must remain in darkness,
you shall be my eyes and ears.
You do me
great honor, lord.
Something troubles me.
l feel a presence
in the forest,
a force l had mercifully
almost forgotten.
Must be dread, indeed,
to trouble you, lordship.
Looking upon
these frail creatures,
one would not think that
they could contain such power.
One could rule
the universe with it.
You must find them for me
and destroy them!
[ Gurgling ]
What do they look like, lord?
Fool! Let this
serve to remind you.
They are each crowned
with a single horn...
reaching straight
to heaven.
I get the point, lord.
Bring the horns to me.
You will be well rewarded.
You shall be a prince
here in my realm.
A rare privilege, master.
[ Sighs ]
Where shall I look, sire?
There is only one lure
for such disgusting goodness,
one bait that never fails.
What be this bait?
Please, you teach me.
Innocence. Innocence.
[ Woman Humming ]
Come, white flowers
Weave us a carpet
Spreading oak
Make a shade where we lie
Leaves and branches
whisper our love song
When I look
in my true love's eyes
Young as any spring
His eyes almost sing
To me
[ Humming Continues ]
[ Rooster Crows ]
[ Gurgling ]
[ Humming ]
Blooming fairies!
[ Snoring ]
[ Birds Fluttering ]
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Clock Clattering ]
[ Clock Chiming ]
[ Woman ]
Lily!
God bless, Your Highness.
A royal visit's
always a pleasure.
Have another biscuit.
Nell...
I have no time to stay
for a visit today.
Oh, you've got
a sweetheart waiting?
No, I don't.
Surely, your father
forbids such folly.
What my father doesn't know
won't trouble him.
Oh, the willful heart
invites despair,
like blind men creeping
in a dragon's lair.
Not a country proverb
nor king's command...
could keep me
from the woods today.
Then it's common sense sort.
Lily. Princess Lily.
I look on you as a daughter.
If you'll pardon my saying it,
it's time you started behaving
like the princess you are.
You should be out looking
for a handsome prince
on a white charger,
not visiting
poor folk like us.
No. Don't you know
I love coming here?
[ Sighs ]
This place holds
more magic for me...
than any palace
in the world.
You live a very rich
life, Nell.
I don't know of a prince
who could carve wood like this.
You're very sweet, Lily.
Magic is a wonderful thing.
You'll find your own magic
one day.
l'm sure you will.
I have no time for this.
I'm going.
Oh, and you look out
for spriggen and banshee,
my girl.
These woods
be thick with them.
Stay clear of toadstool
rings and willow trees...
and old oaks.
[ Lily ]
Jack!
Where are you?
- [ Gurgling ]
-Jack! Jack!
Jack?
Jack, answer me.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Goblin Croaks ]
Jack! Jack!
[ Voice Echoing ]
Jack.
Jack, please.
Please, if you're here,
say something to me, please.
[ Screams ]
Jack, you scared
the life out of me!
[ Laughing ]
[ Whistling, Chirping ]
You're so clever.
Oh, here.
Whoops. Look inside.
See what you can find.
That's something to eat.
[ Laughs ]
l made that for you myself.
Well, I-I took it from Nell.
[ Laughs ]
Do you like it? ls it sweet?
I know someone sweeter.
May be innocent,
may be sweet...
ain't half as nice
as rotting meat.
[ Snorting ]
[ Whistling ]
Good. Very good.
Just right.
Jack, now teach me rabbit
like you promised.
Rabbit?
It's much harder
than finch.
Let me try.
I'm a good student,
and my father says
I'm brilliant.
[ Jingling ]
See how brilliant I am?
Let me dazzle you
with my wisdom.
It's much more than wisdom
that dazzles me, Lily.
Jack, teach me rabbit.
Not today.
Why not?
Because...
there's something
really special that I've
been promising to show you.
-Jack, do you mean it?
- Only if it pleases you, Lily.
Oh, it pleases me
more than anything.
We must go now...
because they'll only be here
for a short while.
Don't you trust me?
I trust you, Lily.
Oh, Jack.
[ Laughs ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Look! Ugly
one-horned mules.
Nothing is more magical.
[ Whinnying ]
As long as they roam
the earth,
evil can never harm
the pure of heart.
Do you speak
their language?
They express
only love and laughter.
Dark thoughts
are unknown to them.
No! No.
Please.
Lily, no, please!
Come dance, sparrow
Sing me good morning
Rise up, sun
Like the arch of the sky
[ Whinnying ]
[ Rumbling ]
- [ Growling ]
- [ Horses Neighing ]
[ Neighing Continues ]
You'll spook the beast
and spoil the trap.
[ Unicorn Whinnies ]
Living river
Turn the light to diamonds
When l look
in my true love's eyes
Like a child feels
Watching a rainbow
Like a bird feels
The first time it flies
l feel magic
Stirring within me
When l look
in my true love's eyes
Young as any spring
His eyes almost seem
This shot be
just as sweet as pie.
[ Whinnies ]
[ Squeals, Neighing ]
Jack? Jack?
Jack!
It was lovely...
like a dream.
[ Jack ]
What you did is forbidden.
Who says so?
lt is known, Lily.
These are sacred animals.
- l don't care.
- You risk your immortal soul
talking like that.
I only wanted to touch one.
Where's the harm in that?
It was magic.
Thank you.
Let me sing to you.
I'll chase your fears away.
ln the bumps and the hollows
The sunlight and shadows
He kissed her as those
Bluebells blow
As his lips met her breath
He went sweetly to death
At the roots
of the bluebells
ls where he is laid
[ Laughs ]
Are you afraid
to kiss me, Jack?
I'm afraid
you'll break my heart.
Then still your heart.
You're dear to me
as life itself.
Don't you wish this
was our wedding ring?
If I say yes,
will my wish come true?
I'm a princess.
It's my right to set
a challenge for my suitors.
[ Laughs ]
I will marry...
whoever finds this ring.
Jack!
[ Screaming ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Neighing ]
[ Thud ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Squealing ]
Lily!
[ Panting ]
[ Fiendish Cackling ]
I smell human flesh!
[ Laughter Continues ]
[ Blix ]
After you, Pig.
Oh, no, after you.
[ Groaning ]
Clock. Mortal world
turned to ice.
Here be goblin paradise!
[ Laughing ]
Plenty hospitality here.
Baby!
l simply adore milk-fed meat.
What are you,
some kind of animal?
[ Gurgling, Groaning ]
Ohh.
- [ Squeals ]
- How did you do that, Blix?
Yeah, tell us how
you do those tricks.
Quite easy, actually.
- [ Gasps ]
- Goblin omelette.
- Very nice, very nice.
- [ Squeals ]
[ Laughing ]
Lucky day! Kill
ugly one-horned dead!
You act like you do all.
It was me who shoot
the poisoned stinger.
Me! Me! Me!
You only got the shot in
because the princess was there.
Wrong! 'Twas beauty
led the beast to bay.
She was so sweet.
l could eat her brains like jam.
- I could suck her bones--
- Enough!
Better hurry. Dark Lord,
he don't like to wait.
- [ Snorting ]
- Mmmm.
[ Yells, Laughing ]
- [ Laughing Continues ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Door Slams ]
[ Grunts, Sobbing ]
- Hyah! Hyah! Hyah!
- What have I done?
[ Sobbing Continues ]
Four, five, six!
Hurray for Blix!
[ Laughs ]
I'll make it right.
[ Wolf Howling ]
[ Faint Humming ]
[ Beam ]
Jack.
[ Laughing ]
Lily? Lily?
-Jack?
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Squeaking ]
- Who's there?
Who are you?
Here be forest child
and not know the Gump?
[ Fairies Giggling ]
Gump, is it?
Honeythorn Gump
at your service.
[ Fairies Muttering ]
[ Fairies Giggling ]
I, I must be dreaming.
If life is a dream,
better you dread the waking.
Jack?
Stop it!
That's Oona.
She likes you.
Go away!
Does your blood
run so cold, Jack?
You'll be a gobs
before your time.
How'd you know my name?
How does
a migrating swallow...
know the way south
in winter?
Or a spawning salmon...
find the very source
of his birth...
from the cold, black depth
of the mysterious sea?
I know everything, Jack.
Everything?
Then why is it like this?
Why is there winter now?
I'd be a powerful wizard,
indeed, could I answer.
Suppose you tell me, Jack.
Me?
You know these woods
as well as any elf.
Did you not see
something odd today?
Any strange spirits?
Did nothing untoward happen?
No.
No? No?
Nothing?
Uh, I did take Lily
to see the Unicorns.
- You did what?
- [ Murmuring ]
Silence!
Oh, God, Gump,
she touched him.
Touched it? A mortal
laid hands on a Unicorn?
Jack! Squawk, squawk,
no more talk!
Do you think you can upset
the order of the universe
and not pay the price?
[ Fairies Murmuring ]
But she meant no wrong!
[ Jack ]
What l did is done,
but l did it for love.
- [ Snickering ]
- Silence!
Love, you say?
But answer me this riddle,
and all will be forgiven.
And if l cannot?
Why, Jack,
then 'tis your death song
I'll be playing.
[ Giggling, Murmuring ]
Then ask away...
and pray God
my answer pleases you.
What is a bell
that does not ring...
yet its knell
makes the angels sing?
- [ Fairies Murmuring ]
- Shhh!
Answer me this...
and all will be forgiven.
[ Quiet Murmuring ]
- Flowers?
- [ Gasps ]
Bluebells! To hear them ring
means your life is at an end!
No!
[ Shouting Gibberish ]
[ Creatures Laughing ]
[ Gibberish Continues ]
Damn it! Damn it!
Damn it!
Riddles! Riddles!
Riddles!
Damn it! Riddles!
Riddles! Riddles!
Gump?
You've bested me, Jack.
Bested me, bested me.
A riddle without an answer's
like an empty cup when
you're thirsty for wine.
Well spoken!
And if it's wine you want,
it's wine we shall have.
Brown Tom! A small measure
of entertainment at best.
[ Brown Tom ]
But, Gump, it's the last bottle
of me best wine.
Oh-Oh, if you say so, sir.
Mmm.
Now, Gump, don't you
be forgetting me.
Oh, careful now.
Oh, it's so precious.
Elderberry wine.
[ Flatulence ]
Sorry.
No finer drink
under heaven.
Here's to Jack,
Oh, brother.
riddle solver, dancing fool
and fairy friend.
Tip it.
Hmm. Ahhh.
[ Sighs ]
Here, this'll help.
Don't you care
what's happened?
Of course we care.
What good's a world locked
in a season of death?
But we must find
the answer.
That we must.
But first we must see that
no harm's come to the Unicorn.
[ Brown Tom ]
l sadly fear the worst.
[ Wolf Howling ]
[ lndistinct Squealing ]
Wait. Shhh.
Lily!
Jack, what?
Jack!
[ Unicorn Neighing ]
[ Neighing ]
[ Neighing Continues ]
- [ Unicorn Squeals ]
- Forgive me.
I meant no wrong.
[ Whinnies ]
[ Neighs ]
[ Neighing Continues ]
Well, Jack, tell us
what has happened.
Come on, Jack.
Don't keep us in the dark.
The dark
is where we'll stay.
We're cursed.
Is there naught
we can do?
[ Unicorn Neighing ]
We must get
the alicorn back.
Only then will the world
return to normal.
We must find a champion...
bold of heart
and pure in spirit.
[ Brown Tom ]
Champion? What champion?
[ Gump ]
Don't give up so quick, lads.
You'll do.
We must get you
some weapons.
But, Gump, I know
nothing of weapons.
You'll learn. I know
where to find the best.
Brown Tom,
stay here with the Unicorn
and guard her well.
Like me own life.
Better.
She's the last of her kind.
[ Sighs ]
[ Whinnies ]
Magic horn
is mine, mine, mine.
Now all creatures
will love the night...
and worship goblins
as divine.
You shouldn't
talk like that, Blix.
Why not?
I've got the power now.
[ Squeals ]
Plenty big talk.
Hah!
[ Laughing ]
[ Indistinct Shouting ]
[ Laughter, Chattering ]
Not even darkness
lasts forever.
Jack, I can't go
with you now.
Anyway, Oona
will guide the way.
Follow me, Jack.
Over here. Come on.
Come on, Jack.
[ lndistinct Whisper ]
Here, Jack.
Come on.
[ Jingling ]
Oona.
Nobody knows but you.
It's our secret, Jack.
Don't tell Gump. Promise?
Promise!
l could be anything
you want me to be,
even your heart's desire.
You've got to help us,Jack.
The fairies'love
makes anything possible.
Higher, higher,
burning fire.
Making music like a choir.
[ Fiendish Laughing ]
It seems a pity
to waste such power.
Waste? Better watch out,
old pal Pox,
or I'll turn you
into little pork chops.
Why not turn everything
into garbage?
A great towering
mountain of slop.
- Wouldn't that be magic?
- [ Laughing ]
Higher, higher,
burning fire.
Making music like a choir.
[ Fiendish Laughing Continues ]
Blix, Blix. Blix!
- What?
- Big D.!
[ Groaning ]
Stop!
[ Coughs ]
Hear me,
you angel of darkness!
Your reign is over!
A new order begins!
- I hold the power!
- Enough!
Shit! Please!
It was only a joke.
[ Groaning ]
I didn't mean it.
No! No!
Have you no sense of humor?
Adios, amigos!
[ Screaming, Crashing ]
Wow.
Forgive that intrusion,
great lord,
but goblins are inclined
to be outspoken.
Yeah.
and I like to encourage
their initiative.
Did you think
this a mere plaything?
With it,
my empire is eternal.
Before l ruled
only the night.
Now my minions
will frolic in darkness
until the end of time.
[ Chuckling ]
The Unicorns are dead,
is this not true?
True, lord,
very plenty true.
Undeniably true.
You lie!
Here is dawn!
lt is essentially true.
On the other hand--
Stallion is dead.
Dead as dreams.
- Out with it!
- The mare lives still!
lf even one Unicorn
walks the earth,
my power is not complete.
She's just a female, lord.
She has no power.
Only the power of creation.
Get the mare!
I command you!
Well, let's see,
what have we here?
Ahh, a little sassafras.
[ Unicorn Whinnies ]
A little spearmint
would be nice, huh?
Some fox glove?
And a little colt's foot.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Crying ]
[ Unicorn Neighing ]
Hey, who goes there, what?
[ Neighing Continues ]
I'm-- I'm Princess Lily.
You! You're the cause
of all our sorrow.
[ Crying Continues ]
I'm-- I'm so sorry.
I didn't know.
Please, please forgive me.
- I'm not the one
you should be askin'.
- Listen to me.
Try and understand.
I'm only trying
to make things right.
Darkness has sent the goblins
back for the mare.
It's not safe to stay here.
You'll have to hurry!
Leave now! Go!
Good lass. You're
a plucky little partridge.
- Hurry! Aaah!
- Too late!
You imps are lookin'
for a fight, you come to
the chap who'll oblige ya.
[ Growls ]
Ooh! Ah! Ah!
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Unicorn Neighing ]
- Try this on for size.
- [ Lily Screams ]
You can't beat me.
Ha-ha, look at that!
Keep 'em coming, fellas!
Ha-ha!
Oh, check this out!
Yes, sir. You see?
You just can't beat me!
You can't--
Little tool is stuck.
They done for me.
[ Growling ]
[ Neighing Continues ]
Quick!
Wait for me!
[ Panting ]
Brown Tom!
Brown Tom,
you can't be dead.
This is terrible.
Terrible!
Brown Tom.
Gump?
Screwball.
Jack, lad.
- They killed you too?
- Of course they didn't.
- But what in blazes
are you talking about?
- Goblins.
- Goblins?
- Shot me through me brain pan.
Oh.
[ Groans, Chuckles ]
That's one spot an arrow
will do no harm.
l did my best to fight 'em off,
but they swarmed up
by the hundreds.
All fierce creatures they were.
The princess warned me, but--
Lily?
Aye.
Then she's alive!
She was alive still
when they killed me.
The goblins
must have taken her.
[ Gump ]
We follow their tracks
in the snow.
The Great Tree.
When evil anarchy
ruled the land,
the wicked came here
to sacrifice.
[ Birds Squawking ]
Ugly. I hate it.
Good. You go first.
Why always me?
Go!
[ Groaning ]
[ Muttering ]
Foreigner.
[ Muttering Continues ]
Ooh, slippery.
Uh, uh--
Oh, okay, okay.
[ Muttering Continues ]
[ Squeals ]
l made it!
[ Gump ]
Screwball!
- [ Gasping ]
- [ Shrieking ]
Foul-tasting fairy!
Come to Meg, juicy boy.
[ Shrieks ]
Who be this tender morsel...
disturbing
Meg Mucklebone's rest?
Jack.
They call me Jack, ma'am.
[ Squeals ]
And what a fine,
fat boy you are, Jack.
You don't really mean
to eat me, do you, ma'am?
Oh, indeed I do!
[ Cackling ]
[ Cackling Continues ]
But that would be a shame,
because someone as fair...
and lovely as yourself,
Miss Meg, deserves far better
than scrawny me.
Don't you think?
You think me fair,
do you, Jack?
All the heavenly angels
must envy your beauty.
[ Giggling ]
What a fine meal
you'll make,
be the rest of you
as sweet as your tongue.
- [ Cackling ]
- Wait! No!
Your Loveliness,
feast on the beauty
of your reflection.
You are an angel, Miss Meg.
Look. Look.
Ohhh.
What a splendid idea.
[ Yells ]
Clever boy!
[ Evil Laughter ]
Yes.
Your alchemy makes
crusted steel shine like silver.
[ Whining ]
That's discerning taste...
for one so young, Jack.
[ Whining Continues ]
Come. Come,Jack!
Give us a kiss...
before dining!
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Screaming ]
I did it!
[ Panting ]
[ Birds Croaking ]
[ Chattering, Indistinct ]
- [ Screaming ]
- Screwball!
[ Mumbling ]
[ Mumbling Continues ]
Oh, okay. Okay.
Oh! Whee! Look.
What a big trumpet!
I'll bet it makes a lot of noise.
[ Whispering ]
Our lives are lost if it blows.
Hmm.
Mm-hmm.
[ Arrow Clattering
To Unknown Depth ]
Mm-hmm.
[ Grunting ]
Oh!
I think it stopped.
[ All Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
Look out!
[ Grunting, Shouting ]
[ Brown Tom ]
My back! Me achin'back!
Oh, I'm not as old
as I used to be, you know.
[ Clattering ]
[ Rumbling ]
Ooh. Hey, where are we?
Someplace
we don't want to be.
[ Mutters, Indistinct ]
Hey, hey!
Wait for me!
We gotta get out of here!
It's the stench of hell itself!
Shh! Quiet!
You'll be fricasseed fairies
if you don't keep quiet.
Who be you, bucket head?
Who I am won't help me
nor you, neither,
even though
we are all brothers.
[ Screwball Shouts ]
[ Giggles ]
What happened to you?
It's a long story.
Let's just say
I went looking for adventure...
and found
more than l could handle.
Doesn't matter now anyway.
We are all in the same fix!
I knew it. I knew it.
I should have stayed at home.
Let's face it, brothers.
Me and you all...
is barbecue.
[ Mutters ]
Barbecue?
That's right. Barbecue.
Only dead meat waits
for the stew pot.
Spring the lock
with your magic, Gump.
Ooh!
Ah!
Iron is trouble for elves.
Iron, huh?
Oh!
[ Growling ]
Oh, no!
The thing!
[ Groaning, Laughing ]
Oh, no!
He's coming! Hide!
Hide!
Hide! Hide!
[ Sniffing ]
- Oh!
- [ Growling ]
[ Evil Laughter ]
I don't think I can handle it!
Help me!
[ Shouting ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Screaming ]
Let me go! Let me go!
Help! Help me!
Please! Please!
Help me!
Oh, you beast!
[ Screaming ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Screaming, Shouting Continue ]
Let me go!
Ah... ah... ah...
ah... ah... achoo!
Gump, we've got to help him.
Oh, don't worry.
Our brother can take care
of himself.
I'm sure of it,
I think.
Screwball's right.
It's more important
that you find the Unicorn.
Why not have Oona fly out,
find a key?
Oona?
But she's much too small.
Could never lift it.
Our secret!
Our secret will keep forever
in this grave if you don't help us.
- You promised!
- [ Hisses ]
You willful sprite.
How dare you keep such secrets?
They're mine to keep.
I'll do what you ask...
if you'll kiss me, Jack.
Easy enough.
[ Chuckles ]
You call that a kiss?
Am I not sweet?
Sweeter than bee pollen...
on a summer wind.
Sweet as the wind
that blows me to you.
[ Gasping ]
Oh, it's fairy magic.
Lily?
- Lily?
- Yes, Jack.
This isn't real.
Oh, it is.
I'm warm and alive...
and want to be in your arms.
No, I, I can't. No.
This is just
more fairy glamour.
Human hearts
don't work that way.
What care I
for human hearts?
Soft and spiritless
as porridge!
A fairy's heart beats
fierce and free!
[ Whimpering ]
[ Jack ]
Oona!
Your fine sensibilities
have left us here to rot!
[ Brown Tom ]
l'm behind you all the way, Gump.
You look like mourners
at your own funeral.
Oona!
[ Snaps Fingers ]
[ Gate Creaks ]
Quick, lads!
You!
You mortal, you!
I could vex you!
Dance your life away!
Uh, I'll stay here and--
- Ahh! Wait for me!
- [ Creature Howls ]
[ Mumbling, Shouting ]
[ Screwball ]
A terrible sight
for a sober man.
Shh!
We must find the dungeons.
[ Nervous Laugh ]
I think I'll stay right here,
thank you very much.
You'll search
with the rest of us.
Then I'll go with Jack.
No! We split up.
Yes! It's better
if we go in teams.
- No, I will go with Ja--
- Shh!
Gump and me,
Brown Tom and Screwball.
Right. Let's synchronize.
Oh!
[ Chuckles ]
[ Grunting ]
Oh! A-ha!
We meet back here in twice
500 beats of a bluebird's heart.
Do you know what I think?
I think we should add a couple
more hundred breaths of a--
Shh!
Take care.
Come on, Jack.
Be careful.
There's only one thing
I want to know.
What?
[ Crying ]
Why me?
Shh!
I think we should go west.
I think we should go east.
Oh, okay.
Wait!
[ Lord of Darkness ]
Father, l hold the world
in my grasp,
and yet this girl...
distracts me.
lt has been an eternity
since l felt such desire.
What am l to do?
She fascinates you
because her soul is pure.
l'll take her then.
Fool!
You must woo her!
She remembers the world
as it was,
so... tempt her.
Win her.
Make her one of us.
Hmm. Hey. Psst!
Psst! Psst!
Did, did you see something?
No, did you?
I don't know.
I think.
[ Evil Laughter ]
[ Heavy Breathing ]
[ Muttering ]
D-D-D-Did you hear that?
[ Neighing ]
What's that?
That's a horse,
you idiot.
[ Faint Voice ]
Woo her.
[ Faint Breathing ]
Win her.
[ Tinkling ]
Woo her, win her.
[ Gasps ]
Make her one of us.
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
[ Gasps ]
Lady, do not be afraid.
Quiet, quiet.
How like you my gifts?
Does the gown
not please you?
[ Crying ]
No.
[ Laughs ]
Can you speak so
of your bridal gown?
I've found my true mate,
and you know it.
- Never.
- Beneath the skin,
we are already one.
Was it not your sin
trapped the Unicorn?
- No.
- Even now...
the evil seed
of what you have done...
germinates within you.
No. You lie.
You disgust me.
You're nothing
but an animal.
[ Evil Laughter ]
We are all animals,
my lady.
Most are too afraid
to see it.
[ Laughter Continues ]
- Lily!
-Jack.
There's nothing
you can do now to help her.
Be thankful she still lives.
[ Oona ]
You've got to help us,
Jack.
The last Unicorn dies
tonight.
- As her blood ebbs,
- [ Whispers ] Never.
the sun sets forever.
There shall never be
another dawn.
[ Lily ]
No!
[ Evil Laughter ]
Lady, l require the solace
of the shadows...
and the dark of the night.
Sunshine is my destroyer!
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Damn you!
[ Grunts ]
We are all of us damned,
my queen.
[ Laughing ]
As long as the sun still shines,
we can destroy him.
Let me dazzle you
with my wisdom.
I think I know a way.
Come on, come on, come on.
You're holding us up.
Listen. We're not going down
the same corridor umpteen times.
I think we should go that way.
No, we're going this way.
No, not me.
Let's go down there.
Stay close to me now.
[ Creature Wailing ]
[ Shouting, Indistinct ]
You know what?
What?
I vote we run like hell.
I second the motion.
[ Screams ]
[ Whispering ]
Screwball.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Gump ]
Where were you?
In another three flicks
of a badger's tail,
we would have gone.
While you're having fun,
time goes by fast.
Yeah, we found the mare,
and it's alive in the dungeon.
Excellent.
Excellent, you two!
Thank you very much.
Now Jack has a plan,
and a good one!
We must gather every
shining object we can find.
We're going to bring light
to darkness.
[ Snoring ]
[ Snoring Continues ]
[ Buzz ]
[ Muffled Cries ]
[ Banging On Pot ]
Blunder.
[ Snores ]
Blunder!
[ Muffled Cries Continue ]
Shh!
Any more noise,
and you're shish kebab.
You do what we say, understand?
Swear it.
[ Mutters ]
I swear it on the festering
forelock of Nicodemus!
Please, help. Help me.
Thank you.
[ Lord of Darkness ]
Judge me not so harshly,
mistress.
l invite you
to share this supper.
Look how sweet it is.
Hurry, hurry.
Keep 'em comin'!
Come on, come on!
- Ow!
- [ Loud Clattering ]
[ Grunting, Yelling ]
- Brown Tom!
- Huh?
[ Grunting ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Grunting, Shouting Continue ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Rat Squealing ]
Gump? Gump!
Gump?
Jack.Jack!
Three cheers
for our champion!
Hip hip!
Hooray!
- Hip hip!
-Hooray!
Hip hip!
Hooray!
[ Laughs ]
Now what, Jack?
[ Jack ]
Must go all the way out.
Light.
Not much to hold on to.
Take a pea pod pixie
to make that climb.
I'll do it.
What's the matter?
Ain't I small enough
for the job?
No job is too small
for my little brother.
Please, Gump. Let me try.
I won't let you down.
All right, all right.
Do it, but be swift!
Oh, thank you, thank you.
You'll never regret it.
I always knew you'd
be going places, Screwball.
Yes.
Uh--
[ Stammers ]
- Eat.
- I'm not hungry.
You lie.
[ Laughing ]
Just to please me.
I do nothing
for your pleasure.
All I wish...
is for you to sit
and talk with me.
Sit?
- Here?
- Yes.
Please.
- I prefer to stand.
- Sit!
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
Or stand.
As you wish.
lt is enough that
we are alone together.
Just the two of us.
Some... simple conversation.
I have nothing
to talk about.
You've stolen my dreams away.
All things change, Lady.
The dreams of youth...
are the regrets of maturity.
Dreams are my specialty.
Through dreams
l influence mankind.
My dream...
is of eternity with you.
I offer you this rose,
Princess--
my heart,
my soul,
my love.
Love?
[ Grunting ]
[ Lord of Darkness ]
Once l was content
with solitude...
[ Gasps ]
until that moment...
l felt your vivid presence.
[ Gump ]
A little to the right.
Left. Good!
It grows late. Sit.
I value your thoughts.
Share them with me.
Sit?
Yes.
- Nothing more than that?
- And talk with me.
I think I'll stand,
if you don't mind.
[ Yelling ]
Damn you!
No! Never! Never!
[ Growling ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Growling Continues ]
[ Neighing ]
l hear a throat
begging to be cut.
- [ Growls ]
- [ Neighing Continues ]
Are you so... anxious...
to see blood flow?
As you are to drink it.
Grant your bride one wish
on this night.
You have but to ask.
I will stay here with you
as you wish.
- But on one condition.
- Anything.
l want to kill the Unicorn.
[ Laughing ]
[ Roars, Laughs ]
I can't let that happen.
In the beginning...
there was nothing--
a void of darkness,
a cold eternity
of silence.
Jack, your greatest challenge
is still to come.
And we have not much time.
[ Humming ]
When the perfect void
was corrupted...
by light,
a great wailing was heard,
and all the brethren fled
in terror.
Gump!
Oona, fly up like the wind.
It's time.
Jack!
[ Unicorn Neighing ]
[ Neighing Continues ]
[ Hisses ]
Lily.
[ Gump ]
Jack.
Judge her with your heart,
not your eyes.
Hear me,
ye powers of the night!
We offer this sacrifice,
in honor of you,
sanctified with blood...
[ Neighing Continues ]
and with fire!
l pray you, Father,
accept my sacrifice.
Let light
be forever extinguished.
Let the age of darkness begin!
Come, Lady.
The birth of a new world
awaits your stroke.
Let my offering be made
of flesh and blood.
She means to do it, Jack.
She's one of them.
I am sister to the Fates.
Kill her. Forget her.
Think about the Unicorn.
- Do it!
- Lily.
- I'll do it.
- No! No.
- I trust you, Lily.
- [ Neighing Continues ]
I'll always trust you.
Run!
Run! You're free!
Darkness!
[ Grunts ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Growling ]
[ Arrow Whistles ]
[ Jack Grunting ]
What have we here?
A little boy.
[ Grunting Continues ]
Screwball!
Screwball, wake up!
[ Grunting Continues ]
Wake up, Screwball!
Wake up!
[ Snoring ]
It's always a pleasure
to take a brave man's life.
[ Yelling ]
Wake up!
[ Laughing ]
[ Jack Screaming ]
Don't you know me, boy?
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Grunts ]
Quickly!
What time is it?
Every wolf suffers fleas.
'Tis easy enough to scratch.
Give it to me, boy!
[ Groaning ]
[ Screaming ]
Father!
Protect me!
You think you have won!
What is light...
without dark?
What are you...
without me?
[ Laughing ]
I am a part of you all.
You can never defeat me.
We are brothers...
eternal!
Do it, Jack! Kill him!
Kill him!
[ Yelling ]
[ Gump ]
She's under a spell.
A powerful spell.
Do something.
Look what we've been through.
Look who you are.
Have faith in yourself.
lt is the greatest lesson
you have learned.
Only you
can answer this riddle.
[ Lily's Voice ]
l'm a princess.
It's my right to set
a challenge for my suitors.
[ Chuckles ]
I will marry...
whoever finds this ring.
We too have
a promise to keep.
[ Snorting ]
Now fulfill your promise.
I will miss you.
But don't forget us.
Never.
I love you, Lily.
Come back to me.
I... love you, Jack.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
I love you, Lily.
I had such a terrible
nightmare.
Did you?
It's over.
[ Laughing ]
Jack, was it all a dream?
You're safe now.
So many terrible things
happened.
I--
I learned something
about myself...
and something about you.
What's that?
You belong here.
You're my prince.
I'm only Jack.
My Lord Jack.
So you take that...
and you keep it,
treasure it.
It's part of me.
Can I come tomorrow?
[ Chuckles ]
Of course.
I'll be here.
I'll always be here
for you, Lily.
Will you sing for me?
Come down, sparrow
Sing me good morning
Rise up, sun
like the arch of the sky
Living river
Turn light to diamonds
When I look
in my true love's eyes
[ Horn Blowing ]
[ Neighs ]
[ Neighing Continues ]
[ Choir Singing ]