[ Seagulls Calling ]
[ Gears Clinking ]
Jesus!
Anybody out there?
I need a little help.
You're alive!
[ Panting ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Choking ]
Okay.
[ Coughing ]
Okay. All right!
You're all right!
[ Gasping ]
Okay, now.
You're going to live.
Can you stand?
Come on. Come on.
Hold on.
[ Speaks Indistinctly ]
[ Gasping ]
It's okay.
What do you mean I'm --
I'm alive?
You're on a boat.
My boat.
Why am I on your boat?
Maybe you can tell me.
[ Vomits ]
All right? Out?
I was dead.
I was sure of that.
No. But you're not.
You're alive now.
Why? Why am I alive?
I don't know.
You were in my net.
Net?
Yeah.
You were --
you were drowning.
You swallowed water.
You sank.
Don't ask me how.
Come on.
Are you cold?
- Yes.
Come on.
Come on. Hold on to me.
Get up.
[ Coughing ]
Okay.
Watch your step.
[ Gasping ]
Keep warm.
You need a hospital.
No!
Why not?
Because I'm -- I'm fine.
You'll need to see a doctor
after a thing like that.
No! I don't!
I don't want to see anyone.
Well, will I just disappear, then?
I don't mind seeing you.
You... Don't mind seeing me?
That's nice.
Say again?
- Most people do.
Well, I don't.
- Why not?
Because you fished me from the water.
[ Horn Blows ]
How are you?
Jesus,
you really don't want people seeing you.
What's your name?
I don't know.
You lost your memory in the water?
Maybe.
- I've heard it happens.
Does it?
People knock their head,
forget the lot,
Then it all comes back,
suddenly, like.
What's your name?
My name's Syracuse,
but people call me Circus.
Why?
To let on, you know,
that I'm a clown.
- A clown?
In a circus?
- Something like that.
I think I'll call you
Syra--
Syracuse.
Okay, then.
And I'm taking you to a hospital.
I have a car on the shore.
Are you one of those asylum seekers?
- What?
You swam here
all the way from Arabia?
It's a hell of a swim.
Let me go, then.
Do you really want to drown?
I can't die twice.
- Well, you can die once for real.
[ Coughs ]
Please.
I don't need a hospital.
I know a place...
where people won't see you.
Come on.
[ Coughs ]
Whose is this place?
- It was me mum's.
She lived here?
- On and off.
She was a kind of a loner.
Loner?
- Bit like you.
She didn't like people much.
Why?
- Ah.
She was a kind of...
Gypsy.
Where is she now?
She's with her maker.
You mean she's dead?
Yes.
- Like me.
You're not dead.
No. But maybe I should have been.
Here's some sandwiches.
Have my lunch.
With all the strange fishing today,
I forgot to eat it.
Thank you.
Right, can I leave you now?
- If you have to.
I do. Yeah.
Got to be somewhere.
Okay.
Okay?
[ Doorbell Rings ]
She's been waiting.
I know, I'm sorry.
Something came up.
The appointment's for 6:00.
She gets upset.
I know. I'll make it up to her.
How's my baby?
Bye, mom.
You just have to fuck it up,
don't you?
- Yeah.
It's genetic.
Right, up you get.
Anything strange or wonderful?
- Why do you always say that?
I don't know, Annie.
It's a kind of a wish.
A wish?
Yeah, that something strange
or wonderful might happen.
No, da, nothing strange or wonderful.
Ah, that's good, then.
[ Grunts ]
Woman: Hello.
- How are you?
Is doctor Hannon around?
- No, just missed him.
Oh, I thought he was gonna be here.
- Something came up...
In Cork.
How long this time?
- Same as usual.
An hour and a half or so.
Does she have a book?
No book.
Maybe I'll tell her a story.
I'll be inside if you want me.
- All right.
Well...
Go on.
Go on what?
You said you'd tell me a story.
- Okay.
Once upon a time...
Does it always have to be
"once upon a time"?
Well, it's...
how stories begin.
And a very good time it was.
- Yes.
It was a good time.
And it was a bad time.
How are you feeling, love?
Never mind about me.
Go on.
Once upon a time...
there was a fisherman.
And he was pulling in his nets.
And it was a normal day.
[ ♫ Girl Humming ♫ ]
Annie: And?
- And what?
What was she?
- What was she?
Was she a mermaid?
No. She wasn't a mermaid.
- Was she a selkie, then?
What's a selkie?
A kind of seal woman.
You hear them singing
out on seal rock.
- Who told you that?
Teacher.
She comes out of the sea,
loses her seal coat,
lives on land
until the sea calls her back.
Well, she didn't have a seal coat,
Whatever that is.
She seemed to remember drowning.
And?
And...
That's it.
That's a real shite story.
- Yeah. Maybe.
Remember that thing we ordered
from the CRC?
- What thing?
Wait till I show you.
Now...
[ Laughs ]
You should rest as much as possible
until we sort you out,
all right?
Okay.
[ Both Laugh ]
[ Laughing ]
You've got juice now, Annie.
- Juice!
Yeah.
Annie:
Look at this, Alex.
- Wow.
Doesn't do bumps.
Did your daddy buy you that?
- No. The CRC.
Well, that figures.
How's the fishing, Circus?
It's Syracuse.
Syracuse, how's the fishing?
Same. See you.
- When?
Tomorrow.
So, did you see the doctor?
- He wasn't there.
That's because you were late,
you fool.
Clown.
- Yeah, yeah, you clown.
He's been doing tests, Circus.
She needs a kidney.
Something about...
What's the word?
- Compatibility.
Oh, you understand what that means?
It has to be the right fit.
Blood group, you flipping clown.
You were to ask him had he news.
Good-bye!
[ Sighs ]
[ Car Door Closes ]
[ ♫ Singing Indistinctly ♫ ]
Still here?
You thought I'd be be gone?
No.
Thought I'd dreamed it.
You dreamt you
fished me from the water?
- Something like that.
So, you still dreaming now?
- But that's my mother's coat.
Sorry.
Had to wash my dress.
Doesn't suit the dream.
- No?
No.
She was large, my mother.
And kind of awkward.
- Awkward?
She -- yes,
she was not like you.
- I can be awkward.
So can most of us.
You're going fishing?
Yes.
Thought I might catch another.
Another girl like me?
- Yes.
Maybe the sea is full of them.
Can I come with?
- No.
Why?
Thought you didn't want to be seen.
- I can hide again.
And it's bad luck.
A girl on a boat?
- For the fishing.
Have you been having good luck lately?
[ Chuckles ]
No.
Okay, then. Get in.
What was that song you were singing?
Just a song.
But you remembered it?
I must have.
Do you remember your name?
You can call me Ondine.
- That's nice.
What's it mean?
- She came from the water.
Ondine means
"she came from the water."
- No.
Ondine was the girl
that came from the water.
- When?
Long time ago.
Do you want to help?
Load that pot over there.
Over there.
- They're empty.
So they are.
- Did someone rob them?
I hope not.
[ ♫ Singing Indistinctly ♫ ]
My God.
- What?
You're playing games with me.
- No, I'm not.
What did you just do?
I -I sang.
Yeah...
I know.
Come down here.
[ Grunts ]
Sing again, would you?
[ ♫ Singing Indistinctly ♫ ]
[ Grunts ]
Jesus.
You bring me luck.
- Luck?
Haven't had much.
- Everyone needs luck.
They do.
Not everyone gets it.
- Maybe it's your turn.
That would be nice.
Right, come over here.
Help me tie their claws.
Right, put one in between your
legs so he doesn't bite you.
And just do the other one like this.
What do you do with them?
- What do you think?
Eat them.
No. Sell them.
You always catch this much?
No. Almost never.
Right.
There you go.
Claws there.
Grab that.
It wasn't your song, you know.
Couldn't have been.
- No.
They were already in the pots.
[ ♫ Music: Lisa Hannigan "Lille" ♫ ]
♫ I went to war ♫
♫ every morning ♫
♫ I lost my way ♫
♫ but now I'm following ♫
♫ what you said in my arms ♫
♫ what I read in the charms ♫
♫ that I love durably ♫
Why you put them back?
Save them for a rainy day.
We sell the rest.
We'll get something for these.
- We?
Your share of the catch.
You did sing.
Just don't go around town
singing for everyone.
Come on into the co-op.
We'll get 10 euro a pound.
I don't want to meet anyone.
You've met me.
You're the only one.
Okay.
How are you, Mary?
- All right, Circus.
- Oh, you done well today, then.
Yes, for a change.
And they say there's no lobster left.
They do.
Thank you very much.
- Lovely.
Can I help you, Circus?
Tracy, would this go near you?
You want me to try it?
Okay.
[ Curtain Closes ]
It's a bit tight around here.
At least you're not invisible.
- What?
Nothing.
I'll take it.
For who?
Just for Annie.
- This would never fit Annie.
It will some day.
What do you think, Circus?
I think that's not my name.
Sorry... Da.
Do they give you a hard time?
No, they're jealous.
How many of them have
their own set of wheels?
Motorized wheels!
What are we doing?
I was going to drive you home.
I'll race you.
Annie.
- Yeah?
Go on so.
So, what's the story?
Oh, she sings.
Who sings?
The woman in the story
I told you about.
With the fisherman?
Yes.
She sings to the fishes,
and he catches them.
You sure you're not dreaming, da?
Dreaming?
Yeah.
You sure this isn't
some weird wish-fulfillment
kind of thing?
Where did you learn words like that?
I go to school.
- And I didn't?
No. Let's be honest, you didn't.
You move your mouth when you read.
Is that bad?
No, but it means something.
So she sings, does she?
Yeah. A song in a language
he has never heard.
That would be selk.
- Selk?
A kind of seal talk.
And do you know why she sings?
Why?
That's the way
they communicate underwater.
They don't speak, they sing.
Ah. So the lobster hear her singing.
What lobster?
What I mean is, under the water
they hear her singing.
The denizens of the deep.
- Are you sure?
She's a seal.
She's not human.
- She looks human.
In the story?
Yes, in the story.
Whose story is this?
It's mine.
- You're making it up?
Yeah. For you.
What are you planning for the weekend?
Practicing my new wheels.
Curious.
♫ I went to sleep ♫
♫ for the daytime ♫
♫ shut my eyes ♫
♫ to the sunshine ♫
♫ turned my head away
from the noise ♫
♫ bruise and drip decay
of childish toys ♫
♫ that I loved ♫
♫ arguably ♫
♫ all our labouring
gone to seed ♫
Got you some things.
Things?
- Messages.
Messages?
Food and stuff.
Even girls from the water
need to eat, right?
Need clothes.
Need to...
tie their shoelaces.
Curiouser and curiouser.
You know my size?
Tracy in the shop --
she looked like... your size.
Thank you.
Can I--?
- What?
Can I clean up this place?
I suppose.
How long are you staying?
Depends, I guess.
- On what?
On you.
On me?
It depends on me,
you can stay forever.
Forever?
- Forever.
Happily ever after.
Once upon a time.
I've been telling my daughter a story.
A fairy tale.
What's the story, da?
Librarian: That's great.
See you, Deirdre.
Hi, Annie.
Gosh, you've a load of books there.
I'm researching.
Researching what?
Something on seals, is it?
My name's Syracuse,
and I'm an alcoholic.
I've told you before, Circus,
that confessional is not a chapter of AA.
- There's none in this town, father.
I've been sober 2 years,
7 months, and 18 days.
This is where they all clap, father.
Where did you see that,
in the movies?
- Yes.
Thank you.
So, tell me.
I had a dream, father.
I'm at his funeral,
and she's beside me,
And I'm panicking again.
Maybe you still want to be with her.
No. No, I'm panicking
because I'm back with her.
Can't happen.
She's still drinking.
All I want is Annie.
Perhaps you need
to talk to someone, Circus.
It's Syracuse.
And I'm talking to you.
No, I mean a counselor.
I could put you both
in touch with one
if you'd give me permission.
You have no permission.
I only talk to you
because it's secret.
Whenever you feel able to, tell me,
and I'll set it in motion.
Until then, try to control your feelings.
Anything else?
I suppose there is.
Yeah, I stole.
Oh, dear.
What did you steal, Syracuse?
Some... Ladies' clothes.
Oh, dear, dear, dear, dear.
I don't like this at all, Syracuse.
This is a bad development.
Oh, it's not what you're thinking,
father.
There was a reason.
- What was the reason?
I stole them
because I was embarrassed
to be seen buying them.
What did you want them for?
They were for this girl I met, father.
A girl?
Where did you meet this girl?
I pulled her out of the water
in my net.
In your net?
- In my fishing net.
You're joking, surely, Syracuse?
No, I'm not joking.
Dreaming, maybe.
But sure I went back to my boat
this morning, and...
there she was.
And did she
[ Clears Throat ]
spend the night in the boat?
[ Chuckles ]
No.
- No?
So, where did this girl sleep?
I'm not telling you.
- No. I can't force you to, can I?
No.
And you can't tell anyone, either.
No, my lips are sealed.
But you'll keep me
informed of developments, Syracuse?
Definitely, father.
So, will I see you at mass on Sunday?
You know you won't, father.
I suppose I do.
You only avail of the confessional--
Because there's no AA chapter
in this poxy town.
I suppose you wouldn't say
a couple of 'hail Marys'
on the way out, would you?
[ ♫ Distant Rock Music Plays ♫ ]
What are you reading, Annie?
For school. Selkies.
Selkies?
They're a Scottish thing.
This one isn't.
[ ♫ Humming ♫ ]
[ ♫ Continues Humming ♫ ]
Curiouser and curiouser.
What's that?
What Alice said to the white rabbit.
Come again?
- Curiouser... And...
Curiouser.
- See?
I knew you were real.
I was real?
Yes.
I knew it wasn't a story.
What wasn't a story?
The fisherman.
The girl in the net.
Ah.
My da told me a story about you.
Your dad is Syracuse?
- Yeah, the fisherman.
So, do you have magic powers?
- Do you?
You know I don't.
Okay, you don't.
Can you make me better?
Better?
- I'm sick.
I've got kidney failure.
Didn't he tell you?
What's your name?
- It's Annie.
Annie.
I'm Ondine.
Ondine.
I'm examining you for webs.
Well, do I disappoint you?
Ondine is French, isn't it?
What's a French selkie doing here?
Who said I was French?
You got lost, did you?
Yes...
I suppose I did get lost.
You cold?
- Suddenly.
Because you're on land now.
Your natural habitat
is in the water, you see.
- You seem to know a lot about me.
Yes. I've been reading...
...Researching.
Want to come inside?
- If I walk across the threshold,
you might put a hex on me.
What's a hex?
- It's bad news, a hex.
- Maybe underwater feels better.
Better than what?
Some days I'm sick all the time.
Does it feel better underwater?
I'm not sure I know what you mean.
- Oh, come on.
Let's not try and fool each other.
We both know the truth.
And if we're not straightforward,
there's no point in being friends.
Ah.
So we're to be friends, then?
We could be...
If we play our cards right.
So I need you to be specific.
Does it feel better in that
home of yours under the waves?
Well, it definitely feels different.
- And I know you don't talk down there.
You sing.
Yes. Singing travels better underwater.
And what about the cold?
Get used to it.
Oh, of course,
you have your seal coat, don't you?
My seal coat?
Look, there's no point
in beating around the bush.
I do know these things.
I've been studying them.
So, tell me about my seal coat.
- You lose it when you get out of water.
And you can't go back in
until you find it again.
And if you do find it
and bury it on land,
you can stay for seven years,
and you cry seven tears.
But then,
when the crying's done,
your kind of folk can often find
unexpected happiness with a...
What's it called?
Are you lost for words?
A landsman, that's what.
Selkie women often find...
- A landsman.
...unexpected happiness with a landsman.
And that's all I know.
This is my granny's place.
He misses her.
And where do you live?
- With me ma,
and it's not underneath the waves.
She'll be wondering where I am.
See you again.
Your cheek is wet.
Is that one of the seven tears?
Maybe.
You've only six left.
Can I help you there, Circus?
Yeah.
Have you any books on selkies?
Selkies.
We do, actually.
But strangely enough,
they're all out at the moment.
Out?
- If you want to read them,
your daughter has them.
Annie?
- Mmm, Annie. Doing a project, she said.
Yeah. Just trying to help her
get ahead of the game.
- Good man.
Does it do stunts, Annie?
What do you mean,
"stunts"?
Stunts like this.
I don't think
it's a recreational vehicle.
So it's only for spaz?
You don't say "spaz".
You say "special needs".
Don't you, Annie?
Yeah.
- See, you feckin' retard?
Say it.
- Special needs.
Special needs, Annie.
Give us a go?
Does it float?
I don't think it's amphibious.
[ Sighs ]
Special needs, my ass.
Come on, guys.
Is mum up yet?
No.
Was there something up?
Why do you think?
Is it battery trouble?
It got wet.
Come here.
I don't bite.
Come on.
Jesus, you're getting big.
[ Grunts ]
You said you had selkies in Scotland.
Aye.
We invented selkies in the Outer Hebrides.
[ Hair Dryer Blowing ]
You mean you made them up?
No.
No, they're a Scottish thing.
[ Hair Dryer Turns Off ]
[ Wheelchair Beeps ]
There you go.
She doesn't speak like you.
Who?
Oh, we've got secrets,
have we, little girl?
Well, you could say thanks.
Thanks.
[ Chuckles ]
You're welcome.
Do you want to come again?
- Fishing?
Only if you want, like.
You promise I'll see nobody but you?
I promise you'll see nobody but me.
You're swimming in my dress?
It was a gift...
From a fisherman.
[ Chuckles ]
Ondine:
Can I help?
You can man the tiller.
Right.
Straight out to sea.
[ Gasps ]
Keep her steady, would you?
Fisheries board.
You can't really guide a boat
with your foot.
I'm not doing well?
No, I never said that.
[ ♫ Singing Indistinctly ♫ ]
[ Fishing Reel Clicking ]
Oh, shit.
Would you look at that!
My God.
- What?
That's weird.
Salmon.
Weird?
You don't get salmon trawling.
- Trawling.
Only with a gill net.
- Curiouser and curiouser.
Where did you hear that?
Alice said it.
- To the white rabbit.
Annie says it, too.
Annie?
- My daughter.
Jesus Christ.
Ah... Fuck!
- What?
They're going to come on board.
Lads.
Jesus.
See you caught salmon.
- I did.
How did you catch them?
Trawling.
- And you expect us to believe that?
No, but it's true.
Show us your gill nets.
- In the hold.
That's not wet.
- I know.
So, how'd you dry it?
I didn't.
Told you, I didn't use it.
There's a girl here, Circus.
- Where?
In your net.
[ Clears Throat ]
Is that illegal?
No, but... It's unusual.
And you can see her?
- She's right here in front of me.
Ask her how I caught the salmon.
How'd he catch them?
Trawling.
- And you want us
to believe in fairy tales?
Yes.
Huh?
What did she say?
She said yes.
Well, then,
you'd better believe her.
Right.
Close it up, lads.
[ Laughs ]
So, they saw you.
Is that all right?
No.
- It's a relief in a way.
Means you're not in my mind.
- Means they'll talk.
'Course they will.
What will they say?
- Ah, take your pick.
Circus, clowns,
salmon, a girl.
I'm going to the harbor.
Do you want me to drop you off?
It's done, isn't it?
What's done?
I've been seen.
Here, take a look at the girl
coming in on that boat.
She's not bad, is she?
It is a small town.
Everyone stares.
You can say that again.
What's wrong with being seen?
Nothing...
when you look good.
You look mighty.
I'm going to have to
declare these, Circus.
They've already seen them.
- Who?
The fisheries.
They're fine, believe me.
Thanks, Mary.
Can I buy you a present?
Clothes.
But can I choose this time?
- You don't like the dress?
No, I like it, just...
Underwear could be better.
Didn't fit?
Tight around the edges.
You have edges?
[ Wheelchair Beeps ]
I knew it wasn't a story.
- What wasn't a story?
You're such a shite storyteller anyway.
I knew it had to be true.
Ondine, this is my daughter, Annie.
We've met before.
Yes, we have.
What are we doing?
Buying clothes.
- Okay.
This town is what you'd call
sartorially challenged.
What does that mean?
A supermodel's nightmare.
[ Annie whistles ]
Do selkies do lingerie?
Why not?
They wear seaweed knickers
and a scallopy bra.
But that's underwater.
Won't do here.
I'm not suggesting she buy
them all, da.
Just a selection.
That's where I found her --
Roan Carraig.
- You know what it means?
Seal rock.
It's a kind of sanctuary
for her kind.
Her kind?
Yeah.
The well-dressed kind.
What do you think?
Or should we say
what do 'they' think?
You cleaned the place.
Like Snow White.
Is that all right?
But I'm not a dwarf, you know.
I'm little, but I'm not a dwarf.
Who is Snow White?
Doesn't matter.
She didn't swim.
Can you swim, Annie?
No. There's no pool in the town,
and I've never had lessons.
I think it could relax you a lot.
Unless you have a fear of water.
I wouldn't have a fear of water
with a water creature around me.
Okay, then.
Come on.
What'll I wear?
Underwear.
She's gone already.
Where?
The caravan at Poulin.
Is that where she sleeps,
your water baby?
Thought I might
take her out for the day.
The regatta starts at 3:00.
Oh, the three of you.
Go diving for pearls?
Something like that.
What kind of stories are you spinning?
[ Sighs ]
Just relax.
Okay.
Lie down now.
I'll hold you.
You see?
You're a sea creature.
You think?
- I know.
[ Both Laugh ]
Relax.
Okay. Let's go on the raft, okay?
[ Panting ]
[ Inhales Deeply ]
What's that?
Just something I found.
You found your seal coat.
Maybe.
Are you going to bury it?
Would you like me to bury it?
Yes, because it means
you'll be here for seven years.
Would you like that?
I would like that a lot.
We better bury it then, do you think?
Absolutely.
- Okay.
Help me.
Will I remember where it is
in seven years' time?
Watch this.
17 steps.
And it's our secret.
We tell nobody.
You know, da,
if she buries her seal coat,
she stays seven years on land.
- Annie.
It's true.
With a...
What's it called again?
- A landsman.
Unless her selkie husband claims her back.
- I don't have a husband.
Maybe you don't remember, but you do.
All selkies do.
[ Crowd Cheering ]
Bastard!
Whoo-hoo!
[ Cheering ]
Campione!
These are magic, man,
I'm telling you. Here.
Have a chip.
- No, no.
And the last thing is, da,
she can make a wish come true.
Please, Annie.
If you're a selk, you can.
Then I'm not a selk.
Okay.
You're not a selk.
[ Cheers and Applause ]
Man:
Come on, lads, pull harder!
[ Cheering ]
So you're not a selk.
Prove it.
What?
Annie!
Annie! Annie!
Jesus Christ!
Annie.
Come here to me.
Come here, baby.
I got you, I got you.
I got you.
Jesus Christ.
What happened?
The brakes went.
- What?
Let me see you.
Come here.
And I was lucky, wasn't I?
- Lucky, how?
That she breathes underwater.
Jesus.
What happened?
She fell in the water chasing a duck.
The brakes went, ma.
By the pier. She saved me.
Your water baby?
Clown!
Come on. We'll get you upstairs
and into a bath quick.
The brakes --
they didn't go, did they?
No.
She did that herself.
Why?
Why did she do it herself?
To test me, maybe?
See how much I'd do for her.
Hmm, strange.
Feels like home.
Who is this woman, Annie?
Alex: She's from the Orkney islands.
She swam round the coast to here.
What if she was?
I imagine she'd be a wee bit wet
around the scratcher, though, eh?
Bit cold round the old thigh region.
Stop him, ma.
Close the door.
- Your clown of a fisherman,
he wouldn't notice though, would he?
Close the door, ma!
- Did he declare her
to the fisheries board?
[ Laughing ]
Syracuse: How much
would you do for her?
You testing me, too?
I'm sorry.
So why do they call you
Circus the clown?
Because I was one for years.
I drank.
- What made you stop?
Annie.
I came back from a week
on the trawlers and...
found her unconscious.
Her mother out on the piss.
I thought one of us better be sober.
Then she kicked me out.
You couldn't take Annie with you?
Ah, this is Ireland.
Men like me don't get custody.
Someone was looking for her.
- Who?
A man.
- A dark-haired man?
Yeah.
- You didn't tell him?
What's her name?
- Ondine.
That's not what he called her.
Men like you?
Fishermen.
Are you dry?
Didn't Annie tell you?
When a selk makes love
to a fisherman...
she weeps...
salt tears.
[ Gasps ]
You said you died...
in the water.
How many lives do you have?
For you?
I can't count.
My name's Syracuse,
and I'm an alcoholic.
Priest: And you've been sober
for 2 years, 7 months, and --
- 21 days.
Doing very well, Syracuse.
- It's about the girl, father.
Oh, yes.
The one you "met" out fishing.
I drew her up in a net, father.
She looked pretty real to me, Circus.
Syracuse.
Sorry. Syracuse.
- So, what about her?
You've sinned with her, I suppose?
Of course.
- And I don't suppose you want absolution?
- No.
No.
So, why are you here, Syracuse?
You know the story about
the king who had a secret,
and it drove him mad,
so he told it to the tree?
Okay, so pretend I'm a tree.
She brings me luck,
and I don't know why.
I'm afraid, father, because...
I'm beginning to hope.
We should never lose hope, Syracuse.
She was drowned, father.
My net brought her back to life.
It doesn't make sense.
- I know! None of it makes sense!
That's why I'm afraid.
I know something's going to
happen, something wonderful...
Or terrible!
It's just the kind of girl she is.
It's just the kind of person she is.
And that's my secret.
So what kind of tree are you, father?
I suppose I'm an oak.
You look more like one of the ones
they make hurley sticks out of.
Oh, an ash, yeah.
Well, as long as you're a tree.
Hey. You Syracuse?
- Yeah.
Syracuse the fisherman?
- What's it to you?
You got a light?
The girl on the boat.
What do you call her?
My mascot.
[ Engine Turns Over ]
Syracuse: You were upset last night?
Annie: Not so much.
Your mom said you were.
- Well, she imagines things.
Do you imagine things, da?
- I leave that to you.
It's because I've
too much time on my own.
My blood going from here to there.
Try to imagine a happy ending.
It's hard.
Some days it's hard.
[ Knocking ]
Where is everybody?
- Oh, God.
In town for the regatta.
The regatta?
Yeah. There's bands playing.
Late-night opening.
Mom told me.
I forgot.
Have you got a key?
- Yeah, but I left it inside.
Annie!
Come on.
Where does she drink these days?
Skippers.
- Skippers.
[ Car Alarm Activates ]
Hello?
Annie:
Done it, ma.
Oh, you good thing, you.
Careful. They don't serve knackers here.
Give us the keys, Maura.
I'll take her home.
She'll be fine.
A bar never hurt anyone.
- Please, Maura.
You've cleared a few in your time, huh?
She's coming to my place.
She's not.
Go back to your fucking caravan.
Home to your mermaid, Circus, huh?
You know he's got himself a water baby?
Annie.
I'll be fine.
You just go, da.
Two shots, aye?
- Two shots, is it?
That's it.
Middle pocket, right?
Right middle pocket.
Oh, pish.
- Two shots to me.
Ondine!
Don't I get seven years?
Remember the bit about selkie men?
The husband?
Well, he's here.
- And he's taking her back?
Yes.
So I'll see you at home then, huh?
Whoo!
[ Laughs ]
A guy was breathalyzed
in one of those in Glasgow.
No, seriously.
No, he was six times over the limit.
Ah.
What if I take the footpath?
Look, darling,
You're still in charge of
your flipping vehicle, right?
I'll go slowly.
Tell him to piss off.
I wish I could.
Wish, then.
I can't.
You can grant a wish.
You sure?
Annie says so.
Okay.
I wish she wasn't sick.
So do I.
And I wish you would stay.
That's two wishes.
One for you.
And one for me.
[ Tires Screech ]
Alex: Have you got your lights on, hen?
The cops will get you if you don't.
Ahh!
[ Alarm Blaring ]
Maybe it's all a lie.
Maybe you walked into the sea
to get away from a bad marriage.
Would you believe that?
I did it once.
- And what happened?
I got wet.
Got sense. Got sober.
That's not the story, though.
Well, what is, then?
Like Annie says,
I'm a selk.
[ Sirens Wailing ]
Something's up.
A crash.
No!
No! Annie!
Get -- Get out --
Get out of me way!
Annie! Annie! Annie!
Syracuse! Syracuse!
Annie!
Officer: She's okay, she's okay.
She's in good hands.
Listen! Listen! Jesus Christ!
Tell me what happened to her!
There's been a terrible accident,
But Annie is all right.
Do you hear me?
Annie is fine.
You wore your seat belt, love?
What happened?
We don't know yet.
She's all right, father?
Please God, she will be.
We're just going to
move her to another room.
Do you want to follow me?
Is something wrong?
What's happening?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
[ Speaking In Native Language ]
What's happening?
- The doctor will explain.
Syracuse, can we talk in private?
What's going on?
Alex had a donor card.
- What?
We have a tissue match.
Strangest thing, but it's happened.
Are you serious?
Come on.
[ Speaking In Native Language ]
So why are you here?
You speak their language now.
It's softer than ours.
I wish you were dead.
None of us are that lucky.
So, the sea spit you out, did it?
It can swallow me again.
We don't belong here, do we?
- So, go home.
I can't.
Police want to talk to me.
- About what?
She came from nowhere.
Drunk.
They should talk to her, not me.
- Tell them that.
I will.
And then you'll tell me.
Nothing.
Hey.
Where is mom?
She's asleep.
She can't see you right now.
But she will later.
Where's Ondine?
Ondine's close by.
You'll see her, too.
Just rest.
[ ♫ Accordion Playing ♫ ]
He had a wife
and three children in Scotland.
Where are they now?
They said we were welcome to him.
I'm sorry it happened like this.
Sure I can't take it in.
I know.
It's hard.
Why aren't you blaming me?
Because for once
you had nothing to do with it.
Why do I feel as if I did?
Because you're Circus.
You get everything wrong.
I met him on this ferry.
Where was I?
[ Sighs ]
Where you always were.
At sea.
[Sighs]
Take Annie home when she's stronger.
Till I get out of this thing,
I can't cope.
Okay.
It's what you always wanted,
isn't it?
Yes.
So, you've got it.
But I don't want that woman there.
And take me to his wake now.
I can't.
- Oh, I insist.
Two whiskies and ice.
- One.
Two.
Maura, I don't.
Show some respect.
It's his funeral.
Get rid of her, Circus.
- Who?
Your water baby.
She brings good luck, then bad.
Two more, Maggie.
[ Indistinct Conversations, Laughter ]
[ Retching ]
You all right?
Finders keepers.
[ Laughing ]
Why are you looking at me like that?
Because you're a selkie.
And I'm an alcoholic.
A peaceful night's sleep, had you?
No.
He's still out there somewhere.
Okay.
I'm taking you home.
Hey!
That bit about the husband...
He's not my husband.
What is he, then?
My pushta.
What's that?
Selkie for "squeeze"?
Huh?
Look. You're home.
You'll be safe there.
You can sing your song.
Who will I sing it to?
To me.
Go on, sing!
Make the seals dance!
I can't.
- Why not?
Because you're drunk.
I'll be sober in the morning.
You can sing to me then.
I fished round here for years.
Never knew this selkie stuff.
Jeez, maybe you were dead,
and I fished you back to life.
Yes!
And now you're gonna haunt me, huh?
Forever.
Come here.
What does "haunt" mean, huh?
What does "haunt" mean?
Stop it.
You want some?
Selkies don't drink?
Oh, so you're safe here.
Is that right?
How's Annie?
She's fine.
She's safe, too.
I got another bottle on the boat.
Syracuse.
What does "haunt" mean?
- It means what you're doing...
...to me.
[ Motor Starts ]
He wouldn't!
Syracuse!
- Don't!
What are you doing?
I know it's not how fairy tales end.
But this one does.
This one does because it has to.
What do you mean?
What do you mean?!
I mean your kind and my kind.
We don't belong together.
[ Crying ]
I have to say good-bye...
Go away.
...to Annie.
Syracuse.
Hey, buddy.
Oh, I'm your buddy, am I?
Yeah. You are.
You're my sobriety buddy.
Where were you last night?
I needed you.
You fell off the wagon.
- Big time.
Circus of fools.
I was twirling around that big top.
[ Groans ]
I'm back in the sawdust now.
And it tastes like shite.
[ Sighs ]
Do you know
what my problem is, buddy?
- You can't take good luck.
10 out of 10, Sherlock.
Misery is easy, Syracuse.
Happiness you have to work at.
- Why didn't the tree say that?
Sure, the tree's
not gonna tell you anything.
What about the girl?
- Ah, she's gone.
And Annie?
- She's getting out today.
I'm taking her home with me.
After that, there's no excuses,
is there, buddy?
- No.
Why are you crying?
- I'm not.
Yes, you are.
I can tell.
Maybe because you're back
on the road again. You're home.
Where's Ondine?
- Ondine had to go away for a while.
That's why you're crying.
- It's not, I swear.
Did her husband come?
- He must have.
Because she's gone...
On sea business.
[ Laughs ]
But she'll be back, you know.
- Do you think?
I know.
She left something here.
What?
Woman On Television:
"The eldest of two children,
a younger brother, Robert..."
[ Channel Changes ]
What time is it?
Half-one.
Why didn't you wake me?
Because you were sleeping like a baby.
I thought you were the baby.
Doesn't look like it.
[ Groans ]
Do you want breakfast?
Lunch.
There you are, baby.
♫ Singing in silence ♫
♫ let's sing into the years,
like one ♫
[ Channel Changes ]
Annie, that song...
- What song?
Just a minute ago.
♫ a sound for no one ♫
It's real.
'Course it's real.
It's Sigur Ros.
♫ let's sing in tune ♫
♫ but now it's home ♫
Annie, I have to go out for a bit.
I'll take you to your mom's.
- No.
I can't leave you on your own.
Yes, you can.
Don't you get it? I'm better.
Are you sure?
You got some unfinished sea business?
I suppose.
Go on, then.
I'm kind of busy here anyway.
[ Door Closes ]
[ Sighs ]
♫ I wanted to know ♫
♫ what I have done ♫
Hey !
♫ I wanted to know ♫
♫ it's bad ♫
Hey! Hey!
♫ what I have done ♫
♫ I wanted to know ♫
♫ right now ♫
Ondine: There were seals
down there basking on the rocks.
My kind, huh?
I didn't say that.
No, but you thought it.
Then the storm came up.
They slipped into the water,
one by one.
I was going to join them.
What changed your mind?
What changed yours?
She was switching channels
on the TV...
and your song came on.
It was never my song.
So tell me.
No. No.
Take me home.
Where is home?
What do you think?
You'll tell me the truth now.
The truth?
The truth is I'm a creature from the sea
that found her seal coat and buried it
because she found a family she liked.
Please.
That's...
That's one truth.
You don't want to know the other.
Try me.
Okay.
I am a prisoner
and a drug mule from Romania.
I said the real truth.
This is the real truth.
I was on a boat with
a kilo of heroin in a backpack.
Coast guards came,
Vladic made me swim for it.
Vladic?
My selkie husband.
My pushta.
♫ maybe this time tomorrow ♫
♫ or it may be today ♫
Ondine: He was like
a monster from a fairytale.
But he couldn't swim.
So he made me take to the water.
I was always a good swimmer,
But your Irish waves wore me down.
I swam till I could swim no more.
Then I floated.
Then I sank.
It was almost a relief.
I said, "Here goes. I die".
And that's the truth.
You brought me back to life.
[ Laughs ]
I found a caravan, a family.
Now it's gone, okay?
Caravan's going nowhere.
What's your real name?
It's Joanna.
Joanna.
Just tell her you were
away on sea business.
Sea business? Hmm.
Joanna: Annie !
- I told them nothing.
Syracuse: Told who?
Vladic: Not true, little girl.
You told us about seven tears
and the selkie island,
and how Ondine came out of the water.
- But nothing important,
I swear!
Seven tears are important, surely?
And the selkie island.
Still some details
I'd like to get more clear.
Do you want to eat some?
Oh!
- Da!
Are you okay?
Aah! Ah!
Who the heck are you?!
Circus the clown.
- We've got seals, selkies, clowns!
Someone start making sense here!
[ Speaking Romanian ]
Is she the swimmer?
- Yes, I swim like a fish.
Is she the one that lost it?
I'll get it back.
Just put that thing down!
Where is it?
- Where is what?
He wants her seal coat, da.
Yes, I want her seal coat.
Don't give it to them!
- We have to.
Means you'll go.
- We don't know that.
I know it!
- Tell her!
Tell her what?
- Tell her you don't care about me.
I don't care about her!
- All you want is the coat.
[ Shouting in Romanian ]
What's he saying?
Listen to me!
Let them go!
Put that thing away!
I'll show you where.
- Where?
It's okay.
Syracuse: Give her to me.
Give her to me.
Come here.
[ Speaking Romanian ]
Joanna:
It's here.
Syracuse: Here, Annie.
Come here, come here, come here.
What? What?
It was here, I swear.
I swear.
Stop it! Stop it.
Listen to me.
Look at me, little girl!
Look at me! Don't make me bite!
- Did you move it, Annie?
Annie: Bury the coat.
He digs it up,
and then she doesn't stay...
...For seven years,
then she goes.
- Tell them where you moved it, Annie,
Before they hurt somebody, okay?
I don't want you to go!
If you tell me where you moved it,
I promise I stay.
How long?
- As long as you want.
I'll find a job on a fishing boat, anything.
Just tell me.
- Cross your heart?
Cross my heart and hope to die.
The lobster pot.
- The lobster pot?
What lobster pot?
The one for storage.
- Okay, show us.
Out there.
- Show us.
It's full of water.
He's not a selkie, is he?
No, he isn't.
- And you still are.
It was vacuum-wrapped.
Always.
[ Screams ]
Aah!
Help! I can't swim!
Help!
Syracuse:
Keep that gun on him!
Annie: So, he couldn't breathe underwater?
Ondine:
No, he couldn't.
Does that mean he drowned?
Syracuse: Don't you worry about it, love.
[ Knock On Car ]
Man #1: That's it, lads.
Over this way now.
Man #2: All right.
All right, let's go.
Priest:
Is this not an AA meeting?
Syracuse:
I don't know.
Thing is, father, she's up
in front of the judge next week.
- And?
And she's a non-national.
And this is the confessional, father.
We're not talking gossip here.
- I'm still an oak.
I thought you were
a what-do-you-call-it...
- An ash.
An ash.
Well, her solicitor said
she'll get deported
if she doesn't become a national.
So, she has to apply
to the Department of Justice.
Or... She... Gets... Married.
Ah.
So, who's going to marry her, Syracuse?
Well, it's not like
there's a queue, father.
- Well, I can't marry her.
No, no. You're a tree.
- Exactly.
Annie: And I threw
the selkie coat in the water.
And I told a lie about that, too.
Wasn't a real lie, was it?
Because I wanted her to stay forever.
Priest:
She's staying forever?
Yeah. Haven't you heard?
They're getting married next week
to make her a national.
So I suppose
she isn't a selkie really.
Because you can't marry a seal, can you?
No. You definitely cannot.
Not in the real quotidian world, anyway.
Quotidian?
Yeah. Means the one we have to live in.
If she was a seal, though,
would you still do the wedding?
Me?
Annie:
What about your past lives?
Joanna:
Are you sure I have them?
Oh, yeah, everybody does.
It's just a matter of remembering.
Stop peeping, would you?
I don't peep.
I mean, you could have even been
married in one of them.
♫ and we could
keep each other warm ♫
♫ you bring crocosmia
and fuchsias, and I ♫
♫ I sing your name
into the night ♫
♫ a king of salt and stones,
your compass ♫
♫ it swings from you to me
tonight ♫
♫ we swim
without a word between us ♫
♫ our breath held in ♫
♫ we read enough
in the rush of ♫
♫ braille on our skin ♫
♫ on our skin ♫
♫ I fill a glass
with what you gathered ♫
♫ they wilt
against the windowpane ♫
♫ the morning sees you off
with nets to scatter ♫
♫ you will come in
with the tide again ♫
♫ we swim without a word
between us ♫
♫ our breath held in ♫
♫ we read enough
in the rush of ♫
♫ braille on our skin ♫
♫ on our skin ♫
♫ we swim without a word
between us ♫
♫ our breath held in ♫
♫ we read enough
in the rush of ♫
♫ braille on our skin ♫
♫ on our skin ♫
♫ whoa ♫
♫ we read enough
in the rush of ♫
♫ braille on our skin ♫
♫ on our skin ♫
♫ whoa ♫
♫ we read enough
in the rush of ♫
♫ braille on our skin ♫
♫ on our skin ♫
♫ we read enough
in the rush of ♫
♫ braille on our skin ♫
Subtitles = PhilSpace @ SubScene