[Thunder rumbling]
Think she'll get oer thisaway?
Might.
Best bed them down.
[Whistling]
Come on, Tig.
[Thunder crashes]
[Neighing]
[Whines]
There she goes.
Looks like we're in for it.
You see them?
Can't see them.
Can't hear them.
You eer seen one this bad?
Not since Noah and the flood.
Well, you should know, Boss,
since you was there.
What did you say?
He said, "You should know
since you was there."
Well, een that
wasn't this damn wet.
One thing's certain.
Noah neer shoeled as much bull
from them he had aboard.
Let's rustle up some grub.
Mose?
Hey!
- That hurt?
- Yeah.
Mose, still got them cards?
Yeah, I got them.
Get them out, and let's hae us
a game after breakfast.
Button!
Pull them plates under here.
You gonna play them cards, Mose,
or stare a hole through them?
Don't rush me.
I'll take four.
Oh, for pity's sakes.
"Take four."
All right, that's it.
I'm out.
Me too.
A man's trust
is a aluable thing, Button.
You don't want to lose it
for a handful of cards.
Well, at least it ain't raining.
Get yourself dressed, Button.
Help Mose get things cleaned up.
Then you walk out
and look for them horses.
Looks like you could use
a little muscle there, Charley.
You just keep on like you are.
You'll get your chance
soon enough.
No need to ask
for more chores, Mose.
Eery man's got to pull
his weight.
Yeah, but my weight
is half of yours.
You know, it's hard to figure
Charley sometimes.
I ain't een sure
if he likes me.
He likes you.
You know, Boss had some pause
about hiring me on.
Too big to get around on horses
and work them cows.
Afraid I'd eat too much.
It was Charley
that talked him into it,
and I ain't one to take
a man's confidence lightly.
You know I ain't, either.
I know you ain't, but it's best
to keep remembering it
if you want respect
when you're riding with men
like Charley and Boss.
Button, pull.
Pull it.
Button!
Quit playing with that dog
and pull the wagon!
Pull it!
- Pull!
- Oh, yeah!
Yeah.
That's it.
Hey, hey!
Look at that!
Old Boss sure can cowboy,
can't he?
Yeah.
Broke the mold after him.
Main bunch is working
towards water.
We'll go up-country,
find the rest,
and we'll push them there.
Look at that.
A couple of damn kids.
Anyway, once we get them,
we can start driing them back
closer to camp.
It'll be a while
before we see another town.
Could use supplies,
coffee and such.
Mose!
Ow!
You'll hae to ride back
to that town we passed.
When you want me to go?
Tonight.
BUTTON:
I'll go.
I can go.
How long you figure, Charley?
Without cows slowing things,
maybe one day there, one back.
Sounds about right.
Come on, Boss.
I can do it.
Sure you can, boy.
Just don't know
if that town's ready
to hae you
turned loose on it just yet.
[Mutters in Spanish]
English!
BUTTON:
Damn! Shit!
Bullshit!
By God, if you're gonna pick
your feet like a monkey,
you do it downwind.
Swear to God, old Tig
takes better care of herself.
Starting to think
it was a mistake
not getting you on in some town
to learn a trade.
I don't like towns.
Neer liked them.
Oh, you're just saying that
'cause you heard me say it.
Get yourself a trade
and set up in a town.
You'll always hae
a roof oer your head,
a bed up off the ground,
and food no further away
than a café.
Ain't that so, Charley?
That was a big help.
Might as well be talking
to this horse.
Put your boot on, Button.
Let's go to work.
Course, if you was to lie
in a town...
You'd hae to clean up some.
Otherwise, no one
could stand the stink.
What you do that for?!
Cheating at cards.
Cheating.
I apologized to you for that!
Eh, Boss?
I apologized to him for that.
Eidently he ain't oer it yet.
It's getting dark, Boss.
He could hae got hurt
between that town and the camp.
Probably just taking his time.
Don't suppose he got into
a poker game, do you?
Wouldn't gamble
your money, Boss.
What if he's lying out there
waiting for us to come along?
We'd neer find him tonight.
Now, come on down from there.
He's worried.
- You worried?
- Yeah, I'm worried.
Been worried since yesterday.
Should hae sent me.
Mose can look out for himself.
Then why ain't he here with us?
Well, you neer was
wanting to go to towns.
Well, I don't want to go now
neither.
But we better find him,
whereer he is.
All right.
You and me strike out early.
Button can watch the outfit.
Button, come on down from there
and get supper a-working.
Most likely be back
before suppertime.
But three sets of eyes,
it's better than two.
- You stay with the wagon.
- Come on, Boss.
No one is gonna bother it.
We haen't seen a single person
since we set up the camp.
I always feel better
if someone's close around.
You been working hard,
desere a little loafing time.
Stay right here.
[Tig barking]
Stay, Tig.
Wants to go.
She acts like she does,
but she don't.
Still got the heart,
not the legs.
You keep that rifle close.
Always liked me a sidearm
with some heft.
Took this off a man who couldn't
pay all he owed for some cows.
Damn fine weapon.
Always noticed you faor
something light, don't you?
Set it right down.
Thank you.
Hello!
- Howdy.
Like to feed and water them,
curry them down with saddles on.
Okay, that'll be four bits each.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
Not planning on staying long?
Long as it takes to find
who we're looking for.
Maybe I can help you gents.
I been here since Harmonille
was Fort Harmon
and we still had soldiers
to chase off Indians.
I know eerybody in town
and for miles beyond.
Big man needing a haircut,
about 30.
That's his rig right there.
Oh, yeah.
Know who you're talking about.
Very friendly young fella.
Looks like he's been liing out
of saddlebags most of his life.
Got his horse in the corral.
Ride with you, does he?
Know where we can find him?
Yeah.
Yeah, he's up in the jailhouse.
He got into it
with some cattlemen
oer at the general store.
- Some cattlemen.
- Yeah.
Busted them up pretty bad, too,
before Marshal Poole came up
and hit him oer the head
with his gun barrel.
Yeah, he's lucky he
didn't get shot in the back.
You might want to keep that
in mind
when you're talking
to Marshal Poole.
Saddle his horse.
That coer what he owes?
Oh, yeah.
Name's Percy if you should need
anything else.
Much obliged.
Hold on.
BAXTER:
How long you had him here?
I brought him in here
yesterday afternoon.
It wasn't easy
getting him into the cell.
Why is that?
Goddamn bear.
Size of it.
Eening.
Name's Boss Spearman.
This here's Charley Waite.
Eening.
Beliee you hae
a friend of ours.
Name's Mose Harrison.
Yeah, I got him here.
He started a fight
in the general store.
Mose don't start fights,
just finishes them.
I just said he started it.
You said he didn't.
Maybe you're calling me a liar.
You got a charge against him?
I got plenty.
Inciting a fight.
Disturbing the peace.
Creating a public nuisance.
Take your pick.
Hear tell he got hit
oer the head.
[Scoffs]
He'll be fine.
Well, I come to get him.
Well, you pay the fines,
and you can hae him.
How does $50 each offense sound?
Like robbery.
Lot of money.
Oh, yes, a lot of money.
I been waiting for you,
Mr. Spearman.
My name's Denton Baxter.
Be your men Mose tussled with.
That's right.
You know, folks
in Fort Harmon country
don't take to free grazers
or free grazing.
They hate them more than they
used to hate the Indians.
I expect by "folks,"
you mean ranchers like yourself.
I got the biggest spread around.
Bigger than any three or four
put together.
Built it up with me own
two hands,
piece by piece,
along with this town.
And there ain't no
free-graze cattle
gonna take the feed
off my cattle on this range.
Free graze is legal.
Times change, Mr. Spearman.
Most folks change with them.
A few holdouts neer do.
You know, a few years back,
a free-graze outfit
came through.
One night,
the cattle got stampeded,
the wagons caught on fire,
and one of those boys
was shot off his horse
in the middle of it all.
Shot in the back, was he?
Your man's horse and rig
are at the liery barn.
You can take him with you
when you leae tonight.
And come sunrise,
you hitch up your wagon
and get your damn
free-graze cattle moing
and keep them moing till you're
out of Fort Harmon country!
Now, you let Mr. Spearman
fetch his man
so he can be on his way.
[Lock rattling]
Charley.
- Mose.
- [Grunts]
Mose.
[Groans painfully]
Looks like someone's put the
boots to him after he was down.
Does it?
Mose, you gotta get up.
Charley, I'm glad to see you.
I don't much like this town.
Here you go.
Boy, they really lit into him.
You got a doctor in this town?
Yeah.
Doc Barlow.
It's the house up behind
the barn by the church.
Look for a picket fence.
He's got a sign out front.
Oh, my.
Bring him right in.
Lay him down in there.
I'll fetch the doctor.
Get his legs, Boss.
Easy, easy.
Good.
I'm Dr. Barlow.
Boss Spearman.
Charley Waite.
Patient there's Mose Harrison.
He works for me.
These wounds are old.
Easier to treat
if you bring him in right away.
Your marshal had him, and he
don't keep a friendly jail.
This is the man who was in the
fight with Dent Baxter's men?
He certainly gae
as good as he got.
Broke the arm of one.
Knowing them,
they had it coming, I expect.
Let's see what we got here.
- Aah!
- Easy.
- Easy, Mose.
- Easy, Mr. Harrison.
Nobody's trying to hurt you
on purpose.
I'd say you got a couple
of broken ribs.
Gonna need to get
this shirt off.
Sue, I am gonna need some soap,
some water, and some alcohol.
I want you to drink this,
Mr. Harrison.
- That's it.
- [Breathes sharply]
Let's clean up these cuts
on his face.
He's got a nice gash
in his scalp there.
I'd say to good health,
but then I'd probably be out
of business.
We'll drink to good health
for them that hae it coming.
The two of you
can wait in the parlor.
Be better he didn't trael.
Well, he'll hae to.
How much I owe you, Doctor?
We're een.
I figured I made enough off the
damage he did to Baxter's men.
Wish he'd hae made you wealthy.
Ma'am.
BOSS: Doc Barlow's got him
a pretty wife.
Notice that, did you?
Well, I ain't dead.
Glad to hear it.
Sweet, too.
Treated us as good as anybody.
That's a real lady.
A woman like that makes a man
think about
setting down roots, eh?
Doc looks like a real
hardworking feller.
Probably working away on making
some little ones, too.
Creates quite a picture,
now, don't it?
Yeah.
Heard they're worth
a thousand words.
[Barks]
Hey, Tig.
Now, where do you suppose he is?
Goddamn kid.
Button's all right, Boss.
Anyone done him harm, they'd
hae gone through the wagon.
Reckon you're right.
Here he is.
If you're awake,
you might want to see this.
- Where you been?!
- I seen it before.
BUTTON:
Out with the herd.
I thought I told you
to stay with the wagon.
- What happened to Mose?
- Did you hear what I said?!
Yeah, but what happened?
Run into a little trouble
in that town.
Looks like more than a little.
Are we moing on?
We always do, don't we,
once we'e grazed off a place?
Did I do something wrong?
Just leae him be for a while.
Here.
Hae some coffee.
Made fresh, for a change.
There was three riders scouting
up the herd this morning.
Where?
Maybe half a mile out.
Just sitting there,
looking at the cattle.
BOSS:
Same ones?
BUTTON:
Four this time.
CHARLE Y:
Country's filling up.
BUTTON:
Maybe we should push on.
BOSS:
Do no good, Button.
I seen them like Baxter before.
He means to hae this herd
or scatter it to the wind.
BUTTON:
If he was gonna take the herd,
why not just keep you in town?
Marshal already had Mose.
CHARLE Y:
Wants us all in one place.
Far from there when it happens.
Don't make no sense, him telling
us to moe on and all.
Weren't the only thing he said.
Most time, a man will tell you
his bad intentions
if you listen,
let yourself hear.
A few years back, a free-graze
outfit come through.
That weren't no idle story.
BOSS:
Let's find out for certain.
Beautiful country.
A man can get lost out here,
forget there's people and things
that ain't so simple as this.
How long we been
riding together, Charley?
Nigh on 10 years.
Mm-hmm.
You know what they call that,
call it a decade.
Long time.
Been a lot of change since then.
What's on your mind, Boss?
Way I figure it, we can leae
the cattle and run,
or you and me can go in the dark
and stop them
before they scatter the herd.
You reckon them cows are worth
getting killed oer?
The cows is one thing.
But one man telling another
where he can go in this
country's something else.
That rancher sat
in that jailhouse,
sneering and letting
his lawman lay down the law
till he figured
it was time to show us
that he gae the orders
around here.
Ooh, sticks in my craw.
Well, we sure as hell owe them
for what they done to Mose.
Yeah.
I'll saddle the horses.
You two keep a sharp eye out.
Got the scatter-gun.
We'll be watching for them.
You'll want to douse that fire.
Button, keep to the wagon.
I don't want to see you
out in the open.
Okay?
I got some sugar in that town.
It's in the wagon.
I wouldn't want to hae him
coming down on me
like these cowboys.
What the hell's the matter
with you, Gus?
You're twitching all damn night.
Damn back's so sore from being
flung into that stoe.
[Grunts]
Feel like I been humped
by a 300-pound whore.
Well, Gus, I'd say
you got off easy.
Look at my face.
Well, you can bet Butler will
square things with that big man
for breaking his arm and all.
Did you hear it snap?
I heard it snap.
Lucky for him he shoots
with either hand.
[Gun cocks]
BOSS:
One twitch, and you're in hell!
Now, get on your feet,
all of you!
Now, throw them guns
on the ground.
[Gun cocks]
I ain't a-gonna say it again.
And kick them away.
Which one of you's got
a sore back?
Which one?
Him.
- You're Gus?
- Yeah.
Ought not gang up on a man
three-to-one.
Ohh!
Wait a minute, mister.
- It wasn't our idea to jump him.
- Shut up, Wylie.
Get up, you son of a bitch.
- What's your name?
- Vince.
Mighty nice tie-down you got.
You're a gunhand, are you?
- You fast?
- No.
Uh-huh.
How many riders does he hae?
I said, how many riders?
The rest are on their way
to your wagon.
Uhh! Aah!
You want to smile now, go ahead.
Be a while before he's of use.
Charley, throw me
them saddlebags.
[Neighs]
Put your spook hats on.
The ones in your belt,
put them on.
Now get your britches off.
Not taking my britches off
for nobody.
You listen out
of your good ear now.
Now, get them off!
Pretty scary bunch, eh, Charley?
Get belly-down, flat-out!
Uhh!
Get your peckers in the dirt.
- Hyah! Hah!
- [Neighing]
Hah!
If I hear so much
as a twig break...
I'll come back
and kill you all.
Charley.
Charley!
No Tig come to meet us.
Ooh.
The bastards.
They shot the boy,
but he's alie.
Is that Mose?
He's dead.
Shot him in the head.
Charley?
Charley, get the lantern
and the whiskey.
Yeah.
[Speaking Spanish]
Come on, wake up.
Charley.
They shot him here and
cracked him in the head here.
We'll hae to dig
that bullet out.
CHARLE Y:
You done good, Boss.
Him going in and out like that.
I don't know.
He lost a lot of blood.
A whack on the head
can make a man strange
for the rest of his days.
Well, you done all you can.
He needs a doctor now.
If Button lies through morning,
you take him in the wagon
and moe on.
You just gonna sit out here
waiting with them cows?
That's right.
And I'm gonna kill
eery son of a bitch
that comes to take them.
For one man on open ground,
you sure got a lot
of killing in mind.
You know I neer
gone against you, Boss.
Always let you do
most of the talking.
But he needs that doctor
back in that town,
and I aim to take him.
If you want to come,
we'll go together.
Otherwise, you do what you
hae to do, I'll do the same.
You think they'll let you waltz
in there and waltz out?
I don't figure into it.
Button deseres eery chance
we can gie him.
All right.
But I aim to kill Baxter
and those that done this.
And if that marshal gets in the
way, I'm gonna kill him, too.
So you best get your mind right
about what's got to be done.
I got no problem
with killing, Boss.
Neer hae.
[Metal clanging]
Looks real nice, Charley.
Yeah, a man ought to hae
something to show he was here.
Be gone in another big storm.
Don't matter none.
He's got your dog for company.
He'd like it you put
old Tig with him.
Yeah, he was more
Mose's dog in the end
than he was mine.
Be right to say some words.
You want to speak
with the man upstairs, do it.
I'll stand right here
and listen,
but I ain't talking
to that son of a bitch.
And I'll be holding a grudge
for him letting this befall
a sweet kid like Mose.
Well, he sure as hell
wasn't one to complain.
Woke with a smile.
Seemed like he could keep it
there all day.
Kind of man that'd say
"good morning" and mean it,
whether it was or not.
To tell you the truth, Lord,
if there was two gentler souls,
I neer seen them.
Seemed like old Tig wouldn't
een kill birds in the end.
Well, you got yourself
a good man and a good dog,
and I'm inclined to agree
with Boss
about holding a grudge
against you for it.
I guess that means "amen."
God.
BOSS:
Charley, you all right?
I'm fine.
Seems like you was, you know...
I said I'm fine.
Just got some old feelings
coming up.
You know, we neer asked
each other much.
That's always been okay with me.
I figured it was okay with you.
But you said some things
the last couple of days.
Things that seemed like they had
kind of a history to them.
Hey, Charley?
Don't stand behind me, Boss.
When I was a kid, a bunch of us
would go into the woods
with our peashooters.
Nothing fancy, just enough
to kill a bird or a squirrel,
maybe something larger
if we was lucky.
Killed my first man
in them woods.
Held the paper on our farm,
and after my pa died,
he'd come around to get payment
from my mom in any way he could.
Weren't much older than Button
when I shot him in the throat.
Knew there'd be more killing, so
I run off and joined the Army.
War was on.
They was only too happy
to hae me.
My first skirmish was like
hunting with my friends.
We just sat up in some trees,
and they came marching at us.
Must hae been a hundred of them
dead after the smoke cleared.
Went around and shot the rest
who weren't.
Those of us with the knack
was made into a special squad
so we could trael light
and on our own
into enemy territory.
Orders were pretty simple.
Make trouble whereer we could.
With room like that, it wasn't
long before we was killing men
that weren't een in uniform.
Seemed like that went on
the rest of the war.
After that, I come West.
Lot of call for a man
with them skills.
And I put them to work
for men just like Baxter.
Eery once in a while,
I almost get through a day
without thinking
about who I am, what I'd done.
He drifted off again.
No better, but no worse, either.
You're a real honest man,
Charley.
Well, I ain't gonna lie
about Button.
Not Button I'm talking about.
- Mr. Spearman.
- The doctor in?
No, he's not here.
We got a boy that's hurt bad.
Here, put him
in the examining room.
It's not his hearing, ma'am.
He hears real well
when he's awake.
Mr. Spearman, I'm checking
if there's blood in his ears.
It could mean a fractured skull.
Are you the boy's father?
No, ma'am.
His name's Button,
and he works for me.
It appears that's
not ery healthy.
You know the way to the parlor.
Sit down.
I'll be a while.
[Thunder rumbling]
Well, I don't think
it's a fracture.
Concussion's more likely,
but it's bad.
I hae to admit, we don't see
a lot of people shot.
I cleaned and dressed the wound.
Doesn't look infected.
What about the feer?
He needs to lay still
and let his body do its work.
No offense, ma'am,
but we come a long way
to see that the boy gets looked
after proper by Dr. Barlow.
Now, where's he at?
One of Dent Baxter's hands
came and fetched him
out to the ranch.
Some men there had an accident
night before last.
You must tell me what happened,
Mr. Spearman.
Baxter sent his men
to stampede the herd,
and I figured me and Charley
to stop them.
Surprised them where they was
hiding, and we had at them.
Them's the one Dr. Barlow's
putting back together.
We got back to camp, others
had shot Mose in the head,
shot Button, left him for dead.
Oh.
Shot our dog.
I'll be getting money.
It's not necessary.
We pay our way, ma'am.
Please, sit, Mr. Waite.
Button.
Is that his real name?
Please, sit.
Yeah, it's the only one
we'e known.
He's just a boy.
Yeah.
Picked him up in a Texas town
a few years back,
liing off café garbage.
Couldn't speak a word
of English.
Thought we was doing him
a faor.
What about you?
Hmm?
You know that the marshal
works for Baxter.
People saw you ride in.
There's payment to be made
by them that done this.
Don't intend to run.
We could wire
for the federal marshal.
If he started riding today,
he wouldn't make it for a week.
With the storm coming,
maybe longer.
We're obliged to deal with the
marshal and Baxter ourseles.
What about Button?
Well, he's fighting
for his life.
We're gonna do the same.
[Door opens]
Whateer's needed for Button,
you do it.
If he wakes, he's gonna need
to stay here a couple days
so we can watch him.
Whateer's best for him.
Can't stay away from
my little paradise, gents?!
Beliee Satan says the same at
the gates of hell, old-timer!
[Laughs]
We'd like to put the horses up.
Had a tough trail.
I'd like to set
the wagon yonder.
Help yourself!
Hurry up, though!
I seen it like this before!
Big one's coming!
Hyah, hyah, hyah!
Son of a bitch.
Sorry, Charley.
Yeah.
[Wood creaking]
Jesus Christ.
Ooh, hoo, hoo, hoo!
Maybe you should hae built it
in another spot.
Ah, mercy.
[Thunder rumbles]
MAN:
Get the dog!
[Whining]
It's a dog there, Charley.
Take this.
There he is.
Back here, Charley!
To your left!
Get him!
[Laughs]
You all right, Charley?
Yeah, considering
I'e just been swimming.
I owe you, mister.
That's a sweet pup
you got there.
Remind you of anyone, Charley?
Small ersion.
Too small to be let out
in this weather.
Belongs to my daughter.
I tried to grab him, but
the water was too fast for me.
If you're going into the café,
I'd be proud to buy you both
a cup of coffee.
Coffee would be good about now.
This is like the storm
that washed away Gunnison
10, 12 years back.
The water come down
from the mountains.
Nowhere to go
but straight into town.
- Killed a lot of folks.
- It's okay, Bill.
Town's been here
a long time, Mack.
It'll be here a lot longer.
That's right, Papa.
Eery once in a while,
a good storm washes through
and leaes her as clean
as a baby's bottom.
Got to look
on the bright side, gents.
Marshal.
Meat and spuds, Les, as always.
That should coer our meal.
Worth a man's life to walk
across that road tonight.
Thanks for the coffee.
Well, appreciate what you done.
That'll be two bits.
Two bits.
[Thunder rumbling]
I'll be haing words
with you two.
And we'll be haing more
than that with you, Marshal.
No need to make
the café messy... with folks.
I'e got a warrant sworn out
for your arrest
for assaulting Baxter's men.
We got a warrant sworn
for attempted murder
for them that tried
to kill the boy
who's laying oer there
at the doc's.
Swore out another one
for them that murdered the big
fellow you had in your cell.
Only ours ain't writ
by no tin star
bought and paid for, Marshal.
It's writ by us.
And we aim to enforce it.
Is that so?
We got no quarrel
with none of you folks.
Baxter's men bushwhacked
our friend and shot him dead.
Shot a 16-year-old boy, too.
And clubbed him so hard...
He might not lie.
Tried to take our cattle.
Your marshal here ain't gonna do
nothing about it.
You don't like free grazers
in this town.
We don't much like being here.
But a man's got a right
to protect his property
and his life.
And we ain't letting no rancher
or his lawman take either.
We got no intention
of harming bystanders.
Anyone who helps or comforts
these goddamn lawbreaking
free grazers
is gonna hae to deal with me.
Your call, Marshal.
We don't hae to settle this
here and now.
You ain't going nowhere
in this weather.
But I'll be seeing you gents
real soon.
You can count on that.
[Thunder crashes]
That marshal ain't gonna wait.
That son of a bitch is gonna get
some men, come looking for us.
He's gonna need us locked up
tight in that jail
by the time Baxter hits town,
'cause if we ain't,
Baxter's gonna start to think
that maybe Marshal Poole ain't
worth what he's paying him.
You got something on your mind,
just spit it out.
Well, I say we take him
right at the jail.
Lock him up, wait for Baxter
to come riding in.
Hell, Charley, why don't we
just ride out to Baxter's ranch
and go straight at him, too?
Well, I'll fight
whereer you want, Boss.
You just make the call.
God damn it.
Now, hold on, Charley.
Hold on.
Well, you asked me.
I told you.
Charley, come on in
out of the rain, would you?
Come on.
Just getting testy
in my old age.
Sounds like it's not
such a bad idea.
Just roll it around
is all I ask.
All right.
What'd you think of my speech
in there?
Liked it.
Maybe I ought to run
for mayor.
Well, I beliee officeholders
got to be liing, Boss.
[Laughs]
[Knock on door]
BOSS:
Come to see about the boy.
He's asleep.
But, please, come in.
Are you sure, ma'am?
We're a mite rank.
We don't want to mess
your house.
No, no.
No, please, it's all right.
Come on in.
Thank you, ma'am.
There you are.
[Boss chuckles]
I can't get my fingers in.
We can't get our big fat fingers
in these holes.
- [Laughs]
- Too many broke knuckles.
Oh, let me get you
something bigger.
- No, ma'am, we can make do.
- No, no. It's all right.
It's just nice to be sitting
at a table set with fine china.
Those were my mother's.
They were the only things
of hers
that suried the trip
out here.
I don't know why
I bring them out.
I can't hold them, either.
Guess it just makes me
feel good.
BOSS: I say what's
on my mind, good or bad.
SUE:
I admire that.
Try liing with it.
See that?
No need for a wife or home.
We're just like a...
an old married couple.
[Laughter]
So, is it marriage
that scares you two
- or putting down roots?
- No. Who'd hae him?
All rangy and mangy
like a rough old dog.
How about I hold
your head underwater
for just a little while?
BOSS:
I married once.
Neer knowed that,
did you, Charley?
Had a wife and child.
Sweet little spread, too.
It was nothing fancy,
but we was young.
Loed each other.
Neer had a cross word.
They caught the typhus
and died.
And after that, home didn't seem
a place to spend time.
Beliee I'e changed
my mind on that
now that I'm getting on
in years.
If Button lies
and we surie Baxter,
I swear I aim to see to it
there's a home he's sleeping in
instead of the cold prairie.
Hae yourself a last cup
of tea, Charley.
I'd like to see Button again,
Miss Barlow.
Of course.
I know the way.
Whew.
Been riding with him 10 years.
Neer said nothing
about being married.
Where are you and Mr. Spearman
spending the night?
Don't rightly know.
It... depends on circumstances.
You mean Marshal Poole?
We hae a spare room.
It's yours if you want it.
Couldn't do that, ma'am.
We'd be putting you in a spot
with the marshal and Baxter.
Besides, it's a small town.
Wouldn't look right,
particularly with the doc away.
I'll take those.
You know where they go?
I saw.
Thank you.
Been raining like hell
eer since we got here.
Water washing right down
Main Street.
Charley saed a pup
from being washed away.
Looked a little like old Tig.
Now, if you can, you got to
listen and pay attention.
'Cause I got something
important to say.
I ain't been looking after you
for you to go out this way.
The world ain't
a perfect place, Button.
But you got
unfinished business here.
So you come back,
you hear me, now?
You come back.
Kind of dumb talking to him
like that.
No.
No, it's good.
You all right, Mr. Spearman?
Beliee I'm as right as a man
can be under the circumstances.
Circumstances? That's just what
Mr. Waite called them.
I asked him to reconsider,
and I'm asking you.
By "reconsider,"
you mean tuck tail and run?
I mean sae your life and his.
He'll listen to you.
Charley thinks for hisself,
Miss Barlow.
He's a good man, and he knows
what has to be done.
I'll be paying you now
for whateer else Button needs.
In case it goes bad
for Charley and me,
maybe you and the doc will see
we're taken care of properly.
I'd like to put pen to paper
if you hae them.
Yes. Of course.
SUE:
Mr. Waite?
Look at my face.
- Oh! Sorry!
- [Gun cocks]
[Gasping]
I'm sorry.
It's all right, Charley.
Okay?
It just be us.
It's all right, Charley.
It's all right.
I'll get it.
Jumpy is all.
She ought not to sneak up
like that.
She weren't sneaking.
I scared that woman
half to death.
Yeah.
Scared me a little bit, too.
[Chuckles]
Well, that's how it is, Boss.
Ain't a pretty picture.
Got your wits about you now?
Yeah.
It weren't as bad as it looked.
I'll bet.
Go! Hyah!
Two whiskeys, barkeep.
Barkeep!
Two whiskeys.
You see that sign?
Around these parts,
free grazers is the first.
[Glass shatters]
[Chuckles]
Now, he asked you twice.
Ain't gonna ask again.
Hey, Bill, it's all right.
These are the fellows
that saed my dog.
I couldn't sere them
if they saed Jesus himself.
Mr. Baxter would hae my job.
Baxter the owner?
That's right.
Gie me a bottle.
I'll sere them myself.
You know I can't do that.
[Gun cocks]
Now we'll hae our drinks.
Beliee I'll hae me another.
Yes.
Well, looks like the rain's
let up a bit.
Well, if it don't,
there'll be trout fishing
right on Main Street.
[Both chuckling]
I'd like you to meet my boys.
Ray and Cory.