(WHISTLING)
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(TRAIN APPROACHING)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHUCKLES)
(BELL RINGS)
(TYPEWRITERS CLACKING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC HEIGHTENS)
(MUSIC QUIETENS DOWNS)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC STARTS UP)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CLATTERS LOUDLY)
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC PLAYS SOFTLY)
(WIND WHISTLES)
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC HEIGHTENS)
(TRAFFIC RUMBLING)
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HONKING)
(PANTING)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC PLAYS SOFTLY)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC QUICKENS)
(WIND BLOWING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(MELODIOUS MUSIC HEIGHTENS)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(BELL RINGS)
(MUSIC QUIETENS DOWNS)
(WIND BLOWING)
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)