(PEOPLE SHOUTING HAPPILY)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENTS
ON PA)
(HONKING)
MAN: This is good for...
Hi, Father.
(IN AMERICAN ACCENT) One, please.
TICKET SELLER 1: $10, please.
Did you send the labels?
Every one, $3,000.
TICKET SELLER 2:
Hello, how many?
Here's my bank.
RANKIN: Back in 20 minutes.
TICKET SELLER 3: Yeah, the
rush is about to hit.
(BAND PLAYING MARCHING MUSIC)
(CROWD CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER ON PA: ...some of the donors
that have given, uh, graciously thus far...
Move over, Fred and Ginger.
Contestant number four, Audrey
Clark, has been tap dancing
since she was three years old.
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
Pickaway County has delighted
in Audrey's performances
for 16 years and counting.
Don't worry, dance fans...
(MARCHING BAND MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Smile!
Come on, Mommy!
Oh!
CARNY: One more time, Mom.
One more time.
Here you go. It's all
you, it's all you.
(SIREN BLARES)
Heads up, here they are.
(GRUNTING)
All right, try again
one more time.
I know it's in you. Come on.
Oh! No, no.
GIRL: Come on, Mommy!
CARNY: Come on, one more time.
Hey, Padre. Padre.
Come on in here, help this
little girl out here.
I don't think so. Hey, no
cash, no nuns, on the house.
Come on, for this
beautiful little girl.
Please.
CARNY: You can do it.
Come on. On the house. Pop three for her.
There you go.
Who wants to be next here?
GIRL: Oh, yeah!
Look at that. It's so
easy, he can even do it.
GIRL: Mommy, I won!
Got a winner!
Little girl's a winner!
Here you go.
I won!
(GRUNTING)
Here you go, Padre, it's all you.
You're a winner.
Big old winner.
Thank you.
MOTHER: Thank you, Father.
Come on. On the house. Pop three for her.
There you go.
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
PARKER: Hardwicke!
Hey!
Oh!
Oh.
(GRUNTING)
(TOOL CLINKING)
(WHISPERING) I got it.
Keep it quiet.
(SQUARE DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
How ya doin', Officer? I just gotta
get through here real quick.
Sorry, sir, livestock
shows are changing.
You're gonna
have to wait 20 minutes.
Come on. I'm not gonna say anything
if you don't say anything.
No, sir. Those are the rules.
(SCOFFING) Idiot.
MANAGER: These are stacks of hundreds right here.
MELANDER: Easy.
WORKER 1: I've already counted them twice.
They're good.
MANAGER: Good deal.
WORKER 2: Pass me more bands.
Hardwicke's torching the
hay bales in five minutes.
Wait for my call.
WORKER 3: $20 bands, please.
WORKER 4: Let's move this in because
we got another shipment coming in...
Bet it's gonna be over
100 degrees again today.
Rankin, grab me a lemon shake-up
on your next run? Mmm-hmm.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
This is gonna be fun.
My uncle was a priest.
Sorry to bother you.
I'm on a bus back
to Cleveland at 4:00.
I was wondering
if there's someplace
I could put this
while I walk around.
Sure, Father.
Right where you came in, there's a blue building.
That's the hospitality center.
They will be more than happy to
help you with whatever you need.
They got some
great refreshments there.
Go! Go!
Freeze!
(GRUNTING)
Drop it.
(GRUNTS) Let's go.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Everybody down!
Get down in front
of the table! Asses up!
I'll blow your
fucking brains out!
Move it!
What's the erase code?
487.
Type it m.
Let's go. Move.
On the floor, face down.
I need your phones in a pile over here, please.
(SCARED MURMURING)
Right up here,
like the good Father said.
MAN: Pass them up there.
ROSS: Hurry! Up here!
(CHOIR SINGING
AMERICA THE BEAUTIFUL)
DIRECTOR:
Sopranos, you're flat,
you've gotta reach
for those high notes.
We all want this over
as quickly as possible.
I don't steal from
people who can't afford it
and I don't hurt people that
don't deserve it. So relax.
(WHIMPERING)
I'm no better than you.
You're no better than me.
If I say I'll do
something, I'll do it.
If you say you'll do
something and you don't,
I'll make sure you regret it.
(SQUARE DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(STAMMERING) We don't have the keys to that cabinet.
Only Mr. Leeds has those keys.
ROSS: Shut it, old man.
Hands behind your back. Everyone!
Hands behind the back!
(WHIMPERING LOUDLY)
GUARD: Stay down, Ben!
Back down, sailor!
(STUTTERING) I make minimum wage, please!
I'm nobody!
I don't wanna... Please! I don't wanna die!
I don't wanna die!
Shut your cocksucker
or I'll blow your head off.
(WHIMPERING)
Hey, I'll take care of this.
Tie him up.
(PANTING)
Calm down, calm down.
Take it easy.
Shh. Take it easy.
It's okay. Everything's
gonna be just fine.
I promise.
(WHIMPERING LESSENS)
What's your name?
(STAMMERING) Ben.
You got a girlfriend, Ben?
Mmm-hmm.
She loves you, right?
What's her name?
It's Hannah.
Tonight you're gonna be sitting
with your arm around Hannah,
watching this
on the 10:00 news.
She'll be so close, you'll
feel her breath on your neck.
And when she hears how nobody got
hurt today because of your cool head
she's gonna press her warm
hand against your cheek.
She's gonna look into your eyes
like there's no place else
she ever wants to look again.
Trust me, Ben.
It's gonna be a good night.
Thank... Thank you, Father.
On the floor.
Hands behind your back.
MELANDER:
Okay, let's get in.
That partner of yours better be right
about what's inside these tin cans.
Hurry up before
he drinks it all.
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT) You're right. We
should have left earlier. (CHUCKLING)
Hey. You look
beautiful, Claire.
I bet you say that
to all the girls.
You know you're the only one.
What about your partner?
Come on, your dad's
important to me.
I know it. I love
that you love him.
Hey, Dad!
Hurley!
...you think, and you'll...
Hey! Howard, excuse me a second.
Sure, sure.
There's my little girl.
Claire, who's this bum
you brought?
Hi, beautiful.
Hi, Daddy.
I'm going to find Jen.
Good. Go see her.
It's so good to see you, man.
You too, Hurley.
Okay. One down, one to go.
How's it look?
What do we got?
Full. Totally full.
(SQUARE DANCE MUSIC CONTINUES)
MELANDER:
Ching, ching, baby.
I got everything from a guy who's worked
this fair for the last eight years.
Blueprints,
everything you need.
They rake in a big haul
on Saturday and Sunday.
One, one-and-a-half million.
Not bad, huh?
PARKER: So you think
I need those guys.
HURLEY: Yeah.
It's a five-man job.
How do you know
this guy, Melander?
Melander and I worked together
out in Portland, 20 years back.
Always had a good crew.
Independent, like us.
I told him right off,
if you were in, it's your show.
You're in charge.
Number two, good to go.
(SQUARE DANCE MUSIC CONTINUES)
(ALL EXCLAIMING IN FEAR)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
(IN AMERICAN ACCENT) Let's go.
ROSS: What the fuck was that?
Just stay with the plan.
Move it.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(SIRENS BLARING)
It's total fucking
panic out here!
Here. (GRUNTS)
All right. Down on the floor.
Stay out of sight.
We're going out the back.
So, we all good?
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT) You were
supposed to torch the hay bales
behind the livestock pavilion,
away from the midway.
You know what? There was some
trouble, so I improvised.
Big fuckin' deal... Ahhh!
Someone gets hurt, cops come after us.
That's the big fucking deal!
Motherfucker!
I said behind the livestock pavilion.
(GROWLS)
Thirty seconds.
Come on!
I'm rolling! Right now!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CHUCKLES)
I gotta say, Parker,
you came as advertised.
So, I've decided to bring
you in on something else.
Something big.
Look, 200 grand each isn't
gonna make any of us rich.
But if we all kick in
our share as seed money
towards the next little piece
of business down the line,
we all end up
with two million. Each.
PARKER: We just took
a million bucks.
That's a hell of a lot of seed.
And that's just for the house.
I don't think so.
Look. Picture one
of those duffel bags,
only instead of
tens and twenties,
it's filled with
diamonds and pearls.
Jewelry's 10 cents
on the dollar. No, thanks.
No, not 10 cents.
I'm getting 20.
MELANDER: Parker,
two million each.
We've got someone
on the inside.
It's the score of a lifetime.
Guaranteed.
We made a deal. You said we'd split the take.
That's what we need to do.
Why don't you think about it?
Come on. Parker, hey.
We're talking millions.
Seriously.
(SIGHS)
Okay, Parker,
cards on the table.
I'm gonna need the whole
score for this next thing.
So, if you were me, what would
you do with a guy like you?
Divide up the shares
and that'd be the end of it.
What if you decided
not to do that?
I'd kill him while
I had the chance.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, shit.
(GRUNTING)
MELANDER: Watch it!
(TIRES SCREECHING) Whoa!
Grab him!
MELANDER: Shoot him!
HARDWICKE: Oh, my God!
Grab the gun!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Grab it!
(GRUNTS)
Ahhh! Shit!
Damn!
(MELANDER YELLS)
MELANDER: Stop him!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Oh! Son of a bitch!
My nose! He broke my nose!
Let me see, let me see!
(GROANING)
What kind of an idiot fires
a shotgun in a fucking car!
Shut up, Hardwicke!
CARLSON: Oh, my God!
Shut up!
CARLSON: I'm bleedin', man!
(WHIMPERS) Stop this blood.
Go finish him.
Wait, wait, wait.
Look. He's fucking dead.
Let's just get
the fuck out of here!
I don't give a fuck
who your uncle is!
Now, you wanna be a part of
this, you go finish him.
ROSS: You heard him,
Hardwicke! Go!
CARLSON: Go do it! Get
the fuck out of here!
CARLSON: God,
I gotta get out of here!
Handle your business!
CARLSON: Come on! I gotta go!
Do it!
Blow his fucking head off!
(GRUNTING)
Fuck. Fuck.
You got to fucking
bend sometimes, Parker!
You're so fucking stupid!
Do it!
Come on!
Good. Let's go, let's go!
I didn't get a good look at his
face, just that he was a priest.
So far as his build or that goes, I don't know.
I guess I'd say average.
INTERVIEWER: Did he
say anything to you?
Not really. Nope.
JAMES: That looks like
a man's shoe up there.
JAMES' WIFE:
That looks like blood.
BOY: Hey, Eddie!
Look at that!
James, stop! There's a man!
Boys, stay in the truck.
You think he's dead?
I don't know.
You boys hang back.
I'm going to check it.
Oh, sweet Jesus. Come on.
BOY: What do you
want us to do, Daddy?
He's alive.
BOY: Take him on the other side, here.
EDDIE: Okay.
JAMES: Get him over.
Come on, now.
Get him out. Let's go.
(ALL GRUNTING)
BOY: Wait, wait! Support him.
JAMES: How you all
doing, boys?
Look at my back?
Mmm-hmm.
Too many scars.
If you came into the ER
with this many holes,
we'd be prepping you
for the morgue.
That's why I stay away
from hospitals.
Stay still.
We're going to get you
to the hospital.
We gotcha.
(NEWSCAST PLAYING ON TV)
FEMALE NEWSCASTER: That's right.
Nicely done, Benjamin.
Well, a silver Suburban
used by the thieves
who struck the neighboring
Ohio State Fair on Monday
was found in a strip mall across
the state in Cincinnati, Ohio.
Now, the men made off with
approximately one million dollars
and are believed to have set a deadly
fire while making their escape.
A 51-year-old Sedalia
resident, Charles Stockton
was killed in that blaze
that injured six others.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Anyone with information is asked
to call Crime Stoppers...
(ON ELECTROLARYNX)
Don't get up.
You were shot.
I'll call the nurse.
Don't you call the nurse.
(PANTING)
Where am I?
Covington, Kentucky.
You know... Do you know
what happened to you?
They don't even know your name.
Hey. Hey.
Are you crazy?
ORDERLY: Good morning, ladies.
NURSES: Good morning.
ORDERLY: How are you today?
NURSE: Doing good.
Okay, Mr. Quinn!
Radiation's all set for you.
Help the man.
This man needs some help.
Okay, okay, no problem.
Let me get you set
and I'll check him out.
This man needs help.
Come on. Get up, get up. You
know the drill. Let's go.
Help the man.
Okay. We have to get to Radiation.
Needs some help.
Pick your feet up.
Calm down, calm down.
(STAMMERING)
(CHOKING)
Nurse!
Don't hurt him.
Please... Please don't.
Please don't hurt him.
Please.
Oh, my God.
Is he dead?
He's dead. You killed him.
PARKER: No.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Praise the Lord.
What's... What's going
to happen now?
Please don't hurt me. Please.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
SHERIFF: Ain't no wallet,
no ID on him.
OFFICER 1: You said he was
shot two times, though?
MAN: Yeah. Found at the side
of the road, left for dead.
OFFICER 2: How long
was he in surgery?
I need you in the chair
to hold up my weight.
Don't call attention to us and I'll let you
go as soon as we're outside, understand?
OFFICER 1:
Is he talking?
SHERIFF: No, I believe
he's still unconscious.
Yeah, a farmer found him.
We'll get you inside now.
(GRUNTING)
Hey. Feel better.
You too.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
ROSS: Blow
his fucking head off!
Do it!
HUNTER 1: I got it!
HUNTER 2:
Get your ass in the truck.
Ain't going to be no ducks left.
I'm about to leave you.
(SHOWER RUNNING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
PARKER: Mr. Norte,
I'm a friend of Bob Hurley's.
Yeah. Listen,
I need some documents.
Don't worry about the money.
I start a new job
in the morning.
(VAN BACKING UP)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
JACK: Don't cash your check when she's around.
DRIVER: Be back at 18:30.
All right, we'll see you later.
Do what I say
and you won't get hurt.
Mine's bigger than yours.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(GROANING)
It's not the size,
it's how you use it.
What the hell?
You got hurt because you didn't
do what I said. (GROANING)
Your bulletproof vest
doesn't cover your legs.
Next time
I'll take out your eye.
Who the fuck are you?
Do right, in a few minutes you're
on your way to the hospital.
They'll get you, you know.
Yeah.
So don't sweat it.
It's only money, you're insured,
and they'll get me. Get up.
Remember I got a gun on you.
What's your name?
Jack. People call me Jack.
Move it, Jack.
(GROANS)
What's your partner's name?
Oliver.
You say, "Oliver, I got shot. This
guy helped me." Nothing else.
(BANGING ON WINDOW)
I got shot. Thank God this
guy helped me. Jesus.
It's small but it hurts.
He knows we're wearing vests.
He'll shoot you in the face.
Can we get this over with so I
can go to a goddamn hospital?
Okay, Oliver. Help Jack
get into the other room.
I need cash.
You know they're
gonna get you for this.
Yeah, Jack already told me.
(MUFFLED SPEAKING)
Sorry about the leg, Jack.
You sit tight for five minutes,
I'm gonna call you an ambulance.
NORTE: Hey! Come on in, senor.
You made it in record time.
So you're Hurley's friend.
I'm glad you found us, Mr...
Well, step right this way.
You know, this was
my daddy's business.
We make most of our money
off the high schools.
You know, printing yearbooks, diplomas...
Stuff like that.
I need to be able to
buy a car, get a loan.
Name, birth certificate,
driver's license. Social.
Passport? Anything else?
Did you bring a picture?
No.
NORTE: Ernesto...
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Five days, my friend.
(BELL RINGING)
Come on through.
You're out. Go. Move.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
It's Parker.
Yeah?
PARKER: There was
a problem with the job.
I need you to do
two things for me.
Yeah. Name it.
First, let Claire know I'll be
gone longer than I thought.
All right. You got it.
Second, you know where I can get
a hold of that client, Melander?
What happened?
I invoiced, but I
wasn't able to collect.
Oh, Jesus, Parker.
Uh... Are you all right?
Where is he?
(SIGHING)
This is not a good idea.
After you didn't call
I did some checking.
It turns out that Melander is not
as independent as I thought.
He's got connections. Big connections.
We're talking Chicago.
Danzinger.
So don't start anything.
Hurley, it's me.
Give me a name.
Listen.
Hardwicke is a nephew
of Danzinger.
You understand?
Give me a name!
(SIGHING) Jesus Christ.
All right, here's what I got.
His brother, Bobby Hardwicke,
owns five bars
on Bourbon Street.
Plus a rock 'n' roll club.
Now, listen,
you be real careful.
These are bad guys.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(BAND PLAYING ROCK MUSIC)
(SINGING INDISTINCTLY)
BOUNCER: Trying to get in?
PATRON: Yeah.
BOUNCER: All right, go ahead.
I need to see Bobby Hardwicke.
Not going to happen.
Tell him
Mr. Danzinger sent me.
Wait here.
Idiot. Get out!
(GROANS)
I got 300 people down there and you're
telling me you only got 200 pays.
That means I got
100 fucking guests.
Who are these fucking guests?
Relax, Bobby... Now don't tell
me to relax, you understand?
What?
Bobby Hardwicke?
Out. Private.
I need you to tell me
where your brother is.
Get him the fuck out of here.
Come on, you heard...
(GRUNTS)
You son of a...
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Your brother went off on a job
with a man named Melander.
(WHEEZES) Do you know how
fucking connected I am, chief?
They took money
that belongs to me.
Tell me where they are
and I'll get out of your hair.
Do you have any concept
of the unholy shitstorm you're about
to unleash by fucking with me? Do you?
(GROANING)
First I should tell you,
when I say I'll do something,
I always follow through.
Always.
Ahhh! Fuck you!
If you don't tell me
what I need to know
I'm going to press down on this chair
until it crushes your trachea.
Trust me, it's agonizing.
Plus, there's the
posthumous humiliation
of having been killed
with a chair.
(GROANING)
Florida.
MAN: Joey? Joey?
Holy shit.
(BOBBY GROANING)
Where in Florida?
Palm Beach!
(COUGHING) Palm Beach,
for Christ's sake!
Bobby!
Jesus! You okay?
Fucking get him!
Get him!
(CONTINUES SINGING)
(VIBRATING)
CLAIRE: (ON VOICEMAIL)
Hi. You know what to do.
(BEEP)
Claire. Claire, I wish
you'd keep that thing on.
Look. Trouble might
find its way up there.
I think you'd better
talk to a travel agent.
Tomorrow.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(MUTTERING)
Yeah?
Hurley. Time for a vacation.
Yeah.
(ALARM CLOCK BEEPING)
RADIO ANNOUNCER: Here's your
Mighty 690 forecast, folks,
and let me tell you
Palm Beach weather,
it's just unbelievable this time of year.
(GROANING)
The temperature drops to 50
and everybody's wearing boots,
sweaters, and leather jackets.
Then, poof the next day it's 85
and we're back in flip-flops,
halter-tops, and board shorts.
There's nothing
between Sherry and...
Oh, God!
There will always
be something between
you and Sherry.
Always.
(GASPING) You're not
going to wear that skirt!
You know we can't
wear earth tones!
It's Tahari.
Oh. That's what's important.
Not your hips.
It's what they
expect me to wear, Ma.
They tell you what to wear, what to drive.
You can't afford it.
You know I'm not loaning
you any more money, right?
Can you open my pills?
My hands are bad.
I put them out.
At least take Pipsy out.
(WHIMPERING)
Leslie!
It's your dog.
And it's my house!
It's a condo, Ma.
ROSS: I put one of these
devices in each speaker.
When these babies go off,
all hell's gonna break loose.
Hey, just watch what
the fuck you're doing.
The beauty is, speakers
will still be able to work.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Trigger's very simple.
Hey, bro.
Nah. Hold on one sec.
CARLSON: Now, will you just shut
the fuck up and concentrate?
Are you sure?
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Bobby. I'm...
CARLSON: Look at this thing.
ROSS: Stop playing
with that thing.
(ROARING) Fuck!
What the hell was that?
What!
He's alive.
Who?
Parker. He knows we're here.
Oh.
He ambushed my brother.
He tried to kill him.
Parker's dead.
You got out of the SUV
and you shot him.
Right?
Yes.
I fucking shot him.
You...
(GRUNTS) I fucking...
He was dead when I fucking left him!
I swear to God!
We need five men for the gig.
We can get by with four.
It don't work with three.
Fuck!
(AUGUST CHOKING)
All right.
Okay.
You get with
your uncle in Chicago
and you have him handle this.
With a real professional.
Now.
That fucking Danzinger
better do something
for all the money he's going
to make on this haul.
(PANTING)
The Mafia doesn't
usually touch family,
but who knows with Danzinger.
I'm not taking any chances.
Jen should be packed.
I'll be back and get
you in 15 minutes.
Yeah.
Hey, don't worry.
He'll be fine.
Claire...
It happens.
Yeah. Not to me.
God. Dad, it never
happened to us.
Yeah, I know.
Times change.
I'm the one that should be jealous.
He called you first.
(DOOR OPENING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Lock these doors.
All of them.
I'll be back with your
stepmom in 10 minutes.
(SIGHS)
(TOOL CLINKING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(GASPS)
(DOOR BANGS SHUT)
(LADDER CLANGS)
(AIR HISSING)
(PANTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SOBBING)
Parker?
Did you get my message?
Yeah. Then my dad came by.
Two minutes after he left,
a strange man with a big
knife let himself in.
Was that... (SNIFFLES)
Was that a message, too?
Listen. Drive straight to the
fishing camp at Okeechobee.
No stops, no calls.
You'll be safe there. Gotta make
sure you're not being followed.
How long?
I'll be there Friday.
What if you're not?
Parker!
Empty the cash out of the
storage locker and disappear.
(SIGHS)
LESLIE: Look,
I'm one commission away.
I'll get it to you by
the end of the week. I swear.
No, you don't understand.
I need my car for work.
If you repossess my car,
I can't pay you.
Please, just... Just
give me another week.
Great. Thank you.
Next week at the latest.
(HANGS UP)
LESLIE: Hi. An Americano
with two Splendas, please.
BARISTA: We've got it
all ready for you, Leslie.
Oh, thanks for remembering.
Leslie Cienfuegos.
Rodgers.
Right.
How is the ex?
You hear from him?
Shouldn't you be
over in West Palm?
I like it here fine.
Like you do.
Hey, you have a cup
holder in your car?
Or you just keep that
between your legs?
Well, it's large
and black, Jake.
Where do you think I like it?
(CHUCKLING)
Yeah. We'll see who's laughing
next time you need a ticket fixed.
Jackass.
MAN: Don't fuck with us! Just
give us Parker and you're done!
Am I talking to you, boy? Am
I talking to you? Shut up!
MAN: Fuck you!
You know who we are?
You deliver or you're
gonna be dead like Parker.
NORTE: What are you talking about?
I don't know any Parker!
(NORTE AND ERNESTO
TALKING IN SPANISH)
Huh? Watch out!
Dissatisfied customers?
I don't have dissatisfied customers.
What I have is you.
And now I have this!
(SPEAKS SPANISH) Your gun.
Give me what I came
for and I'm gone.
You brought them here, now you get
down on the floor with them, boy!
We had a deal, Norte. I gave you
your money, now give me my papers.
Fuck your papers!
I don't need this bullshit!
Did they say
they were from Chicago?
We didn't say.
Shut up!
Get on the floor.
Did they mention
someone named Danzinger?
Look, I don't know anything.
All I know is,
I got a situation here.
You know who I think brought them here?
Ernesto. He sold you out.
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Get on the floor!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
All right. I'm done.
(GROANING)
Hey, look. We... We don't
have to kill each other.
These men wanted you. I don't
want any part of it anymore.
I'm like... Sweden.
You mean Switzerland.
(STUTTERING) Whatever.
Your documents are
in that middle drawer.
Right behind me. Right there.
Take them out.
(ERNESTO SWEARING IN SPANISH)
(ERNESTO GROANING)
Daniel Parmitt.
Ecuador
You're an American citizen.
Born in Ecuador. (STAMMERING)
There's lots of gringos down there.
Your family was
in the oil business.
Pick up the gun.
Now look here, there's
not very many people
that can do what I do
as well as I do.
If I get dead, a lot of people
are gonna be very upset
and they're gonna come get you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Everyone's gonna get me.
Pick it up.
(ERNESTO SPEAKING SPANISH)
Shoot them.
The other way we can do this is
I shoot 'em, then I shoot you.
I'm trying to help
you here, Norte.
Listen, pal, you can
still get out of this alive.
Why did you stop?
They're dead!
Then they won't feel it.
Keep going!
(GUN CLICKING)
Toss me the gun.
So now what?
You got a hold on me, right?
I don't need a hold over you.
Not if you make
all this disappear
and tell anyone who asks
I never showed up.
What do I say about them?
Maybe they died
on the way here.
Don't forget to take care
of their Navigator outside.
Ecuador
HURLEY: I just hate flying.
I hate it.
I mean, the goddamn
landing was terrifying.
It went up on one wheel. I thought
I was gonna die for a minute.
I mean, Jesus, Jen's already
at the lake with the damn dog.
What about Claire?
Taken care of.
I promise she's safe.
All right.
Okay, so, Danzinger must be the fence
to get 20 cents on the dollar.
That's why Hardwicke's around.
Yeah, I'd think so.
You know,
two million dollar share,
five ways, 20 cents
on the dollar... Hmm.
Fifty million dollar score.
Yeah. So wherein Palm Beach?
Oh, no, no.
Parker, I'm telling you, Bobby was lying.
Not Palm Beach.
Look, the problem is not the
score, the problem is Palm Beach.
Nobody does business there. There's
a cop to every eight residents.
Drawbridges.
They could shut the island down like that.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
You're trapped.
The state pen is full of
lightweights that have tried it.
You know Melander.
Is he a lightweight?
No, Melander's
not a lightweight.
But it doesn't matter.
Listen, I got a call
from Danzinger.
And for whatever the reason, they
want it to go down without a hitch
so they sent me this
to give to you.
(UNZIPPING)
This is your Ohio share
plus 10 points.
Take it.
Go somewhere with Claire.
Keep your money.
Who are you kidding, Hurley?
Chicago doesn't pay to keep
people out of their way.
For Christ's sake, Parker,
Danzinger's a fucking savage.
He sent an assassin to your home,
he almost killed my daughter.
I'm just trying to help you.
I don't want it from you.
I want it from them!
It's the principle.
Principle.
(SIGHING) You wanna get
yourself killed over principle?
And me? Claire?
Is that what the fuck you want?
You almost died
on a plane runway.
If it's gonna happen,
it'll happen.
It's not something
you can control.
When I enter
an agreement with someone,
terms on both sides
have to be honored.
If they're not,
and I allow that,
I'm asking chaos
to take control of my life.
Nobody likes chaos.
Yeah.
Yeah, no one likes chaos.
That's right.
Hey, look, what if...
(SIGHS)
What if you had a place in
Palm Beach to sit things out?
Nah, nah. Cops would be
all over the rentals.
Nah, not a rental.
What if you...
What if you bought a house?
Hmm.
Palm Partners,
how may I help you?
Hey, Noelle, any messages?
All right. I will transfer
you to Mr. Samson.
BONNIE: Why do you even
read the society pages?
It's not like you could ever
go to one of those parties.
Look, if a normal couple
gets divorced,
they need two houses
instead of one.
Rich couple gets divorced, they
need four houses instead of two.
BONNIE: I don't know
what you're worried about.
It took me two years
to get my first commission.
Even then, it's only
a quarter share.
Yeah, well, I would've had my first
if Jameson hadn't swooped in.
Morning, ladies.
LESLIE: If I don't sell
something soon, I'm screwed.
Amber picked up a cold call
from some rich-ass Texan
looking to buy
his third vacation home.
I've been answering the phone
for three weeks, and nothing.
They are great clients.
All cash.
What's Amber's line?
Twelve.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Yes.
AMBER: But I'm gonna close them.
Um... Excuse me one minute, sir.
Thank you.
No problem. Absolutely.
I'll let her know.
Mmm-hmm.
Hello? Hello?
Oh! That was Mr. Thompson. He said he
wants to close on Edgewater right away.
Said he's gonna be
flying in at noon.
Oh, his phone died while I
was on the phone with him.
If you want I can go take care
of that for you right away.
Oh! That's so sweet
of you. But no.
One, one, at a price of 1,000...
Noelle?
Excuse me one moment.
Call Mr. Parmitt
at the Boca Resort
and tell him that I'll call
him later to reschedule.
Of course.
Sorry about that.
Again, the price was $1,155.
And item 8-0-0-0
at a cost of $2,353.20.
I can't believe you
just stole her client.
There's nothing wrong with a little
(WHISPERING) stealing now and then.
They do it to us all the time.
Welcome to the Boca Resort.
Mr. Parmitt?
(IN TEXAN ACCENT) Miss Rodgers.
Yes.
LESLIE: Anybody who's
somebody, and rich,
(CHUCKLES)
winds up in Palm Beach.
I mean, more billionaires per
square foot than anywhere else.
Palm Beach is about style.
Community.
You know, it's...
It's not about money at all.
Of course not.
Where do you live now?
I got a place in Vail. One in
South Padre Island. One in Maine.
Yeah.
I'd like to see a few more areas
before zeroing in on one.
Do you have time tomorrow?
Sure, yeah. I have
all the time you need
to zero in
on anything you want.
I'll pick you up
at your office at 10:00.
I'll never remember my way
around unless I do the driving.
Taxi.
Can I drop you somewhere?
No, thanks.
I'm good.
Where to?
Lake Okeechobee, please.
Yes, sir. Take Highway
441 to Pelican Bay.
(INDISTINCT MUSIC PLAYING
ON HEADPHONES)
(BLOWING)
MAN: (IN TEXAN ACCENT)
Pardon me, ma'am.
Daniel Parmitt.
San Antonio, Texas.
(SQUEALING EXCITEDLY)
I thought we agreed,
no more scars. Hmm?
I don't want to lose you.
Mmm.
Hey.
I keep thinking about that
man inside our house.
I've been around thieves my
whole life, but this guy...
He was a killer.
He really scared me.
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT) They wouldn't
have killed you, Claire.
They'd use you to get to me.
Then killed us both.
You can leave, Claire.
No one would blame you.
This italianate villa was built three years ago.
It's only $17 million.
If it were older and one mile down
the beach, it'd be $35 million.
You like?
(IN TEXAN ACCENT)
Mmm-hmm.
You know, the furnishings are all
antique and they could be available
for, you know...
For the right price.
So, married?
Once. She passed away.
Oh. I'm sorry.
What about you?
What does your husband do?
Oh. Divorced.
Eleven months.
He was a salesman. He sold me.
The whole dream.
I thought he was something.
His Ferrari was rented.
At least it wasn't stolen.
Well, he declared bankruptcy
before the divorce
so I get to help him
pay off his debt
while he lives there in Key
West with his new girlfriend.
And I do mean "girl."
LESLIE: This one right over here,
this has been on the market
for about a year
for about $27.5,
but if you make an offer now you could
probably get it for about $19.5-ish.
It's a good price.
LESLIE: This is, obviously,
more of a neighborhood.
The one here, with the
screen of palm trees,
this house sold, about two
months ago, for $1.2 million.
Mr. Rodrigo says
he wants to renovate.
Can you believe it?
It's obviously a tear down.
Mr. Rodrigo?
Yeah. Amber sold it to him.
You know, I think he said
he's from Texas, too.
I'll have to meet him some day.
You know, the one nice thing about it
is the Intracoastal's right down here.
Wraps right around the houses.
It's really beautiful.
See what I mean? The
intracoastal widens out here.
So you lived in San
Antonio your whole life?
Yeah.
Since I was about three.
Tell the truth,
I was born in Ecuador.
My folks are both in the
oil business down there.
Ecuador? Really?
That's what it says
on my birth certificate.
(CONVERSING IN SPANISH)
I was in the management training
program here before I got married.
I could've got you a great discounted
room rate, say, 11 years ago. (LAUGHS)
You know, do you mind
if I hold on to these?
Fax a few to my banker so he knows
ahead of time what I'm getting into?
Yeah, sure. I mean,
they're all sold.
I just wind up
tossing them anyway.
Here. My card, too.
Mr. Parmitt? Uh... Daniel?
(CHUCKLES AWKWARDLY)
Um... I know that you're in
town alone, so, if you'd like,
we can go over more
places, say, over dinner
or just drinks?
That is so kind, but I'm
afraid I have other plans.
I'll be in touch.
Okay.
Plans.
(SIGHS)
(PIPSY BARKING)
Pipsy, stop.
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Leslie, put on
the soap channel.
Do we have to have the soap
opera channel always on?
I pay for it.
(SOFTLY) I pay every minute.
I heard that.
(SCOFFS SOFTLY)
I heard that, too.
(SIGHS)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(BEEPS)
(SIGHS)
See? This is the kind of outfit
you would look great in.
Ugh! Don't tell me.
It's Tuesday night.
I'm off to poker.
You're minding Pipsy.
Actually, Marta's still in the hospital.
Why don't you come?
We'll put Pipsy in the carrier.
The girls would
love to see you!
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
(DOOR OPENING AND CLOSING)
(SOBBING SOFTLY)
(DOG BARKING)
MELANDER: All right, let's
get it while it's hot.
HARDWICKE: Jesus Christ. I'm over this shit.
I'm sick of beans.
MELANDER:
We have to lay low.
HARDWICKE: What?
That's bullshit.
I don't understand what the big deal
is to go out and get two pizzas.
MELANDER: We'll go. But we call
it in, we go and we pick it up
and we bring it
back here to eat. Okay?
HARDWICKE: I'm getting cheese.
CARLSON: I'm getting
two pepperonis.
(GARAGE DOOR OPENING)
(UNZIPPING)
If he's in town,
we can't risk him
getting any of us alone.
We have to lay low...
My uncle sent his best guy
to take care of Parker.
Mr. Danzinger's going to be very
disappointed you haven't seen Parker.
Listen, my friend,
I keep telling you.
I don't know anybody
named Parker, all right?
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
Nice new carpet.
(GROANING)
(KNIFE SLICING)
(WHIRRING)
I love that shit.
Give me those pies.
(GARAGE DOOR WHIRRING)
(REMOTE CONTROL BEEPS)
(WHIRRING)
HARDWICKE: I ain't waiting
for you old guys.
CARLSON:
Get that pizza in there.
Don't worry about it, man.
I got the pepperoni.
(GARAGE DOOR WHIRRING)
If you're free, maybe we
can go for that drink now.
(IN TEXAN ACCENT)
Who knows you're here, Leslie?
If you want to go somewhere more
private, we can go to your hotel.
Or we can go to the office.
I have the keys.
You know, Mr. Crenshaw
usually keeps a nice bottle...
(GASPING) om
When I ask you a question,
you need to answer.
Ow! Ow! Ow!
You're hurting my neck!
Who knows you're here, Leslie?
No one, okay? No one!
Let's go to your office.
Fuck!
You know, everything you did in the
car today was almost right. Almost.
But I didn't buy it.
Is Daniel Parmitt
your real name?
Why wouldn't it be?
Because you're less
than two months old.
You have a bank account, an address
in Texas, and a driver's license.
You never owned or leased
a car before this one.
You never had a credit card
and you never had a mortgage.
You know, I've traveled a lot. My
family business pays for everything.
And the only house you showed any
interest in was the one back there.
Mr. Rodrigo's.
Really? It was back there?
Really.
You know, I looked into
Mr. Rodrigo, too.
He's only six months old.
Okay. Why are you parking
all the way over here?
We could've parked right
in front of the office.
There'd be no cars there
this time of night.
Let's go.
Unless you don't want
a chance of being seen.
Is that what's going on?
Wait a minute.
Keep moving.
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT)
Don't turn those on.
Ah. English accent.
I knew you weren't from Texas.
Look at that.
A nice Chablis.
Will you be joining me?
Okay, well, I'm thirsty.
Ugh! Yeah. I drink too much.
And I worry too much.
Divorced, pushing 40.
I have a sister I haven't
spoken to in five years.
And I'm stuck with my mom.
Doesn't look like she's going
to kick off any time soon.
I'm sick of chauffeuring
these fucking entitled
wannabe playboys who have never
worked a day in their life.
Showing them houses
that I could never afford.
Laughing at their jokes
that I can't stand.
All while fending off
their gropes...
But not all their gropes.
Because you never know.
One of these days I just
might get a full commission.
So if you're going
to kill me, go ahead.
I live with a snapshot
of my future
and nobody's going to know
and nobody's going to care.
But if you're not,
I can help you.
Help me?
People in Palm Beach
are sharp. Very sharp.
And people like you only come
down here for one reason, money.
And I don't know
what you're into...
Kidnapping,
extortion, robbery...
But whatever it is, you're gonna need
somebody who knows the territory
or you're gonna get caught.
Take off your clothes.
What?
I'm not sure if I'm better
off with you alive or dead.
Either way, I have to know
if you're wearing a wire.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Look, I've been in a third
of the houses around here
and I know the rest.
I can answer your questions
and I can tell you what questions
you're forgetting to ask.
And all I'm asking
is for you to give me
a small piece
so I can get
the hell out of here.
Turn around.
What?
Turn around!
(SIGHS)
You know, to even find Rodrigo,
you had to play that
roundabout game with me
and all it did was
make me suspicious.
I mean, how many people do you
want asking questions about you?
Lift your hair.
Get dressed.
Wash up the wine glasses.
Lock up before you leave.
I'll think about it.
(CHUCKLES)
MELANDER: Hey, Lionel!
What do you say? I got
something for your jones.
Don't blow it all
on the ponies again.
Tell me what you got. I want
to know every last detail.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Leslie! Okay, last chance.
All this right here could
be yours for one low price.
Hey. What's the matter?
Nothing. Just...
I bought a lottery ticket
two days ago.
I don't think
it's going to pay off.
Leslie, what'd you do that for?
Those things are a waste.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello? Mr. Parmitt?
Yeah, I have the perfect
condo that I could show you!
I'll meet you at 1000 Ocean
Avenue in 20 minutes.
Yes!
(LESLIE GIGGLING)
DISPATCH ER: Signal four,
rollover with injuries
at 124 North County Road.
Code one.
Right on time.
You can park right there.
DISPATCHER:
Bravo 24, please respond.
So, I'm hired?
You don't have to check me
for a wire again, do you?
I mean, you can if you want.
We got work to do, Leslie.
You're hard to read.
Not really. Let's just
stick to business.
Here's the deal.
Don't ask me any questions
because I'm only going to tell
you what I want to tell you.
The man who calls himself
Rodrigo took something from me.
He's in business
with three other men.
They're here for a robbery
and they're gonna use that house
to lay low when they're done.
So...
You let them steal something,
you steal it from them.
I help you
and I get a commission.
You're going to
kill them, aren't you?
I never said that,
Leslie. You did.
Civilized people
need to follow rules.
I'm just going to
put things right.
Where are they going to hit?
I thought that was something
you could tell me.
You don't know?
(CHUCKLES) Well,
when are they doing it?
I don't know that either.
But it's jewelry.
None of the stores I've
checked have the inventory.
How large?
Fifty to
seventy-five million.
Mrs. Clendon's jewels?
Are you fucking kidding me?
(STAMMERS) Forget it!
They are going to
get caught, or killed
and so are you if you're
anywhere near them!
Leslie! You can't leave.
(CHUCKLES) You're in.
LESLIE: Miriam Hope Clendon was the
first lady of Palm Beach Society.
She had more diamonds
than Elizabeth Taylor!
And when she died, she left the
entire estate to Palm Beach.
They're auctioning off her $75
million jewelry collection
right here tomorrow night.
What's behind there?
Thirty acres,
a golf course, pool,
tennis courts, two ballrooms,
and it's one of the only houses that's
on the ocean and the intracoastal.
Hey, Miss! This is
private property!
Oh! Sorry, guys.
Just taking in the sights.
No, no, no. That's too much white.
Take them away and bring
back some pink roses.
And just what is this now?
Speakers for the auctioneer.
Small ballroom.
Around to the right.
Okay, Linda, you cover the
left side, Robert, the right.
Report all paddle numbers to Barry,
who will be standing next to me.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Where do you want these?
Put speakers in the corners.
Uh, Barry, excuse me
a minute, would you?
(WHISPERS) Go get the gear.
I'll meet you by the basement.
Mmm-hmm.
Stash that shit by the exit.
MELANDER: Hurry up!
LESLIE: So, you been in jail?
(CHUCKLES)
Do you ever feel bad
about what you do?
Everyone steals, Leslie.
Some people admit it to themselves, some don't.
It's what human beings do.
That's why we invented locks.
You think the people
in these houses feel bad?
Their grandparents and their
great grandparents,
they're the ones
who got their hands dirty.
I just mean,
how do you sleep at night?
I don't drink coffee
after 7:00.
Is this the back entrance?
Yes.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
There's a taxi stand
at the Breakers.
What's going on?
Out.
Out!
(SIGHS)
Wait a minute. Can't you, like...
What's the plan?
What do I wear? Do I wear black?
What are we doing?
Go to your office.
I'll handle this.
This is getting old,
you know! (SIGHS)
Welcome back to the
Boca, Mr. Parmitt.
Keep it handy, Carlos.
(SIGHS)
(GASPS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
(SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
(KROLL YELLS)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
(THUDS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(PIPSY BARKING)
ASCENSION: Leslie,
someone's at the door.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(PIPSY BARKING)
ASCENSION: Leslie,
someone's at the door.
Jake.
Leslie.
Mind if I come in?
Yeah, I do mind.
What time is it?
I mean, how the hell
did you get my address?
It's sort of official.
ASCENSION: Don't let him in!
At least make your dog shut up!
Can you do that?
Yeah, what's going on?
It's about a man
named Daniel Parmitt.
Oh, I don't know even
how to use this thing.
That's why I always get coffee.
What...
What about Mr. Parmitt?
Do you know him?
Yeah, he's in town from Texas.
I, uh, I showed him
some places,
and he turned out to
be a real time-waster.
I happened to be driving
past Sloan's Curve yesterday,
and I saw you
talking to someone.
Yep, that was him.
I showed him a condo.
You think you can get the other list
of all the places you showed him?
Sure. I'd have to get
it from the office.
Why?
Well, if there's a vacant
place that he knows about...
(WHIMPERING) He may
just get it in his head
to make himself at home
for a while.
Shoot. Can you please
get that for me?
Oh, damn dog.
Always tracking in God-knows-what
from who knows freaking where.
(PANTING)
And, he got into an altercation in his
room with a fellow. The fellow went over
the balcony and he's dead now.
We haven't been able
to ID the victim.
That's crazy.
(EXHALES)
What about Mr. Parmitt?
We assume Mr. Parmitt
was hurt pretty bad.
He ran out of the hotel, stole a car.
No one's seen him since.
Well, I guess I can kiss
that commission goodbye.
They found your business
card in his room.
We don't know what he was into,
but I just wanted to
give you the heads-up.
LESLIE: You know, if you come by the office
later, I could give you his application,
and anything else
you need, okay?
(SIGHS)
You know, makes you realize how
dangerous this business
can be for a woman.
I mean, I was in places
all alone with him.
I mean, he could've killed me.
That's why it might be good if you started
thinking about not being alone anymore.
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Sorry to wake you up.
No, it's okay.
Thanks again.
(GASPS)
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! Mi Dio! I can't
believe he's not barking!
Yeah, dogs like me.
What do you need?
Do I need to get you towels?
Oh, my God.
There's so much blood! What do you
do when there's so much blood?
Do you wash it? Do you not wash it?
I need you to listen...
Do we put pressure on it?
What do we do? Leslie!
Leslie, listen to me! Do we get a towel?
Do we get a... What?
Listen. Get dressed, get in your car,
find a pay phone, and call this number.
Okay, okay, I can do that.
Might not be an answer
but maybe.
Then go straight to work.
What?
Yes.
I can't leave you here! We
have to get you to a hospital!
You could die by the time I get back!
Leslie!
(YELPS)
Leslie! Go.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
(WHIMPERING)
So, Pipsy, you like this one?
Can you make soup?
Como no!
Hi, um, my name
is Leslie Rodgers.
Uh, Daniel Parmitt
asked me to call.
Yes.
Well, why don't you go ahead
and take a look at both places
again before you make
your final decision.
Yeah, I could be there
in half hour.
Okay. Bye.
Oh, my God!
MAN: Is that a...
That's a person!
WOMAN: Oh, my gosh!
MAN: Oh, no!
WOMAN: Did you see that?
Oh, that's so terrible.
WOMAN: Call 911!
(CHUCKLES)
AMBER: You ladies
have a great day!
I thought that guy sounded like trouble.
I mean, Ecuador?
Yeah. Just my luck.
Are you okay?
I'm going out.
If anyone from the police
comes, just give 'em the list
of places I showed
Mr. Parmitt, okay?
What's the matter? Nothing. I just...
I just need some air.
(GASPS)
I was afraid you were the cops.
What's going on?
Are you a nurse?
I'm Claire.
Leslie.
Hi.
I named her after Leslie on
The Young and the Restless.
Mom.
Her sister's named after
Jennifer in Valley of the Dolls.
They don't care, Ma!
(CHUCKLES) I used to have a beauty
salon, and the TV was on all day.
I told you to go back to work.
I was, I did,
I was... I left.
I thought I was calling somebody
to take you to the hospital.
I can't do that, Leslie. I
have something to do tonight.
Are you crazy?
You almost died!
Wait. Well, you have a...
A mangled hand, a broken rib!
Four this time.
This is a real man.
You're in no shape
to do anything!
You... You can
barely even sit up!
Would you tell him, please!
I can't stop him.
He is who he is.
Okay...
All set.
Do you want me to call a
taxi or leave my car?
I'll find a car.
You're good at that.
Claire...
I didn't think you'd stay.
I know.
PARKER: Will you wait
for me at the fish camp?
CLAIRE: You know I Will.
Um, Ascension, I've left a bag with his
clothes and some amoxicillin in it.
Thank you.
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Thank you so much for taking
such good care of him.
ASCENSION: Oh, please,
it was nothing.
ASCENSION: Please, please.
CLAIRE: Thank you. Bye.
Come back to see me.
Bye.
Sopa de pollo.
That cop,
he's watching you.
Go back to work. When you
come back, I'll be gone.
(SCOFFS)
ROSS: All right. Everyone gets
a weapon and two extra clips.
MELANDER: Carlson, you better be
damn sure that firehouse is empty.
CARLSON: Relax.
It's closed for renovation.
ROSS: Hardwicke, I'm
giving you my best .45.
MELANDER: Let's go!
(TIRES SCREECH)
(SIGHS)
CARLSON: No one's gonna
believe you're a fireman.
Even volunteers cut
their fucking hair.
Now put your hood on before your jacket.
Show some discipline!
Hey, he looks fine.
I'm more worried about Hardwicke
getting on that goddamn boat.
Let's go! Come on!
(SIGHS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
DISPATCHER: Battalion 2 Division,
1-Rescue-33,
stand by for additional
instructions...
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
MAN 1: It's going
to start at 12 million.
WOMAN 1: It's mine. (LAUGHS)
WOMAN 2: Oh, Mother!
WOMAN 1: What?
WOMAN 2: They'd look much better on me.
(LAUGHS)
These are too small.
That's sensational.
WOMAN 3: It's beautiful!
MAN 2: It's quite...
MRS. FRITZ: If you would all please
take your seats, we'll begin.
We're here tonight to celebrate
my very dear friend...
Miriam Hope Glendon.
Let me introduce our celebrity
auctioneer, Lionel Flemming.
(CROWD APPLAUDS)
Hello and welcome.
We're here tonight
to pay tribute
to one of the great daughters
of Palm Beach society...
Miriam Hope Glendon.
Her kind works
and noble spirit...
(ALL GASP)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
MAN: Come on.
(ALL COUGHING)
(CELL PHONE RINGS) Talk to me.
Good to go.
We're on.
Let's go.
(SIREN WAILING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
POLICEMAN 1: Keep moving!
Let's go! Come on!
(SIREN WAILING)
MELANDER: Clear out!
All right, everybody, move!
Move away from the building!
There's tens of millions of
dollars worth of jewels in there!
We'll handle this, sir!
Officer! Get everyone
away from the door!
Building's empty!
Do not let anybody in!
MELANDER: These fumes
are toxic!
You!
Yes, sir?
I want you to form a perimeter
around this building.
Nobody gets in here
but my guys! Move!
Cleared out. Lock these doors.
Locking it up!
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Hey!
All right.
(ENGINE REVVING)
MELANDER:
Hardwicke's on his way.
Time to go!
Let's go!
Right behind you!
We got two minutes
to get underwater!
Come on.
Let's go!
(SIREN WAILING)
(ON PA) This is the
Palm Beach County Sheriff.
You have entered
a restricted area.
Please move away at once.
POLICEMAN 1: What the hell is he doing?
Does he realize...
Sir, there's smoke in the building.
Is there a fire?
Yes, there is a fire. The fire department's there.
They're taking care of it.
POLICEMAN 2: Hey,
what's going on?
POLICEMAN 3: Go on
the east side.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(SIREN WAILING)
Excuse me.
Guys, the West Palm
Beach department...
West Palm?
How did they beat us here?
Well, they're already in there!
See anything?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
POLICEMAN 1: Everybody out of the building?
All the guests, out!
POLICEMAN 2: I told you once,
I need you to leave this
area right now,
or I will impound...
FIREMAN 1: Break the glass.
FIREMAN 2: Stand back and let us do our job.
Two more fire trucks
just showed up.
Hey, look at this dickhead!
(POLICEMEN LAUGHING)
POLICEMAN 2: I'm not going to tell you again.
You need to leave the area.
Do you understand me?
Um, sorry, sir. Sorry about that.
Thank you.
Have a good night, man.
POLICEMAN 2: Be safe.
(COUGHING)
Hey, Cap, got
a West Palm helmet.
I got another one. Put them
down, that's evidence.
This is a robbery.
No, God.
Oh, my God!
DISPATCHER ON RADIO: One-nine-five.
Prepare to lock down the island.
Secure the bridges, get units on both
sides of the island, set up a perimeter.
Marine units, intracoastal
and beachside.
Eagles One and Two, get visual of the bridges.
K-9, you're going to track from...
PILOT 1: Eagle One in
position at North Bridge.
I have visual of all three
bridges in "Up" position.
MAN: What's going on?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
PILOT 2: Eagle Two checking pleasure
boat moorings on the Intracoastal.
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
(GRUNTING)
PILOT 1: Eagle One.
I see an outlet.
We need units to Worth Avenue
and South County Road.
Driver's license,
ma'am, please.
Uh, is this your
current address?
It's really happening.
Damn it! I'm not going
to let you fuck this up!
Fuck.
(SPITS)
ROSS: We did it!
(ALL LAUGHING)
ROSS: Did you see the look
on those rich bitches' faces?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yeah! They were freaked!
Tell me about it.
MELANDER: Keep it down till we get inside.
ROSS: They shit their Depends!
MELANDER: No, she was just
looking at your puss.
(ALL CHEERING) CARLSON: You
saw the way they waved us in?
MELANDER: Plan a job right...
ROSS: Whoo! Beautiful!
Smooth as a baby's ass!
Firemen are heroes, baby.
The public loves us.
The public loves us!
(CARLSON LAUGHING)
ROSS: Hey, man, who wants a beer? Time to celebrate.
MELANDER: All right,
let's check it out.
All right.
What you got?
CARLSON: See what we got, baby.
Let's see what we got! Yeah!
ROSS: Wait just
a goddamn minute!
I want to see that ice.
Whoo!
MELANDER: Yes, yes! ROSS: Oh, lookit.
Yeah, bubba.
Give me one of those.
CARLSON: Yeah, beer.
ROSS: Beer and jewels, baby.
CARLSON: What you got, Ross?
MELANDER: Yeah, what you got?
Let me see.
Check it out.
Look at that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Whoo!
ROSS: Mama, we are rich! Whoo!
MELANDER: Beautiful.
(GASPS) Who the fuck are you?
Who the fuck are you?
I'm an, uh, real estate agent!
My name is Leslie Rodgers!
I just came by to see
if the house is still vacant!
Get inside. Get inside!
Get the fuck inside.
Hey, guys!
LESLIE: Ahhh!
Look what I found!
Can someone tell me
who the fuck is she?
ROSS: Where did she come
from, Hardwicke?
Why the hell did you
bring her in here?
She was peeking through the fucking window!
No, I was checking to see...
...if the house was still empty!
Sit down! Sit!
CARLSON: Calm down, calm down, everybody.
Calm down. Shut up!
You can call my boss...
Shut up!
Know what I'm thinking?
What?
Parker.
ROSS: Oh, no.
Whoa!
It's not fucking Parker!
You're being paranoid again!
He sent her in!
He's out there somewhere!
I don't know anybody
named Parker!
Shut your fucking hole! Shut up!
ROSS: Parker's gotta
be hurting bad.
He leaked a whole gallon
of blood up in that hotel.
The news said he
could barely walk.
That motherfucker's
a rock, man.
Oh, my God, oh, my God.
That nine-life son
of a fucking bitch!
(GRUNTS) Move!
Where is he?
No! (SHRIEKS)
Where the fuck is he?
Tell me where he is, or I'll
shoot you in the fucking face!
(SOBBING)
I don't know! I swear!
Let go of me!
Do you want every cop
in the world here?
MELANDER: Huh?
HARDWICKE: All right.
Huh?
All right.
All right, get the fuck off me!
(WHIMPERS)
You're all right. Here, let me help you.
(LESLIE SOBBING)
You're all right. Come on,
now, gonna sit down and talk.
It's okay.
Now, listen to me.
You don't want to die, do you?
Do you?
No.
Then tell me where he is.
I don't know.
(GASPS)
Check the house.
Every inch!
You know who those belong to?
(STAMMERS) No.
I don't have any idea.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah, you do.
(GUSHING)
(TURNS OFF FAUCET)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
What's your connection
with Parker?
Are you fucking him?
What?
You want to hit me now?
Go ahead. You first.
Then it's my turn.
(PANTING)
Hey, it's clear on this side.
HARDWICKE: He isn't on
this side either.
Where's Ro...
Ross?
Aw, fuck!
AW, shit.
Go check it out.
Me? No fucking way am I...
Check!
Fuck!
Get the fucking gun
out of my face!
Stop pointing the fucking gun at me!
I'm fucking going.
Jesus fucking Christ!
If she moves, shoot her!
Why don't we just unbutton this
fucking button right here?
Yeah. (INHALES SHARPLY)
Whoa.
Let me see what you got.
(SPITS)
On! Bitch!
I'm going to fuck you,
and then you die!
In your dreams,
you fat ugly fuck!
Fuck you, motherfuck...
Shut the fuck up!
Shut your hole
and pay attention!
(GASPS)
MELANDER: God damn it!
Ross!
Parker, we've got the girl!
You better come out,
unless you want
to see her dead!
MELANDER: Parker?
What the fuck are you doing?
(CLICKS)
You bitch!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You're fucking dead!
(CLICKS)
(SOBBING)
(BOTH STRAINING)
Ahhh!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
Parker!
You touch me and Danzinger
will hunt you down!
He won't rest
until you're dead!
Listen to me!
We can split this up.
We'll use my connections.
(PANTING)
Do not make me
fucking kill her!
Oh, my God!
You understand?
Go ahead.
I will shoot her! Shut the fuck up!
No! Don't let him kill me!
I will shoot her
in the fucking head!
Don't let him kill me!
Go ahead.
(SHRIEKS)
(SCREAMS)
(CLICKS)
(GASPS)
(SHRIEKS)
Fuck! Let me...
Let me explain.
You were supposed to torch the hay
bales behind the livestock pavilion.
(LESLIE SCREAMS)
(LESLIE SOBBING)
Come on!
Wait. Not so fast.
You shouldn't have come here.
I thought you might need help.
(GRUNTS)
And what happened? Did you know
that guy's gun wouldn't go off?
When I broke in the night
you followed me...
I bent the firing pins
on most of their weapons.
Most of them?
(GASPS)
Here's what's gonna happen.
(GRUNTS)
Take the jewels to your office...
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
Find an AC vent, open it,
and stuff 'em in.
Put the grating back on
and forget about it.
But... You don't tell your mother
and you don't check on them
to make sure
they're still there.
In about three months, I'll send
someone in to get them from you.
Might take a long time to
fence, but after that's done,
you'll receive your share
by express mail.
(BREATH ES HEAVILY)
You can't put that money
in a bank, Leslie.
(CHUCKLES)
You can't go on
a crazy shopping spree.
Okay.
But...
How much will it...
I get the first two hundred thousand.
My original share.
The next two hundred thousand, goes to
my old partner who planned the job.
Then we split the rest.
How much?
With the right buyer,
your share will be millions.
Mmm.
(CHUCKLES)
(GROANS)
Oh, sorry! I'm sorry.
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry. Oh!
What? Wait, wait, wait!
Where are you going?
I'm going to lie low for a week
or so until things calm down.
I'll have someone
drive in and get me.
Claire?
I never did
have a chance, did I?
PARKER: Danzinger?
Yeah.
Who the hell are you?
Parker.
All right.
I was going to give them 20 cents on the dollar.
I'll give you 40.
It's not about money.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
(PIPSY BARKING)
ASCENSION: Leslie!
I got it.
Morning.
Sign, please.
It's heavy.
Okay.
Ooh...
(GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
Oh, my...
ASCENSION:
Leslie, who was that?
It's the mailman!
Nothing but bills!
(CHUCKLES)
(SQUEALS HAPPILY)
(LAUGHING)
We have received
bounties from heaven.
Like a new house, plenty of
money to pay off all our debts.
You know, I believe that man that we
found on the side of the road that day,
he wasn't no man at all.
He was an angel,
sent here to test us.