!![A Life Of ///usion playing]
[alarm buzzing]
[grunts]
[grunting]
Hey, Andy!
What`s up, dude'
Hey, Joe. Hey, Sara.
How you doing'
When you going to
get a car'
Hey, why don`t you
I can`t afford it.
[laughing]
So, Survivortomorrow night.
We on'
See you then.
I`ll bring a soda.
Hey, enjoy your orange.
okay, take care.
See you. Bye-bye.
That guy needs to get laid.
Tell me something
I don`t know.
[chuckles]
Good morning.
Excuse me. Pardon me.
Sorry.
[car horn blaring]
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Hey.
Good morning, Paula.
Andy.
Excuse me.
I have a question.
What is the difference between
Hi8 and Digital video tapes'
I`m not a salesman,
so, I could probably--
Welcome to Smart Tech.
How can I be of service
to you'
Well, I was just
wondering...
what is the difference
between these'
(Jay)
Well, if l`m photographing
someone as fine as yourself...
I`d probably go Digital.
! Hey, don`t worry
/`ve been /ied to!!
My God.
Sorry l`m late, man.
No problem.
oh, man.
I had a weekend.
Yeah'
We went to Tijuana, Mexico,
you know...
and we thought
it would be fun, you know,
to go to this show.
Everyone`s, ``You gotta
check out one of these shows.``
And, you know,
it`s a woman fucking a horse.
We get there,
and, you know, we think
it`s gonna be awesome...
and it is not as cool
as it sounds like
it would be, man.
It`s kind of gross.
Yeah.
You think,
``A woman fucking a horse``...
and you get there
and it`s...
a woman fucking a horse.
Yeah.
It was really
giving it to her.
And you know what...
to be honest, I felt
bad for her. We all
just felt bad for her.
Yeah.
Kind of felt bad
for the horse.
Wow, that`s something.
So what did you get up to'
You know, I just kind
of hung out. I was....
God, Friday,
when I went home...
I really wanted
an egg-salad sandwich.
And I was just obsessing
about it and I was like:.
``Man, l`m gonna
make one of those.``
So Saturday I went out
and I got, like,
a dozen eggs...
and I boiled them all
and then I just...
I spent, I don`t know,
probably three hours...
Iike, three-and-a-half hours
making...
you know, the mayonnaise
and the onions and paprika...
and, you know,
all the accoutrement.
And then, by the time
I was done...
I just really didn`t feel
like eating it.
I can imagine.
And I didn`t have any bread.
So, you know,
it was pretty good.
It was a good weekend.
Sounds pretty awesome.
Yeah, it was fine.
Sounds really fun.
Cool.
Cool, cool.
Hey, Paula.
Yeah.
I gotta tell you something.
I`m really excited about it.
For the first time today,
I woke up...
I came to the store,
and I feel confident
to say to you...
that if you don`t take
this Michael McDonald DVD...
that you`ve been playing
for two years straight, off...
I`m going to kill everyone
in the store...
and put a bullet
in my brain.
David, what do you suggest
we play'
I don`t care. Anything.
I would rather watch
Beautician and the Beast.
I would rather listen
to Fran Drescher
for eight hours...
than have to listen
to Michael McDonald.
Nothing against him,
but if I hear Yah Mo B There
one more time...
I`m gonna yah mo
burn this place
to the ground.
You`re such a smart ass.
Get back on the floor.
[garbled]
Fuck you.
[clears throat]
This is a great TV.
Nothing beats a plasma.
What are you doing'
That`s my customer.
It certainly is not.
When I came upon her,
she was unattended.
No, that`s my--
Wait.
Go to the checkout there.
Pick up there, please.
She was unattended
because I went to the back...
to get the brochure
that she requested.
I apologize,
but it`s too late.
The transaction
has been completed.
Then you`re gonna give me
half the commission.
You`ll receive
none of the commission.
I need to talk to Paula.
This is crazy.
This is bullshit.
Every time I make a sale,
you go crying to Paula.
How about Jesse Jackson'
old Jesse needs a cause.
Sick of you poaching
my customers.
I`m sick of your
crybaby bullshit.
You wanna take this
shit outside' Just take it
outside and squash it'
Let`s stay inside,
so everybody can see
what a pussy you have, okay'
Because when I remove
the blade I keep in my boot
from its sheath...
I can`t return it
until it has spilled blood.
Look, listen to me.
You are fucking
with the wrong nigger.
Hey! You`re fucking with
the wrong sun-nigger, okay'
Dude, I will hang your old ass
by your turban.
Turban now' Do you see
any fucking turban here'
Do I talk like a turban guy'
Do I say, ``Hey, Jay,
do you want a Slurpee'
You want a Slurpee'``
Fuck you, okay'
I was born in Brooklyn.
Brooklyn, okay'
My accent is a fucking
Brooklyn accent, okay' okay'
All right, man.
Calm down, dude.
Look, you still covering
my shift on Friday or what'
If I can keep this commission,
with pleasure.
Cool, then. All right, pop.
No problem.
How about Andy'
No.
Come on, man.
We need, what,
five guys...
to play a decent
poker game, right'
Yeah.
If we cancel this,
l`m gonna have to go...
to some stupid-ass
birthday party with Jill...
and that shit
ain`t happening.
No.
(David)
Why not'
He`s a really nice guy and all
but l`m pretty sure that...
he is a serial murderer.
Who cares, man'
He`s a nice guy.
I just wanna get drunk,
fucked up,
and play some cards.
That`s great.
Look, I don`t wanna
end up a lampshade...
in some creepy apartment,
that`s what l`m saying.
I don`t really see
any other options.
Andy. My man.
You got any plans
later on tonight'
Why, do we have to unload
the Sony truck'
No, the guys
are getting together,
we`re playing some poker...
thought, you know,
you`d wanna play.
With you guys'
Yeah, sure.
That would be cool.
You know how to play, right'
Yeah, I play online sometimes.
We`re gonna play
in the store.
Great.
Are we allowed
to do that'
Absolutely not.
Yeah.
oh.
Well, so l`m gonna
go tell Paula.
I`m just kidding.
I`m kidding.
That sounds great. Cool,
l`ll see you guys tonight.
okay.
All right.
[clattering]
oops.
I almost feel guilty.
No, you don`t.
Going down!
Dumbass.
And a full house.
oh, my dukes!
What'
How much fucking online poker
do you play, dawg'
For like an hour or two
a night, when l`m not
playing Halo.
Why did you invite this guy'
He`s a fucking ringer, man.
This is hog shit.
You, you`re a fucking asshole
to tell me to come here.
You tell me he was a nice guy,
didn`t you'
Well, fuck you people,
and fuck you, you and you...
fuck and kiss my big brown
fucking ass, okay'
(Jay)
l`m gonna see you tomorrow.
Peace.
All right, man.
(Mooj)
Fuck a goat.
[all laughing]
Good night.
I love that guy.
Dude, you totally....
oh, shit, I gotta go. Damn.
About to go see Ellen
in a little bit.
Going now'
Late-night action, huh'
Dude, you know
how it goes.
Does your girlfriend know
about all these
late-night visits'
It`s like an unspoken
agreement. Yeah.
It`s like a completely
and utterly unspoken
agreement.
If you knew her, if you knew
who I was dealing with...
you wouldn`t be
saying this shit.
There`s nothing you can`t do
with this woman...
straight up and down.
I`ve done
every single thing...
I could possibly create.
I`ve literally lubed up...
and made love to the arches
of her feet. All right.
Wow!
(Jay)
Yeah.
Foot fuck!
That`s sick, man.
Wow.
That is not sick.
I will give you sick.
oh, shit.
I was sleeping with a woman
recently, she had the....
Her tits were unbelievable.
oh, man, I love titties.
And so we`re doing it
and l`m about to finish...
and her dog starts
licking my ass.
I swear to God, I have
to decide, do I finish
or do I stop the dog'
I know your nasty ass.
He finished.
I finished.
And then I stole the dog.
No, I didn`t, but....
You know, sometimes,
Amy and I would make love...
till it was almost like
we weren`t two people...
but we were two spirits
or something.
our souls were
connected in this way,
I can`t describe it.
Time stood still.
It was like we were
sharing the same heart.
Stop, man! Why do you
always come and kill the vibe
with those things'
``Sharing the same heart,``
that`s like some...
Britney Spears shit, man.
This is three grown ass men,
don`t nobody want to hear
that shit.
Yeah, man, come on,
nobody wants to
hear that shit.
Thank you, Andy.
Dude, you broke up
two years ago.
You get over it
at some point.
Two years, man.
You need to get past that...
because no ass
is worth thinking
that much about...
I always say.
Andy, do me a favor.
Would you please help him
redeem himself by telling
a real sex story'
Yes.
I don`t.... You know what,
l`m a gentleman
and I don`t....
I don`t kiss and tell.
Fuck it, I raise you.
Nastiest shit
you`ve ever done.
I`m talking about nasty.
Wow.
So many stories
are running through
my head right now.
I dated this girl...
for a while, and she was
really a nasty freak.
She just loved to get down
with sex all the time.
She was like, any time of day,
she was like:.
``Yeah, let`s go.
I`m so nasty.``
And l`d be nailing her.
oh, shit.
She`d be like:.
``oh, you`re nailing me. Cool.``
She talk dirty to you'
She loved to dirty-talk.
Totally into it.
She`d be like:.
``Yeah, let`s screw, let`s....
I wanna fuck.``
God, it was so dirty.
She`d be like, ``Me so horny,
me love you long time.``
So....
(Jay)
So what were the titties like'
Yeah, describe her....
Yeah, she had great tits.
No, I mean, like, detailed.
Did she have, like,
you know...
them little pink
teeny nipples.
oh, yeah.
(Jay)
or like the long
Nationa/ Geographic nipples.
You have like
the bumpy Braille nipples,
the Stevie Wonders.
(Andy)
Yeah, they were nice.
You know, when you, like,
you grab a woman`s breast
and it`s....
And you feel it and...
it feels like a bag of sand
when you`re touching it.
Bag of sand'
You know what I mean.
Why don`t we just play'
Why don`t you just
deal the cards'
What are you
talking about'
Have you ever felt
a breast before, man'
Yes.
Dude, are you gay'
No, l`m not gay.
I`ve been with
tons of women.
I touched a guy`s balls
at Hebrew school once.
Dude, it`s not a big deal.
You like to fuck guys.
I`m cool. I got friends
who fuck guys, in jail.
No, l`m not gay.
No, l`ve borked a lot of women
in my day.
You`ve ``borked``'
Hold up.
Yo, answer this question:
Are you a virgin'
Yeah, not since I was 10.
It all makes sense.
You`re a virgin.
I am.... Shut up.
How does that happen'
He`s a fucking virgin.
I knew it. That makes
so much sense, man.
Look, he`s a virgin.
You guys are hilarious.
All right, come on,
don`t be mean.
I`m not being mean.
I`m trying to
help the partner out.
I`m trying to say
I wanna get you laid, dude.
I understand
what`s going on.
You guys are so up your asses.
From now on,
your dick is my dick.
I`m getting you some pussy.
[men laughing]
A bag of sand! Come on, man!
You could do better than that.
God, me so horny'
Me so stupid!
[yelling]
oh, come on.
[laughing]
It`s gonna be fine.
They don`t even remember.
Those guys are cool.
[alarm buzzing]
This is gonna be bad.
(Andy)
Yeah, well,
virgin`s not a dirty word.
You know what`s a dirty word,
is asshole...
and that`s what you guys are.
You know,
I may not have had sex,
but I could fuck you up.
Yeah.
Come on.
Hey, David.
Hey, Andy.
What`s up'
Cal, good morning.
(Haziz)
Hey, Andy.
Hey.
We`re gonna have to get you
some punani.
[both guffawing]
Andy, it`s going down,
partner. We`re gonna be....
[moaning]
This for you, partner,
this for you.
Waves of them coming at you
on Friday, Saturday.
By Sunday,
your nuts gonna be drained.
Hey, Andy, don`t let him
bother you. It`s okay
not to have sex.
Not everybody
is a pussy magnet.
What are you' 25'
l`m 40.
Holy shit, man.
You`ve got to get on that.
Life isn`t about sex.
Life is about children
and passion.
Yeah.
And spirit.
Yeah, life`s about passion.
It`s not about fucking
and balls and pussy.
It`s about love.
It`s about people.
It`s about connection.
It`s all about connections.
It`s not about cock
and ass and tits
and butthole pleasures.
It`s not about
butthole pleasures at all.
this rusty trombone
and dirty Sanchez.
Please stop.
And Cincinnati bowtie.
And your pussy juice cocktail
and this shit-stained balls.
Mooj, just please stop.
Just relax--
All right.
That`s enough, party`s over.
Let the virgin
get back to work.
Andy!
Andy, come on.
We were just kidding.
Pointless.
Andy, nobody cares
that you`re a virgin.
Don`t be such a baby.
They were just having fun.
They didn`t mean anything.
Get away from me, David.
Wait a minute.
Stop following me!
Hold up.
Hold on.
I`m gonna have to
quit my job now.
You don`t have to
quit your job.
You know what, I don`t wanna
go out with you guys.
Fine.
okay' I don`t need your help.
okay, fine, you don`t
have to go out with us
if you don`t want.
You know what,
I respect women,
I love women.
I respect them so much
that I completely
stay away from them.
okay.
I have a very fulfilling life.
!![playing]
And now, I am making
your silver pants blue.
Get some roadburn, come on!
Come on, sucker!
! Now, pretty ladies
around the world!
! Got a weird thing
to show you!!
[laughing]
oh, my God!
Hey, Will and Grace,
back to work.
Hey, Haziz, can you just
give us a second'
We`re just kind of
in the middle of something.
I`m on my break, okay'
Fuck off, Haziz.
Leave us alone, all right'
Fuck off' Fuck you!
Fuck you!
Fuck you! Fuck off.
Fuck off.
I`m gonna kick you
in the nuts, asshole.
Hey, hey!
Watch the language, okay'
I have a family.
Watch how you talk to me!
It`s a free country, Bambi.
I can smoke out here
if I want to.
Smoke my pole.
You are a very unkind man.
Get inside!
This is not professional.
Paula,
this asshole over here....
It`s okay.
(Haziz)
Paula!
It`s all right. Come on.
You know, it`s just....
So, how could this
not have happened'
It just never happened.
When I was young, I tried,
and it didn`t happen.
And then I got older and I got
more and more nervous...
because it hadn`t
happened yet.
And I got kind of...
weirded out about it.
Then it really
didn`t happen...
and then, I don`t know,
I just kind of stopped trying.
Do you want to give it
another shot'
Maybe it`s too late.
Sometimes I feel that
it is just too late for me.
No, that`s crazy.
You`re 40 years old.
You know, 40 is the new 20.
You wanna spend
the next 60 years
of your life...
never experiencing sex'
And not just sex, but love...
and a relationship,
and laughing and cuddling
and all that shit.
I don`t know.
I wouldn`t know what to do.
Look, you gotta take a risk.
You gotta risk it.
Look at me.
I went out with this girl
for four months...
and it was the greatest...
greatest thing in my life.
Until she went down on this
guy in an Escalade, I think.
And, you know,
instead of saying:
``okay, what am I doing
that caused this behavior'``...
I dumped her. Stupid decision.
I spent the last two years
of my life regretting it.
Why don`t you
get her back right now'
Because she`s dating
this pot dealer.
Stupid horrible decision.
But, hey, that`s her journey,
you know.
I gotta respect that.
I gotta give her the space.
She wants to be
some immature little bitch
and blow everybody...
that`s love, man.
It sounds horrible.
of course it`s horrible.
It`s suffering...
and it`s pain and it`s....
You know, you lose weight...
and then you
put back on weight...
and then you call them
a bunch of times...
and you try and email
and then they move
or they change their email...
but that`s just love.
Do you realize that
this is the first time...
we`ve spoken for more than,
like, 30 seconds'
Uh-huh.
It`s kind of nice.
Come out with us this weekend.
No pressure.
We`ll just have a good time.
okay, yeah, I will.
I`ll give it a shot.
Great.
But l`m not going to have sex
with anybody.
Good, sex should be
the last thing on your mind.
!![/ Got Ants /n My Pants
playing]
Logjam. Hi.
Shit.
oh, God.
Sorry.
See you later.
Thanks for the dance.
I`m okay. It`s all right.
oh, come on, bus!
oh, come on, dogs!
Shit! You gotta be kidding me.
I mean, l`m kind of nervous.
I never had oral sex before.
Jennifer told me how to do it.
It`s gonna kick ass.
[screaming]
What are you doing'
okay, just....
We`re almost there.
[grunts]
We have one.
Houston, we have one.
You`ll pull my
fucking hair out!
We did it.
God!
oh, my God,
you came in your pants.
What did you do'
I had some Cream of Wheat.
You know what else is sexy'
What'
Me...
Yeah'
...sucking...
on your...
toe.
That`s what you want to
suck on'
Yeah.
It`s just so big and thick.
okay.
Yeah.
[laughing]
That tickles.
[screams]
I`m sorry. oh, no.
Your nose is bleeding.
You think'
I`m sorry.
I`m hot.
But, now,
you can`t have any of this.
You should just
give up forever!
[exclaiming]
!![Ain`t No Mountain
High Enough playing]
Cal, what do you think'
Is this too yellow'
No.
What`s Curious George like
in real life'
Come on, man.
!![J.O.D.D. playing]
Wow, this is
pretty crowded.
Yeah. Well,
it`s $9 beer night.
okay, look now.
So, this is
what`s about to happen,
all right'
You about to go run down
some drunk chicks, all right'
And don`t confuse
that with tipsy.
We talking about drunk.
I want vomit in the hair,
bruised-up knees.
A broken heel is a plus.
That`s what you
want to find, okay'
No, Dave already told me
I didn`t have to have sex
tonight.
And now he`s gone, so....
Dude, just stop thinking
for a minute, all right'
You ain`t got to think
on this one.
All you got to do
is use your instinct.
Show me your instincts.
My head, my heart.
I follow my heart.
Now, l`m gonna show you this
one time, all right'
Instincts.
Show me your instincts.
They`re right here.
own your instincts.
All you doing
is using your instinct.
That`s it.
That`s how a tiger know
he got to tackle a gazelle.
There`s a code
written in his DNA.
It says,
``Tackle the gazelle.``
okay.
And believe it or not,
in every man, there`s
a code written that says:
``Tackle drunk bitches.``
No.
You know what,
I don`t feel comfortable...
hitting on drunk ``bitches,``
you know.
I don`t think that`s right.
okay, hold up.
First of all,
you making it out to be
some kind of bad thing.
I didn`t use bitches
in a derogatory sense.
You did.
It just does....
This doesn`t feel right.
of course it don`t feel right.
What has felt right for you
didn`t work.
You need to try
some wrong, dawg.
okay, how do I tell
which ones are drunk'
Now you`re talking.
All right, check this out.
You see this redhead
over here'
Where'
With the big old titties.
I`m not gonna
stare at a woman.
Dawg, l`m not telling you
to stare at nobody.
I`m telling you to use
your peripherals.
Now look at me.
See. Look. See'
Yeah.
I`m not looking at you.
No. I`m looking at--
You`re looking at her'
What do you want me to do'
I want you to use
your peripherals.
See' l`m not looking at you.
No. See, l`m looking
at the redhead at 3:00
with the big titties.
You see her, racked up
right there, see her'
Yes.
Yeah.
You find one with
the peripherals.
okay.
You see, over by the post.
It looks like a....
It`s either a ficus....
It might be
a rubber tree plant.
All right, if you`re
making a joke, dawg,
it`s not funny.
I see a blonde
and she`s very pretty.
Better, okay. All right.
Now with your peripherals...
Yeah.
...you got to scope out
a hot, drunk chick.
And then you should
make your move.
okay' All right.
Yes.
And remember, it`s
more important that she`s
drunk than she`s hot.
For this first one.
Go get her.
Peripherals, though.
All the way.
All peripherals.
That boy is stubborn.
Hi, l`m Andy.
You look comfortable.
Can I get you
another cocktail'
Too drunk.
But you got the right idea.
But clinically alive.
Hey!
Yo!
I`m having trouble
finding the drunk people.
You want to know
where there`s one'
Yeah.
I. I, Captain Yellowshirts.
[growls]
okay. Have a good one.
Yo!
What'
I met a girl and she`s here
with a bachelorette party...
and they invited us
to party with them.
okay, that`s good.
It`s so good...
because no one is hornier
than a girl...
who`s about to watch
her friend get married
to a guy.
It`s so funny.
[women whooping]
So we just decided because
this is my last night
as a free woman...
before I marry Dan,
that we would just wig out.
We`re wigging out!
You guys are hilarious.
Wait a minute.
Yes, Mr. President.
Yes, the erection results
are in.
[all laughing]
Hey, guys, look,
it`s Dr. Zeus` penis.
I really mean this.
Hey, everybody,
who wants penis cake'
I do.
(Cal)
She does.
Hey, you guys,
Betty Cocker.
[all laughing]
What a good guy. What a....
Dan, the guy
Robin`s marrying...
is such a good guy.
He sounds like a good guy.
I hated him for like two years
`cause he cheated on me.
But...
he`s really changed now.
He`s a really good guy now.
Your friends seem nice.
You have really kind eyes,
you know that'
Thanks. Your hat
has sequins.
Mmm.
[both tittering]
Your hands are on my belt.
What'
I`m sorry.
It`s good.
You`re cute.
This is kind of lame.
You wanna get out of here'
okay, yeah.
Yeah.
Fuck.
Come on.
okay.
You wanna drive'
I don`t have a car
with me here, so....
Cars just suck.
[grunting]
I`m driving.
Are you drunk'
No, I didn`t have anything
to drink.
Blow into this'
okay.
[beeping]
What is this'
The judge recommended
I get one.
[engine starting]
!![Get Ur Freak On playing
on car stereo]
Whoa, okay. Wow.
That`s fast.
okay.
Come on, you`re in the lasso.
[giggling]
! Missy be puttin` it down!
! I`m the hottest round!
! I told y`all
mother-uh!
! Y`all can`t
stop me now!
! Listen to me now!
! I`m lastin` 20 rounds!
! And if you want me, people!
! Then come on
get me now!!
And Dan`s like,
``You`re such a B-l-T-C-H,
bitch!``
[tires screeching]
And l`m like,
``You`re the bitch, bitch.``
You know'
Yeah.
What was your name again'
Andy.
Let me tell you
something, Andy.
Don`t ever be named Dan.
Dan rhymes with man,
and men jerk off.
And he was a jerk-off.
Do you know what I mean'
Look out! The car!
Wow.
I like you.
You`re not a....
Ugh.
I think I ate some
bad shellfish sandwich
or something.
You`re cute.
No.
That tasted good.
That tasted like shellfish.
Look out! Sorry.
Watch it!
[exclaiming]
Do you think l`m pretty'
oh, yes.
oh, God, yes!
You`re not looking at me.
Yes, you`re pretty.
Do you think l`m pretty'
Look at me.
Look at me!
I`m looking! You`re pretty!
God, I just wanna live!
God, I hope
I get my period soon.
I am in a bad mood.
okay.
I`m so tired.
Hey, whoa!
[glass shattering]
oh, God! Turn away!
Hey, get off the wheel.
You`re not gonna
get in my pants
acting like that.
I`m starving.
Let`s get some
fucking French toast.
[tires screeching]
okay, here we are.
oh, God, we made it.
Home sweet home.
oh, mommy!
[screeching]
[panting]
Are you okay'
The fucker came
out of nowhere.
okay. We`re okay.
[laughing]
[crying]
Are you okay'
Well, are you....
What`s the matter'
[gasps]
I`m sorry.
That`s okay.
I think I kind of
had that coming.
I`ll still have sex with you
if you want.
You know what, I think
l`m gonna pass on the sex,
if you don`t mind.
At least I don`t have
to work out tomorrow.
Did you have
a daiquiri tonight'
Yeah.
I thought you might.
It was a very bad night.
[all laughing]
Yeah, laugh.
You know what,
you guys wouldn`t be
laughing right now...
if some girl had just
vomited shellfish sandwich
into your mouth.
[grunts]
You know what, you`re right,
it`s my bad.
Let me apologize to you
first of all...
for not mentioning in detail
that when you pick up
a drunk woman...
who`s falling down
on her way out of the bar...
that you should
probably drive.
I drive a bike.
okay,
Mr. Schwinn-fucking-Armstrong,
who asked you to drive a bike'
You know what,
l`m not the only person
in the world...
who rides a bike.
Yeah, everyone rides a bike,
when they`re fucking six.
Why don`t you kiss something'
Because this is over,
you guys, okay'
Can I just interject
for a second'
[stuttering]
Let me just say...
you`re putting the pussy up
on this pedestal.
You`re just building
the pussy up, man.
What are you even
talking about'
``Building the pussy up,``
what does that mean'
You making the pussy into
this great big Greek goddess
named Pussalia...
and what you`re doing is...
you`re psyching yourself
into thinking
it`s some impossible feat.
Yeah, I think
you`re right.
I`m putting the pussy up
on a pedestal.
Right.
That`s it.
It`s ``Pussalia,`` right'
Look where you going.
I don`t wanna say
the word anymore.
Say what word'
``Pussy.`` I don`t wanna say it.
Fuck it.
``Pussy`` is a scientific word.
Dude! New pants, man.
You know what, Dave'
You know, you said
there wasn`t gonna be
any pressure at all.
(David)
l`m not pressuring you.
Excuse me.
Can one of you guys
help me, please'
No hab/o English, lady.
I actually am helping
a customer right now.
okay, well--
l`m on break.
But our stock supervisor
is very knowledgeable.
He can answer
all of your questions
and he`d love to help you.
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
You, too.
Great, okay. Hi, l`m Trish.
Hi, Andy is my name.
This one looks pretty good.
You don`t wanna buy that VCR.
I don`t'
No, actually to be
totally honest with you...
you don`t wanna buy
any VCR.
It`s a dead technology.
It`s like getting
an eight-track player.
Yeah.
or a Betamax.
You know what, actually
l`d recommend this one.
This is a dual.
You`ve got the VCR
and DVD combo.
So, you know,
that technology would be
probably pretty good for--
Six months or so'
Yeah.
That`s good.
At best. Sorry.
No.
As good as it gets.
okay, that sounds good,
then.
okay, all right.
[Cal speaking Spanish]
It`s perfect.
Sorry.
Coming through.
okay.
God, you know,
it`s so funny, I work
right across the street...
and l`ve never been
in this place.
Really' Where at'
Yeah.
The
``We Sell Your Stuff on eBay``
store.
Yes.
And that`s the name'
Yeah, I was
looking for something...
you know, obvious.
So I chose that.
I don`t understand.
So, what, you do what'
Well, I take the stuff
that you don`t want...
and then I ``sell`` it
on eBay.
But you don`t actually
sell anything in the store'
No. I don`t.
So why do you have a store'
I don`t know.
No, I think it`s because,
you know, I wanna maybe
look professional...
and not like a crazy person
who`s just gonna
steal all your shit.
Sure. I didn`t
mean anything by that.
No, it`s okay.
You know what,
you should come by sometime
if you want, you know...
see it for yourself,
check it out.
I`ll check out
your empty store.
Yeah, it`s the one
across the street
that`s not empty.
Here`s my number. So....
All right.
So, just anytime.
Why do I need your number
if you`re across the street,
though'
I don`t really have
a good answer for that, Andy.
I just....
Sorry.
Just giving it to you.
So l`ll write you up,
and l`ll meet you over
at the register.
okay.
And check you out....
Check out.
okay, see you over there.
okay.
Awful chatty.
Hey....
Look, I think she gave me
her number.
She wrote down her number,
but I think she gave me
her number.
No, she gave you.
Dude, man.
See, you still mad at me'
No, I was never.
Right, you see what I mean'
Yeah, we gonna
celebrate it, man. Yeah.
This is pretty cool.
Yeah.
Unbelievable.
Come on,
give him some credit, man.
The man pulled a number.
It`s just.... I was in....
I can`t believe that happened.
What you did
with you`s own hand.
Man, she just gave me
her number.
That`s great, man.
I`m telling you,
love is a mysterious fig.
It is.
okay, here`s a question.
When should I call her'
You like her'
Yeah.
You definitely
don`t want to call her.
When is the next olympics'
(Jay)
So what you just
got to do is...
just get you a bunch
of these hood rats...
run through them,
just knock them out.
Boom, boom, boom.
And once you`ve done
slayed like 20,
30 of them hood rats...
now you ready to go up
to the upper echelon type ho.
You know what I mean'
l`m not a big ho runner.
My uncle used to drive
a ho runner.
Screw these analogies.
What he`s saying is...
you are going to be so bad
at sex the first time...
you don`t want to have sex
with someone you like...
`cause they`ll think
you`re a weirdo for being
so lame at it.
You want to have sex
with hood rats first...
so that by the time
you get to the girl
you do like...
you`re not terrible at sex,
you`ll be mediocre at it.
Probably still
pretty bad, though.
(Jay)
Let`s put it up for my man
for pulling that number.
Way to go, man.
Politicked his ass off.
(Cal)
You did politic.
Thanks a lot.
Like a train, round the bend.
You ready'
[clears throat]
[coughing]
Yeah.
I can`t.
Do it.
I can`t pee in public.
Gotta do it.
I`ve got a mental block
about it.
Come on, do it.
I`m shy!
[shouting]
I peed in public!
Let me out.
I can`t hear
what you`re saying.
I don`t want to be in here.
It`s a soundproof room.
Just learn the techniques.
Right on, man.
[woman moaning]
You guys, this is not funny!
[sighing]
[ringing]
Hello.
[grunting]
Hey, what you watching'
Dawn of the Dead, man.
Great.
The store is slow.
Paula`s gone.
Yo, is Paula back'
No. She`s not here.
She said we can`t
watch this in here.
You sure'
I know.
Can I ask you something
in confidence'
I know this is gonna
sound weird.
Am I good-looking'
Do you think a woman
will find me attractive'
[snar/s]
oh, my God!
oh, my God, the blood just--
okay, never mind.
Wait, Andy. Hold up.
Listen,
this is embarrassing for me.
This is hard to talk about.
Are you ready
for my honest answer'
Yes.
Yeah.
I think you`re
a good-looking cat.
I don`t think
that anybody knows it...
and I don`t think
anybody can see it.
Well,
that`s why l`m asking you.
You seem really well-groomed
and really put together.
I mean, look, dude.
You think this was
an accident'
All of this right here'
Premeditated, partner.
You gotta highlight
your attributes,
like a diamond in the rough.
You willing to make
some sacrifices'
Absolutely.
You see that whole
Teen Wo/fthing
you got going right there'
You need to wax
that right out.
Does it hurt'
No. Waxing don`t hurt.
I mean,
not unless you`re a bitch.
You know what I mean'
It didn`t hurt me.
I get it done all the time.
[screaming]
What the fuck!
[exclaiming]
Fuck that nigger up!
Bitch, get out of the room!
(Jay)
This is gonna be good.
This the one right here,
right'
Hi, how are you'
So this is your first time
getting body waxed'
Yes, it is.
Take off your shirt.
okay.
We`re gonna need
more wax.
I`m staying.
This is gonna be good.
And clear all my appointments
in the afternoon.
Here we go.
That feels warm.
(David)
I like your sweater.
Does that come in a V-neck'
(Cal)
She starts doing his pubes,
l`m out of here.
(Jay)
You gonna look good
after this, man.
Thanks, man.
So, ready'
Yeah.
[speaks foreign language]
[screaming]
You fucker!
I`m sorry.
That`s just your job.
You want me to stop now'
No. It`s okay.
Let`s do another one.
That one little patch
looks sexy though.
Does it look good'
(Cal)
Yeah, it looks really good.
[exclaiming]
(David)
It looks man-tastic.
(Andy)
okay.
Wow! I didn`t expect
that at all.
I really didn`t expect that.
(Jay)
You got it. The first one
is the only one that hurts.
Yeah.
Those hairs are pretty deep.
okay.
You ready'
Yup.
[speaks foreign language]
[screaming]
Sucker motherfucker!
You shithead! I hate you!
I hate you so much!
That one hurt.
That one hurt
just as much as the first one.
That`s great, man.
Man!
[exhaling]
one, two, three.
[grunting]
Fuck me!
In the asshole!
[Andy exclaiming]
I`m sorry.
I really don`t
swear this much.
You know what,
I got a weak stomach.
That`s all I can really take.
I`ll see ya`ll.
(Andy)
Jay.
Be tough, Andy, you got it.
Where did Jay go'
(David)
He went to throw up.
Ready'
Yup.
one, two.
[gasping]
Cocksucker motherfucker!
You pulled on two.
Why didn`t you
pull on three'
Freddy pie hole!
[Andy exclaiming in Spanish]
No! Kelly Clarkson!
[screaming]
[Andy screaming]
Ya`ll done or ya`ll--
That`s fucked up.
(Andy)
oh, shit falls!
That`s fucked up.
I hate you.
Stop smiling, you jerk!
You pussy.
oh, God. What`s next'
You`re doing the nipple.
(Cal)
Not the nipple.
Come on.
Please, Cal,
hold my hand.
You kidding me, man'
Hold my goddamn hand, man.
Do it! Just hold.
okay, here we go.
[exhaling]
(woman)
Ready'
No. Yup.
one, two, three.
[screaming]
Nipple fuck!
Mika, you should
burn in hell!
okay, all right.
No, seriously,
I think l`m done.
I think we`re done.
I think that`s good.
[panting]
You know what, guys...
this is not
a good look for me!
You look like
a man-o`-lantern.
Thank you very much.
Appreciate it.
Thank you.
[screaming]
(Cal)
Thank you very much.
You`re welcome.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Andy,
I owe you an apology, man.
I wasn`t very nice
to you for the past
two-and-a-half years.
You were nice to me.
No, I was.... I thought
you were really boring and...
I kind of thought
you were a serial killer.
[laughs]
I`m not joking.
Hey!
Sorry. Shoot. Sorry, sorry.
Don`t worry. There`s a lot of
padding in these.
I could hurl it
off the balcony,
it would be fine.
Yeah. It will be fine.
We couldn`t break this...
if we tried.
No problem.
Look, you shouldn`t listen
to Dave and Jay, okay'
Those guys are crazy.
You should listen to me, okay'
Look, there is a hot-ass girl
who works right there.
There she is,
in the bookstore.
You should ask her out, man.
Something wrong
with her underpants.
(Cal)
Yeah, they`re not in my mouth.
You know, I kind of...
Iike the woman
from the eBay store.
That`s great, but...
you`re not gonna
get with anyone...
unless you play
the odds on this, man.
You need to plant
a lot of seeds.
It`s like this.
When I was growing pot,
I realized...
that the more seeds
I planted...
Thank you.
...the more pot
I could ultimately smoke.
I think I have all the advice
that I can handle right now.
Don`t get bitter.
I`m not bitter.
I almost lost a nipple, okay'
That was Jay`s idea, okay'
And I wasn`t going to
say anything,
but waxing your chest is...
Iike the gayest thing
you could possibly do, okay'
Look at me.
Looks are not important.
Really look at me.
I am ugly as fuck
by traditional standards...
but I get with women.
Aren`t you curious
as to how that`s possible'
I am not ugly as fuck.
I didn`t say you were
ugly as--
Well, you implied it.
okay.
It doesn`t matter if
you`re ugly as fuck
or you`re ugly as shit.
It`s about talking to women,
and I know how to do that...
because I observe,
because I am a novelist.
What' You never
told me that before.
That`s because I am not
an arrogant prick, Andy.
okay' The problem
most men have is...
they don`t know
how to talk to women.
You know what my problem is'
I am not interesting.
What am I supposed to say'
``l went to magic camp'``
``l`m an accomplished
ventriloquist'``
``l am a seventh-degree
imperial yo-yo master.``
[exclaims]
Do me, yo-yo master.
I want you to do me,
`cause you`re the yo-yo guy.
Are you done' Listen.
The problem
most men have is...
they just plain straight up
have no clue
how to talk to women.
Just ask a question, okay'
That`s it.
Because women do not care
about what you have to say...
at all anyway, you know.
And all they want to do
is talk about themselves.
So you`re just gonna
let them do that.
okay' So remember.
Questions, be cool,
and be kind of a dick.
Here, be David Caruso
in Jade.
okay. I know exactly
what you`re talking about.
You do. That`s good.
(Cal)
There she is.
Go plant that seed, man.
Plant it with your finger.
Can I help you'
I don`t know. Can you'
Are you looking
for something'
Is there something
I should be looking for'
[laughs]
We have
a lot of books.
So, maybe it depends
on what you like.
What do you like'
We have a great section of...
do-it-yourself.
Do you like to
``do it yourself``'
Sometimes. I mean...
if the mood strikes.
How is the mood
striking you now'
[laughing]
[tittering]
What`s your name'
I`m Beth.
Andy.
Don`t tell on me,
okay, Andy'
I wont.
Unless you want
to be told on...
Beth.
Wow. That totally worked!
I literally said nothing.
And she found me fascinating.
I would`ve thought
you were doing that for years.
Should I have asked her out'
No. That`s the key.
You wait for it
to grow into a plant...
and then you fuck the plant.
okay.
This is easy.
All right.
Hello, Trish.
How you doing'
What`s going on'
[laughing]
Good joke.
This is a fun conversation.
Just grow a backbone
and call her.
She asked you to call her.
She wants you to call her.
[telephone ringing]
Hello.
Hey, how you doing'
How you doing'
/`m we//.
Who is this?
This is James.
James. Do / know you, James?
[grunting]
I was wondering whether
you had a few minutes...
to talk about
a little laundry detergent.
Are you a telemarketer, James'
Yep.
Are you at the top
of a ta// bui/ding?
Can you get to a roof quick/y?
Jump off!
I mean, you people are sick.
Get a real fucking job,
why don`t you'
Go shoot yourse/f
in the fucking head.
Hey, why don`t you just,
you know,
get a knife and run into it'
Why don`t you do that, huh?
okay.
/`// see you /ater, James.
Nice to talk to you.
Fuck your mother, okay?
Bye-bye.
oh.
[doorbell ringing]
Hey, man.
Got a big box of porn for you.
Can I come in'
Yeah.
[sighs]
Sweet video game chair.
So what`s in the box'
It`s my personal collection
of erotica.
I want to give it to you.
I think there might be
a few tapes in there
that just might open up...
Pandora`s box of love.
okay.
Amy and l,
we used to watch
Harry Twatter...
and we`d put it on
the television...
and then act it out
as it was going on...
and it was....
She`s adorable.
Fucking bitch.
Well, you know,
this is really gracious
and kind...
and generous and everything.
But I just don`t want
a big box of porn
in my apartment.
There`s some really
great stuff in here.
Really great movies in here,
man.
Hey, did you ever see
Schoo/ of Rock?
Yeah.
Well, this is....
It`s called Schoo/ of....
You know....
That`s nice.
But it stars Jack Black Cock.
That makes sense.
Dude, here it is.
Boner Jams `03.
It`s a mixed tape I made.
All these great scenes
that I was really into
in the summer of 2003.
I think you`d really dig it.
Yeah. Now I can see that.
This is...
Everybody Loves Raymond.
That`s probably
not supposed to be....
This is a good show.
I just tape it sometimes.
Well, I don`t think
you understand something,
Dave.
I don`t want this stuff, okay'
Because I don`t do that,
that much.
What, masturbate'
Yeah.
Dude, l`ve jacked it twice
since l`ve been here.
Are you kidding me' Why not'
lt`s not a hobby of mine.
Well, then,
that`s the only hobby
you don`t have.
No, seriously,
I just don`t feel comfortable
talking about--
You need to.
You`re wound up.
You`re like one of these
action figures...
all hermetically sealed
in your box.
You gotta play with--
Don`t!
Don`t take it out!
I`m sorry.
You know what, it`s just....
It loses its value if you
take it out of its packaging.
I`m just saying, let it out.
Give it some air, man.
Play with it.
Take your porn with you.
I`m not taking it.
Take your box-o-porn.
It`s my gift to you.
No. I don`t want it.
David, it`s not....
Andy, for the last time...
I don`t want your giant box
of pornography.
No, no, no!
Come on, man.
So uncool.
Uncool'
Uncool is trying
to give an honest man
a big box of porn, Andy.
(David)
For the last time,
I don`t want to watch...
Schoo/ of Cock with you.
!![He//o playing]
/t`s nothing officia/.
Just a /itt/e token
of my appreciation.
[tape forwarding]
[woman moaning]
[sighs]
Hi, Andy.
I`m gonna talk dirty to you.
I want to have
lots of sexy sex with you.
I want to touch
your big, fat noodle...
`cause I want to have
naughty intercourse with you.
I want you to put
your penis on,
I mean, in me, Andy.
I want to do lots of,
lots of sexy...
hot things with you. Shit.
This really isn`t working,
Andy.
I don`t know what to say...
because I am you.
[exclaiming]
(Andy)
okay. New tape.
Nothing is ever good enough
and it`s a/ways our fau/t.
Hey, you can`t speak
to your mother /ike that.
You do.
She`s not my mother.
[traffic humming]
I heard Dave gave you
the box of porn.
Yeah, he did.
You ever watch, like,
Primetime Live...
when they take a black light
into a hotel room...
and show you all the semen
all over the bedspread'
Yeah.
You blind someone
with that box.
Could see that thing
from space.
This right here,
you looking at
the Bentley of big screen TVs.
I`m talking about,
this is the Rolls-Royce
of big screen....
[exclaiming]
Sometimes,
I think these butterflies
are in here.
I think he might be
fooling us all, though.
Really'
I actually think he might be,
like, some genius...
and this is like
some big, like, hilarious....
Like he`s bored at work
and he just wanted to
kick up some shit...
so he told us all
he`s a virgin.
You`re seeing that
a lot of stuff
that`s not there.
You`re just projecting
all over him.
He might be an idiot savant...
but he`s not, like,
clever enough to go that deep.
But he`s got a great body.
Would you fuck him'
In a New York minute.
You would fuck him'
Absolutely.
Hey, Andy, what are you doing
for lunch'
I don`t know.
I have a turkey sandwich.
We`re gonna go around
the corner. I think you should
come with us.
There`s this great place.
A lot of cute girls.
I don`t know. okay.
We brought you a shirt.
This place is pretty fancy.
Something going on'
Hey, who`s ready
to have some fun?
[people cheering]
Hey, guys....
No, don`t ignore me.
I know what this is.
Within one hour,
you`// each have 20 dates.
Don`t....
Please don`t do this.
I saw this on Primetime Live.
All right, ninja master.
We`ve given you all the advice
we have to give.
Now you gonna put it
in action.
Advice' You guys all
gave me different advice.
He thinks you`re a pothead.
I am.
Dude. Hey, partner.
What are you whining about'
You asked for this shit.
No, I didn`t.
Will you just quit whining
like a bitch'
I`m not whining like a bitch.
You are whining like a bitch.
And you about to cram
like 10 years of pimpage
into one day.
I don`t want to cram pimpage.
And after that...
you on my level. Come on.
(Cal)
Just ask questions.
This is a bad idea.
[buzzing]
[people chattering]
(woman)
Hi.
Hi. How are you'
I`m fine.
Are you fine'
Yeah.
You`re fine then'
Are you fucking retarded'
What the hell`s
the matter with you'
Do you want me to be
fucking retarded'
[buzzer sounding]
When I look into
the eyes of the children
and the parents...
and they are smiling
and saying:
``Thank you, Dr. Montalban,
you saved my child``...
it was worth it.
[buzzer sounding]
Amy...
what are you doing here'
David.
And you are Gina'
Gina.
Hey, what`s up'
Nothing.
Look, l`m going to be
real honest with you.
It`s been a long time
since l`ve been with a man.
Spent a lot of time
with the ladies.
Looking to get back up
on that pogo stick.
You know what l`m saying'
Excuse me.
Remember that time
when we made love
and you cried in my arms'
Please don`t reminisce about
the times we fucked, please.
It`s so creepy.
Let`s go to Paris.
I want to take you
underneath the Eiffel Tower
and make love to you.
Cut it out.
Cut what out'
This go to Paris!
We`ve been broken up
for like two years, man.
I don`t want to
date you anymore.
You`re a whore.
I am not a whore.
I just didn`t like you.
This is so us.
[laughs]
[snickering]
Psycho talk.
What'
You`re a good-looking man.
Thank you.
Very pretty.
Real soft, delicate features.
You`re real feminine,
you know,
which is good for me...
because that would be
a simple sort of transition.
You know what l`m saying'
Maybe throw a little rouge
on you, tuck your sac back.
You game'
No.
[buzzer sounding]
You need to stop
fucking around
with my friend, okay'
Because you`re giving
him hope, and it`s driving
the man crazy.
I moved,
I changed my e-mail address,
my phone number.
He`s practically
stalking me.
Well, I didn`t know all that.
So, l`m sorry.
[buzzer sounding]
I love Minnesota.
(woman)
I grew up in a town
outside of Minneapolis...
with a population of, like,
500 people. Really small.
Yeah, it`s like
the Land of a Thousand Lakes.
What about you'
You`re used to, like,
a really big city.
Really.... God, yes.
The town that I grew up in
was really small. I mean...
you know, it was just so safe.
There was no crime.
I mean, a girl could just walk
from one end of town
to the other...
and just, you know,
feel completely safe.
[coughing]
[buzzer sounding]
(Jay)
You suppose he`s had enough'
Spank bank has
once again been filled.
(Cal)
l`ll tell you
who`s the hottest.
You`re gonna think l`m crazy.
Let me tell you. Gina.
Can`t get va-Gina
out of my head.
Va-Gina all week.
You know what`s a fun game'
Huh'
You take three
Excedrin PMs...
and you see
if you could whack off
before you fall asleep.
[sighing]
You always win
is the best part
about the game.
(Jill)
Are you Andy'
Yeah.
Is this yours'
Did you write this stuff'
My girlfriend, Jill,
found your
speed-dating card.
Yeah, right.
God, l`ve been looking
for that speed-dating card.
Thank you so much
for bringing it to me.
So, you actually wrote
that one girl looked like...
she was
``hurting for a squirting``'
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
Hurting for a squirting,
I wrote that.
So you wrote
``ho fo show.``
Yeah, I remember that girl.
She was a ho.
Fo show.
Let me show you
how this device works.
Right, l`m just looking
for a cordless phone.
Yup, it`s great.
You can do anything,
make video diaries....
Hey, Amy, how`s it going'
How you feeling' l`m great.
I feel fantastic
since we broke up.
I feel awesome!
Can you just show me
the department where there
would be phones'
How have you been'
What`s been going on....
I bet.... Hey, have you been
doing a lot of this'
Sir, please, sir.
You are never gonna
meet anybody...
with that kind of mentality
about women,
you sick son of a bitch.
Who the fuck are you
to put me on trial'
I`ve never even met you.
So why don`t you
back the shit off, all right'
And stop with the inquisition.
That`s how you talk'
You know what,
I don`t have to answer to you.
You ain`t my bitch.
Know what I saying'
So, shit, man. Fuck it.
You shouldn`t even be
hanging out with this pervert.
I don`t hang out with him.
I work with him and that`s it.
I tried to introduce him
to a few nice people...
he made a fool of himself.
I don`t mess with him, baby.
That`s not me.
You should keep your ho
on a leash.
Bro, I can`t let you--
Hey.
I can`t let you be talking
to my woman like that, dawg.
Know what l`m saying'
Bitch is running wild, man.
You miss that ass'
That`s the ass of a free man.
That ass is going out tonight,
maybe to a club.
Maybe to a night club.
Hey, Andy...
take a look at your pal.
oh, my God.
Yeah, he`s performing
a public colonoscopy.
Isn`t that sweet'
I`m gonna send
David home for the day...
and you`re gonna
fill in for him.
What' Selling things'
You got that right.
I don`t think
that`s a good idea.
And you`re gonna have to
talk to people, too.
I know that`s a frightening
concept to you...
but I think you can handle it.
So get out there
and start selling some shit.
...thing for Amy.
Hold it.
Check it out.
(David)
I miss her.
!![music p/aying]
Dude, the floor`s
the ultimate aphrodisiac.
All you got to do
is go make your pick now.
Come on, man.
okay.
And you could act
a little enthused about it.
Yeah.
(Jay)
That`s right. That`s right.
Gazelle in the pink top.
(Jay)
oh, shit.
Hi.
(Andy)
Looks like you`re
checking out digital cameras.
You know what, he ain`t going
to do it willingly.
No. We need to, like,
really facilitate things
a bit more.
Yo, Andy.
(Andy)
Yeah.
What`s up, dude'
This is Jay, man.
Hey, Jay.
I am throwing a party tonight.
It`s gonna be real mellow,
just chilled up.
Now, you rea//y
need to be there.
It`s gonna be
really, really colorful.
Are you free'
Yeah, I think so.
That was a joke, man.
/ know you`re free.
I`m okay.
Gotta go, man.
All right, bye.
So, tell me, Montel...
why weren`t we invited
to the party'
What are we, Al-Qaeda'
No, hold up.
No, no.
It`s not that kind of party,
y`all.
You`re not coming
to our fucking party either,
okay'
Fuck you, okay'
First of all,
it ain`t that kind of party.
Go fuck a goat.
Yeah.
Why you always telling me
to fuck a goat, man'
(Mooj)
Fuck a goat!
[elevator bell dings]
!![music p/aying on stereo]
[knocking on door]
Hello'
Hello.
Hello. Hi.
Are you here for Jay`s party'
Yes.
I am Jay`s party.
You know what, hiring
a transvestite prostitute
isn`t helping me, man.
What' Ain`t nobody hired
no damn transvestite.
What are you talking about'
She was really nice,
incidentally.
If that sister
was a transvestite...
that was the Mona Lisa
of transvestites.
You got a hummer
from the tranny, didn`t you'
You know, aren`t we owed
one now' `Cause technically
we paid her.
Get a dick, man.
Do you guys even like me'
or is this some sort
of cruel joke
that you`re all in on'
Because l`m not a freak.
I`m a good person.
I always thought
that Matt Damon was
like a Streisand, but...
I think that he`s rocking
the shit in this one.
Shut up, Dave!
Hold up. Let`s just chill
on the aggression
for a minute.
Look at him.
He is such a bad ass.
He looks
just like Luke Wilson.
Mmm-hmm.
So you saying
she was definitely a man'
Yes.
okay, well, how do you know
that she was a man'
Because her hands were
as big as Andre the Giant`s.
And she had an Adam`s apple
as big as her balls.
So you have no proof.
You know what'
Just leave me alone.
Just stay away from me.
or l`m gonna tell Paula...
that you`re all stealing
the recordable CDs.
Come on.
That`s like we were
paid to do it.
We did this
`cause we`re your friends...
and we didn`t think you have
the balls to do it yourself.
Really'
(David)
Yeah.
okay, watch this.
Yo, Andy,
it`s just CDs, man.
That`s a third strike
for me, dawg.
[brakes screech]
[man shouting]
[grunts]
[bells chiming]
Hi.
Andy. Hi.
Right, yeah.
You remember my name.
I did.
How you doing'
l`m great.
I like your store.
That`s good, yeah.
If you have time,
look around. It`s....
okay.
How`s business been'
You know, it`s coming along.
I mean, it takes a while.
Do you want to
go out sometime'
Yes.
Yes, I would like that.
That would be great.
I think l`m maybe free
this weekend,
if that`s okay.
or you could call me tomorrow
and we can just firm it up.
okay. Great.
Great.
okay, so l`ll call you,
and yeah, that`ll be good.
How you doing'
Congratulations.
okay, so l`ll.... Yeah.
Can I help you'
Yeah, these are wonderful.
I`ll take these.
Thanks, they are.
They`re great. The goldfish
just crack me up.
Funny.
Yeah, they are.
Yeah.
They`re cute.
I don`t actually
sell anything here.
I just sell them on eBay.