(DARK ORCHESTRAL MUSIC)
WOMAN: The voice you hear
is not my speaking voice,
but my mind's voice.
I have not spoken
since I was six years old.
No-one knows why. Not even me.
SCOTLAND 1852
My father says it is a dark talent,
and the day I take it into my head
to stop breathing will be my last.
(ROLLERSKATES GLIDE)
Today, he married me
to a man I've not yet met.
Soon, my daughter and I
shall join him in his own country.
My husband said
my muteness does not bother him.
He writes, and hark this, God loves
dumb creatures, so why not he?
Were good he had God's patience...
...for silence
affects everyone in the end.
The strange thing is
I don't think myself silent.
That is because of my piano.
I shall miss it on the journey.
(PLAYS THE PIANO)
(STOPS PLAYING)
(WAVES CRASH)
Take her hand, come on.
You're with me.
I've got the lady.
(MAN SHOUTS)
I think you've got it.
(WIND HOWLS)
You go ahead.
Paddington Station.
Over here, my lovely!
(SOUND OF RETCHING)
(MEN LAUGH)
Alright, lads, unbutton your muftis.
Piss like a tom.
Come on!
On the count
of three!
(MEN CONTINUE TALKING)
(MEN SING)
MAN: Jesus Christ,
whose bloody coffin is this?
Christ, it's heavy!
Fuck them! We'll just leave them behind.
It's what they fucking want.
A pox on you!
Oh, I like that. Very good.
Leave them
and be lynched for the pleasure?
It's a bit rough out there.
Could be they can't get through to you
in this weather.
Do you have things for shelter?
She says, "Thank you."
(MEN SING)
(MAN LAUGHS)
Does your mother prefer
to come on with us to Nelson?
She says no.
She says she'd rather be
boiled alive by natives
than get back in your stinking tub.
You be damn fortuned I don't smack
your puppy gob, young missy!
Damned lucky!
(LAUGHS)
MAN: We're all ready now, sir.
(PLAYS SOLEMN MELODY)
(GIRL SCREAMS)
(CHICKENS CLUCK)
Mother, watch out!
The hens! Are they alright? Here.
(CHICKENS CLUCK)
Look, I'm a very big moth.
Will it catch fire?
I'm not gonna call him Papa.
I'm not gonna call him anything.
I'm not even gonna look at him.
(MEN SPEAK MAORl)
Are we stopping?
Shall we stop?
(MAN SPEAKS MAORl)
We must get on.
Hmm?
(ALL CHATTER)
(JAUNTY HORN MUSIC)
Miss McGrath? Alisdair Stewart.
You'll have to wake yourself.
I've got men here to carry your things.
(SPEAKS MAORl)
Well, I see you've got
a good many boxes.
I'd like to know what's in each...
(GASPS)
Can you hear me?
Well, that's good.
Yes, that's good.
What's in this one?
You're small.
I never thought you'd be small.
And this one?
It's very large.
What's in it, then, a bedstead?
It's my mother's piano.
Baines, tell them to carry in pairs.
Take all the boxes, table and, uh...
...suitcases.
What do you think?
She looks tired.
She's stunted, that's one thing.
MAN: And the big case?
No, no. Just the trunks
and the boxes as I explained.
No, it can't come now.
It must. She wants it to come.
Yes, and so do I. But there are
too few of us here to carry it now.
Too heavy!
What, you mean you don't want your
clothing or your kitchenware to come?
Is that what you mean?
We can't leave the piano!
Look, let's not discuss this
any further.
I'm very pleased
that you arrived safely.
Mother wants to know if they
can come back directly for it.
Could I apologise for the delay,
which I regret...
After they've taken
the other things.
(MAN SPEAKS IN MAORl)
(LAUGHTER)
Might I suggest that you prepare yourself
for a difficult journey?
The bush will tear clothing
and the mud is very deep in places.
What do they think they're doing?
We haven't time for this.
Baines!
(MOURNFUL PIANO MUSIC)
(PEOPLE CONVERSE IN MAORI
AND LAUGH)
(SPEAKS MAORl)
What's the matter?
Why are they stopping?
(SPEAKS MAORl)
That's the way to
the burial grounds. It's tapu.
We came down this way.
I'm sure we did.
(MAN SPEAKS MAORl)
They want more money.
They're trying to make two days out of it.
No.
No, they know another track
to the side of this.
(RAIN POURS, THUNDER CRASHES)
Septimus, now take that off!
Take that off!
(LAUGHS)
Watch your feet! Mind your feet!
Septimus! Please stop it!
Stop it!
(LAUGHS)
Stop, please! Or you'll tear it!
Oh, the tag is broken.
Septimus, now stop!
(LAUGHTER)
(GIGGLES)
(SQUEALS)
You'll tear it. Be careful.
WOMAN: Arm down.
If you cannot have
a ceremony together,
you'll have at least
a photograph.
Careful. The lace is most fragile.
My real father was
a famous German composer.
They met when my mother was
an opera singer in Luxembourg.
Why?
I want to be in the photograph.
Going to leave the cloth here?
No, no. It is just
to keep the chair dry.
I almost slipped on the planks.
They've gotten very greasy.
Give the lady a chair.
Pull the tarpaulin.
I am sorry it rained.
We have not light enough inside.
Shall I hold the umbrella
on this side or t'other?
On the t'other! Move over.
Can you take this, please?
And sitting...
(THUNDER CRASHES)
Uh...
Very still.
And where did they get married?
In an enormous forest
with real fairies as bridesmaids,
each holding a little elf's hand.
No, I tell a lie. It was in a small
country church in the mountains.
Which mountains are those, dear?
The Pyrenees.
Oh. I've never been there.
Mother used to sing the songs
in German
and her voice would echo
across the valleys.
That was before the accident.
And what happened?
One day, when my mother and father
were singing together in the forest,
a great storm
blew up out of nowhere.
But so passionate was their singing
that they did not notice
nor did they stop
as the rain began to fall.
And when their voices rose
for the final bars of the duet,
a great bolt of lightning came out
of the sky and struck my father,
and then he lit up like a torch.
And at the same moment
my father was struck dead,
my mother was struck dumb.
She never spoke another word.
Oh, dear!
Not another word?
Well, from the shock. Yes.
It would be. Terrible.
Terrible.
Terrible. Oh.
(TUTS) Terrible, terrible.
Yeah, there...
(LACE RIPS)
Dear?
(MOURNFUL PIANO MUSIC)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(FOOD CRUNCHES)
Sorry.
Um, I have to go away for some days.
There's some Maori land I'm interested in
which I may buy very reasonably.
Well, I hope you'll spend
the time to get settled in
and perhaps... in some ways...
...we could start again.
Alright?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
I'm not able to read.
Please take us back to the beach
where we landed.
I am sorry. I can't do that.
I don't have the time.
Goodbye.
(HORSE SNORTS)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
(DOOR CLOSES)
I can't take you there.
I can't do it.
(HORSE NICKERS)
Whoa, whoa!
(HOPEFUL PIANO MELODY PLAYS)
(PIANO MELODY CONTINUES)
Mamma! Mamma, watch me! Watch!
Mamma! Mamma!
(GIRL SINGS)
(SINGS)
(ADA TAPS ON TABLE)
(SINGS HIGH NOTE)
(SINGS)
Hello there.
Hello.
Well, you've stopped combing your hair,
which is a good thing.
It was looking overdone.
You see, these are the slits
that the heads will go through.
Show him, Nessie. They'll be dead.
Slits.
The Reverend's going
to use animal blood.
No doubt it'll be very dramatic.
It'll be very dramatic.
Tea!
Morag... (CLEARS THROAT)
...what would you think if someone
were to play a kitchen table...
(NESSIE POURS TEA)
...like it were a piano?
Like it were a piano?
It's strange, isn't it?
I mean, it's not a piano.
It's... doesn't make any sound.
Biscuits!
MORAG: No, no sound.
(BOTH SING
'GOD SAVE THE QUEEN')
ALISDAIR: I mean, I knew
she was mute, but now I'm thinking...
...perhaps it's more than that.
I'm wondering
if she's not brain-affected.
(GIRLS SING)
Shush!
No sound at all?
Well, no. It was a table.
Well, she was very violent with
the gown. She tore off a chunk of lace.
If I hadn't been there to see it,
I'd have sworn she'd have used
her teeth and wiped her feet on it.
Wiped her feet on it.
Well, it hasn't come to anything yet.
It's simply a concern, that's all.
Yes.
Yes, of course. A concern.
There's something
to be said for silence.
MORAG: Indeed. Cotton.
And with time, I'm sure
she'll become... affectionate.
Certainly, there's nothing
so easy to like as a pet.
And they're quite silent.
(GIRL SINGS) # And when
they were down, they were down
# And when they were only halfway up,
they were neither up or down
# The grand old Duke of York
He had 10,000 men
# He marched them up and up and then
he marched them down again. #
Those 80 acres across the stream,
what do you think of them?
I don't have any money.
What are you on about?
I'd like to make a swap.
What for?
The piano.
What, the piano on the beach?
It's not marshy, is it?
No.
Oh, Baines, the music lover.
I never would have thought.
Hidden talents, George.
(LAUGHS)
I'd have to get lessons.
It wouldn't be much use without them.
Yes, I suppose you would.
Well, Ada can play.
I have it in a letter that she plays very well.
She's been playing
since she was five or six.
What on?
Well, on... on your piano.
That's the swap.
What does she say?
She says it's her piano
and she won't have him touch it!
He's an oaf. He can't read!
He's ignorant!
(KICKS FURNITURE)
He wants to improve himself,
and you'll be able to play it.
Teach him how to look after it!
You can't go on like this!
We're a family now.
We all make sacrifices, and so will you!
You will teach him,
and I will see to it!
(DOOR SLAMS)
(BIRDSONG)
(MEN CHATTER IN MAORl)
MAN: Oh. A Broadwood!
Oh, a fine instrument!
I've not seen one here,
nor in New South Wales
where I've tuned some 200.
Yes, they like their pianos there.
(SNIFFS)
Scent?
Hmm. And salt, of course.
(STRIKES TUNING FORK)
(STRIKES KEYS)
(MOURNFUL MUSIC)
Mother says she can't stand to teach
piano with it all out of tune.
So, I'm to do scales.
I hope you've scrubbed your hands.
(PLAYS SCALES)
Oh, it's in tune.
It's in tune.
(PLAYS NOTES)
I was teaching!
Mother would like to see
what you can play.
I'd rather not play.
I want to listen,
and learn that way.
Everyone has to practise.
I just want to listen.
Ow!
(ADA PLAYS SCALES)
Lovely.
(PLAYS SCALES WITH CHORDS)
(CONTINUES PLAYING SCALES
WITH CHORDS)
Oh, but tell me again.
Was he your teacher?
How did you speak to him?
What happened?
Why didn't you get married?
(GASPS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Shall I kiss you goodnight?
(DOOR CLOSES)
Get out! You need a bath!
Out! Bad dog!
Move! Go on!
(DOG BARKS)
Bad bloody dog!
(WHIMPERS)
Move it!
(JOYOUS PIANO MELODY PLAYS)
(GASPS)
Ada, wait. Wait.
Do you know how to bargain?
There's a way
you could have your piano back.
Do you want it back?
You want it back?
You see...
...I'd like us to make a deal.
There's things I'd...
...like to do while you play.
If you let me,
you can earn it back.
What do you think?
One visit for every key.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Your dress?
Skirt?
For every black one?
That's a lot less. Half.
Alright, alright.
Then the black keys.
(PLAYS BASS NOTE)
Poor baby!
What horrid little person
put you in the rain
and shoved you with a stick?
Hmm, baby? Huh?
Huh?
You're alright with moi.
MORAG: Scissors.
Thank you.
MAN: Nessie! Put that down
and come and put your hand out.
Oh, no. Use Mr Stewart.
Nessie, please!
ALISDAIR: No, no. Go on, Nessie.
Alright, Mary, come along.
Down here.
Come on, girl. Get a move on.
Oh, alright, then!
Down here. Put out your hand.
Now...
(GASPS)
No, no. Put out your hand. Here.
Now...
Aahh!
(LAUGHS)
Look, look! You're being attacked.
(SCREAMS)
(ALL LAUGH)
No, come on, come on. There you go.
(SCREAMS)
(ALL LAUGH)
And with the blood,
it will be a very good effect.
Here, Flynn!
Here, Flynn. Here, Flynn. Flynn!
Flynn, Flynn! Here, Flynn. Bad boy!
Heel, boy. Bad, bad boy!
Flynn! Flynn, don't be trouble.
Flynn? Flynn!
(WISTFUL PIANO MELODY PLAYS)
(KNOCKS)
(DOOR OPENS)
I want to speak to my mother.
(PIANO STOPS)
I don't want to be outside.
I want to watch.
I'll be very quiet!
I won't look at him!
(WISTFUL PIANO MELODY PLAYS)
MORAG: Be very careful.
NESSIE: Careful.
I hardly need to give one to you,
but here you are, anyway.
Don't be late.
You will see that
there are two times.
And since you are
accompanying a performer,
you will need to make
the earlier time.
ALISDAIR: Wait!
How are the lessons going?
He's getting on alright, then, is he?
She seems quietened down.
Is she more affectionate?
Ah, well. Slowly, slowly.
(PLAYS NOTE)
Lift your skirt.
(PLAYS MELODY)
Lift it higher.
(STOPS PLAYING)
(PLAYS MELODY)
Higher.
(KEEPS PLAYING)
(BANGS)
Higher!
(STOPS PLAYING)
Lift it higher.
(PLAYS MELODY)
(STOPS PLAYING)
(RESUMES PLAYING)
(CHILDREN SPEAK MAORl)
(WOMAN SPEAKS MAORl)
(LAUGHTER)
You no worry, Bainey.
I save you.
I have a wife.
I save her too!
(WOMAN SPEAKS REPROACHFULLY
IN MAORl)
(LAUGHS)
Where's your wife?
My wife?
Oh, she has a life of her own,
in Hull, England.
Must be ugly... for you to run away.
You need another wife.
(SPEAKS MAORl)
BAINES: Undo your dress.
I want to see your arms.
Play.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(PLAYS GENTLE MELODY)
(STOPS PLAYING)
Two keys.
(PLAYS GENTLE MELODY)
I shall listen hard at rehearsal
because I live too far
to come often.
Which sign is the word 'rehearsal'?
I can't imagine
a fate worse than being dumb.
To be deaf.
Oh, aye. Deaf too. Terrible! Awful!
Actually, to tell you
the whole truth,
Mother says most people
speak rubbish
and it's not worth the listen.
Well, that is a strong opinion.
Aye. It's unholy.
(MAN SPEAKS MAORl)
What do they say?
Are they selling?
Offer the blankets for half the land.
12.
Eugh!
(HOICKS)
Offer the guns, Baines.
Offer the guns.
What do they want the land for?
They don't do anything with it.
They don't cultivate it,
they don't burn it back. Nothing.
I mean, how do they
even know that it's theirs?
Um...
Thought I might as well
mark it out, you know, as we agreed.
Yes, why not?
Well, Ada says
you're doing well with the piano.
I'd like to come and hear you play.
What do you play?
Nothing just yet.
No?
(TENDER PIANO MELODY)
(SNIFFS)
Oh!
Oh.
Ada, four keys.
Why five? I just want to lie.
Alright, alright... five.
(GASPS)
(SINGS) # In the month of May
# The angels were sweetly singing
# A young man on his deathbed lay
# For love of Barbara Allen. #
(BELL CHIMES)
(DOG BARKS)
(THUNDER ROLLS)
MAN: Alright, take it easy.
Mind that hole, now. Steady.
Hang on now. There you go.
You there...
I'll dress you.
Will you marry me next week?
That's the way.
(LAUGHS)
Come on, come on!
We're running late!
If you haven't got your lip colour on,
line up behind Rose, please.
You all been to the lavatory?
ALL: Yes!
Why don't we drink to Myrtle?
(GIRLS SING)
MAN: I want no running on the stage!
WOMAN: They're bringing in
extra chairs!
Do not touch the blood in it!
Look who's here, hmm?
The musical Mr Baines.
Whoa. What are you going
to play for us tonight?
'Twinkle, Twinkle', eh, George?
How about a little
tinkle-tinkle, George?
Excuse me.
Perhaps you would you turn
the pages for Nessie?
She's playing for the children.
(MEN LAUGH)
I'm in costume.
MORAG: I'm very pleased
you've taken up the piano.
Now, where's this song?
WOMAN: Hello!
(AUDIENCE MEMBERS TALK)
George, excuse me,
how about 'Mary Had a Little Lamb'?
Baa-aaa.
Or a polka? Come on, George,
what's it to be, hmm?
Fools.
Come on, George. Move along.
(APPLAUSE)
MAN: Ladies and gentlemen,
could you take your seats, please?
We're about to begin.
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYS, APPLAUSE)
AUDIENCE: Ohhhh!
(ALL SING)
# Early in the month of May
# The angels were sweetly singing
# A young man on his deathbed lay
# For love of Barbara Allen
# Out of there sprung
a red rose full
# And out of it a briar
# Then they flew up
to the high church wall
# Till they could go no higher
# And then they came
in a true love's lock
# Red roses and sweet briar. #
(APPLAUSE)
And so the young maid came upon each
and all of Bluebeard's missing wives.
(AUDIENCE GASPS)
Their severed heads still bleeding,
their eyes still crying!
Slow down, Nessie, slow down.
But hush!
(CLANK!)
Who comes?
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
I am home early, my sweet wife!
(DOOR CLOSES)
Where art thou?
Oh! Husband!
What a surprise!
Yes, wife!
A surprise, indeed.
So now you know my secret.
No! No!
You, the youngest...
(WHIMPERS)
...and sweetest...
(SQUEALS)
...of all my wives...
No!
...must be prepared...
...to die!
(SCREAMS)
No! No! Wait!
I shall not wait!
No! (SCREAMS)
Bare your neck!
(SHOUTS IN MAORl)
(AUDIENCE SCREAMING)
(SHOUTS)
(SCREAMS)
So the ladies would be
quite alright.
MORAG: I'd like to introduce you.
This is Mrs Williams,
this is Mrs Parsons, this...
This is Mrs Reid,
this is Miss Palmer,
and this is Miss Kerr.
(SPEAKS MAORl)
It's very... very nice.
(PLAYS NOTE)
Hmm.
Do what you like.
Play what you like.
(PLAYS DARK MELODY)
(RUSTLING)
(GASPS)
I want to lie together
without clothes on.
How many would that be?
Yes. 10 keys.
(HUMS)
(BAINES MOANS)
(STOPS HUMMING)
(SPEAKS MAORl)
What the clock say, Mr Stewart?
Mr Stewart.
(LAUGHS)
Mmm. Mmm.
Never behave like that.
Never nowhere.
You're greatly shamed!
You've shamed these trunks.
I know why Mr Baines
can't play the piano.
You missed some here.
She never gives him a turn.
She just plays what she pleases.
And sometimes
she doesn't play at all.
When's the next lesson?
Tomorrow.
(PLAYS DISCORDANT NOTES)
(MEN SING)
I have given the piano back to you.
I've had enough.
The arrangement...
...is making you a whore
and me wretched.
I want you to care for me...
...but you can't.
It's yours. Leave.
Go on, go.
(SPEAKS MAORl)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(JAUNTY HORN MUSIC)
ALISDAIR: Stop right there!
This isn't yours. What are you
doing with the piano? Hmm?
He's given it to us.
Put that down. Put it down!
You're very cunning, Ada.
I've seen through you.
I'm not going to lose the land this way.
Stay there!
(SPEAKS MAORl)
WOMAN: Hori George don't
wanna see nobody. He's sick.
You got the Tupeka for Hira?
No.
Baines.
Baines... Baines, look.
I don't think
you should've given up the piano.
I'll make sure
that you're properly taught
with, you know, music written on sheets
and so on.
I don't want to learn.
You don't want to learn?
No.
What does this do to our bargain?
I mean...
I can't afford the piano
if you mean me to pay.
No, no payment.
I have given it back.
I'm not sure that I want it myself.
It was more to your wife
that I gave it.
Oh...
Oh, I see.
Well... I expect
she will appreciate it.
(SPEAKS MAORl)
This is all I have.
Bring that back!
(PLAYS DIFFERENT KEYS)
(PLAYS SCALES)
Is it alright?
Why don't you play something?
What will I play?
Play a jig.
Do I know any jigs?
Play a song, then.
(PLAYS THE PIANO AND SINGS)
(STOPS PLAYING AND SINGING)
Why won't she play? We get
the thing back, she just wanders off.
Well, keep playing.
(PLAYS THE PIANO AND SINGS)
(TAPS ALONG TO THE TUNE)
(MOURNFUL MUSIC)
(PLAYS TENDER MELODY)
(STOPS PLAYING)
Wait! Wait!
Why?! Why can't I?
I shan't practise and I don't care!
Blast and damn! Bugger her!
Bloody... bloody... Bugger her!
Let her fall face down
in boiling, bloody mud!
Let a mad dog bite her
till she bleeds!
Where's your mother?
Where's she gone?
TO HELL!
(FLOORBOARDS CREAK)
(DOOR OPENS)
So, what brings you here?
Did you leave something?
I've not found anything.
Does he know something?
The piano was not harmed?
It arrived safely?
Would you like to sit?
I am going to sit.
Ada...
Ada.
I am unhappy...
...because I... want you...
...because my mind has seized on you
and can think of nothing else.
This is why I suffer.
I...
I'm sick with longing.
I don't eat. I don't sleep.
(SIGHS)
So, if you've come
with no feeling for me...
...then go.
Go.
(OPENS DOOR)
Get out.
Leave!
(TENDER ORCHESTRAL MUSIC)
(BAINES MOANS PASSIONATELY)
(ADA MOANS)
(BAINES AND ADA MOAN)
(MOANS)
(MOANS SOFTLY)
What?
Whisper it.
Now you are going I am miserable.
Why is that?
Ada, I need to know, what will you do?
Will you come again?
(ALISDAIR GASPS)
Wait.
I don't know what you're thinking.
Does this mean something to you?
I already miss you.
Ada...
...do you love me?
Come tomorrow.
If you are serious, come tomorrow.
(GIRL GIGGLES)
GIRL: Mamma, stay still!
(GIGGLES)
Stay still!
(SQUEALS)
(GIGGLES)
Mmm. Mmm.
(LAUGHS)
Mamma! Mamma!
They're playing your piano!
Mamma!
(PLAYS DISCORDANT NOTES)
(HAMMERING)
Here, Papa.
(KISSES)
You shouldn't have gone up there,
should you?
I don't like it, and nor does Papa.
We can play cards if you like.
(PLAYS GENTLE MELODY)
She's asleep. Look.
(CONTINUES PLAYING)
One night she was found in her
nightgown on the road to London.
Grandpa said her feet were cut
so badly, she couldn't walk for a week.
Ada.
(MOANS)
Alisdair, is it because of our play?
Have the natives aggressed you?
Well, I have to say, you have done
the wrong thing here.
You have put the latch
on the outside, you see.
Now when you close the door,
it will be the Maoris
that lock you in, you see.
With the latch on that side,
you are quite trapped.
Quite trapped.
We have just come
from George Baines'
and they have taken him over.
It is no wonder he is leaving.
He got in too deep
with the natives.
They sit on his floor
as proud as kings but without a...
BOTH: Shred of manners.
He's quite altered.
As if they have been trying
some native witchcraft on him.
Well, tomorrow or the day after,
he'll be gone.
ALISDAIR: So Baines is packing up?
Well, he's nothing to pack,
but he's leaving. And it is just as well.
Nessie has foolishly grown
an affection for him.
(SOBS)
We have had some tears.
Stop it! Stop!
STOP!
MORAG: I am quite frightened
of the way back.
We must leave in good light.
We will be safe?
Oh, yes, if you leave now,
I'm sure of it.
(PLAYS MOODY MELODY)
MORAG: Nessie, hold this.
You know,
I am thinking of the piano.
She does not play the piano
as we do, Nessie. Up! Up!
(URINATES)
No. She is a strange creature.
And her playing is strange.
Like a mood that passes into you.
Up!
Now, your playing is plain and true
and that is what I like.
To have a sound creep inside you
is not at all pleasant.
(BIRDS FLUTTER)
What's that?
(SCREAMS)
It's a pigeon, Auntie.
I should have waited.
(GASPS)
I want to touch you.
Why can't I touch you?
Don't you like me?
(WOOD BREAKS)
(ROOSTER CROWS)
Come on, Lucky!
Who's gonna be my friend?
I'm coming to fetch you!
(CHICKENS CLUCK)
(WOOD CLATTERS)
(SHOUTS)
We must... get on.
I've decided to...
...trust you to stay here.
You won't see Baines?
Good.
Perhaps with time...
you might come to like me.
(FRETFUL ORCHESTRAL MUSIC)
(WATER SLOSHES)
GIRL: Stop complaining, I said.
And be quiet.
You'll just have to be naked
until I finish washing
and drying your clothes.
I don't mind if you're cold.
Be quiet!
No, we're not supposed
to visit him.
What?!
(FRETFUL ORCHESTRAL MUSIC CONTINUES)
(SINGS) # The grand old Duke of York
He had 10,000 men
# He marched them up
to the top of the hill
# And marched them down again
# And when they're up, they're up
# And when they're down,
they're down
# And when they're only halfway up
# They're neither up nor down
# The grand old Duke of York... #
(MAN SPEAKS MAORl)
Crooked, Mr Stewart.
Crooked.
Mother wanted me to give this
to Mr Baines.
I thought maybe it was not
the proper thing to do.
Shall I open it?
No. Give it to me.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(SPEAKS MAORl)
(MAN SPEAKS MAORl)
(RAIN PATTERS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Ohhh!
(GLASS SMASHES)
Why? I trusted you!
Oooh!
I trusted you! I trusted you!
Do you hear?!
Why do you make me hurt you?!
We could be happy.
You have made me angry! Speak!
You lied to me! You will answer for this.
Speak or not,
you will answer for this!
Do you love him?!
Do you?!
Is it him you love?!
No, she says... no!
(SCREAMS)
Mother!
Mamma!
You give this to Baines.
Tell him if he ever tries to see
her again, I'll take off another
and another and another.
Mamma!
Run!
(SOBS)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
(WOMAN SPEAKS MAORl)
(CRIES)
(WAILS)
What has happened?
Hush, hush.
(KEEPS CRYING)
What is it?
You're not to see her!
He'll chop her up!
(CRIES)
What happened?
Tell me.
(WAILS)
Tell me!
(DOOR SLAMS)
(SCREAMS)
Where is she?
Ssh! Quiet down! Quiet down!
Where is she?!
He chopped it off!
(CRIES)
What did she tell him?
(SPEAKS MAORl)
Oh.
I am going to crush his skull!
NO! NO! NO!
He'll chop them off!
You pushed me too hard.
You cannot send love to him.
You cannot do that.
Just even... even to think about it
makes me very angry.
I meant to love you.
I clipped your wing, that's all.
(SINGS) # We will be together
# You will see it will be better... #
Are you hot? My sweet love bird.
Are you feeling better?
What?
(RIFLE COCKS)
Oh, look at you.
It's your face.
I've had that face in my head,
hating it.
But now I'm here seeing it...
...it's nothing.
You have your marks. You look at me
through your eyes, yes.
You're even afraid of me.
Get up.
Baines...
...has Ada ever spoken to you?
You mean in signs?
No. Words.
Have you ever heard words?
No. Not words.
You never thought you heard words?
I heard it here. I heard her voice.
There in my head.
I watched her lips.
They didn't make the words.
But, yet, the harder I listened...
...the clearer I heard her.
You punished her wrongly.
It was me, my fault.
She said...
...I'm afraid of my will.
"Of what it might do.
It is so strange and strong."
She said...
..."I have to go. Let me go.
"Let Baines take me away.
Let him try and save me."
I wish her gone. I wish you gone.
I want to wake up and...
...and find that this...
...was all a dream.
That's what I want.
(PEOPLE SPEAK MAORl)
MORAG: It was a terrible shock.
NESSIE: Aye, it was.
Oh, dear.
(MAN SPEAKS MAORl)
(BAINES SPEAKS MAORl)
(SPEAKS MAORl)
No. She needs it. She must have it.
(MEN CHANT)
(SINGS IN MAORl)
What did she say?
She said, "Throw
the piano overboard."
It's quite safe. They are managing.
She doesn't want it.
She says it's spoiled!
I've been given the key.
I'll have it mended.
(MAN SPEAKS MAORl)
Please, Ada. Ada!
You will regret it. It's your piano,
I want you to have it.
She doesn't want it!
Ada, sit down! Sit down!
Throw it over!
Sit down!
Alright, we'll throw it over.
(BAINES SPEAKS IN MAORl)
(MAN SPEAKS IN MAORl)
Ahhh!
(GASPS)
ADA: What a death.
What a chance.
What a surprise.
My will has chosen life.
Still, it has had me spooked,
and many others besides.
I teach piano now in Nelson.
George has fashioned me
a metal fingertip.
I'm quite the town freak,
which satisfies.
(PLAYS GENTLE PIANO MELODY)
I am learning to speak.
My sound is still so bad
I feel ashamed.
Deh, deh...
I practise only
when I am alone and it is dark.
Kah, kah, kah, kah, kah.
Vah, vah, vah.
Bah, bah, bah.
Pah, pah.
At night I think of my piano
in its ocean grave.
And sometimes of myself
floating above it.
Down there, everything
is so still and silent
that it lulls me to sleep.
It is a weird lullaby,
and so it is...
It is mine.
"There is a silence
where hath been no sound.
where no sound may be.