(VOLARE PLAYING)
(TRAFFIC OFFICER
SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(CRASHING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(MEN ARGUING IN ITALIAN
IN DISTANCE)
Sorry.
I don't speak English
very well.
I'm from Roma.
My job, as you can see,
is to see that
the traffic move.
I stand up here,
and I see everything.
All people.
I see life.
In this city, all is a story.
See that young man over there?
He's a Roman.
Michelangelo.
Oh, uh, scusi.
Um, Fontana di Trevi?
- Uh, so it's two blocks.
- Uh-huh, two blocks.
- And then across the piazza.
- Okay, and that's
Piazza Mignanelli...
- No. No. - Okay, no,
Piazza di Spagna is this...
- No, so this is Piazza Venezia.
- No. Okay.
Okay. Right?
- Look, I'll show you.
This is Piazza...
- Yeah, I don't...
I don't know.
- Look, you know what?
I'm going that way.
I can show you.
- Thank you.
Thank you so much.
You speak very good English.
- That's because of my work.
I visit New York often.
- Oh, that's where
I'm from. - Oh.
- What do you do?
- I'm a lawyer.
- And you are,
let me guess, a tourist.
- For the summer.
I'm Hayley.
- Hi. Michelangelo.
- Hi.
(INAUDIBLE)
It's been
an unbelievable summer.
What you read about
in all those romantic novels.
American goes to Rome,
meets handsome Roman
at Trevi Fountain.
(LAUGHS) He's utterly adorable.
NARRATOR:
Now, Antonio and Milly
were also a young couple
in love.
They married
in the little town of Pordenone
and came to Rome
for their honeymoon
with plans to settle there.
And then there was
that well-known American architect
concluding his vacation
with a few days in Home.
(ALARM BEEPING) And, finally,
we meet Leopoldo Pisanello,
an average Roman citizen
of the middle class.
Dependable, agreeable,
predictable.
Everything happened so fast.
- I can't wait
to bring you home
and introduce you
to my parents.
- I can't wait to meet them.
This looks delicious.
Buona, Mamma.
- And what do you do, Hayley?
- I'm self-employed.
I help clients find art.
My background is in Fine Arts.
- He's lawyer.
I'm very proud.
All my children.
I work night and day
so they get education.
We want to meet your parents.
They come to Rome?
- Well, yes.
As a matter of fact,
they're on their way.
PILOT OVER PA:
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are beginning our descent into
Fiumicino Airport in Home.
We may experience
some turbulence.
Please keep
your seat belts fastened
and make sure all trays
are in an upright position.
Great. Turbulence.
My favorite.
- No, if you'd just relax
and stop clenching your fists.
- I can't unclench
when there's turbulence.
You know I'm an atheist.
(RUMBLING) I don't like this.
It's bumping.
The plane is bumping.
I don't like when
it moves like...
- I can't wait
to meet her fiance.
- You know, he's a Communist.
- No, there's not even
a Communist party here any more.
No, he's just very, very left.
- Hey, listen, I was very left
when I was his age, too,
but I was never a Communist.
Well... I couldn't
share a bathroom.
- No, he's not a Communist.
He's just a do-gooder.
- What does
it mean, "a do-gooder"?
- Well, he's not into
material possessions, you know?
- Well, well, look,
if she's going to marry an Italian,
I want her to marry
somebody with...
You know, with
material possessions,
with a yacht,
with a couple of Ferraris,
with a villa in Sardinia.
You know, don't you
want our little Hayley
to marry into Eurotrash?
(RUMBLING) Oh, I don't like.
I don't like when
the plane does that.
- Just stop it. Stop it.
- It's not... I can't...
- Just relax. Okay?
- I don't like that.
I get a bad feeling in...
- Breathe.
- Okay.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Grazie.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- Do you like it? - I love it.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- It's late.
My uncles and aunts will be here.
We have to hurry.
- Will they like me?
- What are you worried about?
You're beautiful. Just be yourself.
Don't worry.
They're important people.
Perhaps a bit severe.
But don't let it throw you,
they're nice.
Starting next week
I'll be working in their firm...
...and I don't want to say or do
anything that could jeopardize...
...his wonderful opportunity
they're giving us.
- It'll be fine. You'll impress them.
- You think so?
- I know so.
About your question on the train,
yes, I'll miss Pordenone...
...but this position is too good
to turn down.
Think, Milly, if all goes well,
we will be living in Rome...
...entering society,
having children.
And maybe one day
we will own a villa like my uncles.
- I have to get my hair done.
I look like a small town school teacher.
I want to look chic.
- It's late.
Do you have to go now?
- I'll be right back.
- I don't want them waiting for us.
- Okay. But hurry.
- I will.
Ciao.
- Hurry.
I'm sorry, the salon is booked up.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- ls there another one near here?
Exit the hotel, go right,
down two blocks and to the left.
Past the archway, on the right,
you'll see a small bridge.
Cross the bridge, go left,
and you'll see it on the right.
- Grazie.
The food is better
than Malibu, I'll say that.
- I can't wait to do
some sightseeing.
- Oh, John can show us around.
He used to live here.
- Oh, God, Carol.
That was 30 years ago.
- So?
MAN: It must have
been great then.
- Yeah, it was fabulous.
- I was young and in love
and a complete fool.
- But it's the Eternal City.
It never changes.
And I, too, want
to go see the ruins.
It is Rome, after all.
- All those old ruins
just depress me.
I get Ozymandias melancholia.
Besides, I saw it all
when I lived here.
- So we'll leave you,
and then we'll hook up later.
Okay?
WOMAN: Okay.
- I'm just not
a good sightseer.
I prefer just to walk
the little streets.
- "Ozymandias melancholia."
Where'd you get that phrase?
(CHUCKLES)
What...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Excuse me, are you...
Are you John Foy?
- Yes. How did you
know that?
- No, I recognized your picture
from the Herald Tribune.
You design all those
shopping malls.
(LAUGHS) That's how
you think of me?
- No, I'm an architect.
Studying to be, anyhow.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You working
on a project in Rome?
- No, a vacation.
I lived in Rome for a year when
I was your age.
- Really? Where?
- Here... Trastevere.
- Yeah, I live here.
I'm on Via dei Neofiti.
- That's my old
stomping ground.
I've been wandering
around all day.
- I can't seem to find it.
- Really? No, it's literally
two blocks up to the left.
- Well, I... (SIGHS)
- What?
Do you want me to...
You want me to show you?
- I don't know
if I should revisit it.
But... Okay.
Why not?
(ALARM BEEPING)
I saw this honey for half the price.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Finish your breakfast.
- I'm not hungry.
- You have to eat.
Where is Camilla?
You know why there's
so much unemployment?
Because people are being replaced
by advanced technology.
- What's on the movie page?
- Eat! Here's Camilla.
You're always late.
If you ask me,
the way the world is going...
...one day the whole planet
will be speaking Chinese.
- No one's asking you.
- No one care what you or I think.
We just have to pay taxes.
Look, look!
Here she comes.
- Where was she
when we had the blackout...
...and I was stuck in the elevator
for two hours?
Oh to be young and single,
or at least single.
Did you see her do that? Beautiful.
- You still wouldn't have a chance.
- Why not?
- She takes her weekends with the boss.
- Since when?
- Since always.
- If you ask me...
- What, again?
What, I can't say one thing?
If you ask me...
It's an enigmatic film.
Very interesting.
Beautiful.
Better than The King's Speech.
- Oh, come on!
- I didn't get it. (CAMERAS CLICKING)
The director didn't want you
to understand. Life's a mystery...
...the atmospheric cinematography.
Did you see that shot? (CROWD CLAMORING)
if I could vote
there would be no question...
- But you don't vote.
- I don't vote, but if I could...
- I hear Brad Pitt and Angelina
are in town promoting a movie.
- Do you think it's Brad Pitt?
This week we'll interviewing Tony Blair...
(MAN SPEAKING IN ITALIAN ON RADIO)
...the winner of the Miss Universe
contest and Johnny Depp.
(BELL TOLLING)
PHYLLIS: Oh, my God.
Look at this city.
You're tipping him in euros.
When you realize
what you just gave him,
you're going to have
a heart attack.
- Well, you know, they gave us such
a great room, Phyllis,
and I'm delighted to be here.
- Yeah.
- This is great.
- See, you always
used to travel for work.
Isn't it nice to be
someplace for pleasure?
- No, I miss work.
I don't like being retired.
- Oh.
- You know, I keep
having fantasies
that I'm going to wind up
an old person in a hotel lobby
watching a communal
television set and drooling,
with a colostomy bag
or something.
- But, you see, you equate
retirement with death.
- Yes, exactly.
Exactly.
- Yeah, but it's a fantasy,
because you're not dying.
- No, I'm not dying now,
but, you know,
it's conceivable I might one day.
(LAUGHS)
- You know, I'm talking 50,
60 years from now.
(SIGHS)
- Can I get a little water...
- Oh, sure.
- Yeah, you just have to ask.
- You know, and I
haven't made my mark.
I haven't really achieved what I wanted
to do. - Oh, you did just fine.
Your problem was that
you were just a little ahead of your time.
- Hey, I'm way
ahead of my time.
You know, you married
a very bright guy.
I got a 150, 160 IQ.
- You're figuring it in euros.
In dollars, it's much less.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
(CLEARS THROAT)
HAYLEY: Hello.
- Oh, darling.
- Hi, Mom. Hi.
Hi, Dad.
- Hi.
Hi. Hi.
- How are you?
- Good. Good.
- Hello.
- This is Michelangelo.
- Hi.
- This is my father.
- Nice to meet you.
- My mother.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
- Did you have a good trip?
- Good trip? Yeah,
we had a good trip. - Yeah.
- I thought it was a little bumpy
when we landed,
but, you know,
you'll probably read about it
in the paper if the airline ever
recovers the black box.
- So, our plan is to get married
around Christmas.
- Oh, really?
(STAMMERING) You're a lawyer,
Michael-angelo?
- Michel.
- Michel. Michel.
Michel?
- Yes.
- Call you Michel?
- Yes, for the oppressed,
those who cannot pay.
- Ah. So, pro bono.
So... (CHUCKLES)
She'll taking in washing soon.
Um, would you like
a drink or something or...
MICHELANGELO: Sure. Um...
HAYLEY: Yeah. Water?
- Oh, would you like
water or...
- Yeah, water's fine.
Water. Water is fine.
- Hayley told me that you work
in the music business.
- I did. I'm retired.
I used to work for...
In the classical music division of
a record company.
And I was an opera director
for many years.
I used to...
HAYLEY: You know,
Michelangelo's great-grandfather
knew Verdi.
- Really? Well,
I staged some Verdi. I did.
But basically,
I did avant-garde stuff.
Atonal things, but I jazzed up
a couple of classics.
You know, I did a production
of Rigoletto
where all the characters
were dressed as white mice.
I did Tosca once
all in a phone booth.
- Jerry was ahead of his time.
- Yeah, I was a little,
you know, a little fast
for mass appeal, but...
You know, then
the productions got...
Between the critics
and the costs, the unions, we...
- I'm sorry, you don't
like the unions?
- Well, you know, unions...
- You know, without the unions,
the worker would be
ground into dust.
- Yes, I understand what you're saying,
Michael-angelo, but...
HAYLEY: Michel.
Michelangelo.
- What?
- Michelangelo.
- Michel.
Michel.
Yeah, like
Michael-Angelo, the painter,
only, with him,
for some reason, it's Michel.
- Michelangelo feels very deeply
about the workers.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Excuse me, Via della Penna?
- Take the next right,
go down one block...
...you'll come to a gelato shop,
walk one block...
...and turn left.
- Grazie.
- Prego.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN) At the next traffic
light, there's a fish restaurant.
You can't miss it.
Walk one block, make a right, go up
two blocks and take another right.
- You following?
- Yes, yes. Thank you.
- Prego.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SPLASH)
(LINE RINGING)
Here.
This is where I live.
- Oh. Nice.
This might have been
my exact street.
- Hey, can I ask you in
for coffee?
- Coffee?
- Yeah. Yeah, come on in.
Sally makes great espresso.
- Sally?
- Yeah, my girlfriend.
She's studying here.
Hey, Sally.
- Hi.
- Hey. I brought someone home
who used to live here.
- Oh, my gosh.
Yeah. This is John Foy.
This is Sally.
- Wow.
- Hello.
- Hi. It's Sally.
That's so wild.
- Yeah, I know.
- You were right. She's lovely.
- Yeah, she's the best.
- Well... Oh, can I
get you something to drink?
I could make some coffee.
- That would be great, honey.
Yeah, thank you very much.
- Thank you.
- Oh. Oh, my gosh!
My friend, Monica, she called.
She's going to be in Rome,
and I told her
she could stay with us.
- Ah. Well, so I'll finally
get to meet her.
- She just broke up
with her boyfriend,
so she's a bit at loose ends.
- Trouble.
Trouble in River City.
- What, trouble?
Why trouble?
- You're just going
to love her.
She's smart and funny
and interesting.
Men just adore her.
I think it's because
of the sexual vibe
that she gives off.
Mmm-hmm.
- And how long
is she coming for?
- Oh, I don't know.
Between the breakup,
and then her acting career
isn't going that well...
- Jesus Christ, can't you see
the situation
is fraught with peril?
- What? Give me a break.
Her friend is coming.
What do I care?
I'm not looking for anything.
I'm perfectly happy
with Sally, and...
Actually, judging
from Sally's description,
Monica's kind of like a neurotic,
unpredictable type.
- Beautiful, funny,
smart, sexual
and also neurotic?
It's like filling
an inside straight.
Monica.
Even her name is hot.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Congratulations.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Yes?
- I have your special gift.
- What gift?
- A special gift for a special man.
- What is this special gift?
- I am.
Everything's been paid in full.
I'm yours.
- I think there's been a mistake.
- Whatever pleases you.
- That's okay. Please leave.
- I can't. They'd be very upset.
- Who?
- They said you were high-strung
and would be quite surprised.
But you're the lucky winner.
- What winner?
- The winner of the bet.
- What bet?
- Tommy and Fabio. They paid me
and said to say, congratulations.
- I don't know who they are.
Please leave, miss.
- I am told to ask no questions.
I am hereto fulfill your dreams.
- What are you doing?
Please, miss. You must leave.
- You are Mr. DeBroca, room 504?
- You have the right room
but the wrong person.
And now you must leave.
- Anybody here?
(GASPS)
Excuse us. So sorry.
- I told you we should wait.
- That is not what you think.
Come in.
- Our date was for noon.
The door was open.
- You can't just barge in
without knocking.
- What a way to meet your new bride.
- She's not my bride.
- No?
- You're joking I hope.
- Of course I'm joking.
This is my wife.
- I am his Uncle Paolo.
- Giovanna.
- Uncle Sal.
- Aunt Rita.
- Anna.
- Anna?
Isn't her name Milly?
- Milly? Uh...
Yes. Definitely Milly.
Her middle name is Anna.
- Milly?
- Milly.
- We'll wait downstairs.
Don't worry about us.
Let's go Paolo.
- We'll see you soon.
(CHUCKLES)
- I'm dead.
My life is over. I'm ruined.
- Just tell them the truth.
It was all a mistake.
- How do I do that?
They saw us on the bed.
I'm in my underwear.
They won't believe me.
It's useless.
They'll think my wife is out of the hotel
so I hired a call girl.
Why did you grab me like that?
- I was paid to make love to DeBroca.
- And you leave the door open? Idiot!
- I thought I closed it!
They barged in.
These upper class feel entitled.
- Milly will be back any minute.
We have to get out of here now.
You have to pretend to be my wife.
- Pretend to be your wife?
I'm not an actress.
And you just called me an idiot.
- I'm sorry. I apologize.
You must help me. And hurry.
If Milly walks in I will jump
out of the window, I will kill myself.
- Sooner or later they'll find out.
- I need to buy more time, so I can
think of something, some way out.
We need to get out of here now.
SALLY:
Can you walk faster?
- I'm walking fine.
Relax.
- Her flight should
have landed.
Relax. By the time she goes through
customs and luggage,
we'll have been
waiting an hour.
- I hope that you don't
fall in love with her.
- In love with her?
What the hell does that mean?
- Well, men always,
they just go crazy for her.
- Well, I'm crazy for you.
Okay, that's her.
Monica!
- Hi!
It's so good to see you.
- You look so great.
- Nothing special, right?
- No, no, nothing
special at all.
I got no buzz.
I mean, look at her.
This is the hot femme fatale?
- Of course, she has been
flying for 14 hours.
But you will admit
there is something about her.
- All I can say is,
if something is clicking,
it's so subconscious,
I'm totally unaware.
She's no big deal. Certainly not some
formidable heartbreaker.
She's a disheveled,
out-of-work actress.
- I've been wanting you to come for so
long, and now you're here. I just...
- Hi. Hi. I'm Jack.
- This is Monica.
- Hi. It's so nice to meet you.
- I'm sorry.
- I mean, I must look awful.
- What do you mean? - I mean, please
don't make any snap judgments.
- No, you look fine.
- Like, I grown on people.
I just... I can never
sleep on planes.
I had a scotch
and three Ambien, but still...
- Pretty cozy,
this ride into town.
- I keep telling you, I have no interest
in Monica.
I just hope having her around
is not going to
interfere with my work.
- But there is an element
of excitement...
A germ, a spark, one molecule.
God.
I see it so clearly,
now that I'm older.
Thank you.
Dinner was great.
- Thank you.
JACK: Ah, yeah.
You're becoming
a really great Italian chef.
SALLY: Well, I figured,
it was your first night here,
so, why not stay in?
- No, yeah, it's perfect,
just the three of us.
What are you reading?
- Oh, the poetry of Yeats.
(SIGHS)
- The "gong-tormented sea."
- Yeah, yeah.
You know it?
- Do you want to talk
about the breakup with Donald?
- Well, Donald was gay.
It was my ego
that thought I could change him,
and I couldn't,
and believe me, I tried.
- Oh, yeah?
How does one try?
- Well, I mean,
I don't want to get graphic,
but, I mean, let's just say
that I gave it my all.
And it's such a shame
because he is so brilliant
and he's so wonderful
out of bed.
I mean, so much fun to be with.
(STAMMERING) I tried
to show him how sex with a woman
could be as exciting
or even more so
than with someone
from his own sex.
And he tried.
He... He did try.
But, in the end,
I struck out, so...
- I remember you
saying how much fun
you had when he
took you to Paris.
- Have you ever
had sex with a man?
Me, sex with a man?
God, no, no, no.
I mean, no.
It's not something
I'm interested in ever doing.
- Why are you blushing?
Probably because
you want to try it.
Look, I always had a little yen
for sleeping with a woman,
and when I finally did it,
it was... (CHUCKLES)
It was very intense.
It was very exciting,
but unnerving.
- I really have no repressed...
- I shot this TV movie once,
and one of the scenes
was with this incredible
lingerie model.
I mean, she was to die.
And for whatever reason,
I get this message one day
from the assistant director
that Miss Lee
would like me to go
to her dressing room.
And why she was so suddenly
obsessed with me, I don't...
And I go.
And she's in a robe,
and she takes it off,
and gives me a big hug
and kiss,
and I just become crazed.
I mean, I become so excited.
I mean, she was just
too beautiful to turn down.
We had this thing
for, like, three months.
Yeah, it was like being
in an erotic dream.
And on the one hand,
yes, it was very exciting,
but on the other hand,
just very confusing.
And that's when I started
seeing the shrink
five days a week, and...
Well, fortunately,
Jamal came along,
and we had
a great relationship.
And as great
as the orgasms were
with Victoria,
they were stronger with Jamal.
And a lot less bewildering.
Excuse me.
- She's something, isn't she?
- Yeah, I think I need a few minutes to
recover from her story.
I'm still vibrating.
- I think she's so fun.
- Yeah, but look, finally,
what has she got?
I mean, no real acting career,
no relationship
that's remotely stable,
sleeping pills, shrinks...
- You sound like you're trying
to convince yourself.
MONICA: Hey,
I've got a great idea.
Let's go for
a little walk tonight.
- Oh, no, I'm exhausted.
But why don't you
take her, Jack?
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
God, no, that would be
a catastrophe.
- Why are you so worried?
You think of me
as this seductress.
This is your problem.
- Bullshit.
You deliberately made up
this provocative story
with some lingerie model.
- It was true, most of it.
Okay, I exaggerate a little.
I like to embellish.
It's a part of
my creative charm.
- Come on. Come on.
Why don't you come?
- Sally, you've got
to go along with them.
(INAUDIBLE)
(ALARM BEEPING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(PHOTOGRAPHERS CLAMORING)
(LEOPOLDO SPEAKING ITALIAN)
What's going on?
What is this? Are you crazy?
Move away.
You've made a mistake.
Sofia!
Sofia! Look at this!
What's going on?
What do you want?
(LEOPOLDO SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Move away! I'll call the police!
I'm a responsible person.
I have to go to work!
These people are crazy.
- Whose car is this?
- We'll be late for the studio.
- But I'm late for work.
- That's right, Mr. Pisanello.
- Sofia, come with me.
Good morning and welcome to TG3.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Today we have a special guest with us,
Leopoldo Pisanello.
Welcome, Mr. Pisanello. Welcome.
- Thank you. Sorry, why am I here?
- Tell us,
what did you have for breakfast?
- Coffee and two slices of bread
with butter and jam.
- Two slices of bread.
What were they like?
- They were good. Toasted.
- You prefer toasted bread?
- I do, yes.
- Can you tell us why?
- Yes, well, I don't know.
I usually favor toasted bread.
- White bread or wheat bread?
- White.
- So it's safe to say that
Leopoldo Pisanello prefers...
...two slices of bread toasted.
- Yes. And coffee with milk.
No sugar.
- And you shaved before
or after breakfast?
(ALL APPLAUDING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
You were extraordinary!
(CLAMORING)
My God, still here! Enough!
Move away! Sofia. Sofia!
Get out of here.
Leopoldo!
You were brilliant.
The phone hasn't stopped ringing.
- Yes, but...
- They want you
for the eight o'clock news tomorrow.
- What? Me? But why?
- You're famous.
PHYLLIS: 95...
JERRY: 95.
- Oh, I don't know.
I can't find the address.
- This is 91.
So, it's... (STAMMERING)
This goes down.
That's 93.
- Uh-huh.
- Can't be 95.
95's a funeral parlor.
- Oh, then we're right.
- What do you mean,
we're right?
- Mr. Santoli's a mortician.
- You're kidding.
- He owns a funeral parlor,
and don't make an issue of it.
- Jesus, the kid's a Communist,
the father's a mortician.
Does the mother run
a leper colony?
- I guess they live upstairs.
- Excuse me.
95... This is 95?
- Yes, 95, Santoli.
- Yes, yes.
- Someone dead?
- No, but it's early.
- No, no.
We're Hayley's parents.
- Hayley's parents.
- Yeah.
- Welcome. Welcome.
Such a big pleasure
to meet you.
Oh, I'm sorry
if I'm not cleaned up.
I work all day.
But please come to our place.
We live over there.
Oh, thank you.
- Please, come, come. Follow me.
- Thank you so much.
- You have a nice trip?
- Oh, it was wonderful.
Wonderful.
- Great.
GIANCARLO:
Please, come in.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Oh. Hello.
- Hello. Nice to meet you.
- Phyllis.
Jerry.
- Buongiorno.
- Oh, Mariangela don't
speak good English.
- No.
- No, no.
- What to drink?
- Wine would be great.
- Wine.
Michelangelo and Hayley
should be here any minute.
But if you excuse me now,
I need to go to clean up.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Okay.
HAYLEY: Hello.
MICHELANGELO: Mamma.
Hi. Hi!
- Hello.
- You guys find
the place okay, right?
- We just followed a passing hearse,
and here we are.
You know.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Oh, Mom, the green ones
are like a tapenade.
- Oh.
- They're so good.
- Oh, you should try them.
They're amazing.
- Oh, okay.
- Oh.
(LAUGHS) Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Oh, excuse me...
It's great.
I mean, I try and make this,
but I never get this taste.
- Well, she could teach you.
(BOTH SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- No. Oh, no, really.
- Oh, come on.
Mom.
- It's a free cooking lesson.
- I don't want to be a...
- I'll interpret for you.
- Si. Si. Si, si.
- Have one.
I have to find out how to...
(SNIFFING)
- Mmm, formaldehyde.
(GIANCARLO SINGING OPERA
IN DISTANCE)
(SINGING OPERA)
(SINGING CONTINUES)
She showed me how to
make these, Jerry,
but of course she gets
the mozzarella fresh
every day
from Naples. Oh.
- What do you do, Phyllis?
- I'm a psychiatrist.
- Oh.
(REPEATS IN ITALIAN)
- I've never been to Naples,
but I hear it's beautiful.
- Oh, there's no cooking
like in Naples.
- You see much of Italy, Jerry?
- Jerry, he's asking you
a question.
- Hmm?
Just of Naples.
(STAMMERING) Have you ever
taken singing lessons, Giancarlo?
- Singing lessons?
No. What for?
- Well, you have just
a natural voice...
- I'm no singer.
Ising for me.
Since I was a boy.
- You have a very,
very beautiful gift.
- Yeah.
- No.
She says that I make only
too much noise
around the house.
- And no one's ever heard you?
- No. He's our own
private Caruso.
- You have a fantastic voice.
Have you ever thought
of doing anything with it?
- He sings for pleasure,
not money.
- Well, there's a great deal
of pleasure in money.
You know, you...
It's green and crinkly.
You can fondle the bills.
- Listen, I'm no singer.
- No, I don't know.
Is it possible that after dinner, you could
sing something for me?
- Me?
No, no, no, no, no.
I'd become too embarrassed.
- No, no, right here.
Just among...
- Oh, no, no, please.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Ah, si.
- You know,
I have a friend in town here
who's in the
recording business.
And if you would just sing...
He's a very knowledgeable man.
And, you know, if you'd just...
When you're not busy,
when you're not
cremating anybody...
- Look, he already said no.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Dad's not a singer.
I'm sure you don't want him
to make a fool of himself.
- Jerry, back off.
- Okay, forget it.
I'm not gonna say another word.
I... Forget it.
But the guy has
a fantastic voice.
This is...
You have...
Hey, I'm finished.
The subject's closed.
But his voice is great.
Somebody's got to do
something with this,
because he's got...
- Jerry, Jerry...
Not me. I'm not saying I would.
But he's got a...
The man is a genius.
- That's enough.
- He's got a natural, great, natural...
- Oh...
- I'm not saying anything.
You know, I'm off the subject.
(QUIETLY) Great voice.
Fantastic.
Big star.
Big, big...
- What's the name of the hotel? - I can't
remember. (SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Was it around here?
- Yes, more or less. It was red...
Here we are. Sorry we took so long.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Yes.
(SIGHS)
You don't have a more relaxed dress?
- We'll be seeing some
rather important people.
- I mean, we love your look.
- What?
- But some of our colleagues
might not understand.
- The train lost my luggage,
so this has to be it.
- We arranged a private tour
of the Vatican for you.
- How nice! Isn't it darling?
- Yes, I know it well.
- Let's go, then.
- Let's hope they let her in.
Miss.
Are you okay?
- Yes, thank you.
Grazie...
But you... aren't you Pia Fusari?
- You recognize me?
- Si.
You're one of my favorite actresses.
- I'm flattered.
- What are you doing just walking
the streets like an ordinary person?
- We're making a movie here.
- You want to watch?
- Me?
Yes!
Si.
Oh my, that's Giulietta Falcone.
No! There's Luca Salta.
I adore Luca Salta.
He's so charismatic.
I can't believe this.
He painted that ceiling
on scaffolding lying down.
- Can you imagine working
all the time on your back?
- I can.
- Shoot. I'm gonna be
late to class.
Could you take Monica
around today?
- No, I can't. I'm working on
my drawings.
- Oh, please.
She doesn't know Rome at all.
- No, no, I can't, I can't.
I don't have time to go visit
the Colosseum
for the millionth time.
- Please, just...
Just, please, for me.
Could you do it for me?
(SIGHS)
Thank you.
Okay.
MONICA:
I mean, wow.
That is so impressive.
JACK: Oh, I know.
The lines,
the empty space. - Yeah.
- Yeah, exactly. It was a lot of
negative space.
Are you sure I'm not taking you
away from anything
important today?
- No, I think that I...
I was worried
I was taking you
away from something.
If you had work to do...
- No, no, I'm fine.
This is actually
my favorite thing to do.
Yeah, if you weren't here,
I'd probably be doing this alone.
(MONICA CHUCKLES)
I mean, it's incredible
that the Colosseum
is still standing
after thousands of years.
You know, Sally and I have to
retile the bathroom
every six months.
These guys were truly, (SIGHS)
truly brilliant architects.
- I just find it so ironic
that there was once
this magnificent civilization
and now just these ruins.
- Yeah.
- I call that futile feeling.
Ozymandias melancholia.
- Okay.
MONICA: Is this the kind
of thing you want to build?
JACK: Oh, I'd be very
proud to have done this.
- Did you always want
to be an architect?
- You'll laugh if I tell you what
my ambition is.
- What? No, no, I won't.
- To build radical structures.
I mean, to be scandalous.
To change the
architectural landscape.
Are you interested
in architecture?
- I'm interested in Gaudi.
- Huh.
- Antonio Gaudi.
I mean, for me, La Sagrada Familia
is poetry in stone.
- Oh, bullshit.
You had six months of college.
You know nothing of architecture
but a few names.
You saw the movie
The Fountainhead.
- I just find something so sexy
about an uncompromising artist.
I mean, I would do anything
to spend a night
with Howard Roark.
- Oh, God, save me, save me.
Another young woman who
wants to give her body to Howard Roark.
- Oh, come on, I mean,
she is fun to talk to.
- Yes, and you buy into
her bullshit because
she seems to know all
the right things to say.
She knows names,
she knows buzzwords,
she knows certain
cultural phrases that imply
that she knows more
than she does...
The anxiety of influence,
the Bartok string quartets,
the perversion of the dialectic,
La Sagrada Familia,
"the gong-tormented sea."
- So, what, I should press her
and not let her get away
with the name dropping?
- But you didn't.
- Yeah, I mean, it's sort of charming
that she's a con artist.
- Yes.
She does have
a certain something
which trumps logic,
so go ahead,
walk into the propeller.
- So, was it okay
with Monica today
or did she just
drive you crazy?
- Yeah, I really don't
have time to spend
squiring her around, you know?
I'm trying to work.
- I started having those
insecure thoughts again today.
- Please, stop.
- No, because I thought
maybe it was a bad idea
that I put you guys together
for the whole day,
because what if you ended up
attracted to her?
- Could you please
stop worrying?
She's a self-obsessed
pseudo-intellectual.
I mean, yeah, she's pretty,
but so what?
- She is.
She's very pretty.
- Yeah, she's very pretty.
I mean, not conventionally.
- I'd like to see her
with someone.
Who do we know?
We must know someone...
- Grazie.
- ...to fix her up with.
- Uh, yeah.
I'm sure we could
scare somebody up.
- Who?
- Hey, what about
Leonardo Basso?
Yeah, we exercise together.
He's nice-looking and he's smart,
he makes good dough.
Actually, I think he broke up with
some girl who is also an actress.
I think he'd be a perfect
choice for Monica.
- That's great.
- Yeah.
- Can you call him?
I'll be the matchmaker.
- Great.
Please come in, Mr. Pisanello.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
This will be your new office.
- My new office?
But I'm a clerk.
(LAUGHS)
- Very amusing. Serafina, come.
We have a renowned man
in our company.
She'll attend to your needs.
All day long.
- With pleasure.
- Grazia.
You will attend to me all day long?
- Yes. lam here
for whatever you may need.
- Si.
(REPORTERS MURMURING)
Is he close?
(REPORTERS CLAMORING)
(CAMERAS CLICKING) Easy, easy.
- Mr. Pisanello, how was your day?
- My day?
- Yes, how was it?
- It was fine.
I spilled coffee
on a few documents.
Apart from that it was fine.
- Mr. Pisanello was caught short
spilling some coffee.
But quick thinking saved the moment
from escalating into...
...a full-blown crisis
with perhaps loss of life.
Why the coffee was spilled
will be the subject of tonight's...
...in-depth analysis, with special guests
from the illycaffé company...
...and the Brazilian ambassador
to the U.N.
- Can we get a statement?
- A statement?
- Yes sir. A statement.
- Any statement?
- Please.
- Well... It looks like rain.
- You heard it here.
Mr. Pisanello says it might rain.
- How will you be sleeping tonight?
- I usually sleep on my back.
- Leopoldo Pisanello
sleeps on his back.
Tell us, have you ever slept
on your stomach?
- No, I suffer from indigestion.
Nothing serious.
But enough now. No more, no more.
Please stop.
(ALL CLAMORING) Go away.
What do you want from me?
Do I sleep on my stomach.
How's this dress? All I have
are these junky cotton prints.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
I have to buy some clothes
now that you're famous.
- Sofia, I'm tired.
I have a headache.
I had a horrible day
with reporters.
I don't want to go
to the movie premiere.
- We must.
They're counting on our appearance.
- Who, Sofia?
Who's counting?
So if Leopoldo Pisanello doesn't go,
the movie won't start?
- That's right.
- I'm Leopoldo Pisanello, a schmuck.
You're the schmuck's wife.
- You said we'd go.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(LOUD CHEERING)
There's Gina Francone.
(MALE REPORTER SPEAKING)
And there's Tony Branca.
There he is. Good evening.
Who do I see?
Leopoldo Pisanello.
(CROWD CHEERING)
His lovely wife, Sofia, looking
elegant in her junky print.
- Yes, she's wearing a junky cotton print dress.
(FEMALE REPORTER SPEAKING)
Looks to be second-hand,
maybe even a thrift shop.
And I believe she has a run in her
stocking. We're checking and yes...
...it is a run in the stocking
of her left leg.
Mrs. Pisanello, the run
in your stocking, was that deliberate?
- There's a run?
- Yes, it's very dramatic, very stylish.
Wouldn't you say, Martina?
- We'll be seeing you at Cannes soon?
- Yes, for sure.
- Great.
- I must move on to Gina Francone.
- Mr. Pisanello! I'm Marina Raguso.
I'm such a great admirer of yours.
- Thank you.
- I think you're so much sexier than
all the pretty-boy leading men...
...who makes those
comic-book movies.
- I see.
- I'd love more time
to talk to you...
...to hear your views
on the state of culture in Italy.
- Mine?
- I'll give you my number.
Call me.
- Your number?
- Any time.
- Okay.
- Mr. Pisanello, tell us,
do you wear boxer shorts or briefs?
Me? Boxers. Loose, white.
- I knew it!
You're the classic boxer type.
I knew!
(ROMANTIC ITALIAN SONG PLAYS)
(INAUDIBLE)
(SIGHS)
So, what are you thinking
now that you've fixed
her up with your pal?
- I don't know.
Sally and I thought
it would be a fun idea
to come out and visit
these ruins.
- Yes, so then
what occurred? What is it?
- I don't know, I just...
I know I regretted
introducing her to Leonardo.
- Yes, you're jealous.
- All of a sudden, I wanted
to get her alone in a room
and tell her I loved her.
Isn't that stupid?
I never felt anything
until this afternoon,
and suddenly
her face got to me.
And I loved
how she wore her hair.
And she looks great.
How'd you like Monica?
- Oh, she's lovely.
Can't wait to see her again.
- Oh, yeah? You gonna...
You gonna see her again?
- Tomorrow night.
- I think Sally and I
are free tomorrow night.
- I think it's better
if it's just the two of us.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
JERRY: Giancarlo, I took the liberty
of calling my friend,
and I set up an audition for you
with the recording company.
- I told you no!
- Why? What do you have
against live people?
Your whole life,
you can't just deal
with people
who have rigor mortis.
You have a great voice.
You should be singing
Pagliacci for multitudes.
You... You know.
- Pagliacci?
- Pagliacci, yes!
You were born to play that.
- I always dreamed of
singing Pagliacci.
- Yes, I know!
Of course.
'Cause you're a natural.
That's... You know,
stick with me.
We can go very far, really.
- " We"?
- We, yes.
Well, I would manage you.
And I will direct you.
I'll put on the greatest
production of Pagliacci.
I'm telling you, I know
exactly what to do.
You have to believe me.
I don't know why
I'm shouting, you know.
You're two inches
in front of me.
Trust me.
(SINGING OPERA IN ITALIAN)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(CONTINUES SINGING)
(SONG ENDS)
(DOOR OPENS)
How did it go?
- You know what?
Ask your father.
- Uh-oh.
- I'm so sorry, Jerry.
I let you down.
- No...
- You should have
seen his face.
He knew it was terrible.
JERRY: It wasn't terrible.
You know, yes, if you...
If it was at La Scala,
would they be throwing
fruit and vegetables?
Yes, they would have.
But this was
a cold audition room.
PHYLLIS:
It's all fantasy.
You imagine his voice
is better than it really is
because you're searching
for an excuse
to come out of retirement.
- Hey, don't psychoanalyze me,
Phyllis, okay?
You know, many have tried,
all have failed.
My brain doesn't fit the usual
id-ego-superego model.
- No, you have the only brain
with three ids.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- It was a foolish idea
to begin with.
- Well, your father's
a grown man.
I mean, he can make
his own decisions.
- I don't know why you
showed up at all.
You know, you were sitting there with
a disapproving face,
very sour
through the whole thing.
Maybe you made
your father nervous.
- I came because
he's a simple man,
and I didn't want
to send him alone
into a tank of shark
of the music business.
JERRY: Tank of shark?
- Whoa, you think
my father is a shark?
- In the aquatic world,
I've been likened
to a spineless jellyfish,
but that's about it.
- Look.
You defend your father
because he's family,
and I understand,
but here, he's wrong.
- No, I defend him
because you're wrong.
There's no sin in trying
something and failing.
- I don't want to say anything,
but I told you.
You choose projects
that are doomed to fail.
You get some kind of a payoff
out of failing.
- What projects do I choose
that are doomed to fail?
- Rigoletto with everyone
dressed like white mice.
(GIANCARLO
SINGING IN DISTANCE)
Can you hear him?
Is that not a gorgeous voice?
- Sure. What good it is if he can only
do it in the shower?
- Well, but you admit he can...
PHYLLIS: He's right, Jerry.
Everyone sings great
in the shower.
- That's right.
He does it in the shower.
- Dad, even you sing
in the shower.
- I know. I...
In life,
I have a terrible voice,
but when I'm soaping myself
under hot water,
I sound just like Eartha Kitt.
- You look strange.
- Phyllis, I'm having...
There's a psychological
term for this.
I'm having a breakthrough
or an epiphany.
What is the term
for what I'm having?
- A death wish.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN) Bravo. You were fantastic.
Come meet your biggest fan.
She's seen all of your films.
Milly, right?
- Si, Milly.
- So you're a fan? - Yes, oh, yes.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- I've seen everything
you've ever done.
- You're flattering me.
- No, it's true.
You're so great.
You're an exceptional actor.
As the Arab spy, as the terrorist,
as the divorced father.
I've always dreamed of meeting you.
- Will you join me for lunch?
- Lunch? With you?
- Together?
- I only have a hour.
- Oh my God.
You're the sexiest man in Rome,
according to Mondo Film.
- Did you know?
- Yes. I've been told.
- Shall we?
- Yes.
Thank you.
Are you planning a large family?
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- No children.
You become their slave.
Diapers, school, illness.
They grow up, they move out,
you never see them.
- No, that's not so.
- It was with me.
I couldn't wait
to get out of the house.
My father sold drugs...
...my mother was a shoplifter.
What could I do?
Can you blame me?
- Look, look!
There's the actor Luchino Salta.
- Yes, yes! That's him.
- He's married.
Who is that woman he's with?
(SPLUTTERS)
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
(COUGHS)
- I can't believe I'm having lunch with you.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- I'm the lucky one.
Otherwise I'd be dining alone.
- Why alone? Aren't you married?
It's in all the papers.
- Yes, but marriage is like wine.
When it's right, it's beautiful,
when it's not...
We're separated.
The press doesn't know.
It's a secret.
- Of course. I won't tell anyone.
- What are they doing?
- He's looking into her eyes
and making love talk.
- I'd love it if you could
watch me film this afternoon.
You could give me your insights,
observations, point of view.
We could do that back at my hotel.
- You value my opinion?
- Is there something wrong with that?
- No, not at all.
Antonio, my husband,
thinks my head is in the clouds.
Which may be a bit true.
- He doesn't take your ideas seriously?
- He takes them seriously.
He respects them...
...but in the scientific area.
I teach high school astronomy.
- Oh my, how sweet.
- Yes, so I doubt he'd want my opinion
on anything artistic.
Astronomy. So, the skies,
the planets, the stars.
You're a... wait, don't tell me.
- Please, I'm not saying anything!
- You're a Libra.
- No, a Sagittarius.
- He's taking her hand.
- She should slap his face.
- Oh no, she loves it.
(CLATTERING)
- Are you hurt?
- No. No.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN) Hello, this is Brunella
Matteucci live with Leopoldo Pisanello.
It's 7:30 AM.
Mr. Pisanello is going to shave.
We're covering that shave live,
from the first to the last stroke.
Mr. Leopoldo Pisanello is getting
a haircut. (SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Just a trim.
- He's opted for a trim.
(PULSATING DANCE MUSIC BLARES)
Sorry, all full, no table.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- You must be mistaken.
My husband made reservations.
- We're all full.
- I can't believe this.
- Oh no tables, I'll come back.
- Oh no, Mr. Pisanello, right this way.
- The nerve!
- It's not fair.
- You are losing a longtime customer.
- They're right.
They've been waiting.
- Nonsense. Please step this way.
(LIGHT APPLAUSE)
I watched you in the office and couldn't
resist you. (SPEAKING ITALIAN)
They say power is an aphrodisiac.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
- Who's she?
(LEOPOLDO SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Tanya. She's my friend.
She's dying to go to bed with you.
I promised her you would
make love to her after me.
It will make her year.
He worries because he's married.
- Mr. Pisanello,
the rules don't apply to you.
You're special.
Yes, yes, I agree
with you completely.
- I mean, the first time I read
The Myth of Sisyphus,
my whole life changed.
- Yes. Yes.
- And, of course, the Russians.
- Dostoyevsky. Thank you.
- “Stavrogin's Confession."
- And Kierkegaard...
- I mean, you can feel his pain.
- Didn't you say that Rilke
was your favorite author?
- Oh, Rilke.
"You must change your life."
- Or was it Ezra Pound?
- "Petals on a wet,
black bough."
- Look at this.
She knows one line from every poet.
Just enough to fake it.
- I have such a great idea.
Tonight, after they're closed,
we should sneak
into the old Roman baths.
- Sneak in?
- Well...
You know a way, right?
- Yeah.
- He knows a way in.
Come on. It'll be dark.
It'll be spooky. It'll be fun.
- No, Jack doesn't do spooky.
Believe me.
MONICA: Oh, well...
I love entering places
illegally, so...
- No, I mean, yeah, sure.
I mean, I don't want
to be a spoilsport.
- First, it's Camus
and Kierkegaard,
and now, " I've run out
of namedropping",
"so let's break
into somewhere."
Pretty soon, she'll have you
holding up filling stations.
Yeah, I understand,
from where you sit,
it sounds crazy,
but from where I sit...
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
MONICA:
Oh! Oh, isn't this great?
My God. I can't believe
we snuck in here.
SALLY: I have never seen this at
night before. JACK: Okay. Yeah.
- It's amazing. How are you doing?
- No, I'm fine. I'm fine.
Just, it looks like
it's going to rain, doesn't it?
(LAUGHS)
- He can't break any rules.
- Oh, whoa! Okay,
there's lightning.
Hey, guys, come on.
- Are you afraid? Come on!
- I'm not afraid. We're just
sitting ducks here.
- Come on!
It's unbelievable!
- Okay, let's go
back to the car.
- I love electrical storms.
- Okay, now
it's definitely raining.
- It's just a little though.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
- Sally! Sally, come on.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
MONICA:
This is amazing.
JACK: It's
a little loud.
- That means it's close.
- Okay...
- It's very close.
- I actually went to school
with a boy
who got killed by lightning.
- Do you hate it?
- Well, no, no. I mean,
I didn't mean to imply...
- I just think storms
are so romantic.
- You know, you actually...
You look really
beautiful all wet.
- You're so sweet to say that.
- No, no, really, you do.
- You know, I just...
I love it here.
I mean, I think Rome
is so charismatic.
- Oh, God, here comes
the bullshit.
- Hey, will you keep out
of the goddamn scene
and let me have
a moment alone with her?
- Okay, I'll allow you
your moment,
but remember,
I know how it turns out.
- I feel like I have completely fallen
in love with Rome,
just this little while
that I've been here.
I feel like I could
spend my whole life here
and just never go back.
I'm sure meeting Leonardo
has a lot to do with that.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
- Oh! Oh, my God.
Oh, that one scared me.
- Yeah.
If we die, we die together.
(CROWD APPLAUDING)
(APPLAUSE FADES)
(FAUCET SQUEAKING)
(PLAYING DRAMATIC
OPERATIC INTRO)
(SINGING ITALIAN ARIA
BEAUTIFULLY)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
(CHEERING)
You were absolutely fabulous.
This guy created
a sensation today.
I see a big future here.
- What does the future mean?
I see New York.
I see the Vienna Opera House.
I see Paris.
- All in the shower?
- Yes. They love it that
he sings in the shower.
They identify.
You know, he's going to be the most
popular opera singer in the world.
- Certainly the cleanest.
- You don't want to really take this
further, do you, Dad?
- Why not?
JERRY: - Yes, I got big plans for him.
I want to do now
a production of Pagliacci.
Your father was born
to sing that role.
- This is decadent stupidity.
GIANCARLO: My whole life,
I sing that role
while I am in the bathroom.
- He's wanted to do this
his entire life.
You're going to deny
your father his shot?
- It's your shot, not his.
- I resent your tone
with my father.
- I happen to think
out of the box.
- Oh, out of the box.
Oh, that's a very interesting
choice of words.
Listen to me, you're retired.
You equate retirement
with death.
Giancarlo's an undertaker.
He puts people in boxes,
and you want to think out of the box.
- It's true.
- If you're channeling Freud,
ask for my money back.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(STAMMERING)
I failed high school Spanish.
I really don't...
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
He's going to be
a big star... Star?
Big opera star.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
I'm going to take care of him.
Yeah, yeah.
(IMITATES WATER SPRAYING)
Yes, I'm going to take...
Oh! Oh!
Hold it, hold it.
Hold it.
Interpose yourself.
Wait, wait.
Wait, go ahead. Jerry, no!
She probably
won't stab a woman.
Go ahead. Go.
Calm. Calm.
- Relax. Relax.
- No, you have
an attitude problem.
- Put the knife down.
- We're... This is going to
be our mother-in-law here?
We wanted you to meet these people.
Mr. Massucci is our firm's CEO.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
He threw this cocktail party
to welcome you.
It's a chance to meet the creme de
la créme of Rome's business world.
We talked you up and everyone's
looking forward to meeting you.
(GIOVANNA SPEAKING ITALIAN) - And it
doesn't hurt to impress their wives.
- You think it's wise
to drink so much, darling?
- Maybe I should get some coffee.
Coffee, anyone?
- There he is! I want to present you
to my nephew. (SAL SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Hello everyone!
Beautiful party, isn't it?
- This is Antonio.
- Pleased to meet you.
You're the famous nephew.
I've heard fine things about you.
They said you fit the image
of the company.
Image is very important to all of us.
You follow football?
- No.
- It's you.
- Yes.
- What are you doing here, Anna?
- Milly, Milly.
- Oh, my wife.
- How are you?
- Good, thank you.
- A pleasure.
- The pleasure is mine.
- Milly.
We're off. Excuse us.
- Coffee?
- Coffee, please.
- Anna.
- Hi!
Milly.
- Since when is it Milly?
- It's Milly.
- My wife is here.
- Relax, don't worry.
- I was going to call you.
- How's next Tuesday?
- The usual time?
- Anna.
- Oh God.
- My goodness, I didn't expect
to see you here.
- Milly. Here I'm Milly.
- Milly. All right.
Can you come to my office
tomorrow at three?
- I don't have my book with me.
- I see. If I don't hear otherwise
I'll expect you at three.
And wear the black brassiere
and the thong.
- Do you sail?
- No.
- Do you hunt?
Anna, how are you?
- Milly. Milly, Milly. Milly.
I'm so nervous. I can't afford to
look foolish. (SPEAKING ITALIAN)
These men are the most important
business tycoons in Rome.
- Some créme de la creme.
It's my whole client list.
- My nerves are shot from today.
- You're too uptight, honey. Relax.
You'll have a heart attack.
- How can I relax when
my life is falling apart?
- How does your wife stand it
if you're always such a wreck?
- She loves me the way I am.
Is that why she was smooching
with Luchino what's-his-name?
Salta.
- Mmm.
- They were smooching?
- Practically.
- You said holding hands.
There must be some explanation.
She's a Madonna.
- The explanation is he's a movie star,
a sex symbol.
- And Milly is pretty, but
she'd never look at another man.
- You obviously don't know women.
Especially if her husband
is a nervous man afraid of his shadow.
- What the hell was she doing smooching?
He made love to her with his eyes.
- You probably don't know how
to make love with your eyes.
- To a woman of your profession,
I must appear a middle class mouse.
- Was your wife a virgin
when you married her?
- None of your business.
- I'll bet she was.
- We had some pretty
wild times together.
- What's your idea of wild times?
Sex with the lights on?
- Believe me, she was not a virgin.
I was.
- You really need a lesson in love.
- From who? Surely not you?
- Why not?
It's all paid for.
- There are people...
- No one can see us.
Don't let me
forget the carrots.
- Okay. You really need
all this pasta?
- Yeah, I think
we need more pasta.
- More pasta? We're not cooking
for a small village.
- Tomatoes.
- Okay.
- Whose idea was
this enterprise?
- Uh, it was hers.
It was Monica's.
We all agreed
to have dinner together,
and since Leonardo's at work all day
and Sally's at school,
Monica suggested
we do the cooking.
- Oh. Can I make a prediction?
- What?
- She can't cook.
(LAUGHS) - Apparently,
there are some things she can cook.
- Like what?
- Like chocolate brownies.
- Brownies. You're going to have
brownies as a main course?
- Yeah. Yeah, I think
it should be fun.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Do you think it needs more wine?
- Mmm, none. Mmm.
- I mean, I know the Italians
cook with a lot of...
- There's a lot of wine in here.
- I can really feel it.
I don't know if it's...
You know, I...
It might be the French.
- No, no. Let me see.
- I just... I don't want it
to be too subtle.
- No, it's definitely not subtle.
- No, I can definitely...
- Well, can I taste it?
- Yeah, of course. Please.
- Um... You know,
- I think it needs...
You know, I'll get some of that
other wine that's there.
- The other... Are you sure?
We already finished this one.
- Uh...
- Okay.
- Oh, oh, we have to put
the brownies in.
- Can you bake?
- Can I bake?
You said you baked.
- Well, no, I can.
I have. I just... I left the recipe
in Los Angeles.
But, you know, I'll do it.
I can do it by memory.
I'm sure I can do it by memory.
- Hey, you want to just order
from a restaurant
and maybe dirty up the kitchen a little bit
and say we cooked it?
- Well... Here,
let me check the sauce.
- Hey, you know what, I'm going to
check it, too, actually.
- Oh, do you want
penne or rigatoni?
- Don't put the pasta in now.
They're not going to be home for hours.
Mmm.
(CHUCKLES)
- What?
I think I'm a little drunk.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- We can just...
We can fake it.
- Yeah, I'm...
I'm done with this.
- Good. Me, too.
- I'm done with the cooking.
- Okay.
- I just... I promised Leonardo
that I'd make
a really great dinner.
- Yeah.
You know, I'm so...
I'm so glad it worked out
between you and Leonardo.
No, really, 'cause, you know,
I'm the one that
got you together.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
- Yeah, I mean, he...
He's nice.
- "Sexy," I think,
you told Sally.
- Mmm... Mmm...
(STAMMERING)
Look, and this is the wine talking.
He's not the most
soulful character.
He's not, um...
He's not a sufferer.
- What's so great about suffering?
- Well, I just...
There's something
attractive about a man
who's sensitive
to the agonies of existence.
(CHUCKLES)
- God, you would be perfect
to play Miss Julie.
The Strindberg play.
- The Miss Julie tactic
I learned
from a friend of mine
who's a theater director.
Tell any actress
she'd be perfect
for the role of Miss Julie,
and you can have
your way with her.
- I'm just so amazed
that you would say that.
I mean, Miss Julie is the role that
I was born to play.
She is me.
How could you know that?
- I have a kind of non sequitur question
to ask you now.
- What?
- How would you feel
if I kissed you?
- Oh. Um...
That is a non sequitur.
JOHN:
Oh, Little Miss Shocked.
Didn't you see that?
Two minutes ago,
she popped a Tic Tac.
What do you think that's about?
JACK: I'm serious.
I'm serious.
What would you think?
- I would think that you're
living with my best friend.
- Yeah, this is true.
And yet I can't stop myself.
- Oh, that's not good.
- Wait, what,
you didn't like it?
- No, I liked it, and
that's what's not good.
JOHN: And you,
will you ever recover from it?
- I don't know.
She's perfect.
I mean, this is
too good to be true.
- If something is too good to be true,
you can bet it's not.
- I have to have her.
- What are we going
to do about this?
- Were you acting?
Was this a performance?
- I can't do this to Sally
in her home.
- No, no, no,
it's okay, it's okay.
Trust me, she won't
be home for hours.
- No, I just mean I...
- What?
- I don't want to do it here.
JOHN: For Christ's sakes,
what is all this
posturing about?
If you're going to screw
your best friend's boyfriend,
does it really matter
what the venue is?
- You will never
understand women.
- That's been proven.
- This is not going to be some
ongoing affair behind Sally's back.
All right, this is one
rainy afternoon,
I'm a little bit drunk,
and yeah,
I'm turned on by you, but...
Just not here, not in her home.
- Okay, look, the time for
debating is long past.
Let's go down to the car.
- Well, the car is different.
You can fuck me in the car.
I'm fine with that.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(PHOTOGRAPHERS CLAMORING
IN ITALIAN) - Smile!
- Is it true you're a couple?
- She's my cousin, my cousin.
We happened to run into each other.
I have no statement to make.
- Is Leopoldo going to direct
your next picture?
We happened to run into each other.
- I was waiting for my wife.
Marisa, run.
We were waiting for my wife.
Leave us alone. Enough already.
Leave us. Please.
Show some respect
for the procession.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Roberto, I can't take it.
Why me, Roberto?
What's going on?
- Sir, you have to accept it.
You're a very famous man.
- But why? Look, these pills,
the bottle was full this morning.
But why am I famous?
- You're famous for being famous.
But I didn't accomplish anything.
- You think everybody who's famous
deserves to be?
I don't know. Even you want my opinion.
Everyone wants my opinion.
I don't know!
My life has become a living hell.
A journalist asked me if God exists.
I told her I didn't know.
She was upset. "Mr. Pisanello
doesn't know if God exists!"
Everyone wants answers.
"Pisanello, Pisanello!"
How do you scratch your head?
With the left of right hand?
With both. He scratches with both!
That's private business.
I scratch my head with the hand
I please, okay? It's private.
- From where I sit, sir,
I find it hard to sympathize.
To be a celebrity, the excitement,
the special privileges...
...adoring crowds
wanting your autograph...
...never having to wait in line.
- The women adore me.
They kneel before me.
Pisanello, you are so handsome.
They want to go to bed with me
three and four at a time.
I have enough trouble
when we're two.
- The wife of a man
of your stature understands...
...she must share him with the public.
- I want my anonymity back,
no one interrupting me.
(CLAMORING)
Enough!
Roberto, take me home.
I will sue you for violation of privacy.
You have no heart.
Let's go. Take me home.
Bravo.
You were better than I thought.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Why are you so silent?
- I committed adultery.
- Think of it as
part of your education.
- I never did any of those things before.
- Why not?
- Because Milly would be shocked.
- But with me you had no problem.
Why? Because I'm a whore?
- With you I was uninhibited.
But I feel so guilty.
Milly would never in a million years
commit adultery.
- Maybe she wouldn't mind you having
a learning experience.
- I can't do those things with Milly.
She's too saintly.
- Yes I know, Madonna-like.
Except you're the prude, not Milly.
You were the virgin
at marriage, not her.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN) You like it?
- This is beautiful.
- A drink?
- No, thank you. I don't dare.
- Why not?
Here.
- Grazia.
(MELLOW INSTRUMENTAL
JAZZ BEGINS PLAYING)
- I love old songs from my childhood.
- Very pretty.
- And the old way of dancing.
(LAUGHING)
- You're very good.
- What can I say.
- Oh...
I thought you wanted to talk.
- My weakness is nostalgia.
- Yes, there's something charming
about reminiscing.
(CHUCKLES) - Did anyone ever tell you
you were beautiful?
- My husband, maybe once.
But never a movie actor.
- Please don't think of me
as a movie actor.
I'm an ordinary human being,
with the same feelings...
...the same vulnerabilities
and desires.
- Scusa mi, scusa mi.
But when I see you kiss
those beautiful actresses you seem...
...how shall I say...
larger than life.
- A movie kiss, what is it?
All pretend.
- I always wondered what it must be like
to be kissed by Luca Salta.
- Now you know.
- It was amazing.
- Only amazing?
- More than amazing.
- Wait till you experience the rest.
- The rest?
- We must, I can't turn back now.
You're far too enchanting.
- No, no.
- My goodness, what a dilemma.
- I see no dilemma.
- Of course it is.
I'm so tempted to make love to you,
so I can tell my grandchildren.
- Relax.
- On the other hand it is adultery.
- Let's not get into semantics.
I want you.
- Oh, my goodness.
I don't know what to do.
I love Antonio, my husband.
But I am so curious.
- Listen, life is short. And some
moments are written in the stars.
- This is one of them.
- Yes.
No, wait, wait.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Don't move.
Don't leave, okay?
What?
- I swore I wouldn't do this.
- I know, I know, I know.
Me neither.
I have to tell Sally.
- But you said your relationship
was winding down.
I mean, this cannot be
because of me.
- No, no, don't say that.
No, no, it is, it is.
It's wound down.
- I...
I had fantasies yesterday
of us being together.
- Really?
- Exploring Italy
and looking at all
the great architecture
of Milan and Venice and Naples.
You could teach me.
- I'm a good teacher.
- We could stay
in little towns
at bed and breakfasts.
(SIGHS)
- Since Sally is taking
her exams next week at the university,
I just don't want to break this
to her before then.
- No, of course.
- Yeah, but right after.
Right after.
I love you.
(REPORTERS CLAMORING
IN ITALIAN)
You are the greatest, the greatest.
- Who's that man?
He looks even more interesting.
- We're here on the street
with Aldo Romano.
If I'm not mistaken,
you drive a bus.
- What's going on?
I don't understand.
What do you want from me?
- Is it true you are bringing
your laundry in to have it cleaned?
- Yes, but what do you want?
- Do you use starch?
- No, I don't like starch.
- Is that a stain on your jacket?
- It's marinara.
- Can you tell us how you got it?
- I was eating a plate of rigatoni.
I lifted my fork and the sauce fell.
Why do you care?
I don't understand.
(LAUGHS)
Gabriele! Camilla! Sofia!
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- Hi, Dad!
- Easy there.
The curse is lifted.
We're back to normal.
I'm so happy.
- A man named Aldo Romano
is in all the papers.
- Let's celebrate with a pizza.
My treat!
- Who is the new star?
- Aldo Romano.
I think I did really well
on the exams.
- Of course you did.
- Yeah, you sailed through it
because you studied
hard enough.
- I worked hard.
- Yeah, you did.
She doubts herself for no reason.
I don't know why.
- Do you guys
want something else?
- Uh, sure.
- No.
- Oh. Oh, okay.
All right, well...
- Okay.
You see how confident she is?
So, I'm gonna
take her to dinner,
and I'm gonna tell her tonight.
- Okay, are you sure?
- Yeah, yeah,
of course, of course.
In fact, I planned out
an amazing trip for us.
Believe it or not,
I've never been
to the Acropolis
or the Parthenon.
- Oh, can we go to Sicily?
- Yeah, of course...
You know what, actually,
we could, we could
hire a sailboat
and go around the boot,
if you want to.
- I've always seen
pictures of Palermo.
I just think it is so romantic.
- Yeah, well,
you can see pictures,
but nothing is like being
there in the real place...
(PHONE RINGING)
Do you want to...
Yeah, sure, no problem.
- Hello?
No, I... Hello?
I'm gonna see if I can...
Sure, okay.
Hello?
- It's sad.
- What is?
- That you're in love
with Monica.
- There's just
something about her.
- You know that Sally's
in love with you, right? - I know.
- And your common sense
tells you
that Sally is the much more
sensible choice.
- Yeah, I know...
I know all of that, and
yet I can't explain it.
- I understand.
- Guess what.
JACK: - What?
I got a part.
- A part?
- A good part.
In a movie.
It's high-budget.
It shoots in Los Angeles and Tokyo.
- Wait, where?
- I have to leave tonight.
- What was that about
a sailboat in Sicily?
- They need me for,
like, five months.
- Five months in Japan?
- One month in Los Angeles,
four in Japan.
I mean, assuming
it all goes on time.
Oh, I cannot wait to go.
I mean, it is, like,
my dream in life
to spend time in the Far East.
- That's your dream?
- Who's in it?
- Justin Brill,
Ricardo Ramirez.
- Ricardo Ramirez,
he's a very attractive man.
- And I worked with
Justin Brill before, like,
when he was married
to Rebecca Wright,
and he had this big,
mad crush on me.
- Well, he's available now.
- This is so exciting.
I can't wait
to get back to Los Angeles,
see my acting coach...
I mean, no matter what it's like to visit a
place, there's nothing like home.
- Who's directing?
- Mark Strombel.
I adore him.
I adore his work.
And you know what,
he's, like, the only director
that I would trust to direct the nude
scenes that I have to do.
And although I hear
he does a lot of drugs,
somehow that burnt-out look
is just so...
It's just so sexy on him.
I have to lose some weight.
I mean, the, the writer
saw me on that TV thing.
He just... He flipped out
over my quality.
Like, five pounds or so...
I'll just start running again.
I'll start running again.
This part is such
a great showcase for me.
I just hope I can bring my dog.
I hope it's not like London,
where it's so hard
to bring a pet.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Stay calm, Milly, stay calm.
Better to sleep with him
and regret it...
...than not sleep with him
and regret it.
What do I do?
Better to sleep with him.
Absolutely better
to sleep with him.
Yes, better to sleep with him.
- Be quiet.
Quiet or I'll kill you.
Now, open the door.
You understand?
Let's go. March.
- Are you ready, my love?
- Keep your mouth shut.
Do what I say and you won't be hurt.
You understand? - Si. Si, si.
- Give me your wallet
and all your jewelry. Hurry!
- Don't you know who lam?
- No and I don't care. Hurry up.
You keep quiet and don't cry.
Hand over everything.
- It won't come off.
- Your watch.
The watch, shut up.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
- Open up!
(MAN SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Open up! House detective!
- Open up Luca. I know you're in there!
(WOMAN SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- My wife!
- She probably had me followed!
- You said you were separated.
- Oh god, the alimony! I'm finished!
- I'll be in the newspapers
as the other woman!
- I'm finished. I've lost everything.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
- Listen, I got an idea.
We do this...
you go into the bathroom.
Hide in the shower.
Go. Close the door.
Get in there.
Come with me.
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
- Open up!
(MAN SPEAKING ITALIAN)
(ALL ARGUING IN ITALIAN)
This man has a lot to explain.
- There, in the bed!
- Did you not hear us knocking?
- What's going on?
- Have you gone mad?
- Didn't you hear us?
What am I going to hear?
I'm here with my girlfriend.
You come barging in
at a delicate moment.
- You're not this woman's husband?
- Husband? I don't know her.
- You told us he was your husband.
- Are you crazy?
I'll sue this hotel
for barging in here without knocking.
- Pardon, sir, pardon.
- How could you?
- What's going on here?
(ARGUING RESUMES)
- Everyone out.
- This isn't my fault.
- Madam, please!
- Pardon us.
- You'll hear from my lawyers!
- We'll get him.
- Madam, please. Thank you.
- This wasn't supposed
to end like this.
- Madam, after you.
(CONTINUES ARGUING
IN ITALIAN)
Oh thank you, thank you!
- You're welcome.
- I'll leave now.
Here take my watch, my ring.
It's all yours.
- Thank you, really.
- Thank you.
Bye, thank you.
- I can't believe this.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(WHIMPERS)
- I don't blame him,
you're really very pretty.
- Excuse me?
- I said, you're pretty.
- Thank you.
Are you a real burglar?
- Yes I am.
You could say I specialize in hotels.
But I do break-ins and holdups.
- Really?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Huh.
- How exciting.
- You're exciting.
I've never made love
with a criminal.
My husband
is a respectable businessman.
- Is that so?
- Yes.
- Well, how do I say this?
Opportunity makes a thief.
Here's your chance.
- You're right.
We're alone in a hotel room.
- Exactly. We're in bed.
You're in your slip.
- So?
- So...
(BOTH MOANING SOFTLY)
(SIGHS)
I guess I'll never
hear from Monica again.
- Yes, but you can read about her
in the gossip column,
dating Justin Brill, vacationing in
his Aspen lodge.
Consider yourself lucky.
You saved your own life there.
A year with her, she would've had you
free fall parachuting
and adopting Burmese orphans.
(CHUCKLES)
- Well, with age comes wisdom.
- With age comes exhaustion.
- Look, here's where
we first met. - Yeah.
I should be getting back
to the Excelsior.
- Oh, it's a nice hotel.
You're obviously doing well.
- There's a lot of dough
in shopping malls.
- You've sold out.
- Well, as a foolish man
once said, stuff happens.
- I'll leave you here.
- Yes.
- Goodbye.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
This is nice.
There's a movie premiere tonight.
We can just go with no fuss
and enjoy the picture.
We don't have to pose for photos.
- We weren't invited.
- Ah.
Well, we can stay home
and watch it on television.
And I don't have to share you
with beautiful models and actresses...
...and sexy secretaries.
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
I'm Leopoldo Pisanello.
Miss, this morning for breakfast...
...I had toast with butter and jam.
Then I shaved and used a cream.
I prefer a cream to a gel.
I'm Leopoldo Pisanello.
- Hi. Want my autograph?
- No, I'm in a hurry.
- You want it?
- I don't know you!
- I wear boxer shorts.
Do you want to see my boxers?
See, I wear boxer shorts.
White and loose.
Miss, I am Leopoldo Pisanello.
Looks like rain. I got a trim.
She's my wife.
Miss, there's a run in her stocking.
It's trendy. Runs are trendy.
You want to see me on one foot?
Look, Pisanello on one foot!
It's a great scoop!
I had breakfast this morning.
Excuse me, I recognize you.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Yes, I know that face.
Didn't you used to be...
- I'm Leopoldo Pisanello.
- Yes, that's right.
- Do you want my autograph?
- Sure, if you insist. Here.
- Here's my autograph.
I am Leopoldo Pisanello. Remember.
- Thank you.
- That's me. Thank you.
- You see.
- Yes. Let's go home.
- The kids are there. I'm there.
- Here. Yes!
He'll remember me, Sofia.
This man was once my chauffeur.
- Right?
- Yes.
I told you, sir...
...life can be very cruel
and unsatisfying...
...whether you're a celebrity
or poor and unknown.
But of the two,
to be a celebrity...
...is definitely better.
- Good bye.
- Good bye. Thank you.
- Come, let's go.
- Did you hear what he said?
- Yes, I heard.
I heard.
Milly? Milly?
- There you are. I was so worried.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- What happened to you?
- When I came back you were gone.
I lost my phone. I got lost.
What happened to you?
- My uncles,
they had every moment planned.
- Did it go well?
- We're going home.
- Home where?
- Back to Pordenone.
- But we've just arrived.
- I had my full dose of my uncles
and aunts and all their phony friends.
I don't want the job.
I want my old job back.
We'll never get rich,
but we'll have a better life.
You loved teaching at the school.
- Yes, but...
- But nothing!
We'll go home. We'll have a...
...a better life, with children.
And maybe...
I'll even have time to paint a little.
- Okay.
What a surprise.
I don't know what to say.
- Say nothing.
Let's make love.
- Make love?
- Before we leave, to celebrate.
- Oh.
- It'll be my turn
to teach you about the stars.
(LAUGHS GENTLY)
And don't be surprised
if I shock you.
- Shock me.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING
DRAMATIC OPERA INTRO)
(CHOIR SINGING)
(GIANCARLO SINGING)
(MUSIC SWELLS)
(MUSIC ENDS
WITH DRAMATIC FLOURISH)
(CHEERING)
Dad, the critic says
you were wonderful.
"A voice from
the golden era."
- That is so great.
I can't believe it.
Eh, but no more for me, eh?
Oh...
I prove myself enough.
(SPEAKS ITALIAN)
Mamma don't fly, I don't tour.
My life is fulfilled.
I have a great family.
I stay home, I relax,
I bury people, I'm happy.
(SPEAKS ITALIAN)
No, no, no, no, no.
- Tonight, I owe
everybody an apology.
- We should get to the Spanish Steps soon
for Max's cocktail party.
- We're late?
- No, no.
- I mean, he's an old friend
of my father.
He's not gonna mind
if we're a bit late.
But we should go soon.
- All right.
Do you forgive me?
- I'm so happy
for your husband.
And as for you, how could I
not forgive you?
I love you.
(CHUCKLES)
- "Another Caruso."
"And in difficult
conditions."
- Oh, goodness, they weren't very kind
to my father, were they?
- Uh...
Ooh, I think it's better
you don't hear that.
- No, no, I can take it.
Just don't tell my dad.
Thankfully, he doesn't
understand a word of Italian.
- All right, um, "Except from Mr. Santoli's
magnificent voice..."
- Magnifico!
(LAUGHTER)
(MARIANGELA
SPEAKING ITALIAN)
- "...whoever imbecile..."
(STAMMERS) imbecile?
- Yeah, imbecile.
- "...whoever imbecile conceived this, um,
moronic experience
"should be taken
out and beheaded."
- Oh. - Oh, well.
He's gotten worse.
This has to be the most beautiful terrace
in all of Rome.
- Yeah. For my wife and I, it's a privilege
to live up here.
- Oh, yeah. I mean, the Spanish Steps right
there, the people watching.
- Phyllis, the reviews
were so great.
(STAMMERING) I mean,
the press called me, um...
Not, not... What was
the word they used?
Not a maestro, but a,
um... An "imbechile."
What does it mean?
- Means you're ahead
of your time.
- Your mother, I'm happy to say,
lucky woman,
married an "imbechile."
- So I toast to
my future father-in-law.
- Ah. Well,
good luck to you guys.
- Honey, let's go
see the piazza.
- Yes. Yeah.
- Gotta click, 'cause...
- So glad to see them.
They make a lovely couple.
- Wow.
(SIGHS) - Oh.
This city is unbelievable.
Think we should get married
right in front of
the fountain there.
- Anything you want.
(CHUCKLES)
- Oh, I could
stand here all night,
it's so beautiful.
(BAND PLAYING VOLARE)
It's me that knows
Rome the best,
not a traffic policeman
or anyone.
I see all from here.
The Romans, the students,
the lovers
on the Spanish Steps.
There are many stories,
next time you come.
(VOLARE CONTINUING)