- $500?
- It's called an attention-getter.
I'm a private investigator.
I don't play games.
[ Yelling ]
Some wives drink,
some take lovers.
I play.
I hold you responsible
for everything that's happened.
You think she'd risk dying?
She would risk anything
to keep the game going.
[ Gunshot ]
You shot them.
Are they--
They're dead.
Of course, darling.
All dealers get it eventually.
And so will we.
Someday.
Well, what are we going to do now?
Bury them under some dead brush
and set them on fire.
You take the car.
I'll meet you back at the club.
[ Engine Starts ]
Is she always like this?
500 for you,
3 50 for your friend
because he didn't have to do
any real acting.
[ Chuckles ]
And for the rental of the plane.
Thank you very much, gentlemen.
When she went for the gun--
I mean, I knew it was a gag--
but for one second,
I didn't think she was acting.
[ Magnum Narrating ]
This morning was like
any other on Oahu.
A beautiful woman
named Christie Odebolt
had hired me to,
uh, play games
with her sister Louise.
She said games.
I would have said
helping a rich girl live out her fantasies.
Okay, so it wasn't
like any other morning,
[ Dog Growling ]
but one has to be ready
to expect the unexpected.
At any rate, I wasn't gonna
let it affect my workout.
Hi, guys.
I'm afraid I've opened it
by mistake.
My assumption, of course,
was that Mable Dodge sent it over
as a thank-you for our lunch.
Mable Dodge.
She's the designer...
who's doing over the guesthouse.
I'd never seen a black orchid before,
although technically they can't exist,
you know.
The box doesn't have
the florist's name on it,
and the card doesn't reveal a thing.
- Higgins, you opened it, and you read my card.
- How else could I have known
who it was for?
""The Black Orchid''?
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Higgins ]
Whoever can that be?
Higgins, the orchid
was just a joke.
Rick and T.C.
Why don't you
take it back into the house?
I don't think I've ever encountered
a Rolls of that vintage in the Islands.
It's simply impeccable.
Terrific. Why don't you
take the orchid back
into the house, Higgins?
I'd like to meet the owner,
if you don't mind.
Which of you is Thomas Magnum,
the famous private investigator?
I'm the Black Orchid.
I say, you're who?
- Who is this little man?
- Well, he sort of runs things around here.
Higgins, I'd like you to meet...
Orchid.
He was just admiring your Rolls.
He's an expert on classic
and antique cars.
Isn't that right, Higgins?
Well, yes. I have been consulted
on the restoration of rare automobiles.
Would you have a light?
No, I'm sorry, I don't.
In fact,
the Hawaiian Antique Motorcar Society
asked me to present a paper...
on the proper restoration
of vehicles that have been
exposed to salt air.
It really can be
quite devastating.
Right. And he would like to
take a look at your Rolls
while we have our little chat.
Well, it's really just another car.
Are you Mr. Magnum's assistant?
I say, it's a 1 936,
Gurney Nutting Sedanca Coupé, isn't it?
Extraordinary.
Uh, would you mind
lifting the bonnet?
Mr. Magnum,
I am desperate for help.
Someone is trying to kill me,
and I'm terrified.
Do you know who?
I can't tell you.
Or why?
Please don't ask me that.
Well, what about how,
Miss DeBolt,
or is that a secret too?
Of course it's not a secret.
What did you call me?
You just called me Miss DeBolt.
Of course.
Because that's who you are.
Magnum, darling.
You don't understand.
This isn't how we play.
First of all,
the clothes are all wrong.
It should be a double-breasted gabardine
and a hat with a snap brim,
and secondly,
why couldn't we have
met in your office?
Everybody knows
that private investigators
work out of seedy buildings...
and their names are on the doors
with frosted glass.
- Louise, will you calm down?
- And you do not know my name
since we have only just met...
and my identity is a secret.
That is why I sent the black orchid.
Now, Magnum,
shall we try it one more time?
Mr. Magnum.
Thomas Magnum,
the famous private investigator?
[ Mimics Humphrey Bogart ]
At your service.
You look like a dame--
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Let me try it again.
I'll do it right.
[ Mimics Bogart ]
At your service.
You look like a dame
in big trouble.
Do you know who I am?
You could only be the Black Orchid.
I'd know you anywhere
by your perfume.
[ Sighs ]
Do you have a light?
No.
[ Mimics Bogart ]
[ Chuckles ]
Of course not.
Do you know that ever since
you've taken my case,
I have felt so protected...
and so safe for the first time...
that I know that the man
with one ear will be foiled.
The one-eared man?
Oh, you remember.
The one who's vowed vengeance
on me because I rejected
his romantic advances.
Sure, baby. Sure.
It just slipped my mind.
That's all.
That's because I'm on guard,
expecting an attack.
And because the touch of my hand
drives you crazy.
What?
I feel it too.
It's the electricity,
the chemistry between us.
It's overwhelming,
it's overpowering,
crushing us together.
[ Gasps ]
I don't think you realize
how vulnerable we really are.
Rick and T.C.
I mean the one-eyed man.
The one-eared man.
What?
Of course.
I know you're fighting
your code of honor,
but this feeling's just too intense.
You can't help yourself...
and I can't resist.
[ Yelling ]
- No!
- Rick, make it look good.
[ Yells ]
Save me!
Please, save me!
[ Groans ]
I've got to save
the Black Orchid.
[ Yelps ]
[ Yells ]
Louise, get the car.
Oh, never.
I'll never leave you, my darling.
Yes.
[ Yells ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Choking ]
T.C., it's too hard. Give up,
or I'll set her loose on ya.
Give up, or I'll--
I give up!
Don't kill me!
You were wonderful.!
Oh. You were wonderful.
My hero.
[ Magnum Narrating ]
I know what you're thinking.
After the phony beach attack,
I should have said good-bye to Louise
and meant it.
But you know something?
I was starting to have a good time.
Maybe she wasn't the only one
who had fantasies about
famous detectives who were heroes.
Magnum, I do hope you're not
going to be underfoot...
while the renovations
are going on.
Renovations?
You said something about
a little paint to freshen up the place.
Basically, that's all we're doing.
While you were swimming,
Rick called.
""Basically''?
Something about the woman
in the alleyway last night.
What about her?
He said to tell you
it was the wife of Wyndom Jackson.
You know, now that I think of it,
that mysterious woman yesterday--
Orchid, you said her name was.
It was difficult to tell through
the black veil, but she could have been
Wyndom Jackson's wife.
Of course, we've never
been properly introduced,
but once at the garden club
cotillion when I chaired
the entertainment committee,
she was chairing
the dance committee--
Oh, well.
It's not important.
[ Magnum Narrating ]
When Christie hired me
to play games with Louise,
she'd conveniently used
her sister's maiden name.
She knew if she told me
who Louise was married to,
I wouldn't have anything to do with her.
Even at triple my normal rate.
Wyndom Jackson was notorious
for two things--
his money and his temper.
The first he'd picked up after the war
by investing in property.
The temper I guess he was born with.
He was known as a man
who always got his way,
no matter what it cost...
or who.
Hello? Anybody there?
Hello?
Magnum?
Well, I'm surprised to see you here.
I'll bet you are.
Where's Louise?
Out riding.
She won't be back
until after lunch.
Is something wrong?
Plenty. Starting with
who your sister really is.
Oh. Apparently that makes
a difference to you.
Uh, married makes a difference.
Married to Wyndom Jackson
makes a real big difference.
I can explain that.
Don't bother.
'Cause this is gonna take
about 1 0 seconds.
I'm off the case.
You can mail me my fee.
For my own curiosity, Magnum,
is it morality or economics?
Are you so angry because
Louise has a husband...
or because he's one of the Islands'
five richest men?
Both.
And I sure as hell
wouldn't play war games
in an alley with Wyndom Jackson's wife.
Why not, Magnum?
Are you a reverse snob?
No. Because the stakes
are too high with your crowd,
and things go wrong.
And people like you
don't pay the bills,
and people like me get stuck.
Are you afraid?
I'm afraid of a lot of things.
I'm afraid of hurting my friends
who helped me stage the attack.
What if Jackson finds out
and he doesn't like
that particular game?
He'd run them down
without even looking back.
Are you so confident
he doesn't know about Louise's
penchant for drama?
Oh, come on.
That's the whole idea
of the games, isn't it?
To keep Louise occupied
and out of public trouble?
The spoiled wife of a man
old enough to be her father.
[ Sighs ]
Magnum.
It's not a very original story, is it?
No.
Wyndom worships my sister.
Louise has always been
extremely high-strung and vital.
Lately it's become
like a narcotic.
She needs more and more excitement.
Well, she's bored.
She feels neglected.
And she's becoming reckless.
Magnum, I do apologize.
It's just that I care
very, very much about my sister.
Christie, your sister is not crazy.
She just wants
a little excitement in her life.
Will you keep
that appointment today?
No games.
I'll just talk to her.
And after today, it's finished.
Okay.
I'll try to prepare her.
Frankly, I don't know
how she'll take it.
You just remember no more games.
[ Car Door Opens ]
[ Engine Starts, Revs ]
[ Tires Squealing ]
Whose Ferrari was that?
I damn near hit him.
Oh. Just a friend
I met at the club.
Some car, hmm?
Never mind the car.
Who's the driver?
Somebody I do not intend
to let get away.
A friend of yours...
or Louise's?
He's mine.
Come on. Lunch is ready.
And I want to hear
all about what happened
at the board meeting.
[ Magnum Narrating ]
I know what you're thinking.
I could have just as easily
picked up a phone and laid it out.
I could tell Louise it was over.
No more meetings or games.
I guess I just preferred
to do things one on one.
[ Sighs ]
Hello, Thomas. Tell me,
will it be cold roast beef or...
turkey?
[ Chuckles ]
I understand.
I really do understand.
They're going to be here
very soon, Thomas.
They want that emerald.
Louise.
The Montezuma Emerald.
I know they--
Louise, don't you know?
There aren't gonna be
any bad guys. No games.
What?
This... is good-bye.
Aren't you having a good time?
Louise,
you are going to have to
get a hold of reality.
Don't talk to me about reality.
I have tried it,
and I find it vastly overrated.
Is that why you married Jackson?
When are you going to
learn your lines?
Come on, Louise.
You want reality,
I'll give you reality.
My father was a minister,
here in the Islands, of a very fashionable,
fashionable church.
Mind you, that doesn't mean
the pastor has money--just the flock.
But we all became very good
at pretending we had it--
had it all.
Especially me.
So I decided then and there
that when I grew up,
I was going to be...
an actress.
I was doing such a good job
with the congregation, imagine--
just imagine what I could do
in Hollywood.
What happened?
I met Wyndom.
His wife had just died,
and he was looking for someone.
A companion. Someone to share
his interests, his life.
His money?
You are a tough one
when you want to be, Magnum.
Would it make a bit of difference
to you if I told you
that the money didn't matter?
Oh, you're gonna tell me
that you really love him...
and you do all this
just to please him.
One day, I was out riding
one of Wyndom's horses.
It started to rain, the horse slipped,
and I ended up on my back for six weeks.
And needless to say,
Wyndom felt very responsible.
So he brought me
into his home and...
he took care of me.
Everybody in these Islands
think of him as a rough, tough
son of a gun.
- But not you.
- No, not me.
He brought me my meals.
He would read to me.
And I told him about
wanting to be an actress.
And so we would even play out...
little scenes.
Then eventually we started
writing our own scenes--
or games, if that's what
you want to call them.
jackson played games?
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, he was terrible at it.
So bad, in fact, that...
right before I was
getting ready to leave,
he asked me to marry him.
And I thought it was
one of his games.
And you said yes.
And then this rough, tough,
son of a gun started to cry.
No one's ever loved me
like that, Magnum.
I will never, ever
do anything to hurt him.
That's reality.
Some wives drink,
some take lovers.
I play.
Hold it.
You're in trouble, Mr. Magnum.
[ Magnum Giggles ]
Ooh!
You just don't give up,
do you, Louise? Hi.
That's it. Do you have any idea
what a windshield costs
on a car like that?
Oh, my God. Get a--
I am not paying
for that windshield! Get--
No.
[ Grunts ]
Louise, get the car!
[ Groans ]
[ Blows Landing ]
[ Grunting ]
Come on. Come on.
Go, go.
[ Magnum ]
Watch the steps.
[ Louise ] Ooh. Where's the table?
[ Groans ]
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, dear.
Oh. Come on.
Careful, careful, careful, careful.
Poor darling.
Oh, dear.
What can I get you?
Anything?
Some ice.
Ice. You have ice.
A towel for the ice.
Towel. Where's the towel?
In the bathroom.
Where's the bathroom?
In the--
You go through the door--
Shh. Shh. Don't say another word.
I'll find it.
Don't-- Don't move.
Red.
Re-- Ow.
Red?
[ Door Opens ]
They painted it red!
What have you done
to the Ferrari?
Do you have any idea
what a windscreen costs?
Higgins, the walls are red.
Hot tropical magenta,
to be precise.
Mable Dodge's
trendiest color this season.
You said ""subtle changes.''
You said ""imperceptible changes.''
Obviously this is not a moment
for rational conversation.
It appears you've been
beaten up again.
We'll talk in the morning.
Higgins, you promised!
[ Groans ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Grunts ]
Red.
[ Sighs ]
Magenta.
[ Ice Rattling ]
Oh. Ooh.
Careful. Careful.
[ Groans ]
Oh!
Ah.
There.
You were wonderful.
You were terrific.
You were so... masterful,
the way you took their punches.
Louise, I got beat up.
Everything they threw at you
and back for more.
Louise, this was not a damn game.
Your hiring them was...
perfect.
I didn't hire them.
[ Groans ]
You don't know
how to play the game.
No.
I-If you and your sister
didn't hire these guys,
then somebody's after you for real.
Besides, it's too late to be playing.
Good night.
[ Groans ]
Louise. Oh. Wait.
Now, you listen to me.
If you take one step out of this house,
there's not a damn thing
I can do to protect ya.
I'm just too beat.
But I swear to you,
if the guys who are after you
don't get ya,
then I'm gonna
beat the hell out of you myself
when I catch ya.
You really mean that,
don't you?
Every word.
You know, Thomas,
in some ways,
I like this game much better.
[ Mimics Bogart ]
That's terrific, sweetheart.
Oh. You were wonderful.
[ Chuckles ]
Ah!
Magnum, where do you
keep the coffee?
Magnum.
The marvels of modern technology.
Mmm. Coffee.
Coffee.
Louise.
Oh, good morning, darlings.
What have you been
doing here all night?
Taking care of Magnum, of course.
Magnum, would you
come out here, please?
Louise, please.
Right now I just want to kill you.
When I find out what went on here
last night, maybe I will.
You're Louise's husband.
Well, before you get too busy
making threats--
I don't feel so well.
Louise, not now.
- I think I'm sick.
- Louise, I am trying to make your husband
understand about the guys at the beach.
jackson.
[ Gasps ]
[ Christie ]
Louise.
[ Whimpering ]
This time she's not acting.
She's really sick.
[ Christie ]
Call the doctor. Quickly.
Louise, calm down.
Come on. Relax now.
This is an emergency.
Calm down.
Come on. Just relax.
How is she?
She's out of danger,
but she's feeling pretty uncomfortable.
Wyndom is with her now,
but he'll be out shortly.
And I'd advise you
to be out of here.
No. Not till I find out
what's going on.
It's pretty obvious.
She took poison.
What makes you think
she took it?
It's the only logical answer.
Unless you gave it to her.
Quite frankly, I don't think
you're the type to do that.
Christie, two guys
beat me up yesterday,
and now your sister
almost dies of poisoning.
Somebody's out to get her.
Come on, Magnum, darling.
You provoked her.
You told her you were no longer
playing the game, right?
What's that have to do
with her poisoning?
She took poison,
you saved her and here you are.
The game is still going on.
Oh, come on.
You think she'd risk dying?
She would risk anything
to keep the game going,
and you know it.
I'd better go back in.
And, Magnum, I meant it
about not being here
when Wyndom comes out.
[ Woman On P.A.]
Dr. Mort Levy,
please report to surgery.
[ Magnum Narrating ]
What Christie was saying
made sense... in my head.
But in my gut,
it felt all wrong.
I didn't believe Louise
would poison herself
and hire those thugs,
but then I was still feeling
a little fuzzy,
so I decided to let the episode rest
until I got some sleep
and cleared my head.
[ Banging ]
I should have known better.
[ Banging Continues ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Door Opens ]
Higgins.
Higgins--
What is that?
Ah. Awake, I see.
Why would I be awake?
Stunning, isn't it?
Mable Dodge is mad
for this sculptor.
Reflecting native Hawaiian themes
in a modern idiom.
Higgins, that is terrible.
And I hate that!
Higgins, I want it down.
I want it all down.
I want you and Marble Arch--
Mable Dodge.
Whatever her name is.
I want you and her out.
Since you weren't up to
driving today, I took the liberty
of putting it in the shop.
Higgins, this bill is for--
Taking the old windscreen out,
installing the new one,
plus the unit cost itself.
- But this is--
- Simply staggering.
But I can hardly make a claim
on Robin Masters's insurance,
can I?
[ Magnum Narrating ]
Later that afternoon, a messenger
delivered a letter from Christie firing me...
and enclosing my fee,
which, coincidentally, was almost
enough to pay for the windshield.
I'm not saying that Higgins
was eager for the money,
but he did stand over me
while I endorsed the check.
That's what really made me mad.
It's bad enough to be beaten up,
but it's downright humiliating
to pay for the damages yourself.
[ Woman On P.A.]
Nurse Barrow, station three, six west.
Nurse Barrow,
station three, six west.
Magnum.
I assumed you got my letter.
I did.
There's just, uh,
one little outstanding item.
[ Sighs ]
A windscreen?
It's Louise who plays games,
not me.
Maybe she plays them,
but you seem to pick up the tabs.
By the way, how much
did the guys with the ski masks cost?
I didn't hire those thugs.
Well, somebody sure did.
And if it wasn't you, it had to be Louise.
Or Jackson. One way or another,
I'm gonna find out.
We're taking Louise home.
She recovered? That fast?
- The hospital's been upsetting her.
- Well, the poison in the coffee
didn't help much.
Magnum, I would never
cut you out if I thought
that somebody was poisoning Louise...
other than Louise herself.
[ Magnum ]
What if I don't believe you?
Then I suggest you ask Louise.
Magnum.
Thank you for saving my life.
I meant to thank you before,
but I'm afraid I lost consciousness.
Christie, take Louise
down to the car.
No. Wait, please.
Magnum, maybe you think
you saved Louise's life
and I should be grateful,
but you're wrong,
because I really hold you responsible
for everything that's happened.
Stop it, both of you, please.
You know,
I don't know who beat me up
or who's after her or why,
but somebody poisoned her.
I poisoned myself.
I put the poison in the thermos
the night before as part of the game.
To take if you wouldn't continue.
And the next morning,
when it was obvious
that you weren't going on with it,
I took it.
But believe me, Magnum,
I would never have let you
take any of it.
But I took it.
And I'm ashamed.
Please take me home.
I'm sorry.
[ Higgins ]
You promise to leave
the living room exactly as it is...
and stay away until Mable Dodge
has redecorated the bedroom?
Whatever you want.
Now what can you tell me
about the poison she took?
She was very fortunate
to reach the hospital so quickly.
The poison Louise ingested
is particularly vicious,
because unless counteracted quickly,
it's virtually impossible
to reverse its destructive processes.
Like, uh, breathing carbon monoxide.
Even when pure oxygen is administered,
the victim's red blood cells
are already so damaged that--
Are you saying
she wasn't kidding about this?
If Louise Jackson swallowed
that poison deliberately,
she was either an ignorant fool...
or a woman determined
to take her own life.
[ Magnum Narrating ]
Louise may be a little offbeat,
but she wasn't suicidal.
And death would have been
a sure bet if she'd taken the coffee
on schedule.
At the beach,
miles from nowhere.
Too far from any medical attention.
Someone was trying to kill her,
and she was lying to protect
whoever it was.
And there could only be
two people for whom she'd do that.
Her husband and her sister.
[ Groans ]
[ Grunts ]
Hold it.
That's enough.
All right, get out.
He works for you.
Not anymore.
You just gave him
his termination notice.
- You sent those guys
to beat me up.
- Yes. Yes, I did.
Now just wait one minute.
Do you think you can just admit...
you sent those goons after me
and then just walk away?
I don't believe you people.
You're just incredible.
I didn't mean
to have anything happen to you.
I was just trying to scare you.
I'm sorry they got carried away.
Now, if that's not
good enough for you,
we can fight.
You're younger than I am
and stronger maybe,
so you'd probably win.
But I'm richer than you are,
so in the end I'll beat you.
Now, why don't you just
accept my apology?
[ Sighs, Chuckles ]
Did you do this
'cause of Louise's game?
I was afraid--
I was afraid she was
beginning to care for you.
And I couldn't stand that, you see.
If she left--
Afraid enough to kill her?
Hey, I love Louise very much.
Maybe I do hold on too tight.
Maybe. But I'd never hurt her.
And I'd never let anything
happen to her.
That's funny.
That's exactly what Christie said.
Christie's a wonderful girl.
If it wasn't for her,
I never would have met Louise.
Wait a minute.
Christie introduced you to Louise?
Yes. Christie was my secretary.
She worked in my office
in my home.
We were very close.
Louise used to come by and pick her up,
and once in a while she'd take
one of my horses out for a ride.
She had an accident.
She told me.
You know, I never met a woman
with such spirit.
I was beginning to feel old.
But when she came
into my home to recover,
suddenly I had a whole new chance.
I could never even
think of her ever leaving.
Mr.Jackson,
she really does care for you.
There's absolutely nothing between us.
Christie and Louise,
where are they?
Gone for a drive, I guess.
Well, where'd they go
for a drive?
Do they have any special spot?
Any favorite spot? Anything?
Not to my knowledge.
- Magnum, what's on your mind?
- Christie poisoned Louise.
Oh, come on.
That was just another game.
It's just another game, Mr.Jackson,
but this time it's Christie's little game.
Where can we find 'em?
Well, sometimes they drive out
to the other end of the island.
To an old landing strip.
I still own it. Come on.
Do you think it's going to work, Christie?
It'll be the most exciting
game so far.
I assure you.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
You poisoned the coffee,
didn't you, Christie?
I didn't know
if it was you or Wyndom.
You covered for me.
That was noble.
But coming up here with me,
that was stupid.
I had to find out, didn't I?
Why, Christie?
Why?
I love you. I've always tried
to give you everything.
Give? Give?
All you've done
your whole life is take.
You go crashing through life
knowing that somebody's going to
look out for you.
That's not true.
It's always been the two of us.
You took Wyndom from me,
didn't you?
Didn't you?
Oh.
Oh. Oh, Christie.
Wyndom is very fond of you,
but you are deceiving yourself.
He would have loved me.
It just needed time.
[ Engine Starts ]
just a little more time
and he would have loved me.
But you came crashing in,
and you took him from me.
Christie.
So beautiful,
so vital,
so much imagination.
Killing me isn't going to
make him love you.
[ Chuckles ]
This time you're gonna die
playing one of your little games.
This time the dope dealers
are using real bullets,
sister darling!
Christie, come back! No!
Christie!
[ Panting ]
[ Plane Approaching ]
No! Stop! Stop!
Where is she, Christie?
Where's Louise?
Where is she?
She's back in there, Wyndom,
playing another one
of her little games.
Another game, Christie?
Like the poison in the coffee?
[ Gunshot ]
Louise.
[ Whimpering ]
Take that way.
Hicks!
[ Panting ]
[ Gunshot ]
Oh--
Louise.
[ Whimpers ]
[ Whimpering, Sobbing ]
[ Groaning ]
Louise.
[ Panting ]
jackson?
- Louise.
- jackson.
[ Sobbing ]
Oh, Jackson!
It's all right, Louise.
[ Gasps ]
jackson!
Hold it!
You're hurt, dear!
[ Gasps ]
He's been hit.
You all right?
Okay.
You stay with him.
I'm going after Christie.
Wait a minute. Magnum.
Leave her alone.
What?
Let me handle this my way.
I have just about had
all I can take with your version
of reality--both of you.
You're rich, you're spoiled
and you--you try and twist life
around your finger like it was gum.
And she's my sister, Tom.
And no matter what she did,
I can't forget that.
- She's my sister.
- Magnum, please.
Let me settle with--
with Christie.
[ Sighs ]
On one condition.
The games stop.
Okay, I promise.
No more games.
It's only for a few days,
until after the photographic session.
Hey, Higgins, no problem.
No problem at all.
Well, I must say
you're being very decent
about all this, old boy.
Uh, Magnum--
Look, Higgins,
why should I have a problem?
jackson and Louise are going
to the mainland for two weeks
on a second honeymoon,
and they've hired me
to stay at their house.
It's a security check.
I'm sure you know about that.
It's a wonderful place, Higgins.
Thirty rooms.
A staff of six.
Oh, did I tell you
about Jacksons yacht?
They hired you?
Now let's get this straight, Higgins.
I want fresh, white paint on the walls...
and the furniture cleaned
because of dirt from storage.
[ Engine Starts ]
I'll see you around, Higgins.
Give my love to Mable Dodge,
whoever she may be.
Are you Mable Dodge?
Yes, Magnum.
This is Mable Dodge.
She of the magenta walls.
I love your work.