STEPHEN: My name is
Stephen Jameson.
I'm one of the
Tomorrow People.
They call our powers
the three T's.
- Telepathy...
- CARA: Stephen?
STEPHEN: Telekinesis...
And teleportation.
There is a shadow war going
on between us and Ultra...
No!
The secret organization
that hunts us.
The only way to keep my
species from going extinct
is to find my father.
And the only way to do that
is by working for the enemy.
Previously on The
Tomorrow People...
You overrode my leadership
in front of everyone.
If you're gonna threaten to kick me
out every time I step out of line,
you should just do it already.
Pack your stuff.
- Our kind can't even kill.
- Yet.
But you are one mutation away
from acquiring that ability.
Activate the clean-up unit
tailing Astrid Finch.
- You made a promise.
- It's already done.
CASSIE: Stephen, they're
going to kill your friend.
Get down. Under the table.
Now!
No! No! No!
Sorry. I should have
told you sooner.
(INDISTINCT POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
NYPD!
Can you hear me?
I'm coming in.
It's a lot of bullets
for no bodies.
STEPHEN: Mom. Mom!
Where are Astrid and her dad?
I dropped them at the bus stop.
They paid cash, like you said.
What is that?
Get a bag for you and Luca.
Pack only the essentials.
- No, Mom. We need to talk.
- No, we need to pack.
As many questions as you have for me, I
have for you. But now is not the time.
Mom!
Does Jedikiah know about you?
No.
Your father kept me
away from Ultra.
But Mom, all this time, you
made me think I was all alone.
I know. Honey, I'm sorry. It's
the only way I knew how to help.
- Why didn't you just talk to me?
- (POUNDING ON DOOR)
- I'll stop them. Get Luca.
- No.
- Get him out.
I'm your mother. I protect you.
- How? By lying to me all these years?
- JEDIKIAH: Hold it!
Stephen, you're okay.
Marla, I'm sorry for barging in here.
I just thought you were in trouble.
Armed men just shot at
Astrid and her father.
Wait for me in the car. Guns
down. Wait for me in the car.
Please. Let me have a
moment alone with Stephen.
If you think I'm gonna
leave him alone with you,
- you're crazy.
- Mom, Mom,
it's okay.
STEPHEN: (THINKING) I will take
care of this. I think he can help us.
(THINKING) Five minutes.
What just happened,
Stephen, wasn't me.
The Founder ordered that hit.
So I trust you see now how dangerous
it is to make an alliance with him.
You're saying this was my fault?
Revealing your powers to
Astrid put her in jeopardy.
It is an honest mistake.
I'm willing to offer you a clean
slate if you do the same for me.
You ordered my father's death.
I think it's time you finally knew
the truth about what I did and why.
(PULSATING)
I wasn't sure you'd be alone.
I don't want to hurt you, Roger.
I've done everything in
my power to prevent that.
- Wow, you look good, kiddo.
- (LAUGHS) You, too.
Sit.
(SIGHS)
(CLINKS GLASS)
You ever think our two species
could live together in peace?
You evolved to replace us. We
have no choice but to fight.
You gonna do that by allying
yourself with a paranormal madman.
Oh, God damn it. Come on. Do we
have to go through this again?
How many times do I
have to tell you?
The Founder is committed
to helping my species.
- Humanity.
- Oh, come on. Don't be naive.
The Founder's after power.
Period.
And what are you
gonna do about that?
How do you expect to beat him?
He's too strong.
(SIGHS) Yeah.
- The least I can do is try.
- And what about Marla?
And the boys.
You know if you do this, Roger,
he's gonna make me come after you.
Yeah.
- You do whatever you have to do.
- Oh, Roger, come on.
- Please. I'm begging you.
- Good to see you, Jed.
Thanks for the drink.
I tried to warn him, Stephen.
But he was stubborn.
My mom wants us to run.
That would anger The Founder.
And there's nowhere
you can hide.
Here, I can help you.
So what are you offering?
Come back to work for me.
And I promise you
that you, your family and
Astrid will be safe.
Says you or says the Founder?
Trust me.
If I do this,
my friends, my family, my
home, they are off-limits.
I see one blacked-out
SUV, I am gone.
You have my word.
(DOOR OPENING)
Are you sure we're safe here?
The Bratva has ears and eyes.
We're safe.
I would feel more
comfortable with a Marshal
who didn't have
stains on his shirt.
I gotta take a whiz.
If you need anything,
Ron and Larry are on the door.
(SHOUTING AND THUDDING)
(YELPING AND THUDDING) Hello?
You there?
Ron? Larry?
(GASPING)
Hello, Alexe.
Please, I have a family.
There's nothing in this world
more important than family.
(STRAINING)
So you kicked him out?
A kill squad almost took
out my mom and Astrid.
Now, more than ever, we need to
be watching each other's backs.
John wanted to leave.
And he defied my judgment
in public. I had to...
set an example.
He wanted to leave. You
went along with this?
Hell, no!
- What happens if Ultra tracks him down?
- John can take care of himself.
You willing to bet
his life on that?
(RUSSELL SIGHS)
- How about another drink?
- I think maybe you've had enough.
- Stephen?
- Hey...
You remember John?
He needs a place to crash.
Tonight?
Where have you been?
- I feel like maybe I should leave.
- You are staying.
STEPHEN: I'll make up the couch.
Stephen, kitchen. Now.
No. Absolutely not.
Mom, he needs a place to stay.
He's stuck.
Not our problem.
He is one of us. He has
nowhere else to go.
(SIGHS) Great.
It's just not good timing.
We need to leave tonight.
Honestly, Mom, you lost your
right to make decisions
when I found out you spent
a year drugging me.
Hey, that is not fair.
I was protecting you the
only way I knew how.
I protect this family.
I have been protecting
us for months.
How? By working for your uncle?
You don't understand.
I just need a little
bit more time.
I am getting close
to something big.
Like what?
Dad.
He is not coming back
to save this family.
- It is just us.
- You're wrong.
John can stay tonight,
but that's it.
Tomorrow, we are leaving.
- Synced and corrected by
chamallow - - Www.addic7ed.com -
I had two men at the door. I was
in the can, what, 20 seconds,
and then I hear this noise.
Suddenly the door's
locked from the outside.
I wouldn't beat myself
up if I were you.
It's a professional hit. There's
nothing you could have done about it.
But it just doesn't
make any sense.
The killer must've been a ghost.
MARSHAL: Wait, who are you?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Dr. Jedikiah Price.
What kind of doctor?
The kind who tracks ghosts.
- Talk to me, mama. What's happening?
- I couldn't get close.
Stephen and his Ultra gal-pal
were crowding the scene.
But what do you think?
Did a breakout actually
bump someone off?
Clearly Jedikiah thinks so.
It doesn't make sense. How?
We can't rule out the possibility
of an evolutionary mutation.
Whoa. You think Mother
Nature created, like,
a Tomorrow Person 2.0?
A Day-After-Tomorrow Person.
There's nothing new and
improved about killing.
Well, even Mother
Nature can brain-fart.
Unless it wasn't nature at all.
And what if he's another one out
of The Annex Project, like...
Like that other guy that used
to hang out around here?
Blond hair, blue eyes,
about yay tall.
John's gone, Russell.
(SIGHS) Poor guy's probably
dumpster diving for lunch.
Mmm. Oh, man.
Wow.
- Horseradish?
- It's in the mustard.
This is beyond a sandwich.
(CHUCKLES)
Honey, some lunch?
I need to talk to John.
All right. Well, John,
good luck wherever you end up.
Don't worry, you're staying.
Okay? We're all staying.
It seems like she's
got her mind made up.
Well, it's not
really her choice.
Go easy on her, huh?
The Annex Project,
you said there
were no survivors.
Other than me and Killian.
Hey, what about after you?
I'm tracking a
breakout who can kill.
Maybe Ultra rebooted
the project.
What does your boss say?
Jedikiah denies knowing
anything about it.
Hmm.
- Which he would in any event.
- Exactly.
So how will I know
what I'm up against.
You won't.
Until he tries to
slit my throat.
That's why your uncle
was so hell-bent on
weaponizing our species.
We are the ultimate
killing machines.
I was about two minutes away from
sending a TAC team out after you.
- Not funny.
- Not joking.
- Where are we?
- Nowhere.
No signatures matching our
killer. The guy's under a rock.
Sure about that?
No teleports within
the last 12 hours.
Try changing your
search parameters.
Why would he use that
much energy to teleport?
Because that's how much
he used last time.
(GASPS) Oh. What...
Did I break it?
It was five minutes ago.
Hillary, what happened?
(CLUB MUSIC PLAYING)
HILLARY: This place
is owned by the guy
our dead witness was testifying
against in some mob trial.
Maybe our hit man is here
to collect his money.
With his lethal gene unlocked,
he's gonna have a leg up on us.
Well, there's one of
him and two of us.
- Did you feel that?
- Yeah, he's here.
We should split up.
(THINKING) Stay on channel. Give
me a heads up if you spot him.
Whoa, dude, you
should see your face.
What are you doing here?
Same as you.
Tracking a breakout.
Why didn't you tell me your
partner was hella fit?
- Damn, girl.
- I have a deal with my uncle.
I stay in line, he
keeps my family safe.
- I'm bringing that guy in.
- You have a family to protect,
I have a species.
HILLARY: (THINKING) It's
all clear. I'm coming back.
(THINKING) No, no, no,
wait. I'm coming to you.
HITMAN: Call me if you ever have
another problem, I can solve it.
That's him.
(THINKING) I got this.
CARA: (THINKING) I'll head him off.
(LAUGHS)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Had enough?
Where is he?
- I'll take that.
- No, not this time.
Later, Stevie.
(EXCLAIMS)
Shoulda been a hit man. (CHUCKLES)
Caviar palooza!
This briefcase is bait.
Hey.
What up, Mom?
Are we purging the
basement again?
Oh, don't toss my
Star Wars figures.
They're worth serious coin.
Wouldn't dream of it, baby.
I'll throw together dinner.
Oh, already thrown.
John hooked us up.
John.
- Mmm.
- I thought...
Stephen was going to talk
to him about leaving.
(CHUCKLING) What's this?
Dig in.
Luca already ate
about half a cow.
I'm guessing you guys
don't get a lot of
proper family dinners.
I try.
But lately I've been lucky to get a
glimpse of my family these days.
It seems like Stephen just comes
home to change his clothes.
Well this looks great.
You know, I...
I can't even begin to imagine
how hard it's been for you.
And Luca. I can tell you this,
when Stephen's gone, he is out
there protecting paranormals.
What do you mean?
I thought he was just an intern.
Don't Ultra study the
Tomorrow People?
Ultra hunts the Tomorrow People.
What?
Stephen has been acting
as a double agent
to help us stay one step
ahead of Jedikiah and his
lunatic partner.
That we're even surviving is
pretty much thanks to him.
He's a hero.
(SIGHS)
Just like his father.
Ahem.
Your husband was, umm...
very important to me.
You knew Roger?
So I know how much
Stephen takes after him.
Carrying the world
on his shoulders.
Doing the right thing.
No matter what the cost.
I pay the cost, every day.
Right here.
So does Stephen.
Family is everything to him.
Which is why you got to
understand that if you leave,
if you force Stephen,
he would be leaving
his other family.
And we need him just
as much as you do.
Hi.
(EXHALES)
My God.
They've gotten so big.
It's been four years.
I keep trying to
lose track of the time,
I figured it would...
you know...
make missing you hurt less.
Am I supposed to
feel sorry for you?
No.
You were right.
I brought nothing but
danger to your doorstep.
I know we've said our
share of goodbyes, but...
this is it.
I love you.
(GROANS)
(LAUGHS)
A woman?
(GRUNTS) (GROANING)
I ask the questions.
Who are you?
See? That was a question.
Are you getting the
hang of this, yet?
The hit man you hired.
The one you gave the money to,
how do I get ahold of him?
What hit man?
Was that a question coming out of that
pretty little Russian mouth of yours?
Uh...
I have a number for you.
Good boy.
(THINKING) If you can hear
this, we have the briefcase.
We mean no harm.
Talk about a fishing expedition.
This fish lost a million bucks,
he's out looking for it.
Only a matter of time.
(THINKING) If you can hear
this, we have your briefcase.
Get up.
What are you doing?
Have you ever heard of pajamas?
Oh, excuse me.
Wasn't expecting company.
An Ultra agent is always prepared
to dispatch at a moment's notice.
Read your handbook.
We gotta go.
- Where?
- I found him.
Our breakout assassin.
How?
The owner of the club is being
indicted on racketeering charges.
He was the one who ordered
the hit on his main witness.
The motel murder victim.
I've got the hit man's number.
So what are we gonna do with it?
Not we. You.
You're going to hire
him to kill a guy.
It's under "H", for hit man.
Let me grab my "P" for pants.
You the guy?
I'm the guy.
Have a seat.
You seem
young.
Well you're not exactly what
I was expecting either.
You know, you come highly
recommended from a friend,
but maybe he was wrong.
Look, I gotta ask.
Are you affiliated with a
law enforcement agency?
Reminding you it would be entrapment
to lie about said affiliation.
No.
I'm just looking for a permanent
fix to a real problem,
you know what I mean?
You mean...
Murder?
The murder you had in mind
is gonna cost you a
million dollars.
Seems a little steep.
Plenty of guys could
do it for less.
But I'm the best.
I can get in anywhere,
anytime, anyhow.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hands on the table.
Bad idea.
(GUN SHOT) (PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
STEPHEN: Thanks, partner.
No problem.
Sorry.
(THINKING) Sorry, Cara. It's over.
(THINKING) That's funny, I was just
about to tell you the same thing.
(THINKING) What are you talking about?
We just brought the
breakout into Ultra.
(THINKING) Oh yeah?
Then why did he just
walk onto my subway car?
(THINKING) Hate to break it to you,
but you got the wrong guy, Stephen.
(THINKING) Yeah nice try, Cara.
You wanna see what I'm seeing?
Be my guest.
(THINKING) There's two of them, how...
(THINKING) They're twins.
Didn't your mother teach
you not to steal?
Didn't yours teach
you not to kill?
I never killed a soul.
(CLICKING) (ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
Oops.
How is he able to kill?
He's human.
That's impossible.
Only a paranormal could
have pulled off those hits.
We've felt him teleport.
The large tele-signatures.
He has a partner
teleporting him.
Where are you pulling
this out of?
Wait! Who?
Someone with powers.
A twin.
A paranormal twin.
We need to capture him
as soon as possible.
My brother's not
going to like this.
He'll come after you.
And when he does,
it won't be pretty.
So how does this work?
You teleport him in.
He does the dirty work.
Tell us what happened
at the hotel.
If you need anything,
Ron and Larry are on the door.
(SHOUTING AND THUDDING)
(GASPS)
Hello, Alexe.
Please, I have a family.
There's nothing in this world
more important than family.
(STRAINING)
Hey!
Guys!
Larry, open the door!
- MARSHAL: Ron! Larry!
- (GAGGING)
MARSHAL: What the
hell is going on?
So you're the executioner?
Your brother's the getaway ride.
What can I say? We
make a good team.
You're as powerless
as a mewling kitten.
You wouldn't say that if I
had a wire around your neck.
Really?
Textbook overcompensation.
The fact of the matter is,
your brother was born with gifts
that would make the gods jealous.
But by some horrible
twist of fate,
you were born with nothing.
You're wrong.
Who do you think
sets up the hits?
Manages the money?
Huh? My brother needs me.
Because you're
shrewder than he is.
Nature's
pathetic attempt at
balancing the scales,
but let me tell you
something, kid.
One day your brother's going to
realize he doesn't need you.
You're weak.
You're a burden to him.
An albatross around his neck.
He doesn't need you.
But what if I could help you?
What if I could help you get the
powers that are your birthright?
Make you your brother's equal.
How?
Mmm. Well I would
need a donor, first.
Your twin.
The answer's no, Stephen.
Cyrus may not be able to kill,
but he's an accessory to murder.
Let me take him in.
It is my duty to protect the
Tomorrow People. All of them.
What about the other criminal
breakouts we've given to Ultra?
Cyrus was being manipulated
by his brother.
If you want to punish someone, it
should be the brother that you've got.
But no. You and Jedikiah
are too busy scheming
to make Nathan sell
out his own twin.
(THINKING) Are you reading my mind?
Since you've become your
uncle's lackey, yeah.
I am.
You're supposed to
be our inside man.
And you're supposed to
help me protect my cover.
I don't want to argue
with you, Stephen.
I'm sorry, I just
don't have it in me.
This place is falling
apart without John.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Oh, this is ridiculous.
Cara is so...
Stubborn? Fearless?
- Beautiful?
- In over her head.
First kicking out, then
refusing to let go of Cyrus,
she's just making one
mistake after another.
She does have a point.
Really? You're going
to defend her?
Jedikiah is going to use
these twins as Guinea pigs.
I thought that was just a ploy.
No. It's real. Trust me.
Power transplants are the
Holy Grail for Jedikiah.
Well, has he ever succeeded?
No.
I saw one once myself.
The human is forced to watch
as the paranormal is strapped
into this medieval looking chair
that harvests their stem cells.
Every time,
the paranormal dies.
In pain.
Imagine if that
was you and Luca.
Okay. I get it.
So, like I said, maybe Cara's
right to want to hold on to him.
Look, uh, obviously murder is...
wrong, but...
How do you and your brother
spend all the money?
Are we talkin', uh, models
and bottles in Dubai?
Savile row tailors?
Holidays on the Riviera?
Paint me a picture.
Uh, we bought a house.
Uh, in Connecticut.
Buzzkill.
Uh, it's big, it's got
two washer-dryers...
(PULSATING) Nathan: Cy?
Where are you? I need you.
Cy, they're hurting me.
Dude, are you okay?
Nathan's in trouble.
I can feel it.
They're hurting him.
(THINKING) Cara?
Please. Take off the cuffs.
I have to help my brother.
Cyrus, listen to me.
It is a trap.
Your brother's been
captured, and he's trying
to manipulate you into
turning yourself in.
(STAMMERING) No, I can
feel him. He needs me.
Your brother has been
using you for years.
This is finally your
chance to be free of him.
No...
(STAMMERING) No, I have to
get to my brother. Please.
- No, I will not let you...
- He's my family.
You must have someone in your life
you'd sacrifice everything for.
I thought your offer to give
Nathan powers was a trick.
But it's real, only the procedure
will kill his brother.
Hmm.
I wonder where you got that
little piece of information?
Not many of our agents know about
our transference protocol.
Well, you're right. In the past
the donor has typically...
expired.
But that's science, Stephen.
It's success built upon
decades of failure.
And besides, we've never tried
the experiment on twins before.
And you never will.
Cyrus isn't gonna fall for your little trap.
The guy's sitting on a million bucks.
He's probably out of
the country by now.
CARA: (THINKING) I hope you're happy,
Stephen. Cyrus is turning himself in.
You okay? You're looking
a little dyspeptic.
I'm unarmed. I don't
want any trouble.
Well, well, well.
It looks like my
little trap paid off.
Take him to the lab. Prep
them both for the procedure.
- Nathan, don't do this.
- What are you doing?
If you try and take away his
powers, Cyrus will die.
I've seen my share of death.
He's your brother.
What are you doing? Even if this
procedure works, which it never has,
he dies.
Are powers really worth
that much to you?
So easy for you to say.
You don't know what it's like
to be born without them.
Step aside.
STEPHEN: (THINKING) Cara,
my uncle's gonna kill him.
No, he's not.
What did you do?
No. No.
JEDIKIAH: (WHISPERING) I don't know
about you, but this is very exciting.
You're gonna do well.
May I say goodbye first?
Indeed.
You ready, brother?
If you think it's for the best.
I do.
(WHISPERING) Waistband.
STEPHEN: Get down!
CYRUS: (THINKING) Nathan!
(PEOPLE MOANING)
Forget him. Let's go!
(CHOKING) Hold your fire!
What are you doing? Nathan!
Finishing the job.
STEPHEN: (GROANING) No,
you don't wanna do this.
I could think of one
million reasons why I do.
- We've gotta jump, let's go!
- No.
NATHAN: You thought...
You thought you could convince
me to betray my own brother?
What do you know about
the bond of blood?
(HILLARY GRUNTING)
No, no, no, no, no!
No.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) You've
carried me long enough.
(SOBBING) No.
(EXHALING) You let him get away.
(PANTING) Why'd you let him go?
You let him get away.
(KNOCKING)
Saving my life earns
you free entry.
No knock required, Stephen.
Saved your life a
few times, now.
Well, it goes both ways, right?
I trust Astrid is getting
over her trauma.
What was so important
about those twins?
I've, um, never
seen you like that.
You must forgive me for
losing my composure.
It's just the
perfect case study.
Two specimens, almost identical,
offers us the chance to study the
gene that makes you so special.
Any scientist would've killed
for the chance to study them.
Perhaps a poor choice of words.
Or maybe a scientist who himself
had a paranormal brother.
Hmm.
Well, I'm sure my own
personal history probably
fueled my interest
subconsciously.
I think it's a little
more than that.
Meaning?
When I asked you what happened to my
father's body after he was killed,
you said you cremated him.
I did.
Why?
You are so excited
about the possibility
of transferring powers
between siblings.
You're telling me
that you didn't wanna
study your own brother?
See if it was possible
to gain his powers?
I value my humanity, Stephen.
And he was my brother.
Not a lab rat.
I shouldn't have to explain
those feelings to you.
You have something for me?
I'm not sure you earned it.
You didn't finish
the job, Cyrus.
Your boy, Stephen,
got in the way, and now
my brother's dead.
(SNIFFING) So, yeah, I'd say we earned it.
(SNIFFING)
JOHN: Has it really
come to this?
Hiring contract killers
to do our dirty work?
What'd you do, give him
my gun from the lair?
You know, I have always
admired your resolve.
But this time,
you've gone too far.
I had a chance to take
out Jedikiah. I took it.
Would you listen to yourself?
You still care for Jedikiah.
Or else you'd see I'm right.
Cyrus asked me something.
If there was anyone in my
life I would sacrifice
everything for.
It's you.
You're my family.
Come back with me.
So that you could have an
assassin at your disposal?
No thanks.
No, John, that's not what I...
I miss you.
Hey.
What are you doing up?
Waiting for you.
Is everything okay?
You tell me.
Yeah, everything's fine.
For now.
For now is about as
good as we can hope.
(SIGHING)
John told me what
you're doing at Ultra.
The war that you're fighting.
After everything I did
to try to keep you safe.
Mom.
(SIGHING) I always resented your father for
choosing the fight over our family, but...
Maybe I was wrong.
Mom, everything that I'm
doing is for this family.
I know.
And I'm proud of you.
You're a born leader,
just like your
pain-in-the-ass father.
So we can stay.
And you can keep
working at Ultra.
Because I know it's important.
But I can't stop being your mom.
I need to provide some
semblance of a normal
life for you and Luca.
I know.
Luca needs it.
So do I.
But the days of burying my
head in the sand are over.
I know you're in danger.
At Ultra.
So every night,
when you come home,
I'll be waiting.
Because I won't be able to rest
until I know that you're safe.
I'm safe.
For now.
That's gonna have
to be good enough.
Good night, Mom.
I was so close.
So close.
I had the perfect two candidates,
and somehow, I just let 'em
slip through my fingers.
Well, you know what that means.
You and I are going to have
to put our plans on hold.
Again.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, yeah, you know, I
forgot to tell you.
Your son.
Sharp kid.
He's looking for you.
He's getting closer every day.
You'd tell me if he tried to contact
you in any way, wouldn't you?
You know what happens when we
keep secrets from each other.
Okay.
Anyway.
Good night, little brother.
- Synced and corrected by
chamallow - - Www.addic7ed.com -