(ROARS)
(CHAINS RATTLING)
(DOOR BUZZING)
Where do you want to begin?
MIKE: Dustpan...
Spoon...
Noodles...
Bear...
Frying pan...
Fire. Apollo Ape. "Marry Me."
Where did it all begin?
(INDISTINCT VOICES)
MIKE: Okay, it started
three days ago.
In the town of Liman,
West Virginia.
It's where I lived
with my girlfriend, Phoebe.
She is the only good thing
that's ever happened to me.
I honestly cannot even
remember my life before her.
- (BLOWS RASPBERRY)
- (GIGGLES)
We were the perfect
fucked-up couple.
She was perfect,
and I was the fuck-up.
And we were really,
really happy.
And I wanted
to make it forever,
so I saved up
for the perfect ring.
And I planned the perfect
romantic trip to surprise her.
And then I fucked
that up, too.
WOMAN ON PA: This is
the final boarding call
for Flight 1204,
departing for Oahu, Hawaii.
I repeat,
this is the final
boarding call for Flight 1204,
- departing for Oahu, Hawaii.
- (TAPPING)
Now boarding
all rows and all zones.
All passengers should be
onboard at this time.
(RETCHES)
(COUGHS)
God damn it, Mike, come on.
All passengers
please proceed to the gate.
I really am sorry, Phoebe.
I really thought I could beat
the panic attacks this time.
It's okay.
- It's not.
- No, it's fine.
No, it's not fine.
This is something
I really wanted to do for you.
Then I ruined it
and now we're going back home.
- You didn't ruin this.
- Yes, I did. It's my fault.
You should be mad at me...
- No.
- Why not?
- You can't help it, Mike...
- Okay. Thanks.
- (POLICE SIREN WAILING)
- Oh, shit.
Jesus.
Are you holding?
No, of course not.
We were going on a plane.
Why would I...
You holding?
Yeah. Sorry.
(EXHALES)
- Hi, Phoebe.
- Hey.
- Hi, Mike.
Heard you two
were going on vacation.
Hawaii.
Get another one of your
little episodes there, Mike?
You know, Phoebe.
I once had to drive
your boy home
'cause he was
having one of them
panic attacks
up on the freeway,
trying to leave town.
Is there a reason
that you pulled us over?
Hey, easy on the tone,
Miss Larson.
I'd hate to have
to search this car.
It's getting to the point
where your boyfriend
should start
leaving a toothbrush
at the overnight
down at the station.
Ain't that right, Mike?
That's right, Sheriff Watts.
Well, just wanted to
welcome you back to town.
(ENGINE STARTS)
I'll get the bags.
(SIZZLING)
Hey, Phoebe,
do you want an omelet?
(HAWAIIAN SONG PLAYING)
This could be
the right moment.
PHOEBE: Hey, Mikey?
(SIZZLING)
- Is this okay? I think this...
- (FIRE ALARM BEEPING)
- Ow!
- (CLANGING)
Oh!
(PHOEBE GRUNTING)
What the fuck!
Oh, Phoebe, oh, no, I'm sorry.
Oh, did you burn your hand?
Just let me
do the cooking, okay?
- I will. I'm sorry.
- Stop apologizing.
Okay.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS)
Apollo Ape...
Pow!
I got you.
No, what do you think
you're doing?
Hey, honey, no,
I just wanted to tell you
I had, like, a really
funny idea for Apollo Ape.
PHOEBE: (CHUCKLES)
That's cool, what is it?
(MIKE COUGHING)
How the fuck am I
supposed to read this?
(SIGHS)
- (TAPPING ON GLASS)
Hey. Hello there.
You're here late, Lasseter.
You're not my
assistant anymore, Petey.
What are you doing down here?
I know, I just miss ya.
Oh, come on, you're not
at the big desk anymore,
you can let
a few things slide.
Enough, Agent Douglas.
Oh, okay, I'm leaving.
Do you need anything
- before I...
- (PHONE RINGING)
(BEEPING)
Lasseter.
MAN: (DISTORTED VOICE)
The Ultra Program Toughguy
is active.
Wiseman asset Howell
is the target.
What?
He'll be eliminated
within 24 hours.
This is American soil,
they can't do that.
We promised to protect him.
Who is it? Yates?
The operation is in progress.
You're being informed
as a courtesy.
Who is this?
Do not interfere.
Have a nice evening.
So Apollo Ape
and Chip the Brick are, like,
"Hey, what the heck
happened?" You know?
And then they find out
that Spicy Tomato was
in charge of the resistance.
Okay, but what they
didn't find out,
which they'll find out
in the next book,
is that Fido Astro
is also in on it.
Oh, no. Dude.
I know.
I feel so betrayed.
Do you get it?
It's because
he's man's best friend,
not monkey's best friend.
Of course.
I mean, in hindsight
it makes total sense to me.
It's just that...
He's a dog.
You should write it down,
I'm telling you.
I don't know, I mean, I really
just like thinking about it
and like talking about it.
Apollo Ape and his adventures.
No, I love when you
talk about it.
I think other people
would love it, too.
Like, even...
Like they might love
to read it
if you wrote it down,
seriously.
(SIREN BLARING)
Do something
really real with it.
MIKE: You know what
skives me out, Pheebs?
What?
That car down there
has moved so much.
Like it was built
in a factory,
on a production line.
And then it was like
shipped, like, here.
And then, like, this guy
drove it all over the place.
Yeah, exactly.
But all that time,
like for years,
or really for, like,
decades really,
this one tree has been
sitting in this one place
not doing anything
until tonight,
when it, like,
stopped the car.
Yeah?
Okay, so this car
is always going.
And that tree is always just,
like, stopping. You know?
Like, it's been
stopping there for years
until tonight
when it met something
that it didn't want to
keep going,
and it was like, "Mmm-mmm. No.
"You're stopping, too."
And then this tree
that has never done anything,
is fucking, like...
(VOICE BREAKING) Like,
destroying this beautiful...
Like, really beautiful
and fast-moving thing.
Why? Why are you crying?
Because, Phoebe, like...
Am I that tree?
No.
I think I'm that tree.
And I think...
I think you're the car.
And I think I'm stopping you.
- You are not the tree.
- Okay.
I love you.
Phoebe, I really am sorry
about Hawaii.
It's okay, honestly.
I totally over-reacted.
I was really upset.
It's not going to be
like this always, you know.
Mike, you're like...
...the strongest,
kindest person
I've ever met
in my whole life.
I fucking love you.
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
- You're a fucking mess, man.
- I know.
- Yates!
- Oh, for Christ's sake.
Yes, Victoria?
I need to speak
with you right now.
Okay, I guess we were
pretty much done here.
Thanks, guys.
Stop avoiding me.
I've got word that Toughguy
is moving in
on my old Wiseman asset.
What is Toughguy?
- And where did you hear that?
- Is it true?
It doesn't concern you. Okay?
Wiseman was my baby.
Yeah, and it's still-born.
So, what are you crying about?
So you're coming after
my still-born baby?
Let's finish this
in my office.
I don't understand why
you're so upset here.
Aren't you the one
who shut down the program?
Yeah, because it was
a flawed model.
Because we were
hurting people.
I didn't expect your
yuppie ass to come riding in
on a vulture and pick
at the bones of my operation.
I was made supervisor
fair and square.
You were made
a temporary supervisor
because you kissed
the right asses.
Because I'm the right man
for the job.
According to who? Daffy Duck?
(CHUCKLES)
Daffy Duck...
Well, I guess I'm doing
something right
because I've had the job
for about two years.
(GROANS) Yeah, it should have
been two months.
You're supposed to protect
these assets. Not kill them!
Victoria, we're clearing
the portfolio.
What?
Mike Howell keeps trying
to leave town.
He needs to be eliminated.
You're going to kill him
for trying to leave town?
That's a security breach.
I'm just doing my job.
He's a human being.
- They're assets.
- He's an American citizen.
They're government property.
Are you actually
fucking insane?
Oh, language.
Listen to me, King Idiot!
If you think
I'm just going to sit back...
No, you listen to me,
you snipey overbearing bitch!
Howell dies today!
Yeah. And you can't do shit.
What are you going to do?
Huh? You going to go over me?
You're my
fucking dog here, okay?
Sit. Stay. Behave.
Now get the fuck
out of my fucking office!
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
(MIKE COUGHING)
Mike, what's happening?
Oh. Um...
Nothing. Just, uh, something.
I have to go to work.
Isn't it early?
Yeah. Yeah. But, um,
they needed me to do a thing.
What thing?
Groceries.
I love you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(HIP-HOP MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO)
(MUSIC STOPS)
- Rose.
- ROSE: What's up?
- How's it goin', man?
- How you doin', baby?
What's up!
I really appreciate
you doing this for me, man.
Come on, man. Come on, baby,
you know I got you, right?
- Okay.
- I got you.
You're my nigga-nigga-noga.
You know that shit, right?
All right. Yeah.
All right, right.
Now go open up your trunk.
- Oh, okay, all right.
- It's all cool.
Casual like, no big D.
Stay chill.
You ready?
Come on, come on, come on.
All right.
Yo', this is more illegal
than the shit
you usually get,
know what I mean?
- Yeah.
- Feel me?
This is some fucking
powerful fireworks, man.
This gonna light up
the sky for ya bitch.
Oh, Rose.
Phoebe is going to love this.
This is perfect, Rose,
this is so perfect. Oh, man.
I'm tellin' ya,
this is some serious
proposal-engagement-
wedding-type
life changing shit
you're doin'.
- You know what I'm sayin'?
- That's the plan.
Yo' you're
a sensitive nigga, bitch.
Well I love her.
You got to give it all when
you love like that, you know?
Yeah, exactly.
Comes once a life, right?
Oh, serious. Yeah, yeah.
- All right, thanks, man.
- Oh, you goin'?
- Yeah.
- Where you goin'?
Gotta drop those off
and I gotta go to work.
Wanna drop some acid
and go inside the titty bar?
Nah, that's okay. It's 8:15
in the morning, Rose.
- Thank you, Nancy.
- Thank you, Mike.
MIKE: Bye.
(BELL CLANGING)
Chariot Progressive. Listen.
Mandelbrot set is in motion.
Echo Choir has been breached,
we are fielding the ball.
Is that a lyric
from something?
Fuck.
No. Chariot Progressive.
Listen.
Okay.
- Mandelbrot set is in motion.
- Yeah.
Ma'am, are you going
to get something?
Chariot Progressive, Mike.
Lady, could you please, like,
stop it with...
Chariot Progressive.
- Are you okay?
- Listen.
Mandelbrot set is in motion.
Echo Choir has been breached.
We are fielding the ball.
Chariot Progressive.
Listen, Mike.
You're not listening...
Listen. Chariot Progressive!
Chariot Progressive.
Chariot Progressive
is in motion.
Motion...
(DISTORTED VOICE)
(SNICKERS)
Mike. Please listen to me.
All right, lady,
enough with that stuff, okay?
You're in danger.
You have to listen to me.
I've got to close up soon.
So...
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
About all of this.
I'm sorry, Mike. I tried.
It's cool.
(BELL CLANGING)
Do you want your soup?
(STEAM HISSING)
Hey, stop doing shit
to my car.
- (HISSING)
- (SCREAMS)
(CHOKING)
(GUN CLATTERS)
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
- Hey, babes, what's up?
- MIKE: Hey.
I just killed two people...
Two... Two gentlemen.
(LAUGHS) That's awesome. Why?
No, these two guys
were trying to, like,
break into my car at work
and they had guns
and knives and they
were, like, being total dicks
and they just attacked me.
Shit, babe, you got mugged?
Then I took, like, a spoon
and I just like, mmm...
I, like, shoved it
through this guy.
- Did you call the police?
- No, I didn't call the police.
'Cause I'm the killer...
I'm the murderer.
I also have, like...
I have, like, a lot of weed
and mushrooms in my car.
I just killed two dudes
in a parking lot, okay,
and Phoebe, if you don't
come here right now,
I'm gonna start like
pissing in my pants.
I swear to God, Phoebe,
I'm just gonna
start like pissing.
PHOEBE: How did this happen?
How the fuck did this happen?
I shot those guys in the head.
And that guy, I, like,
I spooned him in the neck
and his shit just,
like, ended.
You just killed two guys?
They were trying to,
like, stab me, Phoebe.
Why are people
trying to stab you?
I don't know! Shh!
I don't know, but I am...
I am, like, freaking out
all over the place.
Babe, I have, like,
a lot of anxiety about this.
- (SIREN WAILING)
- Get your hands in the air.
PHOEBE: Oh, fuck me! Yup.
WATTS: Oh, God, it's Mike.
- I'm sorry!
- Drop it.
YATES: What do you mean,
two casualties?
We lost two assets
attempting to neutralize
Wiseman-designate Howell.
How is that possible?
He was armed
with a spoon, sir.
A fucking spoon? What?
Uh, we're not sure yet,
the exact nature
of the confrontation...
He's been fucking activated!
Do you not see that?
- Yes, sir.
- This is Lasseter.
She's in the town.
Lock it down and find her.
Shut down the bridge,
nobody gets in or out!
Sir, yes, sir.
- Where's asset Howell now?
- He's been arrested, sir.
Perfect. Okay, we go in.
We take him out.
He's trapped in one place.
You cannot possibly
fuck this up.
OTIS: Yes, sir.
YATES: Employ assets
Crane and Laugher.
(LAUGHING)
Okay, so just lead me
through this one more time.
Just so I'm clear.
Just so...
No, no, no.
Um, I hit him with a spoon
and his lungs exploded.
- It wasn't his lungs.
- No, that's what happened.
'Cause he couldn't breathe,
'cause I got him in the neck.
Your lungs aren't in your
neck, they're in your chest.
I know that, Phoebe.
No, I don't know that.
No, I do.
Phoebe. It doesn't even
make any sense to me.
Okay. Okay. So you said
something about a lady.
- Yeah.
- What did she say to you?
Okay, so she said...
I don't know what she said.
Like, some bullshit. Like...
- Babe. We're in jail.
- Yeah?
So maybe just try
and remember and focus
and put it together.
What did the lady say?
Okay.
(CLEARS THROAT)
She said...
Mandelbrot set is in motion.
Echo Choir has been breached.
- (MOUTHING)
- We are fielding the ball.
Mike, what the fuck
does that mean?
I don't know.
Phoebe, I don't know
but I remember it
like it just happened.
I remember every single thing
that happened
to me in the last 94 minutes.
94 minutes? How did I even
get that number, Phoebe?
I remember literally
every single thing
that happened,
I can picture it.
- Mike, listen.
- Okay.
Just slow down.
WATTS: Yeah, Mike.
You slow way down.
(NERVOUS TAPPING)
How many times have you been
in this station, Mike?
Since you were 22?
Your probation officer must be
the Michael Jordan
of bullshitters.
Because I've never
seen you gone
more than couple of hours?
Mike.
Tell me you didn't
kill these people.
They attacked him.
- He was defending himself.
- Yeah.
- Excuse me?
- What was he supposed to do?
You're his girlfriend.
You're his mom.
You're his maid.
You're his landlady.
- Now you're his lawyer?
- MIKE: It was just a thing.
It was just a thing
that happened.
Mike...
- I didn't mean to.
- You didn't mean to?
Two men are dead, Mike.
There's no
walking away this time.
(POWER SHUTS DOWN)
(ALARM BLARING)
- What the hell is that?
- OFFICER 1: What's going on?
- (ALARM BLARING)
- Shit, lock it down!
Hey, we've got a problem.
PHOEBE: Why is the power out?
Oh, hell, Phoebe,
I don't know.
Just keep moving.
Hold on. Hold on.
Mike, I really don't want
to go in there.
Mike... There we go.
Just hold on.
OFFICER 2: All the lines
out of the station are down.
Radio, Internet, the phone...
Who the fuck is that?
Mike!
(GRUNTS)
Mike, grab his gun!
WATTS: Move! Move! Move!
Get down! Down! Stay down!
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(GROANS)
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
Ah!
(WHIMPERING)
No, no, get out.
Phoebe, get out!
(LAUGHER LAUGHING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (GROANS)
Oh...
Phoebe, the gun.
Just go!
(GRUNTING)
(POWER TURNS ON)
(RADIO STATIC)
(DOO-WOP SONG PLAYING
OVER RADIO)
(GUNSHOT)
(STRAINING)
(HANDCUFFS CLICKING)
Get out of here!
(GUNSHOT)
Come on!
- Wait!
- Hmm?
Huh?
- (BEEPING)
- Uh...
(BONE CRUNCHING)
(NECK SNAPS)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Hi, darlin'.
LASSETER: Why is Liman
on lockdown?
Why are there men
in hazmat suits
walking around
like extra-terrestrials?
What the fuck are you doing?
A dog with rabies got loose.
A real old bitch.
Oh, you're all class, Adrian.
You activated Howell.
Now two of my
Toughguy assets are dead.
I know what you're doing here.
Don't fuck with my operation!
Your operation is murder.
This is the last time
that you and I speak.
I'm taking you down, Yates.
You understand me?
That's pretty big talk
for a middle-aged woman
with a... What? A cell phone?
You can't touch me. Okay...
You can't even...
Did you just hang up on me?
Please tell me you did not
just hang up on me.
Yo, Phoebe,
where are we going?
We are leaving, we are getting
the fuck out of town.
No, I can't leave town,
you know that.
Well, you didn't have people
try to kill you before,
I was thinking maybe
that could motivate us here.
Okay, fine.
So where do you want to go?
- Fuck!
- All right, listen, listen.
We'll take my car and we'll go
to Rose's house, okay?
- What?
You want to get high
right now, Mike?
No I don't want to get... No.
Rose has like guns
and shit, okay.
He can help us hide out
and I'm still in handcuff.
Okay, you are not
in any position
to be making the plan
right now.
Really?
Well, who is, all right?
- The cops are all dead.
- The guy in the thing,
in the cell thing,
doesn't see the gun,
you don't point at it and go,
"Gun..."
Okay. No, no.
I recognize that now
as, like, a faux pas.
I'm sorry.
Like, and if someone
who's trying to kill you,
goes, "Wait..."
You don't go, "Oh, what do you
want to talk about?"
Okay, you're right.
Sorry. I'm sorry.
Please just don't
yell at me, okay?
- I'm starting to freak out.
- No. I know you are.
I just think that maybe
we need to figure out
what the fuck we're doing...
Come here. You're fine.
I'm fine. All right?
We made it out of there. Okay?
And nothing else is
going to happen, I promise.
(BAG RUSTLING)
Let's just get in my car...
Oh, fuck!
MIKE: So that's what
those guys were doing?
That would have hurt.
Okay,
let's take my car.
(TEXT MESSAGE CHIMES)
(MUMBLING)
Aw.
(CHUCKLES)
- Hmm.
- (SHUTTER CLICKS)
(CELL PHONE CHIMING)
Hello?
I'm in Liman.
I activated Howell.
What?
Yates' Toughguy assets
are in town.
I'm here trying to save
asset Howell
and derail this operation.
But something's not right.
I'm standing in front
of the sheriff station
which is on fire.
I don't understand...
(STAMMERS) Why would you...
I should not be talking...
Listen to me. I need a weapon.
Oh, my God.
There's an empty field.
I'm going to send you
coordinates for the drop.
And I need to know
where the fuck
Yates is pulling the subjects
for this operation.
If they're trained assets,
they should be doing this
quickly and quietly.
This behavior makes no sense.
Okay, I'm sorry.
I gotta hang up. I can't...
No, no, no. No, no, no.
Don't hang up. Don't hang up.
He's boxing me in,
in this town.
He's going to trap me like a
rat and he's going to kill me.
Please, Petey,
I really need you.
PHOEBE: Okay, here we go.
- (CRYING)
- (GIGGLES)
Hey.
Hey, you seem, like,
spooky quiet.
I am spooky quiet.
I'm like...
I think I'm in
anaphylactic shock.
That's not what that's called.
Like, I'm trying to think
of stuff, you know...
Phoebe, I can't
remember anything.
Like I never even...
I can't even remember
where I went to school.
- Maybe don't think about it.
- Did I go to school?
Uh...
Did we even talk
about my parents?
We walk from here.
Is that what's happening now?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
- Shit.
- What?
What if I'm like...
Like a robot?
No. No...
With gigabytes
of memory recall,
and, like, karate programming
where I use
objects to kill people.
Mike, you're not a robot.
With advanced
biological engineering.
Maybe I am.
- Mike.
- Yeah?
- You are not a robot.
- But how do you know?
I have the weirdest thoughts
in my head right now.
I know. I know, babe.
Do you know
what a M1 Abrams is?
- (DOGS BARKING)
- Hmm?
It's a type of tank.
I could list like 50 types
of tanks right now.
When did I learn about tanks?
I didn't.
I know nothing about
tanks or guns or bombs
but I suddenly know, like,
everything about tanks
and guns and...
- (COCKS GUN)
- Freeze, motherfucker!
- Oh, shit, Mike! It's you?
- Rose. Rose.
What the fuck
you doing here, man?
- Can we come over?
- Yo, yo, yo... Get inside!
Get inside right now, man!
Shit crazy tonight.
I ain't tryin' to die
from no monkey disease.
Come on, get inside!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
What the fuck?
(RADIO CHATTER CONTINUES)
What the fuck is all this?
- Mr. Yates, sir...
- I said subtle!
I said covert!
Not pitch a tent in the middle
of the fucking parking lot!
OTIS: Sir, this is...
YATES: Where are the assets?
YATES: You got them all just
sitting in a dark truck?
You said as bare bones
as possible.
Yes. Right, you're right.
Thank you.
Laugher?
What happened to you?
I heard you were KIA.
We recovered him
from the sheriff station
30 minutes ago.
But you saw him, right?
Howell?
He took my teeth.
But I got 'em back.
Oh.
- (MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKER)
- MIKE: Yeah, thanks.
We just wanna, like, hang out
here for a couple of hours.
'Cause things are like...
I don't know,
but things are, like,
pretty dangerous right now.
Yeah, so why you come
to my house, Mike?
Why didn't you go
to your house, huh?
Crazy is as crazy does
and you dragged crazy here.
And I don't even know what
that does or what that is.
You see what I'm saying?
I don't know, Rose.
We just thought it would
be, like, safer here. Ow.
ROSE: Safer from what?
Wait, why do you think
it's dangerous?
Yeah?
Like I said to you before
because of the...
(MIMICS MONKEY GIBBERING)
The what?
The monkeys. The monkeys!
And, yo, Mike, what you
gonna be safer from, Mike?
What you gonna be safer from?
- Rose... I...
- (DOOR OPENS)
Safer from what, Mike?
Perimeter's clear, man.
Yo, this is Big Harold
and Quinzin.
Niggas, this is Mike
and Phoebe.
Mike? Me and Mike
know each other.
MIKE: Me and Quinzin
Ah. Ha-ha! Jinx, right?
Dude, it sucks,
you were in first place
for like three weeks
- and your kickers got hurt.
- QUINZIN: I know, man.
What?
We do Fantasy Football
together, you dig?
And you ain't even tell me?
Shit!
Oh, everybody's got a Fantasy
Football league but Rose,
is what you're sayin'.
I guess Rose just sits alone,
I guess.
I don't know nothin'
about no Fantasy Football.
Well that don't make me
feel better, man,
nobody tell you shit.
So hurtful.
Sorry, man, sorry.
But it's all about
conspiracies tonight.
Sorry, can I just ask
about the monkeys?
And the gas masks? What...
You ain't heard? Town's under
the government wildfire.
Outer-space shit, straight
Andromeda Strain bacterial
disease type shit!
I'm sorry?
You ain't seen it?
Fuckin' look at the TV, man!
Look at the fuckin' TV!
Look at that shit,
right there!
FEMALE REPORTER: (ON TV)
...level six quarantine
around the town of Liman,
West Virginia.
The CDC has said a breakout of
what is being described as
Super Typhoid began
earlier this evening.
The bridge into town
has been blocked
with access
in or out of the town...
What did I tell ya?
What the fuck I tell ya?
That's not real. That can't...
...sources believe
the beginning of the outbreak
traced back to
these two individuals...
PHOEBE: That can't be real.
Anyone having knowledge of
their whereabouts
should contact
the authorities immediately.
MIKE: Shit, Phoebe. Fuck...
These two animal activist
are highly contagious...
MIKE: That's that lady
I was telling you about.
...and should not
be approached
under any circumstances.
ROSE: What?
Officials have indicated that
Victoria Lasseter
is responsible
for the outbreak.
Why the fuck
y'all on TV, Mike?
...Victoria Lasseter's
inappropriate close contact
with several test monkeys.
ROSE: Yo, Mike,
are you in on this?
You mean, this is the lady
that talked to you?
- Yeah.
- ROSE: What?
Why the fuck do you know
that monkey fucking
motherfucker, man?
- Dude, calm down.
- ROSE: Calm down?
I want fuckin' answers now.
Yo! Yo! Yo!
Okay, Rose, listen...
Things don't mean
what you think they mean.
This is going to sound crazy.
(FEMALE REPORTER
READING PHONE NUMBER)
Something very weird is
happening to me tonight, okay,
and I don't know what it is,
but I keep,
like killing people, okay.
And there's a chance
I may be a robot.
Oh, shit.
You got the fuckin'
monkey virus.
No, Rose. Stop...
You're fucking going to
quarantine, Mike!
- Rose, mm-mmm, don't do that!
- Wait, wait, wait! No, no!
You're going to quarantine,
motherfucker!
HAROLD: Damn!
Whoa, whoa!
Yo, bitch!
Rose. I'm sorry.
(HAROLD MUMBLING)
PHOEBE:
Okay, Rose, can you just,
whatever you do, not call
that number that's on the TV.
You think I'm gonna
call the government?
Bitch, I ain't
trying to get neuralized.
MIKE: Rose, maybe we could
just talk about this, okay?
Nuh-uh, Mike.
Nuh-uh!
MIKE: Okay.
(LOCK CLICKING)
- Hey, Rose.
- ROSE: Yeah?
I think I could probably
break this lock.
- ROSE: Please don't.
- Okay.
- (MUSIC BLARING FROM SPEAKERS)
- Wow.
Wow.
I've never been down here.
Hey, Phoebe...
Phoebe, do you really think
I have that disease?
What? That fake monkey
news-story disease?
How do you know it's fake?
I did meet that woman.
PHOEBE: Well, how do you feel?
You feel sick?
No. I feel kinda amazing.
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Hello?
- YATES: Hola, Petey.
Why am I hearing that there's
a supply drop made over Liman?
Do you understand that
you're assisting the efforts
of a rogue CIA operative
acting against
national security?
What do we call that, Petey?
When someone is
actively working against
the interests
of their own country?
Treason.
Gosh, help me out here
because I always forget,
what's the punishment
for treason?
We take you outside and we
shoot you in the fucking head.
Now I'm keenly aware
that you have a degree
of loyalty to Lasseter.
That ends now. You're not to
help her again. Understood?
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
LASSETER: Thanks for the
location on Howell.
I'm heading to him right now,
but in the meantime
we've got to go public
on this. Call Krueger.
I can't believe
Yates has been training
mental patients
for his program.
It is my duty to inform you
that should you go public
with this operation...
It's your duty? What?
We have to stop this!
He's completely out of his...
If you go public
with this operation,
you're committing treason,
and will be treated
as a traitor
to the United States
of America.
No! Pete? Peter?
- I'm sorry.
- Petey!
I can't help you anymore.
Fuck!
Phoebe, what are you doing?
We are escaping.
Phoebe. No, Phoebe, stop.
I really don't think we should
do this, okay?
I think we should
just wait here.
Rose is like a really good
guy, he'll come around.
You'll see. He's just
a sensitive and complex man.
Babe, I'm not going to
sit around
and wait on the judgment
of your drug dealer.
YATES: Do we have
a location on Howell?
He's at his friend's house.
Okay, we roll in waves.
Got it?
Employ Newton,
Laugher and Bourbon.
Is the press package ready?
- Yes, sir.
- Activate it.
And...
I'm clearing
use of Riofloxin gas.
No more risks.
No more mistakes.
Clean sweep.
PHOEBE: Fuck!
Do you know
what you're doing?
I'm just going to scoot
a little bit further
and see if I can get
into the other room.
Just give me one second.
This is not the right moment.
(GAS HISSING)
ROSE: What do you mean,
Quinzin,
I can't be in your league?
- I know football. Dang.
- QUINZIN: It's too late, man.
ROSE: Too late?
It's never too late.
Whoa!
What the...
Oh.
(LOUD THUD)
Oh, shit! Phoebe!
Oh, shit!
- (GUNSHOT)
- (GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
What?
(GRUNTING)
(PHOEBE MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOOR OPENING)
(YELLS)
(COUGHING)
Babe, come here. Hey, honey?
Mike... Come here. Come here.
Hey, wake up! Wake up!
Come on, come on.
You have to stay awake,
all right?
Hey, that Riofloxin shit,
it's going to make you
really tired!
This is going to
help a little bit.
Only if you stay awake
for me, okay?
- I feel sleepy.
- Don't sleep! Don't sleep!
Baby, if you sleep you die.
Okay? If you sleep
you die, Mike.
That's how this shit works.
Shuts down your senses one
by one. Keep your eyes open!
Baby, keep your
fucking eyes open!
Honey? Honey? Babe!
Babe, wake up! Wake up!
Wake up, okay?
Fuck! Babe...
No, what the fuck! No!
What about Chip the Brick?
Hey! What about...
What about Apollo Ape?
I love them. I love them...
If you die, they die.
I don't want them to fucking
die. I love you, babe.
(ECHOING) Babe! Please!
PHOEBE: Mike, wake up.
(ECHOING)
I love you.
Look at me.
Mike, you won't remember this,
but I love you.
...new start,
away from all this.
Just you and me.
You're free.
Away from all this.
I love you.
It's over. I love you.
Interview number 13985.
This is our
last session, Mike.
Mike!
You won't see me again.
I love you. It's over.
Wake up. Please!
Wake up! Mike.
Mike, you gotta wake up.
Mike! Mike!
Please!
(MIKE RETCHING)
(COUGHING)
Okay.
Hey.
No, no.
How do you know
what that gas was?
Okay... I...
No, no, no. What is going on?
How do you know...
How do you know
what that gas was?
I don't know what's going on.
But, listen...
- Baby...
- No. No.
Okay, Mike.
Mike. Mike... Hey...
(STAMMERING)
I don't know what's going on.
But I do know what's going on
with you, okay.
If you just listen... Listen.
Okay, tell me then.
It's not going to make
any sense right now.
What is going on?
What's going on with me?
I...
I'm your handler.
I was assigned to you
five years ago.
- And...
- My handler?
Please understand...
I'm CIA, okay.
- But...
- Hmm? You're what?
- Listen to me. It's okay.
- You're what?
I've been trying to tell you
this for so fucking long.
Phoebe... Are you not...
Are you not my girlfriend?
Of course I'm your girlfriend.
- Babe, that's what...
- Please stop it.
That's what I'm telling you.
No...
Please stop it. No.
I can't even look at you.
No, no, no, I gotta go.
PHOEBE: Mike!
Mike, you have to
let me explain!
- No. No. No... Mike...
- No, no, no.
- Hey...
- Leave me alone!
- Unlock the door, Mike!
Oh, shit!
No, no, no. Get off of me.
Get off of me!
Mike, relax...
Look, I just need to know.
Am I real?
Yes, you're real.
Are your parents really dead?
Okay, how much of everything
that you've ever told me
is just a complete lie?
Not everything is a lie.
No, please don't use
your grown-up voice with me.
I'm not.
Okay... No.
I was in love with you.
I am in love with you...
I don't even know who you are!
Fuck, Mike!
No, you don't get to like,
fake cry with me, okay.
They probably like train you
how to do this, don't they?
Fuck with my emotions.
Okay, well stop it.
Please stop it.
Hey! Hey! Stop it, okay!
Fucking stop it!
I'm not lying anymore.
Just give me one chance.
I'm not going to
lie to you, okay?
Get out.
No. No, Mike.
Phoebe, get out of my car.
I can't...
- Get out of my car, okay!
- I can't...
- Get out of my car!
- It's my fucking car!
- No! Get out of the car! Okay!
- (CRASHING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
(LAUGHER LAUGHING)
(LAUGHER WHISTLING TUNE)
Phoebe...
(PHOEBE GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Phoebe!
- Phoebe!
- (CHOKING)
(BLOWS)
(LAUGHING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(YELLING)
LAUGHER: I'm supposed to
bring you in alive.
Lucky you! (LAUGHING)
Oh, shit!
Fuck!
No, no, no.
Bang! Bang! Bang!
(LAUGHS)
Phoebe! Phoebe!
Phoebe!
I'm going to do
something very bad.
- MIKE: Phoebe!
- (LAUGHER WHISTLING TUNE)
(GRUNTING)
MIKE: Oh, shit! What is that?
It smells like gas!
- Gas!
- No! No!
Fuck! No! No! No, don't!
Oh, fuck! Oh, man!
I fucking hate you, man!
Well, I fucking
hate you too, man!
Oh, shit!
(GRUNTING)
Hey, I wanna show you
something! Hey, wake up.
Hey, wake up!
I said I wanna
show you something.
Look!
(LAUGHER LAUGHING)
Mike! Mike!
OTIS: Sir!
Well, if it isn't
Miss Stockholm Syndrome 2010.
Yates. What the fuck
are you doing here?
Whoa. That's unprofessional.
Who's running this operation?
Since when did desk jockeys
like you run field ops?
Well, I guess
that's the problem
with going dark
for five years.
You kinda fall out of the loop
on a couple of things.
Do you have
authorization at all?
Where's Krueger?
Phoebe Selburg,
she who'd rather suck
some stoner's cock
than turn herself back
in for debrief,
is going to question
my authorization?
I've read your file.
You have no secrets from me!
Your boyfriend isn't real.
We made him.
Oh, I'm so sorry,
that some lab-rat
made you cum a bunch of times
in the back of a Taco Bell!
Yeah, that's probably
a good reason to throw away
your entire life!
Well, I guess
it all worked out.
Because look where I am now.
In charge
of a major operation.
And look where you are.
Under departmental arrest
for insubordination.
And your face
is all messed up.
And I'm gonna get a promotion.
Your pathetic stoner boyfriend
has been burned alive.
(MIKE COUGHING)
Hey. Hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- It's okay. It's okay. Hi.
- Hi.
Mike, do you recognize me?
Do you know who I am?
Yeah, you're the woman
from the market.
Yeah.
Do you really know who I am?
Are you my mother?
No.
Okay, you know what,
I gotta take you somewhere.
- No, no, no.
- We got to go someplace safe.
No, we have to.
You're coming with me. No...
No, I'm...
Stop. I'm not going anywhere
until you tell me
what the hell is going on
with me, okay?
Who are you
and what did they do
with my girlfriend?
Okay.
Do you remember
when you were arrested
when you were 18 for the acid?
That was when we first met.
I was recruiting people for
a program called Wiseman.
Which was basically designed
to take third strike
misdemeanor offenders
and offer them
the opportunity to volunteer.
Volunteer? For what?
To be... To be an experiment.
An experiment?
Yeah.
That was a mistake.
No, but Mike, you worked.
All the other subjects
that came in,
they were all failures.
But not you.
You were a success.
But it was driving you insane.
It was driving
everybody insane.
The risks weren't
worth the rewards.
So I shut it down,
and I gave you all
new lives and new identities.
- A fresh start here.
- Yeah.
So you erased my memories.
And you fucked with my head.
And you left me here
with a fake girlfriend.
- No.
- No, Mike, Mike, wait.
This isn't who
you always were.
The slow thinking,
the inability to leave town.
The phobias...
We did that to protect you.
- To protect me?
- Yeah.
Well tell that to the guys
who are trying to kill me.
Who the fuck are those people?
- (DOOR CREAKING)
- Hey. You're the lady from TV!
Hey.
You fuck monkeys!
What?
Mike, where are you going?
Sir, asset Howell
is still alive.
He and Agent Lasseter
were spotted at the gas
station near Chestnut Street.
YATES: Shit!
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Hello?
- YATES: Hola, Petey.
I need a drone in the sky
in less than an hour.
Call me when it's entering
my air-space.
So you're going to blow up
- a civilian town?
- YATES: If I have to.
To catch one guy?
This is it, Pheebs.
The kid gloves are off.
It's fine. Go back to work!
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
HOME: Sir, new sighting.
Two subjects
heading east on Perryman Way.
They're going
back to the house.
He's not just going to go
Mike can be
a little slow sometimes,
but he's not a fucking idiot.
LASSETER: Mike,
I can't believe
you're going
back to your house.
MIKE: I'm going inside
and I'm going to sleep.
LASSETER:
He could have snipers
taking aim at us right now.
Really? Then shoot me, please!
- (LASSETER SHUSHING)
- So what?
Why are you still here?
LASSETER:
I don't want you to die.
MIKE: Why?
Because...
Because I care about you,
all right?
Okay, well I don't care,
all right.
If I die, I'm going to
do it stoned,
and smiling in my bed.
And you can stay
or you can go.
YATES: Otis, I need you and
Beedle to go to the house
and confirm the location of
Lasseter and asset Howell.
Now, thank you, now!
OTIS: Sir, yes, sir.
What the fuck
are you looking at?
(HAWAIIAN SONG PLAYING)
Who's Apollo Ape?
He's a monkey astronaut.
I made him up.
He goes on adventures.
Hey, Mike, you know Phoebe
was supposed to come back in.
When you were in the program,
she always looked out for you.
As all the other assets
kept failing,
you kept succeeding.
She had so much faith in you.
You were real to her.
She was just supposed to
get you settled into this town
and then she was
going to be reassigned.
But she decided
to stay with you.
She gave up everything,
her whole real life.
Just thought
you should know that.
- (OBJECT CLATTERING)
- (LASSETER GROANING)
Miss Lasseter?
(LASSETER CHOKING
AND COUGHING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(BEEDLE GRUNTING)
Come here.
Asset Howell
confirmed on site!
Sir, asset Howell
confirmed on site.
Requesting immediate backup.
Copy that.
Drone strike is a go, call it.
But what about Otis?
Drone strike is a go! Call it!
We are go for strike.
MAN: Roger, go for strike.
Agent Douglas, please confirm.
Go for strike.
Moving into attack position.
MIKE: Okay.
There you go. All right.
Oh, shit! Okay, stay here.
- (GUN COCKING)
- (MUFFLED GUNSHOT)
OTIS: Beedle!
(BEEPING)
Target lock in progress.
Waiting confirmation
to strike.
Fire!
Agent Douglas,
please confirm deployment.
YATES: Fucking fire!
What the fuck is wrong
with you! Drop it now!
Drop it!
Now! Fire! Now!
Agent Douglas?
We're losing
our target window.
- Do you copy? Agent Douglas!
- YATES: Fucking idiot!
AUTOMATED FEMALE VOICE:
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
- five, four, three, two...
- No, fuck you.
AUTOMATED FEMALE VOICE:
Target lock disengaged.
WOMAN:
Predator satellite link down.
MAN: Ground station has lost
communication with the drone.
(MUSIC CONTINUES
ON RECORD PLAYER)
Wow.
The ol' frying pan
bullet trick.
(MUSIC STOPS)
(LAUGHING)
Shit. Oh, shit!
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(PHONE RINGING)
This is Krueger.
MAN: (DISTORTED VOICE)
Hello, Mr. Krueger.
Um, do you have a minute?
(ALARM BLARING)
MAN: (OVER PA)
All personnel evacuate.
Initiate immediate
non-combatant
evacuation protocol.
All transport vehicles...
LASSETER: Otis,
how'd you get tied up
in all this?
(PHONE RINGING)
Don't answer that.
What if it's the guys
who have Phoebe?
It definitely is.
Okay, then I'm
going to answer it.
No, Mike.
- Hello?
- Hello.
Who's this?
You first.
Oh, fuck me.
It's you, isn't it?
- It's Mike Howell.
- Yeah. Who's this?
Is the house not all
on fire?
No. Man, the house
is like basically normal.
Okay.
So what's the plan now?
I mean, like,
like do you surrender?
Fuck! You got me.
I surrender.
Why don't you come on down to
the Max Goods parking lot,
and accept my surrender.
- The Max Goods on Wilson?
- Yeah.
Yeah, is that one across
from the tire shop?
The Ten Minute Tires?
What? Yes! That Max Goods.
So what happens
if I meet you there?
Like, how do you accept
a surrender?
Do I need to sign something?
Uh, your girlfriend's here.
Would you ever like to
see her alive again?
I don't know.
So if I just took out my gun
and blew her fucking face off,
you'd be cool with that?
No, that wouldn't be cool.
Is she really there with you?
Mikey?
I'm sorry.
But I'm the tree.
I've been the tree the entire
time, you're the car.
Okay?
I love you.
So you can leave,
you can go wherever you want
and they will fucking never...
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(SCOFFS)
That was really fucking lame.
LASSETER:
Mike, what are you doing?
I'm going to save my
girlfriend from Max Goods.
Get out!
Get out of the fucking truck!
You're all now
Code-3 right now!
Go! Go! Faster! Go!
Go! This is it!
This is the moment
that I have trained you for!
This is not a fucking
dress rehearsal, okay!
This guy is deadly.
He is silent
and he will sneak up on us.
- Are we clear?
- (FIREWORKS BURSTING)
Fuck!
(ALL GRUNTING)
Laugher, get out here!
(ALL EXCLAIM)
Hey, Phoebe! Phoebe!
- (OVER PA) Hey, Phoebe...
- Mike!
I just wanted to say
that, um, I love you.
And that everything
is going to be okay.
I mean, not like perfect,
obviously, but better.
Like we'll probably
have to get a new house,
- and also cars...
- You two, can you kill him?
- Please, kill him.
- ...but I'm coming to get you.
And this will all be over.
Soon-ish.
(GUN SHOTS)
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOTS)
Oh!
- MIKE: Phoebe!
- (MEN SHOUTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT)
Yates, give up!
Just let me go,
that's all he wants!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
Aah!
Go! Go!
- Laugher, grab her.
- Fuck!
MIKE: Phoebe!
(MOANS)
(MEN SCREAMING)
Laugher, end this.
(PHOEBE STRUGGLING)
(GRUNTS)
Don't hide!
Come out.
I really want to talk to you.
(EXHALES)
(LAUGHING)
Come out!
(PHOEBE GRUNTING)
Come here!
Oh. You know...
What? What do I know?
What do I know?
Why don't you tell me
what I know?
You're fucked!
Am I? How?
My pathetic
stoner boyfriend...
He's going to kill you
and you know it.
You know what?
Hmm?
- You...
- (SPITS)
Huh?
(LAUGHER LAUGHING)
I think you're a lot like me.
Ah!
Ahh!
(SCREAMING)
Fuck this!
(LAUGHS)
Fuck you! They're going to be
laughing at your pothead ass
tomorrow morning
at debriefing!
You know what, Tarzan,
why don't you go burn
with your fucking ape!
(YATES CHOKING)
(GRUNTS)
You're scaring me.
Will you please come out?
Can we just talk?
I wanna talk...
(GROANS)
(LAUGHER GROANING)
(LAUGHING)
(LAUGHS)
Oh...
I'm sorry.
I can't control
the things that they did
to my head.
They made you
like they made me.
But you're better than me.
Who told you what to do?
Nobody.
That must be nice.
(LASSETER YELLING)
(CHOKING)
(GRUNTING)
Who's the bitch now, fucker?
- KRUEGER: Enough, Lasseter.
- (GASPS)
(YATES COUGHING)
Enough!
PHOEBE: Mike?
Mike?
(CLATTERING)
Baby?
Phoebe...
(SOBBING)
Fuck.
(SNIFFLES)
(DOOR CLICKS)
Do you want to go home?
Okay.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(INAUDIBLE)
She said yes!
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
(CHUCKLES)
She said yes!
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Oh, man, come on,
just give us, like, one...
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(TROOPERS SHOUTING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(DOOR KICKS OPEN)
- AGENT: On the ground!
- Ah, perfect.
- (GUNS COCKING)
- (AGENTS SHOUTING)
KRUEGER: Congratulations.
In the fucking woods,
in the fucking rain!
That is the level of fuck-up
you have achieved!
LASSETER:
I just want to say, sir,
that Peter Douglas
should not be held responsible
for any of his actions
in the last 24 hours.
Douglas will be dealt with
when he's dealt with.
You, on the other hand,
you directly interfered
with a government operation.
And as a result,
you caused the death
of innocent civilians.
Is that correct?
- Yes, sir.
- You're absolutely right, sir.
Thanks to Lasseter
activating asset Howell,
seven American citizens
are now dead.
In an operation
that wouldn't...
This is an operation that
you created and spearheaded
without any authorization,
is that correct?
Yes, sir,
but you have to understand,
I was self-starting.
Excuse me?
Did I make some mistakes?
You know, I did.
Did I take some shortcuts?
Sure.
But in the end, I was just
doing what I needed to do
to create
a cost-efficient exploit
of a system
already put in place.
And if I pulled it off,
you'd be thanking me. Right?
Come on, you'd be
fucking thanking me, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Thank you.
- Now I'm...
- (GASPS)
(LASSETER WHIMPERS)
I don't know
if this is appropriate,
but please,
please do not kill me.
I'm your source.
When I called you
to notify you
that the sweep was happening,
I did it out of respect
and courtesy,
and you've made me
regret that now.
It was not my intention
for you to act like a child
and try to save your puppy.
The puppy was going down,
I was notifying you
of the puppy's death.
But the puppy just shit
all over everything!
You have a crazy,
scary rabid puppy
that murders people
and will still need to be
put down.
You understand that? Correct?
Yes, sir.
You better pray you can find
a way to turn this into a win
and pull a miracle
out of your ass!
Because if you can't...
That's you.
You already have
your miracle, sir.
My program worked.
Wiseman beat Toughguy.
Mike Howell eliminated
17 Toughguy assets
single-handedly.
That makes him
the most effective asset
we've ever seen
in any of the Ultra Programs.
Ever. In 60 years.
Pardon me for saying it, sir.
But that is a puppy
worth saving.
That is a $400 million puppy.
And you have him sitting
in a holding cell right now.
You're just going
to put him down?
(DOOR BUZZING)
ANALYST: Where do you
want to begin,
Agent Howell?
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(BELL DINGING)
I'll be up in a minute.
Okay.
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
Hello. Hi.
They took the bait.
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(MAN SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(SNICKERS)
(MIKE CHUCKLES)
(IN ENGLISH)
Something funny?
(SPEAKING MANDARIN)
(ROARS)
(ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(SINISTER LAUGH)
(ROARS)
(GUNS COCKING)
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
(DINGS)
(ROARS)
(SNARLING)
(HAWAIIAN MUSIC PLAYING)