(SIREN WAILS)
Dr. Ross, we've got satellite
from the Congo.
- What did he say, Rudy?
- I can't repeat it here.
- It's Charles.
- It won't work.
- You changed the code already?
The old man's got me changing it
every three hours now.
- Rudy, Rudy, Rudy, Rudy.
- Very inventive.
We should have a visual momentarily.
- They said they found it.
- You're kidding?
Seven volcanoes, and he picks the
right one. His luck's finally changed.
- Karen?
- I read you, Charles. And I see you.
Well, eureka and all that.
I found the bloody thing.
(RUMBLING SOUND)
- What was that?
- That was about the usual.
This whole place does the shimmy.
- How's the volcano?
- Acting very much like a volcano.
They tell me it's fine,
but I wouldn't build condominiums.
Charles, did you really find it?
Chemically flawless,
blue diamond alluvia.
Johnny-on-the-spot phasic laser.
Now this is going to look kind of
raw without a real diamond.
Would you say that test
came back positive?
Oh, my God.
We found the sand
in a mineral stream.
Jeffrey's gone off
in search of the source.
- I'll get Travis.
- Wait. Let me get Jeffrey.
He should share in the glory.
- Let's link up again in one hour.
- Great.
- See you in an hour.
- Give me your coordinates.
Charles?
- Jeffrey...
- Charlie, over here.
Charlie, I think this
may be really something.
- We haven't got much time.
- I'll show you.
Jump in.
- What?
- I'll go first.
Jeffrey!
- What is this?
- Come on.
From below it just looks like jungle,
but it's not just jungle. See?
Jesus Christ.
This is a big deal, Charles.
This is a big find.
I can't believe
it's just sitting here.
All these centuries,
just waiting for lucky us.
Listen, I raised Houston.
They're getting the old man.
Come on camera
and share the glory.
- We'll have to get another team here.
- All right. Let me grab my bag.
- Perfect? A flawless diamond?
- He found it. He was right.
With the right laser and diamonds
we can dominate the
communications industry.
- Has he found a source?
- Jeffrey's into it.
Charles says a laser with a diamond
like that can punch a hole in the moon.
Don't say any more here.
Come on, Jeffrey.
Jeffrey!
Come on, we're supposed to transmit
in ten minutes.
Now you're throwing stuff at me?
(GROWLING)
- Where is he?
- I don't know. They're ten minutes late.
- Activate the remote.
- Yes, sir.
- I guess he's still looking for Jeffrey.
- Pan the camera.
What in God's name?
Lock the remote. Back scan. Give me
thermal readout. Resolve to six-six.
(LOUD GROWLING)
- I can see seven dead people.
- What's that sound?
Come on, come on!
- I didn't see him.
- What?
Charles. Charles!
- I'll get help.
- You can't get out. I changed the code.
Well, what is it? Rudy?
- Sir?
- Use the fire extinguisher on that.
- What's the code, sir?
- Do what I say!
- No one knows this happened but us.
- Families must be notified. Your wife.
We didn't see him.
If it's reported, they'll close the border.
- What was that?
- Baboon.
- I thought it was a gorilla.
- Gorillas didn't kill all those people.
It could have been locals
or a rival company.
Not another paranoid fantasy.
- I need those diamonds, Dr. Ross!
- Are you for real?
It's the future.
Most people think
children are the future.
I've got 40,000 people working
for me. They all depend on me.
This satellite is our
communications cash cow.
In three years it'll be obsolete. I need
a new cash machine. This diamond's it!
Charles knew it. That's why he went
to that godforsaken place.
Charles went into the Congo
to please you.
- I know you had feelings for him.
- I almost married him.
Listen to me. I'm talking like he's...
You have to go down there, Dr. Ross.
You're good in the field.
You were good in Panama.
Once you're local, the laser's power
pack should give off a readable signal.
- Take over an existing expedition.
- What are you talking about?
There's no time! Once we let out what's
happened, Zaire will shut the border.
- By the time the investigation's over...
- Are you human?
I'll be human later. Hire people
when you get there. Good people.
Never mind, I'll have some waiting.
- Find out what happened to Charles.
- Tell me you love your son.
- I do.
- That's why you're sending me.
It is.
OK. But if I have one moment when
I think otherwise, I'll make you sorry.
That's a promise.
Oakland's number one classic station,
taking you back in time, all the time.
Isn't that beautiful?
What's Amy's favorite color?
Green, that's right.
How green was my valley... Drop that!
Good. Pretty, so pretty.
No, Amy, on the paper.
Yeah. Good.
Amy, get some more paint.
Good. That's green.
No, Amy, on the paper. On the paper.
Good. That's good.
Good girl. Such a pretty girl.
That's your lovey.
Amy!
Hey, you!
Yes!
- How did she sleep?
- Great.
- No nightmares?
- Not a one.
Good girl. That's my Amy.
Richard, you better clean her up.
It's showtime.
When we started out it was so simple.
Communication was what separated
human from animal. Speech.
And for those who had an impairment
which inhibited speech - sign language.
An alphabet in gestures.
Words in motion.
Then came virtual reality.
Sensors worn like clothing could read
and replicate the body's movements.
Professor Arliss Wender at MIT
was the first scientist to apply
this technology to sign language.
Our subject, William,
was born without the organs of speech.
Isn't that right, William?
That is absolutely right.
This is the first time
I have ever heard my own voice.
Lights, please.
It's hard to get grants for what I do.
Most people just don't believe it.
They think it's a parlor trick. A gag.
But it's no gag, ladies and gentlemen.
With this new technology
I can demonstrate it
in a way that it hasn't been possible
to demonstrate it before.
Animals can talk. Amy,
could you come down here, please?
Hello, Amy. Thank you for the flowers.
Peter. Hello, Peter.
Amy, how old are you?
Amy seven.
Amy good gorilla.
- Amy pretty.
- Yes, you are.
This is a talking gorilla, Moira.
This gorilla is talking!
- I know, Boyd.
- This is really happening.
- This isn't Mr. Ed.
- I know it's not Mr. Ed.
Amy, look at me.
- Amy mother.
- That's right. That's your baby.
- Amy wants lunch.
- OK.
- What do you think, Mrs. Romy?
- It's spooky. Very spooky.
Amy's above average intelligence
for a gorilla, but she's not a freak.
What she has learnt, other gorillas
have learnt and can learn,
but it takes money, of course.
Isn't that right, Amy?
(SCREAM)
Amy, calm down. Easy.
It's OK. You're all right.
- You've got her sedated. She'll be fine.
- She won't be fine. Nightmares again.
It's happened before. Gorillas
in captivity degenerating mentally,
having to be destroyed.
When she did these paintings
she got better. Why?
Hey, hey...
What's this room starting to look like?
- She's been painting the jungle!
- I don't know, Peter.
She wants to go home.
Peter, you did a great job.
You taught a gorilla to talk, to paint.
You can get a grant for anything
for Amy except for setting her free.
How about this? I taught her,
now she can teach them.
- Who?
- The mountain gorillas.
Teach an animal to talk and we can
translate what other animals are saying.
Oh, please!
Making you what, Dr. Doolittle?
No foundation would fund
an expedition with that objective.
I will pay.
- I will pay for Amy to go home.
- And who are you, sir?
Herkermer Homolka,
formerly of Romania.
Free now
of the chains of Ceaucescu.
Traveling the world, doing good.
- A Romanian philanthropist?
- Herkermer Homolka.
- Something's voodoo.
- Don't look a gift horse in the mouth.
- I don't know.
- It hasn't penetrated.
We're taking Amy home.
Get packed.
Do you know where we're going?
Amy, where are we going?
- Jungle. Me jungle.
- She's really excited.
Are you excited?
- Me? I'm terrified.
- Jungle.
Safari? I don't even like picnics.
Nice glasses.
Jungle. Me, jungle.
- That's right. Jungle. Home.
- Tickle me. Tickle me. Tickle me.
Come on, time to go.
Someone looking for me?
Herkermer Homolka, hello.
The transport.
Oh, yeah. Um...
- Is there a problem?
- Not unless there's a problem.
Are you excited? That's a camera.
Be careful, it's expensive.
I think she's got a real eye.
- Professor Karen Ross.
- Professor Peter Elliot.
- Doctor.
Have you got my faxes,
Fed Exes and phone calls?
- I'm sorry. You're the one.
- I'm the one.
- It's a hastily put together expedition.
- To the Congo. The talking gorilla.
- Jungle.
- That's right, the jungle.
- Jungle. Tickle Amy.
- Just a minute.
- I need to join up with you.
- I'm afraid that's impossible.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
- I have all the visas.
- This is ready to load on the plane.
- We're taking this stuff off the plane.
- Off the plane?
I can make it worth your while,
pay part of the cost.
Why are they taking stuff
off the plane?
- I'm sorry, we don't need any money.
- You can easily find room for me.
- It's not a matter of that. It's Amy.
- Ugly woman.
- The gorilla?
- She gets jealous very easily.
- Why are you unloading the plane?
- Talk to the operations guy.
- Can't you tell me?
- No.
I have to be on your manifest, or my
visas are worthless. Name your price.
I don't have any. I'm not
a pound of sugar, I'm a primatologist.
Don't be hasty, Dr. Elliot.
Herkermer Homolka,
formerly of Romania.
Dr. Karen Ross.
There seems to be some glitch.
They're unloading the plane.
Yes.
Unfortunately there has been
a slight interruption in my credit flow.
- I am unable to pay for the fuel.
- I'll pay for it.
- I'll pay for it. How much is it?
- $56,000.
- 56,000? What are you smiling about?
- You need me, Dr. Elliot.
Three-three-zero.
Oakland ground, Omni 901.
I'd like to taxi to the active.
Taxi to runway three-one left.
This is your captain speaking.
We've been cleared for take-off.
Make sure that your seat belts are
fastened and luggage safely secured.
We're returning her to the jungle
from whence she came.
From the look of it
not a moment too soon.
- You're the reason she's upset.
- Me? What did I do?
- Ugly woman.
- Yes. Now let's get your seat belt on.
Forgive me. I'll explain later.
See? I'm buckling my seat belt.
- We're all buckling our seat belts.
- You can do it. Go on.
That's it.
Good girl. Here's an egg.
- Amy, we do not throw things.
- Is that animal dangerous?
Humans are dangerous,
gorillas are very gentle.
You think she may be dangerous?
Maybe so.
- Don't perpetuate a myth.
- What myth?
The King Kong myth,
the myth of the killer ape.
- Are you sure some gorillas don't kill?
- Please. You can't be serious.
What's your area of expertise,
folk singing?
- Communications technology.
- So you're a geek with a cellphone.
I'm a scientist. But you
and your protégé belong in the circus.
Just because you came up with
a wad of cash at a crucial moment...
It's OK, Amy.
- Where ground? Where ground?
- It's fine. We're flying.
- We're going to the jungle.
- Amy want green drop drink.
- No.
All right, all right.
You'd swear they were married.
The notion of the "killer ape"
may be politically incorrect,
but that's not to say it's untrue.
- I can't believe what I'm hearing.
- Clichés usually contain some truth.
- Are you serving that ape a martini?
- She's allowed one. It'll calm her down.
In my life I have heard
many a bizarre story.
Many a bizarre story
containing bizarre truth.
(AMY BURPS)
- I'm sorry I called you ugly. If I didn't...
- I know, it was for Amy's benefit.
- Can I ask you something?
- Sure.
Why teach an ape to talk?
Why teach anything to anyone? It
doesn't make you rich or get you girls.
Why did Prometheus steal fire
only to give it away?
There's an inherent generosity
in the human spirit.
One of its faces
is the face of the teacher.
I repeat, why teach an ape to talk?
- No practical reason.
- Then why did you do it?
"A lonely impulse of delight."
- William Butler Yeats.
- Very good.
- Did it work?
- What do you mean?
You're not lonely anymore?
Why are you going to Africa?
To find something I lost.
- There you go. Watch your step.
- Dr. Ross!
- Hello.
Eddie Ventro. Mr. Travis asked me to
meet the plane, set up your expedition.
- Hers? She's just along for the ride.
- Whatever. Be an asshole.
- Who is this guy?
- Ventro, transportation and equipment.
But I don't supply assholes with new
personalities. Let's see your new plane.
Let's go. Hold on.
- You want to sell that gorilla?
- No, I don't.
- It's worth a lot of money.
- How much?
- I can't believe you could ask that.
- I'm just curious.
20-25 grand for a female.
- Amy want to go home. Go home.
- I'm taking you home, Amy.
Whoa, a talking gorilla!
I feel the money hairs
on the back of my neck going "woo!"
Mr. Travis told me
to load you up. The works.
- You know how to use all this stuff?
- I'll get by.
- Do you really need a balloon?
- No, I don't. Let me see that.
- Who are they?
- Hi, fellas!
Fuck if I know.
It don't pay to ask.
We're on our third government
in two years.
- So you're our guide?
- No way. I stay at the airport.
You've got Monroe Kelly.
- Is he good?
- Very good, and very late.
- Holy shit, now what?
- What was that?
I haven't a clue, but why do I feel like
this airport's just gone to shit?
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
All right, give me your passports.
Excuse me, but we've already got
a guide, Robertson Reynolds.
Yeah, I fired him.
Robertson Reynolds is a bird-watcher.
- I hired Robertson Reynolds.
- You would.
Do you know what's going on
in the Congo as of this morning?
The Kigani have had it with Zaire
and they're eating people.
You go in with Reynolds, you come
out somebody's bowel movements.
There you go.
Wasn't that easier than customs?
Monroe...
- Guess what?
- What?
- We need to switch airports.
- Oh, shit. Why?
- Bomb in the president's car.
- It was his car? Did they get him?
That's the bad news. No, they didn't.
- I hope you folks have lots of money.
- We do.
Jemama!
Thank you. Now run away.
Come on, man. Run away.
- Get in the back.
- What about our equipment?
Leave it to Eddie.
I would hurry, I really would.
- Is this normal?
- Get in.
- You're on your own, right?
- Yeah.
Better go than stay.
- Where do you want me to set you up?
- Get a DC-3. The strip near Kegoma.
First the Kigani in Zaire,
now this godfather stuff.
Not a good day to be in Central Africa.
- Lower the flaps.
- Good luck!
Now sit down.
Hey, hey, hey!
- Mnakwenda wapi?
- Mjini.
- Mmepitia uhamiaji na kuruhusiwa?
- Ndiyo, bwana!
(CONVERSATION CONTINUES
IN NATIVE TONGUE)
I'm getting out of here.
- What's going on?
- Are we safe?
It's all right, just a few bumps.
Amy, leave that man alone.
Amy, don't inhale.
- Karen Ross?
- That's me.
Monroe Kelly. I'm your
great white hunter for this trip.
- Though I happen to be black.
- How bad is this news for us?
Whenever the leadership in
these countries comes into question,
they tend to murder everyone.
- Oh, my God!
- Not really?
They live for the opportunity
to settle scores.
And they've got a lot of scores to settle.
It's like in the Congo.
- Things are pretty bad in the Congo.
- We heard.
The Kigani are pissed off.
Can't blame them. The 20th century
sucks. Maybe the 21st will be better.
- Are you some kind of criminal?
- Aren't we all?
I'm not a criminal, I'm a scientist.
Scientist? I run a few guns,
you sons of bitches ruin the world.
We shouldn't be involved
with these people.
Well, what would you suggest we do?
As soon as we can,
we should go our own way.
Don't I know you?
Perhaps. I travel a great deal.
What are you doing with that gorilla?
Taking her home. She was caught
in the Virunga region of the Congo.
Taking her back to the farm
now that she's seen Paris?
- And this is your cover?
- Yes.
Pretty good. Or, it would have been.
I'm nobody's cover.
Cover for what?
You find yourself
in the middle of something.
- Cover for what?
- I don't know, and she won't tell you.
But the money her company
is throwing around isn't for a gorilla.
Relax. You're in better hands
then you should be.
Jimama, jimama, jimama.
- Imo kwindo wapi.
- Tunes farin duffy.
(DISCUSSION IN NATIVE TONGUE)
No one can go to Zaire.
The border is shut. There is a revolt.
- It's not my fault. Where's my gorilla?
- She will stay on the truck...
- Isn't this a hospital?
- This one's decided to speak.
- This is pure Kafka.
- Who is Kafka? Tell me!
- Monroe.
- Captain Wanta.
How are you?
Miss Ross, such a pleasure.
Have some coffee and cake.
Have some!
You have our visas and our manifest.
This is a legitimate scientific mission.
You have no right to detain us.
Liar, liar, pants on fire.
So says my computer, Miss Ross.
You used to work for the CIA.
Now you're TraviCom.
- Travicom pays better than the CIA?
- You have a big mouth.
Everybody says that about me.
What can I do?
- Monroe, you have terrible timing.
- Tell me about it.
They blew up the president's Mercedes.
Did you know that?
This is a big plot.
Our country will be in shit for a year.
Captain, I need that truck.
You need the truck. You also
need ten good men to the border.
More.
Mr. Homolka?
- Yes?
- Stop eating my sesame cake.
Stop eating my sesame cake!
What are you doing in my country,
you bag of shit?
Captain, please.
I only wish to explore and discover.
This fellow is a big bag of shit.
Shake this rat from off your neck.
He owes money
to everybody, everywhere.
I will ask you to wait outside,
Mr. Homolka.
Yes.
I like that, Miss Ross.
You surprise him.
(SOLDIER GROANS)
Now...
Hey. So, I put this away.
Don't want nobody peeking.
It's the gorilla that will get you
across the border safely.
Everyone's afraid of being seen in an
American movie being cruel to gorillas.
This is the crazy world we live in.
OK, you can go.
Hit the road, as they say.
And have a nice day.
(IN NATIVE TONGUE)
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Admit it, you're glad to see me.
(DIALOGUE IN NATIVE TONGUE)
- Kahega!
- Monroe.
Kikuyu tribesman, very nice guy.
- Are we in Zaire?
- Tanzania.
(KAHEGA AND MONROE
TALK IN NATIVE TONGUE)
So, what's the story?
Stay close to me.
Amy, come on.
- I think this is at my expense.
- You're right.
- When will we get to the rainforest?
- Herkermer Homolka, right?
Yes. Hi, hello.
You're not looking for
Solomon's city again?
What are you talking about?
Mr. Homolka was part of a
disastrous expedition five years ago.
Please don't...
They were looking for a city
called Zinj, but it doesn't exist.
- It does exist!
- Three members died from exposure.
A fourth was
shot by we don't know who.
- It was an appalling suicide.
- We won't quibble.
Mr. Homolka had to be
carried out of the jungle by me.
I knew he wasn't
a Romanian philanthropist.
He is a Romanian and has done
a lot of good, mostly for himself.
- Shut up, you filthy...
- Filthy what?
Forgive me. All that traveling
has left me... shaken.
Think nothing of it.
All aboard!
- What's all this stuff?
- Courtesy of Eddie Ventro.
Eddie, what happened to your head?
A customs guy hit me with
a can of peanut oil for stamping visas.
I'm never going back to that country.
Those people have wigged out.
- Dr. Ross.
- Hi.
The equipment list.
You got everything,
but the balloon
and the home entertainment center.
- Your boss says "Call me".
- OK.
You have 11 good guys, significant
firepower and significant technology.
- I don't think you need more. Agree?
- I agree.
- Good luck.
- Bye, Eddie.
Bye, Monroe.
(DIALOGUE IN NATIVE TONGUE)
- May I?
- There's one thing I don't understand.
- What's that, Dr. Elliot?
- If the border's shut, how do we cross?
Luck.
(THE CREW SING A SONG)
What's going on?
What the hell was that?
Shit. I thought we'd get farther.
I'd put her out now, Doctor.
- Would you! Who's firing on us?
- Kahega!
We're violating Zaire's airspace.
- She likes bananas?
- Sure.
- Eat this, darling. She'll feel great.
- What do you mean?
Something to keep her calm.
Gorilla Prozac.
(EXPLOSION)
- Can we make it to Bondo?
- I don't know.
The last one was a heat-seeker.
We're done.
- What are you doing?
- Step aside, please.
Hey.
Miss Ross. Here.
- Why are they putting on parachutes?
- Figure it out.
- Here.
- Oh, no!
- This isn't gonna work.
- Yes, it is. I'll take Amy.
- She might get hurt. I can't risk it.
- You know how to fly this plane?
The pilot and co-pilot
are already gone,
so what are you going to do?
Go, go, go!
Push me, please.
Harder, please.
Aaahh!
You want me to push you, too?
See you down there.
- Where's Amy?
- She's asleep. She's over there.
She woke up on the way down.
- That lady has some set of teeth.
- Sorry, but we have to call this off.
- Pardon?
- I'm in over my head.
- I'm not James Bond.
- I'll take care of you.
I don't want you to take care of me.
Fine. I'm taking a safari
into the Virunga region of the Congo.
If you don't want to go, go wherever.
But this is a dangerous place,
and people die here very easily.
Now, excuse me.
Amy, Amy?
Amy?
Such an extraordinary animal.
Those paintings.
Do you think she was drawing
something from real life or a dream?
- I think she was drawing home.
- What about those oval shapes?
- Just a shape she likes.
- Perhaps.
- Video game?
- It gives latitude and longitude.
- More than that, from the look of it.
- Well, it's a gadget. It has features.
You're picking up a signal.
Was it some one or some thing?
A little bit of both.
- Why did you quit the CIA?
- I never worked for the CIA.
Of course you didn't.
But if you had, why would you quit?
Because they're a loveless bunch
of sons of bitches.
- And you're not?
- And I'm not.
Glad to hear it.
OK, here we go.
- Fabulous equipment.
- The best of the best.
- I have air-conditioning, too.
- Air-conditioners?
- I suppose it is a bit much.
- Shit, I'll take one.
Stop it.
Mr. Homolka...
- Please, call me Herkermer.
- All right. You can call me Mr. Kelly.
- I wonder what she's about.
- What do you mean?
She's after something.
What you're after, I've got figured.
What she's after, I don't know.
I'll get you!
I'm helping that young scientist
return his ward to the wild.
He says the ape may be able to tell us
the thoughts of the wild gorillas.
Well, I can tell you
your thoughts, Herkermer.
You're looking for King Solomon's
diamonds. The lost city of Zinj.
- I've given it up.
- You'll never give it up.
The problem is, it doesn't exist.
Solomon must have got his diamonds
from Cartier, like everybody else.
You like that, don't you?
Time for Madam Amy's vitamins.
This is Karen Ross. 81452.
That is KR 81452.
Travis, do you read? Karen Ross,
81452. Houston, Travis, do you read?
I read and see you, Dr. Ross.
Congratulations on crossing the border.
I'm picking up a signal
from the laser's power pack.
Excellent. Wherever the laser is,
Charles should be.
Let's hope so.
Tomorrow we enter the rainforest
at the base of the volcanic range.
Good. Karen, I've had those
images of the creature analyzed.
- What is it?
- My primatologist says it's new.
He doesn't know what it is,
but it's gorilla-like.
Are you sufficiently armed?
Do you have enough manpower?
- Yes.
- Good.
The bad news is geo-thermal.
You've got to hurry.
That region in the Virungas is bad.
The volcanic activity breaks out of
the graph. The region's going to blow.
It could be a week,
or sooner, and Dr. Ross...
- What the hell?
- Watch out!
No, dammit! Not again!
I'm terribly sorry.
It's destroyed.
It's completely destroyed.
(AMY IS SNORING)
(MONKEYS ARE CHATTERING)
- What is that?
Full moon. Colobus monkeys.
- That's monkeys?
- Mating season.
When there's a moon like that, every
monkey for 200 miles thinks he's Elvis.
Ack!
It's Amy's medical supplies.
They can't get wet.
- Are you OK?
- No, I'm not OK!
Don't let go of the tent!
(INAUDIBLE VOICES
OUTSIDE TENT)
- Oh, shit! Somebody help me.
- What is it?
There's something on my...
There's a creature on my... Look.
- That's a leech.
- Take it off.
It's your leech, you take it off.
- Need some help?
- No.
Here, burn it off with this.
This is disgusting.
Thank you for your compassion.
Here.
- Monroe.
- Don't indicate you see them.
Mizumu. The ghost tribe.
There are probably 20 of them.
- I only see two.
- Yes, that's how they are.
- Are they friendly?
- They're sensitive. Forest people.
- Hamjambo?
- Hatujambo.
- Nani mkuu wenu?
- Ni mimi hapa.
- Why are they laughing?
- I told them I was in charge.
- What's so funny about that?
- I'm black. I should carry luggage.
Mzungu amekuja
msituni mwetu.
Amekufa. Ameumia sana.
Alama iko hivi...
He says there's a dead white man
in the forest
with a symbol on his clothes.
He's dead. Did they say he's dead?
- What does "TC" mean?
- TraviCom. The company I work for.
They have many levels of "dead". You
aren't dead till you're completely dead.
(MIZUMU TRIBESMEN CHANT)
They haven't moved him.
They believe his soul has left his body.
If they move him, his soul will be lost,
never finding his body.
They're calling to his soul
to come back.
Where is the man?
- Waka jhuimtu.
- Nini. Humpalikani.
It's not him, it's Bob Driscoll.
Jesus, what happened to him?
Bob? Bob?
- Who is this man?
- My company sent an expedition here.
This man was with them.
- Lay him over there.
- What happened to him?
I don't know.
Bob?
Aaahh!
Easy.
- He's dead.
- God, no!
- That region is uninhabited.
- Well, something inhabits it.
- What did you see?
- The camp destroyed. People dead.
- A grey gorilla or something.
- It doesn't exist.
- I saw one.
- Hard to believe.
Two men are missing. Jeffrey Weems
and Charles Travis, my fiancé.
- My former fiancé.
- Your former?
Beautiful boats.
Money's a wonderful thing.
- Give her the banana with the dope?
- Yes, he gave it to her.
I know. Shitty Peter, I know.
Hey, what's this?
All the leaves are brown
and the sky is grey
I went for a walk
on a winter's day