[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[SNARLING]
MAN: Hyperion!
[PANTING, GASPING]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
MAN: When this world
was still young...
long before man or beast
roamed these lands...
there was a war in the heavens.
Immortals, once thought
incapable of death...
discovered they had the power
to kill one another.
Lost in this war was a weapon
of unimaginable power:
The Epirus Bow.
The victors declared themselves gods
while the vanquished
were renamed Titans,
and forever imprisoned
within the bowels of Mount Tartarus.
Eons passed. Mankind flourished.
And the great war
receded from memory.
But the evil that once was...
has re-emerged.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
[SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[MULTIPLE FOOTSTEPS
RAPIDLY APPROACHING]
Stop. You cannot enter here.
This is sacred ground.
Sacred for who?
What do you want with us?
Where is the virgin oracle?
Defile this house further
and you will risk the wrath of the gods.
The gods?
[SPITS] Gods.
Gods.
Go ahead, call upon them.
Pray. Ask for their help.
Pray to the same gods
who idly stood by...
as my wife and my children
were stricken by disease.
I, too, cried to the heavens for help.
But instead of mercy,
I was met with silence.
And the wretched sight of my family...
suffering like animals
until their deaths.
Your gods will no longer mock me.
[CUP CLATTERS]
I will release the Titans.
It's not too late to end this madness.
Salvation can be yours, if you wish it.
Let me enlighten you, priest.
[SCREAMING]
I will end the reign of gods.
You wield that ax well, Theseus.
Maybe someday we'll see you use
the same determination to find a wife.
Are you conspiring with my mother now?
She worries about you.
There's no need to worry about me.
You know, being a warrior...
is not just being able to strike
your opponent down with a sword.
It's finding good reason
to draw your sword in the first place.
I draw my sword
to protect those that I love.
What about the others?
- The others turn their backs on me.
- The weak?
The defenseless?
Who's going to protect them?
[SCOFFS]
Careful. Too much worrying
will make you an old man.
- Whore.
- Oh!
MAN: Last lights for the labyrinth.
Last lights for the holy labyrinth.
Let the ancestors rest in peace.
[COOING]
[WHISPERS] Theseus...
MAN: May the gods be with you.
Thank you for the offerings.
Another accident?
Theseus. Maybe one day
you'll join me in prayer.
Ask the gods to grant me grandchildren
before I'm too old.
Mother, your gods are children's
stories. My spear is not.
And you know, Mother, it takes more
than lighting candles to make babies.
[MOTHER CHUCKLES]
THESEUS: Besides, our priest
wears a ridiculous hat.
MOTHER: Theseus.
[SEAGULLS CRYING]
[GONG CONTINUES]
Mother, stay here.
Theseus.
MAN: Fellow Hellenics!
It is with great concern
that I stand before you.
The Heraklion king, Hyperion,
has seized the Sibylline Monastery.
[CROWD SHOUTING]
He is only a day's march from here.
We must evacuate
this village immediately.
We must fight him
at the gates of our village!
Silence, please! Quiet!
MAN: Villagers, we stand no chance!
- I said fall in, Lysander!
- We stand no chance!
He is weary from battle!
Please. We ask that every man, woman
and child gather your belongings.
Leave for Mount Tartarus.
Seek refuge behind the safety
of the great wall!
There you will be protected.
Anyone who needs more time,
the old, the infirm,
we will escort in a day's time.
- Only what you can carry.
- MAN: Prepare your departure.
Leave it. It's not essential.
Give me that.
- Leave that.
- [ANIMAL SOUNDS]
MAN 2: Move along now.
You're with the wrong party.
Is this not the caravan
traveling to Tartarus?
It is, but you will not
be traveling among us.
Go in the morning with your own kind.
My kind?
Peasants and undesirables
travel tomorrow.
My kind's blood
is the same color as yours.
- Should we spill some to prove it?
- Theseus.
Mother.
What happens here?
This bastard and his whore mother...
[GRUNTING]
Stop! Fall back!
Fall back!
- Put the sword down.
- I will not!
- Kill him!
- Try! He dies first.
What is it that you want, brother?
It seems as though my kind
travel in the morning.
I want them to have a proper escort.
[BOTH SHOUT]
Move again, and I will bury this
in your skull.
- What's your name?
- Theseus.
Now is not the time
for violence, Theseus. Let him go.
Only if I have your word the rest
of the village will be protected.
You have my word. I will leave
capable men for the caravan tomorrow.
- Kill this traitor!
- Enough with your spectacle!
Restrain him! Get him out of my sight!
MAN: He's a bastard!
MAN 2: Take him away and disarm him.
Mother...
Save your bloodlust
for Heraklion veins, Theseus.
Join our ranks.
You have been trained well.
I had a good teacher.
I could use men of your skill at our
side to defeat Hyperion's legions.
Why would I serve you?
You who would so easily abandon us.
Let's go, Mother.
Lysander. You're no longer
part of this army.
Relinquish your shield, your spear...
and remain here to travel
with the peasants tomorrow.
- But you saw him...
- It's done.
I'll see you later.
Where are your things, old man?
Are you not prepared for the march?
Such odysseys were meant
for the young and expectant,
not for a worn-out old goat like me.
Please reconsider.
You know staying here is suicide.
If the Heraklions show up,
at least I'll be spared a slow death.
From what I understand,
indecision is not their style.
You are mad.
[CHUCKLES] No.
Just tired.
It's not living as such
that's important, Theseus.
It's living rightly.
They fight with a ferocity
unlike anything I've seen.
It was as if they could
see in the darkness.
As though it suited them.
You speak as if they're not human.
They are human.
The Heraklions bleed just as we do.
The only difference is
they fight for a belief
which allows them to kill
without restraint.
That is why they will win.
Lysander. I thought Helios
ordered you disarmed.
He did.
[GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
[GRUNTING, PANTING]
[SHOUTS]
[WOLVES HOWLING]
Reveal yourself.
[RUMBLING]
- Father.
- Athena.
- Zeus.
- No need for formalities.
None of the other gods
are looking, are they?
[CHUCKLES]
What?
When you walked up here just now,
you actually looked like a father.
Or maybe a grandfather.
[VOICES OUTSIDE]
We must tread carefully here.
Heed the law.
None of the mortals on Earth
should witness us in our immortal form.
But, Father, you've come
dangerously close.
You've been influencing
the boy Theseus for years.
Yet as one of them. Never as a god.
Only as his friend.
And why him?
He does not fear danger.
Nor pain, defeat, or ridicule.
He fears only the failure to defend
that which he holds so dear.
His loved ones.
If there is one human who could
lead them against Hyperion...
it would be Theseus.
But it must be his choice.
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
He's a defector.
He wants to meet the king.
- [SIZZLING]
- [MUFFLED SCREAMS]
[GRUNTS]
[CLANKING SOUNDS]
[MUFFLED SCREAMS]
Move.
[MUFFLED SCREAMS CONTINUE]
[PANTING]
You are a defector, I understand.
- Yes, my king.
- I am not your king.
But I wish you to be.
But you are a traitor by definition,
are you not?
What would I want
with a traitor in my midst?
I can tell you of a village
that lies unprotected...
where you can gather young women.
I have plenty of women.
- Slaves and weaponry.
- I have plenty of weapons.
What I want is the Epirus Bow.
Like this monastery, I have moved every
precious stone your people worship upon.
And I have yet to find it.
[MAN MOANS]
[PANTING]
Have you ever met
a Sibylline monk, traitor?
Monks of his order are unwavering
in their obedience to the virgin oracle.
With the right prodding, the oracle
could see where the Bow rests.
Couldn't she, monk?
Tell me where she is.
I know of your faith, monk
Sybellines are forbidden to take a life
under any circumstance...
even their own.
You have no choice
but to tell me what I want to know.
[GASPS]
[GROANING]
A monk can be made to talk
with or without his tongue.
Give him to the beast. Make him tell you
where the oracle is being kept.
Do you have any children?
Not yet.
A man's seed can be
his most brutal weapon.
For generations, your people will
stare into the eyes of their sons
and they will see my likeness.
I will be remembered
in every glance, every smile,
every tear that is shed for eternity.
But before your baptism,
understand that you are not
drawn here to my flame on instinct.
[WHIMPERS]
But you ran here
because you are a coward.
And the world does not need
any more cowards.
So, I shall do this world a great favor.
Mark you as one of us...
[SCREAMS]
and rid you of your ability
to populate the Earth.
- Traitor.
- [WHIMPERS]
Although you will not hear them...
your forefathers weep
from their graves...
for the future of their bloodline...
ends with you here tonight.
- [CRUNCHING SOUNDS]
- [LYSANDER SCREAMS]
Theseus: Old Man?
Old Man.
Hello?
[BIRD SCREECHES]
[FAINT THUDDING SOUNDS]
Your anger rules you, Theseus.
You must learn to master your emotions.
[THESEUS GRUNTING]
Rhythm, Theseus. Rhythm.
[BIRD SCREECHING]
[FIGHTING SOUNDS]
[WOMEN SCREAMING]
MAN: You! Burn that down!
Get over here!
" No! " Huh?
Theseus!
[SHOUTS]
[GRUNTING]
[SHOUTS FIERCLY]
[GASPS]
[SHOUTING CONTINUES]
- HYPERION: Wait.
- [WHIMPERING]
- [THESEUS CONTINUES GRUNTING]
- [GASPS]
Witness hell.
No!
Not him.
Give him to the jailer.
He can work in the salt mines.
His pain has just begun.
[WOMEN CONTINUE SCREAMING]
WOMAN: Hyperion's legions
show no mercy.
They have destroyed every holy shrine
in their quest for the Epirus Bow.
It is only a matter of time
before they find it.
I've noticed their king
takes the greatest care
with all women who carry a child.
And personally sees
to their slaughter.
He ventures to eradicate
a Hellenic future.
They honor no rules of engagement.
Effective. At least thus far.
Effective?
- Cowardly.
- That may be...
but the Hellenics have yet to adapt,
and until they do...
Isn't it time to intervene, Zeus?
How can you stomach bearing witness
to such atrocity whilst doing nothing?
I obey the law. No god shall interfere
in the affairs of man
unless the Titans are released.
If we are to expect mankind
to have faith in us,
then we must have faith in them.
We must allow them
to use their own free will.
And what if they unearth the Bow?
If any of you come to the aid of man
or otherwise influence
the affairs of mankind as a god...
the punishment will be death.
Who are they?
The virgin oracles. The Heraklions
must have found their temple.
- You don't know of them?
- MAN: I don't.
I wouldn't mind knowing them all
for a night.
[GASPS]
[PANTING] When cloudless
skies thunder, stand fast.
[WATER SLOSHES]
You were a thief?
I am a thief, my lady.
Were it not for these chains,
I'd steal your heart.
Tonight we must flee this place.
Whichever are strong enough to fight.
And that man there.
He didn't even go for the water.
He won't make it till morning.
Just be ready.
Stay apart.
Inside.
Stay alive.
[WHISPERS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Only one of them is the true oracle.
A seer. She is pure.
The others are there
to protect her identity.
The virgin oracle is blessed
with visions of the future.
Were she to be violated,
her gift of prophecy would be corrupted.
What a waste.
- [SLICING SOUNDS]
- [MUFFLED GRUNTING]
- Guards!
- Keys!
[FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[WAVES CRASHING]
You should get some sleep.
Do you know, I am stronger than I look?
I'll be fine.
Perhaps...
Perhaps you have
trouble sleeping because...
you're haunted by your visions.
A warrior who reads minds.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Some people do consider
my visions to be a gift.
Gift? How can it be considered a gift
when you can see the future but you
don't have the power to change it?
Sorry.
Why would you do such a thing?
You risked your life
to save a complete stranger.
Only a faithless man
would ask such a question.
My mother was a woman of faith
and her gods were absent
when she needed them the most.
As was I.
So we both mourn.
You for what has passed and...
and I for what is to come.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
HYPERION: What happened to them?
I gave an order
for them not to be touched.
MAN: They tried to flee, my king.
Seven of our best men
were killed in the struggle.
Seven of your best men killed by women?
I wish to know where
the Epirus Bow rests.
Which of you can tell me this?
Which of you are the true oracle?
If I'm forced to sort you out
by other means
you will experience discomfort.
Discomfort unique to your gender.
So you tell me, which one of you is her?
I am the one you seek.
No, it is I.
The other one said the same thing.
They all claim to be the oracle.
The other one?
Yes, my king.
The other one? What other one?
There were four of them.
One of them escaped.
With a group of slaves
from the watering hole.
[SCREECHES]
- HYPERION: Mondragon.
- Sire.
Find the one that escaped.
Bring her to me alive.
MAN: The dark seas.
These waters are thick with oil.
- THESEUS: And the boat?
- It's a Heraklion merchant ship.
Our best bet is to ambush it
and head south.
- South is not our journey.
- It is for me.
From what I hear...
the women down there can get
to the meat of a Malaccan chestnut
with only their tongues.
Shall you and I test the limits
of that desire, my dear?
The gods have given me vision. Yet all
you do is dream of your appetites.
I'd rather follow my appetites
than the hallucinations of a harlot.
- She's a high priestess.
- It doesn't matter to me.
High priestess or whore,
I'm heading south.
[GRUNTING]
Was it something I said?
Well, friend, what will it be?
South with me, or will you follow...
the lady?
Neither.
I'm taking that ship north,
to Hyperion's camp at the monastery.
Your savior sounds a lot
like a madman to me, Your Highness.
Personally, I'd rather fight
with a madman than against one
Are you minding this?
That is the mortal
your father so extols, is it not?
And he is with the oracle.
Poseidon, if Zeus were to suspect you,
we will come to your defense.
[GRUNTING]
The rear!
[SHOUTING]
I thought you said
this was a merchant ship!
I guess I was wrong.
The sea has forever been
an unpredictable domain.
[SHOUTING]
When the cloudless skies thunder...
stand fast.
- We gotta jump now!
- Stand fast!
[SCREAMS]
[SHOUTS]
You knew that wave would save us.
What I see is only a glimmer
of what may come to pass.
Your actions and desires
shape what lies ahead.
What else have you seen?
A body wrapped in a shroud on a rock.
You holding the Epirus Bow...
and...
embracing Hyperion. Impossible.
I would never embrace Hyperion.
He killed my mother.
Your mother.
Was she given a proper burial?
No.
She still lies
where Hyperion cut her down.
Then you must bury your mother.
Her faith demands it.
I do not believe in the gods.
But she believed.
She believed, Theseus.
You must return to your village.
[DISTANT SHOUTING]
[DOG SNARLS]
Have you found the oracle?
We did, my Lord, but our men were lost
before we could recover her.
A storm swept them to sea.
And the oracle.
Did she survive?
She travels towards Kolpos
with the slaves.
She could be leading them to the Bow.
Mm.
Send the Beast to Kolpos.
We will go to Tartarus.
- Mondragon?
- Sire.
HYPERION: You stay here...
and set an ambush in the pit.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
[WAVES CRASHING]
[BIRDS CALLING]
[WIND HOWLING]
[STONES GRINDING]
I'm sorry I couldn't
protect you, Mother.
But I promise you our family name
will not die with me.
- [GRUNTS]
- [STONES CONTINUE GRINDING]
[INDISTINCT WHISPERS]
[RUSTLING]
[GASPS]
[ROARING]
[SNARLS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[CRIES OUT]
[SNARLS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[GROANS]
[SHOUTS]
[PANTING]
[GRUNTING]
[LOW GROWLING]
MAN: Hyperion's legions
are gathering at Tartarus.
That's where Hellenes will fall.
That future is not set.
But likely. It will be a slaughter.
- You have no faith.
- Heathens.
That is true, Dareios, but not always.
When I was just a boy,
I prayed to the gods... for a horse.
The gods never answered me,
so I stole one instead.
[DAREIOS PANTING]
We're surrounded by heathens.
[SWORDS UNSHEATHING]
[PANTING]
[SHOUTING]
[BIRD SCREECHING]
[GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
It's all right. It's all right, Theseus.
What happened to me?
Your arm. You were poisoned.
Where are the others?
They're putting Dareios' body to rest.
She was right.
For all those years, I doubted her.
Doubted their existence.
Your mother's death
was not in vain, Theseus.
It was fate that brought you back.
For the Bow.
And in your hands, Theseus...
it will bring Hellenes victory.
You were right, Theseus.
My visions are a curse.
I want to see the world
through my own eyes.
And feel with my own heart.
And touch with my own flesh.
Hey, monk, I did a little shopping
last night. Good weapon, huh?
Good to you see you're still alive.
I was worried that cow
had gotten the best of you.
It almost did. She saved my life.
Looks like she did more than that.
Careful.
Just because you have that bow doesn't
mean I'm going to treat you differently.
Good. We march to the monastery.
We have a war to fight.
LYSANDER: The faithful believe the Titans
are still buried deep within the mountain.
The Great Wall is the Hellenics'
only hope against your army.
Defenses?
Originally it was a dam,
but the Hellenics have since adapted it.
No one could have anticipated the enemy
you have become.
How many are there?
How many have made it here,
Your Majesty, I'm not sure.
How many?
I'm not sure, Your Majesty.
- Eight hundred.
- And the gate?
Twenty feet of marble stone,
weighing over 12 tons.
It was designed to be impenetrable,
Your Majesty.
Have you ever known of a gate
designed to be anything but?
Go be of service somewhere else.
[EERIE HOWLING SOUNDS]
Where is he? I thought Hyperion
was supposed to be camped here.
We should continue. Tartarus is another
two days along this ridge.
What is that sound?
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
[MAN SHOUTING]
Stay down, monk! Stavros, help me!
Help me keep him down!
No! No!
My sisters! My sisters!
STAVROS: They're in the bull!
No!
[SOBBING]
- I am the true oracle.
- It's me, Phaedra!
I am the oracle.
Theseus.
They're still here.
[SHOUTS ANGRILY]
Wait, monk!
It's a trap!
[SCREAMING]
[PANTING]
- Monk!
- [SNARLING]
[ALL GRUNTING]
[SNARLING]
[GRUNTS]
Theseus.
[SHOUTS]
[GRUNTING]
[HORSES WHINNY]
Do not stop until you reach Tartarus.
The horses will run
until their hearts give out.
Hyperion will soon have the Bow. Leave.
[PANTING]
[FOOTSTEPS RUMBLING]
Forgive me, Father. Forgive me.
I only broke the law
to protect the mortal.
[SLOW-MOTION SHOUT]
No god will ever again come to your aid.
You are on your own!
Do you understand, mortal?
I have faith in you, Theseus.
Prove me right.
Lead your people.
[SCREECHING]
Halt!
[HORSES SNORTING, PANTING]
[SNARLING]
The horse I prayed for when I was a boy.
What is wrong with him?
They're dying.
Where are the men?
MAN: They have yet to return, sire.
What does the sight
of the bird tell you?
Speak.
The gods.
They came from above.
The gods?
They appeared and laid waste
to the men, my king.
The gods.
They protected the slave
who travels with the oracle.
The gods fight on their behalf, sire.
If the men hear of this,
there will be panic.
I know. I know.
[SQUISHING]
[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
ATHENA: In peace, sons bury their fathers.
In war, fathers bury their sons.
Are we at war, Father?
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
I have important information
for the council.
Theseus.
I know this man. Let him through.
I hope you've come to join the fight.
Where's the army?
Tell me about the slave.
He's from your village, is he not?
- Answer me!
- Yes.
He was a peasant.
As was I.
Forgive me, Your Majesty.
- I meant no...
- Quiet.
And his family?
His mother was raped by some villagers.
Nobody would marry her.
He was a bastard.
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
And his name?
Theseus.
Very well. I'll meet him.
Helios tells me you have information
that could be of use to us.
Hyperion is in possession
of the Epirus Bow.
- The Epirus Bow?
- Yes, it's a weapon forged by Heracles.
Oh, please. I heard the same stories
you did as a child.
There are gods living in the clouds.
Titans buried in the rocks.
Listen, I was a disbeliever just like
you are. But the Epirus Bow exists
I understand there are many Hellenics
who put faith in the myths and the gods,
but we on the Hellenic council do not.
They are metaphors, son. Nothing more.
We are a society of laws
based on negotiation and reason.
If you try and negotiate with Hyperion,
you will be the death of us all.
If I were to accept your counsel,
Theseus from Kolpos, what would it be?
Seal the gates and prepare for war.
We have Hoplite battalions returning.
We can't seal the gate.
No one will return! We are the last!
I'm sure you'll understand
if I don't accept the advice
of an alluring palm reader
and her peasant lover.
Sir, a Heraklion envoy approaches.
There, you see? No ruler wishes for war.
They only wish to be taken seriously
at the bargaining table.
Alert the council. Prepare a delegation.
MAN: Bows!
HELIOS: Stop!
Stop! Remain still,
or we'll be forced to fire upon you.
Extend your arms outward.
He bears the olive branch of peace.
HYPERION: My king wishes to speak
to the one called Theseus from Kolpos.
Theseus.
Hyperion's envoy
desires a word with you.
Like the vision,
he sends for you with arms open.
Seeking an embrace of loyalty.
Phaedra.
Have you never been wrong?
We can't protect you beyond this gate.
I am Theseus!
Come closer. I have a message for you.
Don't risk it.
At worst, you lose a peasant.
- Better?
- Uh-huh. Yes.
Why do you cover your face?
All are equal in Hyperion's midst.
I myself am only a vessel
for his demands. Nothing more.
- And he asks me by name?
- Indeed he does.
And how does he know it?
There's little the king does not know.
He knows that you have no father.
And like him, you were cast aside
by your own people.
Does he know of my rage?
Does he know that I live only to see
his blood at the end of my sword?
Does he know he butchered my mother?
Now that he's seen your face, he knows.
You wouldn't make it.
Coward!
Embrace me, Theseus.
They will never give you a seat
at their table
but you could sit at the head of mine.
Long after this war is over, my mark
will be left on this world forever.
The sun will never set
on my blood, Theseus.
This is what I offer you. Immortality.
Deeds are eternal. Not the flesh.
The gods may be on your side,
but tomorrow...
I unleash the Titans.
What was discussed?
Seal the gate.
- What were his demands?
- Seal the gate.
HYPERION: Theseus.
Ahh...
[SHOUTS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
- That was him, wasn't it?
- I was that close.
I don't know if I can do
what Zeus asks of me.
By doubting one
comes the truth, Theseus.
The gods chose well.
Sir, there's movement on the front.
What is he holding?
The Bow.
MAN: The commanders
are all dead! Fall back!
[PANICKED SHOUTING]
Hold! Stand your ground!
Listen to me!
Listen!
- Who are you to tell us what to do?
- I am nobody to tell you what to do!
I am Theseus, a common man! One of you!
I share your blood!
And I share your fear!
But to run now would offer our souls
and the souls of our children
to a terrible darkness!
[ALL SHOUTING]
Hold! We must stand and fight!
Their numbers count for nothing
in the tunnel! Stand your ground!
Stand your ground!
Who are they that we are not?
Just because they scald their faces
and scar their bodies...
does not mean they are braver
or stronger than we are.
They are cowards!
They hide behind their masks.
They are human,
and they bleed like you and I.
Listen to me!
Stand your ground!
Fight for honor!
Fight for the man beside you!
Fight for the mothers who bore you!
Fight for your children!
Fight for your future!
Fight so your name survives!
Fight...
for immortality!
Let us write history
with Heraklion blood!
[FOOTSTEPS RUMBLING]
Ready! Move!
[SHOUTS]
[ALL GRUNTING, SHOUTING]
King Hyperion.
We can negotiate. I see no reason...
HYPERION: Theseus!
Here I am! Theseus of Kolpos!
- Where's your king?
- He is no king.
[SHOUTS]
Stavros! The shrine!
Theseus! I'm right behind you!
Phaedra!
Stay in the shrine.
Hyperion!
[SNARLING]
No!
[GRUNTS]
STAVROS [MUFFLED]:
Theseus, wake up!
Theseus!
[GROANS]
I got the Bow!
Stavros.
I got the Bow.
Get out of here while you can!
I'll hold them off!
Stavros.
Go now! I got the Bow!
I'll hold them off while I can!
- Get out of here! Go!
- [CREATURES SNARLING]
Which one of you are coming with me?
[SCREAMING]
None of you will leave this place.
[SHOUTS]
Leave here!
This is no longer your fight.
Find Hyperion.
[ALL SNARLING]
[eons GRUNTING]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTING]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[GROANING]
[PANTING]
Die with your gods.
[BOTH SHOUTING]
[SNARLING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GRUNTING]
[SHOUTING]
[ALL SHOUTING]
Athena!
[GROANING]
Father!
Don't forsake mankind.
[GRUNTING]
[SIGHS]
What does it feel like, knowing...
knowing that there'll
be no memory of you?
I have won.
My death will make me a legend.
[PANTING]
My deeds...
will go down in history.
I'm writing your history.
[ROARS]
[SCREAMS]
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
Do it!
[MEN SHOUTING]
This... is our last embrace, Hyperion.
Look at me.
I'm the last thing...
you will ever see.
Witness hell.
[STABBING SOUND]
[GURGLING]
[FADING GROAN]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[SHOUTING, RUMBLING FADES]
OLD MAN: All men's
souls are immortal.
But the souls of the righteous
are immortal and divine.
Once a faithless man,
Theseus gave his life
to save mankind
and earned a place amongst the gods.
They rewarded his
bravery with a gift.
A son. Acamas.
[ARMIES SHOUTING]
[GASPS]
Don't be afraid of your visions,
little one.
- What's your name?
- Acamas.
Acamas.
A strong name.
I knew your father.
He was a very brave man.
Soon, it will be your time
My time for what?
The fight against evil
never ends, Acamas.
War is coming to the heavens.
And your father will be there,
fighting for your future.
PHAEDRA: Acamas.
Acamas.
Who was that, son?
Just...
Just an old man.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[SNARLING]
[ARMIES SHOUTING]
[GASPS, PANTING]
English - US - PSDH