[¶¶¶]
[CHILDREN CHATTERING]
[MEN SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING]
[YELLING IN SPANISH]
[SPEAKING IN SPANISH]
[ALARM BLARING]
[MAN YELLS IN SPANISH]
[SOBBING]
[SCHUBERT'S ''PIANO TRIO NO. 2
IN E FLAT MAJOR'' PLAYING]
[REMOTE CONTROL CLICKS]
BISHOP:
What I do
requires a certain mindset.
I do assignments,
designated targets.
Some jobs
need to look like accidents.
Others must cast suspicion
on someone else.
A select few
need to send a clear message.
Pulling a trigger is easy.
The best jobs are the ones
nobody even knows you were there.
[¶¶¶]
Liquor fairy paid me
a visit last night.
Left me a big old bottle of Scotch.
He even sprung for the good stuff.
See you, Henry.
[GROANS]
Why the fuck do I let you drag me
out to this shit hole?
You're a snob, Harry.
Eleven hundred people
come through here every day.
Hard to remember
two fellows passing through.
Thank you.
Of course,
people might remember them.
Yeah.
Then that kind of defeats
your purpose.
I don't go anywhere without them.
Nowhere.
Try to get them shoes that fit.
They look like cartoons.
Everything went okay?
It got done.
[SIGHS]
There's no one better than you,
you know.
That's why they give you those jobs
that could get hairy
because if they were to get hairy,
then you would take care of it,
and that's all they care about,
services rendered, no loose ends.
Fait accompli.
You're a goddamn machine.
You see things.
You view people differently than I do,
differently than anybody does.
Yeah, but you've got a problem,
Arthur.
You need companionship.
I have you, Harry.
Oh, then you're in deeper shit
than I thought.
[CHUCKLES]
So how's Steven?
Did I tell you that I got him a job
at a private security firm?
They kicked him out last month.
He beat some guy half to death.
[SIGHS]
Goddamn disappointment.
Always has been, always will be.
Call him.
Me? Call him?
For what?
He probably needs
to hear from you.
Yeah.
Let's go. I'll get your money.
[¶¶¶]
[INTRO TO ''BETTER OFF DEAD''
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
[SINGING ''BETTER OFF DEAD'']
Come on. Dance with me.
Come on, please?
[GALACTIC'S
''DO IT AGAIN'' PLAYING]
[TV PLAYING]
You hungry?
Sure.
I gotta go.
Okay.
You ever gonna tell me your name?
Arthur.
[LAUGHS]
Nice try.
But you're no Arthur.
No, more like a David.
Or Brad. Hmm.
[¶¶¶]
Yeah.
See you, Brad.
MAN 1 : Yeah, I know.
MAN 2: Whoo!
MAN 3:
Yeah.
[¶¶¶]
WOMAN [OVER PHONE]:
Global Engineering.
BISHOP:
I'm calling about the ad.
There must be a mistake.
One moment, please.
The advertisement was proofed.
The information is accurate.
I want a meeting.
We'll get back to you.
Mr. Bishop,
Mr. Dean has agreed to a meeting.
A private jet will pick you up
in one hour
and deliver you to a site
of his choosing.
You'll be allowed 15 minutes.
The jet will then return you.
MAN:
When we tell you to be home
at 10:00, we mean 10, not 11 :30.
I don't care, baby.
You scared your mother to death.
You're grounded for two weeks.
Just one second.
Well, that's not my problem.
All right, look.
Ten days and you volunteer
two Saturdays at the shelter.
Eight days and three Saturdays.
Nice ring.
DEAN: Done.
Where do I get one of those?
You can't.
Unless you're a world champion.
DEAN:
Just tell him to come out
and fix it, honey.
All right, let's go.
I've just been out-negotiated
by a 16 year old.
Let's take a walk.
Six months ago,
we were commissioned
to undertake
the largest contract
we've ever attempted.
The target was far more high-profile
than we're normally comfortable with
but the job was just too rich
to pass up.
The target was South African?
The target fled to South Africa.
That's where we made our move,
in Cape Town.
It took six months to set up.
I assigned a team of five operatives
to work in concert on the mission.
All five were killed.
Someone knew everything.
You probably knew
some of the men on that team.
BISHOP:
I knew this one. Sebastian.
You know how this company works,
Mr. Bishop.
Only two partners know
the details of any given job.
Two people knew the details here.
Me and Harry McKenna.
Harry sold us out.
We pulled his financials.
Take a look
at recent offshore deposits.
[¶¶¶]
There's one there made two weeks
ago for 20 million U.S. dollars.
He's gotten old.
He's gotten weak.
He's loaded with debts, his divorce,
his costly, troubled son.
They made him vulnerable.
And for the past 13 years,
I have been fiercely loyal to him.
There's no one I respected more.
But Harry McKenna
has poisoned the well.
He needs to be removed.
Immediately.
Let me talk to him.
Look, I appreciate
your connection with Harry,
but there's no turning back here.
He has crossed his Rubicon.
Every day that he's alive
puts this company in danger.
I know we would all prefer
that you handle this.
Given your relationship,
you're in the best position
to get this done quickly
and discreetly.
And to be honest with you, I hate the
idea of Harry suffering unnecessarily.
We don't wanna go
to an outside source.
But we will if we have to.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
Excuse me a sec.
[¶¶¶]
Jess, negotiations are closed.
I'm sorry.
I'm in a meeting.
Okay, hang on a sec.
Forty-eight hours
or we'll proceed without you.
Hey, squirt?
Remember the expression,
''Quit while you're ahead''?
Yeah, I mean,
Roosevelt, to be truthful, is my hero.
I mean,
the way he dealt with his damn chair.
Jasper, pull your trousers up,
will you? Please?
Pull your trousers up.
You know, the suits
don't really fit you guys very well.
[¶¶¶]
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
HARRY [OVER PHONE]: Yeah?
Get out of the building, Harry.
Arthur?
They're coming for you tonight.
Who? Who's coming?
Dean.
Take whatever you can use
against them and get out.
Oh, Jesus.
Do you have a pair of scissors?
Yeah.
[¶¶¶]
Go to the elevator lobby.
On my way.
[COMPUTERS BEEPING]
Looks like we got a power outage
on the 1 8th floor.
BISHOP:
You have 15 seconds
to get to the elevator
before the emergency power
comes on.
There's a keypad.
Punch in the building number.
We cut the power off.
Service elevators have to work
on a separate power source.
I'm in.
Press the basement floor.
The elevator will take
18 seconds to get there.
The level is empty and unused.
Take the ramp.
It connects to the building next door.
It leads to an underground
parking lot.
Shit.
Security cameras haven't been
fitted in this building yet,
so they'll be blind.
[GRUNTS]
Okay, you should be entering
the parking lot now.
My van's here.
BISHOP:
I left it there.
Oh, shit.
Well, you got me to circumvent
my own security.
Nobody sees me leave.
So, what's this?
Cape Town, right?
Yeah. Right.
So, what's the story here?
Carjacking?
Police will find my van somewhere
in some shit hole section of the city,
stripped and up on blocks?
Something like that.
Well, a slight editorial revision.
You don't mind, do you?
[HARRY READS INSCRIPTION]
Yeah, I get off a couple of shots,
there's a struggle,
they get my gun, c'est la vie.
At least I don't go down
looking like a pussy.
I've had that for 33 years.
Gift from Admiral Beasley.
Sixth Fleet.
That's the first time I ever fired it.
Why didn't you kill me?
Ah.
They'd just send somebody else.
I would rather it was you, Arthur.
You'll have to live with it.
[¶¶¶]
Arthur fucking Bishop.
Sorry for your loss.
More of a loss for you than me,
buddy.
It's a long time.
[NURU KANE'S ''GOREE'' PLAYING]
[TAPPING ON WINDOW]
Hey, would you give me a ride
to my father's house?
Your father talked about you a lot.
He talked about spending time
with you, maybe making up.
Give it a rest, would you?
Yeah, well,
he was always bringing you up.
He had regrets, Steven.
Yeah, he could have picked up
the phone anytime.
I wanna show you something.
I loved this place as a kid.
It's pretty impressive, huh?
Every one of them
served their country.
I guess I could still enlist.
You know, make him proud.
I'm fucking with you.
I don't know if you have
a picture of him,
but I thought maybe you'd,
you know,
want one.
[POURS DRINK]
[BOTTLE CLINKS]
Looks like you're not planning
on sticking around.
For what?
He didn't leave a will.
Accounts are empty.
Bank's gonna take the house.
By the time the lawyers, city
and state get through with the rest,
not gonna be a fucking thing left.
Where you headed?
Next place.
Need some money?
No, thanks.
I got a guy coming to the house.
He's gonna look at the car.
I figure that'll probably
get me through
along to the next spot.
BISHOP:
What about the guns?
I was thinking about going out
and killing myself
a couple carjackers tonight.
Just any old
run-of-the-mill carjacker.
Yeah, well, you never know.
I might get lucky,
find the guys that killed my dad.
It gonna make you feel better?
[LAUGHS]
Fuck if I know.
But I'll find out.
[SNIFFS]
[¶¶¶]
Sleep it off, Steve.
STEVE:
Hey, Bishop?
What kind of person shoots someone
in a wheelchair, anyway?
[CHRIS THOMAS KING'S
''WHY BLUES'' PLAYING]
[GLASS SHATTERS]
[DOGS BARKING IN DISTANCE]
MAN:
How long am I supposed to wait?
WOMAN:
You know what?
You can wait until tomorrow.
MAN:
Look, I told you to be here.
Yo.
Hey. Hey, you need some help?
No, I think I got it.
Mm. Mm.
I'm supposed to meet a friend
and I might have gotten
the address wrong.
Yeah. Maybe.
Well, maybe the address
got me wrong.
[LAUGHS]
Nice car, man.
Nice car.
STEVE:
Thanks.
Can I have it?
What?
I'm relieving you of your automobile,
motherfucker.
Out of the car.
Seriously?
Seriously.
Jesus fucking Chri-- Okay.
Okay.
Mother--
Carjacker.
Did you shoot him
with this?
[MAN SOBBING]
MAN: Fuck.
Is this the gun you used?
No?
[MAN COUGHING]
[GRUNTING]
[MOANS]
Hey. Bad move.
Didn't properly think this through,
did you, Steven?
This may not seem like it, but
tonight's your lucky night,
Raymond.
Anybody asks, you fell down.
Don't make us
come looking for you.
Get out of here.
Stupid to kill someone
when you have a motive.
Might as well paint
a bull's-eye on your back.
I don't give a shit.
I'm aware.
Get out of here.
[STARTS ENGINE]
[¶¶¶]
[TIRES SCREECH]
I was thinking about what you
were saying the other night.
And I wanna know what you know.
Go online.
It's all on the Internet.
But I don't wanna read it.
I wanna do it.
Do what exactly?
Bishop, don't bullshit me.
I know about you.
And him.
He was your mentor.
He chose you over me.
You owe him.
Now that he's gone,
he's left me with fucking nothing.
You owe me now.
Go home, Steve.
[¶¶¶]
[ENGINE STARTS]
Still for sale.
You know you want it.
No other lifetime but this.
Want some advice?
Follow what this tells you.
It's trying to tell you something.
It's telling you you're homesick
for a place you've never been.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
BISHOP [OVER PHONE]:
8600 Alvarado Street,
7 a.m. tomorrow.
What is this place?
It's an animal shelter.
Yeah, I know what it is.
Why are we here?
Look for a dog like this.
Under a year, if possible.
I would have taken you more
for a cat person.
[DOGS BARKING]
You know what a mechanic is,
outside its obvious definition?
STEVE:
A guy who fixes things,
problems, has contracts.
A hit man.
I do assignments.
Designated targets.
I could do that.
I've seen some shit.
No, you haven't.
You know shit about me, Bishop.
Steven Jackson McKenna.
Born in Baltimore, Maryland.
Your mother died when you was 12.
A mixture of pain meds and vodka.
You attended three
different high schools.
Grant, Deer Park and Monroe.
Lettered in four sports,
got a scholarship from Miami
that was rescinded upon
a conviction of possession
with intent to distribute.
Had misdemeanors for aggravated
assault and unlawful threats
against two different girlfriends.
Broke your kneecap in a fight.
Didn't wanna tell anyone,
so you let it heal on its own.
Now, when it rains,
you walk with a limp.
I'll show you the x-rays, if you like.
Our friend here
would like to adopt this little fellow.
Hello, boy.
[BARKS]
What I do
requires a certain mindset.
Revenge is an emotion
that can get you killed.
So no more stupid stunts
like the other night.
Walk it, feed it,
make it your best friend.
Tomorrow, 11 , Fischer Square.
[CHICKASAW MUDD PUPPIES'
''CHICKENBONE'' PLAYING]
BISHOP:
Take the dog
to the coffee shop on Riverdale.
Order a coffee. Black.
Sit at a table by the window and
do the Sudoku puzzle in the paper.
Play nice with the dog.
For how long?
One hour.
Every day for the next three weeks.
[ALARM BUZZING]
[BARKS]
This is yours. This is yours.
This is yours.
Practice on this.
Insurance companies know
everything about how people die.
They even have books
with actuaries,
lists of every cause
of death imaginable.
Why don't you just shoot them
and fuck all this?
Good judgment
comes from experience
and a lot of that comes
from bad judgment.
Bed's under the boxes.
Help yourself.
How long you been working on it?
Two years.
It's nice.
When are we gonna go for a ride?
We?
Never.
Time to take your training
to the next level.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Who's that?
He's good.
Nobody checked you out.
I could come back.
I'd rather not stand out here.
I gotta tell you, man.
I'm a little skittish right now.
Not sure if this is a good time
for me to be doing anything.
There's a lot of shit in the wind,
you know?
I brought the list and the money.
Now's not a good time.
Let me see the list.
All this by when?
As soon as possible.
All right.
Take me a day to make it happen.
Let me have the money.
[GRUNTING]
[¶¶¶]
[MOANING OVER COMPUTER]
Autoerotic asphyxiation?
Yep.
[MOANING]
Just thought
you should see one up close.
[MOANING OVER COMPUTER
CONTINUES]
Don't ever touch this.
[SCHUBERT'S ''PIANO TRIO NO. 2
IN E FLAT MAJOR'' PLAYING]
Follow me.
STEVE: Who was he?
BISHOP: A job.
Nothing more, nothing less.
Makes you feel better,
he was an illegal arms dealer.
Sold weapons to anyone.
Cop killers, gangbangers, terrorists.
He didn't discriminate.
Here's the file.
[¶¶¶]
STEVE:
The guy from the coffee shop?
All yours.
BISHOP:
You wouldn't know it
by looking at him,
but he's a mechanic
for another group.
His only routine is coffee
every morning from 9 to 10.
Doesn't go any place twice
except here.
He's insulated, protected.
No way in
without him seeing us coming.
Except he has two weaknesses.
Chihuahuas--
Mind if I sit down?
Please.
BISHOP:
--and boys. Young boys.
Coffee, black.
Thank you.
BISHOP:
No doubt he's checked you out
and found no connection to you
and this world.
What he sees is a good-looking kid
who's kind of lost.
Do you wanna hold him?
Yeah.
BISHOP: He likes that.
Come here, baby.
BISHOP:
If he's interested,
the first thing he'll do is ask you.
So, you live around here, Steve?
BISHOP: Your answer should be--
I'm bouncing around.
BISHOP:
Which means you're broke
and open to suggestions.
He's my buddy.
Yeah.
BISHOP:
Then ask you if--
You wanna get a drink
one evening?
BISHOP: Your answer should be--
Yeah.
Great.
That's great, isn't it?
Flunitrazepam.
Roofie.
You want me to kill him,
not rape him, right?
Two to three drops, he's woozy.
Over six, his heart stops and he's
brain dead in under three minutes.
Do it in the bar. Make it clean.
[THUNDERBALL'S
''THUNDER IN THE JUNGLE''
PLAYING]
These fancy places,
they always water down the booze.
So I think that's why
these are going down so fast.
They don't water down wine,
that's for sure.
It's really good.
Want another one?
Yeah.
Jameson, right?
Jameson, double, please.
Right.
BISHOP:
Don't mess around with this guy.
Do it in the bar, make it clean.
STEVE:
I wanna know what you know.
I wanna do it.
[CHUCKLES]
What?
What's funny?
No, nothing's funny.
I'm just, I think I've had too many.
No, come on.
No, I think
I'm gonna finish this one--
I'm gonna finish this one
and then I'm gonna--
I really should go to bed.
But it was very-- It was fun.
[¶¶¶]
Steve.
Hey.
You all right?
Yeah.
How are you?
I'm good, man.
Hey, can I give you
a ride someplace?
Car's right here.
Come on, get in.
I wanna show you something.
Yeah?
BISHOP:
He's 6'7, 300 pounds and lethal.
Do not take this guy on.
And whatever you do,
don't ever get into his car.
[ENGINE STARTS]
What do you think?
It's beautiful.
Let me get you a drink.
You paint?
Yeah, it's more of a hobby, really.
Pretty serious hobby.
Cheers.
That's the sitting area,
the fireplace.
Chillaxing room.
Heh-heh.
This is the place I'm most proud of,
right here.
Who's this guy?
That is 1 4th century Buddha.
And that was a bitch
to get into this country.
It's nice to have friends, you know,
good friends that make a difference.
You got food friends?
I mean, really good friends.
You're shaking like a leaf.
Sit down.
[¶¶¶]
All right, all right.
Okay, let me do it.
Slow down, cowboy.
[CHUCKLES]
[GRUNTING]
[STEVE COUGHS]
I told you to make it clean.
[NORTH MISSISSIPPI ALLSTARS'
''SHAKE (YO MAMA)'' PLAYING]
See you later.
Was it work or pleasure?
I wish someone
would hurt me like that.
[AMON TOBIN'S ''VERBAL''
PLAYING]
[MOANING]
[CHRIS THOMAS KING'S
''MISSISSI PPI KKKROSSROADS''
PLAYING]
Hey.
Thanks.
I'm gonna call him Arthur.
[DOG WHIMPERS]
[¶¶¶]
[LINE RINGING]
Yeah.
You used an outside individual
to complete your assignment.
That's a violation
of our arrangement.
My arrangement was with Harry.
You and I don't have one.
Just the price.
Or think someone trained by me
would be valuable to you.
Harry McKenna's son?
Does he know you killed his father?
This job needs to be done
immediately.
The client's willing to pay
a premium for it.
I don't think so. It's too quick.
Your behavior is making me
and the others extremely uneasy.
You're on a short leash
with this one.
The file is a priority.
I'll look it over.
[DOOR OPENS]
I am one with God.
God touches me
and I touch his people.
Andrew Vaughn, 45 years old,
calls himself The New Messiah.
REPORTER:
So, Reverend Vaughn--
Just Vaughn.
I'm not a reverend. I'm not endorsed
by any of the world religions.
I am above them. I am Vaughn.
He has made millions of dollars
through his churches
his ministries,
his television programs.
Basically, he is running a cult.
Adrenalin shot to the heart,
12 cc's, and he's dead
in under three minutes.
Adrenalin's unreliable.
One in four survive cardiac arrest.
But when the EMTs arrive,
the first thing they do is jam you
with a shot of epinephrine.
Which is toxic when combined with--
Adrenaline.
So in the off chance
our shot doesn't kill him--
STEVE:
He left a Bible study group
with a young devotee one night.
They didn't find her body
until two weeks later.
[ELEVATOR BELL DINGS]
The autopsy said she had
an abortion and was telling her
friends it was his.
Cost him $22 million to hush it up.
Okay, let's get this over with.
Bless you. Next.
Why don't you come sit right here?
You're new here.
How long you been here?
Two weeks.
How old are you?
Eighteen.
[¶¶¶]
[DEVICE BEEPS]
You could have found us
someone more attractive to spy on.
He's still eating.
Soup, salad, sandwich.
Double chocolate cake.
Bishop, I'm hungry.
The guy at the deli,
he had Band-Aids
on all of his fingers.
If you find a Band-Aid
in your sandwich, it wasn't mine.
BISHOP:
We're all clear.
How do you feel, Vaughn?
How do you think I feel?
Where's Frank?
I sent for him.
He should be here any minute.
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
RALPH:
Speak of the devil.
[VAUGHN SIGHS]
Give me something special today.
I feel like celebrating.
I have the spirits' work to do.
The spirits are gonna work
in your favor.
Hmm.
STEVE:
The guy's a junkie.
He's giving him ketamine.
So?
Ketamine counteracts adrenaline.
This won't work now.
[MOANING]
VAUGHN [OVER SPEAKER]:
I have been tapped
on the shoulder by God.
What do you wanna do?
VAUGHN:
I did not ask for this,
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
but my shoulder was touched
by the sword of the king.
And he told me to rise up.
We've gotta pack it up.
Wait, wait.
If he comes back in here--
We'll be gone soon.
Yes, hello.
Yes, yes, it is.
VAUGHN:
In the king's name.
Hey.
BISHOP: Get the scope.
Put it down his throat.
Down his throat.
This will choke him.
[CHOKING]
If they think
that I'm going to pay full price
for a four-bedroom in this market,
they're crazy.
VAUGHN:
Only I can tie others.
How can I change the world?
How can I be a better man
for my parishioners,
for my flock?
Let's go.
VAUGHN:
Sometimes I wonder.
Sometimes I wonder
if I have the strength,
the courage.
I look at myself in the mirror
and think...
And then I...
Christ.
Ralph, get in here.
RALPH: What is it?
What is it?
RALPH: Is he dead?
DOCTOR: Yes, he's dead.
Motherfucker.
I knew this was gonna happen.
Get all this shit rounded up
and get it out of here
as fast as you can.
[CREAKING]
Try and pick him up.
Fuck.
RALPH:
Go check it out.
Take it off the wall.
They're in the wall.
Follow them.
Cover the exits
and get me two guys on the roof now.
[GRUNTING]
GUARD:
There he is.
Oh!
Go that way.
[SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
[GROANS]
[BOTH GRUNT]
[ALARM BLARING]
MAN 1 :
Stay calm
and exit through the main door.
They're looking for two men. Get a
connecting flight out of Midway,
I'll fly out of O'Hare,
I'll meet you at the house.
MAN 2:
Right this way. Let's go.
MAN 3:
This way, folks.
REPORTER:
Andrew Vaughn, the controversial
and polarizing religious figure,
REPORTER:
Andrew Vaughn, the controversial
and polarizing religious figure,
has been pronounced dead.
Police are investigating the shooting
that occurred shortly thereafter.
The perpetrators
have not been found.
[¶¶¶]
WOMAN [OVER PA]:
Attention all passengers,
please keep all of your belongings
with you at all times.
Do not leave bags unattended.
DEAN:
All five were killed.
You probably knew
some of the men on that team.
MAN:
Taxi.
Terminal D?
Next bus. Down the street.
Leaves in 15 minutes.
Thanks.
When does this leave?
In 15 minutes.
Doesn't give us much time, then.
What do you want?
I wanna know
what you're doing alive.
Last time I saw you,
you had a bullet in your head.
What really happened
in Cape Town?
Where's the rest of your team?
They're dead.
Who paid you?
Was it Harry or Dean?
Dean paid me a very large amount
of money to kill the others.
Told me to fake my death.
Disappear.
You know what else he told me?
That Harry was getting suspicious
about a blown operation.
He was about to blow the whistle
and had to be taken care of.
They knew just the man for the job.
Someone who could get to him.
It's not the fact
that you killed him, is it?
It's that they played you so easily.
That's what bothers you.
Am I right?
[¶¶¶]
[GRUNTING]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[SCREAMING]
[¶¶¶]
[LINE RINGING]
Well?
Not so good for your side.
Those were my two best teams.
I guess I'll have to send more.
Save the fuel.
I'm coming for you.
[¶¶¶]
[LINE RINGING]
STEVE [OVER PHONE]:
When are you gonna be home?
I'm really hungry.
Where are you?
I'm in the living room.
Sit down on the couch.
Okay.
BISHOP:
I'm guessing you're not alone.
There's a gun
down the left side cushion.
It's loaded and the safety's off.
But I'm not a lefty.
BISHOP:
Then you're gonna die.
All right.
I'll see you when you get here.
[GUNFIRE OVER PHONE]
I'll be there in five.
STEVE: Who sent those guys?
The man who employs me.
Grab all the gear on the top shelf
and put it in the boat.
[¶¶¶]
You set?
Get in the boat.
[STARTS MOTOR]
You ever think
about the people you've killed?
No.
You ever kill someone you know?
Yes.
Did it feel any different?
Not in the moment.
After.
Do you give them some
kind of warning or time to prepare?
Kind of time to
make peace?
There's no peace.
So it's best not to let them know
when you're coming.
Yes.
I guess
it doesn't really matter anyway,
as long as they're dead
and you're not, right?
[¶¶¶]
Hello, Finch.
[FINCH SCREAMING]
Oh, my God, who are you?
What are you doing here?
Oh, God. Jesus.
[SOBBING]
I want you to listen to me closely.
I don't care who I hurt or who I kill.
Understand?
No, please. No.
No, no, no.
[MRS. FINCH AND DAUGHTER
SOBBING]
You're gonna tell me exactly
what I came here to find out.
Where's Dean?
[GARBAGE DISPOSAL WHIRRING]
It's up to you how far I go.
Fingers.
Wrist.
Elbow.
Jesus, John,
tell him what he wants to know.
FINCH:
Okay, okay.
300 Colby Plaza.
That's where he is, I swear.
[TURNS OFF GARBAGE DISPOSAL]
Looks like you're gonna miss
a good dinner.
My God, you're a bastard.
[PHONE RINGING]
Yes.
BISHOP [OVER PHONE]:
How much was Harry's life worth?
Fifty million.
And here's what I'm gonna do.
Ten million wired to the bank
of your choice within 24 hours.
It's a good deal. You should take it.
Not interested.
The killer grows a conscience.
I'd say that's a breach
of professional ethics, Mr. Bishop.
Harry's death was business,
pure and simple.
Well, it's not gonna be
so simple now.
You got that right.
Because now I'm gonna put a price
on your head that's so big,
when you look in the mirror,
your reflection's gonna
wanna shoot you in the face.
You won't survive that long.
You're a fool.
You think you can get to me
before I get to you?
I already have.
[¶¶¶]
Where's Conference Room E?
MAN [OVER SPEAKER]:
Floor upstairs, sir.
He's in the building.
Get me the fuck out of here.
[BEEPS]
Did they find Bishop?
Nothing yet.
MAN: No, no, no.
Get off the fucking bus.
Move. Get off the fucking bus.
Move.
Go!
Whoa!
Back up, come on. Let's go.
[MOANS]
[MOANING]
[¶¶¶]
[GASPS]
Fuck you.
[¶¶¶]
What's the plan now?
Disappear.
New names. New occupation.
Together?
That's up to you.
What are we gonna do?
We gonna whittle?
We gonna get bunk beds?
Move into a teepee?
Want a water?
I've always had this
anger inside,
and now I feel
like I have a place to put it.
I think I would miss this
if I had to stop now.
I could always go
into business for myself.
There are a lot of people out there
who would pay.
And I think you were wrong.
Vengeance is the mission.
[¶¶¶]
You want anything?
No.
Last chance.
I'm good.
Steven.
I'm sorry
for everything that happened.
Well, you know me, man.
I don't give a shit.
[¶¶¶]
[SCHUBERT'S ''PIANO TRIO NO. 2
IN E FLAT MAJOR'' PLAYING]
[ENGINE FALTERING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[BEEPS]
[¶¶¶]
[LAUGHS]
[SIREN WAILING]
All four cameras.
Watch number two.
Okay.
[¶¶¶]
COP 1 : Yeah. This one here.
COP 2: Yeah.
[SIREN WAILING]