[Dog Barking]
[Siren Wailing]
[Engines Idling]
[Engines Stop]
[Siren Wailing]
[Siren Stops]
Wonder what's going on?
Here comes C.B.S. News.
Must be important.
[Siren Wailing]
[Siren Stops]
Unit 2473 to helicopter.
Helicopter.
Over.
Have you
located suspect?
[Pilot]
Suspect under surveillance.
[Engine Revving]
[Car Engine Revving]
[Helicopter Passing]
[Sirens Wailing]
[Sirens Stop]
Helicopter to 2473.
Suspect stopped.
He can't get away. Over.
All right. All right.
Maintain surveillance.
[Helicopter Whirring]
[Engine Starts]
- [Bell Clanging]
- [Train Horn Blows]
Kowalski... and the keys
for a sawed-off weekend.
Well, you're both welcome.
- What do you got going for Frisco?
- You're not going back tonight.
Hey, you're gonna kill yourself someday,
you know that?
- Do ya know?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Look. W-Why don't you
stay over till Monday, huh?
So you can
go home right now.
Oh, yeah. Sure, sure.
Just before midnight.
Hey, look,
you know something?
When the clock strikes 12:00,
my car turns into a pumpkin.
[Huffs]
Hey, Sandy, you're a born actor.
Yeah. Sure, sure.
That's what my wife will say...
when I tell her I've been
waiting up for you all night.
Hey, look, look. Look, seriously, look,
why don't you stay over?
- Nah.
- Huh? Look, you can do with some sleep, can't ya?
Look, I gotta get started out tonight.
Now, which car?
Which-
[Tires Screeching]
[Man] # I can't believe it
Could it be I've gone astray #
# Whoa, Lord, won't you help me
find myself a place to pray #
## [Continues]
Hey, "K!"
[Laughing]
What's happenin'?
- What ya need?
- Speed.
White lightnin'!
Hold this.
- How you doin'?
- I'm fine. How you been?
- Lookin' good. Say when.
- Whoa, whoa.
- That's good. That's good.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hey, man. Hold it. I'll get you some water.
- Mm-mmm.
- That's okay. Forget it. Yeah. I'm gonna split.
- You sure?
- Hang out for a while.
- Uh-uh-uh.
- I gotta get moving.
- "Gotta get movin'. Gotta hit the road."
Bullshit. What about them two chicks
over there to slow you down, huh?
Yeah. They're beautiful.
So drop out
and join the cause.
Look, no offense, Jake, but I gotta be in Frisco
3:00 tomorrow afternoon.
- Ahh! You puttin' me on, right?
- I wish to God I was.
Well, then you bullshittin' yourself,
because you cannot make it.
- You wanna bet?
- Well, this must be
a souped-up somethin'.
- Yeah. It's hopped up to over 160.
- Whoo! But even so-
I tell you what. I'm gonna bet you
the tab for the bennies.
I'm gonna be in Frisco, I'm gonna call you
3:00 tomorrow afternoon.
Now, if I don't, double the deal
the next time around.
- Bet?
- Bet.
Good luck, whitey!
[Engine Revving]
[Dog Barking]
[Man On Radio] There have been genetic
studies on beef cattle.
There has been concern
the degree of heritability...
of economically important traits
such as rate of growth...
meat conversion
and carcass quality.
Thin breeds,
and in many cases Herefords...
they have been selected
for these traits.
Findings have shown generally
that such traits are highly heritable.
This is consistent
with similar studies...
conducted elsewhere
around the country.
On the other hand,
some other traits...
such as fertility
and calf-survival rate-
low inheritability.
Heterosis,
or hybrid vigor...
may be an important factor
in these latter traits...
and the crossing
of genetic unlikes...
produces heterosis
for best crossbreeding.
So just a few views
of what's to come...
of what will be seen
in crossbreeding...
from today's Farm Report.
- Ten seconds, Super.
- ## [Twangy Guitar Intro]
## [Soul]
- You got it.
- Aaah!
Good morning, folks!
This is yours truly, Super, Super Soul.
Direct and live with no net,
early people. Without a net!
Transmittin' from KOW,
spelt K-O-W.
Uh-huh. The noisiest, bounciest,
fanciest radio station...
in the Far West!
Now let's cheer up the morning with some
wham-bam, zoom-boom, wake-up music...
with a little help
from my friend.
Now take it away, amigo.
Hey! Get it!
All right!
Hubba hubba!
## [Rock]
[Super Soul]
Bring it on home!
We got a long way
to go today, baby.
# I just got the feelin' #
# Like my life was new
and this is my first day #
# She said she loved me #
# And she started to show me
in a personal kind of way #
- # Ooh ooh ooh Ooh ooh ooh #
- # Ohh, ohh, yes, she did #
- # People, now, the girl has got it together #
- # Got it together #
Hey! Come on!
Pull over!
# The girl done
got it together for me #
# And that's
how it's gonna stay #
- # I say the girl has got it together #
- # Got it together #
- # I said the girl has got it together #
# I say the girl
done got it together for me #
# And that's how
it's gonna stay #
## [Singers Vocalizing]
Wake up now!
Hey! Pull over!
Pull over!
You son of a bitch!
# She turned me inside out #
# With a kind of love #
# You just can't hardly find #
# She got the kinda lovin'
make a king bow down and it- #
[Announcer On P.A.,
Indistinct]
[Announcer] There's a lot of traffic
moving through there.
I can't see too well.
One rider is up,
moving to his bike.
There is a yellow flag
in this race.
All riders
will hold their positions.
Kowalski also is up and moving to his bike,
and he's firing it up...
and he's back in this race.
- You okay?
- I'm okay! Get him! Get him!
# That's how it's gonna stay
yeah #
- # The girl's got it together #
- # Got it together ##
[Super Soul] And now,
crashing into the top ten...
comes the first really
monstrous hit of the '70s.
A number that all by itself
jumped 29-
29 places
in one week!
Uh-huh! There's absolutely no doubt
whatsoever, as they say...
that this will be
next week's number one!
Numero uno, baby!
The itchy bang entitled "Where Do You Go
From Here, Baby?" by Brian O'Brian.
Sock it to 'em, Brian, baby!
All right! Let's get to it!
- # Christopher came in the name of Spain #
- Yeah!
- Tell it to me!
- # In 1492 #
[Super Soul]
Talk to me now!
# He said, "I think
the world is round" #
# And I believe
I can prove it's true #
# The waters raised
and his ships were lame #
# But onwards Christopher came #
# His desperate dreams
finally found a shore #
# And the world's
never been the same #
- # Hooray for the men of vision #
- [Horn Honking]
# Hooray now #
# Who are never satisfied #
- # Who believe the way to a better world #
- [Horn Honks]
- # Is to give it a better try #
- # Give it a try, yeah #
# Hooray for
the men of vision #
# May they never disappear #
# Who live
just to ask the question #
# Where do we go
Where do we go #
# Where do we go from here #
# Where do we go now
Where do we go now #
# Where do we go from here #
# Take a look
through the history book #
# It's amazing
how far we've come, huh #
# Now, some folks say
there's no more to learn #
# Others say
we've just begun #
# We've explored the world
from inside out #
## [Continues]
[Horns Honking]
- [Horn Honks]
- # Hooray for the men of vision #
# Who are never
never satisfied #
- # Who believe the way to a better world #
- [Horn Honking]
- # Is to give it a better try #
- # Give it a try now #
# Hooray for
the men of vision #
# May they never disappear #
- Oh! Speak to me!
- # Who live just to ask the question #
- # Where do we go Where do we go #
- All right!
# Where do we go from here #
# Where do we go now
Where do we go now #
# Where do we go from here ##
123, what's your location?
Uh, we've been
in a two-bike pileup on 53.
- 10-4. How far out are you?
- About five miles from Thompson.
- Can you give me a description on the car?
- 1970 white Challenger.
Colorado license
O-A-5-5-9-9.
- 10-4. Was anybody injured?
- No injuries.
- 10-4. Return to your station then.
- Okay.
Uh, we're on our way in, but you best send
a truck for that other motorcycle.
[Engine Sputtering]
- [Bell Ringing]
- ## [Rock]
Hey, Supe.
Pick up on this, man.
"Attention,
all highway patrol stations.
Suspect vehicle 1970 Dodge Challenger,
white in color."
[Horn Honks]
[Truck Horn Blows]
[Announcer On P.A.,
Indistinct]
[Announcer] Number 71 just crashed
into number 63!
It's a pileup! Eight cars, nine cars!
Gasoline on the infield!
Plenty of cars who were-
Oh, my God!
It's number three!
Kowalski!
He's in a roll! Look at him,
landing on the roof of the car...
coming to a rest
on the east end of the field.
Greetings, Sir.
Let's race.
Ya got any balls in that mother?
[Laughing]
Whoop!
[Continues Laughing]
Sayonara!
[Laughing]
You bastard.
[Horn Blaring]
[Sirens Approaching,
Faint]
- Car 24 to Headquarters. Car 24 to Headquarters.
- Come in, Car 24.
Yeah. We lost him
at the Nevada border.
We better let Nevada handle it.
This guy's nuts.
[Dispatcher On Radio]
10-4. Will advise Nevada Highway Patrol.
## [Rock]
## [Continues]
Yeah.
I got it, all right.
Initials O-A-5-5-9-9.
Colorado plates.
Now, what's this
roadrunner done, fellers?
Hey, Supe.
I got them on the air now.
Yeah, quite a mother,
but, uh, well, fellas...
as you know, we can't
throw anything at him...
except, uh, dangerous driving
and failure to stop-
misdemeanors, both of'em,
over here.
[Nevada Officer]
Yeah.
You told me that once,
comrade.
But has this bronco in the Jaguar
filed a formal complaint?
- [Dispatcher] No, he hasn't.
- Well, there you are.
That isn't even a felony,
brother.
- [Dispatcher] What are you guys gonna do?
- He hasn't got us bugged any.
He's the one that's gonna have to
start worrying as of right now.
- [Dispatcher] Hmm. Good luck.
- Yeah. Don't you worry.
We'll catch him.
[Horn Honks]
[Parking Brake Sets]
May I help you, sir?
May I help you?
- Yeah. Fill her up, please.
- Thank you, sir.
[Man] Come on, will ya?
Relax. I'm not gonna hurt you.
- [Heavy Breathing]
- [Man] Come on, baby.
You play ball with me,
I'll let you go, huh?
All right. Come on. Tell me.
Where'd you get the stuff?
Huh?
Which house?
- Come on. Come on.
- [Grunts]
[Whimpering]
Jesus.
Get outta here.
Get out of here.
Go.
And there goes
the Challenger...
being chased by the blue,
blue meanies on wheels.
The vicious traffic squad cars
are after our lone driver...
the last American hero-
the electric centaur,
the demigod...
the super driver
of the golden West.
Two nasty nazi cars are close
behind the beautiful lone driver.
The police numbers
are gettin' closer, closer...
closer to our soul hero
in his soul-mobile.
Yeah, baby.
They about to strike.
They gonna get him,
smash him...
rape... the last
beautiful free soul...
on this planet.
But...
it is written...
"If the evil spirit
arms a tiger with claws...
Brahman provideth wings
for the dove."
Thus spake the super guru.
- Did you hear that?
- Yep.
Where the hell did he get
so much information?
Same place as you do,
Charlie.
You mean from
our own frequency?
That's right.
How long's
he been at it?
Year and a half.
Maybe two.
Hell,
that's against the law.
So's carrying
a transistor on duty.
- Come on now. That's different.
- But he never says anything to incriminate himself.
Brains and lawyers,
Charlie.
As far as the law's concerned,
he's clean as Kleenex.
It's true.
True. True.
True, my friends!
For by
the latest information...
our soul challenger has just
broken the ring of evil...
the deep-blue meanies
have so righteously wrought!
Get through 'em, baby.
Get through 'em!
- [Clicks Off]
- Friggin, faggot.
[Man On Radio]
Attention. Calling Car 44.
Attention, Car 44.
Do you read me?
Gimme that.
This is Car 44 reading you
loud and clear. Over.
Where are you,
Car 44?
We're on 80 some 10 miles
from Argenta. Over.
Well, good.
Stay with it.
Watch for a white Challenger,
license plates initial...
O-A-5-5-9-9.
Colorado plates. Last seen heading
for Dunphy on U.S. 40 at cruising speed.
We have reason to believe
that it's supercharged...
so maintain double alert
till you spot it...
and then call in
for instructions.
Over and out.
Let's go.
Come on!
Let's go!
[Engine Starts]
[No Siren]
What do you
think he's done?
Don't know.
Well, what
do you think?
I think
he's gonna...
hijack that car
to Cuba.
Don't be ridiculous.
Hell, Charlie.
I don't know.
Maybe he killed
somebody.
Maybe he stole
that big dude of his.
Maybe both.
Hey.
What's he doing?
Jesus Christ. Watch it.
Watch it. Whoa! Watch it!
Move over.
Let me take it!
Let go. Let go!
I'm gonna get that son of a bitch.
So help me, I'll get that son of a bitch.
- [Teletype Machines Clacking]
- Hello, Nevada.
Hello, Nevada.
Nevada, this is Colorado
State Highway Patrol.
This is about a special query raised
by the Utah Highway Patrol.
Affirmative. That's correct.
But later they asked that the information...
be forwarded to you guys,
so get ready for some details.
Turn on your tape recorders
and all that sorta jazz, huh?
Apparently, this speed maniac
you've been chasing all over your territory...
is a former professional
road racer named Kowalski.
K-O-W-A-L-S-K-I.
Repeat. Kowalski.
First name unknown.
Other particulars
also unknown.
All we do know
is that he's employed...
as a car delivery driver
by an agency in Denver.
He's presently driving
a Dodge Challenger...
Colorado license plate
O-A-5-5-9-9.
This is not a stolen car.
He's driving it to San Francisco
for delivery due Monday.
[Nevada Officer]
It's only Saturday. What's his hurry?
[Colorado Officer] That's what
we wanted to know ourselves...
so your guess
is as good as ours.
10-4.
[Siren Begins Wailing]
[Siren Stops]
- You all right?
- Yeah.
[Groans]
Forty-four to Headquarters.
- Come in, 44.
- He's on his way. I lost him.
- What? What the hell's
goin' on out there, Collins?
- Headin' for Twin Falls.
- He creamed my car.
- What's the matter with you? You gone crazy?
Correction. We're still after him.
We haven't lost him.
- We're still after him. Now, come on!
- Stay right where you are.
We're coming to you
right now.
Come on!
Let's go!
Give me that.
- Car 44 to Headquarters.
- Come in, 44.
He's jumped the main road
and headed out into the desert.
Let him cook out there
for a while.
He ain't
going nowhere.
What's he trying
to prove now?
- Any time now, Super.
- Yeah. Run a tape.
I already
ran a tape twice.
Come on, man! Are you blind or somethin'?
Can't you see I'm thinkin'?
Crazy-
[Engine Stops]
[Super Soul On Radio]
Kowalski.
Kowalski, can you hear me?
Do you hear me, Kowalski?
Now, I know
you can hear me, Kowalski.
I'm sure you hear me now,
this very minute.
Now, you listen very carefully.
The whole mobile force of the Nevada
State Highway Patrol is after you.
They waitin' for you
to come up for air.
Yeah.
Now some people imagine...
you'll try to get to California
through Death Valley.
And others bet
you'll die there in the desert.
These few are just too happy
to see you vanish for good out there.
But my tape deck
is just as jammed with telegrams...
as my head
is jammed with phone calls...
from people who are wishing you well
in your getaway...
no matter where
it might lead you.
I wish I could help you,
but I can't. I can't.
I don't think anybody can, except
for that crazy lucky streak of yours.
And now you gonna
need more luck-
all of it, perhaps,
and badly.
You can beat the police,
you can beat the road...
and you can even beat the clock...
but you can't beat
the desert.
Nobody can.
You just cannot-
- [Clicks Off]
- Go to hell.
Wait.
[Engine Revving]
[Woman]
I love you.
[Woman] Wouldn't it be funny after all
if you did have to arrest me?
I mean,
me trying to turn you on...
and you trying to turn me in.
I love this.
I love your scar.
You hate it, but I love it.
No, I don't hate it.
I just hate what it means.
What does it mean?
Only if you make war on war
will you overcome it.
I love you. I love you.
Mmm.
You're crazy-
surfing in the middle of winter.
I'm going out again.
Maybe I'll catch an eight-footer.
[Exhales Deeply]
I'll ride it in your honor.
Sayonara.
Remember me.
[Engine Stops]
[Bystanders Talking]
[Whirring]
Here we are at point zero
where the Kowalski saga began.
And to be interviewed
by K.L.Z. TV News...
is the owner of the agency,
Mr. Holly Mekas...
and one of the attendants,
Sandy McKees.
Sandy, uh,
you knew this man best.
- What do you think of Kowalski?
- Well, he's a great driver.
Sir, what?
What did you say?
- [Sandy] I said he's a great driver.
- Great driver. We all knew that.
- You won't find a driver like him
on the road every day.
- But as a professional driver...
he never really
made the grade, did he?
You know why?
He never really wanted to.
So far as I'm concerned, he was number one
then and he's number one now.
- [Bystanders Cheering]
- [Sandy] Can't find a driver with his potential.
Why don't they let him alone?
Let the guy alone!
Look, he never done any harm!
This is Bob Bolmer,
K.L.Z. TV News in Denver.
Super Soul needs no introduction
as our number-one disc jockey.
But he's certainly on his way to becoming
a national celebrity in his own right...
as the invisible guide
of Kowalski.
- Blind leading the blind.
- As you all remember...
Kowalski was involved in a cross-country chase
starting in Denver, Colorado.
[Rattling]
[Man]
Stay right where you are, son.
Don't move, stranger.
Don't move.
I'll get him for you.
I'll get him.
Stick your pretty little head
right through there, baby.
That's it.
Now we got him.
Now we'll get our basket
over here.
Look at that.
Live and wigglin'.
Yeah.
Ain't that a beauty?
Ohh. Ain't that
a fat one, though?
Now we'll get him in here.
Thank you, son.
- That's got him.
- Thank you.
How many
do you have in there?
Got six rattlers,
two sidewinders...
and now we've got
one very precious diamondback.
What do you do
with those things?
Trade 'em. Trade 'em
for coffee, sugar...
chewing tobacco,
salt, flour and beans-
and lots of beans, son.
[Chuckles]
You live out here, huh?
Look, I'm lost
and I need your help.
[Super Soul On Radio] Attention, Kowalski.
I've got an important message for you.
Kowalski, are you listening?
Now dig this.
Coppers from
the highway patrol...
are combing the desert
hunting for you.
Listen carefully. Believe it or not,
they trying to help you.
They really are.
Dig it?
[Clicks Off]
That depends, son.
- What?
- You said you needed my help.
So that depends
on your helping me first.
Helping me
to get to where it was that-
to get where it was
that I was headed for.
One of them is a-
is a-comin' on now.
I can't see
a damn thing out there.
I bet you can't even see my truck neither,
and that's... [Spits]
Just over there.
Let's get the hell
outta here, huh?
No, no, that ain't
any way to do it.
That's no way to-
to get the hell out.
No, the best way, to my knowledge,
to get away...
is to root right in where you are,
just root right in.
He just went over,
yeah.
But stay put.
Tracks. Let's go down
and take a look.
He must have found my old truck.
He's circlin' it, yeah.
There's a truck.
That's a derelict. Probably been there
since the depression.
- [Engine Starts, Revs]
- He's headin' north. Okay.
- Where to now?
- Straight ahead.
- Okay.
- Take it easy.
"Name: Kowalski.
"K-O-W-A-L-S-K-I.
Christian name-"
Christian name, my flat foot.
What is that?
# Away #
# To the River Jordan #
# You got to talk
to the Lord #
# To be free #
# Oh, you got to tell him #
# Oh, walk on by His side #
# You can believe
every word yourself #
# You gotta believe #
# You gotta believe
in the lamb of grace now #
# Believe it
You gotta believe it #
# Come to the Lord
and you'll be heard #
# You gotta believe it
Yeah, yeah #
# You got to read
the Holy Bible #
# Sit down
Sit down right now #
# 'Cause that's
what He said #
# "I'm the way"
Ohh #
# I've been wadin' #
# In the River Jordan #
# I'm gonna walk on my two feet
to the house of the Lord #
# Hear now #
# I'm gonna get down #
# On my knees
and pray to Him #
# Thank you, Lord Jesus
for thinking of me #
# You gotta believe
in the resurrection #
# Believe it
Believe it #
# Ask of the Lord
and you'll be heard #
# I believe it
Oh, yeah #
- What is that?
- Faith healers.
Don't you come any closer. You just wait
for me right here in this automobile.
- You hear me?
- Okay.
'Cause them healers
don't like strangers much.
Especially that deacon
Jesse Hovah.
He's a-
He's a mean one.
- And don't forget about the gas.
- I ain't forgettin' the gas.
## [Continues]
# You gotta believe
in the resurrection #
# I believe it
I believe it #
# Ask of the Lord
and you'll be heard #
# I believe it
Oh, yeah #
# You gotta read
the Holy Bible #
# Sit down
Sit down right now #
# Because that's
what He said #
# "I'm the way" #
- # Yeah #
- # Yeah, yeah #
## [Continues]
- You're late.
- Mr. Hovah, my truck broke down.
Who is that man
over there?
Just like I was tellin' you,
my truck...
she ain't gettin'
any younger now, and-
Who is that man?
- He's a friend.
- A friend, eh?
How do you know?
- [Snake rattling]
- Ain't that a pretty one, though?
Ain't that real pretty?
## [Continues]
[Rattling Continues]
Yeah.
But we don't need him
anymore.
Look, I told you'
these meetings are private.
Why did you
bring a stranger?
Mr. Hovah, I didn't bring him.
He brought me over.
Why?
Well, he needs some gas.
Gas.
Hmm.
Just take your gas
and take him out of here.
But, Mr. Hovah...
ain't you gonna give me my coffee
and sugar and all the-
Yeah, you'll get it.
And all the stuff
that you promised me?
You'll get it.
We just don't need the snakes anymore.
We got the music.
So... we are going to...
free the vipers!
[Rattling, Hissing]
## [Continues]
# Wadin'
in the River Jordan #
# Lord, I'm a believer #
# Lord #
# Ohh, Lord #
# Wade in the water
Oh, my Lord #
# Wadin' #
- # Oh, my Lord #
- # Wadin' #
- # Ohh #
- # Wading #
- # Oh, Jesus #
# Come on
and save me #
# Ohh, yeah #
# Gotta read the words
of the Holy Bible #
# Sit down
Sit down right now #
# All this hurt and sin
washed away #
# Wading #
# I'm a-wading #
- # Oh, Jesus #
- # Wading #
- # Everybody #
- # Wade on #
- # Wading #
- # Hallelujah #
- # Wade on #
# Wading #
- # Ohh, yeah yeah, yeah #
- # Wade in the water #
- # On the water #
- # Wading #
# Wade in the water #
- ## [Continues]
- Think she's pretty much filled up now.
- Yeah.
- # Wade in the water #
# Yeah, yeah
Ohh #
Well'
you can leave now, son.
How?
Well, just follow
the Larrea Belt.
[Sighs]
The what belt?
The Larrea Belt.
Always keep your eye
on the trail of the sun.
- Never lose your shadow.
- # Ohh, Lord #
Then when you see very tall saguaro cactuses,
don't lose them neither...
'cause that's
the Larrea Belt.
The saguaro and a creosote tree'll
take you right back...
onto the trail
of the earth.
Mm-hmm.
So, th-that's the road?
That's the road, yeah.
[Laughing] You're beginning to get
the fundamentals of it, son.
Maybe.
Well, thanks, Pa.
## [Continues]
Thanks
for everything.
You're very welcome.
## [Continues]
Hope I'll be
seeing you again.
- # Hallelujah #
- # Wading #
- # Ohh #
- # Wade in the water #
[Engine Starts]
Vaya con Dios.
# Wade in the water #
- # Wade in the water #
- # Yeah, yeah #
# Ohh, ohh, ohh, ohh #
# Ohh-oh-ohh ##
"Enlisted U.S. Army,
1960.
"Service in Vietnam war.
"Wounded,
Mekong Delta.
"Honorable discharge
from Army, 1964.
"Medal of honor for bravery in battle.
[Snickers]
"Entered San Diego
police force, 1964.
- "Twice promoted.
- [Typing Continues]
"Detective First Class,
1966.
"Dishonorable discharge.
"Classified documents available
to authorized personnel only.
"Demolition derby driver
and auto clown, 1967-68.
"Driving license suspended,
1968.
"Previous failure to submit
to alcohol level tests.
"Minor jobs.
"Other driving jobs
from 1970 to date.
Additional data: None."
## [Funk Rock]
Ready now?
- Not yet. Not yet.
- Just tell me when.
Hey, I'm ready,
but he's not ready yet.
- What?
- Forget it, forget it. I'll tell you when I'm ready.
Goodness sakes.
Well, come on.
[Muttering]
I'm coming.
Push it.
I am pushing.
[Vehicle Approaching]
There's
a car coming.
[Car Stops,
Engine Idling]
Going our way?
Be back
in a second.
Okay, let's push her
off the road.
[Grunting, Groaning]
[Sighs]
Oh, what a relief!
Yes, thank you.
You're very kind.
You're welcome.
Uh, pardon me, but could you please tell us
which direction you're headed?
I'm going to Frisco.
Oh, well, that's perfect.
Thank you.
[Chuckling]
Is something wrong?
No. Why?
Should there be?
Well, you're so silent...
and moody.
Maybe it's just
part of my nature.
Why are you laughing?
[Chuckling]
I'm not laughing.
Yes, you are.
Way down
deep inside yourself.
It's because
you think we're queers...
isn't it?
Hey-
This is a stickup.
Stickup?
[Laughing]
Why are you laughing,
Mary?
Well, tell me.
Tell me!
- [Groans]
- [Tires Screeching]
Hey!
No! No, please! It hurts! Oh, my head!
[Groans]
Ohh!
You bitch.
## [Funk Rock]
[Women]
# I get so #
# Tired #
# Clouds fall down
from early mornin' #
# It just rains rain
I've never seen #
- ## [Continues]
- [Super Soul] Hey, Brother K.
- Hi.
- Welcome back.
- How you feelin'?
- Tired.
Oh, I bet you're tired. Well'
you wanna know what's happenin'?
Yeah.
What's happening?
Big Brother's not so much
watching as listening in...
as you well might have
gathered by now.
But what you probably don't
know is that they found these two...
let us say'
gentlemen on the road.
They was pretty badly
battered up.
Yeah, they must have had an accident
or something like that.
But some smart-ass was puttin'
the pressure on them to charge you...
with some ugly, nasty crime.
Let us say
assault and battery.
But the two gents in question
refused to comply.
Or as my alter ego
might put it...
stickin' to they guns.
Now listen to this.
Some party or parties...
are busily preparing
a little welcome committee...
in the sunshine state...
and the main doors,
and even some side doors...
are heavily embellished
with garlands and fuzzy frills.
You know what I mean?
Yeah, I know
what you mean.
## [Continues]
Hang on now, brother.
Hang on.
[Women Continue]
# Skylines rise and they fall away #
- # Fall away #
- # Ohh-ohh-ohhh #
# I'm so tired ##
[Horn Blaring]
- [Horn Stops]
- ## [Folk Guitar]
All right, everybody, clear the streets
and you won't get hurt.
Hey!
Hey, nigger!
- ## [Continues]
- Hey, loudmouthed nigger!
I'm gonna shut your big, black mouth.
Let's get him!
[Man]
# And dear Jesus God thank you for #
# The morning fog
and the rain #
# That clears my weary head #
# Give us the strength
to do #
# The things
you wanted us to do #
# Like love one another #
# Believe that
we're all brothers #
# We've just said it
in the past #
# And you know
that'll never last #
# Dear Jesus God #
# Thank you for #
# The winter snow
and the things that grow #
# On the way back
to my home #
[Backup Singers]
# Ooh, ooh-ooh #
[Man]
# And dear Jesus God #
# Thank you for the feeling #
# That I have for you #
# When I'm all alone #
# Give us the strength
to do #
# The things you wa- ##
[Radio: Tuning]
[Radio: Off]
Kowalski! Hi!
Hey.
- Hey, you need any help?
- No, thanks.
- You sure?
- I'm sure.
Far out, man.
- Hey, wait a second.
- What?
You got any ups?
- You mean speed?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I got some
back at the place.
How far is it?
About a mile.
Okay?
Wanna go back?
Far out.
## [Rock]
# Mississippi Queen #
# She taught me everything #
# Way down
around Vicksburg #
# Around Louisiana way #
# Lived a Cajun lady #
# We called her
Mississippi Queen #
# You know
she was a dancer #
# She moved better on wine #
# While the rest of them fools
was a-gettin' their kicks #
# Boy, now, beg your pardon
I was gettin' mine #
# Mississippi Queen #
# If you know what I mean #
# She taught me everything #
# This lady, she asked me #
# If I would be her man #
# You know
that I told her #
# I'll do what I can #
# To keep her
lookin' pretty #
# Buy her dresses that shine #
# While the rest of them dudes
was a-makin' their bread #
# Brother, beg your pardon
I was losin' mine ##
[Screen Door
Shuts]
Thanks.
- You want more water?
- That's okay.
[Sighs]
Keep these.
I got a whole bunch.
Oh, no, no.
I can't use all of that.
Well, take
what you need.
- Thanks.
- All right.
[Super Soul]
Person-to-person call for Kowalski.
Person-to-person call
for Kowalski.
Can you hear me,
Kowalski?
This is to inform you
of the latest developments.
Correction
to my last delivery.
All the main doors
are closed...
except one.
- This one opens to Sonora.
- [Biker] Oh, far out, man.
- [Super Soul Continues]
- That's just a couple minutes up the road.
You're gonna make it,
Kowalski.
[Super Soul Laughs]
Yeah. The last chance.
- Or some oasis around there.
- Hey, are you, uh-
are you familiar
with this jock's voice?
- Now all you super people on the super highways...
- Super Soul? Yeah. Why?
And byways and freeways-
- [Sighs] I don't know.
- I said freeways-
[Biker]
That's Super Soul.
- If any of you should spot our hero out there...
- Maybe he's got a cold.
- But that's his voice.
- Help the man.
- You really think so, huh?
- Cheer him on.
- Let us know where he is...
- Wait a minute.
- So that I can personally
deliver your message...
- Hey!
- Of good will to our superhero.
- Come here!
Are you listening,
K?
- Come on!
- We're gonna help you. Dig it.
All of us.
- [Super Soul Continues] Yeah.
- Listen to this.
So, friends, call me.
- Yeah?
- Yours Truly, Super Soul...
- Whose voice is that?
- Right here at KOW...
- It's Super Soul. Who else?
- You sure?
- The noisiest, fanciest station in the far west...
- You absolutely sure?
- Right here in eautil,
uptight, downtown Goldfield.
- Well, hang on a minute.
And Brother K, just
keep the faith in us, baby...
and we'll lead you
right on...
to glory.
Yeah, it sounds
a little different.
He sounds kind of stiff
or square.
He sounds
a little mechanical.
[Biker]
You sense a trap, man?
[Kowalski]
Yeah, maybe.
[Biker]
Wait here till I get back.
Where you going?
Just wait here.
You gonna stay with us?
No. No, I don't think so.
Is there something
I can do for you?
- Like what?
- Like anything you want.
No, I can't think
of anything.
You don't fancy me.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Very much.
Then why don't we
have some fun?
Thanks.
Thanks just the same.
That's okay.
Isn't there something
you'd like?
Yeah.
Yeah, how about a smoke?
Oh. Okay.
I'll roll you one.
No, no, no.
A straight one.
Yeah.
All right.
[Screen Door Shuts]
Here.
- Keep the pack.
- Thanks.
You know'
you haven't changed much.
Hmm?
I said you haven't
changed much.
Haven't I?
Here.
That was a long time ago.
I know.
I pasted it up
when it first came out.
When I cut it out, I-
[Motorcycle Engine Starts]
It's a lot like shootin' jackrabbits,
ain't it?
Mm. God damn it's hot.
I know that.
[Radio: Man]
# Dear Jesus God #
# Thank you for
the winter snow #
# And the things
that grow #
## [Continues]
[Backup Singers]
# Ooh, ooh-ooh #
- # And dear Jesus God ##
- You were right, man.
He sold you out.
[Radio Off]
More cops than
I ever seen, man.
You were sold out.
- What the hell's that for?
- That's your pig pass.
[Air Raid Siren Wailing]
[Patrolmen Murmuring]
I figure I'd trade in the truck
for the station wagon.
[Siren Wailing, Faint]
It's police!
Clear the road!
Clear the road! Get those cars outta here!
Get those cars back!
That's him!
Get those cars outta here!
Get after him!
- Move! Move!
- [Tires Screeching]
Move!
Goddamn!
Hey, that's my car!
This is California.
We don't call them mothers
or speed freaks around here...
but we're gonna do what
you haven't been able to do.
We're gonna stop him
for good.
Yes, we've been previously
informed of all that.
Thank you, Nevada.
[Phone Hangs Up]
[Sirens Wailing]
Well, you don't
need me anymore.
You're in California.
You're almost home.
- Can you make it on that?
- You bet your ass, baby.
You take care, Kowalski.
[Engine Starts]
Hey, K.
I knew you wouldn't make it.
"What's happenin"'? You happenin', man.
You're all over the front page.
Here's the headline:
"Ex-Race Driver Involved
In Massive Police Chase."
Yeah, they even printed
poor Vera's story, plus her picture.
You out there drivin'
like a wild man.
You know you gon'
lose your gig.
It's not your car anyw-
What you tryin' to prove?
Are you high,
or what?
Hey, K,
you still there?
[Kowalski]
Look'just tell Sandy not to worry.
I'm okay, and that car's gonna be
delivered Monday, right on time.
You're gassed, man.
No incidents.
But it's double the bet
next time around, huh?
Hey, man.
Don't do no silly shit
out there. Okay?
- Take care of yourself.
- Okay. I'll see you, amigo.
[Radio: Man]
# I never dreamed #
# He meant so much #
# Till I felt #
# His loving touch #
# Now my soul #
# Is free from sin #
# Since He
opened up the door #
# And let me in #
# Soon I'll walk #
# On streets of gold #
# I'm a sheep #
# In His great fold #
# I'm no longer #
# All alone #
# Since sweet Jesus
made me whole #
# And led me home ##
Ten seconds, Super.
## [Gospel]
[Man, Chorus]
# Sing out strong for Jesus #
# Sing out for His love #
- ## [Continues]
- Ohhhh, lordy!
Good mornin' to
all you folks out there.
Sunday morning here
with all men of good will...
and some of evil will thrown in
for good measure.
All peace-lovin'
Christians...
gettin' ready to go
to church this mornin'.
And here I am, yours truly-
yeah, Super Soul-
bantering a stream
of unconsciousness...
and peddlin' these labels
for the sake of good music...
to all you listeners
out there!
But I'm here on Sunday
for the first time in my life...
and for the very first time
this KOW radio station begins...
not only to deejay
and to do my own thing...
but to tell you
a little story.
[Super Soul]
Now, let's start at the beginning.
But before we start, here's some early
Sunday morning wake-up music!
- Take it away, baby!
- [Chorus Continues] # Sing out forJesus #
- # When you're tired and weary come to Jesus #
- [Shouting, Indistinct]
- # He's the man who really cares #
- We are live out there!
- # Come sickness or health #
- # Sing out for Jesus ##
- ## [Continues]
- Right on!
[Super Soul]
And today...
in a beautiful gesture made
by the beautiful people...
of beautiful
downtown Goldfield...
this radio station
was named Kowalski...
in honor of
the last American hero...
to whom speed means
freedom of the soul.
The question is not
when he's gon' stop...
but who is gonna stop him.
## [Rock: Piano]
# Whoo-hoo
I'm feelin' kinda lonely #
# Gonna be in there
for only a few days #
# At the most #
# I realize it's early
but I'm feelin' kinda squirrely #
# So I go downstairs
for a toke #
# Clink a glass
and drink a glass #
# And pretty soon
I think I'll ask #
# The lady
for a dance or two #
# I try my legs
and test 'em #
# But my feet
they up and lef 'em #
# And the music
makes me wanna move #
# I got to rock it
Roll it #
# Reel it, Feel it #
## [Continues]
Hello, Kowalski.
Kowalski.
## [Continues]
# Roll it, Roll it #
# Roll it #
## [Continues]
Please listen,
Kowalski.
It's useless.
Cut it off, man.
## [Continues]
# The band was really playin'
The guitar was almost sacred #
# And the music
made me dance some more #
# I got to rock it #
# Roll it #
# Reel it #
# Feel it #
# Somethin's
Somethin's comin' #
# Over me, yeah, yeah
Whoa #
## [Continues]
Stop!
# Well, now I'm really drunk
and now my heart is startin' to pump #
# And then I can't dance
with anybody else #
# The thought of conversation
takes up all there is of me #
# I only look
around the floor #
# A woman walked in by me
Tossed a double down and said #
# Looks like you're cheatin'
on her with a friend #
# But as I aimed the glass
I got brass enough to ask #
# If somethin's terribly
terribly wrong with me #
# I got to rock it
Roll it #
# Reel it #
# Feel it #
# Somethin's
Somethin's comin' #
# Over me, yeah, yeah #
# Oh, I got to rock it #
# Roll it #
# Reel it
Feel it #
# Somethin's
Somethin's comin' #
# Over me, yeah, yeah #
# I got to rock it
Roll it #
# I got to reel it #
# Feel it ##
## [Mid-tempo]
[Woman]
# My eyes were opened #
# I was readin'
every line #
# Then somehow
I lost my place #
# In the book of life #
# Was I lookin' afer Jesus #
# Was he lookin' after me #
# Before I found
the answer, Lord #
# We parted company #
- # Nobody knows #
- # Nobody knows Nobody knows #
# Nobody sees #
# Until the light of life
stops burnin' #
# Till another soul
goes free #
# Nobody knows #
# Ooh, nobody knows #
# Nobody sees #
# Until the light of life
stops burnin' #
# Till another soul
goes free #
# Who is the giver #
# Mm-mmm
And who shall receive #
# Who knows the answer #
# Who shall be free #
# What is the question #
# Mm-mmm, now, now
where is the rhyme #
# Who's gonna testify
for me #
# When I die, yeah #
- # Nobody knows #
- # Oooh-ooh, oooh-ooh #
# Nobody sees #
# Until the light of life
stops burnin' #
# Till another soul
goes free #
- # Nobody knows #
- # Nobody knows Nobody knows #
# Nobody sees #
# Until the light of life
stops burnin' #
# Till another soul
goes free #
- # Nobody knows #
- # Nobody knows No, no, no #
# Nobody sees #
# Until the light of life
stops burnin' #
# Till another soul
goes free #
# No-ohhh-ohhh-ohh #
- # Nobody knows #
- # Oooh, I said no #
# Nobody sees #
# Until the light of life
stops burnin' #