Guys, this is the best
laundry party I've ever thrown.
You can't just stick
the word "party" on anything
and make it fun.
You're just
mad because you missed
Brad's gum surgery party.
(Brad and Jane laugh)
Well, save the date,
because next week...
I'm having
an asymmetrical mole removed.
The theme will either be
"dressed to the benigns"
or "it's time to get
my affairs in order."
(Plastic rustles)
Ooh!
That's a lot of laundry, buddy.
- Actually, this is all candy.
- Oh.
Yeah. I trick-or-treated
my way over here.
It's not even close
to Halloween.
Yeah, but it turns out
if you ring someone's doorbell
and then scream in their face
"trick or treat?"
as loud as you can,
they'll just give you
whatever they have on them.
This one guy-- he gave me
all his laundry.
- Hmm?
- And the cool is that it's all XXL,
so I have room to grow into it.
You're a terrifying individual.
Oh, hey, Dave, you wanna
throw your shirts in with mine?
Oh, no, no, no. These-- these
require special attention.
In fact, sometimes I throw them
on wet and run-dry them
so they keep their shape.
But then I get all sweaty,
and it's like, here we go again!
Would not change a thing
about what you're doing.
(Whispers) - Thank you.
- Oh, my God.
There's a groupon
at the aquarium
to swim with the dolphins.
Mama likes dolphins.
- Nope. (Sighs)
- Hey!
(Beep) Mama always does this.
You see something you like,
you buy it,
and then
you lose interest immediately.
You're too impulsive.
I am not too impulsive.
You bought us a time-share
in Tampa.
The lady at the kiosk said
it's the Sacramento of the East.
Now we gotta go to Tampa
every year.
Tampa's not a place that you go.
It's a place that you end up.
My bitch is the same way.
- What? - Brad buys so much junk on QVC,
we could start our own show.
(Gasps)
But we won't.
Whatever, Jane.
It's not junk, all right?
For example, while you porkers
have been doing laundry,
I've been sitting here,
getting a killer ab workout
with my new...
electro ab-belt. (Chuckles)
The electro-pulse stimulation...
(Electricity pulses)
Uhh! Tones and shapes your...
(Strained voice) ...abs!
(Grunts) Huh?
(Normal voice)
For improved muscle defi...
(Electricity buzzing)
(Strained voice) ...nition!
(Buzzing stops) (Grunts)
Anyway...
I predict that Alex buys
the groupon and never uses it.
I am absolutely gonna use it.
Okay, how many unredeemed
groupons do you have currently?
(Mutters) (Brad and Dave) What?
Mm? (Mutters)
- How many?
- 11.
11. Okay.
Well, I think it's time
that you learned a lesson.
Tell you what. If you use
all your groupons in one week,
I'll buy you that
dolphin groupon and...
I'll do it with ya.
You're on, ping-pong.
- Mm. Okay.
- Well good luck, Alex.
(Electricity pulses) I'm (Strained
voice) rooting for you. (Exhales)
Okay? You all right?
What I meant to say is,
I'm in your...
(Electricity buzzing)
(Strained voice) ...corner!
(Voice breaks) Ow! Oh, God!
It's just--
it's not even pulsing anymore.
(Zaps) Ow!
- Get that off of him.
- It's just constant.
I don't-- ow!
- So painful!
- It shocked me!
- Take it off! (Cries) - All right.
I'm trying. I don't know where the--
Ohh.
(Buzzing stops)
- I need to sit on a trash bag. - We need
a trash bag. We just-- it happened.
(Alex) - No!
- It's happens. It just happens.
(Groans)
It's okay. It's okay.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Last time I was there,
I think I left a suede jacket.
I'd love to get that back,
with or without the cat.
Oh, PS. There's a live cat
living in that jacket.
(Splat) Oh, my God.
I see the guy
whose life I ruined,
who in turn vowed to ruin mine.
If you find my coat cat, he
answers to the name "coat cat."
Gotta go. Bye!
Hey, Chase.
Buddy, old pal.
You know what's cool?
The last time
we saw each other,
we left things
on the best terms possible.
I've been looking for you, Max.
To tell me that
you're back at work
and that you're back
with your wife?
Nope. Thanks to you,
I'm still unemployed,
and my ex-wife's engaged
to my brother.
(Groans and exhales)
I'd kill myself,
but guess who has to give
a toast at their wedding?
Ooh, boy. That is
rough'em stuff'em robots, pal.
I've been following you
for weeks,
trying to craft a plan
to ruin your life.
Funny thing is,
your life is so pathetic
I doubt I can
make it any worse.
It's un-sabotagable.
Hey. Come on.
I got a lot of stuff going on.
I, uh, recently bought
a ladle...
for soups.
I, uh, I read half an article
on fish oil.
And, uh, I just learned
how to do the heimlich.
Can even do it on myself, so now
chewing food is my prerogative.
Your life sucks.
You have no job, no love life.
Your apartment is disgusting.
I considered releasing
rats in there,
but you already had rats
in there way bigger than mine.
Don't beat yourself up, pal.
We're all just raising our rats
the best we can.
What I'm trying to say is,
I'm not gonna ruin your life
because it's impossible to ruin
something that's already
terrible.
It'd be like adding more moms
to Facebook.
Penny, aren't you sick of paying
a professional ear cleaner
to come to your house
and painfully remove
your unwanted canal wax?
Look, Brad, I know
Jane's making you sell
all your little gadgets, but--
Well, now you don't have to...
with the revolutionary ear genie.
Try it out.
(Whirring) No!
What?
(Click, whirring stops)
No, I do not wanna buy
your used ear cleaner.
Totally understand.
I get it.
(Inhales sharply)
Let's talk shoes.
How are you heating yours?
I have a problem!
I need help!
- I have a problem and I need help.
- No! Me!
Okay, okay.
Alex first. Alex first.
Yeah. Okay. Thank you.
So you know how Dave challenged
me to do all these groupons?
I-I keep getting distracted.
I didn't even make it to
my pottery class this morning.
(Gasps)
(Puppies barking and yipping)
Ohh! It was
a total puppy pile-on.
So you never used
your pottery groupon?
- Which means you still have 11.
- 12.
The puppy store lady said
that there was a groupon
for eyelash extensions.
I need those!
I have my dad's
stubby eyelashes.
You guys have to do
these groupons with me,
keep me on track.
Well, as the author of
several dozen cries for help,
I know a good one
when I hear one.
But we have to be fair.
In the interest of conducting
a civil discourse,
the fat slob from Illinois
has the floor.
Thank you. Now you guys remember
Chase, right?
Yes. Super cool guy,
vowed to ruin your life.
That's the one. Well, he said
that my life is so pathetic
that it is un-sabotagable.
So I need to improve my life
to prove him wrong.
Hmm.
(Clicking tongue)
(Brad clicks tongue) - Huh.
(Penny) - Hmm.
Well, Max...
you know we love a challenge.
But that's not
so much a challenge
as it is a suicide mission.
So we're gonna go with Alex!
Yes!
Sorry, brah.
You're on your ahn.
You ain't Private Ryan,
and I ain't shaking hands
with Tom Hanks.
Max, there's only one person
who's really
up to this challenge.
I've waited ten years
for you to come to me.
(Inhales deeply)
Mm!
(Whirs)
How did you get a picture
of me in my underwear?
Well, you're-- you're always
in your underwear.
In fact, it's hard to find
a picture of you
when you're clothed.
I do not envy the task
you are about to embark on.
What are
all those red arrows for?
Oh, those are all the areas
that need improvements.
But those are all of them.
Yeah. You got lots
of bad areas.
You're like the Oakland
of gay guys.
Okay. Well, where do we start?
Small stuff--
haircut, shower,
stop asking waiters if
your food could be "lasagna'd."
Jane, I'm in
your undiagnosed OCD hands.
- Ahh.
- Let's do this.
(Robert Palmer)
♪ how can it be permissible? ♪
♪ she compromise my principle ♪
♪ yeah, yeah ♪
(Whispers) Yeah. Yeah.
♪ That kind of love
is mythical ♪
♪ she's a craze you'd endorse,
she's a powerful force ♪
♪ you're obliged to conform
when there's no other course ♪
♪ she used to look good to me ♪
♪ but now I find her ♪
(Blows air)
♪ Simply irresistible ♪
♪ she's all mine ♪
♪ there's no other way to go ♪
♪ simply irresistible ♪
Well, well, well...
if it isn't doubting Dave.
Might have to start calling you
"doubting dolphin Dave."
(Alex and Brad
laugh as dolphins)
Feeling pretty good 'cause you
knocked out a few groupons, huh?
Not just a few. Many few.
We got
these cool hooded scarves...
(Pops lips) and we got
our teeth whitened... twice.
Whitened up them teeth! (Laughs)
(Chuckles)
And we took this
gorgeous portrait. Show him.
Got it. Isn't it beautiful?
It's like a portrait
of two lipstick lesbians
who adopted
a lost boy of Sudan.
Yeah, it's just been good times.
Oh! You guys, up next...
(High-pitched singsong voice)
tequila shots!
(Normal voice) 50% off...
with this guy.
Si, señor.
Ooh! Yay!
I hate tequila.
These groupons are
the worst thing ever.
No, the worst thing ever
is that at this rate,
Alex is gonna finish
these groupons by tomorrow.
You know what we need to do?
We need to sabotage her
so she can't finish.
Why would I do that?
Because, Pen,
if Alex wins this,
she's gonna be dragging you
to groupons
for the rest of your life.
You wanna be 50 years old
and single
and doing half-priced
trapeze lessons?
I resent you making me single
in this hypothetical.
See, you could've at least
given me the dignity
of having been widowed.
Okay! Down the hatch.
Our brow-shaping groupon
is in 10.
They shoot a laser
right between your eyeballs!
(Chuckles) Here.
Ready, Pen?!
- Yes!
- Whoo!
Whoo!
(Grunts and groans)
- Mm!
- Ugh!
(Inhales sharply)
Let's take that bitch down.
(Whispers) Yeah.
(Whirring)
Jane!
(Turns off vacuum)
Check out this machine.
It's amazing.
It sucks the garbage
off the ground,
so now I don't have to throw it
out on the street
through a hole in my pocket,
Andy Dufresne style.
Max, you look great.
I mean, really great.
I feel great.
This morning,
I flossed my mouth,
and my gums only bled a lot,
as opposed to
an alarming amount.
And you had that interview today
at that grocery store?
How did that go?
(Thud) I nailed I it.
This supermarket is the worst.
(Muzak playing)
Here's what you gotta do.
You gotta move
the sugar cereals
from the bottom shelf
to the top shelf,
'cause people like me
don't and/or can't
bend over to pick it up.
I thought you were here
for the bagger position?
I said, any questions?!
Chop-chop!
I thought you said
you nailed it.
I did nail it, Jane.
In fact...
they're making me...
assistant manager.
No way.
Curds and whey.
Guy said he liked my real talk
and fresh takes.
Wow. My plan is working
much faster than I thought.
Come to think of it...
maybe a little too fast?
I mean, I'm weirdly happy.
My nipples stopped burning.
No one likes my real talk
and fresh takes.
Once, a guy liked
my real fresh take on talks,
and that guy was me,
and I was lying.
What is your point?
There's no way my life could've
turned around this quickly
on my own.
The only logical explanation
is that Chase is
secretly trying to improve it,
building me up
only to knock me down.
That is crazy.
Just relax
and enjoy your progress.
Enjoy the progress, huh?
That's exactly what
Chase would say!
- What?! Ah!
- Show yourself, you beautiful genius!
- Max!
- I'll tear this face off!
All righty.
Max, I'm not Chase!
(Exhales deeply) My bad, Jane.
- Full disclosh, though?
- Yeah?
Not the first time
I thought you were a dude.
Aw. Thank you.
(Clattering)
- Oh!
- Okay. (Sighs)
Today is the last day
that Alex's dolphin groupon
is available.
All we have to do is make sure
she doesn't finish the others.
- Exactly. - So you, Alex, and Brad are
supposed to go to dinner tonight
at that new barbecue joint,
except you're not
because you and I are gonna--
Throw the phones
through the window,
covering their pulled pork with
shattered glass and phones.
What? No. No, we're gonna call
and make so many reservations
that you guys can't get in.
But you are overlooking
one very obvious detail--
the restaurant is gonna
recognize our number.
That's why I got
all these burners, baby.
To throw at the reservation guy
to distract him. Yes!
- No! No! You fool, no!
- Oh.
We call from 40 different phones
using 40 different personas.
Here are yours.
Uh, Southern lawyer?
(Imitates Southern accent)
"I do declare."
Nantucket housewife.
"Uh, white wine spritzer,
please?"
Julian Assange?
Is that the Wikileaks guy?
- I can't do him.
- You want me to do him?
Whatever. Just honor the spirit
of the characters.
But don't forget
to have fun out there, okay?
(Mouths word)
- Now your first character is Alex.
- Mm.
Call the restaurant as her
and cancel the reservation.
(Whispers) Okay.
(Whines) Oh, I don't know
if I can do this.
(Whispers) You got this.
You got this. You got this.
(Deep voice)
Hey, I'm Alex Kerkovich.
I'm short and I love ribs.
Do you know anything about Alex
or how reservations work?
(Lowered voice)
This is what she sounds like!
(Deep voice) I need to cancel
a reservation.
Uh... fantastic. Thank you.
(Beep)
(Normal voice) We're screwed.
She has been there already
and used all three
ribs groupons herself.
God, we should've known.
Breakfast ribs are her favorite.
Damn, damn, damn!
Wait. Why do you care so much?
I... it's just a bet.
Because I care about Alex,
and I'm trying
to help her grow up
and be more responsible
with her money.
What's the real reason?
I have a paralyzing fear
of dolphins--
as in, when I'm near them...
I lose my poop.
Now come on.
There's only one groupon left,
and it's
the military obstacle course
- at the Major Fitness Boot Camp.
(Whispers) - Okay.
If she does this, I lose,
all right?
- So we gotta stop her.
- Okay.
Why dolphins?
They seem so sweet.
Let's just say they understand
a lot of things,
but "no" isn't one of them.
(Door opens)
Hey, Max.
(Muzak playing)
- How's the new job?
- Great.
Actually, too great.
This morning, I got approved
for a credit card,
my teeth stopped burning.
There's no way Chase is not
behind all this.
Max, that is just normal stuff
that happens to pretty much
everyone every day. (Woman gasping)
(Speaks indistinctly)
Oh, my God. She's choking!
(Continues gasping) Kevin!
- I don't know what to do!
- Do I have to do everything?!
Okay, ready? Here we go.
Heimlich on three.
One, two, three!
(Inhales deeply) - Oh!
- Oh! Oh!
All right.
(Applause)
Wow.
- It's great!
- No, it's not.
Chase knows that
I've been learning CPR.
(Groans) He is behind
everything that's happening.
It's a coincidence.
Thank you so much.
I'm a reporter for WLS Chicago,
and you've gotta let me
do a story about you.
You're a real hero.
- Yeah, it's Chase.
(Loudly) Welcome to
the Major Fitness Boot Camp!
We have a groupon to use
the military obstacle course.
Yep. Can't wait.
Let's do this.
- Sorry, it's closed!
- Oh.
The course is flooded.
It's super yucky, ma'am.
Welp, I guess the only obstacle
left for us to overcome
is disappointment.
That's it?
(Sighs)
I lose?
I'm sorry!
Do you have to yell everything?
I'm yelling on account
of my injury!
Of course.
You lost your hearing in combat.
Well, we appreciate
the sacrifice you've made
- to preserve our freedom.
- No!
I busted my eardrums using
that ear genie ear wax remover
you buy on TV!
Stay away from them!
(Keys jangle)
Well, well, well.
Penny told me you didn't finish
the obstacle course.
So it looks like
instead of swimming
in a tank with dolphins,
I'll be soaking in our tub
with a well-worn copy
of "The Time Traveler's Wife."
Yeah, you won. I lost.
You're right.
I make terrible decisions.
I'm an impulsive idiot.
Oh, honey, come on.
I wouldn't say "idiot."
Really? The cotton candy maker
I bought on the way home
might disagree with you.
It doesn't actually talk.
Those were, like, $200 more.
Hey, listen.
Don't beat yourself up over it.
I love cotton candy, too.
Well, I am returning it,
'cause it's time for me
to get my head out of the clouds
and stop eating food
that looks like clouds.
Cauliflower is healthy,
and it looks like clouds.
Now I'm confused...
and hungry.
(Automated male voice)
Would you care
for some delicious,
fluffy cotton candy?
I lied. I did spend
the extra $200.
And it was... (Whispers) $300.
_
Chase is doing
some dang old good work.
A tip of the ol' James hat
to him.
But I am not gonna give him
the satisfaction
of destroying my life.
No, sir.
I'm gonna do that myself.
(Sighs deeply)
You're sure you wanna do this?
Yeah.
Breaks my heart, but okay.
(Sighs) (Whirs)
You do have a full-time job,
right?
♪ Simply irresistible ♪
There we go. Get it.
♪ she's so fine, there's no
telling where the money went ♪
♪ simply irresistible,
she's all mine ♪
♪ there's no other way to go ♪
♪ simply irresistible ♪
(Clink)
Well, you're pretty much right
back to where you started--
human pastrami.
It's not good enough, Jane.
You gotta take me
to negative 5,
make sure Chase stays away
for good.
But there's nothing left
to destroy.
I mean, all you really have
left is your health.
Okay. Take it. Hit me.
No, I'm not gonna hit you.
Jane, you ankles are fat.
(Laughs)
Yeah. I'm not falling
for that.
Jane, your bundt cake is
on the wrong side of moist.
(Laughs) That is ridiculous.
At times,
you're woefully unprepared.
- Uhh!
- Ohh!
Oh!
(Thud) (Sighs)
This is the first time I've ever
been attracted to a woman.
(Sniffs)
I wanna put a baby in you.
So what'd you guys do,
bring me here to gloat?
(Sighs) Alex...
I have a confession to make.
Penny and I engaged in
the French art of sabotage.
(Gasps)
- We flooded the course
so you couldn't do it. - What?!
I can't believe you guys.
I didn't want a laser
shot at my eyes.
I don't think that's
an unreasonable position.
But then, Alex, I saw you
with that cotton candy machine,
and I realized that I love
that you're impulsive
and you do those kinds
of things.
That's what makes you, you.
Aw! Yeah, it is.
It's great.
We really complement each other.
I mean,
you're the impulsive one,
and I'm the grounded one
that thinks things through.
No. No. No, no, no, no.
- You're not grounded in the least.
- No. No. (Chuckles) No!
- Super impulsive.
- No. Yes.
How am I impulsive?
When you saw "Munich,"
you tried to get Bar Mitzvah'd.
You bought a time-share in Tampa
next to Alex's.
You bought
40 burner cell phones
to make 40 untraceable
dinner reservations.
- You have the facial hair you have.
- Eh!
Okay, I get it! I get it.
Leave the goatee out of it.
- It's hard to leave it out.
- Really hard.
You know what? (Sighs)
Maybe two impulsive people
can work in a relationship.
Hey, it works
for Ice and Coco T.
Sure as hell does.
Here's the dolphin groupon.
(Gasps)
But before I give it to you,
you have to do
the obstacle course.
But it's closed.
So let's be impulsive.
Hmm.
(Laughs)
(Heroic fanfare playing)
♪
Aah! Uhh.
Uhh!
♪
Aah!
Perhaps there's a downside
to having two impulsive people
in a relationship.
Someone should warn
Ice and Coco T.
I don't think you guys should be
left alone without supervision.
Yeah, it's like all of a sudden
we're parents to
two 30-year-old dum-dums.
(Max) Three.
Max, again, I am so, so sorry.
It's okay.
You did good, baby.
Chase can't hurt us anymore.
(Chase) Max, is that you?
(Curtain rings swoosh)
(Max) Chase?
What are you doing here?
After we spoke on the street,
I slipped on that slice of pizza
you dropped and I hit my head.
I've been unconscious
for three days.
Unconscious?
So then it couldn't have
been you building my life up
only to knock it down.
(Inhales sharply)
First of all, I'm fine.
Thanks for asking.
(Whispers) - I didn't ask.
- Secondly, no, I wasn't.
But I'm so glad you're here
because I wanna
tell you something.
I don't know where you fall in
the existence of an afterlife,
but I'm here to tell you
there is another place.
It's a spiritual realm ruled
by powerful yet merciful beings.
I was there, Max,
and I was headed
for sweet eternal peace.
But then I realized I could not
transcend to the next plane
until I took care
of the unfinished business
of this world--
the unfinished business
of ruining your life.
It was you.
I came back for you.
I have looked deep into
the abyss of the next world,
and it is beautiful.
But before I make
that pilgrimage,
I will stop at nothing
to lay waste
to what you so tragically call
your life.
Wow.
That guy is still so cool.
That was perfectly timed
with his exit.
Do you think he rehearsed that
with the nurses beforehand?
You know, Max, the good news is
that now we know you have
the ability to improve your life
all... by... yourself.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
And I would be more than happy
to help you.
Because if you put your mind
to it,
you could achieve things
you only dreamed of.
So what do you say?
It sounds like a lot of work.
Hard pass.
(Voice breaks) Yeah,
that's okay. I understand.
- Well, I gotta go, buddy. Take care.
- Bye, everybody.
Ugh. I got passed up
for another promotion at work.
I really need to change
some things in my life.
(Squeals)
(Whirs)
You know, on second thought,
why should I even doubt myself?
I mean, I don't even want
that job anyways. (Whirs)
Yeah. Yeah.
So, Alex, are you going to that
dolphin thing with Dave today?
Oh, no.
(Dolphin chirping)
I can do this. I can do this.
(Breathes deeply)
(Chirps and squeaks)
Oh, no. No way.
I know what you guys want,
and you're not gettin' it!
(Dolphin squeals)
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com