[PLAYS HARMONICA]
[MIMICS BATMAN] Cheers.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] Bitterman?
Why are you shaving?
Because Robin doesn't have a beard.
Bitterman, we're only doing this
for a bit of a laugh.
We're not genuine crime fighters, are we?
And if we were, you would not be
my first choice of sidekick.
Look at your shoes.
They're your chauffeur shoes, aren't they?
I can see your tummy.
Mr. Bach, are you sure you wanna go
to your mother's fundraiser like this?
I think it's black-tie.
This is black.
Just that Hobson said
not to get into any trouble.
What trouble could possibly come
from a harmless game of dress-up?
Hmm?
Already bought the car.
[SIRENS WAILING]
You think they're chasing us?
Don't be ridiculous, this is the Batmobile.
We're their friends.
OFFICER [OVER SPEAKER]:
Driver, pull the car over.
How do you slow down?
- Where are the brakes on this thing?
ARTHUR: What do you suppose this does?
[BOTH YELLING]
ARTHUR: Oh!
BITTERMAN: Ow!
BITTERMAN: Ask the police for directions
to your mother's fundraiser.
ARTHUR: I think that problem
has been recently superseded.
BITTERMAN: Tell them it's at a museum.
ARTHUR: We destroyed a beloved landmark.
BITTERMAN:
It's around here somewhere.
ARTHUR:
I need you to not to talk for a little while.
Good evening, officers.
What seems to be the problem?
You're drunk again, Arthur.
No. I have remained drunk
since our last encounter.
Let's go. Batman and Robin,
out of the car. Come on.
Could I just point out
the elephant in the room?
Are these testicles strictly necessary?
They're an accident waiting to happen.
Okay, let's go. Come on.
See, I don't like being this close
to these balls.
I'll be right with you.
[ARTHUR GRUNTS]
Gotham is safe.
Oh, man.
If I could just write you a check
for the damage to your golden cow...
...we can all be about our business.
Say no more.
- Or not. Turn around. Come on.
ARTHUR: What's it...?
- Are we going to prison?
OFFICER: Yes.
We're going to prison.
We're going to prison, Bitterman.
BITTERMAN: Yes.
- I knew this day would come and it's today.
CHANCELLOR:
That's all well and good...
...but it's not a market crash
we're concerned about.
Your concerns are legitimate, chancellor.
[SUSAN SIGHS
AND CELL PHONE BEEPS]
VIVIENNE: I do assure you that Arthur's
a bit more serious these days.
- He's begun to take an interest in finance.
- Wonderful.
[CHANCELLOR CHUCKLES]
- Could you excuse us?
- Sure.
I'm sorry, Vivienne. The university
cannot wager its endowment...
...on a fund
with such an uncertain future.
[CELL PHONES RINGING]
[MURMURING]
He's like a ship without an anchor.
Maybe it's time we tied him
to another ship.
[CHEERING AND SHOUTING]
[ARTHUR CHUCKLES]
Tito! Tito, I'll see you at the cockfight.
Better be what I think it is.
Wow, you paid for everyone's release?
It seemed unfair that we'd leave
and that they'd remain.
How do you explain
this frivolous spending during a recession?
Fair point.
Uh, recession...
Free money!
[CHEERING]
This is yours.
Okay, recession's over! We're in a boom!
[OPERA MUSIC PLAYING]
[GRUNTS]
[ARTHUR & TIFFANY
CONVERSING INDISTINCTLY]
ARTHUR: That was brave.
What incredible flexibility.
[GASPS]
- Hello, Hobson.
- Morning, Arthur. And friend.
Tiffany.
Oh, points for knowing her name
and saying it with confidence.
I made a mental association
with my lamp.
Tiffany, this is my nanny, Hobson,
my best friend in the whole world.
- Your nanny?
- He's merely shaped like an adult.
So how are you feeling
on the other side of...
...that vast moat of champagne
called "last night"?
Splendid.
Your mother called.
She wants to see you this morning.
Vivienne? Why do you think
Vivienne wants to see me today?
It doesn't make sense.
HOBSON: After destroying
a world-famous landmark...
...and giving away $78,000
from an ATM, I can't imagine.
- Is she gonna stay here?
HOBSON: Um...
...I wouldn't recommend letting him
get used to your breasts, dear.
He's got an addictive personality,
you know. He was at mine till he was 6.
Hobson.
I had to dab Tabasco on the nipples
to see him off.
- That lady has never once breast-fed me.
- Despite his best efforts.
Hey, that's my purse.
ARTHUR:
Oh.
Look, I don't know how that
got in there. I don't know, Arthur.
It's probably just one of those mysteries
that will never be discovered.
JFK, who nicked my watch.
- Oh, that's actually mine.
- Bravo, well done.
Something of yours in your handbag.
No, you don't have to
go through the pictures, actually.
HOBSON: Arthur.
ARTHUR: Oh, don't worry about all that.
TIFFANY:
That's very rude. Invasion of privacy.
[TIFFANY GRUNTS]
Oh, you're leaving?
I support your decision 100 percent.
Will you be requiring a taxi
or just getting into a random passing car?
You guys are weird and racist.
ARTHUR:
Bye-bye, Tiffany.
I'll call you,
if you've not stolen my phone.
Help yourself to that priceless sculpture
on your way out the door.
Put it down.
Say goodbye
to your other new friends now, Arthur.
They have to go back to the real world.
Oh, I hate the real world, Hobson. I'll work
from bed today if you don't mind.
Hobson.
Breakfast, now.
Here.
[ARTHUR SIGHS]
ARTHUR:
Hobson!
Hobson?
Hobson! Hobson! Hobson!
- Hobson! Hobson!
- What?
Lesbian Simon and Garfunkel,
61st and Park.
Look.
Hmm. Well spotted.
Another of your wasted talents.
Wash your winkie. Thoroughly.
Heaven knows what exotic wildlife
that girl was harboring between her thighs.
Whoa, Hobson. You're missing Asian you.
ARTHUR: Ah! You're going too quickly.
You're pushing it too hard.
- I don't like it here, Hobson.
- Course you don't. People work here.
But there's an elevator.
You get to press the buttons.
Silver lining.
[ARTHUR CLICKING TONGUE]
RECEPTIONIST:
Mr. Bach?
Your mother will see you now.
Don't worry, Arthur, it won't take long.
Then we'll watch cartoons.
Hello, Arthur.
Oh, hello, Susan.
I didn't see you there coming down this
long, brightly-lit, unobstructed corridor...
...walking straight towards me.
I owe you a call, don't I?
From January.
We dated three months.
You just disappeared.
When Houdini did it, it was fun.
Hmm.
Houdini was a conjurer.
He used to disappear.
- I understood the reference.
- I just thought it deserved more.
You know, you're the only man
I ever slept with who broke up with me.
- Really?
- Really.
Well, call me a romantic...
...but I believe
that dating should involve crazy things...
...like talking.
- Oh, ha, ha.
- What are we gonna do with you, Arthur?
- Release me into the wild.
Hunt me down with dogs.
Good luck with your mother.
[SUSAN CHUCKLES]
VIVIENNE [OVER SPEAKER]:
Come in, Arthur.
Oh, hello. The future's now.
Hello, Vivienne. I remember you
from when I used to live in your womb.
Arthur.
Well, today, Arthur,
we're gonna have a friendly chat.
Then a serious talk.
And finally,
I'm going to offer you an ultimatum.
How does all that sound?
Like it would be improved by vodka.
So I hear you've been having fun.
Quite the contrary, actually.
I've been rather busy.
I've got a riding boot shoot and, uh,
I had a bit of a scare with Bitterman.
Thought he'd found a lump. Turned out
it was just his phone in his back pocket.
But worrying time nonetheless.
[SIGHS]
Well, that went very well.
Surprisingly warm. Our best chat yet.
I'm aware that our relationship
has never been ideal.
ARTHUR:
Mm...
No, please. Don't reproach yourself.
Yes, motherhood wasn't your forte...
...but you did provide me with
that lovable cloth monkey as a surrogate.
You know, sometimes I'm glad he's gone.
I'm gonna assume you mean Father
and not Mr. Tickles.
So that he never had to see this.
In fairness,
those two told me they were over 18.
And that they weren't men.
It's terrible the way you find out.
Who is this lovable rogue who's rough
around the edges, but with stars in his eyes?
What forgivable antics.
Who could be anything other than charmed
by this delightful individual?
- Congratulations.
- How can you squander...
...your considerable intelligence
on idiocy like this?
It's quite easy.
I don't consider it to be idiocy...
...rather a savantish gift
for defying death with fun.
That's your justification?
That's why you crashed a Batmobile?
Yes, it is. Are we done?
Sit down.
When the sole heir of a corporation as big
as ours gets arrested, it frightens investors.
The nonsense has to stop.
As the charming, coffee-colored gentleman
who runs this country said...
...the time has come
to set aside childish things.
I don't think
you can say "coffee-colored."
So I've arrived at a solution.
- Susan Johnson.
- Interesting.
Dresses well.
Borderline personality disorder.
How is that a solution?
You're going to marry her, Arthur.
- Why?
- Susan is a very impressive woman.
Lovely, yes.
She's certainly in control of that beast.
Capable woman, and quite willing to help
poor people if there's a camera nearby.
Actually, if you want videos of Susan,
you should come to my apartment.
- I've got one that'll knock your socks off.
- Bach Worldwide has been run...
...by a Bach for generations.
With Susan as one of us...
...investors will be comforted to know the
line of succession doesn't end in a bottle.
When did you become so cynical?
Marriage isn't a tool
to protect a corporate image.
It's to validate unwanted pregnancy.
If that's how you feel, Arthur,
you give me no choice.
As of this moment, you are cut off.
What do you mean "cut off"?
Cut off from you and the?
You don't mean cut off from the?
The money, Arthur.
No. I'm not gonna allow you
to manipulate me, Vivienne.
I shall get married when I fall in love.
I respect your integrity.
You've just lost $950 million.
Actually, Susan is a very special girl,
isn't she?
With that mouth,
that velvety, beautiful mouth...
...like a clown's mouth.
But not in a bad way.
Like a sexy clown.
And she'll make a wonderful wife.
Yeah. I mean,
who wouldn't wanna marry a sexy clown?
Congratulations, Vivienne. You win.
I don't respect you, Arthur...
...but I do applaud your talent
for self-preservation.
Congratulations. You're gonna be
a wealthy man for the rest of your life.
That's all I've ever wanted to be.
The ring your father
gave your mother, I believe.
[ARTHUR SIGHS]
It's like an ice rink for a mouse.
I don't like Susan.
Well, I don't like you very much and we've
been happily stuck together for 30 years.
I know it's not perfect,
but Susan is smart and capable...
...and you need a woman like that
to look after you.
I think I already have one of those.
In fact, do you want it?
Hobson, will you carry on
being my nanny?
This is just my mother
trying to control me.
Hey, Hobson, do you have the checkbook?
I wanna squander some wealth.
AUCTIONEER: Ten thousand dollars
for this item from the czar's collection.
Are we all done at 10,000? Ten thousand
dollars going once, going twice.
Twenty thousand dollars of money!
Twenty thousand dollars is the bid.
Thank you, sir. Do I hear 30?
Do I hear 30,000?
[IN DEEP VOICE]
Thirty thousand dollars, please.
AUCTIONEER:
Thirty thousand.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Thirty-five thousand.
[ALTERNATING VOICES] How dare you.
It's a challenge you want, is it?
Yeah, I want a challenge, plus I bid first.
That is irrelevant.
The highest number has supremacy.
You've clearly never been to an auction.
That's tit for tat.
That's exactly how the situation
in the Middle East began.
You leave me no choice.
One hundred thousand dollars
and one penny...
...because you, sir, are a vile spendthrift.
Well, that's the first sensible thing
you've said all day.
Sold to one of the Mr. Bachs
for $100,000 and one penny.
- Thank you, sirs.
HOBSON: Congratulations.
Hey, come on, Hobson.
You know I've always coveted
the cutlery of Czar Nicholas II.
- Me too.
ARTHUR: Oh.
Our last item up for bid today:
The suit in which Abraham Lincoln
delivered his second inaugural address.
Let's start the bidding at 50,000.
Do I hear 50,000?
[IN DEEP VOICE] I'll take it.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] And the teleportation
device in which it stands.
If you think this represents a victory
over your mother's financial tyranny...
...you're deluded.
- Thanks for the spoon, Arthur.
- Anytime. Buy me a fork one day.
- Where's Bitterman with the car?
He said he was gonna be
by the big gray thing.
- Where?
- He said...
...the big gray sculpture thing
with things on it.
It was like a riddle.
He can be very vague.
It's the blind leading the drunk.
ARTHUR: Hobson, you find Bitterman
while I wander off.
Wow.
What is this for?
Where's everyone going?
NAOMI: This is actually not Grand Central
Station, it's Grand Central Terminal.
- Oh.
- Oh!
- Sorry.
- No, no, I was static in a thoroughfare.
Uh, I'm lost. Do you know where I can get
a drink, please?
Um...
This is really all I have.
Good luck.
- Come on.
- Coins.
- I played with these when I was a boy.
NAOMI: Let's keep going. Time's a wasting.
Speaking of time...
...the clock behind me is one of the
most expensive clocks in the world.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
NAOMI: Thousands of people
pass through here every day...
...and no one ever bothers to look up.
It's magical. It's the only place
in Manhattan where you can see the stars.
But it wasn't always that way...
Oh, you again.
If you look in the corner you can see
one dirty brick...
...and the whole ceiling used to be
like that until it was renovated in 1998.
Wow, this is brilliant. If you like ceilings,
I've got a beautiful one above my bed.
[NAOMI SCOFFS]
That sounded cheeky.
I didn't mean that. It lights up.
Thanks for that.
If you direct your attention to the
opposite corner, you'll see a...
...police officer.
- Miss, I warned you about this.
You don't have a tour license
and now you're impeding foot traffic.
Come on, up, up, everybody up.
Officer, which law prevents
this radiant stranger...
...from finding the magical
in the mundane?
- MTA Code 1085.1, Section 5.
- Could you be more specific?
OFFICER: Hey. Hey!
- Oh, there's a chase. We're in a chase.
Sir, grab my Lincoln stick.
Chase!
My mind is racing. My heart is pounding.
This is my first chase, and I love it.
- Let me through, I'm a free spirit!
OFFICER: West on 42nd.
This is what I live for!
OFFICER:
We've got a runner.
ARTHUR: A chase is happening!
This is a genuine chase!
Oh! I'm... I...
- No, no, no.
- I was gonna go get my license.
You ran from me, Naomi.
Now I gotta take you in.
Besides, you've had three warnings
for operating an illegal tour.
Except this isn't an illegal tour...
...because these people aren't tourists,
they're our family.
Yes. They are, they're my family.
That's my family.
We're having a family reunion.
Reunion. Uh, that, for example,
is Uncle Stuart waving there.
NAOMI:
Yes. Oh, hey, Uncle Stuart.
Under that sun hat,
that's Caribbean Diane Keaton.
- Yes, exactly.
- And also we have...
NAOMI:
Uncle Korean John Lennon.
And this is, uh, Abe Lincoln, I presume.
- Oh, no.
ARTHUR: No.
- He is my admittedly eccentric...
- Fiancé. I'm her fiancé.
He is my fiancé.
NAOMI:
Oh. Mm-hm.
Darling, you don't want
these people to think...
...that you're some kind of
random British pervert.
No, I'm a very specific British pervert,
which is why you fell in love with me...
...from our first date.
- Which was where, exactly?
Grand Central.
You had your first date
at Grand Central Station.
It wasn't a shabby affair. I'd hired
out the entire place. It was deserted.
Acrobats were in the place,
put on quite a show for us.
- Didn't they, Naomi?
- No, no.
The floor was strewn
with a million petals.
Their scent hung in the air
like the sweet breath of angels.
And we forgot ourselves entirely.
Didn't we?
And ran nude through that concourse.
No, no, we just...
We had clothes on and we ate.
- What'd you eat?
NAOMI: Oh.
Oh, what was that?
NAOMI: Pe...
ARTHUR: Pe... Pe... Pe...
[BOTH]
PEZ.
Have any identification, Mr. Lincoln?
ARTHUR:
Actually, I do.
Um, here you go. I think you'll find that
should do the trick.
There's plenty more where that
came from, if you catch my drift, hmm?
Ah. You keep it, Arthur,
and thank you for the show.
[ARTHUR CHUCKLES]
- Naomi, get a license. Good luck.
NAOMI: Okay.
What was that? Who are you?
I'm just a ragged-trousered stranger
with a crazy hat.
Oh, my God.
Arthur, your safari into the pointless
ends now. Get in the car.
No. It's okay.
Uh, Hobson can't tell me what to do.
Yes, I can. I work for his mother.
Get in the car. Bitterman, open the door.
ARTHUR: Bitterman, close that door.
- Get in the car.
- Not you, Bitterman.
ARTHUR: Yes, you, Bitterman.
I'm sorry. Who are you people?
I'm his nanny.
I'm not, I'm Bitterman.
Well, I have to get back to our confused
family over there, so have a nice day.
ARTHUR:
Oh, hang... Uh, excuse me.
Naomi Quinn,
I'd like to see you again.
- I don't date boys who have nannies.
HOBSON: Very wise choice.
You're not the first woman
who walks the streets for a living...
...that he's taken a liking to.
Is she always with you?
Okay. 917-176-2030.
- Uh... Did you remember that?
- No.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
Arthur, get in the car.
I'm gonna get in the car now, but because
I want to, not because you have told me to.
Distinction.
Bitterman.
ARTHUR: It was magical. We ran
from the police, then we lied to them.
- Have you ever had days like that, Evander?
EVANDER: I believe I have.
Me and this girl are two perfectly matched
opponents, like you and Mike Tyson.
- She could be the one.
ARTHUR: Yes.
Oh. I'm so sorry. That went
right through your guard.
- Are you okay?
- I'll make it.
What I like about her, Naomi...
...is she's got a very unique way
of seeing the world.
So do flies.
This is a repeat of when you were certain
you needed a pet giraffe to be happy.
- Well, you were bored after a week.
- Because he ate his monocle.
The brute had no regard
for fashion, Evander.
No, because you were from two
different worlds, the same as this girl.
Listen, could you just let me focus
on my jab and refresh me, please?
- Aah! That's vodka in there.
- Refreshed?
No, but I think some of it probably went
in my bloodstream so it's not all bad news.
- Get dressed.
- Why?
Because at 3:00
you're going to ask Burt Johnson...
...for his daughter's hand in marriage.
I will do no such thing. I'm going to
remain here and box with Evander.
And then I shall have my music lesson
with Kanye West as planned.
Out, now.
Make me.
I'll just have a bit of fun with her.
Use the old rope-a-dope,
I should think.
- Stick and move, like you taught me.
- Arthur, after you're married...
...you're going to have to stop this
obsession with random women.
She is not a random woman,
she understands me.
She laughs at my jokes. She's like you, but
with a more appropriate potential for sex.
[ARTHUR YELLS]
Ow! That really hurt. Evander,
you assured me I was indestructible.
Burt Johnson, 3:00.
Evander, if he's not out of this ring
in one minute, I'll bite your other ear off.
What am I doing here, Bitterman?
Uh, you asked me to drive you
to the Burt Johnson Tower.
- But if you were me...
- I would like that very much.
That's very flattering.
But if you were me
and you were in this situation...
...what would you do? What should I say?
Uh, I'd go in there and say, um,
"Mr. Johnson, I like your tower.
But I love your daughter."
- But I don't love his daughter.
- Don't say that, because then he'll say no.
You've been very helpful.
Put this on. Wait here.
It's the same as your one.
"BJ," I'll never get tired of that.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[LOCK CLICKS]
Woo-hoo, Bitterman!
[AIR HISSES]
Bloody hell.
It's an apocalyptic future.
The Upper East Side lay
in absolute ruin.
The machines have taken over, as usual.
Ah, malevolent toaster.
Only one man can save civilization.
And that man is Arthur Bach.
Justice!
Hello, Arthur.
- Uh, sorry, I've never used...
- Never used what, Arthur?
One of these guns what makes nails
come out of it.
Oh, the Grip-Rite GR 350.
It's a good gun.
It's lovely, isn't it?
It's also one of my favorites.
Do you know you've got nails sticking
in you?
Framing nails.
Standard.
Well, I love what
you've done with the place, Burt.
It reminds me of a gay club
I went to once in Copenhagen.
This is gonna be my new office.
Oh, my God. I live right over there.
I can see my living room, Burt.
That's interesting.
And frightening.
Did you put this building here just
so you can spy on me?
BURT:
Mm-hm.
Shouldn't you be getting
to the hospital?
If I ran off to the hospital every
time I got a little boo-boo...
Yeah. What's a nail through the body?
Made a hero out of Jesus.
Uh, Burt, I'm starting to feel
a bit queasy.
Let's cut the bullshit, Arthur.
I'm from Pittsburgh...
...and now I own skyscrapers.
Unlike you, I wasn't given my billions.
I took them.
But you know...
...I'm actually fine
with my little girl marrying you.
Do you know why?
Because you've lost a lot of blood
and you're disoriented?
My little Susan can turn you around.
You know, she once bought a crack house
and turned it into a condo.
That's funny,
I once did the exact opposite.
Now, you listen to me carefully. I need
to trust that you'll do what she says.
- Yes.
- Table saw.
[WHIRRING]
Most dangerous piece of equipment
on a job site.
Hands five inches on either
side of the blade and you'll be fine.
- No, I don't like things like this.
- Come on. You can do it.
No... Just, uh... Just push it through.
I did it, Burt! I did a man thing!
That was incredible.
- Let's saw something else in half.
- How about your finger?
My finger?
It's okay, the saw has a safety
device. It detects moisture.
Anything containing moisture touches
that blade, and bam, it'll stop.
That sounds a little bit risky
to me, Burt.
Use your tongue.
- My tongue?
- Plenty of moisture in your tongue.
Oh, no. I don't think
I should do that, Burt.
I think I'd like to go back over there
now to house.
- No, Burt! What are you doing?
- Lick the saw!
No, Burt.
You've taken leave of your senses.
You need to stick out your tongue
or it won't sense the moisture.
[ARTHUR YELLS]
I want my nanny.
Mr. Johnson,
a very wise man once said:
"I like your tower,
but I love your daughter."
Can I marry her, please?
Sure.
[GULPS]
SUSAN: Pascal, I'm gonna have the veal.
WAITER: Excellent choice.
Could you tell Jerome, please,
that it was a little dry last time?
WAITER: I will see to it.
- Thank you.
WAITER: For you, sir?
- Just a caldron of tequila and a spoon.
I hear you have something to ask me.
Yeah, I do, as a matter of fact, Susan.
Would you mind telling me what
the bloody hell's been going on?
We're having a magical night.
I don't understand.
You don't understand
that there's a macabre conspiracy...
...to inveigle me into a loveless marriage.
Susan, we...
- "Loveless marriage."
- We should not get married.
We don't have anything in common,
do we?
I mean, we don't like the same food.
Veal? I think that's really cruel.
Do you like it because it's cruel?
We don't like the same people, music.
You love horses.
- I do.
ARTHUR: I don't trust them.
SUSAN: Think about this.
- Their eyes, their sneaky feet.
- This is a business... Stay with me.
- Their shoes are permanent.
SUSAN: All you have to do...
- Who makes that commitment to a shoe?
- Most marriages devolve eventually.
- Mean faces.
[MIMICS HORSE WHINNYING]
This is all it is,
it's a business partnership.
With the added benefit of attraction.
Undeniably, you have got something
dark and twisted in you.
And for awhile,
I thought I might be able to bugger it out.
But I tried really hard
and I think it's still in there.
Reach into your pocket, pull out the ring,
and say four little words.
Okay. Uh, I don't love you.
Try again.
I like other girls.
- Oh, well, me too. Let's invite one over.
- I'll embarrass you. Daily.
For example, look, I'm quite capable
of this kind of conduct.
I've seen it before.
[GARGLES]
SUSAN:
All right. Yes.
That's just part of my repertoire.
By thunder, here's a pretty dame.
[WOMAN GRUNTS]
[PATRONS GASP]
There. Hmm? What do you think
about that? She's probably pregnant.
- Well done. Go on.
- Okay.
Where's the kitchen?
I'm going to the kitchen.
- Coming in the kitchen.
- Isn't he mad?
[CLANKING]
I'm a naughty robot.
- But I just love him.
ARTHUR: I've got tin titties.
This is what you're doing to me.
This is how I feel.
[CLEARS THROAT]
ARTHUR: I think this sausage is cooked.
- Pascal, drinks, for everyone.
I'll tell you what, it's a lot more fun
in that bloody kitchen.
Daddy did, uh, show you
his little table saw, didn't he?
Turn around and tell everyone you're
crazy when you're in love. Ready? Go.
I don't know why I did all of those things
just then. I go crazy when I'm in love.
[LAUGHING]
[WHISPERS]
Sit down. Great.
Help me. Help me.
Embarrassing me or your family
is the one thing that will not be tolerated.
- Is that clear?
- Yes, please.
Sweet boy, this can all be
a ton of fun if you let it.
Shall we try again?
On one knee. I'm just an old-fashioned girl.
Just go ahead.
ARTHUR:
Susan. Pfft.
- Are you sure about this?
- You're running from yourself, Arthur.
I wish I was,
because I'd let me get away.
Ask me. Ask me.
Have it. Go on.
Yes, Arthur.
Madames et monsieurs, the happy couple.
[APPLAUDING]
Ah!
Aspirin.
Give me the whole bottle.
My life's over.
You're gonna be looked after
and you're gonna stay fabulously rich.
Maybe I'd rather be fabulously poor.
Some poor people I see look really happy.
That's because they're far away
or you've given them money.
What do you know, Alfred?
Arthur, poor people have to work.
They have to stand in the rain waiting for
buses to take them to things called jobs...
...which they have to do all year round
for holidays away from those jobs.
Don't patronize me, Snobson.
I know what a jobs are.
I model riding boots, don't I?
Posing in riding boots for another pampered
prick is not a job. Now take your vitamin.
- I erased her number.
- Hobson, I have to see her.
We'll unravel
this engagement bollocks later.
Arthur, you made the choice.
An engagement is a promise.
Be a man.
[SPITS]
NAOMI: Continuing on,
this is Grand Central Terminal...
...and it is home to more
than 750,000 commuters a day.
Boring. What a tiresome fact that was.
Oh, ladies and gentlemen, this is a
classic New York architectural feature:
The man who takes your number
and then never calls you.
Ooh.
- I'm bored too.
- Yeah, he's bored, I'm bored...
...the whole tour is really bored.
Come on, liven it up, lady.
Okay, well, what about this:
See that clock up there?
See those statues?
That's Jupiter and Minerva
and Hercules.
When the clock strikes 12,
they reach down and they stop time.
And then they go out on the town. They go
swim in the Hudson and cavort at the zoo.
- Sometimes they even go to a strip club.
- Oh, okay.
Okay, guys,
that's the end of your tour. Um...
Your complimentary pretzel awaits.
It's only $5.
[CHUCKLES]
- Wow, you look really, really amazing.
- Okay.
- I've got something to show you.
- I don't...
We're on a tight schedule. Come.
- Okay.
- Stop thinking.
Um, Arthur, there are no people.
Where are the people?
The people have been rerouted
for 45 minutes by me for you.
It's sort of romantic, but in another way,
it's incredibly selfish of you.
Grand Central.
Rose petals.
Dinner. Oh, my God.
This is our first date.
Oh, is that what we said to the police
officer? I'd quite forgotten.
NAOMI:
Wait, I'm not getting naked.
Don't rule it out at this stage, it takes
some of the pizzazz out of the evening.
It's like we're the last people
on the planet.
Wow, this is amazing. Thank you.
- There's a waiter on that escalator.
- Shh.
NAOMI:
He's in formal attire.
- He's carrying a platter.
- Wait for it.
Excellent.
- Your dinner, madam.
NAOMI: Thank you.
PEZ.
These are us as PEZ heads? Ha, ha.
You're the cute one.
Well, the cuter one.
NAOMI:
Do you want me?
- Thank you.
- Ha, ha.
Hey, you know, as soon as I saw you...
...I knew I wanted to eat candy bricks
out of your neck hole.
You're not the first.
[ARTHUR CHUCKLES]
What do you think? Do you like it?
Well, on my last date...
...the guy told me that I could only
eat salad and then he said he was gay.
- This is better.
ARTHUR: Yeah.
I mean, I'm heterosexual, so...
Oh, already winning.
[LAUGHS]
Did you know that the zodiac
is painted on backwards?
It was a goof by the artist, but then the
Vanderbilts, who commissioned the place...
...said that it was God's view
of the heavens.
Trust the Vanderbilts to see the world
from God's perspective.
[SOFT CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
There's a woman jumping behind you.
Oh, yeah. I promised you acrobats.
[NAOMI LAUGHS]
NAOMI:
Arthur, this is... This is insane.
Yeah, this is what money is for.
Creating excitement and joy
and acrobats and PEZ heads and...
Italy.
- What?
- Let's go to Italy.
Okay, let's go.
When do you wanna go to Italy?
- Tonight. I'll charter a jet. Giuseppe, hi.
- I can't go to Italy with you tonight.
Excuse me.
- Naomi...
- Mm-hm?
...I'm talking about Tuscany.
White truffle gelato. Have you ever
tasted white truffle gelato?
It makes all other gelato
taste like shit.
Arthur, you emptied out
Grand Central Station.
Can't you just be here?
Can I show you something?
NAOMI: After we moved to New York
when I was 11...
...my mom used to bring me down here
all the time.
We'd take the train in from Queens.
This is the Whisper Wall.
It's a really special place.
Okay, you have to go in that corner,
and I'll be over here.
And say something.
What?
I don't know, anything.
Oh, you could call me up and ask me out,
like you failed to do.
Good idea.
[MIMICS PHONE RINGING]
Hello, this is Arthur.
Is Naomi there, please?
Yes, this is Naomi.
My God, that's amazing. You're over there,
but I can hear you perfectly over here.
- It's acoustics.
- Wow.
I'm gonna buy one of these.
You don't have to buy it, it's free.
Incredible.
I was just having a phone call,
so I've gotta go back.
Oh.
If you're, um, not too busy, would you like
to maybe go on a date with me?
[CHUCKLES]
NAOMI: Actually, I'm free right now
if you'd like to do something simple.
Food, my house?
[CHUCKLES]
What is this, please?
- Oh, this is, um, generic brand Saucy-Os.
- Saucy-Os.
Yeah. It's one of the few times the generic
brand's actually better than the real thing.
Something happens in the factory.
It's delicious.
Welcome to the life of humans.
It is the culinary success of the season.
[GLASS CLINKS]
- Mademoiselle, you are...
- Shh. Shh. Shh.
ARTHUR: What?
- My dad is asleep.
But your mum wears earplugs,
so we don't need to worry about her.
My mom doesn't wear anything anymore.
Naked. Sleeping au naturel.
She's dead.
I'm so sorry.
She died, um, last year.
It's really recent, and I made a joke about
your dead nude mum. I'm so sorry, Naomi.
- No, no, no, really, it's okay.
- I'm always doing things like that.
If it's any consolation,
my dad is similarly deceased.
I'm so sorry. Was that recent?
No, it was when I was a child,
so you've won that round, but, uh...
- Point, Naomi.
- Right, well done.
You're winning,
but it's not too late for me to run home...
...and butcher my mother
just to edge into the lead.
Uh, no. My dad died when I was a kid.
He was by all accounts a very
sensible, uh, frugal man...
...who didn't drink, didn't smoke,
walked everywhere.
NAOMI:
Hmm.
Dropped dead of a heart attack
when he was 44.
Lesson being,
why bother taking care of yourself?
- Cheers.
- I don't think that's the lesson.
- It's the lesson I learned.
- Cheers.
ARTHUR:
Mm.
[HUMS]
Ah.
No, thanks.
What were you like as a kid?
Well, ha, ha, aside from being
grief-stricken...
- Ha, ha, yes.
- I was kind of little...
...and I didn't drink so much then.
What about you?
Did you drink much as a child?
Strictly juice boxes.
- What a weirdo.
- I was a weirdo.
I thought that the moon
followed me everywhere.
I thought it meant something special
was gonna happen.
Well, that's a pretty
ridiculous hypotheses, Naomi...
...because by that notion,
the moon would be out there right n...
[CHUCKLES]
Naomi, the moon is literally out there
right now spying on us...
...his light shining down on your face
and clutter.
What is all these things?
[MUMBLES]
- My dad's pills.
- Hmm.
Got a lot of incriminating stuff lying
around in here young la... What's this for?
- That's nothing. That's...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
This is not nothing. This is something.
I used to write stories
and draw pictures for kids.
Ah.
Wow.
"The Statue of Liberty had traveled
all the way from France.
She missed her friend,
the Eiffel Tower, and her arm hurt."
- Naomi, that's wonderful.
- Thank you.
In this, the Statue of Liberty
is a lonely French giant.
Yeah. And she stays lonely until
she meets her friend, the Chrysler Building.
That's brilliant, Naomi.
You should quit your job
and focus all your energy on this.
- I can't.
- Why? What have you got to lose?
The house and electricity and...
You can pay for all those things
when this is published.
Arthur, things like that don't happen
to people like me.
Then why is the moon
still following you?
[TRAIN PASSING NEARBY]
But this doesn't wake your father?
- He's used to this.
- This could wake my father.
From his grave.
[NAOMI LAUGHS]
PHOTOGRAPHER:
Okay, lovely, but a little closer together.
SUSAN:
All right. Smile, Daddy, smile.
PHOTOGRAPHER: Okay, and now,
I'd love to see some more love.
[SUSAN CHUCKLES]
What is this?
Your engagement photo
for Town & Country.
How about a couple
of you and your mum?
Oh, all right, yeah. Okay.
All right.
ARTHUR: Vivienne?
VIVIENNE: Yes, Arthur?
If hypothetically...
...uh, I was to develop feelings
for a woman who isn't exactly Susan...
...kind of an un-Susan, an anti-Susan,
as it were...
...um, how would that make you feel,
hypothetically?
Hypothetically, I'd say congratulations.
But unfortunately,
the most magical relationships...
...will wilt in the midst
of grinding poverty.
Wonderful.
Arthur, how about a few of you...
...and your future father-in-law?
- What? No, no.
- Ha, ha. Hello, Burt.
BURT: Hello.
[ARTHUR GRUNTS]
I'll never get used to
that handshake.
Where were you last night, Arthur?
What? Just at home. Home.
You sure about that?
- Yes.
- My turn, Daddy.
- Oh, Jesus.
PHOTOGRAPHER: Oh, great.
This is for the cover shot.
I need the bride and the groom, please.
Get on the horse, Arthur.
I love animals, but I don't trust you.
Get on the horse.
You will not make me cry today.
For the riding boot shoots, we use
a stuffed horse or sometimes a girl.
- Maybe Daddy could help?
BURT: Yeah, let me help.
- No, it's all right, Burt.
- Help him up.
ARTHUR: You're a weak man, Burt. Burt.
No, Burt, you're... That doesn't help.
Ow! Oh, my God.
Burt, you're not qualified.
Aah! Ha, ha.
That was no trouble. That was no tr...
What a lot of fuss.
What a lot of fuss about nothing.
Okay, lovely.
Who is she, Arthur?
I don't know, I imagine she's called
Trixy or Rocket. Something like that.
Not the horse. The girl.
I don't know what you mean.
We'll be right back. Excuse us.
[HORSE NEIGHS]
ARTHUR:
Wha...? Aah! I didn't agree to this.
First your father, now the horse.
When will my testicles get some rest?
Delaying a hundred commuter trains
for a secret date wasn't the smartest move.
It was in The Times and the Post.
I must've hurt you with that. I understand
if you wanna cancel the wedding.
We're not gonna cancel the wedding.
It's happening as scheduled. End of story.
Are those gonna be your vows?
"To death do us part, as scheduled"?
Listen, Susan, is this about money?
I've got news for you, you're already rich.
I'm not you rich, Arthur.
My family doesn't have a coat of arms.
I'll draw you one. It's quite simple.
It's usually just a sword.
I hear them whisper at functions.
In their eyes, I'm just the daughter
of a contractor from Pittsburgh.
They sneer when I walk past.
That's probably just because
of who you are as a person.
[SCREAMS]
Bach Worldwide has been run
by a Bach for generations.
Susan Johnson-Bach will be in control
of one of the largest trusts in the world.
You're not gonna get in my way.
Say goodbye to your little girlfriend.
But Vivienne. Susienne. Satan. Susan.
I like this girl.
We connect, she and I.
She's spontaneous and...
I'm spontaneous.
Really? You planned to confront me
during a contrived photo shoot...
...wearing an outfit you selected
when you were a child.
Ow!
PHOTOGRAPHER:
Okay, lovebirds, are you ready?
Don't forget, it's all about the eyes.
Those happy eyes.
You embarrassed me.
Embarrass me again
and my father will cut off...
I know, my tongue.
No, your balls.
Not if I keep them moist.
Thoughts, Hobnobs?
I think you're engaged, and going out
with Naomi is a really bad idea.
Exactly.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Which is why I've invited her here.
HOBSON:
Arthur, think.
I have thinked. And that is why we're
all gonna hang out together.
I've never hung out in my life.
I'm not gonna start tonight.
Hobson, if you get to know this girl,
you're gonna love her.
Arthur, you must tell Naomi
you're getting married.
You don't think that might rather
mar the romance of the evening?
Hello, Arthur.
[YELLS]
- Hi, Hobson.
- Hello, Susan. How nice to see you.
Can you just give us one
little minute?
Yes, of course.
Thank you.
[ARTHUR GRUNTS]
ARTHUR:
Mm-mm.
- What was that?
- A French kiss.
Really? Because the French
always surrender.
That was decidedly German.
I was just at home
feeling spontaneous.
I decided to put on
a little something spontaneous...
...and come over here spontaneously.
Susan, mentally ill people are spontaneous.
It's all about context.
[CELL PHONE BEEPING]
Oh, good, this is happening now.
Shall we go to the bedroom?
- You're a bit drunk.
- Okay.
So you just, uh... You wait here. Oh, no.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Oh-ho. Lovely. That's come off.
- Um, I'm gonna get ice.
- What do you have in mind?
Uh, I imagine there'll be some injuries.
It'll reduce the swelling.
Hurry.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Naomi, I'm very happy to see you.
- You are?
ARTHUR: Um...
Naomi, I'm so glad you're here.
Um, did you kill Minnie Mouse
or did she surrender her dress willingly?
If it makes you feel better,
she didn't suffer.
Well, this is all very nice.
Come in, Naomi. Come in.
Now, I know we were gonna
have a night in...
- I can see why.
- But, actually, why don't we...?
- This is amazing.
- Uh, no. Um...
- That fish looks like a cat.
ARTHUR: Naomi. No, it doesn't.
NAOMI: Wow, bubblegum rocket.
- Don't look at that.
Now, tell me where the room
filled with buckets of gold is.
It's over here,
away from the bedroom, actually.
You have a glittery camel. Why?
They're 10 a penny in England.
Ignore that.
Naomi, let me give you a full tour of the
apartment while Arthur primps himself.
I'll be primping. I've gotta primp.
NAOMI: Oh, that's you.
- Yes, thank you.
Ah, Susan.
You're posing suggestively.
Do you like it, my fiancé?
Buckets of gold?
Broken lunar module.
Silly bugger drove it down the stairs.
Come through here. This should keep your
eyes off the valuables for a few minutes.
[CARTOONS PLAYING ON TV]
Get out.
Oh, I love Looney Tunes.
Are these always playing?
No, it, uh, alternates between this
and historical documentaries.
- Really?
- No. Just this.