- Who's dealt the last time, you or me?
...me, who else...
...one card for you......one card for me.
...three for you, one for me.
...four for me, one for you.
...five for me.
...shit cards
...you feel lucky, eh?
No more cards for you? Ah well, just asking...
...how many cards do you want?
Three...?
...one for me, one for you, one for me, one for you....
...you stand no chance...
...with cards like those...
...I'll show you...! You cretin...
My time has come!
(singing...): "My pack of beasts is one of a kind...."
- Dad!
...check out that ship, dad!
- Let's see those cards...
...I have three...
- Dad!
- Great hand!...
Interrupt me again and I'll smack you!
...you know I hate being interrupted!
- When I get married,
Will you buy me a truck like that?
- Three cards.
And you? Nothing to add? Bravo, bravo...
...and for you? Two cards...
- Dad, check out that machine!
- Lovely hand. Three Aces. Three lil' cards...
...Daaad, Promise, when I get married!
- Two Sevens.
- What a machine...
- Screw your machine!
- Dad, come here!
- I told you, not to interrupt
when I'm playing cards!
- Daddy likes you, and you don't give a shit about him...
keeps bloody interrupting....
- One for me, one for you, one for me, one for you....
...cards are like whores. They can get pretty addictive...
...who do you think I am?
I could as well bluff!
...gimme two more cards!
- Maxim Gorky is here! The Russians!
...look at this. Poker dammit, Poker!
Maradona!
- Hurry up, Zare!
- Oi, give my eggs back!
- How much for the horns, comrade?
- Ten marks.
- Look, I'll give you five.
- No way. Ten.
- Dad, what do you want with it?
- Shut up! I ain't stupid! It is secondary raw material.
- One horn for five marks. One million horns, five million marks. Isn't it, comrade?
- Sure.
- How much for the washing machine?
- 300 marks.
- Fine machine. Extra good.
- Comrade. Let me tell you something even better...
220 marks for the horns, the washing machine and the computer. Great deal, isn't it?
- No way. 280.
- 250.
- Sold.
- Take them.
- Should I help, Dad?
- It's all right.
- The other side!
- Careful, Dad!!
- The washing machine...!
- Hey!
- The Russians have fucking scammed us once again!
- Come, have a look.
- We got water, not Diesel!
- What?
- I'm sayin', water. Have a look.
- What the hell?
- That's Diesel all right!
- This is water!
- The barrels are full of water.
- Both barrels?
(music): "The cold rain falls at dawn..."
- Why is she wearing spy-glasses
and a grater, do you know?
- She's expectant!
- Well said, smart kid...
- Here's money for your surgery.
- Thanks, uncle Grga! God bless uncle Grga!
- This is too little!
- What the hell's wrong?
- Mother will have twins, the u'trasound has told us!
- Piss off, back into your gypsy mother and away from me!
- Gate, gate!
- Halt, what do you want?
- G'day.
- Who are you?
- I'm Matko Destanov.
- Hands up!
...hands up!
- Goose, come in!
- I was planning to
go to Hungary tonight.
...to the fair in Pécs.
- Go to the fair wherever you like,
but do buy yourself a fiancée! Understood?
(background): - All right, everyone get the fuck out!
- Hello, boss.
- Oh Little bird, you have returned?
- Me...? Back from where?
- You've been here before...5 years ago.
- Me? No.
- Don't lie to me!
- We have met indeed but you didn't live here at the time!
...big players like you relocate often!
- Eight years ago then.
- Eight? That's impossible.
...oh yes, yes, hats off! My compliments, uncle Grga!
- Look into my eyes.
- I am looking at them.
- Why are you here? And don't tell lies.
...I would do anything for your father.
...he saved my life twice.
- I know...
...in Genova, and in Marseille.
...he beat up half the city...to get me out of jail.
...he is a gentlemen.
- Was. May he rest in peace.
- Who should rest in peace?
- My father...haven't you heard?
...so unexpectedly...Would you have thought?
...I became an orphan...just like my little finger!
...unprotected...at everyone's mercy...
- I know that you lot ruined his life.
You swindlers, rotters, gangsters, vagabonds, thieves!
- Allright, allright, that didn't last too long! Everyone makes mistakes in life...
...but now I understand I was on the wrong path and have shown them the finger as the it's said...
...Uncle Grga, I have a bloody good business proposition!
- What kinda plan?
- A train.
- A train?
-A whole train.
...wagons loaded with gasoline.
- Gasoline?
- Twenty wagons altogether.
...but Uncle Grga, since my father died...
...I have nobody to help me.
- That's business for the big guys.
- They'll screw you.
You're a freshman.
- No, Uncle Grga. I've got it all
covered this time. No screwing over this time!
...I'll bring the paperwork, it's all here, clear as water.
....son! Son!
- You're lying again, aren't you?
- Don't come back without a wife!
- What are you up to now? You want to swindle him?
- Smile you dumbass.
- I received this urgent fax.
Everything's in there.
...all the details!
- Birdy! Come here. Come here.
- Goose, over...come in....goose...
- I'm here, uncle Grga. Everything's in the fax.
... I'd need 70,000 marks...
- What, boss?
- Goose, the labourers can go home.
And you too.
- All right, boss.
Let's have a break!
- If you loan me 70,000 within a
week I'll return you 100,000.
- Do you see that?
- I see it, uncle Grga. I see it.
...Uncle Grga, you sure have a lot of dosh.
- I'll help you, but only because of your father.
...and I fully expect you to report back to me all about this 'bloody lucrative business'
...or else I'll send my grandsons after you...
They'll skin you alive...
...and splinter your bones!
- Am I making myself clear?
- Very clear.
- Weirdo.
- Millions. Maradona.
- Why did you say that Granddad had died?
- He's in a hospital, or dead...
That's practically the same.
...he has a large cement factory
and never gave me a penny.
...Zare, my son. With this money
your daddy will ensure you have a future...
...and your children's future.
- Leave me be.
I'll never forgive you.
- Zare!
- What do you want now?
- Come son, take a look at this miracle!
- Now that's what I call an invention.
...only those Germans can
invent something like that.
...but your daddy promises you...
...if we become rich, he'll buy you a ship like that...
- Zare!
...Dadan...
...he's here! Our benefactor has arrived!
(music/singing...) "Pitbull.
Terrier...."
- Fortune favours the bold.
- Your mother....I keep you fed and this is how you thank me?!
- "The dice is cast."
- Welcome, my dear brother.
- Who is he?
- What the fuck do you care?
- I was only asking.
- Well shut the fuck up! Ehh...
- Ohhh fuck...
- So there's a God after all.
- What are you staring at? Stop staring. Chill out! Read something!
- Why did you come here?
- I'm sick of these thieves around...
- What are you waiting for?
Give the man something to drink. Quit fucking laming around...
- I've know of a lucrative plan.
- You?
- Trust me, it's 100% fail-safe.
...it's the plan of the millennium.
...I've got a connection in Jordan. He sells me a train full of gasoline.
...brilliant. A great buy.
- So why don't you buy it then?
- I'm broke...
...listen...I'd need a person to help me out at the customs...
- Don't worry about customers old pal.
...The Bulgarians always say: "Brother, if you
can't solve a problem with money...
...solve it with a lot of money. "
- Lil'o whiskey...
- What's this, eh? What's this?
...you're giving him whisky in a gin glass?
You hate him for being a gypsy, don't you?!
...you stupid bitch! Get the hell out!
- What's wrong?
- Get lost all of you! Get the fuck out!
...you too, out!
-Why?
- You picked her side too you cunt! Out!
- He said nothing!
-Get out! All of you!
...what?!
- Piss off! Piss the fuck off!
....get the hell out, suckers!
Stop trying to relax me dammit!
...I have no racial prejudices!
Fuck my life...
...huh, Matko?
- You have always been tolerant...with everyone...
...ever since you were a kid...
- Sorry.
- I would have been okay drinking out of the bottle too.
- No way! Cheers!
...on our deal! Let's drink!
- Ah you're such a cutie!
- You should find a wife for your son soon.
- Zare? He's not of age, but he is mature.
- Is he honest?
- One hundred percent. He's the most important for me.
- Good for you. You're the image of a real man.
Not like me, with that scum.
...this happens ever again and I'll fuck your junkie mothers you sons of bitches!!
- What you're whining about?
I don't get you...Apparently you're not short on anything.
- What's that to me? Tell me.
...am I successful? Yeah! I have a house as large as a castle.
...2,500 square metres.
...Take a look at the Old Man's mausoleum.
Even the State would be jealous of it!
- Ain't it beautiful?
- Very much so.
...why are you crying, Dadan? Don't cry.
- Why not?
...why shouldn't I cry? Lemme cry!
- It's a wonderful castle!
- It's a shame. A shame.
- What's a shame?
- I can't marry out my sister.
That was Dad's dying wish!
...it's a disgrace!
- Don't you worry, my brother.
All will be well.
...But...we should close our little deal here...
...cheers.
- Hello! Hello! Hello, Aksim?
...I'm in deep shit...I could do with a bit of help here...
...I've heard you have a singer who can pull a nail out of logs using her ass?
- Go serve the customer.
- He'll let us know if he wants something.
- Then go water the pole.
- What's her name? Black Obelisk?
Fuck this shit, it's disconnected again.
...this fucking phone, it's killing me, it's eating my nerves!
...it's eating my whole life!
...damn it. Go water the telephone pole.
I can't hear a fucking word like this over the damn phone...
- May your phone die a horrible death...
- Hey you. Come here.
- Who? Me?
- Stop pretending you're waiting for someone.
I know you're after me...
- I only want a lemonade.
- Of course.
- How many times I need to tell you to water the pole?! Get on with it!
- What's up?
- Go pour the water on the pole!
- What a "man"...lol.
- Get goin'!
- Hey Aksim, I can't hear a fucking word...nothing!
- What are you waiting for?
- You're pouring it yet?
- I can hear you now better,
much, much better!
...listen! Get on the fast train and be here by tomorrow as there's a show to be done!
- Hey, no lemonade for me?!
- You'll get that
when the geese grow a beard. Bleeeh!
- Music!
- My dear grandson.
- I got your stuff for you.
- What does the doc say?
- All sorts of bollocks. I'll live to be a hundred unless the devil takes me!
- And your liver?
- Completely gone to pot. Useless.
- You shouldn't drink that much.
- What do you mean? This time I'll be getting really drunk for once!
...time for me to get wasted!
- This is a hospital!
Music isn't allowed here, what are you thinking?!
- Doctor, you've got to make
an end to this.
- Imagine what it would be like if
all patients left the hospital with an orchestra!
- Ma'am, you really needn't be so cross! No need for it at all, no need!
...here's a bit of money for you!
- Freedom!!
- Excellent booze. Burns my intestines...
- Grandson, I've got to tell you something.
...your mother is dead, and your father is a filthy bastard.
- I sold the cement factory.
- You sold it?!
- Aye, that I did. It's gone now, just like if I never had it in the first place!
...check this out!
...I sold it to that dirtbag Dadan.
...your future is safe. If you need money,
go to my friend...
...whom I haven't seen in 25 years.
His name is...
- I know. Grga Pitic.
- You know of him?
- You've told me about your friendship
a thousand times.
- A seven-foot-tall giant with
hands like shovels.
...he's got two rows of teeth.
...one the regular, but the other is golden!
...elegant as a vampire.
- Music... attack!!
- Shoot here you asshole, shoot here!
...Here's a flowerpot! And another one. Have this too!
Kill my children and family too!
- What are you doing?!
- Hey, leave me alone! It's okay, I'm goin', I'm goin'!
- You son of a bitch!
...careful now, I'll beat the shit out of you!
... I'll get you!
- You old monkey!
- I shit on Death!
- I'll get you, you're mine now, I'll smash your bloody face!
"Louis, I think this is the beginning
of a beautiful friendship. "
- Boss, try this please, what do you think about the tase?
- Our whisky is better than the real thing.
- Logical. Our method is better.
- Where are you, children?
- We're here, grandpa.
- Sit down.
- That's enough, children.
- You, what have you've been up to?
- You know, you sent me to the fair to find a wife.
- We've been to ten...twenty fairs!
- And you managed to find one?
- I asked something, jackass.
- I can find women for entertainment or to foul around with, but good wife-to-be...that's difficult!
- Be ashamed. All your friends are married
and have children.
...when I was your age I had
been married four times.
...it's all about taste.
...don't be fussy. Find a girl and get it over with.
- Granddad, tell us about number five
The one that stole your heart?
...we love listening to that story a lot.
- My darling.
...even the memory of her is
enough to lighten my heart.
...my little dove...
- Blood doesn't turn into water.
...if you managed to find the right one for yourself, so will I!
- When will that be?
Are you just waiting for me to die?!
- Why won't you be a good boy and
marry for him.
- Yesterday I had another stroke.
I can barely see.
- Again?
- Again.
- I beg you for the last time:
Find yourself a wife.
...take me to the hospital
to recover.
...I'll get out for your wedding.
...bring me a daughter in law.
- Ok, grandad.
- Kssss, cat.
- Black cats are bad luck.
- Take care of the passenger train,
I'll take the goods train.
- My lil'o train!
- One...
...two, three...
...five...
...six...
(inaudible)
...eighteen...
- Boo!
- Oh Devla! [god]
- All's well?
...this calls for a celebration. Drink up!
- I am scared shitless of being screwed.
- I made a promise, a promise is a promise!
- And money is money! Everyone got what they're after.
...I'm paranoid to think about what will happen once the train is at the customs.
Hope nobody's going to screw us now!
- Chill out friend!
- Cheers.
- Why are you hiding?
...I call the shots around here.
Relax! Come!
...get in here!
...I'll keep the suitcase!
- But I gave everybody their share.
- Everything' okay...
- That's it guys, that's all there is.
- Where's the rest?
- It's all, I swear on the Bible.
- Brother! There must be a misunderstanding.
- Thou shall die now!
...filthy rat!
Don't shoot!
-Bang, bang, bang!!
- Shame on you.
- Here's the little birdy.
He's sleeping.
- My suitcase!
Give it back! Give it back you douche-bag!...you son of a bitch!
...rot, die! You filthy fucktard!
...stop jumping around, jackass!
Stop doing this to me! Get down!
...come back down dammit!
...fuck I don't need your shoes!
...so be it! I'm coming for you!
...it is time
for you and me...
...to look each other in the eye.
...just you and me. You worthless dumbass! You second class cum!
...there...finally!
...man, this is way too high.
- That's Dadan, thank God!
- Dadan, It's me. Matko.
- The train has disappeared!
- Gone?!
...didn't it cross the border?
...answer me. Where are my 17 wagons
I paid for in advance?
- It crossed the border 30 minutes ago.
It's has to be here somewhere.
- Here? Where?
You don't lose track of a train.
- I can't remember anything. Somebody bloody drugged me.
I was asleep for only 10 minutes.
- Ah come on, who would do such a thing?
- He did. This cum!
...it was him.
- That pig?
- My Bulgarian custom officers
didn't see no train.
- They're lying. They're double crossing,
but they will have to pay.
- A train rides on track,
not just randomly through the woods.
...it can't just have gone up in smoke,
or can it? Boss?
- No way, dammit.
- My dear audience...
...after a triumphant tour in
North-Africa, Asia and Australia...
...I'm proud to present to you in your quiet riverside village:
The Black Obelisk.
...an act, never seen before:
...to pull a nail from a beam
in the most spectacular fashion.
- It wasn't an ordinary fight,
but more one man against King Kong.
- Which one?
- What do you mean?
- That big ol' chunky Bulgarian!
...I've never seen a man that big! That jerk could only pass the
doorway sideways.
- What's your name?
- Rambo.
- A warm welcome for this
young man named Rambo.
- Your moment has come! Hit it!
- Enough!
- My honoured guests...
...the great, unforgettable,
breathtaking moment is near.
...a moment you'll remember throughout your life!
- Bravo!!
- I proposed an honest fight. I've said it: "honest fight!"
...but he kicked me in the balls.
...I grabbed him by the hair and whirled
his head around. He went crazy!
...but I really paid attention not to foil our plan in front of the Customs officers...
I'm good, eh?
- You'll return all my money tonight.
Your deadline is at 11 o'clock.
...if you don't, I'll hang you by the balls
on the windmill.
...so you can get your head aired a bit...
- Awful...
- So how will it be? Will I have the money?
- There's a bit of an issue.
...three wagons were supposed to be mine.
- I've got a better plan.
There's a different solution.
Yesterday I bought your father's factory
in the hospital.
- The cement factory?
- Aye. I paid him a fair price.
...ask him if you don't believe me.
- But it's not enough to cover your debt.
It's only two thirds.
...I have an even better plan! Much better!
- You have a marriageable son.
And I've got a marriageable sister.
- And?
- We arrange a big fat wedding
and forget your debt.
- I'll give you anything you want, Dadan.
But that's impossible. - Why?
- I'll bet on the nail.
- Name?
- Dadan, don't do this to me, you can't ask such as huge favour!
...your sister is 25, my son 17.
- Younger men like ripe women.
- That's not all, Dadan.
- What else?
- You know, you know.
...she looks like a little Smurf.
Everyone calls her little Lady-bird.
- So what? A diamond is small,
but valuable.
- Final bets please! Anyone?
- Hands off!
- Do we have a deal? Give me your hand!
- No. I've got it figured now.
...I know who stole my train
and drugged me.
...and who messed with my father!
You stole my heritage! There's no deal!
- Safet. Kazatchok.
- You stole from my father! And from me too!
- This way! Bit further down!
- Watch! The moment of truth has come!
- I love the huge ass!
- I certainly don't envy your husband!
- Attention!
...one, two, three... freedom!
- Oi! What are you doing?!
- Is this seat taken?
- What do you want?
- Lemonade.
- Hey you.
- Me?
- Get me an ice cream!
- I'm not an errand boy.
- Come on, you're always following me around,
might as well make yourself useful.
- Don't you think so?
- Exactly.
- Out of the way!
- Strawberry or vanilla?
- Strawberry and vanilla. Four servings.
- You're off?
...come back.
...I've got to tell you something.
...you're in a hurry or what?
- Just wanted my lemonade.
- Shame you're getting married.
...you're a bit young for me but rather handsome.
...I could fall in love with you...
...but there's no point when you're getting married.
- Married? Who's getting married?
...I'm only thinking of you.
...you're the only reason for my presence here.
- Hardly matters now...
- You've been fouled.
Someone's setting me up.
...I'm way too young to get married.
- But you are actually engaged!
...I overheard your father and Dadan
in my grandma's inn.
...they agreed last night.
...it's a shame. Here.
- Woe to my head...aaargh!
...Dadan has the factory now. All gone. Whoosh!
- And now he wants me too.
That bastard is like highwaymen. Such a jerk.
- He got the train, the factory...
What else does he want?
- What else?
...his mother's pussy.
- The Russians are here.
- The water is nice.
- There's something else...
...that Dadan.
- he wants to arrange a marriage
to pay of my debt.
- A marriage?
- For our child Zare and his sister.
...The Lady-bird.
- That bawler, the midget?
...that ass-plug dwarf!
- We need to ask for assistance.
We'll have to go and see Grga Pitic!
...he's my friend, he'll help us.
- It's a bit late for that.
...Grga Pitic...is dead.
- Dead?
- God have mercy on his soul.
I haven't had a drink yet...
...but I'll have one now
for his salvation.
- Grandfather.
- There's my grandson.
...ain't he handsome?
- Grandfather, I got you some oranges.
- Now be nice and say hello.
- Hello, nurse.
- Have you seen her?
- Who?
- The girl.
-  No.
- She's the nurse.
...they call her Candy.
...those boobies, that body.
...and that tiny butt. All so delicate.
- You know for me it's love at first sight,
or nothing at all.
- Love at first sight? Ridiculous.
- The son of your deceased friend Zarija
dropped by.
...he came for help.
...all his money has been stolen.
...can we settle this, together with Little Grga?
...we'll skin them alive, and pump them full of lead.
- Nah, I first want to see the grave of Zarija.
- As you will, granddad.
...it was only a proposition.
- Nobody listens to me. I'm talking to you!
- Miss! Please!
- I'm not getting married this way.
- Shame on you.
- Miss, let me take measurements please!
- You're my greatest enemy.
...you're no brother to me.
You're a tyrant!
- Must our parents
curse me from their grave?
- No, no no and no!! I don't want to marry.
...I'm not getting married. Do you hear me?
...I am not doing it! Not even if you kill me. I'll wait for my true love!
- 168.
- Who is it?
...tell me. Who is it? The true love?
- I've seen him in my dreams. I'll find him one day.
...I saw him a hundred times in my dreams.
I know what he looks like.
...I know his eyes,
his face, his lips.
...He's big, very big...
- Neck measurements...13...
- Which big man would want you,
stupid goose?
...an ass-plug like yourself?
- You'll see, he'll come one day!
- Breast, 88.
- Shut up! Leave me alone.
- Safet.
...cool her down.
- Leave me be!!
- Stop arguing with me in my own home!
- Let me go!
I'll marry the man I love, whether you agree or not!
- Pull.
- Aaaaye, my little sister!
...what are you doing? Our father is looking down upon us!
- Changed your mind yet?
...I'll turn you into a garden gnome!
...son of a....go on.
- I don't want to! I'll marry the man I love!
- Do you even have a soul?
Our parents are watching from above.
- They can't see shit, it's cloudy!
- Party!
- Come on! Party I said!
- That's great Dadan, good luck to you!
- Move over, let the lady sit.
- Congratulations.
- Do you want something to drink?
- Coffee.
- Only coffee?
- Only coffee.
- You need any help?
- Ask Matko, that dumbass.
...make sure there's food, I don't trust him.
- The one who looks like a vampire
and the monkey face are both married.
...so only the little one is left.
...the poor Lady-bird
- That midget?
- Yes, in her bridal gown.
...all yours, take her!
- Never.
- I'm here for business.
- What business, Sujka?
- You marry my Ida.
...I see she pleases you.
- You won't find a prettier girl
in the whole region.
...I fed her from her birth.
...we've been everywhere.
...gave her medicines
to make her beautiful.
...to buy her Italian clothes...
...we went to Rome and Napels.
- Liar.
...I showed her all countries.
...in the end we went to Sweden.
- I know. To beg.
- Still better to beg than to scavenge in the rubbish.
- That's what you did!
- Do you have anything against it?
- How much do you want for her?
- Give me 35,000 marks.
- Grandma.
- 15,000, in two installations.
- What do you think I am?
- 17,000 in three parts?
- Give it in one installation.
...and I don't want see you ever again.
- She's selling you like cattle.
- Never.
- Carry me.
...come on, carry me!
...you're really handsome you know.
..and now...kiss me.
- Damn tie.
...save me, grandpa. Don't let me be married.
...I'll drink his blood.
- Where you're off to?
...let go of that!
- I'll kill him!
- Aren't you ashamed of yourself? Give it to me!
- Let it go! You should be ashamed of yourself!
...Relax. Keep your cool!
- Look at this. Watch.
- I'll teach him.
- I know what I have to do.
- I don't want to.
- Listen.
...Listen, listen, let me tell you something!
...her brother Dadan...
is a common war criminal.
...he almost killed me. He'll exterminate our family.
He'll drink our blood.
- But she's a midget.
- O mirror, the dead with the dead...
- He'll be drinking out blood!
- ...the living with the living,
the children with their father.
- For two months. Then you get a divorce.
- Still no!
- ...the dead with the dead...
- I said no and that's it!
...leave me be!
- I'll prevent the marriage in an
elegant manner.
- Zare.
- Help me climb up or else I'll beat you up!
- Zare!
...damn you stupid kid!
- Where is he?
- Who?
- Your grandson.
- Aye, you keep sitting here and playing!
...don't even be bothered by Dadan making mince meat out of all of us.
- Where is my son?
- I don't know. Couldn't care less.
- Where is he?
- I don't know.
- Get out of there.
...out! Hiding is futile.
...today's his wedding.
...you disgraceful lot!
- The dead with the dead,
the living with the living...children with their father...
...the dead with the dead,
- Granddad.
- He's not breathing.
- Grandpa is dead.
- Did you hear me?!
- The old man's dead!
...I said, grandpa is dead.
- His heart stopped beating.
- Dead?
...did you have to die on the day your
grandson marries?
The day he marries...
- Grandpa wanted to saved me...
...we'll flee together after the mourning ends.
I'll take you with me. Just you and I.
- Ah now I'll need to get a new costume, shoes,
a butterfly-tie...
...wreaths of flowers, candles...and so on...
- It's ok...
- Definitively dead.
- It's okay...cry...
- Ah it's you, Matko, you womaniser.
...you're early. Eight o'clock, you said.
...where's the son in law?
- I need to speak with you immediately!
...it's urgent.
I've got to talk to you in private.
- Hope it's not bad news! Today I only want to hear good news.
- I'm listening.
- My father is dead.
- Really?
- Really.
- My condolences.
- What can I do?
...a wedding and a funeral don't
get along well.
- You're right. How about he dies in three days?
- Three days? But he died this morning.
- Who says so? Who knows?
- I know it. Zare...
...I came straight to you to tell you!
We'll have to mourn for forty days.
- I'll mourn with you... in three days.
...you're a wise man.
...you're not postponing the wedding.
- We'll have to!
- You're mad? Should my father turn in his grave? That's what you want?
- Of course not Dadan.
- Don't tell anyone about the old man.
...it doesn't matter to him if he dies on
Wednesday or Friday.
...death's forever.
...it doesn't matter when it begins.
...did you hear anything?
- Nope.
- We didn't hear anything.
- No.
- Me neither.
...get the guests
and come pick up the bride.
- As you like, Dadan.
- Cheers.
- He's not impressed.
- What?
- Even if he kills us and places us dead at
the dinner table, the wedding will continue!
- I won't do. No way.
- Don't be daft. He'll rip my head off!
...take this...
...for your soul, daddy.
...take his legs. We are going to the attic.
...turn him aside.
...bring up some ice.
...hurry up!
...quick!
...don't do this to me.
You don't need money anymore.
...put his legs on the chair.
- Get the grandchildren of Grga Pitic here!
- I left six messages.
They don't answer.
...who knows where they are?
...daddy, forgive me.
- Hold it above the bride.
- I don't want to.
- Hold it above her head.
- I said no!
- Get away you.
- Take the child, it will bring you luck.
- My dear ones...This is the most beautiful day...
...of your whole life.
...a unique day...
...to say so.
...because this is the day of your lives.
...answer now in front of the witnesses...
...the following questions.
...but be brief. And quick.
...just yes or no.
- Do you...
...Zare Destanov do you...
...out of free will...
...take Afrodita Karambolis to be your wife?
Karambolo.
- Say yes.
- Yes.
- And you, Afrodita...
...lovely beauty and so sweet...
...do you take Zare Destanov to
be your husband out of free will?
- She said 'of course yes'
- Let her say it. Yes or no.
- I want an answer.
- Yes.
- So yes it is.
...I don't see any legal objection.
...I now declare you man and wife...
...in my presence...
...and in the presence of this crowd.
- Hurry up, make sure everything's okay.
- I don't want to.
- You know my hands can be very swift.
...thunder in one hand,
lightning in the other.
- Please sign this.
- I cannot wait on his wedding.
- Why do you care about his wedding?
- As the community's administrative officer...
...I declare married:
...Zare Destanov and Afrodita Karambolis.
- Do you cry for him?
- Yes.
- Then cry.
...cry, baby, cry.
- I will buy you a convertible
and half the ocean!
...and three houses
bigger than America
...little girl,
you have stolen my heart
...and if you were mine,
you would live like a queen,
...at daytime a queen
and at nightime an empress.
- Come on!
- Come on, hands up everyone!
- Way to go, Dadan.
...a real businessman and patriot.
- Come and dance, little sister.
- Fuck off.
- Ok, let her go.
- Respect your brother in law, a sensible man.
- Dance with your brother, it's tradition.
- I don't want to.
- Fine. It's your wedding.
...freedom.
- Daddy, I hope you see this.
- Let's see who has spent the most on gifts.
...a portable record player...
...from Nada Adzovic.
...Zudija Adzovic donates
a vacuum cleaner.
...Spaho Ahmetovic, pots and pans.
- Keep going, pal!
- Something's amiss. I am going to look how daddy is doing.
...stay here and please
don't get us in trouble.
- Nebojsa Palanovic
donates this ugly thing.
- Don't show the people you are crying.
- Promise you're not going to do anything stupid.
- I am a
pit bull-terrier.
- I am going to give new ice to daddy.
- You live poorly. Repair your roof.
- There is nothing wrong with the roof.
- It's daddy who needs to be repaired.
- Wipe your nose.
...do you want to marry someone you don't love?
- No.
- Neither do I.
- Do you love her?
- Yes.
- Then help me run away.
- What?
- Help me escape.
- There is a big shutter near the table...
...on the floor...
...turn left at the oil-barrels.
- Ahh, what a joyful moment, fuck me!
- For once be honest with me, daddy.
...where is your money from the factory sale?
- Safet.
...bring grenades!
- What? Grenades?
- But why? Your husband can't see it.
- He'll rip your heart out if he learns about it.
- You, stop wandering around, come and dance instead!
- Where is the bride?
- Hell I know! Ask the businessman and patriot.
- Everybody listen.
...the bride is gone!
- Chief, the bride is gone!
- Chief, your sister is gone.
- What sort of a husband are you, letting your wife run away?
- Bugger off!
- My dress!
- Hey, what's happening?!
- My sister...
- Stop this, sister!
...don't worry.
...your brother will not abandon you.
...I will find the guilty one.
- How could she remove her dress and escape?
- Dunno.
- You let your wife escape?!
...you son of a bitch!
...what have you done?
- Has your sister escaped?
- No, yours.
- Then why the fuck are crying?
Get fucking lost.
- Stupid junkies.
- What is she doing here, eh?
- Searching for smurfette.
- How did you call her?
- Smurfette.
- Shame on you.
- You don't call my sister smurfette.
...understood?
...do you even know who I am?
- Leave her be, she knows nothing!
...it's not her fault,
she doesn't know anything.
- She does know something.
- Stop it. Everybody calls her
ladybird or smurfette.
- Grandfather!
- Grandfather? You are unrealistic, boy.
- Let him go, he doesn't know anything!
- Don't bother your grandfather, he is dead.
- Leave him, he doesn't know anything.
- Where is she?
- My ear.
- Let go of him, bastard.
- Where is she? She hasn't vaporised.
- Let him go. Now!
- Tell me, suckers. Or I will kill you.
...you're not telling me where she'd gone?
- Shall I shoot him?
- Later. Later!
- Dadan.
- What are you doing here?
- Dadan, I am stuck.
...I have important news.
...my balls are stuck.
- Shame on you. Repair that roof.
- Who cares? I have seen the bride.
- Where?
- At the Dead Tree.
- Safet.
- Not there, friend. This way, she came this way!
...this way!
- Granddad, do you hear me?
- Yes, what's the matter?
- We should turn back.
- We need some things sorted!
- You can visit his grave another time.
- No, now.
Who knows how long I will live.
- You'll get a stroke in this heat, Granddad!
...it's a hundred degrees out there...
- I'll live, plus, Zarija deserves to my visit.
- Ok then.
...I said it for your own good.
- Afrodita.
- Sister.
...I will not harm you.
- There she is.
- My sister.
- All ends well.
- She is not here.
- Maybe she is in the woods.
- What a shame the bride runs
away from her own wedding.
...everybody will talk about it for years.
...it's my shame that she'd gotten away.
- I will find her. The wedding will continue.
- Chief, it's a shoe.
- Sister!
- I will kill you!
- Wakey, wakey! We're stuck!
...wake up! An earthquake. Earthquake!
- Why am I listening to you in the first place?
We always get lost when I listen to you!
...where did you get that stupid map?
- Hey, Dad, you're asleep or what?
...I think we're lost...
...what's going on with you?
...they're gone!
- This is my destiny!
- Why destiny?
- All this. I will still marry you.
- Yes.
- Who could have thought Ladybird
would be so brave?
...I don't know anyone daring to go up against Dadan...
- She is indeed brave.
- I am so afraid.
- Of what? We'll drown this filthy son of a bitch in his own shit!
- Congratulations, son. Brilliant idea.
- I thought I saw the devil itself.
...but it's destiny.
- And my other shoe?
- We will find it.
But this is one hundred percent destiny!
- Don't be silly.
- I was looking for someone, just like you...that matches my taste!
- Me too.
- I looked and looked, found
her when I least expect it.
- Me too.
- Let's introduce ourselves. I am Grga.
- Me too. I mean, I am
Afrodita Karambolo. Ladybird.
- We must celebrate,
if you agree.
- My sister...
- Quiet.
- Hey, what are you doing, stop it, stop it, hey!
...it's a misunderstanding!
...you silly sod, stop shooting like that.
You know how much money is at stake?
- Excuse me. If the lady has any debts
I will pay them.
- What the fuck you're waiting for? Take action!
- Grga.
- Give me back my sister.
- I'll shoot holes in you, filth!
- Fuck off. Come here, sis.
- You're a shit driver!
...you lost your old man, you lost me...you suck!
- Look what I have got.
- Don't come any closer
or I will pump you full of lead!
...I swear to God. You think I'm kidding?
- Sister in law...
- Who are they?
- Put your guns down.
- Don't move!
- She is my sister. Understand?
...and she's fled her own wedding!
- Oh well, she's my trouble now
- And he's mine.
- Shame on you. And you! Give me back my sister!
- She's coming with me. If you are really her brother,
we can come to an agreement.
...I want to marry her immediately.
- She just ran away from her wedding.
- You can run away from a fake marriage,
but you can't hide from destiny.
- Ewww, what a sharpshooter.
- Who the fuck is that?
- Drop the guns!
- You call this driving, idiot?
...Why didn't you take the other road?
- Ok, but look what I found.
- Very cute.
- Chill out!
...this isn't necessary.
- How's it going, consignor Grga?
- Is it you, worthless piece of shit?
...what are you doing here?
- We were just talking.
- Talking about what?
...are you here to pay off your debt?
- Do you know each other?
- Last time I was in Italy...in 1982...
...he was a newbie in my gang.
...the worst kind.
...I lost the landfills in Trieste and Udine because of him.
- So don't you want to marry her?
- No.
- I want her.
- A bit later about that one...
- Now.
- Be silent when you are speaking to me.
- And you, do you want my grandson?
- Yes!
- And you do not object to your
sister marrying my grandson?
- Of course not, if they love each other.
- What the heck's making you unhappy?
...what's wrong?
...ahh the cement factory...
....and the three wagons of petrol he nicked from you...
...you'll pay him back, understood?
-Right now!
...he will pay at once.
- Of course.
- And the wedding must
start immediately.
- The wedding can begin.
Music!
- What counts, is that love conquers all.
- Cheers!
- Has he drank it yet?
- Not yet.
- My beautiful sisters.
- I hope there won't be any complications.
- You will swim in your own shit.
- Do you need anything, uncle Grga?
- Have fun, I am going visit
the grave of my friend.
- The grave?
- Where is it? Tell me.
- Uncle Grga...
...don't you want to drink something first?
...a refreshment. Eat something as well.
...at this hour there are
vampires in the graveyard.
...by the time we get there,
they will be gone.
- As you wish.
...my servants will bring
you to the graveyard.
...but where should the grave be?
- Give me the money.
- Traitor.
- It was only ethical.
...I think we're sorted then.
...be jolly. Your sister is happy, so is my son.
...like our benefactor, uncle...
...What's going on?!
- What's the matter?
- Look.
- What's the matter with him?
- He is dead.
- Really dead.
- No. He will die the day after tomorrow,
like your father.
...the wedding must continue. I can't
start over a hundred times.
- Am I right?
- Completely.
- Shall we put him in the attic?
- We told his grandchildren,
we were taking him to the graveyard.
- What about the registrar?
- What registrar?
- He must cancel the first wedding
and perform the second wedding.
- Don't worry,
I thought you were asking it in relation to the old man.
- Chill out!
- Goddammit...
- Eat your shit.
- Two sixes.
- A bit of refreshments...
- Duh, that's sweeeet!
- The more natural, the sweeter.
- Fifty marks.
- Look, Dadan...
...500 horns at 5 marks is 2500 marks.
...I know someone in Düsseldorf who'll buy the whole lot.
- Are you crazy?
Do you want to stuff those horns?
- Wait, Dadan.
...be a gentleman.
...my stake is the factory.
- You have lost that one already.
Look, you have signed this.
- Ok, I still have a house.
- You have lost that one too, idiot.
- But you do have...
...a nice golden tooth.
...that will be the stake. 500 marks, ok?
- What's with the ice?
- Get lost.
- What's going on?
- Damned black cat.
- I am soaked. She has pissed on me.
- Brother.
- You're alive?
- Aren't we dead?
- I'm not.
- I was told you were dead.
- They have lied to you.
I am alive.
- Daddy. I am glad you are alive...again.
- Of course you are...
...dead cows can't be milked!
- Granddad!
- Your father is alive.
- I will now explain to you
of the laws regarding...
...the holy matremony...
...and the responsibility of marriage.
...I wish everything will be beautiful for you...
...may it last a life long...
...and enjoy each others company.
...think of it as this...what happens today...
...is a prelude to fulfilling the most important
and beautiful tasks in life.
- It's kicking in...
- Be jealous, not with each other,
but on your marriage.
...honor it and protect it
against all evil.
- Consider it...
- When you died,
I decided to leave.
- What has fallen?
- Very wise. There is no sun here.
- Forget your glasses. Hurry up.
- Agreed?
- I agree. But don't tell that to anyone.
- I have been drinking
on the funeral, just now.
- Don't forget the accordion.
...in it you will find enough,
to live happy.
- Shit, I got the death certificate
instead of the wedding certificate.
- Are you crazy? Junkie.
- My reputation...
...shall I call the police?
- Here.
...everything is allright.
...the signatures please.
First the ladies, then the men.
- The ladies don't marry each
other, stupid fool.
- He knows his job, chill out!
- Keep making sure it's all legal!
- Do you, Afrodita Karambolo...
...take to be your husband...
...Grga Pitic junior?
- Yes.
- Do you, Grga Pitic junior...
...take to be your wife
Afrodita Karambolo?
- Yes.
- Sign the register.
...according to the law you
are now husband and wife.
...congragulations!
- Swim, you bastard!
- Brother!
- Sister! Someone, help me!
Give me your hand!
- I can't work like this.
- There it is.
- It's amazing.
- Quickly!
- We are not married yet.
- We will do it on the way.
- Mr. Dadan, you're in deep trouble.
- You always spoil everything.
We must continue the ceremony.
- I haven't had this much fun for a long while!
- I can't work like that.
- Yes you can.
- It can't just be done. It's a ceremony!
...hey, I'm an official!
- We are missing the boat. Get going!
- The boy has guts.
- Granddad's blood.
- Zare, my grandson.
- You're just a kid, what do you want from me?
- I want you to marry us.
- Don't forget the accordion.
- Come back, we need to finish the ceremony!
- Sit down!
- You don't have any witnesses.
- Yes we do!
- Who?
- The cats.
- Oi, wait for me!
- You stink, boss.
- I'll fuck your mothers!
- Ida, will you take Zare as your husband?
- Yes.
- Do you, Zare Destanov, take her
to be your wife...
- Of course!
- Children...
...have a good journey!
- Good bye granddad!
- My dear friend...Shall we drink to it
like it is tradition?
- Grandmother!
- You have fooled me, daddy!
- Don't forget about your loving father!
- It's all chaos!!
- Nice stuff.
- Thanks, daddy,
for everything you have done for me.
- My soul is on fire.
- Ah, children...
- Dadan, brother.
- Hey, stop it!
- It doesn't smell at all! I don't mind it...
- "Louis, I think this is the beginning
of a beautiful friendship. "
- Jesus, you smell!