[ALARM RINGING]
[SIGHS]
[IMITATING
DARTH VADER'S BREATHING]
Give me your press badge.
No way, you're not my dad!
Then I shall take it by force.
Oh, he's my brother!
Then you shouldn't have
made out with him.
[GROANS]
[IMITATING DRUMMING]
[SEAGULLS CAWING
OVER SPEAKERS]
[SIGHS]
[HORNS HONKING]
GULLIVER:
So, your name's Dan?
Yeah, Dan... Dan Quint.
Like on the resume.
Dan Quint. Born 1990.
I didn't think that was possible.
Yeah, 1990.
People are born every year.
What do you hope to get out of
being in the mailroom, Dan?
I guess I hope to get out of
being in the mailroom.
You got sass. I like it.
Guess what? You're hired.
I'm Lemuel Gulliver.
Welcome to the team.
I was hired...
yesterday by HR.
Doggy wants a bone.
What?
Floor 30.
This is the editors' floor.
Oh, yeah.
This is the epicenter, my friend.
Feel it. Feel it.
Okay.
Oh. Got a little
something for you.
Aah!
God dang it! Sorry about that.
I will dry-clean that.
Sorry about that. My bad.
Just wait out here.
What?
One second.
Here's your mail, sir.
Hey, you're Harold Jones, right?
Yeah.
I loved your piece on
the failure of derivative markets.
[WHISTLING]
Thanks. I look forward
to seeing you around.
DAN:
Thank you...
from me and
all the readers.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Dan, what are you doing?
You can't talk to those guys!
Why not?
Okay, this is your first day.
We are the mailroom guys.
Mailroom guys are meant
to be seen and not heard.
And ideally, not even seen, okay?
We're not on their level.
We're little people.
No, I think you're
just scared to talk to them.
I am not! Dude, listen. I am
just respectful of their workspace.
I talk to these people all the...
I'll let you know as soon as
I've made a decision, Nigel.
[IN AUSTRALIAN ACCENT]
Okey-dokey, thank you. Good day, fellas.
Good day.
Good day, mate.
Gulliver, got any mail for me?
Yeah... Uh, no... Maybe.
Let me check.
Hi, I'm Dan, from the mailroom.
Hey. Darcy.
And I'll do whatever it takes
to not be from the mailroom.
[GULLIVER LAUGHING]
Dan doesn't need to be bothering
her right now. She's busy.
He isn't bothering me.
I love to have a reason
to procrastinate.
Yeah, me, too.
You're not bugging me.
There you go.
Well, I'll see you guys later.
Good to see you.
Okay.
Oh, boy. Let's go.
So, how long have you had this
debilitating crush on the travel editor?
Crush? On Darcy?
No way, dude.
First of all,
you're a terrible liar.
Second of all, why don't
you just ask her out?
You don't think I could ask her out?
No.
I could ask her out whenever,
wherever. It's no problem.
It would take me five seconds.
"Will you go out with me?" "Yes." Done.
I'm now going out with Darcy Silverman.
We are boyfriend and girlfriend.
"Gulliver and Darcy?"
"Cutest couple ever."
Okay. So, then, do it.
Pfft. Next time I see her, I will.
DARCY:
Hold on! Hi, again.
Hey, Darcy.
I just remembered,
I get claustrophobic in elevators.
How is your day going?
Really good.
Just really, really, good.
What are you doing this weekend?
So much stuff.
It's just going to be...
a bunch of stuff.
Cool.
Yeah, it's cool.
Have a good one.
You, too.
[MOUTHING]
Wait! I forgot something.
Yeah, me, too.
[KISS'S "ROCK AND ROLL ALL NITE"
PLAYING]
[ON VIDEO GAME]
You show us everything you've got
You keep on dancin'....
So?
Yeah?
Yeah!
You chickened out, didn't you?
I wasn't... I just... You know...
I didn't chicken out.
Being respectful of her workspace.
Exactly.
Dude.
Speaking of which, after work...
do you want to go for a couple
of brews and shoot some poos?
Maybe a little man-date.
I don't think so. Especially
because you called it a man-date.
I got you. You want a rain check.
You want to wake up all bright-eyed
and bushy-tailed for the boss.
You're not my boss anymore.
What are you talking about?
I just got promoted.
That's impossible.
You just got here.
Yeah, they promoted me...
to head of the mailroom.
So I'm your boss now.
Look, Gulliver, the reason you didn't
ask her out and you never will...
is the same reason that you're
not going to leave the mailroom.
You've been here 10 years, man.
You peaked.
You talk a big game
and that can be fun sometimes.
And you're pretty funny around the office,
but that's all you are.
It's just talk.
So you might as well face it...
you're never really going to
get any bigger than this.
[DAN SIGHS]
These talks. This is the worst
part about being a boss.
Anyway, be in tomorrow at 7:00.
We're going to sort of
change things up...
and we're gonna start with getting rid
of "Guitar Hero" during work hours.
MAN:
Night, Darcy.
See you.
Gulliver?
Hi.
Can I help you?
Yeah, I...
I wanted to see...
if you wanted to...
You seem a little nervous.
Are you all right?
No, I'm fine. I'm just...
[CLEARS THROAT]
I got so much going on.
I wanted to pick this up,
and then I'm on my way.
You want to apply for
a travel writing assignment?
Hm?
Yeah. Exactly.
I had no idea you wrote or traveled.
I do. I travel a lot.
I go to New Zealand.
Been to Mexico.
Méjico, they call it...
in the locals.
Africa, the Congo.
Which I know is in Africa
because I travel and write.
So this is kind of what I want to do.
Why don't you bring in a writing sample
tomorrow and I'll see what I can do.
Perfect.
Okay.
Okay. Ahem.
Hey, Gulliver.
Hm?
Nice job putting yourself out there.
Yeah. Cool. Okay, bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
[HORNS HONKING]
GULLIVER: I should've just manned up
and asked her out.
Now she's expecting a writing sample?
What was I thinking?
[SINGING] I saw some things
In different lands
Karate chop-- I gotta write this thing!
No, I got nothing.
Wow.
I am so impressed, Gulliver.
I had no idea
you were such a good writer.
I kind of keep it secret. I don't like
to brag about my more literarian side.
These samples are terrific.
And you exhibit such variety.
This one about Oaxaca feels really classic,
like it came straight out of Frommer's...
whereas the description
of Barcelona is all...
sassy.
It's like I'm reading Time Out.
Mm-hm.
Yeah.
I think I have the perfect
fluff piece to start you off with.
There's a guy down in Bermuda who claims
he has the secret to the Bermuda Triangle.
He's either crazy or he's trying
to bilk tourists. But I figure...
it could be a fun way in...
to explore Bermuda
and the smaller islands around it.
You do have boat experience, don't you?
I'm a... boat... man.
I'm a boatman.
Okay, good...
because I have to be honest, it was
hard to find someone to do this.
You have to be at sea for three
weeks, completely off the grid.
That's okay with you, right?
Mm.
Good,
because I thought...
I was going to have to do it
and I get super seasick. It's crazy.
So, what do you say?
It's not a big story,
but it's a start.
Mm-hm.
So, the Bermuda Triangle, huh?
Everything I need
to know is in here?
It is.
Your contact's been arranged...
and there's a boat
waiting for you.
Yeah.
[WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER PA]
GULLIVER:
Oh, hey!
That's me!
GULLIVER:
Okay, precious cargo! No, no, no!
Whew. That was close.
All you chickens,
get out of the road, man!
GULLIVER:
I don't know about this, Hank.
I mean, are you sure this is safe?
HANK: All this Bermuda Triangle talk
is just to sell T-shirts to tourists.
It makes for good stories...
if you want to skeet-skeet
with the girls on the mainland.
This is your boat.
Ah. Knotfersail.
They really went pun-tastic
on that boat.
The dock master's really into puns.
He believes it keeps the pirates away.
Ship Happens.
HANK: This is you, and the dot
is your destination.
You just follow that dot,
and you'll find yourself in a triangle.
In the Bermuda Triangle?
Yeah.
And then to come home,
you say I turn this knob...
and I follow the dot back home?
Yeah.
Easy.
Done.
I've got it.
I am fine.
Fine.
It's not moving.
Okay, where's the clutch?
Cruising in my car one day
Minding my business on my way
Oh, mama
GULLIVER:
And as you go out to the ocean water...
towards the Bermuda Triangle...
there's reflections everywhere.
I should've brought some sunglasses.
I am as hungry as a horse.
I could eat 1 ,000 cheeseburgers.
Okay.
Quitting time.
She didn't really mean to hurt me
She didn't really mean to make me cry
Yeah.
But if you really want to go that way
How to build your own robot?
Yeah, that's going to happen.
She didn't really mean to make me cry
I met this girl in a club one night
She was riding off like dynamite
Oh, mama
After night was closing in
We started....
[BUZZING AND BEEPING]
Darcy.
[SNORING]
Cheeseburger.
Darcy.
[GRUNTS]
Huh?
[YELLS]
No!
[SCREAMS]
Safety! Okay.
Rubber ducky.
No!
Floaties! Floatie one.
Floatie leg, floatie left...
floatie right, floatie head.
I am safe!
There is no--
[GRUNTING]
9-1 -1.
[BEEPS]
Oh, no.
[SCREAMS]
Oh, God, help me!
[SCREAMING]
[SEAGULLS CAWING]
[GULLIVER GRUNTING]
GULLIVER:
I'm paralyzed from the neck down.
What's that crawling on me?
Not fire ants.
Please don't be fire ants.
I am General Edward Edwardian,
Commander of Lilliput.
[OVER BULLHORN]
All hail Lilliput!
SOLDIERS:
EDWARD: You are herewith charged with
aiding our sworn enemy, the Blefuscians.
[SOLDIERS BOO]
You are my prisoner, and shall be presented
to our Royal Highness, King Theodore.
What say you...
beast?
[GULLIVER SCREAMS]
[SOLDIERS YELLING]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
You are not real!
Where is my--?
Where am I?
This must be a dream.
I'm gonna close my eyes, then I'm gonna
open them, and I'll be home in bed.
Okay! Okay!
My spear!
Ow!
Bring the beast down!
All right, boys!
Release the hookers.
Pull, pull!
Hey!
Pull!
GULLIVER:
Hey, not cool.
Hey, that's my pants.
That's not funny!
Aah!
[SCREAMS]
Unlucky.
[SOLDIERS YELL]
MAN 1:
Heave!
MAN 2:
It was awful, horrid! Nightmarish!
I was trapped in the valley
of violent rumbles.
I was nauseous!
[CHATTERING]
Lift!
Squad, halt!
This giant is hereby declared...
the property of
His Majesty King Theodore.
All hail King Theodore!
ALL:
I wanted a bracelet,
not a great big hairy beast.
Oh, dear!
Are those restraints really necessary?
They are, my innocent,
naive little bunny tail.
To prevent the giant beast from
running rampant and killing us all.
What is this thing?
A Blefuscian spy.
I'm not a blue fish man.
I don't even know what that is.
Will someone please just
tell me where I am?
You are in Lilliput.
Lilli-puh?
JINKS: The grandest and greatest land
in all the world. All hail Lilliput!
ALL:
All hail Lilliput!
This is insane. This is insane.
Okay, enough.
Come out with the funny cameras.
[SCREECHING]
MAN 1:
Mealtime, beast!
Ah.
Hay? I can't eat hay.
FOREMAN: Eat up! You have
a busy day ahead of you, beast!
Enough with the beast!
I may be a giant, but I have feelings!
MAN 2:
Ahem. Um....
I think you'll find that the hay...
is a bit more digestible
if mixed with some...
sewer water.
I'm sorry that my countrymen call you
a beast. I do not think of you as a beast.
As a matter of fact,
before you arrived...
I was the tallest man in Lilliput.
So I know how you feel.
Thanks, man.
I'm, uh--
I can't reach you for a handshake.
I'm Gulliver.
Horatio.
Oh, man.
You guys are so tiny.
Are you the only other prisoner
in the whole dungeon?
HORATIO:
Yes.
I have been placed in this prison
by the great and glorious...
General Edward Edwardian...
for sending a lascivious look
to his betrothed...
Princess Mary.
That's it?
He put you in prison
for hitting on his lady?
Mm-hm.
Dude, that is harsh.
No, you must understand.
I am of a lowly station.
To legally court a woman
of her stature...
one must commit a valiant action...
and this is virtually impossible
as a commoner.
Come on, don't be so hard on yourself.
You seem like a cool guy.
You could do something valiant.
General Edward has led
countless crusades...
and is known far and wide
for his bravery.
I'm no General Edward.
Well, no offense...
this Edward guy seems
like kind of a lame ass.
EDWARD: A lame what?
Huh?
It is my impression...
that "lame ass"...
is a negative expression
from whence you came.
If this is the case...
you shall be thrown in the stocks!
No, no, no!
"Lame ass" means...
great...
brave and courageous...
heart-of-a-lion man.
Is this the honorable truth?
Yes, this is the honorable truth.
EDWARD:
Then, I am not just...
a lame ass.
Oh, no.
I'm a big lame ass!
The biggest!
I, General Edward Edwardian,
am the biggest lame ass in all of the land!
Heart of a lion.
Hurrah!
GULLIVER:
So, listen...
now that you know we're cool...
what do you say you loosen
up these shackles a bit?
No.
It is time for your life
of hard labor to begin.
[SIGHS]
EDWARD:
Left!
Forward!
GULLIVER: Ow! Ow!
EDWARD: Left!
Right!
Left!
Their defense system is operational.
We must move in stealthily.
Left!
Did I tell you to stop fanning, peasant?
Sorry.
They will be too busy with the fire
to protect their princess.
[BELL TOLLING]
A fire!
A fire is two bells, that was three.
It's an attack!
No, it actually sounded more like...
two bells, and then, a pause...
and then a third bell.
So, it's an attack and a fire?
The Blefuscians!
The princess!
EDWARD:
To the castle, beast!
Left, right, left, right.
Faster, beast!
[GULLIVER GRUNTING]
Oh, no. The Blefuscians.
Do not kidnap me.
Please do not kidnap me.
GULLIVER:
Why is she just standing there?
Of course, she's gonna
get kidnapped if she--
You speak not of the princess. Down!
I shall save you,
my princess.
My princess.
Dude, I can help.
We do not need your help, beast.
You just stay here.
Nobody save the princess!
He'll never get to her in time.
Please, you must save the princess.
But you heard that angry
little dingleberry. He said I shouldn't.
I beg of you!
It is too late.
You are kidnapped.
I am kidnapped!
GULLIVER:
Not on my watch.
[BLEFUSCIANS WHIMPERING]
[BLEFUSCIANS SCREAMING]
GULLIVER: Hop on, princess.
Let's get you out of here.
Fear not, my darling!
I am here to save you.
Where has she gone?
Oh, she has been kidnapped.
GULLIVER:
There you go, Princess.
Thank you so much.
HORATIO:
Are you okay?
Yes.
Thank God.
[BELL RINGING]
The Blefuscians are retreating.
We are to have a victory feast.
HORATIO:
How lovely.
[BELL TOLLING]
The fire has raged out of control.
My father is trapped!
You guys have to invest
in a more efficient warning system.
Your Highness!
[JINKS SCREAMS]
Out of the way.
I have to put out a fire.
I'm coming through!
The beast!
Ah!
[GRUNTING]
Yama-schatzi, that's hot!
HORATIO:
Princess, no!
Princess, you mustn't.
Father! He's burning!
You have served me
with great honor.
We need access
to a great deal of water.
MARY:
Do something!
[SINGING]
Oh, Lilliput, great kingdom...
[SOBBING]
I do not wanna do this.
You have a plan?
I have a plan,
but you're not gonna like it.
[ZIPPER ZIPS]
[CROWD MURMURS]
Don't look.
Cease, beast!
It's working!
Huzzah!
Yeah, it's working!
EDWARD:
Out of my way!
How dare you evacuate yourself...
on our great and glorious king!
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Sorry about the smell.
I've been drinking sewer water.
This is grounds for execution!
I know, that was pretty gross.
Let me pull up my trousers.
MARY:
Father!
Oh-- Aah! You look glorious.
Thank you, my dear.
Our savior!
The beast!
JINKS:
Beast! Beast! Beast!
[CROWD CHANTING]
You guys, it was nothing, really.
I saw a fire...
I had some water, I released!
Flood on aisle two.
Does that translate here?
Is that a joke here?
Flood on aisle two?
[LAUGHS]
Thanks, you guys.
[JINKS CLEARS THROAT]
The king requests the honor
of your company...
at a banquet this evening.
Do you accept?
Yeah.
On one condition.
You free my friend, Horatio,
and allow me to bring him as my plus one.
He is jailed for... unlawful
courting. He must return.
That's my condish!
One moment, if you will.
Why are you doing this for me?
Because you're my buddy.
I'm not gonna go to this thing without you.
I'm not gonna know anybody there.
You have to come.
JINKS: Ahem!
GULLIVER: Play it cool.
[JINKS CLEARS THROAT]
The king requests
the honor of your...
and Horatio the Glovier's company at a
royal banquet this evening. Do you accept?
Yes, indeed.
[PANTING]
I can make it.
JINKS: Oh, God.
HORATIO:
Whoa. Oh, my God.
I'm forever indebted to you.
It's not necessary.
Instead, let's just do this.
What is that?
You pound it with your fist!
Come on, don't leave me hanging.
Yeah!
Now let's go party!
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC]
GULLIVER:
Is anyone gonna...
I'm just gonna go ahead and get this.
[GULLIVER SLURPING]
ISABELLE:
So, since you're not...
from Blefuscia...
where are you from...
beast?
Uh, heh. Once again, totally cool
to be just called Gulliver.
Some people believe you've come
from the Island Where We Dare Not Go.
[ALL GASP]
Is there any truth to this rumor?
No. Where's the
Island Where We Dare Not Go?
[ALL GASP]
THEODORE:
There...
beyond the fog bank.
GULLIVER:
I didn't come through a fog bank.
I'm from the island of Manhattan...
between the islands of...
Staten and Long.
This island of Manhattan,
what sort of kingdom is it?
I'm not from a kingdom.
I'm actually from a democracy.
You see, we elect a president
every four years.
ISABELLE:
You are so honorable...
and courageous.
Were you the president?
Of course, he was, Mother.
Look at him.
He is the most powerful
gentleman in all the land.
I'm so sorry if Mother
embarrassed you.
No, it's a common mistake
to not think I was president.
THEODORE:
Were you a victorious president?
Yeah. I was pretty victorious.
Noble, as well?
Yeah, I was super noble.
I was actually known
as "President the Awesome."
"President the Awesome."
Pretty unlikely title.
When do you return home,
noble and awesome Gulliver?
Pretty soon, I suppose.
Yes?
I should imagine they're
falling apart without you...
their greatest hero.
Well, without my boat,
looks like I'm stuck here.
THEODORE: Don't worry.
My army will find your boat.
In the meantime,
we could find you accommodations.
Like some hay to sleep on?
Anything.
Anything?
We are the finest builders in all the land.
We can build you anything.
Seriously, we are ridiculously
good builders.
And we are your servants,
awesome Gulliver.
I don't wanna take advantage,
but, uh...
GULLIVER:
It's day seven of my stay here in Lilliput.
At first, me and the little guys
got off on the wrong foot...
but turns out they're
a pretty solid group of dudes.
They're building me
a temporary place to live.
They threw me an awesome party
just for releasing myself...
and the king sent out
a search party to find my boat.
In the meantime...
I'm roughing it.
Mm.
That is a good cup ofjoe.
Good morning.
MAN 1:
Morning, Gulliver.
MAN 2: Morning!
MAN 3: Morning!
Top of the morning to you, fellas.
HORATIO:
Gulliver...
your media room is ready.
[SCREAMS]
Obi-Wan never told you
what happened to your father.
AUGUST [AS GULLIVER]:
He told me enough. He told me...
you killed him!
JINKS [AS DARTH VADER]:
No, Gulliver.
I am your father.
[GASPING]
No way.
This is an impossibility!
Yet somehow, it seems
completely inevitable.
Gulliver, you truly have
lived a thousand lives.
[AUGUST SCREAMS]
King Theodore, it is time to perform
our bi-weekly military exercises.
Just one moment.
We're watching the stories...
of Gulliver's life.
We have not missed a military
exercise in over three hundred years.
Dude!
Get out of the way.
We cannot see the screen!
EDWARD:
Move! Move!
AUGUST [AS GULLIVER]:
The Titanic is sinking!
But it was meant to be unsinkable.
[ROSE GASPING]
I love you, Gulliver.
AUGUST:
No, don't do that.
You're gonna make lots of babies
and die in a warm bed...
in old age.
AUGUST:
I'm cold.
And also...
I'm king of the world!
ROSE:
Oh, Gulliver.
[SOBBING]
MAN 1:
Bravo!
MAN 2:
Encore!
EDWARD:
Wait!
I'm sorry.
You mean to say that you actually died
in this shipwreck?
Yeah, I died.
You actually died.
But I was resuscitated.
It's preposterous.
No, but then I survived.
It's ridiculous.
You have to see the seq--
But you're okay now!
It's silly.
Just silly, silly stories.
[SCOFFS]
Pfft.
HORATIO:
So, let me get this straight.
After you were brought back
to life as an avatar...
that's when you met your princess,
Darcy Silverman of Manhattan?
Yeah. Can't wait to get back to her.
I noticed you had a little
eye contact with the princess.
How is it going?
Good, yeah!
I think if things go well,
within two to four years...
she may deign to speak to me.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold your horses.
Thank God.
Now, you can't woo a lady
by hoping she'll deign...
to speak to you.
To land a princess, you got to
employ some grade-A court-age.
Could you teach me?
Huh?
This court-age that you speak.
Yeah, I could teach you
some of my moves.
Yes!
Thank you.
If you beat me back home.
I need a head start.
On you mark, get set, go!
HORATIO:
I'm not ready to race you!
Princess! Oh, Princess!
Wherefore art thou, Princess?
Hello! Who calls?
It is I, Horatio.
Why are you so far away?
I don't want to invoke
the ire of thy father.
But I must be honest...
GULLIVER:
And tell ye...
MARY:
Tell me what, Horatio?
You don't have to be rich
to be my girl.
Say it!
You don't have to be rich
to be my girl.
You don't have to be cool
to rule my world.
Horatio, these passionate words
could get us into trouble.
There's no particular sign
I'm more compatible with.
that I'm more compatible with.
I just want your extra time and your...
[KISSING]
...kiss.
Kiss.
What beauty emanates from your lips!
Think I'm gonna dance now.
[TAYLOR GRAVES' "KISS" PLAYING]
I think I'd better dance now.
Think I'm gonna dance now!
[HUMMING]
I've gotta, gotta
GULLIVER:
Put more mustard on it, baby.
Feel it. Move your hips.
Maybe we can do the twirl
I don't think it's working.
You're not dancing good.
Shake it!
To have an attitude
I've never been wooed
with such unique passion.
It's working!
My love will be your food
Did I tell you?
Yes!
I hear someone coming!
Till the morrow.
Don't have to be cool
HORATIO:
It worked! I did it!
Let's go.
HORATIO:
Yes!
EDWARD:
To whom were you speaking, my darling?
No one.
Me. I was-- I was speaking to me.
Myself.
What are you doing in my chambers?
I have come to court you...
as I always do...
at this time of day.
Or have you already forgotten
who is your one true eternal love?
No, no. Of course,
I remember.
Remember what?
Oh, um....
That you are my one true...
...eternal love.
Eternal love.
It's just that I was talking...
with the giant and lost track of time.
I trust not this beast.
Seems trustworthy to me.
He's very nice.
You've done sewing.
Sewing. Yes.
An embroidery.
It's my grandmother's doily
and I'm trying to present--
I captured a hawk today.
Did you?
He lay in a field. I came behind him
and captured him with my bare hand.
This is impressive, also.
Ah.
Fun.
Fun courtship...
you and I have.
It is over now.
Must go.
Those villagers shan't
pillage themselves.
We must alert General Edward
of this at once.
We've found it.
I hear you, ring-a-ling-a-ding-dong.
Okay, I'm coming--
Oh. Hey, how's it going?
EDWARD:
Hello, beast!
I come bearing the most terrific news!
Yeah? Really?
We have discovered your ship.
The Knotfersail. Ha, ha, ha.
Clever name.
You did it!
You found my boat.
I'm actually going home.
Hey, you guys can
fix this thing, right?
Of course, you can.
You're incredibly awesome builders.
Yes!
[GULLIVER LAUGHING]
Darcy is about to read
the best article ever.
I'm talking Pulitzer.
"Slide to unlock."
GULLIVER:
What are you guys doing?
[SOLDIER SCREAMS]
Is that my phone?
Man, it takes a lickin'.
No signal, but I got 12 messages.
Mr. Popularity.
DARCY [ON RECORDING]:
Hey, Gulliver. It's me. It's Darcy.
I just realized why I felt like
your writing came straight...
out of Frommer's. Because it does!
Call me as soon as you get this.
Sergeant Peacock, what's it doing?
He's checking his voicemail,
General Edward.
Good.
What's voicemail?
DARCY: Hey, Lemuel! It's Darcy.
I've totally forgiven you.
Wait! No, I haven't...
because now I have to get seasick
on a boat to cover your butt!
Thanks for this.
And if you can't tell,
that "thanks" was sarcastic.
Darcy, again.
I can't believe you lied to me.
I trusted you.
Wherever you're hiding, stay there.
I never want to hear from you again.
Mr. Beast...
I've instructed our builders...
to work day and night to ensure
you are seaworthy by week's end.
Isn't that just the most fantastical news
you've ever received in your life?
Great.
I can't tell you how happy I am...
for you.
[SIGHS]
MARY: Why do you look
so forlorn, noble protector?
Me? Forlorn? No way.
You do look quite forlorn.
Just for the record,
what's "forlorn" mean, again? Is it "sad"?
Basically, it's just a bit
more dramatic-sounding.
Yeah, well, in that case,
I guess I am a little forlorn.
Oh, Gulliver...
you miss your princess.
Well...
The truth is, we're not super close.
Oh, Gulliver.
She's kind of mad at me right now.
MARY:
I am forlorn as well.
I don't know what to do.
I think I'm in love with Horatio.
But that's great!
Don't be forlorn about that.
Most people spend their lives
looking for that and don't find it.
Go for it! Follow your heart.
But my heart is promised
to General Edward.
And I cannot break that vow.
He will lose honor and respect.
And he will die of heartbreak.
Okay. Look, he's just
being melodramatic.
Is he?
Yeah.
Gulliver, I will
miss you so much.
I'm gonna miss you, too.
Maybe I should stay.
Don't you miss
your subjects?
And the White House?
And the Millennium Falcon?
Yeah.
But Vice President Yoda
can run things without me for a while.
Do you think the king would mind
if I stuck around for a bit?
Well, of course not, Gulliver.
You've made everyone here so happy.
I can't imagine anyone in Lilliput not
wanting you to stay as long as possible.
EDWARD:
Noble and valiant King Theodore.
I trust-eth not this beast,
Gulliver who lives-t in our midst-ith-ith.
He can now leave-th but he
chooses to stay. And furthermore....
I do not believe it
who he say-eth he is-eth.
I most-eth humbly disagree-eth.
And why-eth must we always
go on with these "eths"?
Because we speak officially-eth.
Forget it. From now on,
even when speaking officially...
we must get rid of these "eths."
Official speaking is...
an illustrious
Lilliputian tradition!
Whoa! Inside castle voice. Please.
Forgive me-eth.
Forgive me.
I think this job is
beginning to stress you out.
Maybe a little time off
would be the thing.
[SCOFFING]
Who else could run your army?
THEODORE:
Our new general, Gulliver!
[CROWD CHEERING]
I won't let you down, King.
And I look forward to working with you,
Vice General Edward.
Hm.
"Vice General." Vice!
I've never been a Vice of anything.
I can't be expected to take orders
from that gargantuan fool.
I would rather take orders
from a woman.
You are relieved.
Thank you, Vice General Edward.
All right, Gulliver,
protect against this.
They have turned off
their defense system.
Alert the king,
and prepare the armada.
Oh, no. Our defense system has failed.
We shall never reach
our ships on time.
Careful now. Mind yourselves.
Oh, what a mess.
They are defenseless.
Cease fire and ready the troops!
Gulliver!
GULLIVER: Mm-hm.
HORATIO:
The Blefuscians attack!
Are you sure?
Yes!
Please, we need you.
You're our general.
[SOLDIERS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[BELL TOLLING]
THEODORE:
Good lord!
It's the entire Blefuscian armada!
I know.
Finally! Our general
has arrived.
What's going on?
I heard the bells.
As our mighty general...
you must lead the army
to save Lilliput...
and vanquish
the entire Blefuscian armada.
GULLIVER:
You want me to...
vanquish all of them?
Yes, please.
Every last one of them.
Yeah, fine.
Thank you, fair Gulliver.
Okay, here we go.
Time to vanquish.
LILLIPUTIANS:
Whoa!
[CROWD GASPS]
Ooh! It's cold!
Ha, ha! Whoo!
No problem.
You're going down!
Why have we stopped?
It's him.
Hey.
Hey, dudes.
I'm Gulliver.
I come in peace. Listen...
they want me to vanquish you,
but I don't want to vanquish anybody...
and you don't want
to be vanquished.
Let's just pretend,
okay? I'll go crazy.
You act all scared
and just follow my lead, all right?
Sell it!
Okay. Here we go.
Unfurl the sails!
Hard to starboard!
Battle stations.
Prepare positions.
Move! Move!
This truly is a battle
for the ages.
It truly is.
[YELLING]
Okay, so now, I'll just tell them you
were too swift or whatever and--
How come you all turned around?
Fire!
Oh, no. That looks painful.
[GROANING]
CAPTIAN:
Move!
I'm invincible.
Yes!
Go on, Gulliver!
[ALL YELLING]
[KISS'S "ROCK AND ROLL
ALL NITE" PLAYING]
Well done, sir!
Well done! Excellent!
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Gulliver! Gulliver!
Well done, you big, fat beast.
You show us everything you've got
[CHANTING CONTINUES]
GULLIVER:
Yes!
Pound it.
Respect.
Well done, Gulliver!
SOLDIER: Awesome!
Ha!
You say you wanna
Go for a spin
The party's just begun
We'll let you in
Pass!
That's a foul! That's disgraceful!
[LAUGHING]
Goal!
The beast is
victorious.
Goal!
All right!
Yeah!
Guys, this is what
I'm talking about.
Look at that. With the
billboards and the lights...
it's home sweet home.
What can I say?
Hey, could you guys send over a panzer
division to my left shoulder, please?
Yeah, north, two klicks.
One klick.
Oh, yeah, that's the spot.
Okay, just a little off the top.
Don't go crazy.
And don't shave off my sideburns.
I need those mutton chops.
And you drive us wild
We'll drive you crazy
You keep on shoutin'
BAND [SINGING]:
I wanna rock and roll
All night
And party every day
I wanna rock and roll all night
GULLIVER & BAND:
And party every day
I wanna
Rock and roll all night
And you are
My bitch
And I double-defeated you
because I was playing and singing
You did good, though.
Let's try it again from the top.
One sec, please. Pause game.
Pause game.
I was just thinking.
You're general of Lilliput now.
Shouldn't you be training the army?
What if Blefuscia should attack again?
Come on, man!
No one's gonna attack.
Not while I'm around.
I'm a one-man wrecking crew.
If you want to worry,
you should be worrying about how...
you haven't made a move
on the princess yet.
You're in danger of falling
into friendship lagoon.
What?
Yeah, friendship lagoon. It blows.
You're gonna be like, "We're friends,
it's great. I'm cool with that."
And you won't be cool
with that!
And it kills you inside.
No. No, never!
Yeah, man!
You have to man up and be direct.
Next time you see her,
just tell her what's up.
"Hey, what's up, sexy?
"I hope it's not too forward,
but I find you incredibly sexy.
"Never told you before
but I'm into you...
"but I'm also into a lot of things,
so don't get too excited.
"Got a lot of things going on.
I'd like you to be one of them."
You see the way
I mixed it up?
"I want you, but not
that much." You try it.
Okay...
should I use the face?
If the face comes to you,
but make it natural.
Don't make it a forced face.
I just have one of those faces.
It sort of happens naturally.
My hands are sweating.
Go.
Okay. Ahem.
Well, hello...
fine maiden with
the wide, childbearing hips.
Yikes. You don't want to talk
about wide childbearing hips.
It's a good instinct.
You're getting there.
But try it again. But this time,
more smooth and sexy.
No big hips?
No big hips.
I think I got it.
Ahem.
Well, hello there, slim.
I ought to call you "potamus"...
because you've got no hip.
[LAUGHS]
Do we have to
be here for this?
Take five, save game.
Forget about the hips.
Here's what you have to do.
GULLIVER:
You have to make sure...
[FOOTSTEPS]
[MARY SIGHS]
What are you doing...
in my chambers?
I have come to court you as I
always do at this time of day.
This is not the time of day
for courting.
You cannot just barge in.
I can court you when
I wish to court you.
I am not in the mood to be courted.
I have a headache.
It is your womanly duty.
Section 4.2 of
the official courting doctrine--
Edward!
I am unsure about things
between us.
It be not you, it be me,
but I'm very unsure.
That make-th no sense.
We are to be married.
You are to be my bride.
We are not in love.
What do you love about me?
Name one thing.
Inappropriate, Edward.
Reach for it.
One second.
Okay, take your time.
I find you...
absolutely...
satisfactory.
Ooh. No.
That is not enough...
to say that someone is average
or adequate or moderate.
I want to be loved
for who I am.
There's an awful lot...
going on up here.
Is there?
Now you're being cruel...
and, frankly, melodramatic.
And acting like a complete baby!
You are acting like
a little princess.
I am a princess!
But maybe you should...
act like a princess.
Gulliver was so right about you.
Why don't we all listen to the beast!
Don't call him that!
He's a big ugly beast
and you should know better.
Get out!
You cannot break our engagement!
It is worse than death!
Get out!
You will be sorry you ever
crossed General Edward.
Ugh.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
VENDOR: Get your Gulliver's
T-shirts! Dress like Gulliver.
You, sir!
Get your Gulliver's T-shirts here.
Get your Gulliver's T-shirts here!
Gulliver's T-shirts!
Look at him. He's handsome!
What do you want?
This beast...
has transformed Lilliput...
into his own sordid
and rotten little kingdom.
And he will do the same with
your land if we do not stop him.
To save Lilliput...
I must first destroy it.
How do you suggest
we accomplish...
such a dangerous task?
[FOOTSTEPS MARCHING]
EDWARD:
I have got stuff! Look.
I'm showing you.
GULLIVER: All right! Welcome to
the first ever Lillapalooza!
Let's get this party started
with a little jam I wrote!
[GUNS N' ROSES' "SWEET CHILD
O' MINE" PLAYING OVER PA]
Right?
What are you up to
in the morrow?
In the morrow?
Yes.
I am, uh...
I'm just hanging.
You know, so, yeah.
Oh, um...
Would you care to attend the Ball
of the Moonlit Glen with me?
The ball?
Yeah.
The ball is tomorrow?
Mm-hm.
Right. Maybe.
GULLIVER:
It's a pretty tasty jam!
Pretty tasty jam.
Why are you acting
like this?
Acting like what?
Why are you being so strange?
I'm...
I'm a gentleman merchant
about town...
and I have got to keep
my options open.
Do you?
That's what I've been told.
I'm not an option. I'm a lady.
I know you are, and I love ladies.
Believe me-- Okay!
I'm sorry. I was--
[BELL TOLLING]
Five bells!
Five bells? What does
five bells mean?
There have never been five bells.
Yeah? Don't worry about it...
because this guy throws down
no matter how many bells are a-ringin'.
[CROWD SCREAMING]
Don't freak, little peeps.
This one is on me.
You must be kidding me.
This is five bells?
Pfft!
[GULLIVER CHUCKES]
Ahh. It's cute.
Edward, you traitor!
How dare you forsake
your Lilliputian brethren!
I only forsooked after I was forsooken.
The forsookingness ends now!
I challenge you to a duel!
ALL:
Ooh.
Ooh. Cool. Whatever.
So, you accept?
Oh, yeah! Yeah, I accept your duel.
Oh, goody!
Make a move.
Ha, ha!
Wow, you are hard.
Okay!
Just...
stretching out the hammies.
It's a good thing to do
before the duel.
[GROWLS]
You brought this
on yourself, beast.
Do you surrender, beast?
Sure, yeah! Whatever!
EDWARD:
No, say it properly.
Say you surrender.
Oh, yeah.
Say it! Say it!
Say, "I surrender!"
I surrender!
I surrender, I surrender!
You win.
It hurts my butt.
You cannot surrender!
You are our most glorious protector!
You're President the Awesome!
ISABELLE: And you and Captain Sparrow
defeated the Joker and Magneto!
And you and Jack Bauer
had only 24 hours to do it!
I didn't do any of that stuff.
I'm just a guy from the mailroom.
But you gave us your word!
I'm sorry.
I lied.
[CROWD GASPS]
I knew it!
I hereby banish this beast...
to the Island Where
We Dare Not Go...
never to return
to Lilliput again!
SENTRY:
Take your positions!
Please, Gulliver.
Hey...
is this Island Where We Dare Not Go
really as bad as they say?
It's delightful!
[GROANS]
Okay.
No little people anywhere.
That's a good sign.
Hello! Is anybody here?
No way.
[GROWLING]
Aah!
SENTRY:
Raise the standard!
MAN 1:
Let's lose this rubbish!
MAN 2:
Lower away!
Can I not walk alone
in my own garden?
Go away!
Princess!
I've secured a boat.
We can leave tonight.
No, Horatio.
But Edward is gonna
force you to marry him.
I don't have
any choice.
Please. Of course
you have a choice.
No, you made
that choice for me.
You don't understand.
Gulliver told me--
Everything Gulliver
said was a lie...
including you.
[COUGHING]
DARCY: Oh, I'm paralyzed
from the neck down.
What's that? What's crawling on me?
Not fire ants.
Oh, please don't be fire an--
I am General
Edward Edwardian...
commander of New Blefuscia.
All hail New Blefuscia.
ALL:
All hail New Blefuscia!
I must warn Gulliver.
EDWARD:
State your name...
she-beast.
Darcy Silverman.
Of Manhattan.
[SCREAMS]
[CLOCKS TICKING]
[YAWNS]
[RUMBLING]
Oh, no!
[GULLIVER SCREAMING]
[BURPS]
[GRUNTING]
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I'm not doing this.
You got me in the diaper and the dress.
I'm not doing teatime with you.
Go find another doll.
[GROWLS]
[FABRIC TEARS]
Tea! Time for tea! Ha, ha!
[GRUNTING]
Okay, we're kissing.
Gentler. Let's just
hold hands or something!
[GROANS]
What's up?
What kind of toy are you?
Top Gun G.I. Joe?
Cool detail.
[GULLIVER YELLS]
[GULLIVER SIGHS]
[HORATIO GRUNTING]
HORATIO:
Gulliver!
Down here.
What are you doing here?
Gulliver, you must return
to Lilliput with me at once.
Forget it, man.
It's a no-go.
No, you don't understand.
Edward has--
It doesn't matter.
I may be a hundred feet tall, but I'm not
half the size of one of you little guys.
You have to listen.
This is important.
No, this is where I belong.
As a giant girl's baby doll.
Hey!
Stop feeling sorry
for yourself and listen!
Blefuscia has taken over Lilliput...
and Edward has captured
Darcy Silverman of Manhattan.
What?
She's--
Darcy's here?
Yeah.
Oh, no.
She said she was gonna
do the assignment herself.
She's here because of me.
It's all because of you.
How could you
lie to us?
I...
I was afraid to tell
you guys the truth...
because it was just so great being
a big shot for the first time in my life.
I didn't want it to end.
Snap out of it, man.
You think of yourself as this small
little thing, but that's not how I see you.
Think about what you've done already.
You saved the princess.
You single-handedly defeated
the entire Blefuscian armada.
Didn't you? Come on.
I'm your best friend.
I wouldn't lie to you.
You can do this.
So, take off that dress
and let's get out of here!
Am I really your best friend?
You're kind of my only friend.
Sweet, man. You, too, for me.
Let's go save Lilliput.
Yeah, let's go do this.
Take me with you, yeah?
One sec. There we go.
Oopsie-daisy.
I got you!
Okay, officer...
I'm just gonna borrow this
parachute if it's okay with you.
You don't need it anymore.
Eww.
[SCREAMING]
HORATIO:
This isn't safe!
I'll let you--
Thanks, Horatio.
Good luck.
I got this.
Darcy.
Darce.
Gulliver!
Hey.
I'm coming over there.
Gulliver!
Shh, shh, shh!
Are you okay?
I can't believe you're here.
I mean, of all the places, right?
What... Uh...
What's up?
What isn't up?
Can we talk about the inverted whirlpool?
Crazy.
And why is everybody
calling me your princess?
They don't.
I think you misheard.
THEODORE:
I see you have...
returned for your princess.
He did, right there.
He just called me your princess.
That's because everybody
is a princess here.
I forgot to tell you,
it's just sort of a thing.
If you wish to speak to your
one true love privately...
we shall cover our ears.
One true love?
You told them
I'm your one true love?
Is now a good or
bad time to tell you...
about the crush I've had on you
for the last five years?
Really?
Yeah, I totally have
a crush on you.
Is that why you bring the mail cart around,
but none of the mail is for me?
Yeah... Ahem.
Yeah.
And I...
I told everybody that
you were my girlfriend.
It's really embarrassing.
I think it's kind of sweet.
We must focus
because we have to book...
to the boat and get out of here.
We're surrounded by little people.
Darcy, listen to me.
I would love to book with you over
to the boat right now, but I can't.
These little people have grown
very large in my heart.
They depended on me...
and I let them down.
And I have to do this first.
King...
if it's all right with you, I'd like
to be your glorious protector again.
I don't know.
How are we to believe
anything you say, Gulliver?
Because my word
is my bond.
This time, for real.
I promise.
Gulliver.
Hm?
You work
in the mailroom.
Not today I don't.
[CROWD CLAMORING]
LILLIPUTIAN:
We're all with you, Gulliver.
Hey, Edward.
If I win...
Lilliput returns to her
former glory.
And if you lose...
this is what happens
to Lilliput.
[GASPS]
[GULLIVER GRUNTING]
Oh, I've made
a slight improvement.
Shocking, isn't it?
[CROWD GASPS]
Yeah!
Hey! That's not fair.
He's cheating.
I've got to do something.
[GROANS]
EDWARD:
Now do what you do best...
beast, and run along!
No way. Not today.
I've always liked you,
Gulliver.
I've always thought
we had a real spark!
Fear not, Gulliver!
I'm on my way!
Oh!
Aah!
[GULLIVER YELLING]
Gulliver! No!
Now stay down
this time, beast!
[YELLS]
It is on!
Go, Gulliver!
Yes, Gulliver! Go!
Yes!
Go on, Gulliver!
You can do it! Get him!
[EDWARD GRUNTING]
Help-eth.
Bouche!
Now, that's a wedgie!
Yay, Gulliver!
Yes! Well done!
Come on, Gulliver!
[BOTH LAUGHING]
You did it!
Did you see that?
I wedgied him back
to the second grade!
I'm so, so sorry.
I hope that you can forgive me
for the way that I behaved.
You're not an option...
you're the most beautiful
lady in all the land.
Who's also super cool...
and a stone-cold fox.
THEODORE:
Horatio!
Do you realize what you've done?
You have committed
an act of valiance.
I hereby...
give my permission.
GULLIVER:
Yeah.
EDWARD:
Nobody move!
Halt! Stop!
I have kidnapped the princess.
You have been kidnapped.
Congratulations.
Enough with
the kidnappings!
Bouche!
ALL: Bouche!
GULLIVER: Yes!
Listen, I plagiarized
all that stuff...
because I thought you'd never go out
with a dude from the mailroom.
And I'm sorry,
that will never happen again.
So, yeah, coffee...
THEODORE: I condemn you
and all Blefuscians to the gallows.
Prepare for war!
No...
you prepare for war!
Oh... I have to do one
more thing, real quick.
Kings, kings, come on!
Guys, what is it with you...
and the executions...
and the gallows
and the stocks...
...and the war?
Seriously, war?
Why do war?
What is it good for?
Absolutely naught!
[SINGING]
War!
ALL:
Huh!
Yeah
What is it good for?
Absolutely naught!
Say it again, y'all
War!
Huh!
Good God, y'all
What is it good for?
I find it good
for absolutely nil!
Oh
It's an enemy to all mankind
The point of war blows my mind
Life is much too short and precious
To spend fighting wars these days
War can't give life
It can only take it away
War!
Huh!
Good God, y'all
What is it good for?
Absolutely nothing!
Say it again, y'all
War!
Huh!
Yeah
What is it good for?
Absolutely nothing
Listen to me
Peace, love and understanding
Tell me, is there no place
For them today?
They say we must fight
To keep our freedom
But Lord knows
There's got to be a better way
War!
Huh!
Good God, y'all
What is it good for?
Tell me
Say it, say it, say oh!
War! Huh!
Good God, y'all
What is it good for?
Absolutely nothing
Just stand up and shout it!
Huh!
[ALL CHEERING]
You're gonna miss
your big friend?
A little.
Yeah?
A lot.
Oh, dear.
Oh...
[MIKE DOUGHTY'S "(I KEEP ON)
RISING UP" PLAYING]
I'll keep up risin' up
Well, I'll keep up risin' up
How was Papua,
New Guinea?
It was hot, sticky...
and the most mind-boggling
place I've ever seen.
The most mind-boggling
place you've ever seen?
Okay, second most
mind-boggling place.
Oh. Sorry.
Danny!
Got your morning mail, Gulliver.
[SPEAKS IN GERMAN]
DAN: Darcy.
Who's your friend?
I'm Mark. I'm just the new guy
in the mailroom.
Whoa, just the mailroom?
Mailrooms are where it's at.
Right, Dan?
Yeah, I don't know why
you would say that.
That's where
all the greats start.
Remember, there's no small jobs.
Just small people.
Teeny, tiny, teeny little people.
Remember I told you that?
There are no small jobs.
Just tiny, tiny, people.
Can I take you to lunch?
Of course you can...
my fair princess.
I'll keep up risin' up
Well, I'll keep up risin' up
Every day, I'm risin' up