ASTRONAUT: Mission Control, come
in. Mission Control, do you read?
Mayday. Mayday.
On reentry into Earth's orbit,
I seem to have fallen into,
I don't know, some kind
of tear in time and space.
My coordinates are unknown.
Is this even Earth?
Ship's instruments indicate
should be White Sands, New Mexico.
Obvious error. Is anyone
receiving this? Come back.
(ROARING)
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Recovery team! Recovery
team, fix coordinates now!
Where the hell am I?
Somebody respond!
Recovery team,
come back, God damn it!
Does anybody...
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Oh, God. Oh, God!
Does anyone read...
No!
MALE ANNOUNCER: This is
Today, with Matt Lauer.
We're back now with
Dr. Rick Marshall,
whose new book arrives
in stores tomorrow.
It was back in Oslo, Doctor, last month,
that you just startled your colleagues
with this theory of yours that takes
science in a completely new direction.
- Quantum...
- Quantum Paleontology.
Quantum Paleontology,
that's correct.
What exactly is that?
Well, it's... Not to say modestly,
it's our very future, Matt.
It's the only
real solution
to solving this fossil fuel
crisis we're experiencing.
And it boils down
to two simple words.
Renewable biofuels.
Close. Time warps.
- Time warps?
- Time warps.
You're serious about this.
I'm deadly serious.
Five years, over $50
million on my research.
You've spent $50 million of your
own money studying time warps?
No, that's adorable. No, taxpayers'
money. I don't have $50 million.
And now you're
asking for more.
It's all explained
in my book.
I know. We've plugged the book.
(READING)
Yeah.
Bantam Books. Amazon.
We are living in a time
right now with huge cuts in...
I saw.
- Huge cuts in spending.
- Right.
We're in dire economic straits,
and you're spending $50
million on studying time warps.
How do you not think
that's irresponsible?
- Well, I...
- Are you smoking?
No, I'm making a balloon
animal here, earthling.
But you can't smoke in the studio.
Okay, no one told me that.
Just, you can't.
Look, look... Fine.
There are huge, huge amounts of
trans-dimensional energy out there
just waiting for us to throw the switch.
Energy crisis averted.
You are asking people to stake the entire
future of industrialized civilization
on what you call
"parallel dimensions. "
What about the critics who
have a fair question, Doctor?
Mmm-hmm.
They say this theory of yours is
not science. It is non-science.
And some are even more blunt,
and they say it's nonsense.
How do you
respond to that?
- My critics?
- Your critics.
- And there are a lot of them.
- Can you be more specific?
Stephen Hawking.
Stephen Hawking says this
is nonsense. That's his word.
Okay, you know what?
This interview's over.
Why?
Because, like, your producers said
you wouldn't bring that up, all right?
It's a fair question.
No, it's not! It's a hatchet job!
That was my guest Dr. Rick Marshall,
whose book arrives in stores tomorrow.
RICK: Goddamn right it was!
You might want to look for it
in the "I'm out of my
freaking mind" department.
When we come back, trampolines.
Summer fun or silent killer?
MAN: Wait, wait! He's
making a run for the stage!
Are you out of your mind?
MAN: - Hey, he's so strong!
- What are you, crazy?
(RICK SCREAMING)
Ladies and gentlemen, esteemed
colleagues, I'll conclude with this.
Our very future depends on one thing.
(RICK READING)
Subatomic particles that
move so incredibly fast,
they actually travel backwards in time.
Ask yourself, what if there was a
device that could harness these tachyons?
We could open and travel
through warps in time and space.
What's that?
Not in our lifetime?
My friends, I've designed such a device.
I give to you
the tachyon amplifier.
Genius in a box.
Only with this device, you don't
travel forwards or backwards.
You travel sideways in time
to another dimension where past,
present and future all meet.
And lights!
All right, any questions?
Oh! Great. Yes.
You, right there, young man.
Yeah. If you shot a
ton of pot at the sun,
would it burn up
and get everybody high?
No. No, no.
Are there any real questions
that pertain to science?
Do you take Cialis?
BOY: Why were you crying in the
bathroom before this presentation?
How come it looks like
you're about to cry now?
Do dinosaurs have boobs?
That's it. That's it.
Everybody out of here.
Get out of here!
Go play in the parking lot.
Go run around on the
freeway, I don't care.
MAN: Okay, guys,
let's get some sugar!
I have a question.
Did you ever try to make
the tachyon amplifier?
Who are you?
Oh! I'm sorry.
I'm Holly Cantrell.
I studied all your
work at Cambridge.
I think you're brilliant.
Well, Holly from Cambridge
who thinks I'm brilliant,
I started, but I didn't finish. So, no.
No, but you have to build it. I
mean, it's the most incredible...
What are you eating?
It's a donut
stuffed with M&M's.
That way when you finish the donut,
you don't have to eat any M&M's.
But don't you see?
You were absolutely right.
- Everything...
- Stop!
Chasing that theory got me laughed out
of mainstream science and landed me here.
And you know what? I don't
have anyone to blame but myself.
'Cause, as they say, if you don't
make it, it's your own damn "vault. "
That's a bitch-slap
of truth right there.
If your theories are such
rubbish, then explain this.
That fossil is over
265 million years old
with an imprint
of a $10 lighter.
Go on, explain that.
I found it out in the desert
along with crystals like this
that radiate pure
tachyon energy.
Go on.
Explain that.
Captain Kirk's nipples!
FEMALE ANNOUNCER: The tar pits
will be open in five minutes.
Dr. Marshall,
please return the page.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
HOLLY: Dr. Marshall?
(MOANING)
Oh, my God.
Are you all right?
Hey. Up you get.
(GRUNTING)
Here. Just lean against...
Oh, dear.
I'm fine, okay.
I just worked late.
Then I got hungry, and I had several
meals and lapsed into a food coma.
(SIGHS)
I've had issues with food in the
past, and I don't know, you know,
just with the stress of
everything, I just overdid it.
But I'm in control, and I don't
have to go back to Phoenix.
I just... I wanted to come
and apologize for yesterday.
My behavior was just...
RICK: No, no, no, it was me.
(GASPS)
You finished the tachyon amplifier!
No. No. I mean, yes.
I don't know. I finished
building it, yes,
but I didn't have the
nerve to test it out.
So I thought a trip to Arby's might
give me some courage, but no dice.
Then I had Popeye's, Del Taco.
Fourteen thousand calories later,
I found myself down at Subway,
powering through a 12-inch
veggie on whole wheat,
babbling to a cutout of Jared.
It still didn't give me the
strength to turn that thing on.
I'm a coward.
You are not a coward.
You're a visionary.
This is probably the greatest work
of genius in the last 100 years.
(SHOW TUNE PLAYING)
(SINGING) God, I hope I
get it! I hope I get it
How many...
Is that A Chorus Line?
It's leftover data
from the drive.
What a piece of crap!
(SINGING)
Look at all the people...
The machine, I mean.
Not A Chorus Line.
I love show tunes. They really tell
the story of the human condition.
It's a bit gay.
It is great.
Right. Dr. Marshall, you're
gonna stop selling yourself short.
You're on the verge of
major discovery. Now get up.
Whoa! Where are we going?
We're gonna go and test this
little device in the field.
Are you crazy? I'm not
prepared for a field test.
Look, we're not gonna
make a big deal out of it.
It's just a routine expedition.
A routine expedition?
Purely routine.
HOLLY: Here. Here it is. This
is where I found the fossil.
The Devil's Canyon Mystery Cave.
(DEVICE BEEPING) RICK:
This dump is a portal?
HOLLY: Well, just
look at these readings!
We've just gotta get back in that cave.
RICK: No problem. The place
is obviously abandoned.
HOLLY: Not exactly.
So what's your pleasure?
I got Roman candles, bottle rockets,
twitter glitters, dancing butterflies.
This little bitch here,
I call the Mexican vasectomy.
Yeah?
Okay, that's in bad taste.
How about this?
This little travel mug I like
to call "The Perfect Woman".
Big old set of boobies,
no head and a handle.
Mmm-mmm.
Look, we want to go
in the cave, all right?
Okay, how about this?
Y'all spend $30 on crap,
I'll give you a deluxe tour.
It all goes to a great cause. The
Devil's Canyon Resort and Casino!
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Wow. That's nice craft.
Seven thousand luxuriously
appointed rooms.
Three casinos. One convention
center. Ass-tons of parking.
And when everything is complete,
I will turn the tip of this golden
teepee into my personal lair,
and I will take a mate and live the
rest of my life with her up here.
And when we fight
and she pisses me off,
I will banish her to this tip,
where she will be kept
as a prisoner and a slave.
Y'all gonna buy anything?
Yeah. Fine.
Hey, Ern! Taking these guys
to the cave. Watch the store.
Close your mouth while you're
breathing, like we talked about.
You're making everybody
over here feel weird.
Prepare to meet your darkest fears
inside the depths of The
Devil's Canyon Mystery Cave!
(SIGHS)
Rule number one, keep your
arms and legs inside the boat.
Rule number two, have a
kick-ass, awesome time.
But be warned,
you may get wet.
I'm sorry, "may"?
Actually, I need to know.
This equipment cannot get wet.
Not you. Mary Poppins.
(EXCLAIMING)
Say that again, and I'll drown you.
Good to go.
(WHOOPING)
Cave ride begins!
Caveologists say this
old cave is 100 years old
and holds 1,000 mysteries.
Or is it 1,000 years
old and 100 mysteries?
Well, that, my friends,
is just one of the mysteries.
Say what you will,
the man is a showman.
Without a doubt,
this cave is most infamous
for the legend of the
Devil's Canyon Lizard Man.
He's been seen around these
parts since the Pilgrim times.
Snapping his claws, hissing,
trying to eat people up,
lurking about in the dark,
dark shadows of this very cave.
(LAUGHS EVILLY)
But those are just legends.
Aren't they?
Are you asking us?
No, I'm not. Ernie! Aren't they?
Here it comes, Will.
(WILL SCREAMS)
(WHOOPS) Oh, God!
The Lizard Man!
You're paying for that.
I most definitely am not.
You know, I'm sitting here trying to
give you guys a really awesome adventure,
and you guys are giving me
nothing in return.
I got the gloves on,
the hat, the pageantry.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
Holly, I'm getting
a strong tachyon reading.
I think I can boost the hell out
of the signal with a resonant wave.
Well, go for it.
Man, you guys don't even care.
(SHOW TUNE PLAYING)
(SINGING) God, I hope I
get it! I hope I get it
No, no! There are no
show tunes on this ride!
God, I hope I get it!
I hope I get it
How many boys? How many girls?
Something's happening.
Is this part of the ride?
No, Hoss, this ain't me.
This is an earthquake.
(DEVICE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Greatest earthquake ever known!
Marshall, I think
you should turn it off!
Marshall, the meter!
Swim, Holly!
We're moving!
WILL: This isn't me! This isn't me!
RICK: Why are we moving so fast?
Do I look like I know what's going on?
(HOWLS)
What's that sound?
Is there a waterfall in here?
Hell, no, dude! This
isn't even a real stream!
It's industrial runoff from the
soap factory down the street!
RICK: What is that? What
is that? What is that?
Oh, God! Oh, shit!
This is not a routine expedition!
WILL: Reverse! Reverse! Boat, reverse!
It's beautiful!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(BREATHING HARD)
I gotta say, I did not see that coming.
Ernie, you bastard.
That was way too fast.
Ernie! Too fast!
Marshall!
I think you should
come and look at this!
Do you realize what this means?
RICK: Yes! It means
Matt Lauer can suck it!
(RICK WHOOPING)
- Holly, are you rolling?
HOLLY: - Yeah.
WILL: That was
a Viking ship!
- And a Cessna!
- Shut up! Just shut up!
Okay, currently in our party,
me, Dr. Rick Marshall,
doctoral candidate Holly Cantrell,
and some trashy trailer park reject
who smells of malt liquor and feet.
- I'm standing right here!
- I was right. Okay?
Holly, right here.
Just as I predicted, we have been...
We have fallen through a time portal
from our Earth to another dimension
where past, present and future
are all mashed up together.
WILL: How the hell did this happen?
My tachyon amplifier,
that's how it happened!
You mean that shitty boom box
pumping show tunes?
Yes, it worked.
Well, where the hell is it?
Okay, minor setback.
My tachyon amplifier, which
undoubtedly will be the only
possible way for us
to open a doorway home,
is nowhere to be seen.
What?
(SQUEALING)
(HOLLY GASPS)
WILL: What the hell was that?
I have no idea, but let's go find out.
(SQUEALING)
HOLLY: - Advanced primates.
RICK: - Yeah.
They've got the posture
of an Australopithecine,
but the sagittal crest suggests that...
No, no, no, shut up!
I will not let you ruin this moment.
I've waited my entire life
to see the mighty Bigfoot.
Hey, man, are you touching yourself?
Marshall, look!
(SQUEALS)
Oh, my God.
Tool construction!
No, they're gonna kill him!
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
(SHOUTING) No!
Uh-oh!
Okay, you eggheads,
you follow my lead.
I know just how to
party with these guys.
You little monkey bastards!
Prepare to bow down
and worship me!
For behold, ye troglodytes,
I command the power of fire.
Will, that's not a good idea.
How do you like me now?
You wanna disco dance with...
Ow! Son of a bitch!
(MOANING)
Well done.
You've now just given murderous
primitives the power of fire.
HOLLY: It's all right.
It's all right.
Don't be frightened.
We're friends.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Friends.
(SNARLS)
Careful, Holly.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. There we go.
I spent three years at the
Manchester Zoo primate house.
I'm recognizing
a very primitive language.
Now, me, Holly.
Holly.
Yes! Holly!
Horry.
Holly. Me, Holly.
You?
Me.
Chaka.
Chaka. Chaka! No.
Holly. Chaka.
(WHISPERING) Nice work.
Yeah. Will. Will.
Good work. Good work, Holly.
Let me take over from here.
Greetings.
Chaka! Chaka.
I'm Dr. Rick Marshall.
Dr. Rick Marshall.
Okay?
Let's take a look at that
ankle. Does that sound good?
Keep in mind, Chaka, although I'm a
doctor, I'm not a licensed physician.
Okay? I'm just gonna
take a little look.
(GROWLS)
How dare you? How dare
you? I mean you no harm!
- I mean you no harm!
- Marshall! Marshall! Marshall!
RICK: Don't you run
from me, you little shit!
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
Now you're dead!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL COUGHING)
RICK: Damn you, Chaka.
Now, was that
necessary?
(SNARLING)
Marshall, Marshall,
wait, you'll scare him.
What was that?
Look, he was never
in any danger, okay?
Chaka. Friend.
Safety. Safety. Safety!
Holly, tell him.
Marshall! Marshall!
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Here...
(EXCLAIMS)
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Well, that's more like it.
Holly, what did you tell him?
I think I told him that you're a
great chief, and you're very powerful,
and I think he's pledging
his lifelong loyalty to you.
That's hardly necessary,
my little friend,
but I will honor your customs.
And you may serve me.
(LAUGHING)
In return, I will be a fair
but very strict master.
Okay. Off! Off!
What is wrong with you people?
That sandpit swallowed us!
I mean, can you all please act like
this doesn't happen every single day?
You're starting to make
me feel really stupid.
RICK: Okay, okay, hold on.
Let's gather ourselves.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Take a deep breath in.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS) Oh, my God!
(SQUEALING)
(ALL GASPING)
RICK: Fortunately, I've been in this
exact situation three times before.
WILL: When? When have you ever
been in this situation before?
RICK: I've never been
in this situation before!
I'm just trying
to keep up morale.
(ROARING)
God, I sure hope
that was a coyote.
Good God!
It's a feeding station!
If anyone knows about
meal presentation, it's me.
Oh, God! Oh, God!
Grab hands!
Create some momentum.
Let's swing
over to that tree.
(GRUNTING)
Extension.
WILL: Okay. Reach.
RICK: Good form, everyone!
Working in concert!
Don't be afraid to point the toe.
One more.
One more should do it.
(ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Everybody move out! Chaka,
your master commands you to...
Bad Chaka! Your loyalty
is now in question!
WILL: That was a dinosaur!
RICK: T. Rex!
Definitely in predator mode.
WILL: Will you hurry up?
You're slowing us down!
Why are you wearing high heels?
RICK: They're not high heels.
They're my Florsheim zipper boots.
Why are you wearing Florsheims
on a field expedition?
I told you I was not prepped
to go into the field!
(ROARING)
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait! We need a photo.
Nice field skills, Holly!
- Will, stand over there.
- What?
This is proof I'm right,
and I want photos.
Stand there.
We need you for scale.
Scale?
Marshall, do we need
the red eye feature?
Yes, his eyes do look red.
Jesus Christ, just take the
picture! Okay, just stand still!
- Stand still, please.
- Okay, ready.
One, two, three!
Fantastic.
Run! Run like hell!
Where the hell's the monkey?
Look! Chaka's waiting for us
at the other end of the bridge!
Good Chaka!
Your master's pleased!
(GRUNTING)
Marshall, it really looks like
he's trying to destroy the bridge.
Chaka, wait!
Master not pleased!
It's okay.
He can't cross.
He has terrible
depth perception.
He thinks this chasm's
a million miles long.
He's not what you'd call
an athlete, Mr. T. Rex.
See? He's walking away
in utter helpless defeat.
After all, his brain is
the size of a walnut.
Sure, his sense
of smell may be acute,
but eyesight, hearing,
all of his higher functions
completely compromised by
that walnut-sized brainpan.
I mean, forget
about the Polish.
It's the T. Rexes who are
the real dummies of the world.
In fact, Chaka,
funny story...
(ROARING)
RICK: Frigging run!
RICK: Follow the monkey!
Cave!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
He's looking
at you, Marshall.
No. No.
He's watching you.
He's looking at everyone.
No, I'm certain he's looking at you.
He is grumpy.
(SIGHS)
I think that's what we
should call him, Grumpy.
Yeah, that's a cute name.
(ROARING)
Is he gone?
Yeah.
Pussy.
What a puss.
Mmm-hmm.
This'll work just fine.
We'll call this base camp.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
We cannot stay here. Bad
things happen in caves, folks.
Watch your movies.
Guys, can we just please
take a minute to absorb this?
(SIGHS) I mean, we must be the first
people to ever set foot in this world.
It's incredible!
(UPBEAT JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, God, we're screwed.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING ON RECORD PLAYER)
No, no. No. No.
Chaka, no! No.
Go on.
Okay, you know what?
I don't want Chaka sleeping
in the cave tonight.
Whoa! Not cool, dude.
No, it's a reasonable
precaution, all right?
He was just about to be executed,
and I think he might have
done something to deserve it.
Hey, my man is right here.
Obviously he has feelings, okay?
RICK: He doesn't have feelings.
Man, come on, look at him.
He's adorable.
He's a little cuddle machine.
RICK: What?
WILL: Yeah, the least you could
do is let him defend himself.
I don't speak monkey anyhow. Do you?
No, I don't.
I didn't think so.
Here, let me try.
Chaka?
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
He says he's a prince
amongst his people.
Right.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
The victim of a treacherous
plot to steal his throne.
And the only thing
he's ever guilty of was...
Is love.
Aw!
Oh, brother.
Give me a break.
And he's been treated far too harshly
for the very simple crime of...
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Pooping in the village well.
That's why you're not
sleeping in the cave.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
I can't tell anymore.
(SNARLING)
Hey, mister, fuck you.
(GROWLING)
Hold on, hold on.
Where you going with that?
I'm just gonna block the
first point of egress here
so that we're not vulnerable.
No, no. Bless your heart.
Classic tenderfoot mistake.
Don't beat yourself up
over it. Here's the thing.
Never put anything near the mouth
of the cave to draw attention to us.
Did you not just see
that we drew the attention
of a highly intelligent
psycho dinosaur?
Look, I think
the Ph. D. after my name
means I know a little
something about dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs are creatures
of brute instinct.
Like I've said before, it's got
a brain the size of a walnut.
Okay? You got me?
A walnut.
Now think about...
(RUMBLING)
What's that? What's that?
Sweet Gregor Mendel.
What is it?
It's a walnut.
(SNARLING)
Well, obviously this is
between you and him.
Day two. 0600, Zulu Time.
Did not sleep last night
at all, not one bit.
Still no sign of the tachyon
amplifier, our only way home.
Field rations are
running dangerously low.
Thusly, I've made the
determination that, if need be,
if faced with starvation,
we will cook and eat Chaka.
I've been thinking
about this a lot, actually.
If Chaka meat were the secret
ingredient on Iron Chef,
I'm sure Bobby Flay
would probably serve it
with roasted red peppers and a
dash of cumin and a braised polenta.
It wouldn't be
an easy thing to do,
but if you slow roast
the little guy,
I'm sure that Chaka meat would
just fall right off the bone.
(CHAKA EXCLAIMS)
Food train coming through!
HOLLY: Fantastic!
I'm absolutely starving.
And fresh fruit. It's
like morning at Wimbledon.
Hold on a second there, Holly. I don't
recognize that genus of succulent.
Perhaps the native
inhabitant can help us.
Chaka. Rick Marshall. Chaka.
Are they safe? To eat?
Eat? Eat?
Eat. Marashalla.
Eat. Eat.
Thank you, Chaka. Thank you
so much for listening to me.
Sorry for doubting you,
my little friend.
Has a pungent flavor.
Smells good. Very meaty...
(SCREAMING)
Jesus, Chaka! What the hell?
Friends?
(SIGHS)
Well. Yes, technically, I guess.
However, I am your master.
Okay? We have entered
into a verbal contract.
You need to understand that. Okay?
(SHRILL RINGING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Holly! Quick! To the cave
mouth. Sentry positions.
Looks like a plasma
discharge. Or maybe beta rays!
(GROANS)
Marshall?
Marshall! Marshall!
Help me, please.
I will.
Marshall! Marshall,
where are you going?
Someone or something
knows we're here!
It's in my head,
calling to me!
Step back, Holly!
What are you doing?
I've seen this before.
He's got the jungle madness.
We gotta put him down while
he still has some dignity left.
Chaka, let's roll!
What?
Friends! Friends!
You see?
This is the place!
A beacon.
A transmitter, tapping directly
into my prefrontal lobe.
- What the hell?
- Stop it!
Well, I'll be.
I guess you weren't crazy.
Okay. I'm man enough
to say that's my bad.
HOLLY: Wow. That's
incredible. The architecture.
It's almost like the Olmec
culture of Mesoamerica.
Reminds me of the Prudential building.
(SOFTLY) No!
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
WILL: I'll bet somebody's
growing weed in here.
RICK: You feel that?
That ambient energy?
Just like at Devil's Canyon.
HOLLY: Yep.
Tachyon radiation.
Marshall, the meter can't be far.
(SQUEALING)
WILL: Holy shit.
Finally, something cool, huh?
What, no reaction?
You guys have seen that
before, too, I take it, huh?
In your lab.
What's this thing?
Hey, maybe this is where our ancient
ancestors hosted the Latin Grammys.
Just picture Santana
hauling this sucker home.
(BUZZING)
And it vibrates!
I wouldn't touch that, all right?
(SINGING WITH DISTORTED VOICE)
Do you believe in life after love?
That is so dumb and childish.
(SINGING) Do you believe
in life after love?
Will, will you please be quiet?
Dr. Marshall needs silence.
(SINGING WITH DISTORTED VOICE)
I can feel something inside me say
(BOTH SINGING) I really don't
think you're strong enough, oh!
- Wow!
- Yeah.
I can really feel it in my forearms.
Yeah, usually you have to
pay for something like this.
Oh, gosh.
Holly, you should sit on this.
CHAKA: No! No!
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Hmm? What?
What is it, Chaka?
What did you say?
What is he saying?
I don't know. It's the
same thing over and over.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Chorizo tacos.
Are you saying "chorizo tacos"?
Don't play around,
because I am super hungry.
No.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
What the hell does that mean?
Well, I'm afraid we'll never know.
Oh! Okay.
Oh, shit, it's not chorizo tacos.
No immediate danger.
Cold-blooded and slow.
(WHISPERING) I repeat,
no immediate danger.
Will you stop that?
Please!
You are freaking me out!
WILL: Oh, gosh.
They're everywhere.
They're just like zombies. That's
how zombies get you. Volume!
We're all gonna die.
HOLLY: Like hell.
I'm gonna take at least one
of these bastards with me,
even if he has to choke
to death on my skull!
Oh!
What, do you want some, too, do you?
WILL: What are you guys doing?
One second.
What in the hell?
Get in!
Oh, God.
Wait, stand down, Holly.
All right.
- Hang on.
- Yeah.
Hang on,
I think we're safe!
They don't seem to be able to
make it through the entrance.
Thank God for that. That one
keeps peering into my soul.
Well, this is
just fantastic.
We're gonna just stand
in here and suffocate
in this tiny,
little huge thingie?
RICK: Wow, that is
an efficient use of space.
WILL: It's like
Snoopy's doghouse.
(MOANS)
Look, there's a gold one.
Let's stomp its head in.
Do not fear me.
I am Enik the Altrusian.
Thank Vindok you've come
to my aid, Rick Marshall.
- You know me?
- Of course.
Even in the farthest
reaches of the universe,
we have seen your Matt Lauer video.
I am a prisoner
in this land of the lost.
Only you can help me escape.
The fate of the universe depends on you.
Well. That's very flattering, Enik,
but I think you've
found the wrong guy. I...
No, Rick Marshall.
I have summoned you here specifically
to help me stop an evil madman
who has already conquered my world
and now plans to conquer yours.
His name is the Zarn.
I am the Zarn! Heed my
warning or be destroyed!
The Zarn became obsessed with
using the power of these crystals
to conquer the universe.
If he is not stopped, he will
open a doorway to your world
and lead his army of Sleestak on
a rampage across time and space.
He must be stopped.
Enik, buddy.
I'm a scientist.
You're a scientist.
I think together you and I
can figure this out. Now...
You mustn't touch the crystals!
Okay!
The wrong manipulation of the crystals
could turn time and space inside out.
What do you need from us?
The Zarn lacks only one thing
to enact his evil plan.
A device to amplify tachyons and
unleash the full power of the crystals.
Well, Marshall's created a device
that isolates tachyon interference.
Yeah, I did that.
Of course.
With tachyon particles focused
along the proper temporal vector
a stable passageway
can be opened... Opened
- to any point in the space
- time continuum!
(BOTH GASPING)
You and I are so smart!
Rick Marshall, I knew
instantly you could help me.
Thank you.
You are a truly
advanced intellect.
I don't know how you
manage amongst these others.
I don't know how I do,
either. I really don't!
Excuse me!
You have this tachyon amplifier?
I lost it on the way,
and I don't know where.
It could be lost in time.
On the contrary.
I detect it nearby. It...
Strange. I cannot precisely
pinpoint its location.
It moves.
Leave it to us.
If it's out there, we'll find it.
(WHISPERING)
Not so fast, amigo.
Little rule I live by, "Never
trust a dude in a tunic. "
(WHISPERING)
You live by that rule?
Yes. It's never led me astray.
All right, come on. Enik,
are you well enough to travel?
No. My place is here in the
pylon. I must protect the crystals.
If you wish to return home,
these crystals are the doorway.
Your device is the key.
Find it before the Zarn does.
Bring it to me and rescue
us all. Rescue the universe!
All right, everyone, gather around!
Let's go! Chop-chop!
Hustle up.
Marshall, did you just make that?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm a bit
of a miniatures enthusiast.
It's very impressive.
Thank you.
Yeah, well, I see some
obvious scaling issues, but...
I think
it's pretty damn good.
All right, we are here.
As you can see,
desert, forest.
What's this look like?
It's the cave.
That's the cave.
That's where we're living.
Standard volcano. Okay?
Now, I will tether Will to
this hot air balloon right here.
Okay? And it will be fitted with
a crude tachyon reflector-array
that I fashioned out of a thermal
blanket and a cell phone charger.
I don't remember ever
volunteering for that.
Holly, you and I will
follow Will's directions
as he searches for the
telltale ping of the missing
and still presumably
operational tachyon meter.
(ROARING)
Oh, God, he's close.
I've taken care of that.
During the course
of my professional career,
I've done extensive research with
reptiles and various birds of prey,
of which dinosaurs are.
Well, that's disputable.
Please be quiet.
They have a very
acute sense of smell.
And now while I've gathered this
strictly for genetic research
to be used upon our return,
I think it would prove wise to
use this now. Hadrosaur urine.
We are going
to cover our...
Wait. What is that?
Hadrosaur urine.
How'd you get that?
Well, while you were sleeping,
I'm out gathering research. Okay?
This was to be used
for genetic engineering,
and I was going to write a
report on kidney function,
but now it'll just be camouflage.
We'll all blend in. Okay?
So we will cover ourselves...
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm just trying
to figure this out.
(SIGHING) Oh, my God!
So you've been gathering urine.
Yes. What's the problem?
That means that you stood
under a dino dong with a bucket.
If you want to be technical and reduce
it to its basest element, yes, I was.
How'd that work out for you?
Are you honestly asking me?
Yeah.
It's very peaceful. It's a
little bit like fly fishing.
Just out there in the
night air. Still. Calm.
And then, zing!
You get a big catch.
Okay. So we'll cover
our bodies in urine,
and then we'll be virtually
undetectable to all dinosaurs.
(ROARING)
All right. Here they come. Should
have thought of this a long time ago.
Whoo!
That's refreshing!
Make sure to ingest some.
Get that in the bloodstream.
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
Don't do that.
Okay, who's next?
- Really.
- It's not that bad.
Check that.
Just starting to burn in my eyes
a little bit. Did not plan for that.
It gets up in the nostrils,
too. You do not want that.
Wow. That's early morning stuff.
That is strong!
Maybe a second splash will
reduce some of the effects.
Immediately made it worse.
Where's my laser pointer?
Never mind.
We will probably have to be doing...
(GROANS)
Ow!
(CHAKA SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Who's that?
(HUMMING)
Maybe we should just follow
him. Nice model, though.
Yeah, fine, let's forget my
model and let's follow the monkey.
(CHAKA HUMMING)
RICK: Shut up, Chaka!
Are we there yet?
You find this
funny, Chaka?
This is the damn Bataan
Death March out here.
HOLLY: My God!
RICK: Absolutely incredible.
HOLLY: This must be the main
entry point into this world.
RICK: It's like a cosmic lost and found.
WILL: Wow, look at all
this kick-ass shit to steal.
This is like the world's greatest mall.
Yeah, Will, it's just like a mall.
The only thing it's
missing is a food court!
Compsognathus!
Look how they move!
Wow. Where are all these
chupacabras going to?
I'll tell you where they're going to.
Our raft. The tachyon
meter can't be far.
Our raft? That's my raft!
Get away from there!
WILL: Stop pecking on my raft!
There's your food court.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKER)
Ice cream.
Hey, hey, hey!
What are you doing?
What? I'm gonna go pony up
and get Chaka a cone.
- It's his first.
- No, there's a reason
why those dinosaurs hang
out there. They know.
They know what?
It's feeding time.
(SQUEALING)
(SCREAMING)
- Whoa!
(ROARING)
An Allosaurus. Female.
Yeah.
RICK: We're in luck.
These large predators
are extremely territorial.
Virtually nothing will
distract them from each other.
(BOTH SNIFFING)
Crap balls!
What do you know?
This is one of those situations where
dumping piss on your head's a bad idea.
Run!
Lead, Chaka!
Lead your master to safety!
Hey! Chaka!
Chaka, no!
Why? You're a little asshole, Chaka!
Spread out!
It'll confuse him!
Try running in a serpentine pattern!
He's incapable of rapid
course correction!
Serpentine, everyone!
Serpentine! Serpentine! Serpentine!
(SCREAMS)
Serpentine! Serpentine!
Serpentine!
Son of a tit!
Hey, Marshall, you ever
get tired of being wrong?
I do. I really do.
Bone tired.
Get on your horse, Rick Marshall.
They're working as a pair.
Fascinating but terrifying.
(SNIFFING)
No!
Marshall!
RICK: Still here!
I hope you're taping this!
HOLLY: I got it!
(ROARING)
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKER)
I don't want to... I don't
want to die in a Hummer!
It's a massacre.
(SQUEAKING)
Quiet!
(BURPS)
Gross.
RICK: Set the catapult!
What?
Set the catapult!
Set the F-ing catapult!
This thing?
RICK: Catapult, now!
No, no, no, no!
Take her that way!
Go that way!
Just do it!
Come on.
How the hell do you set a catapult?
I don't know.
Just turn it.
One! Two!
Three!
(ROARING)
Crank that thing!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Crank that mother!
I'm coming in hot!
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
Keep going!
Put your backs into it.
Package has arrived.
What's the package?
It's a canister
of refrigerant.
Hit it now!
(EXCLAIMS)
I did not expect that.
(GRUNTS)
(SHOW TUNE PLAYING)
Gay show tunes!
Cassie. Bebe.
Tachyon meter!
(SINGING) Still it isn't over
We did it! We're saved!
Look at all the people!
(WHISPERING) That blows.
That blows.
Marshall?
What are you doing?
(SIGHS)
I'm giving up.
And it feels good.
But what about finding a way home
and validation for your life's work?
You're just gonna give all
that up just to lie here?
No, of course not.
Lying here is just
Phase One of the plan.
It's Phase Two that
gets me really excited.
It involves adjusting
the angle of my recline
and putting this hand
halfway down my pants.
Deceptively simple,
yet elegant.
Yep. I tried, I failed,
and you know what?
Once again,
it's my own damned vault.
You mean "fault. "
No, I actually mean "vault. " It's
from a poster with a pole vaulter on it.
That's really
freaking stupid, man.
You know, actually, I can't
even believe I'm hearing this.
Any scientist in his right
mind would give his...
Initiating Phase Two.
(IMITATING MACHINERY BUZZING)
Do you know how I first
heard about you? As a joke.
First year at Cambridge, we used
to e-mail your little appearance
with Matt Lauer
around for a laugh.
I mean, as YouTube
Hall of Fame moments goes,
it was Lauer versus Marshall,
and then that monkey pissing
in his own face. In that order.
But I wasn't laughing,
because I was fascinated.
I saw a man who was willing
to swim dangerous waters
for the sake
of his need to know.
I took that to heart,
Dr. Marshall.
I committed myself
to your theories,
and then I got tossed
out of Cambridge for it.
For my theories,
you threw your future away?
Yeah, that's what
everyone told me.
But I didn't believe it,
not till now.
Have you seen
this monkey video?
Yeah, I've seen it
about a dozen times.
God bless the Internet.
Come on, Chaka.
Let's work on our
mission statement.
CHAKA: Okay.
(HOWLING)
How's it going?
What's wrong, little guy? You okay?
Lady troubles?
Yeah.
Yeah, tell me about it.
This obviously stays
between me and you,
but I'm coming up
on a six-year dry spell.
Yeah.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
He says that he misses his
tribe. It's a beautiful existence.
They're carefree and nomadic,
and they live where the food is.
Just like me.
I moved tres times just to
be closer to a Ruby Tuesday's.
Yeah. Continue.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Their women
wait on the men,
serving all
their needs.
I'm liking this.
Continue.
Though they're ugly,
they make up for it
with nice personalities.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
He says as prince
of his tribe,
he personally is served
by a harem of 7,000 women.
Wow. Not bad,
little dude.
Yeah, and they bring him
all the apples he can...
Oh! Yeah.
Yeah, you get the idea.
I'm not translating that.
(BANJO PLAYING)
Any room around that
fire for a jerk like me?
I thought you gave up.
I did.
I gave up on giving up.
(SIGHS)
Sat out there for a long time,
just me, my shame,
and this little four-string.
Then I had a change of heart.
I tried too long and hard to think
of something to say to you guys,
and, well, I realized there
wasn't anything to say.
But maybe, just maybe,
there's something I could sing.
No, it's all right. It...
(SINGING) Marshall, Will and Holly
On a routine expedition
Met the greatest
earthquake ever known
- That's all I got.
- Yeah, that was fine.
Yeah, apology accepted, dude. That's...
Thanks. You guys
are being so generous.
I really appreciate it.
I think the healing has begun.
(SINGING) Met the greatest
earthquake ever known
High on the rapids,
it struck their tiny raft...
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
That's good.
(SINGING) And plunged them down...
(YAWNING)
I'm so tired.
(SINGING) A thousand feet below...
Well, I'm feeling weak.
Really bushwhacked.
Anyway, here's...
Here's how I end it.
A little arpeggio, nothing fancy.
I'm really kind of sleepy.
(SINGING) To the land...
Land of the...
(EXCLAIMING WEARILY)
(ALL SCREAM)
I'm so... I'm so tired. So...
What happened?
You had a bug on you, but it's gone now.
Okay.
(GRUNTING)
(EXHALES)
All right, everyone, rise and shine.
Listen up.
It's a new day.
Yes, we've had a setback.
Yes, it is tempting to
stay in this world and die,
but that's not how the new
Marshall rolls. You hear me?
Not by a damn sight.
This isn't "hands down the
pants" Marshall. All right?
This isn't "gorging on two pints of
Ben & Jerry's and a whole spiral-cut ham
"while watching not one but two
Mama's Family's Reunions" Marshall.
Uh-uh! He's gone.
Here's the deal.
Enik's counting on us.
The whole world's
counting on us.
If we have any hope
of returning home,
we need to take back that tachyon
meter, and take it back hard.
That means climbing, hours of
arduous climbing up sheer cliffs.
Not tomorrow, not in a
few hours, but right now.
- Understood?
- Yep.
Understood, Will?
Hmm?
Let's move out, you pansies.
Hey! This is not a race, okay?
(SQUAWKING)
(SHOW TUNE PLAYING)
(SINGING) Again! Step, kick,
kick, leap, kick, touch
Again! Step, kick,
Right, let's do the whole combination
facing away from the mirror
From the top, A-five,
six, seven, eight!
WILL: What the hell?
HOLLY: Pterodactyl eggs are
incubating all over the caldera.
And there's your
shitty boom box.
Across a sea
of thin volcanic glass.
Okay, Will, what you're gonna want to
do is evenly distribute your weight,
while at the same time,
keeping an eye out for the eggs.
Hey! Will?
I know you're faking.
Okay. Chaka.
(SNORING)
Chaka!
Come on.
Fine. Maybe I need
to listen to the words
of a group of young kids
trying to make it onstage.
God, I hope I get it.
I hope I get it.
Marshall.
Be careful.
I'm up! I'm up.
I got this.
Marshall, you got it.
(SQUAWKING)
(SINGING)
God, I hope I get it!
Do me a favor. Just keep
an eye on the mother, okay?
You mustn't change the surface
temperature of the eggs.
Even a drop of sweat could
activate the hatching process.
Right.
(SINGING) How many people does he...
I really need this job
Please, God, I need this job
I've got to get this job!
(SIGHS)
I got it. I got it.
All right, let me see the
boys The whole group, ready
A- five, six, seven, eight!
(MUSIC STOPS PLAYING)
(RATTLING)
(SQUAWKING)
RICK: They're hatching!
Why are they hatching?
The music!
It must be like a lullaby.
Shut up!
(RICK SHUSHING)
(SINGING) God, I hope I
get it! I hope I get it
How many people does he need?
God, I hope I get it!
I hope I get it
How many boys?
How many girls?
Look at all the people!
At all the people
(ALL SINGING)
How many people does he need?
How many boys?
How many girls?
How many people does he...
(SINGING) I really need this job
Please, God, I need this job
I've got to get this job!
(SNORING)
(WHOOPING)
RICK: People, we are going home!
I'm gonna miss this place
that proves I was right.
Drink. Drink, yes.
Oh! That is delicious
and refreshing! Mmm-mmm.
Sweet and sour,
like Chinese food.
Yeah.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
He's saying it's a celebratory
drink in his village.
Cheers!
Yeah, it brings a joyful
lightness to the heart and soul.
No, no. No.
No, I'm sorry, it's not
"joyful lightness. "
A better translation would
be "howling loneliness. "
And then your bravery will
be tested as your mind fogs.
And the Shadow Hags will
rise from the graves and...
And hold you
in an icy embrace.
And it'll feel like your
bowel's being pierced
by a ghost serpent.
Well, that
can't be right.
No, that can't be right.
Chaka...
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Oh, no, no.
Okay, he says
it's not ghost serpent.
It's much closer
to "zombie dick. "
I think it might
be a narcotic.
Is that so?
I need you to be honest
with me, okay? You a cop?
Chaka.
That's not an answer, Chaka.
That's your name.
Seriously, by law, you have to
tell me if you're a police officer.
- Marco.
- Polo.
You wearing a wire?
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
- Marco.
- Polo.
(DEVICE POWERING ON)
Hello.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Hot coffee!
I need food.
Marshall!
Yeah.
Fruit me, buddy.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(ALL SIGH)
Yeah. Yeah,
right there.
Get it on there.
Thank you.
Chaka.
I owe you
an apology, okay?
(FLY BUZZING)
I'm a guest
in your land.
A guest who came
unannounced, uninvited,
and I've treated you
like a toilet. A toilet!
I wanna make
it up to you.
Because the love I feel for
you, and I'm not exaggerating,
is a billion
times greater
than the love for mankind
that Jesus felt on the cross.
You can take
that to the bank.
(BOTH SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
I'm so glad you
guys squashed that.
I love you guys so much.
You guys are amazing.
I don't ever want to go home. No.
This is just like
Sandals Resort.
Mmm-hmm.
There's good people, a lot
of good food. Good times.
I want to make this my life. I
must make... Be here all the time.
Yeah.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
(REPEATING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
Mmm.
Hey. Hey.
You're funny, Chaka.
- He's hilarious.
- You're funny.
His jokes are disgusting.
(ALL LAUGHING)
You're funny.
- Hey, for real, though?
- Mmm?
How much money would I have to pay
y'all to French kiss each other?
For real?
Totally for real.
For real, for real?
Tongue in his
monkey mouth.
Hey, if it doesn't leave the three
of us, I'd do it for free right now.
It's not gonna
leave here.
I'd do it
right now.
Let me see it.
Kiss him.
It doesn't leave
the three of us?
Never. I won't tell anybody.
Who am I gonna tell?
- You French kiss him!
- I... I'm gonna do it.
Come here. I want you to... What?
- What?
- Get... Get...
(LAUGHING)
WILL: You guys are gross!
I don't wanna do it!
I don't wanna do it.
WILL: Oh! That's gross!
I've changed my mind.
(GASPS)
Dinosaur eggs!
Dinosaur poo.
This is the Zarn!
Heed my warning
or be destroyed!
Well, we're... We're
just trying to get home.
Enik the Altrusian
has escaped our custody!
He has overtaken the central
pylon and its crystals
and now plans to lead his army of Sleestak
on a rampage across time and space!
If you're hearing this, heed
my warning. Do not believe...
(ENIK LAUGHING)
No! Enik! No!
The Zarn.
(SCREAMING) I've gotta
go and warn them that...
Holly?
They've taken Holly.
Chaka? I've got a mission
for you. Now listen closely.
I don't know
what that means.
(WHISPERING)
Just come on.
Oh, man.
Sentries.
Classic hive behavior.
Obviously on patrol.
Yep, just like drones,
tirelessly hunting.
Dude, it looks like they're
getting ready to make out.
No. No, no, no.
(CROAKING)
He's about
to tap that ass.
(WHISPERING)
Would you shut up?
He's not about
to tap that ass.
You're right. He's
totally tapping that ass.
Wow. Our own
little private show.
(CROAKING INTENSIFYING)
(SCREECHING)
WILL: Oh, God, they shed.
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
Hi.
Hey, don't do that!
Just focus.
SKULL 1: We find you guilty of providing
assistance to Enik the Altrusian.
There she is.
SKULL 1: Prepare to meet
the Sleestak god.
No.
- Stop!
- Marshall!
SKULL 1: Do not interfere!
Dude, what the hell are you doing?
SKULL 1: This one was caught trying
to deliver a tachyon device to Enik.
If you want Holly,
you've gotta deal with us.
No, no, Marshall, don't!
Because we're all
friends of Enik!
SKULL 1: Enik the Altrusian is guilty of
the destruction of an entire civilization.
Entire what now?
SKULL 1: Convicted of his crimes,
he was sentenced to 10,000
years imprisonment...
He lied to us.
...and made to wear a tunic
as a symbol of his deceit.
Told you, dude. Tunic.
SKULL 1: As his allies,
you shall die as well.
SKULL 2: Seize them!
Come on.
Marshall!
Hold on, Holly!
(GROANS)
See you.
We can do this. Ready?
Ready.
(SIGHS)
Wait. Wait, what about our...
Our working relationship?
I've wanted to do that
since I first met you.
You mean we could've been
doing this the whole time?
Yeah, but I was worried
it wouldn't be professional
or it'd distract
you from your work.
No. No, not distracting.
Never distracting.
Are you guys kidding me? Come on!
Really! Now is the time for this?
You know, he's...
He's right.
We've got to stop Enik, and
right now he has the upper hand.
I mean, I know we have the
element of surprise, but...
Yeah, about that.
What?
We sent Chaka to go get him.
(ENIK LAUGHING)
Well, then, Rick Marshall.
Coming here represents a slight
adjustment to my plans, but no matter.
I have what I need.
And it's all thanks to you,
Dr. Marshall, and this.
(LAUGHING)
Don't.
We're outgunned.
ENIK: My Sleestak
stand prepared.
With the power
of the crystals,
they are my slaves,
my conquering army.
Thanks to your device,
I can lead an invasion force anywhere
I choose in all of time and space.
But I believe I will
begin with your Earth.
Oh, no.
ENIK: My Sleestaks
reproduce quickly.
Yeah, we already caught
some of that action.
ENIK: In mere weeks, your world will
be overrun by their scaly offspring.
And when I'm standing in the
cinders of your civilization,
I'll be sure to give you
full scientific credit.
I know how important
that is to you.
Now save your strength.
You'll need it.
(LAUGHING)
"You'll need it"?
What is he...
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
HOLLY: Marshall?
Great.
(ROARING)
Right, you run and I'll
distract him. He's not after me.
No. I'm not running.
This ends here.
HOLLY: Marshall,
what are you doing?
Maybe what I was
always meant to do.
Now, just go. I'll meet
you at the pylon, I hope.
No, we're not
leaving without you.
Go!
Get out of here!
I don't love you.
- Go!
- Ow! Marshall!
Get! You're ugly.
(SCOFFS)
(WHISTLES)
(ROARS)
Look, if you're gonna
do this for real, take this.
Got some high-powered fireworks
in here that might come in handy.
Are you kidding me?
You mean you've been
carrying a bag of fireworks
around with you
this whole time?
There's literally a dozen situations
where we could have used these.
(ROARING)
(SHUSHING)
He's right. None of that's
important now, okay?
Listen. I gotta just level
with you, bro. I misjudged you.
I thought you were just a dumbass
dude who dressed stupid, but I'm wrong.
- You're solid.
- Thanks.
Thick or thin, I will follow
you into battle at any time.
You hear me?
Absolutely any time.
Okay. How about now?
- Like right now?
- Yes.
(ROARING)
Honestly, I didn't really expect
you to call the favor in this soon.
So, on this one, unfortunately
I'm gonna have to say no.
But I think it's gonna be awesome
for you, for personal growth,
just to hit this one solo.
I'm gonna be rooting
for you. Okay?
Trenches, bro.
It's all about love.
Okay?
After this time,
I'm there for you, okay?
Any time after now.
He's your man, not me.
All right, it's a fact. You
and I don't like each other.
Yes. And only
one will remain.
I'm just gonna have to
fight you at your own game.
(EXCLAIMS)
(ROARING)
(YELPING)
Stay back. Get back.
Damn, you're quick.
'Cause you're a dinosaur.
But you don't carry
around these, do you?
Huh?
Welcome to the big
bang theory, my friend.
Damn it, Will!
Ah! That was stupid.
You're cornered, man!
There's no way out!
There's always a way out!
'Cause if you don't make it...
It's your own damn vault.
My God! He's gonna do it!
Do it! Do it!
(GASPS)
(BURPS)
(EXCLAIMING)
Oh, God!
No, no.
I don't believe it.
Oh, shit.
(EXCLAIMS)
Yeah! You! You bastard!
Do you realize who you just ate, do you?
Probably the most
brilliant man ever.
Probably the only man
who ever really knew you.
All right, so he was wrong
about the size of your brain,
but you don't go
and eat a man for that.
You reason with him,
you stupid idiot!
He was your future!
He was my future!
And I'm never gonna get a chance
to tell him that because of you!
It's cool. It's cool.
I'm sorry.
(PANTING)
Right. Now we must get home.
We're gonna get back,
and we're gonna tell the world what
Dr. Rick Marshall did here today.
Come on, you big green bastards.
I am sick and tired of you
slow-moving little wankers!
(GRUNTING)
Will!
All right, little dude.
Let's do this.
Lock and load!
(SCREAMING)
Boo-ya!
You want some of this?
Eat, Chaka, eat!
Holly!
HOLLY: Will!
(RUMBLING)
Step... Step and lift!
(ROARING)
All right, my murderous
friend, take us home.
(WHOOPING)
Get!
Bite that guy
right back there! Nice.
(WHOOPS) Good get.
That's him. That's him.
Upper deck! The horror!
God, that is the coolest
thing I have ever seen.
Let's do it, pal.
(WHOOPS)
The only thing cooler would be
if he'd slide down Grumpy's tail
just like Fred Flintstone
would do when...
(WHOOPING)
Oh, God, I've lived.
I have lived.
Easy. Hey, come on, it tickles.
Marshall!
What happened?
Dude, we thought you had died!
Died? No. That was
just a minor setback.
Okay, let's go home.
No, no, no, wait.
This is insane.
We saw you go down
Grumpy's cake hole.
What, did he puke you
out or something? Well...
No, it's not possible. The
T. Rex lacked a gag reflex.
Not important right now.
I'm okay, and that's it.
This is a puzzler.
Look, I'd really rather
not talk about it, okay?
Now, let's light this candle.
No, Marshall,
how did you get out?
I will talk to you
about it later!
Individually, to each one
of you. I'll explain it.
(SNIFFING)
Jeez. Would you grow up?
Oh, my God!
Yes, he pooped me out!
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
And now you guys
are friends?
While I was snaking my way through
his bowels, I don't know, I...
I must have dislodged some
sort of intestinal blockage.
And, yes, he's in
a much better mood now.
So can we move on? I really
would like to go home.
You were deuced out by a
dinosaur. That is incredibly cool.
Grumpy, listen.
When you talk about
this, and you will,
please be gentle. Okay?
All right, gangsta,
let's bones it out.
Don't worry about it. It's
hard with your vestigial arm.
Let's go, guys.
To freedom.
(ROARING)
ENIK: Thank you, Dr. Marshall.
And now, the doorway opens.
(GASPS)
Enik!
It's over.
You're not going anywhere.
You think you can challenge me?
(SHOUTING)
I wrestled at Purdue.
(LAUGHING)
J.V.
Fight, fight, fight!
Chaka!
Nicaraguan ball breaker!
Marshall! I'm coming in!
(WHOOPING)
(GROANS)
Misfire!
What have you done?
The door.
It's closing forever!
It's barely holding.
Let's go!
(SCOFFS)
It's your home or your
comrade, Dr. Marshall.
(LAUGHS)
No, it isn't. Reverse!
You go! I've got this
yellow bastard in lockdown.
I'm gonna stay.
- What?
Yeah. I've been
talking to my man Chaka.
He pitches
a pretty good world.
I mean, think about it. My home
was never in the real world.
I never belonged. This could
be a fresh start for me.
You know, make
some new friends.
I could be somebody, a winner.
Ow!
Wow, I really admire
you right now.
I just feel like so many
people go through this life
looking for what I've
found here, you know?
And they themselves,
they never find it.
Or worse, they find it,
but they let it slip away.
I am so afraid
of that happening.
You wouldn't be human
if you didn't feel scared.
Marshall! Please.
You can't leave me here
like this with him!
As one scientist to another,
I beg you for mercy.
Science shows no mercy,
and neither do I.
- That's good.
- Thank you.
Let's go, Holly.
Ready?
Ready.
Chaka? Technically,
I'm still your master!
HOLLY: Marshall?
Holly?
(SIGHS)
We made it!
- Thank you.
I just want to say you have
grown into a beautiful woman.
Oh, no...
ERN: Hey!
Where's Will?
He went to a better place.
You killed him?
No.
No, he went to a strange world,
a world of dinosaurs,
monkey people, lizard people,
a hole in space and time,
a virtual land of the lost.
And as hard as it is to
believe, Will chose to stay.
All right. Cool.
WILL: Yeah, did you see those
Sleestaks kick the crap out of Enik?
I've never seen
them move so fast.
(CHAKA SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
WILL: Yeah, I couldn't agree
more, little buddy. Tunic.
Hop up.
I got you, come on.
Whoa!
(GROANING)
Man, you are
deceptively heavy.
Oh, my God.
(SPEAKING PRIMATE LANGUAGE)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Chaka! My God!
We're kings!
CHAKA: Yeah.
(EXCLAIMING)
Are those what
your women look like?
Hop off. Be cool, be
cool, be cool, be cool.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Easy! Stand down!
Stand down.
I got this.
How's it going? I'm Will.
Pretty much Chaka's best friend.
I'm here to offer
y'all protection
and shelter and really
pretty much anything
that you guys would
ever need, okay.
Hey, how's it going? Hey,
yeah. Okay, yeah, that's denim.
Denim, yeah. Yeah.
Well, look at that, huh?
Hey, you're back there, too. Okay.
This was definitely a good choice.
ANNOUNCER: This is Today,
with Matt Lauer.
It's been some time since
my final guest was here,
but after the remarkable
events of the past year,
he needs no introduction.
He's back with a new book
and more startling evidence
of, you guessed it,
time warps.
The pipe's allowed.
I asked.
That's great news.
You've had quite a year.
Actually, a stellar year, Matt.
In fact, I brought
you back a dinosaur egg,
which my beautiful
partner and lover,
Holly Cantrell, was
gracious enough to transport.
And I'm obviously very excited
about my new tome.
- It's a book.
Sixteen weeks on the New
York Times bestseller list.
Let me get to your
discovery, Doctor, because...
This is for you.
I signed it.
(SIGHS)
You're supposed to say the
title and the publisher.
That's not gonna happen.
- Just say it.
- No.
Just say the damn title.
Fine.
Matt Lauer Can Suck It,
by Dr. Rick Marshall.
I was so surprised that your
attorney signed off on that.
I was like, "Are you sure?
Is this gonna be okay?"
He said, "Yeah, go for it. "
Son of a bitch. You...
You puss!
MAN ON SPEAKER: And we're clear.
If anyone sees Matt, can you
tell him he forgot his egg?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Edited by: guilty57
www.divxplanet.com