One of us is gonna be here
One of us
is gonna be runnin'
Follow into
the great unknown
You're not me, you're
a model of freedom
All you need are your
kicks when you need 'em
Come and go,
caught that slow all right
With one hand off the side
We get farther away
in the blink of an eye
And it's the time we waste
Swallowed into space
It's the time it takes
To blow away
CARL: Grace!
Carl?
Order's up!
Thank you.
Here, let me top
you off there, Jimmy.
I've got that sausage coming
right up for you, Dale.
Enjoy your meal.
Thank you.
Fran, I am digging
that new hair.
Did you see her hair?
GRACE: Oh. Terrific.
You want me to take it?
My section,
I've got it.
Hi, Amanda.
Hi.
Guys.
So we made it. Graduation.
Do you mind
if we order?
Yeah. What can I get
for you guys?
(WHISTLING)
EMMA: And what
can I do you for?
Let's just see here.
You got any specials?
I sure do.
And I saved you a slice.
Hmm.
Hey, Owen.
Grace, how you doing?
Two more days,
just two more days.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
Well, we made it!
BOY: Yeah!
C) m m z
it's going to be so hard
not to look back on these
as the best four
years of our lives.
But there is a whole world out
there just waiting for us...
(DOOR OPEN ING)
Sorry. Hi.
Dad, I thought you were
gonna wait for me outside.
AMANDA: A world...
They started.
A whole world just waiting
for us to make our mark.
Gandhi once said,
“You must be the change you want to see in the world.”
(SQUEALS) Congratulations, kiddo.
You did it.
You are finally free.
(SIGHS) This place!
You know, I haven't been here
since I didn't graduate.
I was nearly
homecoming queen.
And long
may you reign. Mama!
What?
Nothing.
Just, uh, there are
children here.
Well, it's nice
to see you too, Meg.
Mom, what is she doing here?
It's sweet.
She wanted to be here.
Oh, come on.
You made her come.
Why don't we take
a picture?
I'm okay, Robert.
I'm fine.
Yes, come on, come on.
(SIGHS) Mom.I
This is yours.
ROBERT:
Everybody get closer.
Closer, Meg, move in.
Scoot in.
Dad, just take
the picture.
Pam, I don't want you worrying a
bit about Grace on this trip.
I'm going to take
good care of her.
That's just great, Emma.
No, thank you.
I'm. Fine.
Suit yourself.
More for me.
You guys, this is great.
Thank you for this.
Don't thank us
just yet.
Voile
Wow.
What, you don't like it?
No, no, I love it.
Thank you, Robert.
That will take you to Paris and
straight to NYU in the fall.
It's a Hartmann.
It's nice.
They're very expensive.
ROBERT:
And that's not all.
The next thing is
for both my girls.
Got to get used
to saying that.
Robert and I were talking
and we thought...
BOTH: Yeah?
Well, you and Emma are both
heading off to Paris tomorrow.
They are not gonna
know what hit 'em.
PAM: And Meg is
free for the summer.
And we thought, you know, uh,
why not kick this new sister
thing into high gear?
What are you talking about?
Do you know what they're talking about?
No, I do not.
Meg is going to Paris, too.
(CHUCKLES)
And I'm upgrading everyone!
ROBERT: You would've said no.
No?
No to the sisterhood
of the traveling to France?
Are you crazy?
Who could pass that up?
Honey,
you don't have to do that.
In fact, all through high
school, all I could think,
on the few occasions Texas Barbie
managed to make it to class, was,
"When I finally
do go to Europe,
"l want it to be
with Emma Perkins."
Meg.;0]
I don't even know
why she's going.
She'd be just as happy
at Six Flags on beer night.
Come on. it'll be fun.
I'm not Grace's babysitter.
And I'm not her sister,
no matter what
you and Pam do
with your lives.
(SIGHS) Why are
you doing this to me?
Because I don't know
how to make this any better.
You're 21.
You have one year of college left.
You've stayed in every
weekend since the funeral.
You should be going out
there, with friends.
Going to parties,
living your life.
That’s what Mom would’ve wanted.
Of all the places
she traveled,
she always said Paris
was her favorite.
I guess, on the bright side,
is that we are being upgraded.
Not that it's gonna make
much of a difference anyway.
Everything is so much
better over there already.
Everything?
Yeah, they got the clothes
and the shoes.
Everything, huh?
Are you not coming in?
Don't go.
It's a week, Owen.
Just stay here.
You'll be fine.
And marry me.
Yeah.
Owen.
Yeah, I mean, we been
real serious for a while,
and I've been thinking
about asking you this.
And where's the ring?
The, uh...
The ring.
The ring. Uh...
Let me ask you something.
Do you think you'd be asking
me to marry you tonight
if I wasn't headed off
to the City of Love tomorrow?
I think you mean
the City of Lights.
Something big is finally
about to happen for me.
And you choose the night
before I leave to ask?
Emma, I got everything I want
right here in this truck.
Now, how about you?
I've never once been
outside of Texas.
Not once.
Well,
you go on, then.
Have yourself
a real nice trip.
Owen?
(ENGINE STARTS)
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
Fine.
I will.
And I'll send you a postcard.
Yeah, you do that.
Yeah, I said I will
I might not be here
to get it.
Well, where are you
gonna be, huh?
Your "City of Lights"?
PAM: I love Emma. I love her zest.
But you just don't want me
to go to Paris alone with her.
No,
I don’t.
Look, I know you two have
gotten close at work, but...
Mom, Emma is my friend.
I appreciate that, Grace,
and I appreciate that Meg
is not your first choice,
but knowing that you'll be
with a responsible adult...
Meg is whatever
comes after adult.
Be generous.
You've seen me.
Mom, I have been saving for this.
This is what's gotten me
through the last four years
of pep rallies
and cheer squads.
Imagining myself
walking along the Seine
and standing on top
of the Eiffel Tower.
And having it all just
make me different.
Honey, it's not magic.
It's not going to turn you
into a whole different person.
Thank goodness.
I'm kind of partial to the one I've got.
Mom, you’ve found a whole new life with Robert.
And I'm happy for you.
Just let me go find mine.
Without Meg.
Nobody wants you to find
your life more than I do.
I have to get
to the hospital.
Mom.
Take the upgrade,
don't take the upgrade.
That part's up to you.
(FRENCH SONG PLAYING)
TOUR GUIDE: Welcome to Paris.
MEG: In five days. We’re never gonna get to all this stuff.
GRACE: I know
it's a lot, Meg,
but there's a lot to see.
it's Paris.
Ten, 11, 12 stops tomorrow.
You can't do the Louvre
in 20 minutes.
EMMA: it's their museum.
I think they know how long it takes.
Now, on your left
was Notre Dame,
one of the masterpieces of...
I'm sure
we'll circle back.
Mmm.
(FRENCH SONG CONTINUES)
That way. Thank you.
Sacre Coeur. Let's go. Up.
Nobody pinch me.
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
Miss! Mademoiselle! That way.
How are they all
moving so fast?
Well,
they're not wearing four-inch
hoochie heels, for starters.
Let me tell you something about shoes, Meg.
They ain't hurtin',
they ain't helpin'
OW! OW! OW!
Whew! Much better.
Thank you very much.
No problem, any time.
Oh. Australian.
Mind your step.
Precious cargo.
Good day.
Oh, no more wine. Sorry.
Finished, finished. No more.
What is that?
(PROTESTING IN FRENCH)
Eat soon. Quick.
No, I can't eat that.
Pardon.
Uh, I need a fork.
Well...
TOUR GUIDES Eat quickly, please.
Uh, I need a spoon.
TOUR GUIDE: Quickly, please. Okay.
Thank you. On your right.
You have no luggage?
EMMA: "The
Junior Ambassador Suite
"offers luxury accommodation,
sumptuous decor,
"and oozes charm."
Oozes.
Guys, the room
doesn't matter.
Well, there has to be
some kind of mistake.
Oh, yeah, why don't you
just toddle downstairs
and sort it all out,
en français?
Can we just please
make the best of it?
I mean, we'll hardly
ever be here.
Look, I'll take the cot.
(EXCLAIMS)
Oh, look.
I found the spa facilities.
Oh, great.
Now find an outlet,
because my phone is dying
and I don’t want to miss when Owen calls to apologize.
And when he does,
I need you guys... Oops.
...you guys to act like we're
having a really good time, okay?
We are having
a good time.
No one is having
How can you complain?
I get it, it's your thing,
but come on, we're in Paris.
Ah, bonjour!
EMMA: Got it!
(CRACKLING)
TOUR GUIDE:
Everybody off.
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
Okay.
EMMA: Wow.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
We're up real high.
You okay?
Yeah.
GRACE: Do you
have any change?
EMMA: Meg has got some.
(MEG SIGHS)
Hey, Meg, who's that guy?
What guy?
Dude, that guy clocking you.
That guy, right there.
Wow. You can see
everything from up here.
There is the Grand Palais,
Les Invalides.
There's our bus.
GRACE: Oh, yeah. Huh.
Hello, again.
Hi.
Look, there's Madame Valerie.
I saw you at Sacre Coeur
yesterday, didn't I?
EMMA: Wait a second.
Are they...
They're leaving.
My name's Riley. What's yours?
GRACE: Meg,
the bus is leaving!
Excuse me! Excuse me!
EMMA: Oh, God.
(KEEP YOUR HEAD PLAYING)
(MEG GROANS)
Wait, the elevator's
right here.
We don't have time!
Excuse me!
No, wait!
Ten minutes to go
Go, go, go!
Yeah, I've got to go home
Ten minutes to go
Hurry!
Everybody disappear
You're in it on your own
Ten minutes to go
You know you wanna stay home
Yeah, you wanna stay home
Ten minutes to go...
Emma, come on!
(WHIMPERS)
(EXCLAIMS)
Stop the bus!
Wait!
Excuse me.
Don't leave!
Wait!
Excuse me! Excuse me! Wait!
Wait! NO! NO!
No!
Come back.
This tour
ass
Okay, Meg, it's a disaster!
Are you happy?
Hey, it's okay.
No, it's not.
What is the matter with you?
I'm just being honest.
She's right.
I single handedly chose the
worst tour in all of Paris.
How did you choose it?
Meg, I’m not quite up to reviewing my process right now.
So let's just say
that I'm sorry, okay?
I'm sorry.
Emma, I'm sorry that you
wasted your savings.
No, you got us here.
I'm even sorry that you
got dragged into this
and that I'll have to
hear about it every
Thanksgiving and Christmas
for the next
however many years.
Grace.
But most of all,
I'm sorry that I ever thought I was the
kind of person that could come to Paris.
I'm sorry.
Can we just leave it at that?
(EMMA SHRIEKS)
(EMMA GROANS)
How far is our hotel?
Wait, where you going?
Inside.
She's here. Cordelia!
Cordelia, please!
Grace, wait!
What?
What in the heck
was that all...
Oh, nice and big.
MEG: There she is.
No ticket? No itinerary?
I am sorry,
but there is nothing.
And now do you propose I travel
to Monte Carlo in the morning?
(CRYING)
Hey, Grace, it's okay.
Yeah, yeah, Grace, you just
got to pull it together.
Okay, don't!
Don't be sweet
and don't be whatever
it is that you are.
Just don't talk to me.
(DOOR BANGS)
Meg.;0]
These are cloth.
Mademoiselle Scott, Mademoiselle Scott...
No, Miss Scott,
I explain to you.
I have checked and there is nothing.
No sign of package.
(EXHALES)
Does anyone here
speak English?
This is not English
we are speaking?
It's me, Cordelia.
Yes, I'm still in Paris.
Mother's forcing me to go to some
charity thing to repair my rep.
I don't know.
Polar bears, hungry people.
Where are you?
Majorca! Hmm.
If I leave now,
I can catch a flight
and be on the beach
by the morning.
No, I won't even check out.
Mummy will think
I'm off doing her errand.
By the time she works out
that I'm not there or here...
Let me call you
when I get to the airport.
GRACE: Emma.
It may take a while.
It appears to be raining...
GRACE: Can you
hand me a towel?
...quite hard.
(SIGHS)
Thanks for nothing.
Who was that head case?
Who does she think she is?
(SIGHS)
EMMA: I'm telling you,
trust us.
GRACE: You guys, easy.
Look at this.
Look, with her hair pulled back.
(GASPS)
You look just like her.
I look nothing like her.
You didn't even see her.
I heard her.
Yeah,
that's the same thing.
That's crazy.
Look this way.
You guys are like twins.
Stop it!
Scowl. (GROWLS) Do it.
If only you were British.
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT)
Poor me.
Mummy wants me
to help people, poor people.
But I hate poor people.
How are you doing that?
That's really creepy.
Who Cares?
It kind of sounds like a mean Mary Poppins.
I like it, do more.
Okay. I want
to go to Spain.
I want to see my friends.
I want a golden goose.
Excuse me, Miss Scott.
Good news.
The courier successfully
located your package.
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
Oh, no, I'm not...
She's not...
No. No, there has
been a mistake.
Yes, yes, we know.
We are so, so sorry.
Your package will be
here in the morning.
In the meantime,
we have found,
as you requested,
a 26-pound langouste.
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT)
I shall take it in my room.
In the room.
(SIGHS)
Can you imagine having a room like
this and not even staying in it?
Yeah. So, we're not
staying here.
Meg, you watching?
Great, now we have
to make the bed.
GRACE: Meg,
can you just...
EMMA: Relax.
GRACE: We're just resting.
Oh!
Chocolate.
Mmm!
It's like money.
Meg, come on, it’s been a really long day.
Let's... Let's bond.
Fine.
(SIGHS) Okay.
Just until it stops raining.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
Oui?
Oui, oui?
What time is it?
Meg.;0]
Meg! Hey, wake up.
Oh, frak!
Who fell asleep?
Oui!
What did they say?
I'm not a hundred
percent sure,
but I think
my car is here.
MANAGER: Oh,
Mademoiselle Scott!
Just keep moving.
Miss Scott.
Miss Scott!
Miss Scott, your package.
Your package has arrived this morning.
Take it.
Just take it.
Merci.
Let's help you
to your car.
No! We're fine.
Oh, yes, please!
Thank you, again.
Miss Scott.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Your car is waiting.
No, thank you.
But we'll walk.
But you cannot
walk to the airport.
Airport?
Yeah.
Airport. Thank you.
No! No, we're not...
Au revoir!
MEG: They really do think you’re her.
(STAMMERS)
What? I want to know
where we're going.
We're going back
to our crap tour.
We are going
to Monte Carlo.
Wherever that is.
Hilarious.
Grace, what does "privé" mean?
Is that an airline?
Let me see this.
See, Grace wants to go.
Forget it.
The trip is paid for, whether
Cordelia takes it or not.
And she is
a million miles away.
It's stealing.
It's seizing the moment.
We will get caught.
And then you'll get to say,
"I told you so."
Like you're going
to pass that up.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Warm nuts.
I am never flying
commercial again.
I shouldn’t
Oh!
Hello.
Let's read all about you.
Wait a minute, that's her?
I don’t look anything like that.
No, no, she has
a better nose.
It's a better slope.
Mmm!
"Jet-setting heiress
Cordelia Winthrop Scott..."
You're an heiress.
was caught by paparazzi in Reykjavik when she...”
Oh.
Escandalo.
What?
Cordelia,
you are a bad, bad girl.
Give me that.
What did I do?
What didn't you do?
(THANKING IN FRENCH)
(APOLOGIZING IN FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
And I'm here.
Late.
I still made it before
the little monster arrived.
Look, here it is.
Miss Scott!
On behalf of the Marchand
Family Foundation
and Save the Children,
it's my pleasure to welcome
you to Monte Carlo.
I am Bernard Marchand
and my son, Theo.
Miss Scott.
And you've brought
some friends?
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT) Uh, yes, this
is Emma Perkins and Meg Kelly.
Friends from the States
that I picked up somehow.
Just follow my lead.
Beaujolais!
How do you do?
(IN FRENCH)
It is a pleasure to meet you.
I hope we're not disturbing you.
Meg speaks French.
Yeah, I just got that.
BERNARD:
Let's get you settled
and Theo will be back
to pick you up this evening.
Yes, I will escort you
to the ball.
This keeps getting
better and better.
I'm sorry, the what?
The ball.
Ball?
The Prince's ball.
The one being thrown in her honor.
Oh, that ball.
Yes, that ball.
Perfect.
Come on, please.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MEG: Thank you. Merci
Thank you. Thank you.
Merci. Thank you.
Thank you.
We've got to
get out of here.
Why?
This is all paid for.
You never leave when it's paid for.
What are they teaching
you in college?
Emma, Meg is right.
This is too crazy.
You guys.
You don't take somebody's
private jet to Monte Carlo...
But you made us!
...find out they're throwing
you a ball in your honor
and then go, "Oh, no,
I couldn't possibly!"
You go.
Is this a real conversation?
Emma,
we are way
out of our league.
They're going to see
right through me.
Grace, you'll be fine.
Just keep up the accent
and look down your nose.
I'm sure Meg can
help you out with that.
You know,
I'm out, okay?
This was never part of the plan.
I'm out.
(SIGHS) The plan.
You know what the problem
is with you two?
It's that you are
exactly alike.
We are nothing alike.
Hmm.
Okay, fine,
you kids want a plan?
Here is the plan.
We go to that ball,
real Cordelia gets to play
hooky for a few days,
Frere Jacques gets
his charity girl,
and we
all get the vacation
that I deserve.
(SIGHS)
How's that for a plan?
(GASPS)
All right, I'll tell you one
thing right now, heels are a no.
Grace Bennett
in an Oscar De La Renta.
Oh, I just did
my make-up.
Save the tears
for the police.
Can you just
for one minute...
Nice, Meg.
Thank you.
Y'all, I think
mine is on backwards.
Or maybe the other me has a
little more going on upstairs.
Just feels like something...
Is missing?
Maybe two things.
No. Just one.
(BRIGHT LIGHTS BIGGER CITY
PLAYING)
You're late.
He's so mean.
Are you coming?
Thank you.
So ding-dangy delicious.
So I guess
I'll have to wait and see
How is Owen?
But I'm just gonna let something
brand new happen to me
And it's all right
It's all right,
it's all right
Bright lights
and the big city
Belongs to us tonight...
(ALL CLAMORING)
Say, Owen.
Hey, man, how you doing?
What are you hearing
from the girls?
Nothing much.
Paris, man,
that is far out.
Yeah, how so?
We don't call it the City
of Love for nothing.
It's the City of Lights.
0 w m z C) z
(GROANS)
Hello.
Hello, who's this?
Who's this?
It's Owen.
(GIGGLES)
Is that Emma?
Is Emma there?
She is...
She's what?
Not available to you.
Not available to me.
Yeah, well,
we'll see about that.
(STARTS CAR ENG l N E)
EMMA: Would you relax?
She is with French fry.
I thought you were
keeping an eye on her.
No,no,no.
We need
to stay focused.
Why?
Hello.
Focus, Meg.
You're ridiculous.
Why do people keep staring?
Is something slipping?
It's the necklace.
Your donation
for Friday's auction.
For Friday's auction.
On Friday.
Because I'll be here
all week.
Oh. My father says
we can build 20 schools
with the money
we will raise.
That's amazing.
That's a lot of futures
you're changing.
It almost makes
dressing up worth it.
Well, people are maybe
looking at your necklace,
but me, I have been
admiring the boots.
Theo.
Dom, how are you?
Good. You?
This is Cordelia
Winthrop Scott.
Prince Domenico da Silvano.
Oh, uh, how do you do?
Fine, thank you.
Hello.
Hey, how you doing?
MEG: Yeah hi.
Hey, Cordelia, you were
supposed to wait by the door.
I was, but then he had
me working the room.
DOMENICO: Would you
care to dance?
No, thank you, Dom.
He's not talking to you.
Enchantée.
My father is very
grateful to your aunt.
She persuaded your mother
to donate to our charity.
My aunt?
MEG: Alicia Winthrop Scott was married to your late Uncle William.
How do you know that?
Well, hello, it's called HELLO!
magazine for a reason.
He died two years ago
on safari.
Who? What?
Okay, you were born in
Shropshire, parents divorced.
Schooled at Le Rosey,
but you were expelled
because you set
your roommate's hair on fire
in her sleep.
Cordelia!
Aunt Alicia! Oh.
Well, don't you look lovely.
I'm so glad to see
that you're here.
Well, where else
would I be than here,
in Monte Carlo, where
I'm supposed to be?
At my ball, Aunt Alicia.
(CHUCKLES)
Yes.
I just wanted to come and verify
your presence for myself.
Some peace of mind
for your poor mother.
Well, lovely to see you.
Now if you'll excuse me.
There's something
different about you.
Different?
Yes. Yes, I can't quite
put my finger on it.
People do change,
Aunt Alicia.
Well, here's hoping.
I'm bored.
You can report back to Mother
that I'm doing as told.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I want to dance.
Excuse me.
Well, you two seem
very close.
Mmm-hmm.
Everything is okay?
I'm so worried
about Cordelia.
(LOVE TODAY PLAYING)
I've been crying
for so long
Fighting tears
just to carry on
How long are you
here in Monte Carlo?
As long as possible, Dom.
Really?
Emma. We got to go.
No, I'm good.
Emma!
Dom is a prince.
Okay, my aunt is here.
Aunt Brenda?
Where?
Aunt Alicia,
here to see her favorite
niece, Cordelia.
Oh. That's bad.
And we have to
stay here till Friday.
Oh, that's good.
She totally bought it.
You see? We're good.
Meg, come on.
No, I'm telling you,
she thinks you're Cordelia!
You were just crazy enough!
Excuse me,
I'm going to dance
with her. Sorry.
It was thrilling.
Hello.
Hi.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
to 0 0 C CD C) C) CD N a 0 I
I'm looking for a taxi.
Taxi?
Yeah.
Okay, you have a taxi station
just over here. Straight on.
Merci.
You're welcome.
Mademoiselle Scott?
Oh, thank you.
Mmm.
(SIGHS) This is so nice.
(ALARM BEEPS)
Time to flip.
You have to rotate every three
minutes for optimal coverage.
It's a science.
Biology is a science.
Hey,
Meg.
Classy.
You know,
I picked out a dress for you.
I fixed your eyebrows.
Why are you picking
a fight with me?
I'm not.
Always. Little digs.
I know what
you think of me.
You have no idea
how little I think about you.
You see, Grace,
she's just not happy
unless everybody
around her is miserable.
Emma.
Trust me,
I forgot about you the
minute you left high school.
(SCOFFS)
And so did everybody else.
Yeah, right.
And who quits high school for
a catalog shoot in Dallas?
I was on the cover.
Of a Clip 'n' Save.
You are so delusional.
Okay, you know what this is?
We had a big night last...
You know what your problem is? It’s that you are just jealous.
Jealous?
You're a waitress.
Your best friend is
an 18-year-old girl.
Excuse me?
And your boyfriend...
Okay, who died
and made you such a...
Emma!
That's not what I meant.
(SIGHS)
If you'll excuse me.
Meg, she didn’t...
Nice friend.
Okay.
Ma petite-amie Emma.
You answered her phone.
Come on, help me out. She's my fiancee.
Here, take a look.
Have you seen?
Yeah, you know her.
Where did she go?
But she's gone.
Oh!
Well, yeah...
But where?
(SIGHS)
Hey,
Meg.
Riley?
Hey.
Hi.
You're not
following me, are you?
Following?
No. No, I didn’t...
You okay?
Rm good. (CHUCKLES)
So, where's your bus?
It left us behind
a long time ago.
Stupid bus.
Cordelia!
Oh, hey. What's up?
You're late.
Late for what?
Are you...
What?
You sound...
Something different.
Chip-chop, spit-spot,
come on, let's go!
Off we go! Quickly, come on!
Let's go.
Okay.
Did somebody get flowers?
Meg?
Grace?
Me.
(EXHALES) "Emma, please
allow me the honor..."
Da-da-da-da-da-da-da. .
"I'll pick you up at 8:00.
Domenico"
(SNIFFING)
Cheers, thank you.
Okay, all right.
Yeah?
All right, this is what
you've been waiting for.
Bring it on.
I want to see this.
I mean to just...
(LAUGHS)
Au right, I'll have a go.
All right.
You want to? Go?
Ready?
Go ahead.
There we go. That's it.
You actually know how to do it.
That's good.
Bonjour Lucille,
this is Mademoiselle Scott.
Lucille will take care of you,
she'll show you to your room.
Where are you going?
I have to go change.
Change?
I'll see you on the field.
Cordelia!
There you are.
Ah, Aunt Alicia.
I’d love to stay and chat,
but I must change, so...
Really!
Merci.
Polo, how hard can it be?
Hey! I think we are
going the other way.
Oh, right. See, at home they usually just bring the ball to me.
Right. The other way. Okay.
Go right.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Your niece plays
with spirit.
Usually with more
finesse than spirit.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
(I WANT THE SKY PLAYING)
I'm ready, ready to run free
That's a nice one.
Thank you.
I 'd like to know
what lies beyond the blue sea
You live once,
so drink the honey
(WHOOPS)
I learn my lessons
from the birds and the bees
I want the sky to open wide
Illuminate this fire inside
I want the sky
So, you just go
wherever you like?
Yeah, that's the idea.
For how long?
I'll let you know
when I'm done.
And your parents
are okay with this?
I think they were just happy to see
me walk out of there, you know?
What, did they say you'd never
walk again or something?
I was never much good at being
told what I couldn't do.
But I was in hospital for a
year just flat on my back.
I hate hospitals.
My teammates would come and
visit in the beginning,
but after a while,
I was just a reminder
of what could happen to them.
Bad fall,
get hit in the wrong place,
never play rugby again.
Anyway,
trekking around for a while
just seemed like
the best way back.
You miss your mum.
I can't find my way back.
I went to the hospital to see
her every day she was there.
Almost two years.
That's a long time.
Not long enough.
(SIGHS)
Everyone was so nice, and
understanding, and comforting, and...
I just wanted to scream.
Do it.
Go on. Scream.
Just do it.
Look, I won't even listen.
I won't listen.
I can't.
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
(LAUGHS)
(RINGING)
Is it all right if I take her?
I'd love to brush her down.
What?
The ball. Take it!
This is Cordelia.
Hello?
(SPECTATORS APPLAUDING)
Who is this?
Is it all right if I take her?
I'd love to brush her down.
Really?
Yeah, I've got her.
Odd.
You've never been one
to clear up after yourself.
A new leaf, a new me.
It appears
you've made a friend.
I know.
isn't she a beauty?
Remember that darling
pony you had as a girl?
What was its name again?
My childhood, please!
You know I never look back.
Oh, you remember
the black one
with the little white
star on his forehead.
Yes. Uh...
The one with the star.
I called him Blaze.
Blaze?
I really should get her
back to the stables, so...
The resemblance
is astonishing.
But Cordelia rides
English saddle.
And you, if I'm not mistaken,
were taught to ride Western.
Heaven forbid.
I'm just a little out of
practice, that's all.
Well, this is a new low
even for Cordelia.
To hire a look-alike
to stand in her stead
at a charity event
organized just for her
while she's off partying.
I don't know
if it's the champagne
or the sunlight
that's got to you.
Oh, I will call
security immediately.
No, you can't.
The charity!
Look, I promise you
that I will do whatever is
expected of Cordelia tomorrow.
I'm not about to stand in the
way of helping those kids.
Are you?
BERNARD: Alicia.
No one must ever know.
Is that clear?
Crystal.
Here you are.
What a wonderful match.
I was just
congratulating Cordelia.
The ambassador
is ready for us.
Oh. Shall we?
If you muck this up, you
will have me to answer to.
Both of you.
Pass it on.
Oh.
(SIGHS)
Bling,bling,bling,bling,
bling,bling,bling.
Who are you
hiding from?
Hey.
You ride very well.
It's one of the two things
my father taught me.
And the other?
(WHISTLING)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(LAUGHING)
It's actually more handy
than you might think.
(BLOWS)
No, here. Put your
fingers like this
and now curl your
tongue like that.
Now you try.
(SPUTTERING)
(LAUGHING)
That's terrible.
Well, I'll work on it.
I think you should.
You're not what
I expected.
No?
You're different.
Different?
Different is good.
Is it?
You make me think it is.
You make me
feel different.
Sorry.
Why?
Mostly I always
feel the same.
Same people, same
conversations, same parties.
None of it means anything.
But you help people.
I mean, you're raising
money, building schools.
I wish I were part of
something that important.
But that's my father.
That's not me.
I do nothing.
I've never been
to those schools.
to Africa, to Romania.
I'm only faking
my way through.
I know what
that feels like.
But there is nothing
fake about you.
I want to
show you something.
(MOUNTAIN AND THE SEA PLAYING)
You call me a mountain
And I call you the sea
You can move me
if you want to...
Thank you.
And then we're gonna go
meet his friends
and then we're
gonna go dancing!
Meg, what has
gotten into you?
I know.
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
Me, too.
Oh. (LAUGHS)
Hey, mate.
What?
The necklace.
There's the Meg
that I know.
What were you thinking?
Stay classy, Meg.
RILEY: You good?
Yeah. I'm perfect.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
First class.
(TAKE IT EASY PLAYING)
Relax, take it easy
For there is nothing
that we can do
Relax, take it easy
Blame it on me
or blame it on you
Relax, take it easy
(LAUGHING)
(ALL CHATTERING IN FRENCH)
Jerome.
Merci.
Excuse me.
There are people for that.
Yeah, I know.
Give me your hand.
Thank you.
Wow.
THEO: I'm trying
to impress you.
GRACE: Mmm.
So far, so good.
When I was little, I had a snow
globe of the Eiffel Tower,
and when you
wound it up it played
La Vie En Rose.
(LA VIE EN ROSE PLAYING)
And when I shook it,
the snow inside sparkled.
(HUMMING)
When you kiss me
heaven sighs
It was magical.
Just like this.
I see la vie en rose
Just wait.
When you press me
to your heart
I'm in a world apart
A world where roses bloom
And when you speak
Look at this one.
Angels sing from above
Everyday words seem
to turn into love songs
This is amazing!
(LAUGHING)
And life will always be
La vie en rose
I had a lovely time tonight.
Me, too, Cordelia.
Theo, I need to
tell you something.
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
Yeah, sure, please.
Hi, good evening.
Maybe tomorrow.
All right, then tomorrow.
I'll see you
at the auction, all right?
to 0 0
(CHATTERING IN FRENCH ON TV)
Emma?
I'm in here.
Hey.
Domenico?
Mmm-hmm.
What are you watching?
Grace Kelly.
(SIGHS)
You know how on
Hastings Avenue,
how all the houses
are set way back?
With the front walks and
big lawns and driveways.
I always wondered about the kind
of people that lived there.
You know,
the kind of people with
the dimmer switches
on their lights.
I thought Owen
and I were gonna
live in a house
like that one day.
(SIGHS) It's crazy.
It's not crazy.
So stupid.
I don't need a fancy house.
I just need Owen.
Grace, what if I blew it?
Emma...
Oh, hey.
Hey, don't you
worry about it.
Okay?
We'll work it out.
We always do.
I know. I know you will.
Then what?
I just...
I finally meet a guy
who likes me for me,
and I'm not even me.
But I feel like I am
when I'm with him.
If Theo finds out,
he's gonna hate me.
Grace, trust me.
Once he knows the real you,
the Grace that I know,
he's just gonna know
how lucky he is.
You think?
I knew it from the minute
I laid eyes on you.
(SIGHS)
You're going places, kid.
Wait.
Where's Meg?
Close your eyes.
(LAUGHS) Do it.
Where did you find that?
For you.
Hmm.
Now, run.
Hey!
(PROTESTS IN FRENCH)
(PRODDING IN FRENCH)
to 0 a 0 to 0 a 0
(SIGHS)
This is me.
Back up to
the old Grimaldi Suite.
You're staying here?
Yeah. Sort of an upgrade.
Offer stands, Meg.
It's not as posh as this.
There's a place in Tuscany.
You just pitch your tent
right on the beach.
And
the company is good.
I wish I could.
The train leaves at noon
if you change your mind.
Change your mind.
(SIGHS)
Have a nice trip.
You, too, Meg.
GRACE: Meg? Meg?
Hey!
Where have you been?
Will you relax?
it's okay, she is right here.
The article said
millions, Emma.
Yeah, I heard you
the first hundred times.
On my neck.
I'm not going to relax until
that thing is back in its case.
What is going on
with you two?
Can you please just
give her the necklace?
What necklace?
Om Riley!
It's in his backpack.
I put it in his backpack to be safe!
GRACE: Backpack? Wait!
Wait! What?
Whose backpack?
Riley's.
Okay, so Riley has it.
Where is he staying?
He's not. He's gone.
He stole the necklace?
No, Emma,
he didn't steal anything.
He's getting on
a train to Italy.
Are you kidding me?
At noon.
How far is the train station
from here?
PHOTOGRAPHERS:
Cordelia! Cordelia!
Oh, hey,
what's she doing here?
Oh! Mademoiselle Scott.
Room key.
Faster.
(KEYS RATTLING)
Sorry.
Pillow, there.
Now the blankets.
Nobody in Majorca
knew...
Cordelia?
Right.
Cordelia.
(SIGHS) Hold on, Victoria.
Yes?
Good morning.
Forgot how I hate the French.
Do not even think about it.
(SHRIEKS)
Shanghai?
Well, can you wait for me?
I just have this tiresome
auction I have to deal with.
I suppose it...
(INVITING IN FRENCH)
Well, let's just...
I was meant to have a suite.
Put those in there.
Wait. Wait.
Stavros is supposed
to be here, isn't he?
I don't see his boat.
He's in Mykonos.
PORTER: Mademoiselle?
Hold on.
Yes?
If you have finished,
you may go.
Emma, go.
No, I can't move.
Move!
You have to go!
Do it! GO.
(EXHALING)
Okay, okay.
Oh, God.
Don't look down.
I'm sorry.
I looked down.
Okay.
EMMA: I can't breathe, I can't
breathe, I can't breathe.
Emma, stop it. It's over!
Calm down. Shh!
(RATTLING DOORS)
it's locked.
Come on.
It's locked, too!
Oh, no.
No, no, no. Meg!
Wait, no!
Wait!
No, no, no! Wait!
No! No!
The train.
The necklace.
Riley.
Yes, I'm here, Mother.
So unfair.
I never get to see my friends.
I never do what I want.
When is it
going to be my turn?
Ugh!
(SCREAMING)
You know what?
Let's just get
on a train and go.
I can't.
I pretended to be that girl
and now I lost her necklace.
You didn't lose
her necklace.
I did.
NO, I did.
Well, I lied
to Theo, about everything.
I have to go back.
What?
I have to fix this.
Or at least try.
Okay.
Okay, we go back.
We’ll explain. Maybe she’ll understand.
Fat chance.
Could you be
a little positive?
One night out
and look at you.
Cheers, mate.
Excuse me, excuse me.
I was wondering
if you could tell me
where the Grimaldi
Suite is, please.
(PHONE RINGING)
Pardon.
Hello?
This is Cordelia
Winthrop Scott.
I've been robbed.
Call the police.
Robbed! I will call securité
No, I said police!
Call the police!
C,) CD 0
No, I said police!
Call the...
Oh, forget it!
I'll do it myself!
Securité
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Mademoiselle Scott?
GRACE: Hello, Francois.
EMMA: Hi.
CD CD 0 C,) CD 0 CD
ALL: No, no, no.
You're still robbed?
Yeah
MEG: That’s crazy.
Police? I'm calling to report a
robbery at the Hotel de Paris.
This is Cordelia
Winthrop Scott.
Someone has been robbed?
No, nobody.
Theo! Nobody has been robbed.
We're all right.
But you...
How are you?
Are you teasing me?
Teasing you? No.
Well, because this
feels like a game.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) it's not a game.
Not to me.
But I do need to
tell you something.
And she will.
Later.
But the auction!
Back in 10.
Oh.
I'll be right back.
Okay?
It starts in five minutes.
Ladies, five minutes.
(IN FRENCH)
I don't understand women.
Perfectly good pear.
(EXHALES)
Grimaldi.
(LIFT BELL DINGS)
Riley!
Meg!
The necklace!
Do not touch that bell!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Bonjour.
Hi. I need to find this girl.
Have you seen her?
Oui.
You came back.
I found your necklace.
Thought it was a pretty good
excuse for a second shot.
Wait for me in the lobby.
You got it.
Don't leave.
I'm not going anywhere.
Pardon me.
Hold on one second
there, boss.
You're telling me that
Emma is staying here?
I told you this.
Mademoiselle Scott's friend.
Now, pardon.
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(INQUIRING IN FRENCH)
(DOORBELL CHIMING)
Finally...
We can explain.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(RESISTING IN FRENCH)
GRACE: Listen...
Save your sorries for the police.
Wait, wait.
The police?
Oh, please!
But it's right here.
I have it.
Exactly! You have it!
MEG: Look, this wasn’t planned.
It's just a case of
mistaken identity.
It's impersonation
and it's a crime,
one I'm putting
a stop to this instant.
But the auction...
Oh!
Let me assure you that there
will be no auction now.
Hey! People are
counting on her!
(STAMMERING)
Or on you... What?
That's not my problem.
Don't touch the phone.
Or what?
I promise you it
is a false alarm.
She said everything was fine.
Quoi?
(IN FRENCH)
But why am I speaking English?
CORDELIA: No!
Ow! You let me up.
Now what do we do?
Cordelia?
RECEPTIONIST: Mademoiselle?
Help! Mmm!
(SQUEALING)
Mademoiselle,
open the door!
GRACE: Just a minute.
Give me the...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Bonjour.
Hello.
Hi.
Mademoiselle.
Excusez-moi. We had a call.
There was a robbery?
Oh, no.
A misunderstanding.
YOU see?
Yes, she couldn't
find her necklace.
What? Where is she?
I'm right here.
RECEPTIONIST:
There she is.
Bonjour
mademoiselle.
Bonjour.
Theo, could you help me?
I can't quite
manage the clasp.
But tell me,
we heard a scream.
Oh!
When she found
the necklace,
right now,
she was so, so happy.
(WHISPERING)
What's going on here?
Relieved.
Oh, really?
Yes, I'm very sorry
to have wasted your time.
Well,
allow me to escort you, mademoiselle,
you know, as a precaution.
Would you?
I'm afraid I'm already late.
Right, Theo? Theo?
Coming, Meg?
Yes.
Right behind you.
(RECEPTIONIST
THANKING IN FRENCH)
How's it going in here?
Oh, we're good.
Just getting acquainted.
We Will...
We'll let you go as soon
as the auction is over.
Be right back.
MEG: Oh, come on.
Come on.
Promise
that whatever happens,
you'll think of the girl
you showed the fireworks to.
That was me.
Grace? Meg!
Owen! What are you doing here?
What's with...
Where's Emma?
She's upstairs.
Meg, is everything all right?
Yeah, everything's fine.
Where upstairs?
Trust me, you don't
want to go up there.
(IN ENGLISH ACCENT) Meg?
Yes?
Are you coming?
Coming.
Why is she talking
like that?
(G ROAN S) She's not.
Please, both of you,
just stay here.
Hey, mate.
Third floor.
Grimaldi Suite.
What did you tell him?
It's fine,
he's waiting with Riley.
BERNARD: (ANNOUNCING)
Miss Cordelia Winthrop Scott.
We've got this.
I’m really glad you came, Meg.
I wouldn't miss this
for the world.
(APPLAUSE)
You will never
get away with this.
Honey, we've been getting
away with this for days.
(DOORBELL CHIMING)
You... What?
Don't mess with Texas.
(EXCLAIMS)
Emma.
Owen?
What are you...
What are you doing here?
(STAMMERING)
What am I doing here?
I've been
running all over
Paris looking for you.
Hi.
BERNARD: 1,000,000 eurOS.
'l,500,000.
We have a bid for 1.5.
'l,700,000.
Marvelous!
Do I hear two?
You went all the way
to Paris for me?
I don't want to
lose you, Emma.
Maybe I was trying
to fence you in a bit.
Guess I was just worried
that once you saw everything
there was to see here,
you wouldn't come back.
Owen...
And look,
I'm sorry for that,
because I don't ever want to
keep you from something better.
Emma,
you deserve the best.
But I already
have the best.
Yeah?
Yeah.
(THUDDING)
What was that?
(GRUNTING)
So, Paris. it's pretty
awesome, right?
What was that?
What was what, honey?
You heard it.
No, I didn't.
Is someone in there?
What? Is someone
in here? No.
Emma, what's going on?
Oh, shoot.
OWEN: Grace?
(LOUD APPLAUSE)
BERNARD:
We have a bid for 2.5.
Who Will bid 3,000,000 euros?
Anyone?
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
it's too much.
Mesdames et messieurs,
who will take us to 3,000,000?
Can I have...
Please, I'm sorry.
But,
my dear, what is wrong?
It's okay.
There's something
I need to say.
Of course.
What is it, Cordelia?
Gandhi once said...
Gandhi?
...that you must be
the change you wish
to see.
This necklace isn't mine.
(ALL MURMURING)
CORDELIA:
No, it's mine.
Arrest her,
she's an imposter.
Arrest her.
It's true.
I'm not Cordelia Scott.
There, you see?
I'm just a regular
girl from Texas.
I'm no one special,
but I had
the chance to be,
even if it was only for a
minute, and I took it.
We all did.
And we're sorry.
I know what
I did was wrong
and I don't expect
you to forgive me.
But it wasn't
all a lie.
I thought you were different.
$3,000,000.
(ALL GASP)
Owen.
We're from Texas,
we go big.
He doesn't have
any money.
Look at them,
none of them do.
Arrest them.
it's okay.
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean...
Look, you all came here
to help those kids.
Please don't let my mistake
get in the way of that.
I may not
deserve your help,
but they do.
ALICIA: 6,000,000 euros.
(ALL GASPING)
I would like to
bid 6,000,000 euros
for the necklace...
Aunt Alicia?
...on that young
woman's neck,
whomever she may be.
What are you doing?
I'm doing precisely
as she has asked.
I'm helping.
Sold for 6,000,000 euros
to one Miss Scott.
(CHUCKLING) Yeah!
No! But?
Thank you.
Why are you just standing there?
Arrest them!
For what?
They seem very nice.
They stole
my necklace.
But the necklace
is here, no?
Well, they kidnapped me
and they tied me up.
And yet,
you too are here.
I see no problem,
everybody is very happy.
Excuse me,
but I am not happy.
Hmm.
But this I can do
nothing about.
So, where to?
Let's go home.
GRACE: I don’t know, Meg. Have you really thought about this?
No! No, not at all.
But what did you
tell your dad?
Well, I told him I'd call
and check in every day,
that I won't tell him
everything I'm doing,
that I'll be back
in August,
and then
I hung up
very quickly.
(LAUGHS)
You,
take care of my sister.
RILEY:
Precious cargo.
My driver will take
you to the airport.
Bye,you
two lovebirds.
Please tell Theo
I said goodbye.
I will be sure to.
And that he was right.
I am different.
He knows that.
But I'll tell him.
Thank you.
Bye.
Au revoir!
See you later.
Au revoir.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hi, Mom
Yeah, we had
an amazing time.
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(RILEY WHOOPING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Just like that.
Try it out.
Hey, Grace, I need somebody
to run to the post office.
I'll do it.
That was it.
Yes, all right.
Now I am going to show you the
foundation of the new stadium,
which is possibly to be ready
by the end of the month.
We will have new lighting
for each classroom,
and the computers will
be here by September.
Superbe. Fine.
Thank you very much.
ARCHITECT: So,
what do you think?
THEO: Well!
It's amazing.
This follows the same model
as you saw it in Rajasthan.
This is the dormitory?
Yes, for about
100 children.
And on the other side
we have the garden.
Excuse me one moment!
Grace!
(MUFFLED) Grace!
(WHISTLES)
Theo.
What are you
doing here?
I'm working.
What are you
doing here?
I'm volunteering.
I don't think that
we've properly met.
I'm Grace Bennett.
Theo Marchand.
It's nice
to meet you.
(BLAME IT ON
THE GIRLS PLAYING)
He's got looks that books
take pages to tell
He's got a face to make
you fall on your knees
He's got money in the bank
to thank and I guess
0 0 a
Like lovers on the open
shore What's the matter?
When you're sitting there
with so much more
What's the matter?
While you're wondering
what the hell to be
Are you wishing
you were ugly like me?
Blame it on the girls
who know what to do
Blame it on the boys
who keep hitting on you
Blame it on your mother
for the things she said
Blame it on your father
but you know he's dead
Blame it on the girls
Blame it on the boys
(WHO SAYS PLAYING)
Wouldn't wanna be
anybody else, hey
You made me insecure
Told me I wasn't good enough
But who are you to judge
When you're a diamond
in the rough
I'm sure
you got somethings
You'd like to
change about yourself
But when it
comes to me
I wouldn't wanna be
anybody else
(VOCALIZING)
I'm no beauty queen
I'm just beautiful me
(VOCALIZING)
You've got every right
To a beautiful life
Come on!
Who says
Who says you're not perfect
you're not worth it
Who says you're the
only one that's hurting
Trust me
That's the price of beauty
Who says
you're not pretty
you're not beautiful
Who says?
It's such a funny thing
How nothings funny
when it's you
You tell them
what you mean
But they keep
whiting out the truth
It's like a work of art
That never gets
to see the light.
Keep you
beneath the stars
Won't let you
touch the sky
(VOCALIZING)
I'm no beauty queen
I'm just beautiful me
(VOCALIZING)
You've got every right
To a beautiful life
Come on!
Who says
Who says you're not perfect
you're not worth it
Who says you're the
only one that's hurting
Trust me
That's the price of beauty
Who says
you're not pretty
you're not beautiful
Who says?
Who says you're
not star potential
not presidential
Who says you
can't be in movies
Listen to me
Who says you
don't pass the test
can't be the best
Who said
Would you tell me
who said that
Yeah, who says
Who says
Who says you're not perfect
you're not worth it
Who says you're the
only one that's hurting
Trust me
That's the price of beauty
Who says
you're not pretty
you're not beautiful
Who says?
Who says
you're not perfect
you're not worth it
Who says you're the
only one that's hurting
Trust me
That's the price of beauty
Who says
you're not pretty
you're not beautiful
Who says
THE END