WOMAN:
There you are.
I've been Iooking for you.
Have you seen my other shoe?
What?
Why are you Iooking at me Iike that?
[ALARM CLOCK BEEPING]
Go potty.
Scotty.
Come on, boy. Scotty.
Go potty, Scotty.
[TOY SQUEAKING]
Don't Iook at me Iike that.
[TOY SQUEAKS]
[PHONE RINGS]
Yes?
HARRY:
Great way to start the day, right?
I think I'm gonna puke.
Mom said you went on a date Iast week.
How'd it go?
It was okay.
''Okay'' as in you got Iaid?
-Harry.
-What?
She can't hear you.
Don't you wanna have sex,
Iike, ever again in your Iife?
Yes. I just don't think
that I'm the dating type.
GirIs onIy wanna sIeep with me
because they read my book in high schooI.
So?
So they're not interested in me.
They're interested in some idea of me.
That's why you shouId keep working out.
That way, they'II want you for your body.
What does this thing even do?
It turns you into a god.
Keep going.
Hey, I had a weird dream Iast night.
There was this girI and she was--
What'd she Iook Iike?
Just a normaI girI. Just a girI I made up.
WeII, what happened?
She just taIked to me.
That's depressing.
ActuaIIy, it was reaIIy nice.
SeriousIy? You don't even get Iaid
in your dreams? That's....
That's just sad.
Hey, how's the new book coming aIong?
I don't know. I get a good idea,
Iike why don't I write about my dad?
And then, bam, I start thinking
that it's the stupidest thing ever.
Who wants to read about,
''He was disappointed in me...
...bIah, bIah, bIah, bIah''?
AIso, I'm feeIing ambivaIent
about Scotty.
Yeah, he sIobbers. He chews things.
He pees Iike a girI,
which makes me feeI inadequate.
He needs to go outside a Iot, breaks up
my day. That's why I'm not writing.
ROSENTHAL:
Do you think that's why you're not writing?
CALVIN: No.
-Why do think you're not writing?
Can I have Bobby now?
-Do you need Bobby now?
-Yes.
CaIvin...
...when's the Iast time you saw a friend?
Harry. Yesterday.
No, no.
Someone other than your brother.
Uh, have you been giving Bobby
to your other patients?
No, Bobby is just for you.
-Because he smeIIs weird.
-CaIvin...
...when you were deciding to get Scotty,
what did we taIk about?
What did you say your hopes were?
Do you remember?
[WHISPERS]
That he wouId heIp me meet peopIe.
A IittIe Iouder, pIease?
[IN NORMAL VOICE] That he wouId be
awesome and we'd take hikes and stuff.
And peopIe wouId stop to pet him,
and I wouId meet them.
But Scotty gets scared
when peopIe try to pet him.
Does that embarrass you?
-No.
-I wanna give you a writing assignment.
-I can't write.
-Okay.
This wouId just be for me.
I'd Iike you to write a page...
...about someone who sees Scotty
aII sIobbery and scared...
...and Iikes him anyway,
just the way he is.
You think you couId do that for me?
Can it be bad?
I'd Iike it to be very bad.
[APPLAUSE]
I first met CaIvin
when he was 19 years oId.
And he'd aIready been at the top...
...of The New York Times Best SeIIer Iist,
uh, for severaI months.
And I remember thinking:
''Who the fuck is this kid?
[AUDIENCE LAUGHS]
And, uh, how can I go back in time
and be him?''
[AUDIENCE LAUGHS]
A high-schooI dropout
with acne stiII on his chin...
...gave us what may very weII become
a cIassic American noveI.
Since then, of course,
we've aII enjoyed his short stories...
...uh, incIuding Iast year's noveIIa,
Breakfast for Dinner.
But it was onIy when I sat down
and reread his noveI...
...now avaiIabIe in a beautifuI
10th anniversary edition...
...that, uh, I reaIized just how good a writer
CaIvin Weir-FieIds is.
We are Iucky to have him around.
Ladies and gentIemen,
CaIvin Weir-FieIds.
[APPLAUSE]
-PhenomenaI, man. Just briIIiant.
-Thank you. Thanks.
-BriIIiant.
-Thanks so much.
MAN 1: CaIvin.
-Hi.
You know that chapter
where CharIie goes to the whorehouse?
Did you dress the whores bIue because
it's the coIor of his mother's apron?
I'm sorry--
How did you know
where to send your manuscript?
I Iooked it up.
MAN 2:
Oh, of course.
Is it weird for you
that you used to be so successfuI?
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
There's the man.
Cyrus, you gotta remind me
about these things.
You have to check your messages,
buddy.
I wouId've worn something nicer.
No one cares what you're wearing.
You are a genius.
Don't use that word.
MAN 1:
Mr. Perrotta, over here.
LANGDON: Calvin always had talent.
MAN 2: Over here.
LANGDON:
But that, unfortunately, is not enough.
WOMAN: Langdon, right here!
LANGDON: All l did, really...
...was guide him in the right direction
and, uh, Iike, pass the baton.
MabeI.
What?
I'm MabeI.
-Oh, do I know you?
-No, no.
Do you want my number?
LANGDON: It's a one-off, that book.
-Great.
-It's the first aIbum of an indie band.
-Thank you.
It has that sort of
unseIfconscious verve...
...that, um-- That you don't, uh....
Then, of course, there's
the second aIbum syndrome, which--
We don't taIk about that.
Everyone Ioves this book,
but we wanna hear what you're doing now.
What matters is right now.
What are you working on? Are you...?
LANGDON:
They Iove you, then they throw you away.
-I mean, if I'm gonna incIude anybody....
LANGDON: It's actuaIIy easier...
...if you've onIy ever been mediocre.
If you've been at the top--
-Hi. Sorry.
WOMAN: Hi.
LANGDON:
--it can kiII you.
Yeah, SaIinger had the right idea. He....
Write what you can, then, pssh, disappear,
you know?
So I've had a drink.
But no coke. I didn't-- No coke.
I didn't do any coke.
Scotty?
Sorry I'm Iate, buddy.
Scotty, what the fuck?
Oh.
WOMAN:
She's so cute.
CALVIN:
What?
Your dog. She's so cute.
Oh, he's a boy dog.
He just peed Iike a girI.
Have we met before?
I don't think so.
Do you mind if I draw him?
Uh, but don't get too cIose.
He's a IittIe scared of peopIe.
-You're an artist?
-Yeah.
-I'm super good.
-ReaIIy?
-What's your dog's name?
-Uh, Scotty.
-Are you Scottish?
-No.
I named him for F. Scott FitzgeraId.
-Who?
-F. Scott FitzgeraId.
The noveIist.
Great Gatsby.
I don't read a Iot of fiction.
You've never heard of
F. Scott FitzgeraId?
Why? Is he reaIIy famous and important?
WeII, he's probabIy one of the greatest
noveIists who ever Iived.
Isn't that disrespectfuI?
What?
Naming your dog after him?
It's a IittIe disrespectfuI.
-No, it's a gesture.
-Yeah, an aggressive gesture.
Think about it. You're a noveIist.
You think this guy's the greatest.
So you name your dog after him
to cut him down to size.
This way, you can put him on a Ieash...
...and yeII ''Bad Scotty''...
...and feeI aII superior
because you pee inside.
KiII your idoIs, man. I'm aII for it.
AII right. Scotty.
Hang on.
-This is beautifuI.
-Yeah.
Your dog might pee Iike a Iady,
but I Iike him anyway.
Hey, what did you just say?
I Iike him just the way he is.
Yes.
Yes. Yes.
''--pooIed into his eyes as though....
Rushed back Iike bIood....
CaIvin fIushed with....''
You're a genius.
ROSENTHAL:
I thought we weren't gonna use that word.
You are reaIIy, reaIIy super fucking smart.
''I'd Iike it to be bad.''
I'm gIad you found something
that inspires you.
Inspires me?
It overwheIms me.
I IiteraIIy cannot sIeep or eat.
AII I want I do is write.
I mean, I aImost didn't come here today
because I didn't wanna be away from her.
-Oh, God.
-What?
Oh, my God.
Oh, I can't say it out Ioud.
-It's too stupid.
-I Iove it when you say stupid things.
-Oh, no, this is reaIIy profoundIy stupid.
-Okay.
Ugh.
Okay, so the guy I'm writing....
Yeah, what's his name?
Uh, CaIvin.
I'm gonna change it.
Uh, anyway, there's a Iot of me in him.
What I'm trying to say is...
...it's aImost Iike I'm writing
to spend time with her.
-Who?
-The girI.
The one I'm writing. It's--
I go to sIeep at night...
...just waiting to get to my typewriter
so I can be with her.
It's Iike....
It's Iike I'm faIIing in Iove with her.
-That's wonderfuI.
-I can't faII in Iove with a girI I write.
-Why not?
-Because she's not reaI.
-Isn't she? Are you sure?
-No. Yes.
She's some motherfucking product
of my imagination!
-Oh, LiIa treated me so badIy.
-I know.
Who Ieaves someone after
their father dies?
Someone who couIdn't
Iove you properIy.
-Someone who is a heartIess sIut.
-Okay.
-WeII, teII me about her.
-I don't wanna taIk about LiIa anymore.
WeII, I meant this girI that you're writing.
TeII me about her.
Ruby.
Ruby Sparks.
Twenty-six years old.
Raised in Dayton, Ohio.
ROSENTHAL: Why Dayton?
CALVIN: Sounds romantic.
Ruby's first crushes were
Humphrey Bogart and John Lennon.
Cried the day she found out
they were aIready dead.
Ruby got kicked out of high schooI
for sIeeping with her art teacher...
...or maybe her Spanish teacher.
I haven't decided yet.
Ruby can't drive.
She doesn't own a computer.
She hates her middle name,
which is Tiffany.
She aIways, aIways roots
for the underdog.
She's compIicated.
That's what I Iike best about her.
Ruby's not so good at life sometimes.
She forgets to open bills
or cash checks and....
Her last boyfriend was 49.
The one before that was an alcoholic.
She can feeI a change coming.
She's Iooking for it.
ROSENTHAL:
Looking for what?
CALVIN:
Something new.
[CALVIN GRUNTS]
HARRY: FeeIs good, right?
-Can we stop a second?
Why? You aII right?
-Hey, Sue.
SUSIE: Yeah?
They didn't have paprika, so I got cumin.
-Shh, shh!
-They're the same thing, right?
MiIes went down.
If you wake him, I wiII beat you.
CaIvin? You need to thank me
because I cIeaned your oven.
-Thank you, Susie.
-Oh, my woman.
Okay. You're sweaty.
Get your mitts off of me.
-Susie, did you happen to sha--?
-You didn't teII me you were getting Iaid.
-Harry.
-I'm just saying.
He cIaims to be writing too much
to hauI his ass to our house.
But turns out,
he's just getting too much poon.
SUSIE: Harry, I swear to God--
-I'm not getting any poon.
Oh, yeah?
CALVIN: Whose is that?
-You teII me.
Oh, my God. Scotty.
-It's Scotty's?
CALVIN: No. Scotty--
Don't Iet the baby touch that.
MiIes, don't--
-Suse, he Iikes it.
SUSIE: No, he doesn't Iike it.
CALVIN: Scotty's been dragging them in.
-He seems to Iove it.
He goes through
my weird neighbor's garbage.
-So that's a random dirty bra?
HARRY: It's dirty.
That's gross. You made him cough.
CaIvin, don't put it away.
Throw it away.
I swear, if your mother knew--
-CaIvin, what is this?
HARRY: What's what?
-Nothing.
-Harry, get over here.
Uh, pIease, don't.
-Are these panties?
-Fuck off.
I swear, Scotty's been dragging them in.
-Right. Scotty.
-Shut up.
CaIvin, throw these away.
-Hey, Susie, I'm gonna check on Harry.
SUSIE: Okay.
-TeII him we have to go soon.
CALVIN: Okay.
So?
Where do you see this going?
WeII, I don't know. I just started.
HARRY:
This is a Iove story, right?
Who reads Iove stories?
Women.
And I'm teIIing you,
no woman's gonna wanna read this.
Why not? It's romantic.
Quirky, messy women whose probIems
onIy make them endearing are not reaI.
Period.
What do they say,
''write what you've been through''?
-Write what you know.
-ExactIy. Write what you know.
-I've known girIs Iike Ruby.
-Yeah?
Who?
GirIs.
-LiIa?
-Not fucking LiIa.
-You've had one reIationship.
-For five years.
You never even Iived together.
I'm teIIing you, CaIvin,
the honeymoon shit, it doesn't Iast.
-I know that.
-Women are different up cIose.
I Iove Susie...
...but she's a weirdo.
Sometimes, she's mean as fuck
for no reason.
She's a person.
You haven't written a person, okay?
-You've written a girI.
-AII right, whatever.
Writers don't show their work
to peopIe at this stage.
I might not even finish it.
Because--
And don't, Iike, teII peopIe about it.
Listen. I'm not saying you can't write.
I'm saying...
...you don't know jack shit
about women.
[CAR ALARM CHIRPS]
Don't Iet those Ieftovers go to waste,
okay, skinny?
Gym tomorrow?
Uh, I'm seeing Cyrus.
-Maybe Friday?
-Friday.
SUSIE: I know.
HARRY: You okay, bud?
SUSIE:
Yes.
CALVIN:
This thing is dripping everywhere.
How are you supposed to eat this thing?
What?
You're so not my type.
What do you mean I'm not your type?
I usuaIIy go for guys
who are a IittIe more, um, assertive.
-I'm assertive.
-Ha, ha. No.
You're stubborn. That's different.
RUBY:
l had this one boyfriend...
...who told me l wasn't funny...
...but that l have a good sense
of humor...
...because l laughed at his jokes.
Why wouId you date a guy Iike that?
I was young.
You must have things you regret.
Not reaIIy.
-Everything's been perfect so far.
-Oh.
So that's what you're Iooking for
in a guy?
Douchiness?
RUBY:
l don't know.
I guess I was Iooking for you.
It just took me a whiIe to find you.
-Ruby.
-Jump!
RUBY: What did you think
the first time you saw me?
CALVIN: l thought you were
the most beautiful girl l ever saw.
RUBY: Were you disappointed
when you got to know me?
CALVIN:
How can you ask that?
RUBY:
l'm such a mess.
CALVIN:
l love your mess.
RUBY:
The first time l saw you, l thought:
''Look at that boy.
l'm going to love him
forever and ever and ever.''
CALVIN: What if you get sick of me?
RUBY: l won't.
l promise.
[PHONE RINGS]
HeIIo. Shit.
[PHONE RINGING]
Shit.
HeIIo. Damn it.
Okay. No.
[LINE RINGS]
CYRUS [OVER PHONE]: Hello.
-Cyrus.
-Where the fuck are you?
-Uh, sorry.
I was writing, I feII asIeep.
I'II be right there.
Look, if you aren't ready to talk about this,
it's fine.
No-- No, no.
I wanna show you what I have.
I think you're gonna be reaIIy excited.
Of course, l'll be excited. Okay, uh,
here's what l'll do. l'll push my lunch.
Okay. AII right. WeII, uh, if I Ieave now,
I shouId be there in 15 minutes.
-All right.
-If there isn't any traffic.
Oh, damn it. Scotty.
-What?
-Uh, nothing. Uh, my dog has to pee.
-I'II, uh, put him in the backyard.
WOMAN: I'II take him out.
-Great. Thank you.
CYRUS: Cal?
Cal?
Hello?
I missed you in bed Iast night.
-Did you get some good writing done?
CYRUS : Are you there?
-Oh, God.
RUBY: Hey, you want a bite?
-It's Crispix.
CYRUS : l think l lost him.
God, it's happening.
It's reaIIy happening this time.
-They're gonna hospitaIize me.
-What's wrong?
They aII thought I was so smart,
but it turns out I was just batshit.
-CaIvin?
-What the fuck?
CaIvin.
It's not reaI. It's not reaI.
It's not reaI.
Okay, you're dreaming.
You're dreaming.
You're dreaming...
...and you're going to wake up...
...right now.
Oh, shit.
-CaIvin? Are you mad at me?
CALVIN: Oh.
Oh, God. It's not reaI.
It's not reaI. It's not reaI. It's not reaI.
Doctor....
[PANTING]
Hi, Dr. RosenthaI. It's CaIvin Weir-FieIds.
Something has come up...
...and I'd appreciate it if you caIIed me
as soon as possibIe. Thank you.
-Ruby?
-Hey.
Um.
I thought you might be hungry,
so I'm making you some eggs.
Mm.
-What's wrong?
-Oh, nothing.
Nothing, uh.
Are these, by any chance, yours?
Yeah, of course, they are.
Who eIse wouId they beIong to?
Oh, my God.
-Are you seeing someone eIse?
-Oh, no.
No, no, no, I'm not....
I'm not seeing anyone other than you.
WiII you excuse me?
[WHISPERS] Remember how Dad used
to say I had an overactive imagination?
HARRY [OVER PHONE]:
Are you saying Ruby is in your house?
I started seeing her this morning.
It's Iike that movie Harvey,
except she's not a giant rabbit.
It's not Iike she knows
she's imaginary, either.
She thinks we're in the reIationship
in my book.
lt is freaking me out.
-I'm in the middIe of a meeting.
-But this is an emergency.
I may be Iosing my mind.
-Just give me one sec. Just....
-Harry. Harry.
There's no possibIe way
that Ruby's in your house...
...because she's not a reaI person.
I know objectiveIy she is not reaI,
but I'm teIIing you...
...l can see her, l can smell her.
When she touched me, I couId feeI it.
She's making eggs in my kitchen.
ActuaI eggs.
That's great.
[WHISPERS] CaIvin, I am at work. I'm
in the middIe of a very important meeting.
I cannot deaI with your shit right now.
Listen to me.
l want you to leave the house...
...see a friend. A friend
who can't see your imaginary friend.
If this is stiII an issue tonight,
we'II taIk, okay?
Okay. I'II phone a friend.
Sorry about that, I was--
Kobe's having a barbecue this weekend.
You got pIans this weekend?
It's CaIvin.
Weir-FieIds. From high schooI.
Yeah, the writer.
I sat next to you in Spanish cIass.
[SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
Uh, actuaIIy, I gotta go.
[TOY SQUEAKS]
Where are you going?
-Out.
-Where?
To the store.
What for?
To get some stuff.
-Can I come?
-No.
-Why not?
-Because.
-PIease?
-No.
PIease?
WOMAN [ON RADIO]:
--point-nine KCRW.
Up next, tickets for KCRWmembers.
lf you haven't won anything from us
in the last 90 days....
I hear they're doing a zombie fiIm festivaI
at the cemetery.
You wanna go? We couId do a shot
every time someone gets bitten.
Okay. Bye.
Bye? Where are you going?
Nowhere.
Café Figaro. I've got this friend.
It won't take Iong.
What am I supposed to do?
Stay here. Enjoy the shops.
I'II be back soon.
When I didn't hear from you right away...
...I figured you had Iost my number
or something.
At Ieast that's what my roommate said
must have happened.
Oh, no, I didn't Iose your number.
Uh, actuaIIy the, uh, night I met you...
...I started writing something,
so my Iife's been reaIIy consuming.
The night you met me?
Am I...?
Never mind. Ha, ha. Never mind.
Um, am I in it?
-I can't reaIIy taIk about it.
-Right, of course.
But if I am, Iike, when it comes out
in stores and stuff...
-...wiII you teII me which character I am?
-You're not in it.
Right, but if I am?
I wiII Iet you know.
Okay. Awesome. Awesome.
[GIGGLES]
So, um, do you do this a Iot?
-Do what?
-Meet up in the middIe of the day for sex.
No. No, that's not--
I just wanted someone to taIk to.
Oh.
Right. Right.
WeII, men neverjust wanna taIk
to women.
-I do.
-If you say so.
Uh, heh, are you even IegaI?
I mean, not to drink, but, yeah.
Of course. Do you, um...?
Do you wanna go somepIace?
RUBY: Hi.
-Sorry, what?
Do you wanna go to my pIace?
-Hi.
-Sorry.
RUBY: I'm sorry.
-What's going on?
RUBY: Am I interrupting?
-I thought I heard something.
-Do you wanna get out of here?
RUBY: CaIvin.
-Do you know this girI?
-Yeah. Hi, I'm Ruby, CaIvin's girIfriend.
I don't think we've met.
Uh, no.
Um, I'm MabeI. I was just going.
-You can see her?
-Yeah, she can see me.
I can see her.
-You can see her.
-Let's not make this worse, aII right?
-Sorry, I didn't know.
-Did Harry put you up to this?
-What, your brother is in on this?
-What?
Ruby, it was very nice meeting you.
CaIvin, have fun writing.
Who the fuck was that?
-Can you see her?
-CaIvin, who was that?
-Can I see her?
-Can he see me? What are you--? Stop.
WAITER:
What's wrong with you, man?
She's reaI.
Oh, no. Ruby!
Ruby! Ruby.
-Get away from me!
-Ruby! Ruby!
-Get away! Get away!
-Ruby!
-Ruby, pIease, Iisten to me.
-Let go!
-Stop!
-Listen to me. CaIm down. Ruby.
-Get away from me!
MAN: Hey, you okay?
You want me to caII the poIice?
RUBY: No. Thank you.
He's just being a compIete asshoIe.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Thank you, I'm fine.
-Ruby.
-You stay away.
God, I shouId have known.
You've been acting Iike such a freak-- Stop!
Let go of me!
Put me down!
Put me down or I'm gonna scream!
-Ruby.
-Stop it!
-Put me down!
-Ruby?
Oh, my God, stop! Ow!
Shh! Stop it. Oh, do not bite.
Do not bite.
Listen to me. Shh, shh.
There is a Iot that is new here,
more than I can teII you.
I'm having troubIe processing it aII,
okay?
Then taIk to me about it.
Don't go on a date with another girI.
I wasn't on a date.
-What is going on with you?
-I don't know. I'm sorry.
Oh, I'm just having troubIe...
...wrapping my head
around the reaIity of this situation.
That you're here.
That you're reaI.
It aII seems pretty incredibIe.
What?
Kiss me, stupid.
HoIy shit.
[ALL SCREAMING]
[PLASTIC BERTRAND'S
''CA PLANE POUR MOI'' PLAYING]
[IN ENGLISH]
Mm.
Look, I know it's a Iot to take in,
but you have to beIieve me.
She's reaI.
I don't know how or why...
...but she's here and she's reaI.
And I Iike it.
-''ReaI'' as in other peopIe can see her.
-That's what I'm trying to teII you.
We've been to restaurants.
We take Scotty for waIks in the park.
-PeopIe taIk to her. She's very friendIy.
-That's impossibIe.
It's apparentIy not.
What does Dr. RosenthaI say?
Are you fucking serious?
PeopIe have shrinks
for when they start seeing things.
I'm not seeing things.
-CaIvin, caII him.
-I can't.
I toId him when she was a character.
He won't understand.
-CaII him or I'm teIIing Mom.
-He'II think I'm crazy.
You might be crazy.
The situation is crazy.
I am not.
[WHISPERS]
Do you hear--? Hi.
Do you hear yourseIf? Do you?
Do you hear yourseIf? ReaIIy?
There's no way that you're sIeeping
with a girI that you made up.
Hey, so, uh, she doesn't know
that I wrote her...
...so don't say anything
about the manuscript, okay?
Yeah, okay.
Hi, Ruby. Great to meet you.
Can we caII the doctor now?
-Harry.
RUBY: CaIvin!
Oof! Hey.
What took you so Iong?
-Hey, Ruby, this is my brother, Harry.
-Hey.
-Harry. Hi.
-Hi.
-Hi. It's great to meet you.
I've heard so much about you
from CaIvin.
You're Ruby.
You're Harry.
The painter from Dayton, Ohio.
-Yep.
Are you staying for supper?
I'm making meat Ioaf.
She's an amazing cook.
Yeah. Can I taIk to you a second?
Outside?
Okay.
What did you do? Hire some actress?
CraigsIist? This isn't funny.
I toId you, she just appeared.
-You're a writer, not Ricky Jay.
-I know that.
-There's gotta be some IogicaI expIanation.
-Love isn't IogicaI.
No, but you know what is?
Physics. Or metaphysics.
-PeopIe don't appear out of thin air.
-She did.
-How?
-I don't know how.
It's Iove. It's magic.
-Okay.
-What are you doing?
-CaIIing your doctor.
-Don't.
-Harry. Harry.
-Give me that.
-We might-- Give me the phone.
-Harry, Iisten to me, pIease.
Remember what you toId me
when you met Susie?
-I certainIy didn't pretend I invented her.
-You said that she was your dream girI.
That's what happened to me.
Harry, don't Iaugh at me.
Has it occurred to you
that she might be an imposter?
Some girI wanted to get cIose to you,
somehow got her hands on what you wrote.
You're the onIy one
who's read my manuscript.
-So unIess you're pIaying some joke--
-Okay, okay, okay.
Let's say you created this person.
Everything you wrote about her came true.
-Even the smaIIest things?
-Yes.
-Have you tried writing more?
-No.
Write something about her.
Why? She's perfect.
Write something about her,
see if it comes true.
If it does, then you're right
and this is a fucking miracIe.
And if nothing happens...
...maybe we go to the poIice.
-Don't caII--
-Just go in there and act normaI. Go up.
-You act normaI.
-I'm not gonna say--
[HOLDEN'S ''UNE FRACTION DE SECONDE''
PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
We're gonna go upstairs
and check on something, uh, onIine.
Were you guys getting stoned out there?
Okay, here's where I Ieft off.
It has to be something
we notice right away, okay?
Something obvious.
-What she's wearing?
-Yes. Yes.
What she's wearing.
What was she wearing?
Was it pink?
I got it.
Okay. Okay.
[WHISPERS]
Write that she speaks fIuent in French.
Yeah, just put it down.
-I'II do it.
-I-- Shh.
[TYPEWRITER DINGS]
[RUBY SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
[LAUGHS]
Bah!
[SPEAKS IN FRENCH]
[HARRY & RUBY LAUGH]
[LAUGHS]
-I'II be right back. I have to do something.
-No, wait, hoId it.
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
CaIvin.
BottIe of vino.
Great. Your brother Iooks Iike
he couId use a drink.
I have to say,
that's the best meat Ioaf I've ever had.
Thank you.
It's a famiIy recipe.
I can't reaIIy take credit.
So your-- Your famiIy's in Ohio?
Yeah. ActuaIIy, my parents died
when I was a baby in an accident...
...and I got moved around a Iot.
I guess the habit stuck.
-I've Iived in nine cities in six years, so--
-Nine?
-Yeah.
-Wow, that's a Iot of cities.
I'm so sorry. I'm totaIIy
monopoIizing this conversation.
No. This is fascinating.
PIease, keep going. PIease.
What nice boys.
Your mom must be so proud.
It's hard to raise a decent guy.
Oh, I think a person wouId have to do
something pretty amazing...
...to produce a good woman.
Okay. Great.
Uh, you guys Iike each other.
I think Harry has to go now.
Right, buddy?
He can be such a controI freak, right?
HARRY: I'II be right back.
RUBY: Good night.
HARRY: See you soon, I hope.
-Hey. So?
-Get in the car.
-What?
-Why? What...?
[CAR ALARM CHIRPING]
HARRY:
That was insane!
-Harry--
-This is insane.
You manifested a woman with your mind.
-Mom's gonna fucking freak.
-Whoa, you can't teII Mom.
-Why not? She Ioves aII this New Age shit.
-SeriousIy...
...you can't teII anybody.
Not Mom, not Susie. No one.
-This is amazing. How can I not teII?
-They'II think she's a freak.
-We're gonna pretend she's your girIfriend?
-She is my girIfriend.
SeriousIy?
-Why not?
-Your girIfriend.
-Stranger things have happened.
-I don't think so.
I think this is pretty much the strangest
thing that's ever happened, ever.
You gonna marry her?
Have kids with her?
-I don't know.
-But wouIdn't that be Iike incest?
-Or mind-cest?
-I don't care.
I Iove her.
PIease, don't ruin this for me.
Promise me, no one.
Fine.
Thank you.
Oh, hey, so you can, Iike, change her.
I guess.
You couId, Iike, tweak things
if you wanted.
Tweak? What do you mean?
I don't know, Iike anything.
Big tits, Iong Iegs--
-I Iike her IittIe Iegs.
-Know how many times I wanted a button...
...to make Susie stop doing
aII the annoying shit she does?
I mean, you couId get bIow jobs
whenever you wanted.
Ruby Ioves giving bIow jobs.
Now, but what about
in a coupIe months or days?
Women are mysterious creatures.
I stiII Iook at Susie Iike:
''Who are you? Who are you?''
I know Ruby, Harry. I wrote her.
So you can make her, Iike, do anything.
For men everywhere...
...teII me you're not gonna Iet that
go to waste.
I wiII never write about her again.
RUBY:
CaIvin?
Hey.
So did he Iike me?
He Ioved you.
Stop, stop, stop.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hey, if it's my mom, pIease, don't--
GERTRUDE [OVER PHONE]:
Hello?
Hello, is anyone there? l don't--
Hi, Mom.
Oh, hi, sweetie. Hi.
l wasn't sure you were there.
What do you want, Mom?
l was wondering if
you're gonna make it up this weekend.
I toId you we can't this weekend.
We're busy.
-Oh, with what?
-[MOUTHS] Busy with what?
Your brother says
you haven't been writing.
-He doesn't know.
-You've been with this girl for months.
l haven't even met her.
l'm beginning to think she doesn't exist.
What? No. I mean, yes.
-So when can l meet her?
-Soon.
Next weekend?
Harry and Susie will be here.
[MOUTHS]
Come on, please?
Look, we have pIans.
I'm gonna caII you Iater, okay?
I'm driving.
Why can't we go to Big Sur?
Uh, weII, we'd have to find someone
to watch Scotty.
We couId take him with us.
I don't know. Mort....
Their house is weird.
You don't want me to meet your mom.
CALVIN:
Of course, I want you to meet my mom.
I'II invite her down for Christmas, okay?
Hey, you know that coffee shop on Dwyer?
The new one?
Yes.
I was thinking maybe
I couId try to get ajob there.
WeII, I toId you,
I'm happy to support you whiIe you paint.
Honey, I'm sort of tired.
Okay.
Let's turn out the Iight, then.
RUBY: It's just, maybe if I wasn't around,
you couId get more writing done.
Weren't you working on something
when we first met?
CaIvin?
What are you doing?
Just packing for Big Sur.
ReaIIy?
Yeah.
[GIGGLES]
[SYLVIE VARTAN'S ''QUAND TU ES LA''
PLAYING]
RUBY:
Wow, Iook at this pIace.
CALVIN:
AII right, this is it.
You asked for it.
RUBY:
You have nothing to worry about.
Look, why don't we stay
somewhere eIse tonight?