Marnier?
I know we agreed
to take some time off.
And I think that was a great idea.
My God.
It gave us both a chance
to experiment, if you will,
and meet all sorts of new
and interesting, different people.
You did quite a bit more
experimenting than I did.
A lot more experimenting.
You are like a scientist!
With beakers and... But, obviously,
I'm cool with that. Like...
'Cause the thing is,
I think we're stronger as a result.
But here's the thing, Marnier,
it's been two years.
And that's a lot of time off.
And I'm ready for some time on.
I miss you.
I miss us.
I got something for you.
What do you think?
Oh, man!
It's depressing.
I mean, it's really depressing.
It's horrible to watch you like this.
I think this is really pretty.
How's it work?
What the hell is that?
I got it for Valentine's Day,
right before she broke up with me.
Look, Steiner, I know
you don't like her very much.
No. No. I hate her. In fact,
the day that you broke up with her,
I marked that down in my calendar
as a day of rejoicement.
I'm goanna celebrate it
with a cake with her face on it.
But instead of eating it, we smash it.
OK? You can do a lot better.
- You deserve a lot better, Kirk.
- Thank you,
but I've seen what's out there
and I don't think it gets any better.
When have you been out there?
When have you left the apartment?
I went out on four different dates.
With three girls and that guy.
I don't know what his
intentions were, but it's fine.
We had a great conversation.
He was just looking' for a friend.
- Know what your problem is?
- What?
- You're a moodle.
- A "moodle"?
A man poodle. Girls,
they want to take you out on a walk.
They want to feed you, they want to
cuddle you. But, make no mistake,
no girl wants to do the moodle.
- No one'd ever fuck a moodle.
- No.
- He's right.
- I'm telling you,
if you want to get Marnier back,
she has got to believe
that from the second
she broke up with you,
your life has been
a non-stop snatch parade.
Or you could just be who you are.
Why can't that be good enough?
Why don't you put your
fucking balls in here, dude?
Yeah!
- "Snatch parade. " Really, Kirk?
- Yeah, it's been pretty awesome.
I've been raw-dogging' some randomise.
Usually careful. Mostly careful, though.
Always using protection.
Double-bagging' it sometimes
just to make sure there's
no seepage because...
...gonorrhoea, herpes and stuff.
I don't want that.
Wow. I am really happy that
you are doing so well with the ladies.
But, truthfully, Marnier.
I really just want to give all that up
and get back together with you.
Kirk? You know I'm with Ron now.
Raw-dogging' some randomise?
Wow, Kirky, sounds like you got
some good stuff going' on.
- Yeah.
- Thanks, Ron.
We're kind of in the middle
of something right now.
Oh, you want to talk? No problem.
- I'll just be in the other room.
- Thanks, buddy.
Ah, sorry. One more thing.
Is there any salsa?
You know what? I'll find it myself.
Good luck there, pirate.
- Are you kidding me, Marnier? That guy?
- That guy is an entrepreneur.
- Well, Ron owns a Pizza Hut.
- That's a business.
It's not even a real Pizza Hut!
It's a Pizza Hut Express!
Working airport security
with your dipshit friends
isn't getting you closer
to being a pilot.
I... I got you something'.
Like, remember that time I made you
the mix tape of all the Kate Bush songs
I thought applied to our relationship?
This is cooler.
Happy Valentine's Day
from two years ago.
Hi, honey. Everything OK?
- Yeah.
- Oh, God, what is that?
I think it's an ashtray?
- No, it's for your earrings.
- Or that.
Kirk, please, don't cause a scene.
Everyone's over.
Jesus, Mom,
a little privacy here, please?
- It's OK, Mrs. Kettner.
- OK.
Kirk. You know that I don't
get along with my own parents,
and you've been really great about
your family practically adopting me
since we broke up.
- I love you.
- Marnier, I love you, too.
Just... OK... Let me finish.
I love you like I love... TV.
- I love you like I love pizza.
- Super fly Snuka!
- No, Dylan!
- You still got it!
- Give it to him!
- What's up, little bro?
- Fuck you!
- Dylan! Leave your brother alone.
- Snap him like a wishbone.
- Sore spot? Just let it happen.
- Yeah! You ain't got shit, you pussy!
- I hate you!
Mom! Kirk said he hated me!
OK, let's move out! Movie night!
I do not want to miss the previews.
- Here. I got the brews. Let's go!
- Coming' with us, pirate?
- No, thanks.
- It's Chris Tucker, dude.
Yeah, I think I'll pass.
Do you see the words
coming' outta my mouth?!
Chris Tucker, right?
Mom! I did the Chris Tucker for him.
- That's nice.
- I'm just goanna leave this here.
He's the black guy from Rush Hour.
- Let's go, go, go!
- OK.
- Mom... Yeah.
- You know, it's engraved on...
Boarding passes and IDs
where I can see them, please!
Let's go!
- Hey.
Boarding passes and IDs where I...
Oh, well, well, well.
Thanks for coming' in, Kettner.
Sorry I'm late, Fuller.
- Yeah? You'd better have a good excuse.
- No.
You want to take a second?
Make something' up?
- Nope.
- Interesting.
Oh, look at this.
Yes, yes.
Yeah, that's so good.
That's great. That's perfect.
Listen, Mr. Friedman,
their quote is lower than ours.
So if fake flowers and cheap champagne
is how you want to woo your clients,
then feel free to blow us out.
I'm sure the event'll be fine.
Thank you, Mr. Friedman. Tomorrow.
Have a nice flight.
Boarding passes and IDs
where I can see... Hi!
- Hi.
- Hay-lo.
Hi-lo. Hello!
New York, huh?
Yeah. The Big... City.
Big Apple.
Big Apple City. I get up there a lot,
'cause I actually, I gig up there.
I play in a band.
- I'm the lead in a band.
- Hey, Steiner.
Did you get the numbers with...
For the new procedures regarding planes?
This is Randy.
- What's up?
- Hi.
- Well, everything checks out.
- Thank you.
- Do you need a hand?
- No.
Smooth. Go put this back in the trash.
- It's a memo.
- Put it back in the trash!
- Boarding passes and IDs, please!
- Next! Oh, ma'am!
- Your shoes.
- Oh, sorry.
OK, let's go ahead and strip off
that belt too, while we're at it, huh?
You have any piercings
you want me to know about?
Anything at all?
All right,
I'm really late for my flight.
Why don't you step on through,
we'll see if you set off the machine.
Thank you.
No, no, no. Not so fast.
I'm goanna have to ask you
to step over to the wending area.
- Fuller, why?
- Well, you never know. I mean...
You just waved the wand
over your tie clip!
- No, I did not.
- Yes, you did.
Well, I am keeping an eye on you.
Wow. They let guys like that work here?
Yep!
Yes, they, they,
they let that guy be my boss.
Thank you for pissing off
your boss for me.
Oh, yeah, please, anytime.
- Molly! Your boarding pass.
- Oh, thanks... Kirk.
Kirk.
Flight six-three to JFK, you're
cleared for taxiing on runway two-nine.
Cabin crew, lock doors and cross-check.
Dude! Cut it a little closer,
why don't you?
I think I lost my iPhone.
I left it in security.
Well, here, calm down. I'll call it.
- Hello?
- Who's this?
I don't know. Might be the guy
with the new iPhone. Who's this?
I don't know. Might be your
worst fucking nightmare, you...
- Patty! Stop it!
- Sorry.
Hello? Thank God you have my phone.
My name is Molly McCleish.
I remember you well. What gate
are you at? I'll run it over.
Know what? We're actually
pushing back right now.
Excuse me. You're not
supposed to be on your phone.
- It's bad for the plane.
- Oh, I'm sorry. Are you a plane doctor?
No? So shut the fuck up.
Tell you what, I'll just leave it at
Lost and Found for you. How 'bout that?
Would you hold on to it for me?
I'm coming back tomorrow.
I'm an event planner. I'm having
this party at the Warhol Museum.
- We could meet there.
- Yes, of course.
I know where that is. It's actually
- on my way home from work.
- Sir?
- She's talking on her phone.
- Dude! Go shit in your hand.
I have to go.
Tonight's the night, Kirky.
No. I...
Devon, tonight is just a night
where I return some lost property
to a fellow human being.
Come on, man, you got to be positive.
It's exciting! I mean,
the night's full of possibilities.
- I can almost smell 'em.
- Oh, man.
- You know what this reminds me of?
- What's that?
The moment when Aladdin
went to meet Princess Jasmine.
What?
You're like a street urchin,
and this is the palace!
OK, so then what does that make you?
I'm the Genie.
Why am I so nervous? This is stupid.
Let's get this over with, OK? Let's go.
Yeah. Let's go on a magic carpet ride.
No, I think it's good.
We have to act positive.
- Wendy!
- Hi! Congratulations, ladies.
- This party is so amazing.
- It is, right?
- Hey. Sorry I'm late.
- Nice, Katie. Real classy.
I had a major laundry disaster. This is
the only dry bra that I have left.
- Do you want me to take it off?
- No!
- Just take a tray and circulate.
- Yeah, circulate. Know what that means?
Hey, excuse me.
I'm looking for Molly McCleish?
- Are you here to arrest her?
- No.
What about you?
You goanna search me?
No. No, I'm, I'm not TSA.
I can get you a mad discount
on a flight, if you want, though.
Molly's my sister. She's... up there.
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
Hey!
- Hey.
- Hey. This is Patty.
Hey.
- Oh, this is my friend, Devon.
- Princess Jasmine.
- Here's your phone.
- Oh, thank God.
You... Thank you.
You saved my life.
Oh, please. It's no big deal at all.
I think we're goanna get going' now.
We're a bit overdressed for this.
- Yeah.
- Oh, no! You guys look great.
You should stay
and have a drink, right?
Know what? Excuse me one second.
Get a drink, but don't get it
from my sister's tray.
What's up, freckles?
...your friend's hot.
What'd she just say?
- "I think your friend is hot. "
- Yeah, right.
Seriously, Kirky,
do not josh me. All right? I need this.
Well, Devon, I would never josh you.
She said, "I think your friend is hot. "
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Yeah!
- Oh, stop.
- No. No.
No, you... Devon,
you're happily married.
You and I both know
you'd never cheat on Karen.
Yeah, you're right. I don't need to.
Know why? 'Cause that girl
thinks I'm hot.
Know what? Don't tell Karen about this.
- No.
- Stuffed mushroom?
- Yeah, sure.
- Yeah.
I dropped 'em on the floor,
but five second rule.
- Good. Thank you.
- It's OK, I'll wait.
Suit yourself.
- What the...?
- Shit.
- What the hell are you doing?
- I am so sorry, sir.
I... I...
- What?
- I don't know.
- Katie!
- No, no, no, not Katie.
This is all my fault.
I'm very, very sorry.
Can I see your invitation?
Probably not the best thing
to say to the museum director.
True, but we should do
cultural events like this more often.
Kirk! Oh, my God.
Patty told me what happened.
What can I say? I'm so sorry.
My reputation in the arts community may
be shot, but I think I'll get over it.
Know what?
I'd like to make it up to you.
- Are you free tomorrow night?
- Yeah, yes. Yes.
We handle some of the Penguins events,
we've got seats for the Islanders game.
- Do you like hockey?
- Do I like hockey? Yes, I do.
Great. There's two tickets.
So, maybe, bring a friend.
Wow, thank you so much.
That's amazing.
- And the tickets will be at will call.
- OK.
- Bye.
- Good night.
Fare thee well, dear princess.
Until our magic carpets alight
from Agrabah to the Cave of Wonders
for a night of romance... and hockey.
- I'm taking Steiner.
- Are you serious?
- No. no. no. that's...
- Yeah.
She's not into me. There are very few
things that I am absolutely certain of.
- This chick does not like me.
- Oh, don't be such a Lay down Larry.
I'm not being a... "Lay down Larry?"
It's just like me saying'
that I'll never go to the moon,
I'm all right with that, too.
You don't want to
go to the moon? Bullshit.
No, I am saying that
I never will go to the moon,
and that's fine
because I never expected to.
You don't know that.
Technology and stuff.
- You might go to the moon.
- He's right.
No. This girl is, like, fucking' hot!
Yeah, but you said that shit
about Marnier and, let's face it,
Marnier was kind of a skank.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Marnier. We were just talking about
Marnier, the name... And how it's
unfortunate that it's not more common.
Fuck you, Steiner.
You didn't let me finish.
More common for skanks.
Hey, Kirk, so are you goanna go to
Branson with your folks next month?
- I don't think so.
- 'Cause they invited
me and Ron to come along,
and we'd love to go,
but not if it's goanna be weird for you.
Tickets are non-refundable, and I love
Branson, but it's totally up to you.
- Yeah, no, you should go. It's fun.
- Thanks. OK.
- OK...
- I... That's...
OK, so she's taking her new boyfriend
to Branson with your parents.
I don't know whether to laugh or cry.
Penguins are facing off
against the Islanders.
What do you think
are the keys to the game?
- I got the first one.
- Thank you very much.
I got a 20. Four beers, please.
Three?
Two?
- He seemed nice.
- That was all of my money.
- Oh, my God. She's here.
- What?
- That chick, from the airport?
- I'll try and call him tomorrow.
Didn't think she was goanna show. Hi!
- Hey. So you got the tickets OK?
- Oh, yeah. Thank you so much.
- Cool. Oh, you remember Patty.
- Hi.
Hi, there. Of course.
I didn't think that you were coming.
- I just... This is amazing.
- Hey.
Steiner.
I'm sorry?
- Steiner.
- What?
- His name is Steiner.
- Right.
- Just a non-descript nickname.
Doesn't mean anything,
you know. It's like Greg.
You look like someone
I went to high school with.
- What high school? Maybe it was me.
- No, he's in a coma.
Who brought the good news bear?
Somebody give her some fucking honey.
OK, should we just
meet you up at the seats?
- Yeah, perfect.
- OK.
- Kirk, that Molly girl's insanely hot.
- Yeah, I know.
- So you know what's happening.
- What's that?
She's setting you up with
the bitchy friend.
Perfect for you,
'cause you like bitches.
Yeah, well, that's fine.
Patty's not a bitch, she's different.
Yeah, different in that she's a bitch
and other people aren't.
- Shoot! Shoot! Shoot!
- Come on!
- Will! Will!
- Pass it, pass it!
Come on, Averill,
play the man, not the puck!
Yeah, come on, dick!
I'm sorry, the player that
I was screaming at is a forward,
but for some reason he keeps
hanging back at the blue line
- with the defensemen.
- You realize they're
hanging back 'cause
they're trying to kill a power play.
That is exactly what's happening.
Damn it, Fox, keep your stick down!
- That felt good.
- Yeah.
She knows a strange amount
about hockey.
- Yeah, man.
- Yeah.
Hey, Mol.
What... Scott Reese knows you?
- A little.
- Little bit.
Come on, Reese, pick it up!
You suck today!
- What a save!
- Oh, my God, he caught that.
- Fuck you, man! Fuck you!
- He's such a freak!
- I'm goanna get some drinks.
- OK.
- I'm goanna get some beers, guys.
- Oh, OK.
I see what's going' on.
Yeah, I'll get some beers with you.
Turn your attention to the centre ice...
- You two stay here. You know, talk.
- I know.
Hi.
...Charlie Slaughter from Brookline.
- Ye olde intermission.
- ... pick a winner!
Listen, while we have a minute here,
Molly's always trying to set me up.
That's why she brought me along, but
honestly I'm not interested, no offense.
No offense taken. I assume that
I am probably not your type.
I was talking about Steiner.
What? What do you think, we're on, like,
a double date or something?
- Well, yeah.
- Yeah, but that'd mean that Molly...
- No.
- Yes.
Kirk, Molly's into you.
Yeah! It's effortless.
Listen, Kirk, I love you,
but there's no way on the planet
that Molly is into you.
Why would she bring a friend
and give you two tickets?
Well, Molly brought Patty for you,
but Patty thought you were a moron.
OK, now I know you've gone crazy.
You're telling me the hottest chick
I've met in my life wants you,
and the Ham burglar wasn't into me?
Listen to yourself. Fuck you.
Fuck...
That's a pretty impressive catch, Kirky.
Right. The day that that happens is
the day that Jack sleeps with your wife.
- What, did that already happen?
- We weren't technically dating yet.
My bad.
Are we goanna talk
or are we goanna bowl?
All I'm saying is,
this girl's too hot.
I mean, no judgment on Kirky,
but the guy's just outgunned here.
- Yo, House Ball!
- "House Ball?"
Yeah, I was up first.
- OK. OK. My bad.
- For fuck sake! Hey!
- What is it with you people?
- Hey, he can just wait his turn.
Oh, really? All this noise and shit,
and my best friend is such a distraction
in your goddamn peripheral vision?
All right, take it easy.
It's all good. Let him do his thing.
Well, fucking' roll then.
- Bring it, Brunswick!
- I'm here. Let's do this, come on.
You feel strong, tough guy?
- Walk!
- You piece of shit!
- Get off!
- All right, come on.
- TSA, motherfucker!
- Don't!
He's lucky.
- He's an asshole.
- I'm really sorry.
OK, anyway... I love Kirky,
but let's face it, the guy's a five.
Steiner, that's just dirty pool.
He's at least a six.
A six? You go ahead and
pump rainbows into his asshole,
- but I'm just being honest.
- Come on, cut him some slack. Look.
Half a point 'cause
he's a nice guy. Right?
And he's funny, so that's half
a point each. That brings him to six.
Devon's right.
But he drives a shitbox, deduct a point.
- Take a point off.
- What's wrong with my Neon?
I don't know. Except the people
that make that car don't even like it.
- So we're back to a five.
- Five.
Meanwhile, this Molly is a hard ten.
And that five point disparity,
that is a chasm.
- Chasm?
- Yeah.
Chasm. You can't jump
more than two points.
Where do you get this shit?
Trust me, Kirk.
I can't even get a ten.
- Oh, not even you, huh?
- I'm a six, OK?
Bullshit, you're a six!
Then what am I?
- You're an eight.
- OK, fine, you're a six then.
But I get a one point bump
'cause I'm in a band.
Steiner, you're in a
Hall and Oates cover band!
- I'm pretty sure that's a deduction.
- Adult Education is a tribute band.
So that puts me back at a seven.
On a good day,
the best I can bag is a nine.
- What about your crappy car?
- Artist's exemption.
I'm expected to have a shitty car.
Is there an artist's exemption
for talking' out your ass?
Yeah. It's called
being' a rock star, Jack.
Look it up in the dictionary.
It's there. Next to "Fuck you!"
Guys, I think this system's ridiculous.
All right? If someone really loves you,
then you are a ten.
My God. What, are...
Are you Hannah Montana?
Because nothing you're saying
right now is of any help to Kirk.
What?!
Hello? Hello! Hey, Molly.
I'm well, thank you. How are you?
First of all, thank you. Yeah,
it was great. It was incredible.
Thank you so much. No...
Kirky, what'd she say?
I think she just asked me out.
Yeah! Way to go, Kirkers!
Hey, did she say anything, you know,
about Wendy thinking' I'm hot?
- Oh, no.
- Shoot. I wonder if she's on Face book.
- Devon, you're on Face book?
- Yeah. I got like 37 friends.
Oh, cool.
Moll, what about this
for your date tonight?
Katie, that's the most
disgusting thing I've ever seen.
Wait. You have a date with Kirk?
When do you want the
bad date bail-out call?
I don't want it.
No, seriously,
work emergency or aunt died?
- I'm not goanna need it.
- Whatever.
What is your problem with Kirk?
I don't have a problem with Kirk.
I have a problem with you dating Kirk.
Why?
You dated Cam and got hurt, so you
pick a guy like Kirk because he's safe.
Yeah. Or maybe because
he's just a nice guy.
He's great. I just...
You and I know he's not the
kind of guy you usually end up with.
Yeah, I know.
Ah, goddamn it.
Way to go. What happened to you?
You look like shit. Besides that.
I got, like, 30 minutes
of sleep last night.
What do I even say to Molly tonight?
Like, what, do I just talk about
her ridiculous hotness for two hours?
I don't know. You were
pretty smooth at the hockey game.
Thanks, man. Well, that's because
I didn't think I stood a chance in hell,
but now that she's asked me out
I don't get it. It boggles my mind.
Why would she ask me out?
- Are you dying?
- What?
You maybe have some
rich benefactor in a top hat
who's trying to
set you up before you die.
Like Great Expectations.
Have you read that book?
- Yeah, man.
- It's so weird!
No, Steiner, I'm not terminally ill.
Thank you for your concern.
- Then that's a brain-teaser, isn't it?
- Tell me about it.
- You know, let's go this way.
- Who is that?
What?
Nobody. Just some chick
that I boned when I was drunk.
She's a total psycho. Let's go this way.
- It's quicker. Come on.
- What?
This place is tremendous.
It's... I'm just trying to think
whether or not I've been here before.
Is this real silver?
This is gorgeous stuff.
It has this lovely terrace area.
It's open. It's kind of like
eating on the Today Show set.
- Are you nervous?
- Yes.
So you speak French?
No, barely. I probably just asked
for directions to the beach.
That's amazing. Any other
hidden talents I should know about?
- I'm a lawyer.
- You're a lawyer?
I know. I, well, I'm not real...
Oh, I'm sorry, one second. I...
Ma'am? Ma'am, you... Yeah...
I'll be right back.
Don't know what they were thinking.
If they moved, changed their number.
Excuse me. Ma'am!
You forgot your sweater.
- Thank you.
- Thanks again.
Oh, no, I don't work there.
- I...
- It isn't...
- I'm just returning your sweater.
- Thank you.
- Sure. Have a good night.
- Sorry.
- Sorry, buddy.
- Thank you.
- Evening.
- What's up?
- Cam?
- Mol! Hey!
- Hey! I...
- I'll see you guys there.
- I thought you were still in New York.
- Negative. I flew in this morning.
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.
- Oh, this is Kirk.
- Hey.
- Oh, hey, buddy. Oh, thank you.
- Yeah...
- Can I help you?
- Yeah, you bet.
I'll take an Armagnac. The lady'll
have a dirty martini with three olives.
- Thanks. Her favourite.
- I think there's been a mistake.
- Sorry, friend?
- He's with me.
Honest mistake.
Sorry. There you go.
- Please.
- That's awkward.
- Cam, this is Kirk.
- It's great to meet you, sir.
Great to meet you, sir.
Cam? Is that short for Cameron?
- No.
- Why would it be?
That's funny.
Your friend is funny, Molly.
- Thank you so much.
- Am I goanna see you next week?
Patty and I are working at the
air show and Cam's our liaison guy.
"Liaison guy. " Ouch!
We were more than that, huh?
You see Molly and I used to date.
Well, I'm out.
It was great to meet you, sir.
- See you, honey.
- All right. Bye.
Bye, Cam! He seems great.
He seems really great.
- Should we order? OK.
- Yeah.
So I was interning at the law firm.
studying for the bar.
but I just kept thinking...
Is this what I really
want to do with my life?
And then I volunteered to plan
the holiday party, and I loved it.
And so I quit the firm,
went into business with Patty.
Well, you found something'
that you love. That's amazing!
Yeah. Yeah, it is amazing.
Anyway, I'm bored of me.
What about you?
Oh, me.
Pittsburgh born and bred.
I wanted to go to college, but my dad
bought a swimming pool instead.
So my boy, Steiner,
hooked me up with my job at TSA
and the rest is rock 'n' roll history.
So TSA today.
Is there a tomorrow or...?
Oh, I don't know.
Some days I'll be at work
and I'll look out the window
and I'll see all those planes
taking' off, going' places, and I think
I could really do that, you know.
And it wouldn't matter if it was
jetliners or cargo planes or whatever.
I just would really love
that feeling of freedom.
Yeah. I know what you mean.
So now you know my big secret.
- You should do that, Kirk.
- Well, thank you.
It was easy for you to say.
You switch jobs at the drop of a hat.
No! No! Not at all!
My parents don't even know
I quit the firm.
- What?
- Yeah, I know.
My dad's an old-fashioned guy.
He's all about security
and steady pay checks.
And I guess we have a problem
with communication, and...
I would like that
not to be the case.
And maybe, maybe, one day it won't be.
Yeah.
- Do you have to get that?
- OK.
- No, you know what? It's fine.
- Really?
Yeah.
This is Molly McCleish.
I'm sorry I missed your call.
- Please leave a message...
- What?!
Never been driven home
by a waiter before.
- No. No, nobody usually is.
- Oh, right.
- I had a really nice time.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Thank you. Me, too.
You're not thinking about Cam, are you?
No. "Cam who?" Is how I feel. No...
I've completely forgotten
how good-looking he is,
and how beautifully moisturized
his skin tones are.
OK. Well...
Oh, my seat belt is screwed up.
Wait, wait.
It goes in the goddamn correct...
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
She kissed you.
She, with her actual mouth, kissed you?
On purpose?
- Yeah, yeah, man, I know.
- I'm so happy for you, Kirky.
I'm not. I'm really nervous.
I mean, it feels like
the universe is outta tilt.
You know? One of us is goanna die.
What's the next step here?
We goanna take this up a notch?
I'm referring to
sexual relations, Devon.
She's coming' to lunch
with my parents on Sunday.
What? Why?
Why would you do that?
You can't do that, dude.
You're jumping six steps!
Well, I... She asked me. I don't know.
What was I supposed to say?
That takes care of that.
I mean, 20 minutes with your family
and she'll file for a restraining order.
- We're safe.
- Hey, did she say anything about Wendy?
You know, like, about me?
OK, move it.
Move it, move it, move it, move it.
- That's what I'm talking' about.
- Mom?
- Oh, hi, sweetie!
- Hi. I'm Kirk's mom.
- Hi. I'm Molly.
- Hi!
- Nice!
- To meet you.
- Yes.
Hi. I'm Molly.
Nice to meet you, too.
- Yeah. Thanks.
- Where's your restroom?
- Right through there.
- Thanks. I'm goanna use the restroom.
- Yeah.
- OK.
- Through there? OK.
- Yeah, through there.
- Oh, we don't flush number ones.
- Sorry?
Nothing! Jesus Christ, Dad! That's...
- What?
- She's a guest.
- Though we'd make one exception?
- We got very delicate plumbing.
- I...
- Honey. She's really cute!
- She's beautiful.
- All that hair!
- Yeah.
- You want to watch the Jap show?
- Nailed it.
- Dylan! I...
I was explicitly told
that you wouldn't be here today.
I thought you were
hanging' drywall or something'.
Leroy fired him again.
Whatever. Like that dick
never came to work with a buzz on.
I brought a girl with me,
so I am begging you,
from the bottom of my heart,
please don't be a jerk,
- and I'll do anything you want.
- Slap Shot Regatta.
How long was I down there for?
What's my time? What's my time?
- Nope. Only 58 seconds.
- Damn it!
- Hey, there, pirate!
- So, Ron, you're here.
- That means that...
- Oh, yeah!
Who wants it? Who wants it?
Who wants it? I'll show it!
- I'll show it!
- Yeah!
Oh, yeah! Stop it, guys.
- Boner Patrol!
- Hey, Kirk.
Hi, there. Everybody, this is Molly.
Molly, this is everybody.
That's my brother, Dylan,
his fiance, Debbie
and my... Marnier and Ron.
Hey, everybody!
This is when you say, "Hi, Molly. "
- Who are you?
- She's Molly.
- Why is she here?
- She came with me.
- You hit her car or something?
- Jesus. No, but thank you for asking.
- You his social worker?
- Nope.
- Shit, are we being evicted?
- No.
- You a hooker?
- Dylan!
- Or a prostitute, I mean?
- Oh, my God.
Kirk and I were having dinner
and he said he was
getting together with his family.
It's been a while since I had
a family dinner,
so I hope you don't mind.
- I just invited myself along.
- Well, come on in for a dip, girl!
- Yeah!
- Ron!
- I don't have a bathing suit.
- Wear your underwear.
- Yeah.
- Like a bikini. Covers the good shit.
- Yeah, underwear is fine.
- Ron!
It's like what they did in the old days.
Underwear would be fine...
...if I were wearing any.
- Lunch is ready!
- I'm coming'!
Jeez.
- My mom makes awesome meatloaf.
- Oh, cool.
- After you.
- Sure you want another one, Dad?
What are you, my sponsor? Hit me!
Ron, honey, I never
complimented you on your...
...on your sweater vest. It's something!
Here you go.
Dylan, I think if you
just apologized to Leroy,
- he'll take you back.
- No, screw him.
- Got a foolproof money maker on the way.
- You're goanna want to pay attention.
I know how to make any car
into a convertible in 15 minutes, so...
- Wow.
- Yeah. You know why?
- No.
- Two words: Global warming.
Actually, Dylan, according
to The Day After Tomorrow.
the film, the Earth
actually gets colder.
Yep.
What's, what's up... with you?
Are you...? These days?
- What?
- Want me to help you with the gar...?
Fuck it. You seriously
not wearing any underwear?
- Dylan!
- We're all thinking' it.
If you want to plan an exit strategy
or leave right now, I won't be offended.
- No, I'm not going anywhere.
- What do you do?
- I'm an event planner.
- See?
That's a business to get into.
That's using' your head.
- Thank you, Dylan.
- No, wait for it.
Book a band, blow up balloons, people
pay out the ass for that, don't they?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, they do.
I'm not wearing any underwear.
Hey, Molly. Molly. Check it out.
So Deb and I are getting' hitched.
How much cash
do you pocket for a wedding?
Any of this striking you
as inappropriate?
We're making conversation.
Don't get your panties in a wad.
- Jesus.
- No, it's fine.
A lot of factors affect the cost.
Check it out. We got
about 100 peeps coming.
We're doing' a NASCAR theme in Vegas.
I'm goanna get this kick-ass dress
made outta actual chickened flags,
like real tight, then Dylan's
goanna be in a wicked orange tux
with a Home Depot logo on the back.
What's up, right? Right?
You've never seen anything like that?
- Should be extensive.
- What's the damage on that?
My base fee is 15,000. So 100 people...
I mean, I'd ballpark that
somewhere around 50 grand.
- Fuck you!
- Fuck you.
- What?!
- Fuck you!
- Fuck you.
- Fuck!
That's a lot of
15 minute convertibles, Dylan?
Wait, so you make a
pretty comfortable living?
Sometimes.
You got your head on right.
And you don't do underwear.
What the hell are you
doing' with numb nuts?
- Dylan!
- Honey, what?
- No, hey, whoa, fair question.
- That's a fair question?
- Molly, I am so sorry.
- It's fine. You know, I mean...
Well, I don't...
I don't really know.
No, he makes me laugh.
He doesn't try and impress me.
And I can just be me around him.
- Oh, that's sweet.
- She's a keeper.
Kirk makes you laugh?
You a comedian? I didn't know.
Tell us a joke there, Sinbad.
I totally understand
what you're talking about.
The curse of being
an attractive woman.
I mean, men are always
putting us on a pedestal,
expecting us to be
something that we're not.
- "Us?"
- Come on, Marnier, get real.
- What?
- OK. You know, Molly,
we are taking a big family trip
out to Branson on the 31st,
- and I think you two should come.
- I think you're wrong.
- Got to come to Branson.
- I don't think that's a good idea.
- You should come!
- We don't have room.
- They've got shows.
- Kenny Rogers' got his own theatre.
We'll get a ticket.
I'll get you a ticket.
- Branson's small.
- Branson's a big place!
- Shut up, Ron.
- Can we go?
- It's your call.
- OK. Well, I'll see what I can do.
- Hey, hot dog!
- Result!
All right, relax.
Molly, I think there's
something you should know.
Kirk and I used to be lovers.
If you stay with him long enough
he'll give you one of these.
- They're great.
- Thank you, Dylan.
That's mine. It's for my earrings.
Kirk, you look really good.
Thank you. You look really...
Thank you so much.
- It was fantastic meeting you!
- Oh, you, too.
You're so special and God, I just...
- Branson, think about it.
- OK.
OK?
- She's really great. Later, pirate.
- Yeah. Bye, pirate.
- Let me help you, Mrs. Kettner.
- Maybe you could wrap those potatoes.
Come on. You're a guest here.
You really don't have to do that.
Oh, I don't mind.
Ready? You and me, downstairs,
Slap Shot Regatta.
Man, we're not children anymore.
Do we really have to do this?
- Mom!
- Kirk, go play with your brother.
- We need some girl time.
- Yeah, you promised.
- So pad up, chickenshit!
- Yeah, I'll see you down there.
Aw, crap.
Come on. Let's do this!
- Let's focus it up.
- Left side.
- That was lucky.
- He never saw it, but he stopped it.
Come on, Dylan, give it to him.
You think you're Mr. Hot Shit now
with your new chick?
What? No. Maybe I'm just
a bit lucky tonight. I...
- What are you?
- You're not better than me.
Take a look. All these trophies
say Dylan Kettner.
- First place. First place. MVP.
- I don't think I'm better than you.
I never said that. And maybe Molly's
a little better looking than I am.
A little? Are you shitting me?
OK, I think we can all agree
that Debbie here is one wicked hot box.
Thanks, babe.
This chick of yours
makes her look like a pig.
- What? You're an asshole! What?!
- See?
This girlfriend of yours
is already starting' shit!
Did you see that, Mom?!
One second! Butterfly!
- I want to have another baby!
- No, that's OK, sweetheart.
OK, boys, it's a tie.
There are no ties in hockey,
as there are no ties in life.
- True.
- Last shot. Winner takes all. Go!
OK, come on, you can do it.
He's got nothing.
He's got less than nothing.
Own it. You can do it.
Come on, Dylan! Get in the zone!
You're still my MVP, baby!
Kirk's just a skinny little loser!
- Jesus, Debbie.
- Man, I got to sit down.
You want to do this? Let's do it.
- Damn it!
- There's always a next time.
- Fuck it!
- Dylan.
This floor's all slippery!
And these shoes are fucked for this!
- Dylan, hey! Sportsmanship.
- Fuck you!
- Time out.
- You guys take a time out
from being' assholes!
Oh, God.
- I'll get us some wine.
- Yeah, cool.
- This place is gorgeous!
- Thank you.
This kind of reminds me of my place,
except for my place is a total shithole.
This is awesome.
How long have you lived...
- My God! What the fuck is that?!
- Oh, that's Captain Pickles.
I'm watching him
while my folks are on vacation.
What is he?
A dog or a fucking' horse?
Sit down.
Wha... Me or the dog?
You. He doesn't like people standing.
He feels threatened by it.
He gets all, you know, angst.
Hey, angst, that's...
No, hey, I come in peace.
Thank you.
OK, wait.
I don't want to move too fast.
I... No, sure, no problem. No problem.
No, don't get me wrong.
I mean, once I trust a person
I can experiment
and get pretty generous.
Yeah, yeah, no, me, too. Me, too.
I... I'm...
I love, love, to experiment,
and I get really generous.
I can be very, very generous.
I am quite the charitable lover.
I got... Can we stop for two secs?
No.
- Honey, you there?
- Dad?
"Dad?!" What the...? Oh, dear God!
Are you in?
- Hey!
- Hi...
- Hey.
- Hey, baby.
- Shit.
- Told you we should call ahead.
We decided to come back early.
Thought we'd come by,
take the Captain off your hands.
Hope we aren't interrupting.
- Who's your little friend?
- Oh, God!
- Well, this is Kirk.
- Gerald McCleish. It's a pleasure.
Yeah.
- Nope. Nope.
- No?
I don't... God, where are my manners?
You guys must be exhausted from
your travels. Please, hey, have a seat.
Put your... Put your feet up.
Really get into a groove.
- Thank you.
- Sure.
- That's kind of you.
- I think I have that same sweater.
Really?
So... that's...
Uh, no. Oh, Lord.
Oh, no, Captain Pickles.
No. No, Captain.
Pickles!
- Kirk?
- Excuse me.
Thank you for having me.
This has been a lovely evening.
Good night.
Awesome.
Devon, I'll give you 50 dollars
just to curse once.
- Seventy-five. Just say "fuck. "
- I won't, I won't say it out loud.
- I'll write it.
- That doesn't count!
- You're goanna what?
- I'll write it down.
That doesn't count!
You have to say it out loud.
- Why doesn't it count?
- Say "shit. " I'll give you 100.
- Hey.
- Hey, Kirk.
My shift doesn't start
for another half hour,
but I was so excited, so I came early.
Yeah, and it was weird. He said he was
really excited and so he came early.
Yeah. That ever happened to you?
You're so excited about something
that you come early.
Jesus Christ, you're Fort Knox
over here. Thank you very much.
I didn't mean to tell 'em, Kirky.
I'm sorry.
Come on, he couldn't help it.
It just, you know, slipped out.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Thank you.
Thank you very much.
And go fuck yourselves.
- Hey, guys.
- Oh, shit.
Kirk, can I talk to you for a second?
- In private.
- There are no secrets here, Marnier.
OK. Well,
I think I made a little mistake,
and I see a change in you,
and I really like it,
so let's get back together!
Just to try it out. You know?
That's really interesting.
No, I don't think so.
But you broke up with Molly.
- She cornered me.
- Jesus, Devon!
Look, Marnier, I moved on
like you kept telling me to.
You're here because some
other girl has shown interest.
That's not it! Look, Kirk,
I am really worried about you with her.
She seems like kind of a bitch.
So I'm just saying that
if you want to get back together,
- like you begged me before...
- Shh...
...I am even willing to consider
breaking up with Ron.
- What? You're still with Ron.
- The pirate?
Yeah. I'm not goanna risk
being all alone just 'cause
Kirk doesn't know what's good for him.
Look, Kirky. Deep down you know it is
never goanna work out with you and Molly.
And I just can't stand
to see you get hurt.
So if that makes me
the bad guy... so be it.
It's embarrassing.
Jesus Christ.
Hey.
Did you just come in your pants again?
You can tell us.
We're your friends. Did you?
Hey, why would you tell her
I broke up with Molly?
'Cause I thought you had.
- No. We're just in a sticky wicket.
- A "sticky wicket?"
Yeah, a rough patch. Rough pumpkins.
- How many times have you called her?
- Five.
How many times have you
really called her?
- Seventeen.
- It's done, man. Tao of Love.
- What?
- That's what I call it.
The Tao of Love. You being with Molly
defies, like, forces of nature.
- It's over, man.
- No. It's not over.
Frankly, I'm kind of sick
of you guys pretending
like you know where I'm coming' from.
None of you know what I'm going' through.
- Tina Jordan does.
- Who the hell is Tina Jordan?
- She was my Molly.
- You never mentioned her.
I didn't want to jinx it.
But she was perfect.
Yeah, perfect.
Freckled shoulders.
Anyway, two months into it,
bam, she dumps me.
I should a seen it coming, too,
'cause she was a ten. Like a hard ten.
And I was a six, possibly a seven.
Either way, I couldn't cover the spread.
The universe spoke.
And I was depressed for months.
That's what that was?
You said you had mono.
- Yeah. Mono of the heart.
- Oh, my God. How's your vagina?
Shut up, Jack!
Dude, forget Steiner. All right?
I think you could get her back.
Why don't you look Kirk in the eyes
and tell him you believe
he's goanna end up with Molly.
- Just tell him that.
- Fine.
Kirky, I truly believe that...
I mean, I think anything's possible.
- "Anything is possible?!"
- Come on!
Like, there's a million
examples of guys like Kirky
- ending' up with beautiful women.
- Such as?
- Lyle Lovett and Julia Roberts.
- Right.
Richie Sambora and Heather Locklear.
Then he went on to Denise Richards.
Yeah. All recording artists.
Normal rules don't apply to those guys.
Kirk, as soon as you
record an album and it goes platinum,
you can push your meat into
any human being you want.
OK, OK. OK.
King Kong and Naomi Watts.
Never consummated.
Totally platonic relationship.
- Stephen Hawking and his lady nurse.
- He's the master of space and time!
- He knows about black holes and shit.
- What about the President of France
and that girl that
went out with Mick Jagger?
He knows about wine.
And has a French accent.
Can probably French kiss
like a motherfucker!
- Oh, OK, OK...
- Wait a second. The Beast.
- Who?
- The Beast! From Beauty and the Beast?
Beast won Beauty's love, and he wasn't
rich and he wasn't a recording artist.
- Though he did have an amazing voice.
- OK, Devon, that's a cartoon.
But, yes, that's one.
One out of a million.
You know what, Steiner?
All it takes is one.
Man, you... You guys just sit here
and talk about relationships,
but the truth is,
I'm the only one here that's married.
I'm tired of you guys busting' my nuggets
'cause I've only been with one girl.
It's 'cause she was the right girl!
That's why I married her!
So, Kirky, let me tell you something'.
If Molly's the right girl,
that's all that matters.
You just you stand up.
You stand up, you get in front of her.
You get right in her grill and you say,
"Hey, I am Kirk Kettner
and I am right here,
standing' in front of you...
...right here. Here I am. "
- Something' like that.
- The power of love.
- Beautiful.
- Moving.
Very... Perfect.
Thank you.
I was in debate, junior/senior year.
I don't know if you guys remember that.
Look at that.
Oh, there she is.
Listen to me, dude. Got to go,
loud and proud, got to tell her,
- "Hey, I jazzed in my shorts" you know?
- All right...
No! "That's what I do. OK?
It's how I roll. Deal with it. "
You know, I know I don't know...
I don't know much about this, but
that can't be good advice, I'm sorry.
- Yeah, I'm not goanna do that.
- You have nothing to be embarrassed of.
If anything, you paid her
a compliment. Right?
- Yeah.
- Trust it.
Here goes nothing'.
Oh, shit, Molly. Six o'clock.
- Hey, Molly.
- Hey.
- Did you get my messages?
- Yeah, yeah, I got them, Kirk.
What the hell happened the other night?
You act like a freak
with Captain Pickles,
you won't get off the couch
to shake my father's hand
when we had a whole conversation
about how he was old-fashioned!
Yeah, I know. I know. I'm sorry.
I spent a whole day
with your entire family,
and you can't even spend
30 seconds with mine.
- I mean, that's a pretty big red flag.
- It is not a red flag, Molly.
Oh, Kirk, I can't do this here.
- I'm working, and...
- OK. Sorry.
I ejaculated in my pants.
We were getting sort of
hot and nasty, you know...
It's not every day
that I have a super-hot girl
grinding on top of me,
and I got a little too excited and,
before I know it, your parents
are in the room and I'm there
with just a big fringing'
oyster in my shorts.
Right. Sorry. Sorry.
I mean, I'll say this for him.
He's honest.
So thanks for the advice.
That went horribly.
Enjoy the air show, boys.
I'm going to go...
No guy in his right mind
would ever make that up.
Right?
You should probably go talk to him.
- Yeah.
- Just wait one second.
And... here she comes.
- Kirk!
- Yes!
Yeah.
She told him a joke or something'.
Something's funny.
They're ki... They're goanna ki...
They're kissing! Yes!
- You're like Yoda.
- Yeah, I know.
Like Sex Yoda.
"The Force is strong with you, Jack. "
Trust the system.
It takes care of itself.
- Ah, that went well.
- Kind of.
Wow. She sure is something', isn't she?
- It's Kirk, right?
- Oh, God. Hi, Cam.
Excellent to see you again, sir.
Listen, Kirk.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Yeah, I guess so. See ya.
Listen, Kirk. I understand
that fellas, such as yourself,
have uniquely candid relationships
with the women that they befriend,
- am I right?
- Fellas such as myself?
Don't get me wrong.
I have no problem with your lifestyle.
What two or more grown men do
in the privacy of their own home,
hell, it's of no concern to me.
I don't know what Molly's
told you about me, all right?
If she said anything bad,
let's face it, I probably deserve it.
- Actually, Cam, we haven't...
- God as my witness, I'll get her back.
Cool.
Can I count on you to put in
a good word for me, Elton John?
- Yeah, whatever gets this over with.
- You're the man, Kirk. Bring it in.
- Yeah, yeah, you got it.
- You feel that tolerance?
- Man, you gays smell good.
- That's good.
This is awesome!
Does anybody have a camera?
- Steiner.
- What?
Wait a minute, dude.
Does that, does that say...?
Yep, I think it does.
- Jesus, man. Goddamn it.
- Did you guys get a picture?
By the way, Kirk,
you can do better than these guys.
I mean, this one is kind of cute,
but the other two... Oof!
Show some pride, pal.
Pittsburgh tower. Foot Long, you are
cleared for takeoff on runway two-zero.
Roger that, tower. Turn and burn.
Honestly, I'd have sex with that guy.
Yeah, I would.
- Fuck! You're lucky!
- Yeah!
So how's your sister doing'?
She turns 21 next week
and she's, I don't know,
she still has no sense of direction.
You know? She's coming over for dinner,
and I really want to give her advice,
but I don't know
what to say to her, you know?
So what do you...
You don't know what to say to her?
She's only 20. She's not 30.
And she's not you.
You know? When I was 20,
I did not have my act together, man.
I mean, look at this kid now.
I'm in TSA. I am living' the dream.
You're right.
Maybe I am being too hard on her.
And, I'm sorry, but she's
coming' over for dinner?
She's turning 21!
You got to throw her a party.
I mean, that's what you do for
a living, right? You throw parties?
I can't believe I never thought of that.
- That's a really good idea.
- Thanks.
It's been ten dates and you can't
seal the deal? What's wrong with you?
Listen to me. Things with Molly
are good, right? They're back on track.
You have got to recover from your little
oopsie-daisy, little early-bird special.
Got to get back in that ring.
It's just terrifying, frankly,
the idea of me naked
- in front of her... also naked.
- But what's to be terrified of?
Because you've done
your prep work, right?
Yeah... I think she likes me.
- She really likes you.
- Thank you.
That's cute. Yeah, good. But it's
not at all what I'm talking about.
A girl like Molly, hot as shit,
manicured from fucking' head to toe.
- Yeah.
- Right?
- What the hell are you talking about?
- Listen, I'm talking' about this.
- I'm talking' about this.
- Your chin.
- Yeah.
- And I'm talking' about this.
- Oh, jeez!
- No, no, no, no, no, no.
- Look, guys!
- Jack!
This is fine.
'Cause this is clean. It's organized.
It's kind of
Japanese-looking, to be honest.
Whatever you do,
don't look directly at it.
I'll bet you Cam's balls
look like this. It's like a baby.
It's just smooth. It's a look that says,
"Hey, you can put your mouth here. "
- He is... He just moved.
- It's just a thought.
Just trying' to help, that's all.
All right, Steiner,
let's get outta here.
- Yeah, I'm hungry. I got to go eat.
- Hey, Kirky. Prep work.
You hear me? Out.
God.
OK.
Here goes nothing'.
Shoot! Kirky! Kirky!
We should a done a hot towel.
You know, like those
old-timey barbershops?
- Helps raise the hairs.
- I don't like this!
Kirk, if you want to abort the mission,
that's completely cool.
I don't... I can't really
abort the mission right now.
I've shaved approximately
one-third of my balls.
I'll look pretty fucking' stupid
if I stop now!
Did you shave one ball
and then the other ball,
- or are you working' top to bottom?
- Shut up, shut up!
You shut up. I mean, seriously,
just shave it like your face!
I can't do it like my face!
My face doesn't have
two testicles sticking out of it!
If it did, I would grow
a pretty thick goddamn beard.
Kirk.
Kirk?
- Do you need a hand?
- Oh, mother...!
There we go.
So how is this not gay?
I think there's nothing gay about it.
The fact that you're letting' a straight
married man shave your testicles...
I think that makes you
one of the most macho guys alive.
There is some logic in that.
Thank you. You know what?
Can you pick that up?
Can you pick 'em up for me?
There it is.
That's a lot. OK, drop 'em.
Viola!
Take a look!
What do you think?
Devon!
It looks fucking huge!
My friends wonder why
I call you all the time
What can I say?
Yeah, yeah
Well, I don't feel the need
to give such secrets away
Well, you think maybe I need help
Though I know I'm right, all right
I'm just better off
Not listening to friends advice
When they insist on knowing my bliss
I tell them this
When they want to know
what the reason is
I only smile when I lie
Then I tell them why
Because your kiss
Your kiss is on my list
Your kiss I can't resist
Because your kiss is on my list
Of the best things in life
Because your kiss
All right, everybody, give it up
one more time for Adult Education!
Awesome stuff. They're going to
play some more Hall and Oates for us,
and maybe some other old favourites
from some other artists? No?
- You're kidding me.
- Nope. Just... more Hall and Oates.
Everybody, let's raise a glass
to Patty and Molly for throwing, by far,
the coolest party I've ever
personally been invited to.
Great job, girls.
Let's hear it for Patty and Molly!
And now, to the gorgeous
birthday girl, Katie McCleish.
You're 21 years old now.
What else can I say?
Let life come to you.
- Happy birthday, Katie!
- Thank you.
All right, guys, enjoy the party.
- Can you hold this for me?
- Why?
Better with my jacket off.
Just ditch that somewhere.
What? What am I
supposed to do with this?
OK, now we're goanna
take it down. A lot.
You're totally goanna
jump his bones tonight, aren't you?
I don't know. Maybe.
- Hey.
I think it's time for you
to dance with me.
Hey, Devon! Wendy, remember?
No. No, I don't. I... Aw, shoot.
I think this is the first time
we're meeting. Ever!
- OK.
- This is my wife, Karen.
- I'm Karen.
- Wendy.
Nice to meet you.
- That's good. OK, I'm goanna...
- OK.
What?
- Oh, there's my parents!
- What?
Hey! Hey, let's go meet them.
She's with that fucking' asshole.
- Hi!
- Hey, baby...
- Dad, hi.
- You remember Kirk.
- Yeah, how could we forget? Yeah.
- Oh, this time we...?
- Hi, there.
Mr. and Mrs. McCleish, from the
bottom of my heart, I am so sorry.
The last time we met wasn't exactly
the world's greatest first impression.
- No, it certainly was not.
- I promise you that I will grow on you.
- I hear this party was all your idea.
- No, no. This is all Molly's.
Hey, what line of work are you in, son?
It's kind of a long story.
I grew up with my...
- Kirk's in aviation.
- Another pilot?
- Really?
- Oh, Molly likes the flyboys.
Just like your mother.
I flew choppers back in Nam, Saigon.
Evacuation, April, '75, that was...
He's been pushing Molly
to take flying lessons.
- After she passes the bar.
- Yeah. Flying!
Hey, now here's a pilot! How are ya?!
- You son of a bitch!
- Boy, good to see you!
Good to see you.
Lucille, don't you look lovely.
- Hello, Cam.
- What?
- Kirky!
- I didn't think you were goanna be here.
You bet. You know,
Ger and Lucille invited me.
- What a pleasant surprise!
- Target acquired.
- Cam... How's it going?
- Mol.
Have you seen Katie?
Let's go see Katie.
- OK. I'm... See you down there.
- Good to see you again, kid.
Nice to see you... sir.
I'll see you down there.
Mind if I join you?
So Molly just explained
all about you two,
and I got to admit I feel like a jackass.
Don't worry about it, man...
It's all good.
I thought you were gay, too.
- Just joking. I'm just joking.
- You are funny.
- Thank you.
- All right, then...
Take good care of her.
She's a special girl.
- Yeah, she's perfect.
- Oh, yeah, about that...
Don't really call her that.
She doesn't like it.
And, besides, she's not
exactly perfect anyway, right?
What do you mean?
All right, listen.
Don't let it creep you out, OK?
I mean, the first time
I saw her little defect...
Woof! I'll admit it gave me the willies.
But it might not bother you. Who knows?
All right? And even if it does,
just try to be cool, you know,
and you'll get used to it,
all right? Good luck.
No, no, no, no,
wait, wait, wait, wait.
Please, this is...
This is very important.
- Birth defect? What is it?
- I can't tell you that, man.
Something' you're goanna
have to figure out for yourself.
I'm out.
Interesting.
- OK, your turn.
- Yeah.
Oh, shit.
I haven't really been hitting'
the gym as much as I should lately.
It's OK.
Holy Moses.
- Interesting.
- What, what? What?
Nothing. Nothing.
What's wrong?
It's been a while and
I'm not very experienced sex-wise.
- Kirk, please. Your balls are shaved.
- Oh, I know. I know.
It's kind of a new thing I'm trying out.
It's a bad idea. It's...
I feel like I'm eleven.
What if I show you something
I'm self-conscious about?
- Oh, that would be amazing.
- OK.
- Promise me you won't laugh.
- No, I, I... I promise.
OK.
What am I looking at?
That's it?
- That's your big defect?
- Webbed toes is not a defect!
Yeah, no shit
webbed toes is not a defect!
I was expecting some kind of
pulsating growth
or a cluster of lumps...
...or like a little dick that,
I don't know, talked.
This is what... All you got is it's
inconvenient for you to wear flip-flops?
Who told you I have a defect? Cam?
Well, yeah.
And as far as I can tell that's the
only thing separating you from perfect.
You think I'm too perfect?
So you were hoping there was something
wrong with me so you could be with me.
Look at the evidence, Molly.
It's...
I'm unattractive,
I'm out of shape, I'm uncoordinated,
I've never been to Europe, I'm not
a college graduate, I drive a Neon...
- I like your Neon.
- Oh, God, come on, Molly, look at me.
I'm a five. This is a five. Hard five.
You can't jump more than two points.
It's the Tao of Love.
Everybody knows that.
Even if you were a nine,
and I was in a band,
- but no, you're a hard ten.
- What are you talking about?
Do you even know how hot you are?
No, you probably think that everybody
gets free shit everywhere they go,
and everybody's happy and nice to
each other in shiny, happy Hot Town,
with you and all your hot friends
and ex-boyfriends,
but I hate to break it to you,
it's not the same for the rest of us.
OK, Kirk. You clearly have some
major self-esteem issues.
You lied about me to your parents
right in front of me!
- No, I didn't!
- "Kirk's in aviation?"
That's like saying the guy who
shovels elephant shit at the circus
is in show business.
No, he's just the elephant shit guy.
That's me. I'm that guy.
I'm never goanna be a pilot.
And I am happy with that.
And I'm fine with that, too.
And I was fine with you
up until about three minutes ago.
That's... I'm so glad
that you were "fine" with me.
You know what? Maybe you're right.
Maybe you are a five.
You know why?
No self-esteem, deduct a point.
Every time someone walks into a room
you compare yourself to them,
deduct a point.
You're a smart and talented guy
who's afraid to do anything with it,
deduct a point. How are we doing?
Oh, yeah.
Hoping that I have a defect
that you can work with?
Deduct whatever's left.
I'm outta here. Webbed fucking feet.
Are you kidding me?
- Kirk!
- Hey, do me a favour.
- Tell Foot Long I said hi.
- He's my ex-boyfriend, Kirk. Ex!
- Know why we broke up?
- Because you guys couldn't decide
- which one of you was hotter?
- No. Because he behaved
exactly like you're behaving right now.
He couldn't handle it.
He thought I was perfect,
he had me on a pedestal
that I couldn't possibly live up to!
Oh, and one other little thing?
He cheated on me.
After that I said to myself, "I'm
not goanna date guys like that anymore. "
Wait... "Guys like that?"
So, what, you're just...
- You were goanna date guys like me?
- That what you want to hear?
That I asked you out 'cause you're safe?
Keep going'.
That I thought that a guy
who looks like you wouldn't hurt me?
Is that what you want to hear, Kirk?
Are you happy now?
Yeah, I'm ecstatic.
Kirk!
Fuck.
Six-Delta-Bravo,
flight cleared to land. runway two-two.
- "List. " It's "list. "
- No, it's not. It's "lips. "
- It's "list. "
- "Your kiss is on my lips. "
Why'd it be "list?"
"It's on my list
of the best things in life. "
- Steiner.
- What?
- Hey.
- Oh, hey, Kirk.
Where have you been?
Here. Tune it.
Oh, shit.
So you're all "Branson bound," huh?
Yeah. They were Marines idea.
OK, Kirky, let's go.
- OK, I'll see you guys later.
- Relax.
The Branson flight's
not for another 45 minutes.
I could just meet you down at the gate.
- OK.
- Everybody together? Got everything?
- Yeah, let's go.
- I'm coming'.
Wow, so you're really back with Marnier.
Hey, fellas.
Hand it over, dumb-ass. No liquids
over three-point-four ounces.
Good call. Hey, pirate,
can you spot me a 20?
I want to get one of those
scented neck pillows.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, of course.
- Here you go.
- Thanks, bro.
Yeah, you got it.
Are you kidding me?
This might seem crazy,
but he and I actually have
- a lot in common, so... Oh, fuck!
- Sorry.
You don't have anything in common
with those people.
Look at me. You OK?
Do you think I really
want to be Branson bound?
I don't.
The whole time you told me
I wasn't good enough, you were right.
So this is my life. I got to go.
Marines waiting for me.
- See ya, guys.
- Yeah.
- See you later, Kirky.
- See you.
What?
Goddamn it. Tina Jordan.
Here.
That's a large Coke,
a fry and some ketchup...
- Mary J. Blige!
- Hey, Wendell.
I need to know, right now,
why it didn't work out with us.
- I have customers.
- This is important, OK?
This is important. I was good to you,
right? I mean, I was sensitive.
Remember when you got the flu?
I didn't party that weekend.
Remember?
Remember the leg massages?
Remember when I used to run
my hand down your back? Like that?
Remember when I nursed
that baby bird to health?
Little Timothy? He died.
Christ on a corndog.
Tammy, can you cover for me?
- Yeah, sure.
- Thanks, Tammy.
Whatever, Wendell. Can I help
the next person in line, please?
I really liked you,
but all that stuff about
I'm a ten and you're only a six?
- Seven.
- Fine.
But you were all up in my beeswax
checking to see if I was goanna dump you.
But you did dump me! Why don't you just
admit I was never good enough for you?
Wendell, you were
plenty good enough for me.
You were just
never good enough for you.
Oh, shit.
I'm goanna need some
gravy fries when I get back.
Would you put your seat forward, please?
- Tom fucking' Wopat, bro. Told you.
- Tray table.
- Kirky, look at David Archuleta.
- Can I help you?
TSA. Excuse me.
- You have no authority.
- You better believe I do.
All right, everybody, listen up! TSA!
I apologize. This guy's drunk as fuck.
He shit his pants.
It's very embarrassing.
We have to get him off.
I'll have to have you come with me.
- Jesus Christ. What are you doing'?
- I was wrong about you and Molly.
We got to fix it. Just act drunk.
Thank you. TSA. Come on.
Believe it or not,
this has nothing' to do with you.
- Sir!
- It's not about me.
I'm goanna have to ask you
to exit the aircraft.
to exit my personal space.
- Steiner!
- Fuck off! Sorry, that's yours.
You're goanna get arrested by
the Department of Homeland Security.
They're goanna send you
to Guantanamo Bay.
Yeah. I like Cuba. I like mojitos.
You don't want to go
to Branson with A-holes!
- He call us A-holes?
- Look at them. That one's pregnant.
- That guy's got hair in the front.
- Dude...
Sweetheart, remember the baby.
- I'm doing' this for the baby.
- Don't be a hero!
- How's this work? Seat belt person!
- Stop. We have a...
They are my family.
And I'm with Marnier now.
Marnier is an evil bitch.
All due respect.
Kirk! Hit him!
- At least say something.
- Let's go.
OK. I was right about Molly.
She's a ten, OK? A hard ten.
- My God.
- I was wrong about you. You're a ten.
- You can't settle for a three.
- Two.
- Arguably a two.
- Come on, let's go.
You're the best guy I know. I won't
let you end up with her. You're a ten!
- Come on.
- Listen! You're a ten!
You're a ten! Kirk, don't do it!
I'm not going! I'm not going!
- OK, this is not good.
- All right, I'm going.
Whatever.
Last call for flight four-four-three.
- Damn it!
- Last call for flight four-four-three.
- Hello?
- Hey, Patty.
- Who is this?
- Steiner. Don't hang up.
How the fuck did you get my number?
- TSA. Moving on...
- No. no. no. Let's not move on.
This better not be where you ask me out
because you confused my hatred for you
for some kind of flirtation.
I thought I made myself clear.
No, no, no, you were clear. We're good.
- 'Cause I genuinely hate you also.
- Oh, cool.
Cool. And we're back to talking.
All right. So, Kirk is leaving
on a plane with another girl.
Now, I tried to get him off,
but they threw me off the plane!
Steiner, your screw-up
is not my problem.
No, we both screwed up.
We told them that it wasn't goanna work.
They believed us. So now,
unfortunately, I need your help.
Hello? Patty? Goddamn it.
you fucking hung up on me!
- OK, I'll see what I can do.
- Thank you.
Sorry.
I have a ground X-ray one radio check.
Taxi to one-two.
East West four-three. you're cleared
for taxi to runway two-seven.
So, we are seeing the
Dave Coulier tomorrow night,
and on Saturday we're goanna see
both of the Elvis tributes,
- and then on S...
- No.
- Excuse me?
- No, no, no. Steiner was right.
Flight attendants,
prepare for departure.
- Steiner was right.
- What are you doing? Kirk!
Yeah, I'm not going
to Branson with you people.
You are my family and I love you,
but really, with the exception of Mom,
you're all a bunch
of bloodsucking vampires
who never support anything I do.
I'm going to go find Molly
and show her that I am good enough.
So fuck you, Debbie.
Fuck you, Dylan.
Fuck you, Dad.
Fuck you... businessman. I'm sorry.
And, most of all, fuck you, Marnier.
Yep.
You never deserved me in the
first place, you evil little dwarf.
So fuck you all! Yep.
Sir. You need to take your seat.
We're pushing back.
Don't know if you just heard my speech,
but I need to get off this plane.
Well, if I reopen that cabin door,
that's a 25,000 dollar fine for you.
Twenty-five...?
What do you want to do?
Is there another seat I could take?
We're full. Now,
take your seat and buckle up.
Yep. OK.
Cabin crew, lock doors and cross-check.
Goanna be a long flight, eh, pirate?
What's going on?
What's the emergency?
- Molly, how are you doing?
- Fine.
No, I'm actually asking you.
How are you doing?
- You have photo ID, right?
- Well, yeah.
- Where are we going?
- Just buckle up!
We should be on our way shortly,
so just sit back, relax and...
The white zone is for
immediate loading and unloading...
You're goanna tell me what's going on?
In ten minutes, Kirk is leaving on
a plane for Branson with a horrible,
- horrible girl.
- Marnier?
- Yes. Let's go.
- If Kirk's getting back together
- with Marnier, I'm not going!
- In fourth grade, I peed in my pants.
On several occasions.
Everybody started calling me Steiner.
Know how I made it through
those dark days?
- Plastic underwear?
- In part.
But also Kirk. You see,
he told me to own that name.
Call myself Steiner,
so that nobody could hurt me.
- What's your point?
- Kirk's the best guy I know.
But he's like... He's like a spider.
You know? He's more afraid of you
then you are of him.
And he also, he has long legs and...
Look. If you want him,
you got to go get him.
- We're moving. Where is the package?
- It's here.
OK, we couldn't get him off the plane,
so we've got to get you on.
Oh, thank you, Steiner!
This is so exciting. Yes!
Oh, shit. Follow me.
- Excuse me!
- Hey!
- Come on!
- Boarding passes and IDs out.
- Let's keep it moving!
- One second.
Whoa, whoa! What the hell are you doing?
Putting her on a plane, that's what.
Well, unless she has a
first class ticket, back of the line.
Fuller, you have a choice.
You can step aside or you can fight me.
If that's how you want to go,
I warn you, I will go dark side.
OK? I will rip out your hair,
I'll bite your chin off,
and I will stab you in the eyes
with confiscated scissors.
'Cause I am an insane motherfucker!
You know that from the break room!
What's it goanna be?!
Yes!
Please check your seat belts.
We're preparing for departure.
Branson!
They've gone. We missed it.
No, no, no. No. No, this is not...
This is supposed to happen.
This isn't how this works.
- Yeah? Talk to Jack.
- Stop the plane.
Dude, done and done.
Yeah, that's how we roll.
Oh, come here, beautiful.
Time to go to work.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the Captain.
We got some kind of light on up here.
Some kind of mechanical problem.
Anyway, we're goanna have to deplane.
Oh, man! What's "deplane" mean?
Come on, Jack. Come on.
Come on, Jack!
That's it! Yeah. Let's go, let's go.
Look, Kirk, I do not know
what's gotten into you,
but I just want to say I forgive you
and we are going to go to Branson,
and we are going to enjoy it!
OK, you got something
off your chest, and that is fine.
And it's over now. We are goanna
pretend that it never happened.
Why are you walking so fast?
Kirk! We're solid, baby!
We're... Oh, that is it.
- That is it! Motherfucker!
- Excuse me. Sorry.
- Sorry. Excuse me. I'm sorry.
- I will catch you, Kirk!
- No...
- I will catch you!
- Excuse me.
- I'm faster than you!
Sorry.
I will catch you if it's
the last thing that I do...
- Who is it?
- It's Kirk. Kirk, where are you?
Steiner, you were right, buddy.
I just got off the plane.
I'm goanna go find Molly.
That's great, except
we're right here. I'm with Molly.
What?!
We came to find you. We're at the gate!
Turn around. we're here.
All right, I'm coming' to you.
Coming' to you!
Excuse me! Sorry, sorry!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, God.
Hey, wait! Cart, wait!
What the hell?
- Oh, my God!
- Go!
Hey!
Would you stop it?!
I think we should see other people!
Oh, Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
- You OK?
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- What are you doing' here?
- It was Patty and Steiners idea.
I just...
I just knew that I had to come find you.
- I nearly...
- Kirk, shut up. Let me speak.
That's a good idea.
You are out of shape.
- It's true.
- Yeah, I know.
Not what I thought you were goanna say.
You're uncoordinated.
You're not a college graduate,
you've never been to Europe,
and your car really is a shitbox.
- That's good.
- You were right.
I did ask you out because I thought
you'd be safe and I wouldn't get hurt.
And, yes, I lied to my parents because
I was worried what they'd think.
I'm sorry.
But I'm here to tell you that
I don't care if you want to be a pilot,
a TSA agent or shovel
elephant shit at the circus.
Because I missed you.
And I just want us to be together.
- Jesus...
- You really having to think about this?
- Shut up, Patty.
- You shut up!
I don't remember what the
specific question was, but...
- I do.
- You do?
- I will.
- You will?
I missed you.
Guys, this is...
It's a tale as old as time, you know?
Song as old as rhyme.
Think she's still not wearing' underwear?
- Just stop it.
- I heard you.
Seriously. tell me where we're going!
- Nope.
- Why won't you tell me?
You won't show me the tickets.
I'm goanna find out.
- Just trust me, OK?
- Oh, you're so annoying!
Ah, that she blows!
OK, that is not nearly big enough.
What the hell are you doing?
I've been taking a few lessons lately.
- That's what you've been up to?
- Yep.
I should ask you,
did you pack your bags yourself?
- Yes, I did.
- All right, good.
Everything seems to be in order.
You ever been to San Francisco?
- Yes.
- Good, 'cause we're going to Cleveland.
Pittsburgh tower,
November-five-four-five-Charlie-Papa
requesting takeoff clearance
on runway two-nine.
Five-Charlie-Papa.
you are cleared for takeoff.