**
* YOU WON'T ADMIT YOU LOVE ME *
* AND SO *
* HOW AM I EVER *
* TO KNOW *
* YOU ALWAYS TELL ME *
* PERHAPS, PERHAPS, PERHAPS *
* PERHAPS *
TV:
( couple arguing )
( channel changes )
( laughter )
( gunfire and sirens )
IT'S UP TO YOU.
Susan: OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE--
GISELLE, WILL YOU PLEASE
STOP TALKING TO ME LIKE THAT,
I'M NOT A CHILD!
IF YOU HAVE A COMPLAINT
ABOUT MY WORK,
YOU CAN TAKE IT STRAIGHT
TO JULIA DAVIS.
Giselle: SUSAN--
DON'T YOU "SUSAN" ME.
I'M HAPPY TO WORK
WITH YOU ON THIS PROJECT,
BUT WE HAVE TO HAVE
A SENSIBLE WORKING RELATIONSHIP.
( French accent )
I AM SORRY.
THIS IS HOW WE
DO THINGS IN FRANCE.
I RATHER DOUBT THAT.
AND BELIEVE ME,
JULIA WILL NOT BE HAPPY
THAT YOU ARE TAKING
THIS ATTITUDE.
I AM SORRY,
MY ENGLISH IS NOT SO GOOD.
YOU ARE GOING TOO FAST.
( speaking French )
Giselle: OUI.
AU REVOIR.
( sighs )
UH, SORRY.
IT'S JUST...
WELL, I, UH--
I REALLY LIKE
FRENCH WOMEN, THAT'S ALL.
Jane:
NO!
HE THOUGHT YOU WERE FRENCH?
I THINK THAT WAS
THE ONLY REASON
HE WAS INTERESTED.
WHY WERE YOU TALKING
IN FRENCH, ANYWAY?
OH, A NEW CLIENT.
GISELLE, THE FRENCH BITCH.
THIS IS SOMEONE
YOU DON'T LIKE?
OH, I LOVE IT
WHEN THAT HAPPENS.
MAKES YOU SEEM
LIKE A PERSON.
SHE'S SUPPOSED TO BE
COMING AROUND FOR A DRINK
WITH STEVE AND I
THIS EVENING,
BUT I'VE JUST TOLD HER
TO SOD OFF.
IT MUST BE REALLY GREAT
BEING A FRENCH BITCH.
IT MUST BE
SO MUCH EASIER.
EASIER?
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED
TO BE FRENCH,
BUT I'VE NEVER HAD
THE OPPORTUNITIES.
SO WHAT WAS THE GUY LIKE?
I'M WITH STEVE NOW.
YEAH, BUT IF YOU HAD
A NIGHT OFF FROM STEVE,
IS HE THE KIND OF GUY
YOU'D GO FOR?
THERE'S NOBODY
I'D GO FOR--
ABSOLUTELY NOBODY,
NOBODY AT ALL.
OR AN AUSTRALIAN.
AN AUSTRALIAN?
SORRY.
I DON'T QUITE KNOW
WHERE THAT CAME FROM.
AUSTRALIANS ARE HER WEAKNESS.
SALLY--
WE DROVE AROUND AUSTRALIA
TEN YEARS AGO, REMEMBER?
I REMEMBER WHO WAS
IN THE DRIVING SEAT
FOR THE WHOLE TRIP.
YOUR OVARIES.
SHE'S EXAGGERATING.
WE ALWAYS KNEW
IT WAS TIME TO SKIP TOWN
WHEN A BAR
WAS NAMED AFTER HER.
SO THIS GUY,
WAS HE AN AUSTRALIAN?
NO, HE WAS JUST A GUY,
NOTHING SPECIAL.
ANYWAY, HE ONLY LIKED ME
'CAUSE HE THOUGHT I WAS FRENCH.
SO WHAT HAPPENED?
HE ASKED ME
IF I HAD A BOYFRIEND,
AND I SAID YES,
AND THAT'S ALL
THERE IS TO IT.
SO, I BET YOU'VE GOT
A BOYFRIEND THEN, EH?
OUI.
YOU LET HIM THINK
YOU WERE FRENCH!
WHY?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT JUST...HAPPENED.
IT WAS JUST...
FUN TO PRETEND.
OH, I KNOW
ALL ABOUT PRETENDING.
I ONCE WENT ON HOLIDAY
AND PRETENDED TO BE TWINS.
IT WAS AMAZING FUN.
I INVENTED THIS MAD,
GLAMOROUS SISTER
AND WENT 'ROUND
REALLY ANNOYING EVERYBODY.
I COULD GET AWAY WITH ANYTHING
WHEN I WAS MY CRAZY TWIN JANE.
YOU'RE JANE.
KINDA STUCK.
IT'S A LONG STORY.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
A YEAR INTO A RELATIONSHIP.
STEVE'S WONDERFUL.
I LOVE HIM TO BITS.
IT'S JUST--HE NEVER THINKS
I'M FRENCH ANYMORE.
YEAH.
RIGHT.
DO YOU KNOW
WHAT I MEAN BY THAT?
NO.
NOT AT ALL.
WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT
IT'S LIKE AT THE START,
WHEN THEY'RE ALL
FIERY-EYED AND EAGER
AND THEY HAVEN'T
SEEN YOU NAKED YET.
AND IT'S LIKE HE'S
SMASHING AT YOUR DOOR
WITH HIS MIGHTY BATTERING RAM,
AND HE'S PROMISING
TO RAVISH YOU FOREVER.
SO YOU BRACE YOURSELF
FOR MAN OVERLOAD
AND THROW OPEN THE DOORS,
AND WHAT DO YOU FIND
STANDING THERE?
AN OVERSIZED TODDLER
WHO WANTS HIS DINNER.
AND BEFORE YOU CAN SAY
THERE'S BEEN
A TERRIBLE MISTAKE,
HE'S SNORING ON YOUR SOFA,
AND THE WHOLE PLACE
SMELLS OF FEET.
OH, AND NOW I'M FEELING
REALLY GUILTY.
I'M GONNA,
UH, PHONE HIM.
NOT ENOUGH SHOES.
WHAT?
MEN-- THEIR FEET
GET SORT OF MARINATED.
THAT'S WEIRD.
WHAT?
ALL MY PROGRAMED NUMBERS
HAVE GONE.
I CAN NEVER PROGRAM IN
MY NUMBERS.
NEVER BRING MYSELF TO PUT
MY FRIENDS IN ORDER.
OH, I PUT THEM IN
THE ORDER I LIKE THEM.
YOU'RE AT NUMBER THREE.
NUMBER THREE,
THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WHO'S NUMBER ONE
AND TWO?
OH, I HAVEN'T MET
A ONE OR A TWO YET.
OH.
OR A SEVEN, ACTUALLY.
SO WHERE AM I?
I'VE ONLY GOT
TEN SPACES.
I WASN'T ABLE TO
SQUEEZE YOU IN.
OKAY.
EXCUSE ME WHILE I TRY
TO REMEMBER
MY BOYFRIEND'S NUMBER.
SUSAN LIKES AUSTRALIANS?
HER GREATEST FEAR
IS THAT ONE DAY
THEY'LL ALL TURN UP
ON HER DOORSTEP
AND GRIDLOCK LONDON.
HI.
OH--
( French accent )
HELLO.
I WAS RATHER HOPING
YOU'D BE HERE.
( continues accent )
EXCUSE ME,
I'M JUST MAKING
A CALL TO MY BOYFRIEND.
RIGHT. I DON'T SUPPOSE
THERE'S ANY CHANCE
I COULD TEMPT YOU
AWAY FROM HIM?
NOTHING COULD TEMPT ME
AWAY FROM MY BOYFRIEND.
Man on phone: G'DAY.
BRUCE'S BAR AND GRILL.
PARDON?
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
OH, I'M SORRY,
I THINK I MAY HAVE MISDIALED.
IT'S OKAY.
NO WORRIES.
OH, HA HA HA!
SORRY, MY DARLING.
I DID NOT RECOGNIZE
YOUR VOICE.
YOU SOUND SO STRANGE.
EXCUSE ME?
I SHALL BE AROUND
TO SEE YOU VERY SOON.
MY HEART IS BEATING
LIKE A BIG DRUM OF LOVE.
ARE YOU FEELING ALL RIGHT?
( sighs )
WHERE AM I PHONING?
BRUCE'S BAR AND GRILL.
I TOLD YOU.
WHERE IS THAT?
WHERE?
IN AUSTRALIA?
NO, NO. LONDON.
STADLER STREET.
AH, I KNOW STADLER STREET.
WHERE?
NEAR SUSAN'S.
SUSAN'S?
YEAH, YOU KNOW--
SUSAN'S.
THE BAR.
THE BAR?
YEAH, YOU MAY NOT
HAVE HEARD OF IT,
IT'S FOR AUSTRALIANS.
THERE'S A BAR
FOR AUSTRALIANS
CALLED SUSAN'S?
IN LONDON?!
OH, YEAH!
YOU ALWAYS FIND A WHOLE BUNCH
OF AUSTRALIANS IN SUSAN'S.
THIS MUST SEEM
LIKE A STUPID QUESTION,
BUT DOES THIS BAR
HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH SUSAN WALKER?
YOU KNOWSUSAN WALKER?
TV:
( gunfire and sirens )
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
( sighs )
ALL RIGHT.
I'M JUST OFF
TO THE LOO.
I DON'T THINK
ANYONE ASKED.
OH, SORRY.
NO, UH...
IT'S JUST A HABIT.
OH.
YOU MUST HAVE A GIRLFRIEND.
HELLO.
HI.
SO, DO YOU?
WHAT?
HAVE A GIRLFRIEND?
YOU SAID HELLO?
YES, JUST HELLO,
THAT'S ALL.
SO WHAT DID YOU TELL HER?
TELL HER?
WHEN SHE ASKED
IF YOU HAD A GIRLFRIEND.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S BRILLIANT
ABOUT HAVING A GIRLFRIEND?
JEFF!
YOU'VE BEEN GOING OUT
WITH JULIA FOR THREE DAYS.
WE'VE NEVER SEEN YOU
THIS HAPPY.
IT WOULD BE A SHAME
IF YOU FORCED US TO KILL YOU.
HAVING A GIRLFRIEND
IS LIKE LEGALIZED SEX.
JEFF, SEX IS LEGAL.
IT ALWAYS HAS BEEN LEGAL.
WHENEVER I HAVE SEX
WITH JULIA,
IT'S JUST SO REALISTIC.
IT IS ACTUALLY REAL, JEFF.
I'VE GOT MY OWN PRIVATE BOTTOM!
WHAT?
ANYTIME I WANT TO
SEE A BOTTOM,
I JUST ASK JULIA.
"THERE'S NOTHING TO WATCH
ON THE TELE TONIGHT, DEAR,
WHY DON'T YOU POP
YOUR ARSE OUT?"
IT'S BAD ENOUGH YOU'RE GOING OUT
WITH MY GIRLFRIEND'S BOSS--
I DON'T WANT DETAILS.
SHE'S MY BOSS, TOO.
WHICH IS GREAT, BECAUSE
SOMETIMES WE PLAY THIS GAME--
JEFF, NO!
SO...
SHE ASKED YOU
IF YOU HAD A GIRLFRIEND,
WHAT DID YOU SAY?
I SAID YES.
GOOD. FINE.
OF COURSE I DID.
WHAT ELSE COULD I SAY?
GREAT.
I-I MAY HAVE
PHRASED IT BADLY.
HOW BADLY
CAN YOU PHRASE "YES"?
NO.
THAT WAS
QUITE BADLY PHRASED.
OKAY!
I MEANT TO SAY YES,
AND I MISSED BY ONE WORD!
I'M SOSORRY
I'M NOT PERFECT.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
JUST TELL HER?
I WOULD NEVER
DO THAT TO JULIA.
WE HAVE A RELATIONSHIP
BASED ON COMPLETE TRUST.
JEFF, YOU DON'T
HAVE A RELATIONSHIP
BASED ON A COMPLETE WEEK.
WHAT'S THAT
SUPPOSED TO MEAN?
IT MEANS THAT THERE ARE
THREE THINGS
ALL MEN SHOULD KNOW,
AND IT'S TIME
YOU DID, TOO--
YOU'RE NEVER GONNA BE FAMOUS,
YOU'RE FATTER THAN YOU THINK,
AND MOST IMPORTANT OF ALL--
THEY DON'T
KEEP WEARING STOCKINGS.
JULIA ALWAYS
WEARS STOCKINGS.
( snickers )
NO, REALLY.
SHE'S ALWAYS WORN THEM.
SHE ALWAYS WILL--SHE TOLD ME.
IN FACT, JULIA TOLD ME SHE
All:
PREFERS WEARING STOCKINGS.
WHAT?
STOCKINGS AREN'T REAL, JEFF.
THEY'RE A MYTH.
STOCKINGS ARE REAL,
I'VE SEEN 'EM.
OH, SURE, THERE ARE
SOME STOCKINGS OUT THERE,
BUT THERE'S WHAT,
TEN PAIRS IN THE WHOLE WORLD?
TEN, AT MOST.
TEN PAIRS FOR ALL OF THEM.
THEY SHARE THEM OUT.
( imitates woman )
OH, JULIA, YOU GOT
A NEW BOYFRIEND?
YOUR TURN WITH
THE STOCKINGS,THEN.
BUT WE'LL NEED THEM BACK
ON TUESDAY,
THERE'S AN ANNIVERSARY
IN NEW ZEALAND.
TUESDAY.
THE STOCKINGS WILL GO, JEFF.
THEY'LL JUST MELT AWAY.
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
OKAY...
JULIA'S PANTS--
REALLY SMALL?
YEAH, TINY.
REALLY TINY.
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN WISPY
AND A TRICK OF THE LIGHT?
YOU COULD ACCIDENTLY SWALLOW
THREE WHOLE PAIRS IN ONE GO.
TRUST ME.
HA HA HA!
HA HA HA.
GREAT, AREN'T THEY?
THEY'RE NOT LIKE
REAL PANTS,
THEY'RE LIKE
THE GHOST OF PANTS.
JEFF?
YEAH?
THEY SPREAD.
WHAT?
PANTS. THEY SPREAD
AND GROW.
EXPERTS CAN DETERMINE
THE AGE OF A RELATIONSHIP
FROM PANTS SPREADAGE ALONE.
YOU START OFF
WITH THAT SEXY LITTLE THONG...
AND ONE DAY YOU'RE
LOOKING AT THE MAKINGS
OF A DECENT SIZE TRAMPOLINE.
IT'S NOT GONNA BE LIKE THAT
WITH ME AND JULIA.
JEFF, JEFF...
BEFORE YOU KNOW IT,
YOU'LL BE SITTING
ON A SOFA WITH JULIA,
SHE'LL BE WEARING PANTS
LARGE ENOUGH
TO COVER SWITZERLAND,
AND YOU'LL DISCOVER THAT
YOU'RE UNABLE TO MAKE
THE SLIGHTEST MOVEMENT
WITHOUT HER SAYING,
"WHERE ARE YOU GOING?"
EVERY TIME--
SHE WON'T EVEN KNOW
SHE'S SAYING IT.
IT LIKE YOU'VE SET OFF
A MOTION SENSOR.
AND THEN, YOU'LL NOTICE
THAT YOUR HOUSE
IS COVERED IN SHOES.
SHOES. SHOES EVERYWHERE!
WHY DO THEY HAVE
SO MANY SHOES?
DO THEY HAVE EXTRA FEET
WE DON'T KNOW ABOUT?
DID THEY SPROUT ROWS
OF ADDITIONAL FEET
WHILE WE'RE ASLEEP
AND GALLOP AROUND THE STREETS
AT NIGHT SHOUTING,
"WHERE ARE YOU GOING?!"
AHEM.
SORRY.
DRIFTED A BIT THERE.
SO...
THIS GIRL YOU CHATTED UP
IN THE BAR--
I DIDN'T CHAT HER UP.
I'M WITH SUSAN.
I'M VERY HAPPY WITH SUSAN.
I LOVE SUSAN.
SO WHAT HAPPENED
WITH THE GIRL?
NOTHING HAPPENED.
WE TALKED FOR A BIT,
WE HAD A COUPLE OF DRINKS,
EXCHANGED PHONE NUMBERS,
AND WENT OUR SEPARATE WAYS.
YOU EXCHANGED
PHONE NUMBERS?!
OH, FINE--
FOCUS ON THAT PART.
YOU GAVE HER
YOUR ACTUAL PHONE NUMBER?
I'M A BLOKE.
I CAN'T WITHHOLD
MY NUMBER FROM A WOMAN,
I HAVEN'T GOT THE SKILLS.
YEAH, BUT THIS GIRL,
SHE COULD PHONE AT ANY TIME.
I KNOW.
WHILE SUSAN'S HERE.
WELL, SUSAN'S HERE
ALL THE TIME--
JEFF, PLEASE! I KNOW!
STEVE, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO MOVE OUT.
OKAY, DID SHE LOOK LIKE
THE TYPE TO PHONE?
YEAH, SHE--SHE REALLY
LOOKED THE TYPE.
SO, SHE'S GONNA WAIT
FOR YOU TO PHONE
THEN SHE'S GONNA GET RIGHT IN
PHONING YOU.
HOW LONG HAS IT BEEN?
A WEEK AND A DAY.
( phone rings )
IT'S HER!
IT MIGHT BE!
TELL HER SHE'S GOT
THE WRONG NUMBER.
SHE'LL THINK SHE
WROTE IT DOWN WRONG.
IF IT'S HER, I'M GOING
TO DO THIS PROPERLY.
I'M AN ADULT,
FOR GOD'S SAKE.
( ringing )
( Australian accent )
G'DAY. BRUCE'S BAR AND GRILL.
Susan ( French accent ):
PARDON?
BRUCE'S BAR AND GRILL.
HOW CAN I HELP YOU?
Good accent.
Susan told me.
OH, I'M SORRY,
I THINK I MAY HAVE MISDIALED.
IT'S OKAY.
NO WORRIES.
It's not her,
it's some French woman.
OH...SORRY, MY DARLING.
I DID NOT RECOGNIZE
YOUR VOICE.
YOU SOUND SO STRANGE.
EXCUSE ME?
I SHALL BE AROUND
TO SEE YOU VERY SOON.
MY HEART IS BEATING
LIKE A BIG DRUM OF LOVE.
Could be the girl
from the bar.
She could be
having a joke.
ARE YOU FEELING ALL RIGHT?
WHERE AM I PHONING?
BRUCE'S BAR AND GRILL.
I TOLD YOU.
WHERE IS THAT?
WHERE?
IN AUSTRALIA?
NO, NO. LONDON.
Stadler Street.
STADLER STREET.
AH, I KNOW STADLER STREET.
WHERE?
Near Susan's.
NEAR SUSAN'S.
SUSAN'S?
YEAH, YOU KNOW,
SUSAN'S.
TH-THE BAR.
THE BAR?
YEAH, YOU MAY NOT
HAVE HEARD OF IT,
IT'S FOR AUSTRALIANS.
THERE'S A BAR
FOR AUSTRALIANS
CALLED SUSAN'S?
IN LONDON?
OH, YEAH!
YOU ALWAYS FIND A WHOLE BUNCH
OF AUSTRALIANS IN SUSAN'S.
Near Susan's?!
THIS MUST SEEM
LIKE A STUPID QUESTION,
BUT DOES THIS BAR
HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH SUSAN WALKER?
YOU KNOW SUSAN WALKER?!
YOU ALSO KNOW
SUSAN WALKER?
OH, YEAH.
EVERYBODY HERE KNOWS SUSAN.
HOW DO YOU KNOW HER,
THEN?
I-I AMGISELLE.
I AM SUSAN'S NEW BITCH.
OH, UH...
CLIENT--
SUSAN'S NEW CLIENT.
UH, LOOK, I'D BETTER BE
GETTING ON.
YES, YES,
OF COURSE.
NO, WAIT!
HELLO?
UH, EXCUSE ME ASKING,
BUT, UM...
WERE YOU ONE OF SUSAN'S...
SPECIAL FRIENDS?
WHAT?
SUSAN HAS SPOKEN SO OFTEN
OF HER GREAT LOVE
OF AUSTRALIANS--
AUSTRALIA.
ARE YOU PERHAPS...
DAVID?
NIGEL?
BILL?
MARTIN?
DENNIS?
I-I WILL NARROW IT DOWN--
CANBERRA?
MELBOURNE? SYDNEY?
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
UH, DICK.
UH--UH--DICK DARLINGTON.
( disconnects )
WHAT'S WRONG?
SUSAN SLEPT WITH AUSTRALIA!
Sally:
SUSAN.
WHAT'S WRONG?
WHAT?
UM...NOTHING.
GOTTA GO.
( door closes )
SHOULD WE GO AFTER HER?
IN A MINUTE.
NOW, TRY IT AGAIN.
( French accent )
I AM GISELLE.
( whipping sound )
I AM A FRENCH BITCH.
( French accent )
I AM GISELLE.
I AM A FRENCH BITCH.
OHH...TRY IT
WITH MORE WINE.
HOW COULD SHE KNOW SUSAN?
IT DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
GISELLE. JULIA MENTIONED
A GISELLE-- NEW CLIENT.
BUT HOW COULD SHE KNOW
STUFF ABOUT SUSAN
I DON'T KNOW?
I'M PHONING SUSAN.
AND SHE WAS FRENCH.
SHE CALLED HER
THE FRENCH BITCH.
HOW MANY FRENCH BITCHES
CAN THERE BE?
SEVEN.
WHAT?
IN MY EXPERIENCE.
( cell phone ringing )
WHY HAVE YOU GOT
SUSAN'S MOBILE?
I WAS IN HER OFFICE YESTERDAY.
I MUST HAVE PICKED UP
THE WRONG ONE.
SHE'S GOT
THE SAME ONE AS ME.
SUSAN MUST HAVE MY PHONE.
TELL YOU WHAT...
AND I'M NOT JUST SAYING THIS--
COMPARED TO YOU,
MASTURBATION IS IN
ITS INFANCY.
Julia: I SEEM TO BE MISSING
THREE PAIRS OF KNICKERS.
SUSAN SPEAKS FRENCH,
DOESN'T SHE?
WHAT?
YOUR FRIEND, SUSAN WALKER,
SHE SPEAKS FRENCH, YEAH?
I THINK SO. WHY?
WE'VE GOT THIS NEW CLIENT,
GISELLE.
I PUT HER WITH SUSAN,
BUT SHE'S A BIT OF TRICKY ONE.
I SHOULD HAVE DEALT
WITH HER MYSELF,
BUT I CAN'T SPEAK FRENCH.
SHE'S FRENCH?
WELL, YEAH.
EXCELLENT.
AND A BITCH.
A BITCH?
EXCELLENT.
OKAY, I'M BACK
TO BEING YOUR BOSS NOW.
NOW GO BACK
TO THE OFFICE,
OR I'LL SET
THE FRENCH BITCH ON YOU.
YEAH?
EXCELLENT.
( growls )
JEFF!
( door slams )
( French accent )
THIS IS GISELLE.
YOUR ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS
ARE A DISGRACE,
AND I AM EXTREMELY DISAPPOINTED
WITH YOUR PERFORMANCE.
IF WERE UP TO ME,
I WOULD PUT YOU OVER MY KNEE
AND SPANK YOUR BOTTOM.
Susan:
OH, FOR GOD'S SAKE!
GISELLE, WILL YOU PLEASE
STOP TALKING TO ME LIKE THAT?
I'M NOT A CHILD.
IF YOU HAVE A COMPLAINT
ABOUT MY WORK,
YOU CAN TAKE IT STRAIGHT
TO JULIA DAVIS!
SUSAN!?
DON'T YOU "SUSAN" ME!
I'M HAPPY TO WORK
WITH YOU ON THIS PROJECT,
BUT WE HAVE TO HAVE A SENSIBLE
WORKING RELATIONSHIP.
I AM SORRY,
I, UM...
MY ENGLISH
IS NOT SO GOOD.
YOU ARE GOING TOO FAST.
( speaking French )
HI.
YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
LISTEN, I'VE JUST GOT
SOME WORK TO FINISH UP ON.
RIGHT.
PATRICK AND JEFF ARE HERE.
OH, NO PROBLEM.
I CAN GO IN THE BEDROOM.
FINE.
GREAT.
SEE YOU IN A MO'.
SEE YOU.
( video game noises )
OKAY, THIS IS GETTING
COMPLICATED.
NOW, GISELLE KNOWS SUSAN
BECAUSE SHE'S A CLIENT--
WHAT IF GISELLE FINDS OUT
I'M DICK DARLINGTON?
WHY SHOULD SHE?
SHE MIGHT TELL SUSAN,
AND THEN I'LL HAVE TO EXPLAIN
WHY I WAS PRETENDING
TO BE AN AUSTRALIAN
ON THE PHONE.
IF SUSAN FINDS OUT,
YOU SAY YOU'RE
DICK DARLINGTON.
WHY ME?
OKAY. YOU, PATRICK.
NO WAY.
ANYONE ELSE WANT A BEER?
OH, COME ON.
I-I'LL GET SOME BEERS.
( phone rings )
OH, SHIT!
AM I DICK DARLINGTON NOW?
SHH!
IT MIGHT BE HER.
(French accent )
HELLO.
IS THAT BRUCE'S BAR AND GRILL?
I KNOW THAT IT MUST BE,
BECAUSE I PRESS "REDIAL."
G'DAY...AGAIN.
IS THAT THE LOVELY GISELLE?
I DO NOT BELIEVE THERE IS
A BRUCE'S BAR AND GRILL,
AND I DO NOT BELIEVE
THAT THERE IS A BAR
CALLED SUSAN'S.
THIS IS A JOKE
AT THE EXPENSE OF MY FRIEND,
SUSAN WALKER.
NO, IT ISN'T.
DON'T BE SILLY.
I WILL TELL YOU HOW
I KNOW THIS--
BECAUSE SUSAN WALKER
IS RIGHT HERE WITH ME.
OH, NO, SHE ISN'T.
I CAN ASSURE YOU SHE IS.
WELL, I CAN ASSURE YOU
SHE'S RIGHT HERE WITH ME.
I AM PASSING THE PHONE
TO SUSAN WALKER.
HELLO, THIS IS
SUSAN WALKER SPEAKING.
SUSAN, CAN YOU TELL
THIS FRENCH BITCH
THAT YOU'RE SUSAN WALKER?
HELLO, THIS IS SUSAN WALKER.
HELLO?
( doorbell )
Jeff:
I'LL GET IT.
BRUCE'S BAR AND GRILL--
WERE YOU ANSWERING
THE PHONE AS AN AUSTRALIAN?
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
STEVE...
I'M GISELLE.
YOU'RE GISELLE?
I WAS GISELLE
ON THE PHONE.
SUSAN, I'M REALLY SORRY
TO INTERRUPT,
BUT I JUST HAD TO TELL YOU...
IT WAS ME.
I WAS GISELLE ON THE PHONE.
YOU WERE GISELLE?
I'M SO, SO SORRY.
SHE WAS GISELLE?!
NO, I WAS GISELLE!
I WAS GISELLE.
WHO WAS GISELLE?
I'M REALLY SORRY
ABOUT THIS, SUSAN.
BUT I WAS GISELLE
ON THE PHONE. IT WAS ME.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I PHONED YOU.
JULIA, I WAS GISELLE,
AND I PHONED HIM.
AND HE WAS DICK DARLINGTON.
NO, SUSAN...
I WAS DICK DARLINGTON.
NO. LOOK, IT'S OKAY, JEFF.
AND I WAS GISELLE.
WHAT'S THE MATTER
WITH YOU? I WAS GISELLE!
( doorbell )
I'LL GET THAT.
I PHONED YOU AT LUNCH.
I THOUGHT I WAS
TALKING TO JEFF.
I PUT ON A FRENCH ACCENT
AND I SAID
I'D SPANK YOUR BOTTOM.
EXCELLENT.
I WAS GISELLE!
I WAS GISELLE.
WHAT IN THE NAME
OF GOD IS GOING ON HERE?
Steve: JANE?
( French accent )
NO! I AM GISELLE.
AND SO AM I!
IN THAT CASE,
I'M DICK DARLINGTON.
NO! I'M DICK DARLINGTON!
YEAH, WE'RE DICK DARLINGTON.
AND I'M GISELLE!
I'M GISELLE!
AND SO ARE WE!
WOULD EVERYONE JUST SHUT UP!
THANK YOU!
( phone rings )
OH, WHAT?!
HELLO.
WHO COULD IT POSSIBLY
BE THIS TIME?
GISELLE OR DICK DARLINGTON?!
IT'S SOMEONE CALLED YVONNE
FOR YOU.
NO, UH...
CAN'T COME TO THE PHONE.
WHY NOT?
THERE'S PEOPLE
IN THE WAY.
OKAY, I'LL PUT IT ON SPEAKER.
Yvonne:
STEVE.
HELLO.
HELLO, STEVE.
IT'S YVONNE.
REMEMBER? FROM THE BAR?
OR DO YOU GIVE
YOUR PHONE NUMBER OUT
TO EVERY STRANGE
WOMAN YOU MEET?
H-HI.
LISTEN, I WAS WONDERING...
HI. THERE'S BEEN A BIT
OF A MISUNDERSTANDING.
I'M ACTUALLY WITH SOMEONE,
SO I WON'T BE ABLE TO, UH...
I'M SORRY, YVONNE.
GOOD-BYE.
WELL, I THINK WE'D BETTER, UM...
YEAH, I THINK
WE'D BETTER.
BYE.
M-M-MET HER IN THE BAR--
GAVE HER MY NUMBER.
STUPID, UH...
BUT I WAS NEVER,
EVER GOING TO...
THAT'S WHY I WAS
PRETENDING TO BE A, YOU KNOW...
DICK?
YES.
HMM.
SOMETIMES I MISS
BEING SINGLE, TOO.
I GUESS THIS MEANS
THE HONEYMOON'S OVER.
NO, NO, I DON'T--
I-I STILL...
REAL LIFE STARTS HERE.
IF YOU...STILL WANT IT TO.
IF YOU DON'T, UM...
LET ME KNOW.
I QUITE FANCY
POPPING BACK TO
AUSTRALIA.
THERE MUST BE
A WHOLE NEW BATCH
PAST THE AGE OF CONSENT
BY NOW.
SUSAN.
WHAT?
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
IT'S UP TO YOU.
IT'S UP TO ME...
IT IS UP TO ME.
IT'S UP TO ME.
OH.
( French accent )
HELLO.
I AM GISELLE.
* IF YOU CAN'T
MAKE YOUR MIND UP *
* WE'LL NEVER GET STARTED *
* AND I DON'T WANT TO WIND UP *
* BEING PARTED *
* BROKEN-HEARTED *
* SO IF YOU REALLY LOVE ME *
* SAY YES *
* AND PLEASE DON'T TELL ME *
* PERHAPS *